in the
vocabulary of not an
and an implication
OK it's
the fundamental concept
with which we're dealing here
the notion of
a derivation
derivation of
a set of formulae
the derivation of the
from gamma is
by definition laying down stipulated
is finite
i one
two and
a formula
OK the one
well informed
such that
it's not just any finite sequence satisfy certain conditions
first of all
it gives is becoming specific derivation of the season to forget to include this one
and you try to prove you metatheorem and
you forget that is supposed to be derivation to be
in the sequence
i i
everyone necessary to illustrate the
it can be various things to everything in there is going to be justified in
some way
a member
of gamma
it's the derivation from gamma you're allowed to assume things in gamma
you're you're allowed those
an axiom of logic
tell you what that is
an immediate consequence
of formulae in
the set
i want
two a
i minus one that is
you can derive it in one step
from stuff this earlier in the sequence
the idea is you start your
throwing in your premises assumptions
you may one step inferences from that
extending this sequence until you get
o thing in deriving its
again kind of obviously what a derivation
linear derivation is
two things i haven't told you
what is an axiom of logic and what is immediate consequence
of course if you change if you take different definitions of axioms different definitions of
consequence you get different
so it's a valid derivations
we want to set up so that we get exactly the right classical
first order logic
there are many many ways of
doing that
formulating first order logic
so what's called a hilbert
calculus or fraga system
a couple of
logicians formulated logic like this in the early days
and i'm going to lay things down like this
we have infinitely many axioms
i'm not gonna write all
they are just to the all the instances of some scheme some formulas schemes
so the first one
is there any formula of the form
a implies b implies a
is an axiom
OK so
this is clearly a and b can be any
formulae here there are infinitely many different formerly plug for a and b whatever you
put in a is an axiom if it's about four
i don't speculate as to why
anything of that form should be thought to be logically correct
i just lay down that it is
the second one that i lay down
if a implies
b implies c
if a implies b as well
it implies c
another axiom scheme and again for any formula a b c in the language
and the third axiom scheme
if not a implies not be
then the
implies a
none of those essentially involve quantifiers
of course there are instances
formulae a and b may have quantifiers in that that's all right
but the connectives only the connectives are essentially involved
in the reasoning
there are
we need some axioms
specifically to govern
the notion of universality
and the first of these is just a little bit tricky to state
it's easy to see what we're after
but it just needs a little bit of careful formulation
what we're after is the idea that
this says
but some descriptions true everything
well is true of everything
then it's going to be true of any particular thing
so if you've got something that says for every x kx
you should be able to substitute any term t four x
and get the correct
piece of reasoning
we need some notation for substitution
i'm going to use the subscript superscript notation no doubt every other lecturer in the
summer school is going to use some of the notation
that's life
you have to cope
u graph that you can catch
so the axiom says
but the universal so claim for all x a
with any term t
substituted for x
OK so
all right that eighty four x
substituting for all
occurrences of x
in formula
let's do break this point i talk about
support vector machines
before talking about that but we can
OK we are making the task of classification we want to find
the plane the speed
according to the label information
you can ask ourselves which is the best optimal separating hyperplane
so already fisher discriminant analysis
according to fisher discriminant analysis the best separating hyperplane
it is the one that is obtained by maximizing the difference between the mean of
the two classes normalized by
the sum of the the covered the sum of the variances of the two class
in fisher discriminant analysis we are solving these optimisation problem and the solution is given
five four one
for support vector machine we have the best of luck
that is the one that maximizes the margin between the two classes
this is a pretty quite intuitive
the idea because the
the best hyperplane is the one that maximizes this ability
in the sense that we can maximize the top part of our this without introducing
any make misclassification
i think you know that the
o point closest to the hyperplane are usually referred to as the support vectors
and the distance from the this point from the support vector to the hyperplane
i put
it's got i've indicated with be
you know if we risk scale that
in order to be these
well we can always have scale value in order to be these events equal to
one divided by number of views
if we do that the imagine
given by
two times divided norm of w
let's see how we we can compute our similar separating hyperplane
we are given a training set of
input output b
and we want to the same time to correctly classifying to correctly classify all training
and the maximising the margin so to correctly
by find a lot training that means imposing
the condition that y
the for the next plus b it's great that you wouldn't the one maximize the
this is the expression of the is the expression for the matching
so you imposing to doing this so we get these
optimisation problem that is there a quadratic one
quadratic programming optimisation problem
four from an optimisation perspective this is pretty easy problem because we have a quadratic
objective function
so it means that we can find and we have a set of linear constraints
so it means that we can find
one global of more w
in principle we can compute the solution of this problem using any found to be
solved but it's something that i do not recommend because there are technique that has
been developed for this task
usually from the primary problem that is this one
exactly compute we typically computer this solution passing to that well
and this is the equivalent to do well formulation of the problem that is also
a QP problem
and this could be
he did well problem we
i want to find a solution that of the first
each for a belfast on the lagrange multipliers
and it's a phrase associated with a coarse terrain with linear constraint of the primary
problem and each is associated with training points and i have different from the zero
correspond to support
usually when computing the solution of the support vector machine we get many outside i
went to zero
so we have the fast solution and we only have a few support vectors
we should not that since we are dealing with
this problem and we are computed in the dot product between training basis on the
training set on the form of the product
given the problem there is no
from the solution of the dual problem how far you can get the solution of
the primal in this form
we get what they
and by the
and you should note the solution is computed only from one of the nonzero alpha
so only from the training points corresponding to the support vectors
if did finally hyperplane function is given by
the last four more
you should not that again like this formulation
of the world
or to the issues in function rely only on the inner product between the test
he made this paper which is quite nice
there's the paper and there is the the software as well
that he can do
both the forward and inverse
in this in the squared operations
and the same thing the same performance can get with the
with the
for the correlation
and this is a very important operations
but the compilation the convolution and correlation there are more or less
related to each other
if i'm not wrong here
the convolution and
correlation they are related by transposition of one of those
i think the late one
so you have all efficient things for
limitations on
in this case here showed four continents
here i showed you the sphere but you can you can
we can replace this before
any other group
because you have a representation theory
for all groups
you can construct the representations and
most of them if they have some geometrical meaning they would have a special function
that we have a regression
and then you can exploit it
so here is the
i think the same setup for the
limitations on
for the
we just form on the permutation group
the full performers
exactly the same
it's in a different order here
because this is the forward transform you go from the function space
the fourier space
and here is how you go back from the
to the
the function
and those whole holdings always representation
so this is a representation of one element
times before are transform indexed by that
the example right
other than that
these are
there are the
nothing important thing going
these representations here
you should have asked me this this question
as i said here you have many representations
for the same
how the world also some over there
it turns out that
you have written to the set
if you have for example four
s three
you never get much of this size
that is irreducible
you have all these
all of them
four s three you have
only a one-dimensional
two dimensional
representation and another one which is
so these all
the redoubtable representations for as
for example the that defining representation of a permutation that you probably know
is the metrics three about three right
where you
you have i e j here
and then
four to one here
zero otherwise
i think
is that correct to bear
o is the
well yes i want to represent for example this permutation
two this is not good
OK this should be always one
and you have let's say you want to flee
for one year
and one year
so i would flip this with this
I thought I would start by maybe them
most the outstanding example
the direction of linear programming
so linear programming is it's an a whole area it's linear algebra within quality that's
what it really is about and and the whole area just sprang into existence after
world war 2 or in the in the development of world war 2 but I
guess the name of most famous name in linear programming is dancing tool
created this simplex method is pretty unusual for a method to
fundamentally unchanged for such a long time that that that the 1st method suggested to
solve linear programs should turn out to have such a long life and still still
alive and with competition now from different a different class of methods but they
I hope you will feel that this subject is kind of fun
I'm taking linear programming well just creating an example here but as to show what
duality is about an hour and then the 2nd lecture this afternoon please sources
David part of it is possible that it's about some integer programming problems and like
the marriage problem married usually have an integer number of marriages and in fact this
problem is highly moral you have either 0 or 1 um marriages and and how
many are possible
and the network flow problem maximal flow problem cell that's the 2nd lecture this will
linear algebra as I said let let me see what are the what's the primal
problem the unknown is x
so we
minimize the cost
which is
C transpose that you see the linear narrative that cause depends linearly X one up
to X and might be the
as amounts
of different materials
that we have to buy
these would be the costs over the unit cost of those materials so we buy
and materials and these amounts of these costs that's our total cost what the constraints
the constraints of
the constraints are 1 here is the key constraint is that the vector X all
the components have to be non-negative
we can't use negative amounts of materials
and the other constraint is that we have to satisfy some requirements and those will
be expressed by a x equals the
so there you go
we that here is our friend will be appearing again
it now notice with em
with fewer equations
so hopefully
many solutions we're expecting lots of solutions
if we have
more unknowns than equations
but but where course looking for non-negative solutions well then the question is are there
and that's already a question Are there any vectors x that
some of the constraints this is called feasible if at an X that satisfy the
constraints is called feasible feasible acts and then among the feasible axis we're looking to
minimize the cost
so that use the inputs a B and C
and it's it's pretty straightforward you can see the type a problem that that comes
at the cost is linear constraints are linear and there's this inequality constraint OK
now that I want to talk about the dual problem
you need is simply
and so should be put to be put in quotes find
find breakpoints in that piece wise find function and this is exactly what markovitz and
others have been doing for the last
fifty three years
OK so i won't go into details because it's kind of boring just to show
you might look like when you when you
when you run the algorithm
so in the absence you get along the OK
and get the weights over here
so i'm just showing this picture for the you know
can you say yes
just showing the for the you know for the you know a OK so when
you start with a large number
so everything is equal to zero you select committee regularize lot
and as soon as we do sometimes that start to at some bibles
these ones and you see that you might have some labels might disappear from the
active set
OK so this is
some work to introduce you might decide at one point that you should add the
available and then decided that usually OK so it's quite aware that the variables come
in and out but it does happen
so this is why there is no
currently no complexity bounds for this method
because you can design examples for which all viable become in many many times
but in practice it took me ten minutes to find such an example but using
random matrices so it's not it's not so common
this is no going back to these guys inhaler president of is this is really
is homotopy method that you see the difference
all those first order method which are the best methods like coordinate descent so what
if you don't you don't do sparsity directly so you might be great some technicalities
but if you just apply them straight
you get the same cost per iteration which is all of times p of n
p the number of features and the number of variables
but if you use exact so exact mean solutions which rely on the inventing the
so which we have the precision of your mission precision usually and you see that
there is a strong gain from p square and four vietnam two KPN for the
everyone this is just one of the reasons why the l one on doesn't mean
it uses the fact that
if you stop
at only KLT bibles then you get faster solution of course if you need to
select all of the variables you get back to be scale and there no matter
magic because at the end when they called zero
you get by the
ordinary least squares and sigma DP and when k equal
but many case since you hope for specific you hopeful sparsity we will focus more
this is somewhat
so there are a lot of additional methods which i what i want go into
memory proximal methods so optimal method in the sense for the as minister of methods
have been applied to this problem and this makes some of the tasman for for
software from the group
so the spam software essentially implementing all of these
in the first place and that and it's rather efficient as you would see in
the light of part of the tutorial where we
unable to use that for image denoising
so i went over the convex optimisation and algorithms somebody quite late OK so now
let's go over the article results
so here you have to be considered as well as because life is easier with
the square loss
the main assumption we will make it that the data are generated from a certain
sparse w
w born
and it's supposed to be sparse to have a lot of zeros and came in
we can we do not k
the number of nonzero values for for that setting
so we have three main problems that people have been considering first the problem of
regular consistency
you want to but you had so w you had to be to estimate
obtained from the so
of all quick w had converted w ball
his regular consistency you have model selection consistency
we get the correct zeros
when the number of the boys increase
increases and also
something which is more political machine learning you want your estimate of two leads to
good predictions
i don't care if to estimate the goods you don't care if you're close to
the valuable what you want
is prediction so which are as good as the ones obtained by the
so we should too many results the first one the first one is conditioned form
of the consistency and then the high dimensional inference
so we assume that the very sparse and we denote capital g
born j is set of zero then until about them but people also called the
support and i mean this is very nice support recovery condition for the last so
which is essentially say that the last labour get the correct science hence the correct
zeros if only that condition which is true
so q here is the covariance matrix
c is g complement is the set of an act of parliament bibles the ones
you want to have to remove j otherwise you want to keep on the side
of the bridge design of the
tonight including that of the ricci
so we that the common sense is for me in that
what's important is that that term is large when you have a strong correlation between
relevant and irrelevant variables and small otherwise so essentially so
finds the group
on the if you have low coalitions because this is a ever come back to
that later
so small small lots
so this has been done by many people
OK simultaneously
and then so first noted the condition depends on w and j
so this is of no practical value if you want to know in advance what
the degree to get the good that you need to know the but in advance
OK this is the values less but this is being sent you can optimize you
get max the maximum amount of all possible signs of the value of w
and you get the conditional on only depends on the
sparsity pattern was to use this because you don't need you you don't need you
don't know in advance you can also maximize out the there about ten
it's all about down to the given size
then fall back down the given size
then you get the condition which is of some practical significance
so it's valid in low and high dimensional settings so one goal will go too
much about that but look at high dimensions in the slide
and also important it does require on the web and on the magnitude on the
nonzero wj
so to be able to get good support
you need a non-zero values to be not too small you need a good
good guy between zero and non-zero value
so all these say that essentially the last so usually does not get the goods
it was OK so to me this is
more negative results
positive results
page reads it doesn't make more fireballs and you can see this reference for more
this matrix so this is just the matrix there
has an inverse
you can take the inverse
and you get that fish
so in order to have later policy
what you have to do is that you have to solve
this linear system of equations
you can do that
alternatively you want to find the fixed point of the operator here
fixed points are going to be really handy for us
and for that reason
we are going to
look at a very classic fixed point here and so the question is
if the fixed point for certain operator access or not
previous on the previous slide i or to prove that i i just said that
i just declare that the inverse of this matrix exist but doesn't exist related to
the u
always trust me
we should not
so let's let's look it
let's look at this
so in order to do this
we only need a few definitions
so let's take
OK so this is again might be as concept
one of space but this is just an one cleaner vector space that's complete
think about the euclidean space vector space is finite dimensional vector space
the good stuff
so the value of doing this more generally is that then you can extend the
theory to the large state
security markets
but i just think about the vector space is finite dimensional vectors good friends
and OK so we need this concept of an operator being lipschitz
so what's and operators to take two of these spaces to this to this linear
and the mapping between them so this should be something similar to this
doesn't have to be linear could be nonlinear
i have an example for nonlinear mapping system
and so we are going to say that this operator
is lipschitz if the following inequality satisfied
but this is of and that this is just the continuity property kind of right
so you apply the operator to
some vectors u and v
for the current samuel vectors
and you compute the distance between them
and this this should not be more than at times the distance
between the origin of actors
so this constrains the operator can have on the space
so t
an operator t is called a contraction operator
than the one it was b two so
talks between the same spaces
and is lipschitz constant is smaller than one
and then there is lipschitz constant is called the contraction
coefficient of the tree
and then there is this famous syrian but very easy
to prove theorem of one
let's say that if you have a contraction
the contraction has a unique fixed point
and you can find this fixed point by
for a simple procedure
a similar procedure and probably you are familiar with this idea from mister bono fixed
point theorem
so in american and people
also study this
contractions because
sometimes if you have linear equations which are too big to be solved exactly
it is iteration thing so
what happens here is that the simple procedure slide is you cubic in the trail
back to in your space
and you apply or operator to you got a new vector and then again you
apply or operator
you've got the new vector and users iterate this indefinitely
and the terence say is that these iteration converges to
the fixed point of t
so what's the fixed point so the fixed point of an operator is
in china are you knowledge is this vector
that satisfies the the activation that if you apply the operator to the back fact
get the same to
so the operator doesn't go anywhere
from that point so this is why it's called the fixed point
and so
this process just converges to the fixed point and what's even better is that this
rate of convergence is she chairman
so the distance is decreasing at the tumour rate which is really great
so i'm not going to
talk more about this you should really believe this is the basic stuff if you
are interested in the two line through
come to me in the brain
you can do that
five so we're going to use this
to consider some of the contractions that will so we see that the operators that
editing this article contractions
and this term will be will be very useful for us
so before doing that just in order to make your job offer
reasoning about contracts since easier
they are going to
to look into the second of contractions autograph of lipschitz functions so
these are simple
simple statements
so the first statement goes like this if you have operator
acting between b one and b two b
and you have another operator acting between b two and b three
so you know you remember these vector spaces
you go from the one
be t
and then from b two to b three
is it still operators
and and this is
one lipschitz and this is actually actions
so if you would need to guess what the composite operator does
that goes from b one to b three
i guess you everyone's guess would be that it's one out to lipschitz and it's
and the rest is standard so
having satisfy
so far and wide
so what
now the interesting part is the box diamonds
soapbox he's satisfied that will
all of
world leaders
related to w
g is true that
so remember there is this of possible worlds
currently spending it would have been and you see that
you can jump to all the
and box just say that it is true for all all the world that
it is accessible by car
diamond is just the dual box so damage is satisfied the action
the world is related to the current which is true
now formula is universal
universally true in the model
it is true
at every point in the world
it's just define
but the universe for children
is defined respect to all
and it is satisfiable
the moral restraints some
of his
some examples
that said i
frame which
and it's related so
well one is related to world war two to three and so on
so graphically you can just write down
this is a
this is the world
all possible
and then the assignment
says that he is
three people
and q is true in all
our history in not
and so on
now let's calculate some of the satisfied
paul diamond
but speed true in the world
and again you look at the semantics
diamond says that this is true there's such as the world in which
box p true
we're here
the one
there is only one subset and also we have a choice
this point we have to check
box p is true
and again the semantics of box pews tells us that
to prove this to be true we have to consider all possible subsets
and again there is only one which is
the true here
true because p nine
so the second example
i want to share with this formula is true
check to prove this we have
you have to show that
this is not true
this is true
and this can be true in the first world because
this work one
that means that we have to make sure that
box then p is not true
and again
but we have already proved that box that one
this means that this is also force means that
and for the rest of examples you can also
it's very simple registration
it is time
now validity
remember in propositional logic probability just that is true all possible side
now we have a frame
we have the notion of probability in the brain
now for liberty in the frame and this means that for every value for everyone
he feels that four and that five
we write an entails gene to say you
now we can also define validity in the class of frames so a class of
frames just a set of frames
what we're going to have to do is try to decide between them they're not
the only possible positions on the question of the metaphysics of the person but there
i think the two most prominent positions and definitely the one one the most worth
taking seriously properties so first possible position is this
a person
it is the combination
of the body
and something else
a mind
but the crucial thing about this person and we want to talk about is that
the mind is thought of as something separate from
and distinct from
the body
well do you have a common for it's us all
so people are people have or people consist of bodies and souls
the all
it's something as i say
distinct from the body to get the idea of the bodies the familiar one it's
it's this lump of flesh and bone and muscle you know that that that is
sitting here in front of you and each one of user drags around with you
this sort of thing that we can put on a scale and prod with you
know with a stick and the biologist can study
presumably made up of various kinds of molecules atoms and so forth right so that
the body
but on this first view
we also have something that's not body
something that's not a material object something is not composed of molecules and atoms it's
it's the soul
it's that the house of or the seat of what the basis of consciousness and
thinking perhaps personality
but the crucial point for this view is that the proper metaphysical understanding of the
is to think of it in non physical terms non material terms
that is i say is the first basic human say something more about that you
have a fair bit more about view of the next couple of weeks but first
let me sketch the other
basically so the first few
we can call the dualistic view
dualistic course because there's too
basic components
the body
and the soul and although i may occasionally slip i'm going to try to preserve
the words soul
when i use the word soul i'm going to
have in mind this dualistic view
according to which the soul is something immaterial non-physical
some other kind of the body is a material substance this all is an immaterial
it's do with you
the alternative view that we're going to consider is not dual list but but motorists
it says there one basic kind of thing
and only one basic kind of thing there are bodies
so what's the person
a person is just as surgeon
kind of material objects a person is just a body
it's a very
they insist
material object it's very amazing
material objects that with this second view says the person is a body that can
that most other material objects can do
on the
mona the which we'll call physical is of
because it says that the people just are these physical objects and the physical is
to view
a person is just a body that can
i fill the blank
you you point out the kinds of things that we can do well we can
we can think we can think we we can write poetry we can fall in
love we can be afraid we can make plans we can discover things about the
well according the physical is to view
a person is just a body that can do all of those things can reflect
can be rational can communicate can make plans can fall in love can write poetry
that's the
physical suicide we've got two basic positions
there's the dualistic view
people our bodies and souls
and then there's the physical view according to which
there are no souls there are no
material objects like that
there are only
bodies though when you've got functioning body like ourselves physical says the bodies can do
some pretty amazing things the kinds of things that we all know people can do
which is the same thing
he was one of the y
so here's where the x and the y get reversed
OK now if you don't trust this explanation
you can also get
get the y intercept
at some point zero into the into the equations
i think we plugged y equals zero and we got
and you could do the same thing analogous
right so i'm almost done with the with the geometry problem
and let's
let's finish it off
well let me hold on one second before i finish
what i'd like to say is just making one more tiny remark
right and this is the hardest part of calculus in my opinion
so the hardest part of calculus
we call it in one variable calculus
we're perfectly happy to deal with
four variables at time four five
for any number
in this problem i had an x y
next zero otherwise that's already for different things
various into relationships between
so of course the manipulations we do with them algebraic and when we're doing the
derivatives we just consider
one what's known as one variable calculus but really there are millions of variables floating
around potential
so that's what makes things complicated and that's something that you have to get used
there's something else which is more subtle and that i think
many people who teach the subjects were used the subject article where because they've already
entered into the language and are not as are so comfortable with that they don't
even notice
confusion there's something deliberately sloppy
about the way we deal with these variables
the reason is very simple
there are already four very here
i don't want to create
six names for variables or eight names for variables
and but really in this problem there were about eight
i just slipped from by
so why is that
well notice
that the first time that i got a formula for y zero here
it was
this point
so the formula for y zero which i plugged in
right here
from these the equation of the curve y zero equals one over x
the second time i did it
i did not use y equals one over x
i use this equation here
so this is not like this one already that's the wrong thing to do
it's an easy mistake to make it if the formulas are over word to you
and you're not paying attention
two where they are on the diagram
you see
that's why intercept the x intercept calculation there involved where this horizontal line met this
diagonal line and y equals zero represented this line here
the sloppiness is the y means two different things
and we do this constantly because it's way way more complicated not to do how
to do it it's much more convenient for us to allow ourselves the flexibility
to change the role that this letter plays in the middle of the
of the computation
and similarly later on if i'd done this by this more straightforward method for the
the y intercept i would say x equal that would have been this vertical line
which is x equals zero
but i didn't change the letter x when i did that
because that would be a waste for us
this this is this is one of the main confusions that happens if you can
keep yourself straight
a lot better off and and as i say this is
this is
this is one of the complexities
all right
so now let's finish off the problem and when we finally get this area here
so actually i'll just finish off right here
so the area of the triangle
well it's the base times the height the basis to x the height is two
y zero and half of that so you have two x zero
times to y zero which is two zero y zero
which is lo and behold
so the amusing thing in this case is it actually didn't matter one x one
y zero we get the same answer
every time
it's just an accident of the function
one over x
happens to be the function with that property
all right
we have some more business today
serious business so
so first of all
i want to give you a few more notation
these are
just other ways that people
refer to the notation the the people use to refer to derivatives
and the first one is the following we already wrote wisely that
and so when we write delta y
that means the same thing as delta
it's typical
we wrote
after prime
for the derivative
so this is this is so this is newton's notation for derivatives
but there are other notations and one of them is DFT
and another one is one idea
i mean exactly the same thing and sometimes we let the
function slipped down below so that becomes
the by the act dividing x
so these are all notations that are used for the derivative and these were initiated
by y
these notations are used interchangeably sometimes practically together they both turn out to be extremely
this one
o met notice this thing it
the underlying base point zero
that's one of the nuisances it doesn't give you all the information that there are
lots of
situations like that were
we're up people leave out some of the important information have to fill it and
from context
so that's another
a couple of notations
so now i have one more calculation for you
i carried out this calculation of the derivative of the
they think about
i have
connecting two points
and just the major
if you look at this
look at this that given by application
the john this that have
by point
just the distance
i think about the euclidean space
o point
three of the it into
and what can that comes to
to connect
so four
i mean
and on the right
maybe but change detection
so these two concepts mean i feel
and also the
so a cell does not change direction
it's quite going
in the may be
we used
after that
those concepts quite
so jewish many
this property
OK how about
y and also to concept point
the theory is that
it should be
i also
should be in
in breast cancer
so we think of as
the main idea of the
may be different
we can define on connection
in the matrix
however even the completed
it's something
and to
he has something in nineteen ninety
we have
and you to
by the way
and if you get
by future
permission make
this is unique
from the invading criteria
the pulled
they won't to group area
we have
what's behind
that is we define a jewish
some of unique
one part of me and
all the time
i don't want to explain to the bad
in a meaningful
we already many
given that
to make and to high
all the time
i mean one by one
that nothing about only two
and you got
it's a satisfying some condition
heart saying he
also to connections to and
we to respect to minimum
and that we should
we have sourced
by one x call time to the case of many
so the innovation
william jones
so what
and a
then what
i action and jordan
OK until this very simply
the probability distributions p and q
we connected by
t and one nine
it looks very nice
and the even
you meet a court
the jill
come to me
and i have no idea what
also or
and and the context in this seventy nine
you also need to be explicit
and the cornish explanation yield
comes exponential connections
and to find connection
of the one
and of course
well defined we can context source to
by one
no i called one
this is he explicit connection
but i minus one
it to
makes predictions
and that's what i call
to manually
and indiana connections
hart of all my
and so you see in the process
but how important the two
test p
it is the
you know
state code
how we buy
and from that point of view to find connections
the plan for the same you have the name produced the fair comet losses
mean the case chief
i correct because the track and also
you know
and it's not just be
automatic and how have the politicians
although the
product called
to do
it to a
it automatically
the dual coordinate we have another thing
the OK
the probability distribution function
then will be true
the distribution and the function
the killer
in fact
and in any case
well we have
the divergence
if you think about the hidden markov model at some level is a very simple
kind of non IID models
you have a sequence where the dependence is just between each object and immediately preceding
and succeeding ones in the sequence k so how can we represent that in order
to me
well in markov models have three things we have observations
all three types
in times of positions in the sequence
so here here they are
now we need two predicates
one is the state predicate
this this but it says that at this time i'm in the states
it has an exclamation mark to represent that each time i have to be in
exactly one state no more no less
and then also have observations
but so this is the hidden state versions again what i need for this is
the predicate
observation of of exclamation mark time because at each timepoint i have exactly one observation
being true
take another hidden markov model which just specified by three formulas
very short ones the first formula represents the initial probability that the probability of starting
out in each state that not surprisingly is just a unit clause that's there's state
of process zero
so we can learn a weight for each value of s
which corresponds which is the logo of the probability of being in that state in
the initial time
OK and then we're going to have a formula that represents the transition matrix of
the HMM
the trouble so if you inspect at time t
the in state s prime time we're going to learn is the matrix of weights
for every pair of states that the transition matrix of the HMM not in implication
for the you know solving matrix problem if you want this to be exactly the
parameters of the HMM all you need to do is use the conjunction form for
you here so seven implication is conjunction the weights of these will be exactly the
log odds
the corresponding interest in the in the transition matrix of course we have the observation
matrix that says if you observe all time t state s and again both of
these have pluses silent matrix learning which gives me
you know the that the correlation between each observation in each state
OK so
when you write programs in order to me you can you know use hmms to
your hearts content just by writing formulas like this
each HMM is going to be very simple and i can combine them with logistic
regression for example you could have many different attributes predicting state like this is this
is the kind of thing that people do conditional random fields and then you will
look discriminatively to predict the state and so forth
and you know maybe combine this with other things and
he an example of that
so this is a good point so what happens and you know i've lost of
is that if you just to wait for for markov logic network in this way
it is in service with the training they're not going to not going to necessarily
satisfy the constraints
what happens is that there's going to be many sets of which there are what's
called likelihood equivalent meaning that they all fit the data equally well
one of them is going to be the weights of the standard generative hmm so
if you want you can just edit to those
in fact we should be able to actually just one of those in our community
can do that today but you know we intend to add to the system
so what's going to happen is that if you train this discriminatively we're actually going
on a conditional random field is only generative going lead
not so
very good question and there's two answers to so the question was there these
that's of this region is like the to
two making things worse by doing things in this way
the answer is no
for two reasons one is that if you just want to talk me today
what going to be using is maxwalksat instead of
it's actually an interesting question which i will be faster
we haven't actually try this out but i would anticipate that for some problems which
are will be faster but so far for some problems maxwalksat will be faster
because the charge me you know is a polynomial time algorithm that always does that
amount of work you might be able to find the optimal solution without the network
of course if issues maxwalksat you don't guarantee that find global optimal although probably most
of the time you will
what really we want to have we don't have enough to me at this we
want to have an exact inference algorithms such that we can do exact inference under
the hood
exact inference is what happens
so this is not implemented yet but it will be in know the coming months
and then what happens is that
and the good if you have a system like for example this is just the
of the existence of
but in the
the book is this action
in this state
well of course the world to go from to this
you know this is great precondition this condition that have to be satisfied before this
action to be possible
so the
the left hand side is the condition of the approximate formula and the right hand
side is the
collection of different assignments the effects so the assignments conditional
and in this case all this some happen to be unconditional so there's no then
so that's why it's so this
sorry it's
i had the slide you know this earlier with a set of literals
i thought that with their contacts
for the last one
so this is the
definition of what the definition actions and this is one example of the
we can make this feels like wal-mart and
we can define what i b
active effects of action and events
and what is not something interesting because of the presence of conditional access
conditional access is always
at the beginning is because it was always
and the conditional access are
the text the
all the action and its corresponding condition is true
negation exceed
this is conditional there
and the conditions of the form phi is true in the current
and you say that an action is executable in the state
the precondition is true in that state
the set of active nodes
it consists so
these requirements rules out the possibility that you have to conditional effects
one says that it will be true and the other said there exists it will
be false
and the
three preconditions the
let's start will be true
both in the same
this is not a allowed
and now we can define what is success of events that so the state the
values of state variables
when we take the action or
and the first look what are the active effects of their actions in that state
and then
this so that the acting assignments
building so the what about the
active effects it was about values that there will be true
so this is
and here's an example
because the state is in the weights
a b and c are true so they'll know trees the variables
you have this action there
precondition a two on condition is not a b
this action is executable because the frequency through a straw this and
the set of active effects not being
it consistent
and these are just a simply obtained by making a false making the true
he must already so the the only change is that it will be
two surfaces
you on the consistency condition is only for the
the set of active
i mean this is not a b
is consistent
i'm simply saying that there is no
negation a and a
similar set that's the closest college
i mean this simply because because the conditions for granting that the change we want
to make it possible
so that is not not a single thing because those could be
could not both be
many forcing
and then the
formal definition planet problem big events so
we have a finite state variables
ball is that there was no case
there is one initial state
evaluation of state variables
and we have a set of axioms
in addition the variables
this a
and then we have this report provides so-called g
expresses the goal
so what
what kind of states goals what conditions must be satisfied for the
i be solved
so this is essentially simply almost the
these states values of the variables and
the have direction
by using
this is a precondition
this is simply formalizes any
but the
in this definition is to be very pleased if the graph has been made explicit
the point in this whole thing
well using this
the initial planning problem can
express huge graph by using a very
number of states
and the next one so in the size of the
the latter problem so they could from easily represent the planning problem with ten two
and the one hundred states
by using
this the description that size of one four or more
this allows us to represent the very big planet problems very quickly and then
writing then down it's possible in some cases also
we can solve the linear decision because it was
so four year planning problem we can define what is
black so
a sequence of actions
so that the excuse certain resources with which is the state sequence
so the first stage is the initial state and
they except for the initial stages of ten from the previous by taking the corresponding
action so
and the last stage
evaluation that satisfies the core
i was simply because the notation here so there is this
it's all i
this one
and if the whole thing
but this is basically
the simplest then these
this code is available online
you can
come on folks this is basically like this course but online the questions longer than
the lot linear algebra
but actually the details like
you know well known entities
so what we
with the common filters for each particle
we propagate the gaussians
corresponding to one of the possible discrete states so the continent state is represented with
the particles are actually gaussians
and of course if you approximating a discrete continuous distribution
with gaussians instead of with simple
particles you're going to benefit that's another way to look at it
i'm going to skip over the details of the algorithm i just want you to
know that that algorithm is out there so
the most important is i wanted to get the message to take home the message
if you
integrate out
if you break the state space into separate components of the state space
if anything pay attention to the graphical models
lecture next week
because if you break things into small components
and you can get away with only having to sample a subset
and use this conditioning arguments if i knew this
we would be using is essentially this map i
if i know what i am i can draw the match or if i know
the man
i know where i am is these condition arguments are very fundamental
because that's what allows you to break away from this course of the mission of
the these methods
and in fact can be verified this is the simple particle filter applied to small
problems well was doing diagnosis of this industrial plants
and when you do these tricks
you get an incredibly fast
as if i could be maybe stand up and take up and because i can't
hear you well and i couldn't understand your question
this is applied to real systems by the way
OK so that's the more general question that's like you you come up with the
you're apply it then you realize that the model doesn't do a good job
and more variables
that's the general problem and get the statistics and modelling
if you suspect suspect this is exogenous variables and you will never know if you
have the more
it's it's impossible to know that
because otherwise you would really have the knowledge of
the world
what you should do what you can do it you can do tests for how
well the model was fitting the data
you can try different models and see how well they fit
the essential problem size we come up with models for the world in the model
seem to be doing well
but we never know
if we have captured troops with small
in as much as the models make reasonable predictions we keep them
it's from others not make good prediction and we try to augment it
the theory of relativity has followed the same path
we choose the theory
we go with that
it doesn't prevent innovation
some underwrites new questions and we go with
but everything big bang selection just model
they can all be wrong
OK so
that's filtering
and lighting with
i've been
so that's filtering
that's the way of estimating p of x given y want to t
but let's assume that we have a final horizon of a thousand steps in the
and we want to
do something called smoothing
which we want to estimate the state
not only given all the observations up to this time
but also including future observations
you've collected your time serious
you can now afford to go forward and backward
so you've recorded the soccer matches three a m in europe you're playing it for
the american audience at ten and they've got a few hours
so actually
processed video forward and backward
not you know wrongdoing faltering but you actually want the best estimate of the player
or you might just once
to actually compute
the most likely trajectory with people of the sort of the viterbi trajectory
now all these methods end up smoothing with particles end being and square from
and this huge large ten thousand
so squared is prohibitively expensive
there is a way around it
so again fell train
state given observations up to time t
we want to stay given future observations as well all observations
and when you do this smoothing recurrence you end up
through a bit of algebra you end up with something that looks like this
so you have
the future smooth distribution
you have the transition model which we know that give
if we do a forward pass through with the way we do this with two
and in a tremendous
if everything was described by the way this would be an HMM everything is gone
so we have a common
and then you run your change a very long time in the long range of
get stabilisation
well because p and is p minus one time p
and if you switch the limit and into gaul
you get that the interval of the limit where n and minus one is the
same thing at it from the
three get together
gamma i mean
therefore in the is the limiting behavior
it's necessary environment
there is a fixed point
the fixed point of k
the existence of limiting behavior
depends on the existence of
this environment
major of distribution
of the chain
and in addition if if is is the limiting behavior
it's necessarily
unique because environmental measures are not necessarily unique if the probability distribution
so you can read that layer
in detail but
this is inside that
measures are fixed point
but they also
necessarily the limit
of of your chain if the limit exists
this most most of the problem is we need
it is the rough
we need is is to know
there is
limiting behavior this is called buddhist
the city
the remaining of authenticity city is forgetting of initial conditions
it is not my
well you start from
o point for distribution in the long range the chain we have the same behavior
you can start from here
well there
after a long enough period you just
i cannot tell from where it started from the greatest
if is going to city
the change will end up looking like a simulation
this issue distribution park and i can see where
i mean it
the chinese is good it
if the chain of
we look more and more
so the change will be ergodic if
there is convergence
the end
transitions off the camel
towards the stationary distribution pi it cannot converge
anyway about
to the stationary distribution
and if in doubt
this is called an ergodic markov chain
o nine o nine o here year
that the one norm is just the super of all sets
of the difference
between the two measures
the measure and that nature of a
so it's a very weak
but that's that's the definition
OK now
harris recurrence comes back into the picture
which is that if
recurrent markov chain if you
and invent distribution then
no matter what you you start from the convergence of the and
transition kernel two
machines is about the underlying infrastructure that ranges from the physical locations power and setting
up all the services which motherboards they should have through to the actual software that
runs on those servers so that compute infrastructure can operate effectively is utility
the scientists who creating the models
just a high level
o machines platform
it employs multiple global data center one of the things is really important in terms
you know managing an interacting with online advertising is not to introduce latency because like
really does travel so fast one of the critical thing is actually to have data
centers all around the world and use advanced traffic management so that wherever the consumer
is that their computer knows to go to the closest data center to get the
information you know these real-time edge servers are
responding to two peak days in excess of two hundred twenty five thousand
transactions per second
and all that data needs to be collected and processed
peak analytical throughput actually processing data is about two petabytes today
so the job of the machines bugs
and we have a pretty big thing doing this
is to make sure that people the developing the algorithms don't have to think about
how they're going to handle two hundred twenty five thousand transactions per second how they're
going to how they're going to build an infrastructure that can process two petabytes today
and i mentioned earlier
people develop these algorithms need to think about
the underlying infrastructure as utility
we don't need to know
how the telephone system works to make phone calls
and we do it all the time we pick up the phone and we know
it's ready for us to make a call because we get down to it is
not about this problem so we think about machine infrastructure are you to so
computing utility in terms of the different tones must be present for people to be
successful the pixels related to the availability and latency of real-time architecture always serving everyone
effectively everywhere what happens when the data center goes down in one of the things
that you find out quickly when you have thousands of computers is they fail all
the time
so you have to have robust software systems can recover automatically from those failures without
impacting consumer experience
log relate to
the rate at which were able to retrieve information from norwich service
the centralized processing now many of the things that we do
well just find out complete data in ninety five percent of the data is more
than enough to build models have some of the things we do something very important
to our customers require that you really can close the books so conkers is actually
the first and only syndicated online traffic measurement come service that has media rating council
accreditation in the US one of the things you gotta do it again again get
accreditation make sure you actually counting all the all the impressions made of the website
cluster tone relates to the availability and utilization of our mapreduce cost
we want to make sure that people are waiting a long time to find jobs
that are throughput is continually increasing the jobs are failing when they do fail they
can be automatically restarted
finally at home the user experience customers how marketers
and media companies when the using of services touch upon
cluster time
the way of thinking about this
is how you are doing is scaling infrastructure so obviously the need to scale infrastructure
relates in large part how much data you got family comedy customers your servicing but
another really important variables
in the requirements for cluster bomb is how many scientists you have developed models
the more people we have developing models the more throughput you require new cluster that
satisfy those people it would be terrible if every time every time you add a
new scientist joined the same everything goes slower for everyone people want to have more
people on the same day one the clusters themselves
they big function of all of our of our machines team is to make sure
we can continue scaling the amount of data to process this chart shows the average
terrabytes process per day
by our system over the last four quarters and you can see significant growth two
on average rate about one point two petabytes per day
the algorithmically this this poses significant challenges that this model does not the reason it
poses challenges is because this model is what's known as the tree it doesn't have
cycles there's no way following this cycle around but this model has many cycles right
i can walk around the cycle like that there's a lot of cycles in this
model is not a tree and we'll see for that reason that
when it comes to
solving computational inference problems this models much harder than that
yes i like you you you catch me it's true i'm only going to talk
about undirected but some of my pictures have directed have have arrows on for what
we're going to do later the arrows are are going to play any role
later when i talk about inference the first thing that you would normally do is
what's called moralize the graphs
more lies is a cool name if you have a directed graph if you have
two nodes that come in to the same node it is if you have two
i had a baby
and they're not married so if you're in certain parts of the united states that's
so therefore you more lies the graph by adding an edge between these parents
and then you drop the arrows
so you are correct that directed graphs are very interesting i mean to say that
they're not but for what we're going to talk about in the rest of it
and to think about undirected so should basically just ignore the arrows here
you're also correct that
markov chains if you think about time series is a natural sense of moving forward
versus backward but again for many of the sort of core problems that will solve
their differences is not actually essential it is from the modelling interpretation point of view
but from the computational point of view it actually turns out not to be
that's good question
on anything else
it depends how you interpret the way the way this graph can be interpreted is
that the color nodes have what you've observed which is
what should think is the hidden stuff is you're trying to infer that the identity
of the speakers trying to infer the
stream you know the unmixed audio streams and also unmixed from the video
but you don't observe that the audio
you might have noticed this we could just do with audio you might have three
audio streams as an speakers who are evolving independently but you don't observe them you
have observe their mixture and that's what the colored notes would be similarly with audio
plus video
anything else
any other distribution other than
with certain exceptions and this is probably really what are nodes spoke to you about
how to set things like particle filtering
so tomorrow we're going to talk about message passing these are algorithms that are
for instance one thing you might like to do for instance if you're doing speech
recognition is you'd like to predict perhaps you might like to predict what the next
utterance would be are actually maybe more modern examples when you're taking on uripattern your
right it's actually again running the markov chain it's trying to predict based on language
temporal dependencies what a character going to strike next based on frequency and other things
so if you want to predict the next character for instance you you'd like to
solve an inference problem you by to compute the marginal over that we're going to
talk about algorithms that are
tractable for discrete and calcium essentially closed form
if you have continuous but nongaussian then you have to resort to things like particle
filtering or other kinds of MCMC or sampling based methods those problems are much harder
so yes we'll talk mainly about discrete gaussians but
the talk of our no would be connected to the to the more general problems
did you talk about nonparametric belief propagation already talk exclusively about time series
say no
that was an either or the talked about time series i would imagine right
but but much of what he said can be done in more general graphs and
there has been a fair bit of work on that
the search for nonparametric belief propagation you'll find some interesting hits
OK so social network analysis this is another one quite topical
right so got a bunch of individuals individuals are engaging in some kind of behavior
and you'd like to
to model that
so sort of nice that we've got massive datasets we've got things like facebook we've
got amazon collecting huge amounts of data on you know what people like and what
they don't like this very large amounts of data to model
let me just give you a simple demonstration of this is actually illustrate what's known
as the easing model
it just to be concrete
so this is not pleasing model was was used for
one thing you could think about using it for is you can think about it
for modeling how epidemic spread
so using models an instance of the of the graphical model it's it's a graphical
model in which
you've got a bunch of variables that are just
let's make the minus one plus one
the binary can think about them is indicator variables for the stay of something
so if we wanted to model diseases
then we could think about x i've been plus one that means that individual i
so that the person at node i is infected
and we can think of minus one
if i is healthy
right so going get a pattern of plus or minus ones
it's interesting to figure out for instance how infectious diseases
you to expect well with most diseases that spatial proximity if you're close to someone
is infected in the likelihood that you get infected goes up
for instance every time i try one plane
i worry about this right who's sitting next to someone who happens to have a
horrible cough then
after ten hours of that the likelihood of you having horrible cough is non negligible
right so for modeling this week sort of think about it
we've got some graph if you want to model in the plane would have a
plane like this
now i don't travel first class i just cannot draw enough of these nodes you'd
for the higher order statistics algorithm so what is this separability matrix tell us that
this is stable subspace here
this is also undistinguishable
that's it all the other things are highly stable
and from one dimensional subspaces
this is the tgz solution
so there is some three dimensional subspaces as you can see here
these are all the three noise signals in uniform two gaussians
as expected
and there's also a two dimensional subspace and it's the sine cosine
there's no way to distinguish which direction you should be choosing
in this two-dimensional things because it's the ring
every projection is OK but the subspace itself is highly stable
OK so just
as a reminder
of this multi dimensional subspace
so the idea
could be now
that i mean so what do we learn from this from this example
what we learn
that it might not be a good idea just to use one algorithm all the
i mean
it's it so in that sense it's somewhat stupid to claim that that the algorithm
that one invented is good in any case i mean it's it's anyway stupid claim
to make but but in the way
you know there are several algorithms around and we can actually say well
we can combine them so we know what the stability and the quality of the
solution because we we we made this
estimate which is
well reflecting the truth
and then we can take the one that is most stable
gets so to say in this sense the the lowest root mean squared error
and then project of this component
take another algorithm
projects of
with least error
on the next and so on and so forth so we can actually combined say
data entities that bore you know any method that you want
and so
so j would be
would be getting out the orthogonal some some
goes random sources
and TD that would be getting out the audio sources and if you compare the
the separation quality
if you combine these algorithms then you actually get to three orders of magnitude higher
separation performance which was
quite difficult to reach without any single
OK so what can we do
we can
so we can we can actually do some kind of a moving window reliability analysis
because it could be that
for some reason
the data is nonstationary so that there's some unforeseen noise source that kicks in and
kicks altogether so in a sense we can we can so to say online test
with our model is correct if the reliability index is is not high in in
the sense that
that this high error bars then we should discard
this part of the time series because we cannot get a proper solution for them
at least not with this ICA algorithms
OK so for example these are two speech signals
and you see that
that is in this case there is no additive noise and this is the moving
average estimate of their uncertainty and you see
in this part we have added some noise
and the ICA model is not x equals a times as but x equals a
times as plus eta eta being some noise
so clearly if we go with an x equals a times s model
and try to deconvolve then it's it's wrong in this area
in this sense we that it's very unreliable here so we can actually discard the
estimates here
and then
and by the way also here
you see that there's a big uncertainty and if you look at the statistics of
the singer there it it it actually changes
so so what you see from this is is you you can see the general
model is not correct but also in some sense we always estimating someone less stationary
distribution that we're estimating for the sources
this is also not correct
OK just
this is the favourite one
many people
this is a data set that was used by
john fosse cuddles of for example it's the feature ECG
in the fees fetal ECG you've noise sources you have the mother's heartbeat signal and
the kids heartbeat signal
so this is
the result of the
of the JT algorithm and the respective assessment of the reliability
so we see that
there's two dimensional component down here
and you see that the speed of the heartbeat is is
much higher than the speed of the hobbit here
so this is the kids
the features
the right
so we should be afraid of the kids
you can learn whether or not even though the
things that are easy and don't make any sense just you know
again you need
interesting things for you from the sun hold
because you know the better
but both of respecting domain expertise
on the other side of
the whole world which
he is worse or
an ontology which is very nice and each
the tools will be looking at
the change management
which we're playing around ontology it's easy to all that changes when
and more
it starts is not
what we're all
any more
the support for working with individuals
individuals version
also work that there is
it's very
he was
we also
there are also going
doing the thing that people do learn HTML
you can see
the key
spiritual print if you want to play around
the old
go away
so that's the power of choice of materials and why
materials are bundles of property
conceptually there bundles of properties
what is this
you states and we can all it's a bundle of properties this is the beverage
i could make this sort of porous silicate glass
i could make this sort of power
i could make this sort of model
i could even make it out of steel versus illumina
i could make it out of titania and if i want to i can make
out of gold
i prefer to make it out of plastic i had my way
a bundle of properties mechanical strength chemical in this
he's the fabrication
that's not a unique solution cost there's is a factor that may be determined
so properties and where do we get properties from here
composition clearly
everybody knows that if you change the composition you change the properties but this is
different one tell you now is different
want to tell you now is why you take three online one
the properties are not only a function of composition
the function of the instant atomic arrangement
how we arrange the
same composition
simple example
one inch-thick pine board
one inch thick
both made of pine
both one inch thick
which one has the superior mechanical properties
why why y
because the plywood has been sliced into thin pieces that are laminated across the grain
so composition alone can give you the answer to the question why is the plywood
superior to
the solid pine or
it has to be the atomic arrangement
the thesis of three online one and this is where the chemistry comes in is
that electronic structure of the elements holds the key to the understanding
not just the chemical bonding with the long range atomic war
so that's how we get to the surface
so here's the cells
two big blocks first black general principles of chemistry and that's the same with you
take three o nine one o five eleven one
five eleven two
this is your insurance policy this is what ensures that if take your mind when
you can go on later in five twelve to be chemical engineering go to medical
and this is
the specialty topics
that pertain to
engineering system
let's turn to the handouts now what i want to do for the next fifteen
twenty minutes is just tell you what the class
operation is like so everybody knows what you understand what you've signed up for
the text is
one shown here
out in second edition
it's available to cooper's available quantum blocks
there's even some first editions of their which are
very very similar there are some minor differences in numbering
differences with some of the homework problems i don't care if you buy the book
i don't work for wily i don't shares and why we don't own shares in
the coop
i don't care if you buy the book
you want the book that's the book i use
lectures lectures monday wednesday friday at eleven
or monday wednesday friday one the enrollment
the last time i looked is
and even six hundred
so registrars computer divided between this eleven o'clock lecture one o'clock lecture
if you want to change lectures please go to hillary or lorry and arrange
because as you can see some people don't ever see if everybody goes to the
assigned place
there are obviously for everybody
so to courtesy i think it's important we
follow the
sign so if you if you want to go to let x one o'clock
you're welcome to do so but please
range with my
the one o'clock lecture is the smaller group it's about one hundred fifty
and it's around the corner the first floor building six one twenty
eleven o'clock will be in
ten to fifty and one o'clock will be in six one twenty
so that's one wednesday friday
and that's the standard
lecture format i talk you listen
right things in the border post things up on the screen
where you get a chance to interact with a greater level is in the recitations
recitations and all archaic new england term
go back to the colonial times
education would be conducted in an unheated
by someone who basically hates children
and i would come into the room
and look at someone and glowered yells at away
stand and recite
i would recite some
whatever the articles of confederation i would rise
on my hind legs
quaking in my boots and i would begin until i made a mistake whereupon i
would be castigated the rated totally stripped of self-esteem by this monster who would then
inflict the same plane and somebody else that was education in the old days
we're going to do a little differently this year
so your recitation sections i have asked the instructors not to do that
instead you come to class you control the agenda i have instructed them not to
give you a fourth and fifth lecture
come there with your questions you come to my lectures
take some notes
if you don't record everything i say maybe record what you didn't understand then you
go to recitation
the first thing they supposed to say is good morning or good afternoon and they
what are your questions and they dropped the agenda so someone says i didn't understand
what he was talking about at the end of last lecture is the uniform lighting
get somebody else can you do number three or four
drop the agenda
so those recitations occur tuesdays and thursdays you have at time when you go to
the same time on tuesday and thursday
same thing applies here is with the lectures if you wish to change sections you
may do so only
with the permission of the the
subject administrators because it's very important that those sections be kept at a small population
i want to have the population
number no greater than twenty that we get good access to the a r t
i don't want to have a section with thirteen
there are many sections they run from nine in the morning for four in the
afternoon with multiple sections through the middle of the day one which are the most
popular sections
if you'd like to change
you can do so only with the permission administrator and you have to have the
reason to do so you can do it because i don't do mornings or because
of my girlfriends in this other section no
well i don't give freedom until i got to be here eleven monday wednesday friday
i can go down to the register so you know really like to do it
all the time
but if you have a year after you have some
and so it makes sense
comparing with
so here i mean matrix is greater or equal to zero
if the matrix is positive semidefinite
so all the i values are nonnegative
so it's a very complicated constraint
because i can values are called
you can translate into determined
but that's what
make it look very complicated
and also very intractable because it determines would be polynomial functions of the variables x
if express everything as xt
so it wouldn't be clear that that's actually describes a convex feasible set
so in this notation actually it makes everything look linear
but it's not the linear standard inequalities matrix inequality
so it's may be deceptive because it
makes it look linear
there are some similar examples for rectangular non symmetric matrices and actually extensions of
we saw yesterday for linear programming when we had
l one norm minimisation and chebyshev norm minimisation
so suppose a now is a rectangular matrix or possibly rectangular but not symmetric not
necessarily symmetric again as a linear function of some variables x
and the first problem is to be minimized
matrix norm of this
matrix norm is the standard normal instead maximizing the value of x
so that would be the equivalent of the chebyshev norm for factors
so again that's very quite difficult function
it's convex only because it's or you know that all norms of text
but that's on differentiable
and again as p
as an SDP can solve that gives you practical formulation for solving it
we can again introduce new faculty
and then minimize the subject of this
linear matrix inequality
and you can show that this is feasible this holds if and only if t
is greater than the norm of x
created and all the singular values of x
and again this is linear in all the variables so this is fine this is
an SDP
and so this is the will be the equivalent of the chebyshev or infinity norm
of factors
the equivalent of the one norm will be is not known as the nuclear norm
or the trace norm and is the sum of the singular values
so again that's the norm so we can write it as actually do doing of
this one so we can write it as a convex problem
and using semidefinite programming can actually solve it
by introducing two matrix variables u and v are symmetric and then minimising the trace
of you press the trace of e
subject to an matrix inequality
that's not obvious but that's true
and so they can that is the p because this trace is a linear function
of the variables
and this is a made linear matrix inequality because it's symmetric matrix and all the
entries are linear or functions and variables
fact was rxt original variables and all the entries in you all the entries in
this is so
the something i should mention here is if this is our standard form of an
SDP is have multiple constraints of this form
you can still interpret it as a special case where you put them in a
broad diagonal matrix
we all these
hello my eyes on the diagonal
and then was be and all the eyes will be blocked
so you can have multiple linear matrix inequalities
you can have linear inequalities because if the diagonals are just linear it's linear
you get regular linear inequalities
and many of the examples see actually include
so one of the applications that motivated
interest and semidefinite programming in the early nineties
i was in combinatorial optimization as and they of
bounding computing
bounds on very non tractable
np hard problems
and now interest to illustrate this with a simple example of a boarding least squares
so in this problem i am interested in minimizing the euclidean norm of x minus
subject to constraint on x so that x must have one the negative one has
its entries
right that's excrete this one just means x plus or minus one
now that's a very difficult constrained because it's combinatorial
x has size and that's due to the impossible values so so it's practice too
many to enumerate
so is a combinatorial problems
one interpretation of being communications where x is a sequence of bits to transmit
the received value of
vector is a express noise
from the noise try to estimate what the vector x was that was transmitted
so if you assume that the noise was garcia and then you get this smacks
estimation problem for the value of x
so as to minimize the euclidean norm subject to
this constraint
so it's very difficult because of the combinatorial constraints
so in the relaxation we try to find and
we are interested in finding lower bounds on the optimal value of this problem
the easy
so these
using a technique on a semidefinite lifting
so here i first to simplify notation i just note that the objective function is
quadratic in the variables x
so we have a constant be transpose being called that are to simplify the notation
this a linear term the suppose a XML called q
and then the quadratic term is it's i suppose a so-called matrix b
so the objective in our pulling this crash problem has this form it's a standard
quadratic in x linear constant
so then
you make a change of variables so i'll introduce new variables x i j kappa
x i j we all the cross products between the variables and vector x one
x two to get the matrix
new valuable step to x
so that simplifies the problem somewhat so first of all in the objective i want
to minimize this i can replace the products by the new value x i j
and the constraints they had excised credits one
i can just replace bit XII is one
and of course you have to these constraints to make sure the problems are equivalent
this constraint is now much simpler because it's linear in the new variables
this is also linear but i wasn't really the problem in the the original problem
so the magnetic and the objective is linear in the variables
the matrix x in the vector x
these are linear qualities just says that the diagonal matrix accessed one
and all the complexity now is in this equality constraints because this is a very
equality constraints not convex and so on
in fact it means if you write in matrix form matrix x defined is the