a prior distribution
the likelihood and the posterior
and and these are simply
defined as conditional probabilities
and so we have data random variable
we have
a parameter random variable and then we have the distribution of this of this parameter
random variable we have the conditional distribution of the data given the parameter the condition
is a fusion of the primary given the data
these are the components of the basic model
and so they are defined has
has the conditional probabilities of these quantities
now what the bayes equation says is
under certain conditions you can relate these quantities together in this nice way
that we all know is that that equation
but they are not defined in these terms is just abstract definitions
so on the outside that means we can define this resulted in the creation on
the downside means abstract means we can't handle
after find some way to handle
now the basic theorem says
you know usually the base
the basic creation is written as a as a racial right to get the posterior
on one side the posterior density on one side
and then on the other side you have
the prior density
times like density divided by the evidence density
right that that's
a quotient
if you don't get that from a slightly more abstract point of view
the bayes equation is actually
in the following sense
so here we have the posterior probability and this is a conditional probability
and then we have the prior
which is also a conditional prior which which is which is the conditional probability
base theorem in
and the way it's used in
mathematical statistics
the density
of the posterior
with respect to the prior
remember on
what i just said before in the last slide density is
a rule that tells us how to take one probability distribution
and reweighted
to turn it into another probability distribution
now with this he says is
we have a density
that is parameterized by the data we have observed
and which tells us how we have to reweight given the data how we have to reweight our prior distribution
to give us a posterior
given the state
now that
that's that's simply what we would like to compute
and bayes theorem tells us
this density has a specific form
and that is given by
the likelihood
the density of the likelihood
with respect to
to the evidence and so that's the school she and that we get in bayes theorem
so basically what theorem says is we have this absurd quantities we have no idea
we can handle them
but under certain conditions
which holds in parametric statistics under certain conditions we can nicely express the relation between this
and this
as a quotient of densities
all right
and that provides us with a concrete connection between the prior and the posterior
that's not the same property okay so when i say this doesn't always exists that
is not the same problem has posterior tractability
yeah i mean you might heard that that
and the m step we maximize the lower bound with respect to the parameters holding
the distribution over hidden variables fixed
the intuition is as follows we're trying to maximize the log likelihood we have a
lower bound on the log likelihood in the east that we maximize the lower bound
with respect to distributions over hidden variable so we find the best distribution over hidden
variables in a sense
and that best distribution over hidden variables is in fact is the posterior distribution over
the hidden variables
given the observed variables and the previous settings of parameters
then in the m step
take that lower bound and we maximize it with respect to the parameters
OK holding this distribution six
and i won't go through it but it's very easy to show
doing e step and m step is guaranteed to
either increase the log likelihood or keep fixed and basically what that does is
when it keeps the log likelihood fixed you've just converge to a local optimum of
the log likelihood otherwise each e and m steps will be guaranteed to increase the
log likelihood so you're optimizing the log likelihood
in this procedure
the key thing to think about in the context of
directed graphical models is that the e step requires solving the inference problem that is
finding the distribution over the hidden variables
this p of x even y
and theta
given the current model parameters theta t
if you're graph is singly connected
in the e step you simply run the belief propagation algorithm to find that distribution
if it's mostly connected if you want to do an exact piece that you would
just run
the junction tree algorithm for example
so this is called a subroutine of the EM algorithm
in this case
is that clear
and as you iterate these two steps the index
is the index for iteration
then the parameters data will converge to
a local optimum of the log likelihood
whereas in the complete data case
we can find the global optimum of the log likelihood here
because we have hidden variables in our log likelihood will in general have multiple local
optima and this procedure is only guaranteed to find you a local optimum of the
log likelihood
it's generally fast people have studied the convergence properties of this method and they've analyse
it in terms of concepts
known as
proportion of missing information so the more missing information you have the slower your algorithm
will be to converge
but generally you know this is what one would recommend
here there was no sorry OK i'm i'm maybe it's a little confusing the question
was we're trying to maximum likelihood but are inside the procedure we using the posterior
distribution of the parameters
and here you know
we are using a point estimate of the parameters at every point in time
the only thing we're doing posterior distributions over are the
hidden variables the nodes in the graph which we haven't observed
so it's like classically and we're doing full probabilistic inference over the hidden variables but
we're doing point estimation of the parameters
in polynomial time
i i don't think there is such a guarantee
and in each step increases the likelihood of a little bit so it might depend
on your notion of convergence and i think there could be pathological cases
so i you know i don't think there's such
yes patients
the question was is there a way to do it in a full bayesian manner
OK so i'm working up incrementally to that
here's just the summary
drawback is basically that a lot of noise can be treated as arguments in this
case that's me
lead sometimes to very poor performance
this is another approach from columbia university
and they used to fix with clustering
two classes of data for this very simple approach
there are basically two points conceded the same clusters if their distance is less than
some pre specified threshold
a user specified threshold
and they're are doing this in section in the sequence of all the interaction so
basically after they do this all data across the belong to some of
large clusters that correspond to became
points that are a lot of they correspond to some small classes i consider normally
there's an approach called cluster based local outlier factor
and it's mixing the BSO for quality factor and regular clustering approaches
and it using it using squeezer clustering algorithm to perform clustering first so let's assume
you get
this kind of clusters
and then it
computes the CBLOF
vector for each data record the data records is in the small clusters
then the CBO CBLOF is computed as the size of cluster times
the distance between the days that specific data instances
and the the closest larger cluster because CBLOF is computed for every
data records
if d
object is within the larger clusters
CBLOF is computed again as the product of size of cluster ten distance between the
data instance
and the centroid of the cluster it belongs to
i'm not going into
discussion this is good not obviously has many
drawbacks especially if there is point far from everything else the
size of class can be one of the difference can be huge and be quite
similar to everything else so that can not be useful for detecting
so these are some of the clustering based approach is most of them
rely on similar ideas
i'll briefly go to this statistical
in in statistical based techniques who have the key assumption that are
normal data records occur in high probability regions
all the physical distribution
while anomalies usually occur in the low probability regions of that's pretty of the statistical
and the general approach and the statistical
based anomaly detection techniques is to estimate the statistical distribution using given
and then apply statistical inference test to determine if a test instance belongs to this
distribution or not
people are using a very simple approach is false and for centuries not for centuries
but not since nineteen forty nineteen fifty basically
everything that is more than three standard deviations can be treated as anomaly
people also using the this the square statistics which is basically very similar to mahalanobis
this does
you have a specific data record
x but this is actually the mean
this is covariance matrix
and this is just to draw a actually mahalanobis distances without this term so basically
you're just adding this two
but we this
more robust larger value of the square
would correspond to
later because it and data may be anomalies in the small medical should correspond to
data across
obvious obvious advantages of statistical basic things because they can utilize already
existing as
statistical modeling techniques to estimate the different types of distributions
and they provide statistically justifiable
solutions to detect anomalies
some drawbacks including
the fact that
with high dimensions it's extremely difficult to estimate the parameters and construct the hypothesis tests
also does
automatic assumptions about the real life datasets may not
the true
and this is really hard sometimes to estimate its parameters
of and of course
most statistical approaches work for a relatively small data sets and if you are going
to protection from very large datasets
can this technique can be computationally expensive
as know two types of statistical techniques parametric and nonparametric
in dramatic techniques you assume that normal
data generating from the underlying formatting distribution
and of course you may as
you may have similar assumption for
we will call this an eight
fifty polarized they don't exist it's only in your head
and the fifty refers to the fact
fifty percent get through polarized
in the optics gets that we hand out today we will need throughout this course
you don't have AIDS and fifty polarized they don't exist i don't quite know what
uses idea measure it
he was maybe in h and twenty five
well maybe in h and thirteen
which would then mean
that is i zero
strengths of an unpolarized light of beam wouldn't be happy i zero but maybe only
point two five
four point three but in any case the lights that will come through your
linear polarized this will be very closely two hundred percent polarized
so what i will do now i will take unpolarized light
and i will
this light coming straight out of the blackboard perpendicular to u
strengths i zero
and here is one of my polarizes
and the light that comes through
is linearly polarized in this direction
so we already know
that one half i zero will come through it is an ideal polarizing and it
is polarized in this direction
i take a second sheet an identical one
i put it also in the plane of the
blackboard but rotated over an angle theta
there is no second she
as the preferred directions of polarization
in this direction
and the angle
rotate it
over an angle theta
so between this one
and this one is an angle theta
so you can now immediately tell
what the intensity of the light is that for the second polarizer
it must of course be polarized in this direction
because that is the
allow direction organisation forty second street
and intensity must now be one-half i zero
that's what comes in
and then i have to multiply
by the cosine square of fate
i don't have to ever is now over all angles because there's only one
the value of between the sheets and this is so this is now the new
and it's all polarized in this direction
and this law
by the light intensity is reduced by the vector cosine square say that
is known
as miles long
if a there were thirty degrees
the light intensity he would be one half i zero
times the cosine square of thirty degrees which is o point seven five
if there was zero degrees
that means that the sheet
in the same direction is this one
if everything were ideal
one half i zero will get through to second she
if a is ninety degrees
nothing will get through
because the cosine
ninety degrees is zero we call that cross polarizes
across them like this
no light will
get through
now before i demonstrate this
i have to be honest with you
because the idea of reducing the energy of individual photons
by reducing the electric field strength
as i did
is achieved
the light photon has well defined energy
which depends only weakly on the frequency
of the lights
blue light has a higher frequency than red light
so blue light has a high energy than red
when you send blue light through a polarizer the way i did here
control doesn't come through
but if it does come through it is still blue light there is no such
thing as a reduction in energy
whereas this reduction
by cosine theta would imply that the energy
goes down and that we would imply then that there will be a call it
seems that it would no longer be blue
and that's not the case
if you want to treat this properly you have to do it in the quantum
mechanical way
the interesting thing is that if you use quantum mechanics you find exactly the same
what you find also miles law
so the law is OK
even though to the patient is not kosher
now i want you to get out of the envelope
one of your green plates
which is a linear polarizer
this is the kind of place that you have you have three and their only
take one out
these two lights shining on
unpolarized light
the lights that comes to you now is unpolarized
i'm not going to hold in front of my face this polarized
so the light that comes through is linearly polarized in this direction
and you are going to play the role of the second polarizer close one i
put polarisation from the u i and rotate it
you'll see a huge difference in light intensity
if you crossed polarized with me
you can see me
making very happy
keep in mind
if you can see me
i can see you either
so around and convince yourself
is light that reaches you is now in the linearly polarized
and when you rotate around your parameters
we call the we call them polarizes
you can see me either
or you cannot see me at all there's anything and everything in between
very well
there's a second way
that we can produce
one hundred percent linearly polarized light
we can do that by reflecting
unpolarized light
of the dielectric for instance water
none of this follows from snails law
snails almost two hundred fifty years before maxwell
polarization wasn't even known in today's
o of snow
with maxwell's equations allow u
to properly deal
was refraction
reflection including the polarization
and i will make no attempt to derive this for you in detail
it's really part of eight three if you ever take it
but i will present you with some results
so that you can at least appreciate
the far reaching consequences
of the the
reflection in which we can produce on the percent
polarized light
suppose f unpolarized light
coming in
media one index of
reflection and one
two index of refraction and two
it's coming in
stochastic sometimes some cells go through he one in ten hours some cells go through
cells in eleven hours some through an eight hours
and and as a consequence
as they moved further and further around the cell cycle the population of cells becomes
progressively more
asynchronous and they were really enter into the next phase
totally synchronously
but now we can ask the following question how long is g one
and the way we can do that is to do another kind of experiment where
what we do
is we release cells
the population of cells from an faced by removing the coal cement
for example
and now
we treat cells we treat our quotes of the synchronously advancing population each hour we
pluck out some of these cells and we expose them for let's say the next
hour thereafter
to some it radiated climate
treaty is signed as you may recall h three five minutes it sometimes denoted
it is obviously a radio labelled precursor of DNA
and it's going to get incorporated into the DNA
and in no other macromolecules in the cell
and so the question is
if we expose ourselves from our here
two pretty finally how much
pretty this time is going to be incorporated into their DNA
how do we know what incorporated and how much tritium thirty five remains unincorporated we
extracted DNA from the cells and we precipitated in an acid
and when that happens
the macromer more molecules of DNA go to the bottom they precipitate
and the unincorporated pretty finding which is still soluble has not yet been polymerize into
DNA molecules
it remains
in the acid solution so we just how much as imperceptible
finally counts are there here how many in the neck are made in the next
hour with another eloquent of cells harmony in the next hour and so forth and
when we do such an experiment we find that we get a a curve which
looks like this
all of a sudden
here we got no cells labeling and the second on third fourth fifth sixth and
the seventh our there's some cells which make DNA
in the eighth our the some cells even more cells making DNA and by the
time the in the ninth and tenth our
then we find a high rate of DNA synthesis
now in principle we could continue this experiment if we wanted to if we had
enough money for trade finding which one does because it's very cheap and what we
would find is if we started labeling over here with for another hour
when i say in our poles i mean we just put it really is time
meeting in at the beginning of this one hour period way over here and an
hour later we take out the cells and extracted DNA and measure how much DNA
has been incorporated in that interval
and if we did a pretty impulse over here we begin to see that the
rate of DNA synthesis was actually lower and eventually it would go down but that
down to this
as the cells were moving asynchronously the culture
what does that mean well this is the time obviously these cells are in this
these cells were in g one
and these cells have now emerged from phase into g two and there are no
longer making DNA
and on that basis we can actually calculate we can determine how many hours it
takes for cells to move through g one
we can do is similar kind of experiment to figure out how long
g two is the gap two g two phases g to recall is the time
between the ending of DNA replication and the beginning of mitosis and how do we
do that we can do is inhibitor of DNA synthesis so let's say here is
going to redraw the cell cycle
here's s phase
she one drawing it again here's an
and here's a g one
and now what we can do is will and DNA synthesis inhibitor inhibitor of DNA
synthesis no effect as you can imagine on m phase
this is one of those things it's called hydroxy urea
it actually blocks the biosynthesis of the precursors the arcs around side triphosphate precursors
of DNA and therefore you have hydroxy to cells
and they have their their DNA replication grinds to a halt
OK so let's do that
and i will
will will hydroxy urea cells for twenty four hours what's going to happen
what what the distribution of cells be afterwards well in fact some of the cells
when we first and the hydroxy urea the cells are scattered all around
they were asynchronous will and hydroxy urea and what will find is the following the
cells that were in the middle of s phase when we have the hydroxyl we
will be stuck dead in the water they will be able to move anymore so
these cells that were in s phase and we have the drugs you will be
trapped right here they can't make any more DNA
and therefore they'll will be frozen many point times point in time in space
the cells that are outside of this ways they can continue to advance all the
way around the cell cycle
and accordingly
the be lots of cells over the next twenty four hours a just pile up
at the g one s transition
well the hydroxy really has no effect at all on these other points of the
cell cycle and when these cells try to go go from g one into s
they can get in this phase because they can make any DNA so the trapped
right over there
and now
it will take away the hydroxy urea which is obviously is to use the notation
used before and inhibitor of DNA synthesis
and what we can do now is the following
say oh well i stopped caring about this row the
from node d simon stopped using this
and instead spend some time later is going to hear about this new rowdy and
it's going to take that into stable so this process where is this sort of
process whereby notes continually
in a great drought and we talked about this
and there's this this sort of interesting thing which happened which is the nodes forget
about routs that they have heard about for a while when they went missing
so this forgetting about droughts
is an important principle that is often employed in networking called soft state
the idea is the idea with soft state
you should only
keep state keep information when that information gets refreshed so each all the information that
you have some time limit on it and when you have heard that information refreshed
after some time when you throw it out so that's all we're doing with the
around here and were sort of we only so we only keep droughts that we've
heard advertiser recently basically
i mean that has the nice property that allows us to adapt to falls within
the price we saw failure happened we saw that sometime after that failure this off
the property would cause the information about the link between the DNA disappear from the
network and then those would rediscover their new new links that allow them to connect
OK so
what i what i want to do now so this is sort of the basic
process empathic arriving is fairly similar to the way that routing in the internet actually
next time you guys are in for next time in recitation going to talk about
a particle called the border gateway protocol
you actually study in much more detail how internet routing works but this is a
nice simple model of how routing in a small network my my cat
the problem with what we discussed so far
is that
if this is a very large networks this
number of rows is going to have to hear about is really huge right suppose
that this instead of being applied no network was million or
well now i mean have a million advertise every node is to have a table
that million million entries all right that's going to be really big is going to
happen here million advertisments and every time there's a failure well that's going to be
a pain because we're going to have to wait for that information about their failure
to propagate through the whole network so
in some sense this simple path vector routing protocol we have doesn't really meet the
scalability gold we want to scale the network up to very large size
we have an issue with routing
and it scale
so the solution
is a solution that is often used the scalability problem in computer system
it's hierarchy
so let's see what i mean by
so remember when i when i was showing pictures of the internet
there are these different
kind of sub networks there were
forming over time on the west coast and east coast there was there are that
in itself net and the building that that would be sort of different networks the
all part of the internet as a whole but they were these sort of different
regions that were separately administered and often correspond to a specific organizational like the for
like the military
these oftentimes these regions so it's very common when you look at any network to
see that you have these kinds of regions and so for example you know there's
clearly there's is a network that is MIT's network right and there's harvard for example
has the network that's harvard's right and those two things are sort of logical
regions the define what's the define
different parts are different groups within the network
so if you look at any network you would see it sort of almost any
large network is organised in this way into these regions
the paper next time we're going to call these regions
or a
so autonomous in
operating on its own operating without the the without being dependent on the other person
system so for example if MIT's internet connection went down connection to the outside world
went out that wouldn't stop you from being able to connect to machines within MIT
right so i might is autonomous in the sense that it continues to operate in
the absence of a connection to the rest of
let's let's look at a simple example of the network has this hierarchy property and
see how we would modify the routing algorithm that just talked about
so i suppose i have and i suppose i have two small networks each
with three nodes in them
it's called the ABC
and the e
so these are each to be autonomous systems which are drawn by drawing a circle
around them
the structural information to become a kind of data and you can do real might
want to you can extract patterns due to
in data mining when you reach
information extraction
in other words in the title
we define the identification and consequent or concurrent classification and structuring into semantic classes
and of specific information found in b
such as natural language but it could also be which is on the one hand
which might extract the information provided in addition to that integrates the unstructured data by
so i want to classify the semantic search information graphics in structured sources so because
sources with the computer
it's not
please computer what it means that if sources are
and we have information extraction text
mean on semantic
on the information in the sources so that we can use this for searching for
data mining for
so much
now in the information extraction from text
most common
it's point the fact that
so you extract
actually look for in terms of a system
first of three or four
but quite effective for
that small to extract
now what the four five and what
i would like to have
the image
taking of fact extraction from
but on the other hand i think we should
go beyond fact extraction
information extraction and text mining so i'm like going go to war and information extraction
there are really implemented with
part of our culture that we're going to but they it gives you idea of
what we heard in search
we've demonstrated also with current application
and of course the summer school in information retrieval
so i would like to know
however chapter that integrate with information to the model
so that you how we can use the semantic meaning information extraction in real
so if i j
and the first one is the way we have this introduction
and then i go all the time
use symbolic handcrafted knowledge
we information extraction and text mining
then the rest
they are about machine learning
the second part focused more on learning
structures objects
in text
the force on application i'll go a lot of education maybe that technically
like for many many applications for example and then finally the
we integrate to
i will start with
all you
the first part i start becoming what are we capable of to information
we look at the role of natural language processing
green and the red
apart from some artifacts here which i think are artifacts
and it's got the blue all separate as well
very nice
so that's generative models are working you can do this but we had to use
four hundred samples the more samples you use the computational complexity goes up
okay so deuterium is the same idea
the difference in
the time
and were
two differences i would say the there one difference when
when the car i did his density networks he proposed using a neural network
and duty and propose using
and obvious network right so this is because it's the days the neural networks that
was a big difference ones and i'll be fewer arguments about which these things better
i think today we will defeat those two things as mappings
is nonlinear mappings and in fact you could do these approaches with kernel methods
and indeed i have done their duty and with kernel methods and in
starting on the road is what led to the last model all talk about which is something i developed
two differences one mapping is now an obvious network as a poster
this mapping is i neural network right it doesn't matter the both mappings
that's not really difference and today we will probably be using a kernel mapping unless
we have some particular structural reason for using a neural network
but what your second difference ladies points out on a grid
and then map the grid so sample
lay them out on a grid and then
this is an example that this is a mixture of gaussians
and what's going on is that these is a mixture of gaussians in three dimensional
space where the centers of the galcians
determined by the duty mapping from here to here so these crosses are mapped
without any uncertainty just directly
become the means over mixture of gaussians in the data space yeah
as i make sense
so this is like a constrained mixture gaussians the means are constrained to living on a two dimensional space
an infinite mixture of gaussians by ian
now that's exactly the same algorithm as the importance sampling algorithm i was talking about before
fundamentally when you write it down interpretation is different
but the algorithm is exactly the same mass comes out exactly the same
one flaw in the which people don't really mention if this
what you want to do is you want to the visualization cited mention at uh
for the density networks you want to visualize in this space
i the posterior distribution of x given why
yeah the problem posterior
probability x given what ants in density networks that's been done by
importance sampling you compute the posterior by importance sampling
in the duty em
you can compute the posterior exactly
you can compute what
i mean you can compute using which means
which calcium this cross must come from
you compute posterior that says uh with fifty percent came from here with percent came
from here with twenty percent came from here
they then visualized at
o point five times for this last point three times the plus point two times
at any other point that's how the visualizer but that's actually nonsensical
because in truth it must have come from you that's that's all that's
it can't come from in between because there was no mean being mapped remembered three
in density networks is a real subtlety in density networks use a sample based approach
where you're saying is starting with a continuous space mapping to a continuous space so
we need the posterior it makes sense that you can visualize things in a continuous
teaching them is starting with the discrete space and mapping to a continuous space so
that the theory is really continuous but actually you can visualize exactly as you do
in density networks and you can make the same interpretation of the model is density
networks but that's cleared up in the papers but these two models are really almost
exactly the same thing only this one's laid out on a grid of points whereas
the other one sample from a guassian well show the results over
o thing i described a lot
this is a visualization the oil data with the ten by ten grid so hundred points just like the first
you can really see the grading of bacteria look
the effect always talking about here you can see how they line up along the
grid this is the spacing and the grid
and you just seeing the effect there
if you user four hundred points
looks a bit better
you can still see the effect the grid
nine hundred points looks better again
at i didn't go beyond nine hundred
but you can still see the effect the great on talk a little bit about
how the why effect occurs in a moment
but but but but
they also something else i wanted say i
okay well there was something else but i can't remember this is that's sick man running stick man
you can see the circles the data there but you can also see
how everything's landing on these grid points here
the percent what's happening is the posterior mean the gaussier the posterior
component the calcium is basically saying i'm associated with at mean i'm associated with at
me no one saying that jointly associated with multiple means and i'll explain what happens
in a moment
well next actually as we go to nine hundred points you start seeing
a nice shape yeah
okay so i call at affect the bubble wrap effect
it seems very nice what's going on
is easy to think if you've got these means in
this is the bubble wrap factor
means in latent space
on this grid layout
and that's it is almost like a density but it's like a bubble wrap density
but if you put them in close enough together then the
still overlap and it's like a pseudoinverse moved out things you see what i mean
being a like a bubble wrap is the galcians sent the crosses in latent space
but if i'm at this today displays
in a sort
only sort of nonlinear way
these bubbles still don't matter go through the mapping actually but there exist in latent space then existing data space
they can be a long way apart from each other
um and that's is what gives you the effect on the posterior distributions
if these are two galcians close together
then this is the joint distribution the purple
so these are like to these are the two gaussians in this case
and if you want if you've got a data point along here you want to know its posterior being
in fact distribution it looks like this
nice smooth yeah
so any they quite long hair could be even these guys
but actually move these gaskins apart
when you in this region here which is really unlikely the posterior distribution is the
joint distribution is the posterior starts to become really abrupt and basically the a transition
so any point or living in the region between these two
will even be allocated so that's all backed
and that means that when you look at the visualize their posterior component value
they end up being associated with the that's all that's not in between
well again that is again by mean one i think these actions they get these
values but is to go OK you can see the inductive reasoning going on here
and exactly what should appear so the quality of taking states
taking action a in state i at time t that means to teases is to
it's just recursively
reward i get show how to point
is point
i don't think they would actually one
would be stolen
so i'm looking at that at at the top of the equation
the quality of taking action a in state s it is it to go is
the immediate reward i get past the expectation over
this debate and i would get two in the next steps
and values i know i get this
they start with the one you get a keyword search so you so these are
the ones
let's the same be one
this we know that the TV
really a key one
so i q two
and from q two we can get
the two
OK so just for all t
now if you discount gamma
less than one
then you can guarantee that this will converge
the linear range
to the star
intuitively is very obvious because
say gamma is point nine
and reasoning
one hundred decision stages
would only gamma gamma hundreds
times that value
so at some point this becomes so small become less than
you know when he negative
sixteen or
new or numerical precision on a computer which is i really care about
so you only need to find
you're going to go so he steps back
so you don't really care about the reward you get beyond that the number of
and that's the that's very intuitive obvious proof and why
with discounting
this converges to the optimal value function
and these can also one
in game less than one
the to what participated
well get rid thing is we don't know
because in the beginning the markovian assumption tells us that that's all we care about
w this is exactly what we need to become an assumption
it breaks down the reasoning into
single step
but the nice thing is it's a mechanism has had one that you can always
put information state to make state
markovian you transition looks markovian
the only depend on the list
so this value iteration
this will give you the starring if you get the star
then you can determine the policy
how to act to achieve their full value
and you're done
OK for the model based case
OK now there's two have and the risk of today
one value iteration
and it's very easy to derive first principle because of inductive reasoning
the other out of policy iteration
but it's
by shimon more and he did this in the sixties and seventies he actually recognise
and of course many people recognised that this jellyfish was arrested and isolated the actual
protein and determined to prove that this protein was sufficient to cause the fluorescence so
in terms of thinking about applications of y so exciting that you have this fluorescent
protein other than it's always really fun to look at things that are for us
that we can think about in terms of biology why so exciting actually tag this
protein to any other protein that you're studying and i have a visual handle on
what's going on so for example
if you're interested in some protein involved in cancer you can tag it with GFP
you could watch were localised in the cell therefore as you can use to determine
what other proteins it interacts with you can see for example when it's expressed in
the cancer cell and where it expressed there are all sorts of things you can
do once you can visualize something with reference
the reason is so exciting that it's protein the protein this is the structure here
is the ribbon structures you can kind of see what it looks like it's made
up of all natural amino acids so this means we can code protein DNA you
don't have to worry how my going to get into the cell
all you have to do is to mutate the DNA which is very straightforward to
do in in molecular biology
and now you can tag absolutely any protein that you're interested in in so as
i said this was first discovered and isolated from the jellyfish this was done by
shimon more that was kind of the first step in this process of having become
such a useful tool
and then many years later and until nineteen ninety four
dean martin chelsea at columbia
show that yes i can in fact take the DNA and put it into a
different organism and he put it into equal bacteria
and what he can show
was that it could be expressed as the picture from his nineteen ninety four science
paper in that life and it is going to florence green
now the first application can not be quite exciting as for example the other organisms
people have put it the sense that you can have flies using transgenic mice that
are glowing green with this GFP of course that's not be useful application for its
more proof of principle but it does show you that you can put it in
the first study any organisms
and the field was really pushed forward by the discoveries of robert chance at UC
san diego
what he did was he actually figured out how it was that this protein four
asked what caused the actual for instance and once he did that both he and
many other scientists could then once they understood what caused the fluorescence make little changes
to the actual protein and to what the properties of that the protein were so
now for example there are a whole range just the whole rainbow fluorescent proteins that
can be used and i'm sure you can imagine that if you want to label
one protein green and one red one yellow now you can start looking at really
complex biological processes
so it's pretty rare that chemistry makes everything so hopefully all look in the normal
papers not just the scientific journal get to read something about chemistry so it's fun
to see how it's described in the new york times in the boston globe and
the other thing i wanted to mention i'm not sure if exhibit still there but
there was an exhibit of of jellyfish i know at least until last year at
the boston museum of science in all of you guys can get in free
need to see the glowing jellyfish and think about the fluorescent protein that in them
so i encourage you to do that the next time you have some free time
on your hands maybe i i p
or something like that
right so i like to move into today's know today we're talking about molecular orbital
this is a show this is a new topic that we're starting
so far we have exclusively been using lewis structures anytime we've tried to describe bonding
within molecules
lewis structures are really useful we use them all the time in chemistry and they
are useful because first of all there are easy to depict the easy to draw
relatively easy once we got get all the rules down and also the accurate over
ninety percent of the time
but they are not accurate all the time in predicting bonding between and within molecules
and the reason for this is because lewis structures are not in fact based on
quantum mechanics
so molecular orbital theory on the other hand is based on quantum mechanics
and specifically ML theory is a quantum mechanical description
wave functions within molecules
the saying way functions within molecules might sound a little confusing but remember we spend
a lot of time talking about wave functions within atoms
and we know how to describe that we know the wavefunction just means an atomic
orbital it's the same thing with molecules and molecular function just means a molecular orbital
so we'll start talking about the two kinds of of molecular orbitals we can talk
about bonding or antibonding orbitals
then we're going to actually use ML theory to describe bonding with in these molecules
and we'll start with former nuclear diatomic molecules diatomic means that
diatomic made up of two atoms and homer nuclear means that those two are the
same pattern
then the and looking a at an example of the heteronuclear diatomic molecules so again
the same thing but now two different atoms
so i will point out in terms of ML theory because it rigorously does take
into account quantum mechanics it starts to become complicated once we go beyond diatomic molecules
so we're going to limit our discussion in five eleven one
four molecular orbital theory to diatomic molecules however on friday we will use a different
approach that we can talk about bonding with the atoms that have more than two
more than two atoms molecules with more than two atoms
right so one thing that i first want to point out about theory that is
the big difference from lewis structures that theory valence electrons are d localized over the
entire molecule
so we talked about lewis structures we actually assigned electrons to individual atoms or to
individual bonds whereas molecular orbital theory what i'm telling you is instead we understand that
the electrons are spread all over the molecule they're not just associated with a single
i view
original set s
and the top could be estes
and in between you have all the
other parties although all the subsets of s
so now
he will
so there is another big big big two and says you
take a structure which is completely
they make function
there is always this
for the is written can be very nice to read it
when you have ten
it's just
very easy
to show that the fixed point exists on how do you define it
you define its way
we're actually
you take
the least
so the
lower bound
course fixed point
a particular case of the otherwise is what the quality here
picture which may
help your understanding
so it is and
looks like this
he's telling
we just another so it's sort of the we very often draw the belly
because you may have a point here which is not and there all the here
because it's a partial order cannot compare them
sure this one as this one greater than this one so
so you could say
islands where y
greater than its
a typical example is the were many elements of the latest it cannot be smaller
than its
its image
and here
if you take
police one here
this is a particular element
which displays this
as the list such that
and actually it's very nice to have a full so
i mean some dual way to think here we defined those such that z
is less than half of that
so those are called was fixed point is called reference points
and the fighting in the middle here
those are all the fixed points
fixed points
the list is this is you to also exist
the latest thing here
itself forms the latest
general culture
so what you ought to have
is that you have another way to characterize
well i would say
way to compute the
so the least fixpoint are now this one
that's the least fix and this is the least fix point of
the function f
so this element here
that's the way of writing when you have everything you need commuters use the lib
f gives you the function
so this one
you can either see it as
is the element
of this set
or you can also see it
as something you capture
by iterating
the function f
starting from here
i'm going up
so how do you go
well the list element so if you take its image
the show i mean
the bottom is the list
but because if is monotonic if i play after this
in equation
i get that at all but is less than ever played twice
and so on
so with cardinality argument things like this if you keep iterating f
a lot
with any luck
so that means
if i take the cardinal of my daughter of l
two iterate f
at these
stabilisers i mean this i expected to stabilise somewhere stabiliser mean if i if i
come to a point where the director so far for amount of time
and if you happen to have something like this
that i have a fixed point because f is monotone
you don't know
so what can be alpha
one has to be at least
as big as the cardinal
o my
of my set
so you
just give you an answer more
increased number things but if you want to know more
now wonderful books only fixed point
so that's the way to compute it
because what i do here a little
that's the right here simply bottom bottom to about three
go up
and you can also and the
greatest fixpoint
as you can imagine
you would catch it starting from the top
and it's rating as because obviously
the greatest element is necessarily as big as its image
so another ten go down
so but inclusion because
now we are in the policy it's likely to come morning to
the particle eighties i told you about
subsets of nodes of the tree and so on
put them in
should put
less well as they did here so that they can take people
but not too
two hundred
right OK
you can present text URL
and the semantics of you using sports
so what do i have
so alphabet
she's going remember to integrate
information they used to decorate the no
my ministry
so in my life can will have proposition this is what i introduced already for
i would have for each such
the proposition that says
in this mode
well this node is labeled by a
so i have propositions p a
if you don't like p a
i mean locusts bee is fine
it's just proposition
you also have viable
this will be important because
as you will
each class and we noticed that the mall on top of one another
so we just need to find out maximum
and of course
and the covariance
it is just related to the cover charge
all the posterior of the joint likelihood in this case and again
it just gets a bit more technical but that's all it is the principle is
the same
we're no
the covariance is matrix is is not going to be an n k by n
k dimensional
matrix composed of this thing here
is basically component related to the prior the gaussian process prior to these are the
functions of the covariance matrices for each about individual classes these are in by n
and and then
matrix here if you remember will correspond to the elements are associated with our likelihood
so these are the second derivatives
with respect to
the gaussian process function values
of our our likelihood
and these are multinomial forum so
i won't bore you with the details but
it's just details
that's as we basically be done we we have
approximation for our our posterior it's goes in
and then we can do
we can make predictions and so forth
OK so there is
a small fly in the ointment as far as the laplace approximation is concerned
focusing processes it it's a particular weakness
and what's that well
the lord of the high dimensional goes in
may not necessarily
represent the actual mass
by the actual
probability mass
and we're not talking about very high dimensional go since one of the examples
you'll see we have something like three hundred data points
twenty six classes
so we know operating in new twenty six by three hundred dimensional space so we're
trying to define
goes in in that sort of dimensionality
so trying to find the more
it's actually quite difficult to know about finding what is is is one thing but
the more as i said will not capture not represent the actual probability mass
and you see from the experiments that this is indeed the case
the class approximation is good in the large sample limit
but we have very small numbers of samples
so this is not
a great approximation
we haven't about variational methods
during the lectures on on graphical models
what we're going to have to look at
variational approximations
in the variational approximations of course are
very general methods which can be used for any class of probabilistic modeling
i went to
focus really on the use of
variational methods for gaussian process classification
so what's the problem
well the problem is this posterior distribution we can get an analytic form for the
can we approximate
the posterior
it was a nice analytic forum well that's what we do
with the class approximation
plus approximation we say well we don't really know what the posterior looks like
and so let's approximate it was something that we understand understand the goes
but the the
problem is that we don't know how good this approximation is
where is it good when
so it would be
desirable if could have an approximation where we knew how good it was and some
sensible optimality
the way that we start
as we say OK
i've got a set of
random variables theta one to see to and what i want is this posterior
right it given
my observations
well i want an approximation to this snow
and one way that i can do this as i can see let me
probability distribution q
and i represent
my approximation
of the posterior
and product four
i've done two things i've simplified the problem by representing it in our product four
i still have the issue of what is this value of q
or what what is the representation of q
what we can do
as we can say look
i can represent
the logarithm
of my marginal likelihood
my doing
remember that i've got
given x and theta
p of
integrate over all scenes
so this gives me my marginal likelihood
so i can represent the log
marginal likelihood
the logarithm of the centre group
and what else to do
the result is to introduce this
ten here so q is some arbitrary distribution
so i haven't changed anything
let's just look at this a little bit more
if i write it
like this
does anyone
does this look familiar to anybody but this would be
this is an expectation of this is an average
all this function here
to this distribution
so i can i consider my marginal likelihood
the log my marginal likelihood is equal to the log of the expectations
with respect to
q theta
whatever qs
i'm seeing here is going to be some sort of product four
we have defined it so don't panic
and it's the expectation
p of t
given x
given seats
p of to
over q theta
the logarithm of course is a convex function
and so
we can define
a lower bound
on this logarithm of an expectation by writing
the expectation
of the logarithm
of this function
which is not just going to be
successive application rules two and three was rule one gone well actually it turns out
in that case it's and its it you can derive from the two or three
of them
and there are very explicit algorithms very complex
but they will in principle you know set up in the computer run and it
will it will tell you a is it possible or is it not possible to
derive this cause and effect in terms of the observation data and it's possible they
will tell you exactly what form
which is wonderful
the structure of the graph is yes
it's been around for so history
so there this
so so so doing asks or to clarify the structure of the
graph is given absolutely so the structure of the graph is not under discussion
we've we've come from somewhere we told the story we believe this is the structure
of the graph
on the basis of that we say can we now
use things we can observe the there the joint distribution of the observed the observable
variables in the observation regime can we get some formula putting the pieces together which
will finally come out with
the distribution of of some effect in some intervention regime which then has caused many
and we made enough assumptions you might or might not be able to do it
this will tell you what you can you can't and if you can it will
tell you
what is the
all right
so here
so the question the question is do they have to represent the unobserved variables in
the graph and the answer is definitely you have to understand the structure of the
whole system unobserved variables no
in order because that will determine the the
what you really need out of this is the various
extended conditional independence relationships involving
the observable variables and the intervention
but those what those depend on the structure of the whole graph including where the
unobservable variables are and how they joined by arrows to other things so i can
interrogate the graph
and get various things
out and i need you is here in these things and i need to use
that i couldn't just collapse over it because the whole thing would collapse to complete
unstructured mess
you need to know more structured ideally this is this you know you can you
can say what you even though you can observe that you can say the kind
of thing is you believe it is there
she returned to the number of
that means that you have to remember
what really
very good question so if you just got a lot of numbers and you have
really tried to model the to use the year that trouble you really need to
understand the relationship not only between the variables you got the between potential variables you
haven't got
in order to get anywhere and that's what we're coming to an XML move on
causal discovery how do you get these models in the first place well
i said one you can just make sensible arguments about coin tossing and mendelian randomisation
and justify conditional independencies justify these parts of these models
or you can look at data to try and
but that is
quite problematic but it's a big industry
log of the cardinality restrictions of functions in f
it should be iconographic if
the sequence x one to xn
and then we take expectation of that that's what
well with this appears so
you know there's this inequality between the conditional expectation
given the x one direct so averaging out the
the rademacher random variables plus minus ones that's no more than something like squared of
cardinality restrictions divided by n
OK and we can take expectation inside the this query log
OK this is
you know using using convexity
and yet instance inequality
and so we get a result that looks like this
rademacher averages in terms of expectation of this thing
the cardinality of these restrictions
OK so this is an expectation under the random choice of the
the x one to xn
right now
the growth function is the maximum cardinality
for all sequences of size n
so no matter what distribution we have the growth function will give us an upper
bound on this thing
so we can replace this with the growth function
and get
a result in you know this is just throwing cells liver and the right the
here there is no more than the growth function which is you know the d
to the d
as long as n is
sufficiently large
right and then take the log of that we get this quantity delorean over d
all right so that's how we arrive at this result only question mark is why
is the expectation of this supreme
no bigger than
square root of the lower cardinality over and
well this uses
the hosting kind of ideas again
OK so this inequality
because the slide the question why is this true
well this is the hoeffding
the have kind of
by dr
let's think he is the result that implies that earlier result if we have some
of our and so bunch of vectors of length n
and all of them have euclidean norm
no more than i
then when we take the expectation of the supreme over all these vectors
of sigma i times i i
OK so this is an inner product between vector in a and this plus minus
one guy
plus minus one vector
OK the expectation that supreme is no more than the radius
right of all that is in a times square root of twice the log cardinality
of a
OK so in our case when we apply it to the set of vectors a
is just
the functions
f restricted to x one through x right et cetera makes one through xn
that is about that form as f ranges over class
OK so what's the
in our case
right the euclidean norm of these things is zero plus minus one vectors right so
the euclidean norm is the square root of n
all of them have the same non actually lie on the ball of radius squared
and the cardinality of a is the cardinality of the restrictions of functions in f
two x one xn so this this is precisely the result that we take one
over n times the
the euclidean norm which is square then that gives us one of the square of
times square to the log the cardinality of
a or as set of restrictions
OK so this is
this is an
a result this tells us about actually the rademacher averages of a finite class
and the proof here this is due to
pascal massage
the nice observation that that you can
get this kind of
upper bounds on rademacher averages for finite class using the
the ideas of postings inequality
so what we're doing here is
is considering
over a
right of
this summer
OK so let's take
e to the s times the expectation of this thing is the thing we're interested
in right the expectation of this is the maximum over set of the sum of
sigma i times i i
this this inner product
OK let's take either s times that
and then use
and yes inequality is to pull the expectation outside
right so this is no more than the expectation of the the s times that
and we can pull the supremum outside as well right that he the expectation of
the maximum over
vectors of
e the s
z so by
all this now
it is the moment generating function for this random variable
OK so
you know with this matrix of of taking an exponential either s times the quantity
were interested in and using instance inequality we have again a moment generating function
well not quite i guess story supreme in there we can use the
the fact that the supremum is of positive things so it's no more than a
of exponentials right so with bounding the supremum with the some
and this is not a bad
approximation here
right if the if the
maximum is dominated by one
one element
well that's it
if the sum is dominated by one element
and so of course
then we're in this situation of looking at the moment generating function for such a
random variable
OK and we use hoeffding inequality
to tell us
the that thing is no bigger than either squared times the two norm squared
over two right we saw this
we saw this in the last
in the last hour
you know i i just quoted there and i'm not going to
i'm not going to prove it here either
right but then that's that's no more than cardinality over
a of either a squared r-squared over two because our you could norms are always
no bigger than are
right and then taking logs
of both sides and while minimizing over s
and taking logs we get
so we get this result
right to this thing in here
there is no bigger than times the square root of
two log a cardinality
all rights is in a
no view of
and a trick to get back to this situation is getting nice pounds on on
the generating functions for random variables
slow but i don't have any
the reasons of this so as some researches should be done to analyse why decomposition
is it so bad
that you know
well before nineteen years in their
the force is large
the problem is so serious
with full knowledge of all you have in use composition has then this is large
then y is always more difficult so this effect but the company and not the
union then you clearly see is a big difference is that the coverage is just
very very slow
it may also be related to the starving
criterion or something
well but i
i don't know yet
but fortunately we don't need to use large c so what is sees a penalty
these we will overfit to fit the training data but in practice we can over
peter change
they have to we don't need very large city that is
the result saying that
there's no way using the years yet so they may not be linearly separable so
so for any c for any given to see if the use of dual problem
some props and they are only classifier that actually knows they that correspond to the
situation of right to PC
after about
it is not very precise but rather you for other bounded
four other bounding components they they are related to training error
we can actually prove that if this is large the
primal solution
the primal after about these issues and so there's no need to have to search
for you know you don't c into two to solve the problem
because if w is this and this is the same sort and the performance is
exactly the same
so you don't need to try to use very large c
then we can use another
another property that kind of situation that if the the number of
features is very it is not a large
so remember that in the primal dual relationship this time without is a linear combination
of training instances
so we have to delete these linear combinations of these studies and is the number
of features
somehow we can where we can prove
six property like these that the number of other five
as you can see is a very small than number of features
plus one so right
it is no more than number of features
yes mean even the number of features is very small
is much smaller than the number of training number training
they then
as you change the
probably to see OK so try to solve the dual problem a different see you
you have to have the share many elements it is zero and c
there's is because now
there is a huge difference in means of chinese senses and you only the twenty
twenty features
and you know that in my for any c you can see that after the
number of conformal about one is strictly but things you see is less than twenty
minutes and i use so some
distance between different seat after which they share the same many elements zero and also
other policy c so you can use very well
the kind of technique to speed becomes this
that is
to is what
OK so that's related to parameter selection what about that state so
this is usually we we do is certain kind of evaluation procedure so so point
you start increasing c
the school that later
so so we can use the kind of will start procedures these start to see
that in a situation you get face to convergence they they get up solution
then use that as an initial solution
someone you used information as an initial solution of ecstasy so
so you gradually increasing from small so of
you see because what you that we did that we get so for the same
problem is we can see
if we don't use decomposition methods to solve the situation sequence found it takes so
many iterations strongest sixty sold
but we start from
france equals one then w is country to reach five hundred that although we only
need ten so
so is useful for the number of features is small and so in that sense
we consider composition is it can also handle rather large the new support vector machines
in the number of features is small the number of features is large with you
also problem
so those are wrong but i i want to say about solving linear support vector
so to handle is the difficulty of building large kernel matrix approximation is of course
very very important technique
which is key
because when you use more clever proposals regions when this thing was going to work
and then there's many ways of computing is acceptance
this is just one possible way
in seventy three peskin
prove that
this particular way happens to we have very low
variance asymptotically
so we can write the strong law of large numbers for the
and we can get the central limit theorem we can characterize the various
the algorithm and you look at different schemes and you choose the one
these less variance
it has the better right
and you pick this
simulated annealing to answer your question
and simulated annealing what you do is
you take the distribution and use
and you raise the took part one of its
and then what you do
and you have a staff
you decrease
decrease the temperature decreases so this is sort of like
this minute annealing because it's based on this idea of people you know
you blacksmithing by the hierarchy
the important thing is is the creasing in other words the power of p is
increasing so you think a function power what happens the function gets compressed
so you have a problem is reaching its peak it can be
simulated annealing is often referred to as the algorithm where q is a symmetric random
most papers on that talk about we compared to simulated paper tells you we compared
against simulated annealing
and there were so well
they never tell you what the proposal is so a specification of we use simulated
annealing without telling what the proposal distribution was pretty much rubbish has hasn't carries no
simulated annealing is classifier is not one
so you can't compare against simulated you can compare against dealing with a specific recipe
most often people use the random walk with is very stupid idea
and that's what the compared to other methods
not surprisingly this but
so this is what happens when using nearly
the samples concentrate on the peaks
and this thing again this can be proved to converge to the peaks of the
schedule is low enough
the convergence proof is desirable
but it's not enough
because too slow
we did graphical models yes second skip this
one of the graphical model one of the areas where this is applied to a
lot of physics these models where
you have lattices
the discrete observations
and you have
pairwise relations between the variables
pairwise relations between the variables and observations and it the london used to be used
a lot in image analysis
so you can write the distribution of this model
and then you're goal is given the y given the pixel observations reconstruct the axis
these potentials basically what they do is they want x for for example here
the single for export to be like x two
the introducing smoothness constraint the image
and if i will say that you want to extract the y two
so you have to forces here you have likely model the ones
x to be like y but you also have the primal the spatial prior
once all the observations to be the same so the sort of thing that alex
was talking about history when he was talking about here so
and so
and that's the reconstruction of that image so you you get rid of the noise
so this is your life
computer vision graphics
the algorithm that is used there is the version of metropolis hastings
where the proposal
and note in this so this graph will have many nodes
if you take a note
and your new
by hand you can write the probability of the node given its neighbors
and if you were to sample from the node given its neighbors
and i'm going to leave that as an exercise as well
just substitute this particular proposal into the metropolis hastings
you'll find out that the acceptance is one
i can take over the exercise
so the algorithm then it's very some metropolis hastings algorithm that goes like this
you sample
x one variable x one in the graph so if you have a graphical model
is simple one variable given its neighbors then you move to the next there is
simply given its neighbors to move to next variables sample given expected and usually you
can derive expressions for all of these
graphical models it is this software package called bugs
you can if i wanted to go gibbs sampling
use bugs
bikes is a really really nice package
but is based in the
it's distributed at medical research
anyone from cambridge here
mit MRF or
immersed in cambridge
medical whatever search
council cambridge
addenbrookes hospital
of the AI but i'll just give you a little
i a little sample of this game actually i have really tried it if you
get the sound here now we have to see if it works
signature songs you
i'm afraid we don't have solved with this but well just watch the graphics and
you'll see
what to do that
what wanna give it
that that's actually
good idea
you have to have
she so this last
his last phase he saw as the g-man and his kind of pulling all the
strings in the story
so just point out a few things that are of interest here you saw that
there there was a lot of storytelling in the sense that you know you saw
a lot of people going around and he sees the hardest merges with movies you
see the story involving people talk to each other but you can actually walk around
and see them from the back or interact with them while the stories involving then
you have this thing at some point he grabbed a grenade was thrown at him
with a core of the
gravity grab things and and actually could go back to the opponent before it exploded
and if he hadn't done that it would have explored on his side and taking
taking life from him but so it could hurt the opponent when he's shooting there's
impact on on the environment things
breakdown because the bullets hit hit so there's there's a lot of stuff to find
the things this g-man guy
the big the big guy and for him they developed an entire facial model with
all kinds of actuators artificial actuators and then learn how to control this model in
ways that would fit what he's saying and so he other entire scenes in the
game where he's talking and he's he's really the evil guy in way but he's
i think quite quite convincing
however a lot of the story of course is told
in this
can you fix scripted way although you can kind of walk around things see them
from various perspectives what really happens is that these characters just follow six built in
story and that refer to as scripting and that i mean for example if you
play the second time course they do exactly the same thing and that's that's not
so great
OK so i just wanted to show you this in order to give you an
impression what a state-of-the-art computer game is like and where its strengths lie in words
weaknesses lie and now i would like to move on and
tell you a little bit about where i see potential for for using machine learning
in games and this list will essentially also be
the the structure of the for the remainder of this space lecture
maybe the main point of interest is
adaptive and learning game AI
and here we have different things that we can do we have this idea of
avatars or in in driving games to make all the driver terrace which essentially try
to copy or or learn the behavior that was shown to them by a human
and then emulate that behaviour so that's one one way machine learning can be used
another one is of course to not to just copy the behavior of the player
about to be the opposition
and that's of particular importance in front in these first-person shooters because if you're not
playing online in which case human people are your position which is very nice
o thing to have if you play just with the computer you want intelligent opposition
because otherwise playing it's no fun what's usually happening and that's
still happening in pretty good games is that since they can create really good artificial
intelligence vol one opponent they throw met very many stupid opponents at you for that
that can be done right but it's in the long-term it's really not very satisfying
because this is due one against one is usually more interesting
so the third thing of course is that you might want to have teammates in
the game so in the game of soccer which we see as an example you
want people you can only really control one character right so but you need the
team and they need to go to reasonable positions and and play with the right
so that's something that's of interest and then there's something called ambient AI and that's
the idea that you go through the world and you may not view the people
that you meet as enemy stories friends but you would like to interact with them
in some way and that you want that interaction to be believable and that's also
quite difficult although it may be a little easier than than opposition teammates which involves
the competitive element but they really have to be good at something well and i
just essentially has to be convincing
so a second area
that's very interesting is believing it is been usable physical movement so i showed you
in this little half-life to do more that their vehicles and are nicely simulated the
objects you should behave in good ways but what really doesn't work yet is
animals or
robots or
humans anything that is internal actuators and displaced movement that doesn't work very well in
computer games there was you saw several examples most of them were scripted so we're
using motion capture and so if someone runs along then you are always only runs
along exactly this particular route and
the other own character is very is similarly done in a very script way
and only micro movements are ever simulated if anything so
there are two nice piece of work that i would like to
o point two one is inverse kinematics for dimensionality reduction which
tries to detect this problem in more visually satisfying way rather than in a physical
way and there are some interesting work on learning how to walk
and the benefit of that would of course be that he would have opponents that
directly interact with the physical world and that would much look much more believable than
people who run for example again the one example if someone wanting to find that
may be the case because he's matter right but please don't talk about the same
time run structural will to flipping over the floor we would then want to see
maybe this junk on the site
the negative stuff
the positive stuff
all right
let's think of that instead of thinking it is of it does clause let's think
of it as a sequent
this write it that way
OK the clauses are tautology if and only if the sequence valid which it is
if and only if there is some atom that occurs on both sides
forget they
side stuff again familiar using familiar notation
i'm gonna write that is gamma delta
so that it looks like stuff we had this morning this morning we had sequence
that only had a single formula on the right
but it's not that big a generalisation to allow several formulae on the right
it makes something nice and symmetric
so we can now build up the calculus zero sequence
this a slightly more general than the sequence this morning
the reading of this is
if all of these things hold
that at least one of these things holes
there's a nice sort of duality estimate left-right symmetry about all this
and that's our axioms
that's our axioms for this
proof system
so is there any
such a sequence is valid if the left and right sides are not disjoint
on some matters
the because but
and then
we have rules that correspond exactly to the simplification principles
so suppose we have
and negative formula
occurring on one side or the other negation
not a
that occurs
the in what conditions will that happen well exactly
and negated formula because on the other side so we can read that as an
inference rule going in this direction
this simplification rule going this way
rule of inference going this way
that's how you can introduce
negative formula
on the left of the sequent
you get it from the same thing with the negative formula on the right
and the dual role for the other way around
we can
making deductions we can introduce
the negation on the right
provided we have the simplest sequent with us on the left
they mean
if we are asked to prove something that's got the negation on the right the
way we prove it
is by
to proving this
the this is simpler
it's got there on the left is simply because it's not good many connectives in
so our first system is going to tell us what to do
same thing with other connectives
if we have
if we want to prove something with that
a conjunction
on the left
well we can prove it
i mean what it says if all this stuff follows and this something in here
well for all this stuff to hold is just to hold beta holland
so we can simplify this way or we can make an inference going the other
and for conjunction on the right
we can
to derive something that have to derive the conjunction
this may be parametric stuff
you derive the two conjure separate
the disjunction is going to be dual
so disjunction on the left is just like conjunction on the right
you know because you think about it in this these terms
conversion to
two conjunctive normal form these terms
base if you use like the hinge loss function
now we have an hours lots of them have long
and to generalize well to have a very small norm on your weight vector
this use are convex optimization permits perfect because we just like
like close all from
data can meters solution use quite fast
hallway you can see like yeah this is a picture shows like
the bound this is to allow
in regression problems need the data examples
yeah some outliers
which are both in the actual bound
so you have to use that for i was c and day ok where through the
let's say itself high homemaker parameter which should be assumed to get optimal forms
get these other space recursive problem
so the function should know be much bigger than the outputs func
and the data example should also not like marts
a vector function
so difficult to the dual space of basic parts
yeah each alpha necessarily think yourself kernel reformulations
basically the idea is to work
to use conch multiplies support vector coefficients alpha
and then you come up with the following formulation
when years some workers based on value it's
because we want to maximise his w
objective the dual objective
tool all the all all star alpha
here means that large we lies
the means to correlate well with outputs
and you means that
based on similar you which is very similar
basically you want to set
some of his office cereal because otherwise
would minimize this
function and some on on and this is the bias constraint
which we also it years later
so finally if you'll
get estimated all of those
who can i have a function which is
basically the linear case can transform this just to
tool or normal weight
in the boolean functions each threated here in this way
and this is sites vector x function
but only have to keep my
balance which are the differences between alpha alpha-channel zero
so optimization algorithms on many like many people use svm-light svm
based on s xml that programming
but to make it much simpler for us code developed this deep support vector machine
and also because we don't want to minimize objective
you find that is to acylated
we are developed like the gradient ascent method
basically you just have if you have to do you need to compute the derivative
but the give to each alpha coefficient and
you get right
learning basic this this is very simple to program
although of course is not open more like time complexity
all work needs to be to be down to make spots faster
but it's a very simple way to yeah just developed all support vector machine pulpit
instead of relying
on all known tool this case for the change them
so some relations i have multiple kernel learning
so but also the previous talk francesco dinuzzo we saw like multiple kernel learning
i even like multiple layer kernel learning that's related but
there are some differences in multiple kernel learning
like for example the kernel learning you want maybe who wait so
all of
the ancient to have an rbf kernel in this way
result based can be weighted more heavily than others
which is normal things to do although always normalize the data still makes sense
and then you get some kind both the min-max problem in the dual objective
if ronald bicycle ok
the dsvm is kind of different in this frame because basically yeah if you want
to use kernel you can just like support vectors ok it gets the inputs and goods one feature
so you stack like kind of all those support vector machines
the more you get a big feature
the feature presentation
then this the main
so the topic today is dynamic programming
programming in this
in in the name of this
i doesn't refer to computer programming
programming is an old word means in tabular method
for accomplishing something
so you'll hear about linear programming
dynamic programming those you know
we now
incorporate those algorithms in computer programs
originally computer programming
in a data sheet and you put one line per line of
as the tabular method for telling giving the machine instructions as to what to do
OK so the term programming is older course now conventionally we say programming
software computer program but that wasn't always the case and these terms are continue in
the literature
so dynamic programming is a design technique
i x with scenes such as divide and conquer
OK so it's a way of solving a class of problems
rather than
particular algorithm with some
so now work for this for example
the so-called longest
so called lcs
which is the problem that comes up in a variety of contexts and it is
particularly important in computational biology
we have warned DNA strings and you're trying to find commonalities
between two strings
one which may be
do you know that
and one may be various
when people do is that thing called with a evolutionary comparisons the
evolutionary trees here but there's
right right exactly what is it
phylogenetic trees they go OK for which good
so here's the problem
given two sequences
x going from one to n
running from one end
we're fine
the longest
comment remove
here i say
one of the longest common subsequence
longest common subsequence isn't unique several different subsequence the high
for that
however you know people tend to want the sloppiness is that people will say the
i'll try to say
most is unique
and they slip as well because just such a common thing to
just talk about the even even though it's
now there might be multiple
so here's an example suppose x is the sequence
why is the sequence