we couple information which side of the dice showing up with the number of this
has for example we might assume that the faces of the of the dice show
one two three four five six ten twenty thirty sixty whatever so then this would
be the numbers ten twenty thirty forty fifty sixty and this would still be just
indicator variable indicating which of the sites showing one two
four one two three four five six and and this is then again the noisy
observations whose sometimes little more multimedia to work with because he uncoupled the value
of the face with the indicator which faces showing up played by introducing the auxiliary
variable z is also play a role in this process
first later
but essentially the same model c
because now we say that the probability of observing that this hidden they was in
a certain stage is exactly the case component of g again was going to say
only that we had before here we have to have these here and we strongly
couple disease will affect us all eastern state zk and the is that state
i j then this is equal to one papers chaining zero otherwise so because these
things are deterministically copied is exactly the same model as we had before
i would like to do so
you you have to look the latest version
from the material from this
another common is the said before the following use the collapsed gibbs sampling which means
that we never explicitly said from g we sort of
collapse model before we did simply integrating she this very elegant in particular if g
is infinite dimensional but it has some problems because it gives them does not mix
very well which means that consecutive samples are highly dependent
in fact one
o pins but sampling bias
using the collection itself by sending explicit explicitly from g
which in this model is also possible and if it has become somewhat different
and the advantage is that given g we can now independently sample from the auxiliary
in the block way we don't have to consider
the other values of the other
renovations of the when we separate from the given the
as you have done in the previous approach
remember the sculpting from disease and you see here the first update the g and
then given g of the templates are independent and can be updated in a block
in the block that's why this is also called
is situation considered if g is known example of which is produced and these are
among each other because they are blocked by the
quality g
so in the block itself that we have to send the from the negative labels
the given the given data and then send the g
given indicator variables which blocks away all the data the surveys so we just before
so this is quite simple in this in the finite dimensional case to do and
approximations possibly using the late and it is
this is a slightly different model but also related models if you look at the
situation over here
the nice thing here was that we decouple the indicator here from the value of
the dice now we can assume that this value might be unknown
we are uncertain that we don't know exactly what to do
well you will be of the dice
it might be ten twenty
forty fifty sixty nine people one hundred twelve whatever might be even in on an
ordered set of numbers
and big by the coupling this makes it makes us what we use it to
also estimate these parameters which which which are shown in the face of the time
in this land could closely related to a standard mixture model things graphically shown here
so here we
explicitly indicate that we we specify a prior distribution for the factors which might have
some more parameters over here and that these parameters that are not appearing on but
also estimated by observing the data and
replace this g here by the pi which is
also specify
multinomial distribution and this is also usually process
usually the distribution over here so
a little bit has changed so it's not exactly the same thing is what we've
done before
of photons and some to be able to do anything useful
or if the number of times small that means your kernel function does all the
work and what is coming from words coming from
so this kind of a bit of a conundrum here and you know you you would think that's
some functions that conceptual systems
have to
compute are inherently sequential they require to have a set number of sequential operations
for them to be
a a
computer always sort of a relatively small amount of resources
there's a lot of complexity theorists in the room
and people were studied sort of complexity i'm sure
i'm know that's sure myself to a few layers competitions
are you can gain or an exponential of
factor on the
can not hardware you need to compute particular function
for example
it's a basic example of you know
a bit parity we know that we can do this with
you know again stages or you know look like over two stages
with x gates
but if we force ourselves to do it into layers using the contracting
form we might need an x natural number of minterms
so that you know it's just a very simple question of exchange of complexity between space and time essentially
that we deal with all the time we write programs
for ourselves multiple stages then we might gain a huge factor on
on the overall are not resources we need
so so as a very intuitive you know i don't have easier to tell to
to show you you guys other kinds
of people to
prove the theory as
but the basic idea as a basic intuition of of why we need multiple layers is just
that sort of complexity basically
ok so this is a bit of a petition nightmare here which is that when we
start having multiple layers in a system like a deep know that
we try to train it using a supervised learning
we have loss functions and being non-convex if you have non-convex loss functions and rely on things that
you know like minimal
but i do empirical musicians like that
in all things go out the window because can prove anything about the you know you're you're model
ok but you know they work it's actually worth maybe spending effort trying to figure out
why they work
so all bets are off non-convex losses but then again you know
every speech system deployed as is non-convex optimization
it's not because non-convex that don't work
are you lead to some of us the only interesting learning actually is non-convex
if you have a convex optimization to solve for learning the order in which
you learn things doesn't matter
we know that humans
the order in which you learn things in humans matters this is called pedagogy
can such that k as can start my talk with the last slide i think go
backwards but i don't think you'll get the same state of the in if you do this
in the aggregate statistics is the same so you know is
the order in which you see things actually matters
and in machine learnings actually matters
and suggest the fact that whatever loss function
you know that even write a minimizing given actually minimize loss function
which is another question f has to be non-convex
was the order in which we learn things with matter
ok that doesn't mean that we can actually you know when i with a convex optimization but
but is sort of features consideration perhaps
ok the other theoretician 's nightmare
you know if
if we have all those things deep learning algorithms
we don't have any good jun generalization bounds
are actually not to know to take a big neural net actually has abound z down
think because this dimension is finite
but not tag bounce
now i could be a problem except that i don't actually know anybody practice to use
bound to model selection
ok to see this for this about
but that's true does anyone know a you know anyone who actually uses down in practice to
model selection as opposed to a cross validation
raise your hand
yeah ok you
know and ok i know but i know and to yeah
ok yeah
f so z some of my best friends use bounds yeah
so you know it's hard to prove anything about deep learning systems but then again
if we only study models for which we improve things in speech and writing object
recognition systems today
f ok
on the other hand
it's kind of smorgasbord of of stuff for theoreticians because there are so many things we don't
know about are all methods are used in deep learning and i'll talk about them
some of them as a group
you know doing talk so
you know deep learning is about representing high-dimensional data or representing a high-dimensional spaces
and has to be interesting theoretical questions about this
west geometry of natural signals
you know is equal to a sequel learning theory for unsupervised learning
of computational learning theory for that matter i mean i know there are
efforts on those directions
in this the
what are good criteria on which to base unsupervised learning things so that
you know questions had been answered by this committee for supervised learning which i think you know be
we're thinking about for
teacher learning
which is
sometimes unsupervised
ok so let me talk about the state of the state of affairs for deep learning
it's it's a one
hottest topics in speech recognition for about the last two years
the latest generation of commercial systems that are based on
that speech recognition are all based on deep learning
once from idea and google all microsoft
know based on deep learning one of the phone which is actually directly produced by an
idea and we know once
they use deep neural nets
and has been very very fast transition from gas mixture models to keep on its acoustic
in the us to use
is becoming the hottest topic in computer vision mostly because of the last imagenet competition conducted that
and it's becoming a bit of
interesting topic for natural language processing although it's not there yet
and is a huge interest from the applied math community
into things like where byzantine data
in high-dimensional spaces
people use how many canisius now
sparse coding and stuff like that
ok so
so i said
well done to all these
see my
the two hundred
really to
so we
raise your
smaller loss
and this
need to know
well two
so these are dimensions so
we see
we want to do
this is the
you want
eighteen minutes
well we
and what that
he was
this is really
it will
let g
so here we be
just a
class see you find
one more relationship between the statistics
vision problems
no one was injured
just to
you might also want to be
so what
we i can
all in all
lot of us
well known
all this
the british
the use
more to it for you
sure the
although well then it seems to me
ray t
it also we also
if we went
also can be done in closed form as two
four groups
this because the only non-linear part of the algorithm is to compute the polynomials and
that can be done in closed form after the before
maybe this is a good point to stop
there are any questions so far
but like i said it is nice these equal becomes approximately
so so what to do is find the least squares solution to this linear system
so you can always find this vectors
coefficients no matter whether you have not
OK that's a that's probably the only thing that fails you can know the rank
the image is going to be full rank
with noisy data for any degree
and so
the problem becomes the same question of well how do you know the dimension of
the subspace in principal component analysis
so what you do is essentially find a number of principal components that keeps ninety
something percent of their energy
in a sense and the way you do that is by looking at the singular
values of the matrix and looking when is a big drop
so the same thing can be done here you do it for degree one
look at the plot of singular values and essentially it will be mostly flat
you do for degree two and then will be decreased so you know the two
is the right number but of course in doing that there is always some parameter
that one has to set
so this does not solve the problem of what the number of groups is it
just gives you guidance that then can be used for initializing the more traditional techniques
that are based on model selection
solve simultaneously for the parameters and
so the objective here is to have a quick simple the right technique it'll give
you some idea of what the number of seats as well as well cluster centers
and then you run e plus model selection
to refine your
two answers as the number one is
who cares that much
you just call the roots
the function of matlab
and it doesn't matter what degrees
as the number two is
as you can see moments that the actual technique for solving the case of subspaces
in this case can also be so that way it by computing derivatives of the
polynomial at a data point and that will give you some of the cluster center
corresponding to that point
and as such
it's closed form no matter what the number of groups is
because you'll never have to compute groups of an opponent
in your question
well i already answered that great
the degree of the polynomial is the same as the number of groups
and and so that you look at the
you look at the singular values of this matrix
yes but as i explained
this matrix
the number of columns of this matrix is essentially the degree of the polynomial plus
and theoretically the degree that you should use the rank of this matrix
so you can so if you have a technique for computing the rank of an
ice matrix
you have a technique for computing the degree of the polynomial and you should use
so as i say explain what you do is that
try to look at the singular values of the matrix
whenever there is a big drop
then you will
see with the rank is
and once you know the rank you know what the number of groups
he was
i would like to postpone the later because it will precisely show up and will
be awaits later on
i'll i'll point out twenty comes
it would be about fifteen minutes i think
this was my studies of dimension one pretty much useless
although i'm sure that is actually useless itself the image segmentation problem dimension two
i have
cluster centers that look like this
in this case you can still do the same thing actually
you can take every data point
and make it a complex number
and now you just build your data matrix with complex numbers
from the point of view of the algorithm to just treat them as real numbers
so it doesn't really matter the change is going to be your data matrix is
now complex vector of coefficients is going to be complex ones to compute the roots
the roots are going to be complex
but those complex which besides the clusters into the real part is the x coordinate
the imaginary part is the white court so there is no change you can do
it in the mentioned two as well
look how they correlate with different sorts the cross or we can do that for
completely novel objects with various features
and we can also we can also use this i mean the we used this
in machine learning setting with the conscious company is doing is basically using this for
if you like collaborative filtering or sparse matrix completion now suppose you observe only a
subset of these
these values you want to infer the missing values of others so we can also
do this sort of experiments on people were reintroduced let's say a novel feature it's
like it's like in the netflix problem introducing a new
movie or a new user like and that's like a new row and column here
and you are just a few values and you want to say what are the
values of the
what the missing values and
essentially you know with this model is able to do is to make a richer
range of predictions by figuring out let's say for a new feature is one of
this order is one of that sort
and we can we can show with with in both
one particular we can show with people but what we've also shown some versions of
this just in pure machine learning setting we can do better with this more flexible
model than say just with a flat single mixture model
so let me
talk about some other
other parts of
interestingly structured models
there you again each of these you can see is ways of taking in a
sense the idea of finding clusters and recognizing that in the kinds of mental models
that humans build of the world there's more structure than just a single way of
or you know just what we mean in our textbook notion of clustering so here
that the additional structure is different ways of organizing the world to capture different aspects
of things but another interesting dimension
it is why well what people in machine learning have called learning from relational data
it's really motivated from kind of science point of view about thinking about our intuitive
theories of the world so you think about somebody who's so learning about the structure
of an academic department this was i guess motivated by US department but probably in
in european departments something similar
you have a bunch of people and you could observe the interactions let's say you
observe who gives advice to who and you might want to make sense of this
by organizing the people into
where the
the relationships
abstract relationships between the groups that govern how individuals interact so for example you might
recognise three groups professors grad and undergrad and professors kind of give advice to everyone
grad students give advice undergrad grad give advice to know what i mean that's a
very rough approximation
another sort of more physical intuitive theory
one that i like law and kids enjoy the sort of thing is a learning
about magnets
so let's say i give you a bunch of metal objects let's you don't know
anything about
about magnets they're just these
you know identical looking metal objects you play with them and you see what i
want to bring these together they seem to interact in some way when i bring
these other ones together they don't interact how do you make sense of that will
again you might group these into categories let's say magnets magnetic objects like which i
mean magnetically susceptible things which are not themselves permanent magnets no magnetic objects and we
might say well the magnets interact with each other so it that bring together to
manage their interact
magnets and magnetic objects interact magnetic objects do interact with each other so to magnetic
objects do anything and i'm not going to cut doesn't interact with anything
so that's again the very first approximation to how
metal magnetism works for metallic objects you could of course make this richer by distinguishing
different kinds of north and south magnetic poles and all sorts of things like that
and the the learning problem here
is to observe a matrix of interactions like it might be social interactions are might
be physical interactions and and reconstruct something like this kind of a theory of what's
going on so it in particular again you can think of this as a kind
of clustering problem but it's now this relational clustering problem so we might say well
we observe interactions in these people might turn out we can organize into these three
groups with one group was called the professors who don't give advice to each other
they more let's give advice to everyone else this is the data is a little
bit noisy so maybe
in the summer
more less professors give advice to the grounds and the undergrads grad gemelli advice undergraduate
document also get don't give advice anyone so again it's it's just like a a
i found a certain way of sorting the rows and columns that revealed this
this simple relational theory and we propose to way of doing this which is again
a nonparametric model to take into account the idea that we don't necessarily know in
advance how many ways there are
the were what's the right where there are some right finite number of
auditions this is called the infinite relational model and we've we mostly published this this
is in triple i and we and others have used this for various kinds of
machine learning
tasks but original motivation was trying to think about people's intuitive theories again i will
really go into the mathematical details but basically there's one of these
chinese restaurant process priors over ways of partitioning the objects into categories here i have
three categories but in principle there could be an infinite number of them and their
parameters which unlike in traditional mixture model
the parameters describe the features of the objects here these parameters describe interactions between pairs
of objects we're basically putting one queen wait one binomial
distribution on each block of this matrix so this is sometimes called the matrix block
parameters of the block matrix and the idea is you know here a weighted coin
away point nine generates these bits but the point of weight point once a generates
those bits
so this is the best generative model there is one hundred digits
i say that in every lecture given nobody's yet challenge
and in fact same long enough to become true
so i just changed label here
and now will generate AIDS
once he settled into the ravine in generate it's
one way of thinking about this model
is as a way of dealing with the fact that all real world data
it lies on low dim lies on or close to low dimensional manifolds
in the normal way to deal with that is to say
well it's too slow on the manifold is about twelve dimensional
inside my machine must have twelve members are represented two
in this figure out how to get to these numbers may be less tricky maybe
and we associate sort of twelve numbers with two
the problem with that is if the two has a very long tail
it's actually a lot more degrees of freedom causes or so social fourteen degrees of
freedom is long tail
and obviously somewhere in between it's got thirteen half degrees of freedom
degrees of freedom until one of the things you can do with the two
by making a very wobbly too
making not quite so good too
but none spans turning around the pixels
so that's sort of degree of some freedom but you know it's a bit but
to do that but not too bad
what's more
the data might have many these manifolds you don't know how many
in fact he might be the those thirty eleven of these manifolds
but if you go up in energy appeared that if you allow things to be
not quite so good to the merge
you might have sevens and cross sections
but if you get a bit less sort discriminating they might be sort of
morris in the same manifold
and so rather than dimensionality dealing with low dimensional data
by explicitly
trying to represent
where you are on the manifold
a much better way to do it i think is too
take your data that lies on these low dimensional manifolds
blow it up into some high dimensional space
and in the high dimensional space
have an energy function
start off with everything equal energy so what's the ratty zero
and then gradually dig ravines
low dimensional ravines so
if we say will work in this time it is the five hundred dimensions here
then in this five hundred dimensional space we can integrate out these units so we
can get what's called a free energy for these five hundred motion vectors
and that's going to be ten ravines each which is long and skinny
and has a few degrees of freedom along the floor of the living
and then lost the degrees of freedom the side of it
and in particular the ravine for two years
might in some places come quite close to the to three is the might be
quite an energy barrier that because we expect low density regions of the high energy
regions between
two classes
actually for forcing lines that's not true the ravine falls in the range from nine
sort merge into one point
more less
what this model is learned by this sort of greedy learning in very fine tuning
is to turn the pixels
into these features
and the features of the property that by using these hidden units
to express
sort of energies of combinations of features
we can make ravines in this space
the capture the manifolds if we try to do it by
interactions between pixels we couldn't do it
you just can't express what two is by markov random field on pixels
it is the current in markov random field powers interesting pixels such that the only
happy states two years
but as we've seen we can do it if we use multiple less
the only happy states of the system
when you stick when you claim that label
i do one more because i it so much
you can't generate from
repeat the question convolutional networks do the same thing
well show very good recognizing digits
the convolutional neural networks won't allow you to generate from the model because they don't
have a generative model
if you think of the classic ones from the late nineties from the nineties
more recently he has been doing more complicated things we just combine this kind of
learning convolutional nets
so basically i've infected younes convolutional nets
and he's not doing stuff like this as well
so these are just some
samples generated model where you
run four thousand alternating gives great iterations for example so the independent
whatever comes out of you will indicate your weight
a of c is
smaller than ten
that's meaningless
attention can never be
the string was negative tension has no physical meaning
what it means is that the bucket of water would never have made it to
this point
if you try to swing it up
someone tried in the second lecture we didn't make it to that point the bucket
of water
i will just fall
you end up with a mess with better detail
the bucket of water
when is here
if the acceleration in the absence of the iteration were exactly ten meters per second
then the bucket of water would be
i said earlier that when you in freefall
o object in free-fall i eyewitness
it's like a spacecraft in orbit or the elevator was cut cable
it also means
that if i jump off the table
that i'm weightless
while i am
in midair so to speak
it means this tennis ball
while it is in freefall
it has no weight
now it has weights
now the way even higher because i'm accelerating it
and now it has no weight
and small
right and i assume for now that air drag
plays no role
if i jump of the table
i will be weightless for about half a second
this is about one meter
if i jump from the power which is hundred metres high
i will be waiting list for four and a half seconds
ignoring and
i prefer today
the harvest second
i'm going to jump of this table
with this one in my hands
i tell you
how i can convince you
as i jumped that i will indeed be weightless
here is the bot
the gravitational force on the ball
my hands are pushing up
on this portal
my hands are being
about scale i feel
in my muscles the need to push up
in fact i might even be able to estimate the weight
playing the role of the bathroom scale
to get in the water
it's about nine pounds
now my own body
gravity is acting only
but i'm being pushed up
right there
we jumped
there would be no pushing
for me on the
well anymore
not pushing there
on the
only gravitational will act upon us
and we would be weightless
how can i show you that we await us
well if i don't have to use my muscles to push on this bottle upwards
i might as well with my hands on little bit doing this
and you will see
that the bot will just stay above my hands without my having to push up
being the bathroom scale i no longer have to push on it
i no longer
my muscles don't feel anything
and the model is therefore we
but almost weightless
when we jump
i am weightless and even his beagle is weightless all weightless during harvest second
there is no such thing in physics
as a free lunch
you have to pay a price for his half a second
of weightlessness
what happens
when i hit the floor
i think the floor with
velocity in this direction which is about five meters per second you can calculate
but a little later i've come to stop
that means
during impact must be acceleration upwards
otherwise my velocity in this direction could never
become zero
i will weigh more doing this impact there's an acceleration in this direction
the five meters per second
goes to zero
if i make the assumption that it takes two kinds of the second that's a
very rough guess these impact time
then the average acceleration will be five meters per second divided by o point two
that is twenty five meters per second squared
that means acceleration upwards two-and-a-half g
that means i wait three-and-a-half times more
remember a posting to a historian have to be up
plus the gene that we already have the next three and a half
she so instead of three hundred sixty five pounds i close to six hundred pounds
for two sensible sector
so we get for faces right now
i'm a normal weight
if i stand on a bathroom scale
i john for half a second weightless
but the floor
for about two kinds of the second
maybe close to six hundred pounds
and then after that
one of my normal weight again
now you're going to have only half a second
two c
that this model as i j
it's floating above my hands i will pull my hands off
so you will see
i no longer have to push
that means
it's weight was
you're ready
i'm ready
one zero
you see floating above my hands
we were both
i have been
thinking about this
for a long long time
i have been thinking whether perhaps
this could not be shown
in a more
dramatic perhaps even more
convincing way
and so i thought of the idea
of food in the bathroom scale under my feet
applying it very loosely so that wouldn't fall off when i john
and then show you
that's why i'm half a second in in fall the bathroom scale indeed indicates zero
i don't think that i haven't tried to have tried many times as many bathroom
skills made many jobs
there's a problem
and the problem is the bathroom scales by
you normally get commercially
they indeed wants to go to zero it takes a long time
they have a lot of inertia the response time is slow
even if they make it to zero by the time you get the floor
immediately the
weight increases become it before you wait comes up by three and a half time
so i have
things like classes and properties so i can kinda begin to build up schema that
say things like person is class hascolleague the property
professor subclassof person
and this is kind of trying to represent some of the data that i talked
about before
and and specify some some kind of restrictions on the way in which are my
range and domain should be interpreted
OK and then then we have some some machinery some some RDF the
schema so the distance liberality here
OK so we have things like
there's no
distinction between my classes and instances OK so i could do lots of kind of
quite powerful stuff in my in RDF and RDF schema
so here i have this this kind of metamodelling notion that got liu's ally in
line is a species and species class of this kind of species notion is so
lions playing both the role of the kind of a collection of things the collection
of all the lines and also as an individual which is itself species so i
can do this kind of metamodelling notions RDF schema i could talk about the properties
properties OK so i can in the class of properties but i can also to
say some some rather strange stuff because my my RDF vocabulary is kind of available
to make to the RDF resources there's no clear distinction made between language constructors and
ontology vocabulary so i can potentially do some kind of quite strange stuff in in
applying the constructors to themselves
so in order to deal with this we have some semantics are not going to
go into the details of this cave essentially this this kind of just tells you
one should be interpreting the special built pieces of vocabulary into an describes the kind
of inference is that you might expect to be able to draw from
and among these are kind of the
things that that kind of one would expect based here if i had some graph
here i describe lectures being a subclass of academic academic is a subclass of person
these things are all classes
OK the RDF semantics will tell me that i can expect to find a triple
it tells me that lectures across the person
so essentially this is just telling me that subclasses some kind of transitive relationship
OK this is what i would expect if i need to have a semantic machinery
there to be able to
kind of makes this
make this inference
and similarly if i got here and individual shown them saying sean lecturer lectures subclass
of academic again i can make an inference here that i can i can deduce
that there should be a triple here
it tells the shown as an academic these are the ways that one would just
subclass is an instantiation to work OK but we need to enshrine that within the
machinery of language in order to be able to to actually make this
make this happen and the inference happen for us
so what does RDF schema give us well
it gives us the ability to use some kind of simple schema vocabulary so i
can begin to talk about classes of things i can begin to
build this some sort of taxonomy of how i believe my domain fits together i
get some and through that i can get some consistent vocabulary use case we can
begin to share the classes that we use to describe our object
i get some simple inference in terms of the
the inference is that i just showed you
there are some
OK in terms of
expressiveness OK so if i want to
and if you if you remember
i'm kind of living here and i'm talking largely in this kind of big world
OK so that what kind of started to describe things
in level of detail and i want to express in this to be able to
come describe how i think my domain fits together
so the problem with RDF schema is that it's really quite we in terms of
its expressivity in terms of the things that i can see in the things i
can describe classes that i have
so for example i can express localised range and domain constraints
things like if i have a published by
OK so i journal is published by a publisher
and the technical reports published by an institution
OK so i can't there's nothing in RDF schema that will allow me to kind
of essentially represent that kind of constraint OK so i want to know that this
relationship kind behave differently when it when it's applied to different kinds of objects
i can talk about existential or cardinality constraints
OK so i can't say for example the papers must have off which is the
for that you have got to have at least three reviewers there's no
this is just no vocabulary that allows me to do that in RDF schema and
similarly i can't talk about the characteristics of my properties so
i want to say there is some of entropies transitive
so any sub event subevents some events of the major events in the case of
and nor can i say that the rules have inverses cases you always quite important
my modelling want that hasrole is the inverse of a rule that i can again
i can represent shooting final RDF schema
so it's it's rather kind of weak language in terms of its expressivity however
conversely it's actually quite is quite as a strong and rich language because of some
of the things that i talked about earlier
so for example because i can apply the RDF primitives to the to the the
vocabulary itself OK we we need to have something we need to have machinery in
semantics that allows us to deal with another resulted actually quite difficult to provide a
full reasoning support for RDF to kind of cope with all of
then that expressivity so one of can it's very expressive in some ways but it's
also quite inexpensive and others when you want to talk about the kind of class
so the solution
OK so we're kind of this is this is kind of where we're all comes
in is to provide a language that has
sits within the standards OK so within RDF RDF schema and so on and the
desire the one the desirable features it's easy to understand and use OK again rather
dangerous tend to use objective here
but of adequate expressive power so we were able to capture some more of the
kind of things that we wanted to build models and also we have some formal
specification case that we can provide some automated reasoning support this is where this is
where outcomes in
a little bit of of
background all this is just some kind of historical stuff
and so there were a couple of efforts that were going on i guess at
the end of the
in the nineties really so there was a
there them along which was kind of language being developed under the daml program this
was kind of taking pulling together RDF and RDF schema and frame based approaches at
the same time over here in lies in europe was language called OIL which is
being developed mainly under the auspices of the ontoknowledge project possible some other people
and this was taking approach taking RDF RDF schema and kind of framework modelling approach
and pulling in the formal semantics description logic world OK which we'll talk about later
both these languages then fed into daml OIL
OK and then down was used as the starting point essentially for the w three
c activity they ended up with the yellow recommendation this is kind of where where
some of the stuff has has come from
so i mentioned description logics and i think i think jim used to at some
point during his presentation so what are description logics DL so there
their family of knowledge representation languages OK case there are kind of member of the
DL learning on which construction is one employees and so on
right to work in semantic networks and KL one the desire to try and formally
specify what was going on in semantic networks and they describe domain in terms of
concepts roles and individuals case fitting in with this paradigm i talked about before
just using small positions
we can prove that were purely random forest which is the reason i presented to
which is exactly the reason for which is kind of
i don't want somebody interested is consistent
and the should
but the distributions for one
john roberts assumption kind of just got on me
max vision to
this can environment for some reason which is also
so this is the first step
and show that the very reason for
some represent for
university course
that's correct
so you can
number of you but i will come back the original run we see
we can get
the original
now what's interesting here is that the problem that randomized first system
the average
because it
this is not the real question recreation is the converse is true
i mean you have original bad guys
can the candidate become better when get the question which are first in terms of
the converse is not true
the main message on my talk about randomized average
well because the base classifiers into consistent ones
i will show you how to run the first condition is that start with a
very simple example which is
an example which is inspired by that
contraction of the navigation
and the start with a very simple rule which we call a which is the
one nearest which are going to school
this is what we all the schools
you want to make this school when don't know
just look at the nearest neighbor
one way
it's cool but not in the know
mathematical way away
because this is not consistent
of course just one nearest neighbor except a few regression some special and whatever is
is not of course
to make this request is so we can use the which just like very much
to just go back
back is also randomize reason randomisation machine
by generating many bootstrap samples from the original
and what we are going to do here is to apply back to the nearest
neighbour algorithm reason
just consider very simple model where each data pair just with some probability
and we have some process and the sample
it's that depend on each other so we should approach to it
this way justifying randomized classifier which
classifier which is of course some original
of size and just fine
so lets you picture with this
so you have your original version of this room because samples to take charge separation
with probability qn your don't subsampling which is final
so i
the original one
the correct decision
nearest neighbour decision
so this is the decision of the first
you do this one's enough to of course
way you back
the second term the difference is that some of their decision so this was once
you want
we get this
and what we can prove
that average one nearest neighbour classifier
which is just an aggregation of many that five is consistent if and of course
two and the the sampling rate
and so
it turns out that the proof
it is based on how human by storms
which proves
we now have this knowledge
it just makes
in this
i mean the difference here is
the station is inserted before we had four
the sum of of five i know as a no really
every element of k which is now of
below us so we have for each s makes waves are s
the rate of each dimension h two mix is a two dimen two directors in
each dimension
so we have in two dimensions rich
the relation next direction again the direction index dimensions and then twice and y dimensions
this is a much smaller space because we have much more
right now we can
but the space we need for the sparse grid
the reagan has age to make sense of this function is not responded and in
some so we normally only takes in all secondary does not
all the smaller ones as well
what's quite this space it it just makes also tensor product structure so we can
write this xmax
just as the product of the one dimensional as HS spaces
but there's also a reproducing kernel hilbert space by the way
just because he h once the features
OK just of the tensor product is one is what
so let's assume we have
the function f or of
so outraged as
zero makes means your bona fides because it makes all this stuff a bit easier
to not consider the binary value but you can do it as well
so you can easily show just a bit of calculations that
these basis functions to normal bounded by this term
cluster based calculation
convention for the record the coefficients of the function of h two
so to call freshened
corresponding to the basis functions
filer j
this justice to try to prove was
kind of simple proof and we can sometimes simply one dimensions
so we take into google over omega field j
second the rate of
of a function
so this is essentially since is a local business function we don't have to go
over the support of his basis functions support goes for
good point it excelled j mines h two could such plus h
the media integration by parts
so we move
one partial derivative
to the basis function and get
this term and then we could also
i wonder values
could minus as well as we do is
um to
so we had a
this we can just can just use effectively before that basis functions the value of
the basis function is bounded between use
it is the story
i'm just takes one of which total set
and the distance of the flow left and music can collect
and this is just as before
this is just a regular plus just off the tree
o twice of the tree
so this is
for new moves
age group mexico that's exactly
what i wanted to show here
see why we need to h two
stuff because we
to show
but i have be able to do this
and h two mix
because if we do the tensor product we go to higher dimensions and we need
a product of all these secondary so that's why was aged two mix
comes from
so now we have to record coefficients
i have this
and now we have to
take it apart and a bit more so now we
after the dimensional version we take just
that's what had before you know it takes us out of this
and this is just
just the second derivative of the mexican directors on the support of this function
and this we just cannot
as before
by above the system
so we have seen of j is bounded by some constant which depends on the
dimensions to the power
of some term so level
some of the scenes and support
not support
so each to mixed norm on the support of f on the support of field
and we can send just just have to
put all these
local stuff together
shows that c
two norm of f
can be
founded on the bottom of the african represent f over f of all of these
records places we can show that each
component of set
this despite
but this term so we just fluxes in
and use effect that effects from before that
put all these
local stuff together so that we get
and then we need to be a reference ontology
we will have a different locale ontologies for describing the different estimates sources and we
need mapping between the local ontologies handed out of aces mappings between the local ontologies
and the
the reference
the reference ontology so in that case i will present the
yes an idea of how we have been affiliated network of ontologies in
in this summer
so the first thing is that for building the reference ontology so we have a
using standard in the human resources manager
we are using
ontologies and ontology repositories and we
our lives in the different scheme and that the sources for building these reference ontology
so that the output will be the reference ontology and forbidding the local ontologies we
take as input the the reference ontology and the different schema that the sources in
order to produce several local ontologies one local ontologies for the employment a four four
percent in the
the sources of the different different employment services after that
we will generated mappings between the pervasive
the locale
ontologies using our tool technology
we will also using with some of the knowledge to represent the mapping between the
local ontologies the reference ontology some based on that we create the mappings
the at idea end what we have for
knowledge resources the first one is the reference ontology
four types of knowledge resources the first one is the reference ontology
the second one is all the local ontologies the third one are the mappings between
local ontologies that are based on the fourth one of the mappings between local ontologies
so far below the
the reference
the first things we did is
two to do the ontology
the specification for that we used
the makes named competency questions created by the building and weak focuses the competency questions
related to in this domain to twelve what related to job seekers so in the
competency questions about the article we have something like this he said educational level of
for the job offer we have what are the required skills for the you will
for the last half questions related with time and data management like when the job
seeker completed completed his or her first
with currencies and you know
questions like given employ information economic activity of the employee employer and you will find
what jobseekers had the most appropriate
so from this question what we we do is to to get the vocabulary
so we identified
for instance that we
we have the question we can identify that we need some terms like contract type
what conditions difficult job offers
from the and we we can get information about this is a part-time job or
the salary three thousand euros and based his work on the
that we identify from the questions and the answers to the compared to to the
question we
are able to identify the first set of terms to be included in the in
the ontology life on type compensation work or condition job seeker job offers had just
that everybody has compensation required for speedy name date is it OK so from this
question we can get the first list of the terminology two
to be included in the
in the in the ontology
so since we already know affairs since we already have first
least of the terms to be included in the ontology then this step should be
to go to to look for a system cover is in
internet i mean to know if there is some kind of i is always stand
or domain dependent book on very that has been previously every by by our community
because if they is that we will save a lot of time
when building our ontology so in that case using we search for the book cover
is related with occupation classification classification of economic activities currency classification geographic classification languages classification
so for on and so forth and we did some kind of assessment
activity in order to match
the terminology from the competency questions against the sound in order to know the degree
of coverage of the different in book of
so for this selection
which is the third stage
we have compared
as you can see in this table the different the different terms
well there's one thing which is sometimes sometimes this notion of expansion constant better than
you expect
so for example if you have this data set
it might actually be pretty small because
the expansion constant within these small poisson smaller
and this one
might be relatively small and then of course
for a larger radius is
if you don't you just kind of all the number of points
so you can kind of a lot points to be very close to some
in some ways and very far away from the same distance to have a small
expansion constant
an important simulation
when you throw in this structure the
so for the wall street there's been no analysis of the structure
it seems difficult to actually do it
but should mention that this is not really one of sort of a family about
for the moment
cardinal rule over them
certainly can you make insertion into destruction we log in time
you can construct by it insertion on log n time
he is in love again space
in a blog in time to remove
two on structure
in a blog in time the query this is the big one
so this going from
water and
water log and for some fixed c
yes you can actually be dependent upon the number of samples so it's not
so i really fixed parameter in some sense
so the navigating that
i would like to see if criminal was made this
in log in
space good in space
the cover tree
just makes good in space
you can see
we also work to enable them with exact constants were the constants here
well i just checked down once and failed
OK so
so maybe this is nice and since then
we have some
one of the members that both these are two c delta you this analysis
it says you do well constant small
and then you have
this analysis
which says you're going to be too bad in terms of
and a lot of time in this way to kind of advertisers away
so if you cover sort of an isolated and because it's not going to require
much more space than the brute force
and it's going to give you
as much
speedup with respect to
this expansion constant is this in any other algorithms
and it's also nice because it works pretty well in practice
what we did was we
did that's this is we compared
well we will never datasets
you can sort of bug bites right so the dimensionality now actually
this one for here what has very large dimensionality smaller points
and then what we did was we cover tree
from incoming optimise brute force
and for every point we ask for the
o point and said we ask for the one two three five ten years neighbours
so it's it's one two three four five ten
it's the different parts of
OK so
yes this compared is chemistry is divided by brute force optimise briffa's
so what you notice
so one thing which is nice is the performance except in
one very small case ten years they resort to personal data set
is good one
all these tests always datasets is that that we tested so i'm not holding anything
the time for cover trees also including the construction time
i'm trying to be as fair as possible here
how much of the speed of source very between
almost nothing
and you know all of about
the reason
some datasets we get such that the that's because of this expression because it
charlie parker with the more later but
what you can notice if you analyse data sets is not of expansion constant necessarily
but sort of the
average expansion constant
is small for the once we get a big speed
also he large data scenario big speed because of their independence and so these are
all small datasets
these are getting larger so this one happens to be smaller because it's four thousand
this is in this which is a hundred in direction recognition
and it's kind of cool to give much fewer you going you know
so in between
two and one
the average distances
we get the
now good
like all of the
what else
there's something is strange feature here which is that should have the spike for one
nearest neighbour
cimino one
it turns out that one nearest neighbour
as the degeneracy problem
online at some point right we can i think a little bit about you know
what sort of crazy things are people going to do with this
so we do have prior expectations about
the uses of this code that's probably the rational way of going about
this is
o lord even though like going into the work of the people
i mean you know there are ways of counting and they don't sound so horrible
that you could say i believe that the function is kind of smooth
and you know and
and you know that doesn't sound as scary as i believe that it comes from
a dozen process with this covariance
they were
you have
is there a way
all the way
obviously they have this year
we can see that
the huge are
i mean that's
but that's fine that's fine for the case study view where you're you're going to
peak at the data may be peak i mean i like the idea of peaking
at ten percent of the data saying
i think i see this sort of structure in here and then running on the
rest are something i mean people might object but
at least
but but that different from the black box view where you just put your code
online somebody else is running your code so i mean
god knows that they're going to do with it right
how to predict
you know that's the worst thing they do
you have already
and here is
so let's i mean this isn't unfortunately this and the only problem working limits
move on to other spiking neuron
all right
what you are
well first all
one of the
four in
i mean i think i think that's a valid point
in that
we we don't want to be just sort of blandly uniform over all possibilities we
want to learn from and i think as a community we do this we learn
from things that seem to work and then we develop new models
that have more structure maybe concentrate mass more interesting places where datasets might actually work
over the
so what you
this is about
the problem
have a problem
is the man
i mean the there
we would like to what we would like to do is to be able to
characterize the space of possible problems
so that nu
the method can look properties of the problem and no one kind of prior to
use in that case but let's just let's just move on because i think there
are other issues as well that that there were talking about
so one of them is this sort of nonparametric versus parametric
you know you just roughly speaking we can think of parametric models as
having a finite dimensional refining fixed number of parameters theta
and so
what happens is given those parameters the predictions are independent of the data
the parameters in the parametric model to capture
all the structure
in the data that is useful for doing predictions about new data points
OK we can think of this really is model based learning because you know you've
captured in that
finite dimensional parameter a model of the data
nonparametric models sort of roughly speaking allow the number of parameters to grow with the
data set size so the effective number of parameters grows with the data set size
or alternatively we can think of them as
having predictions that depend on the data
and possibly a usually small number of what we would probably call hyperparameters of well
OK so the predictions then depend on the data and these other
hyperparameters doesn't not like nonparametric models
don't have
any parameters in the
well this is of course you can do it by building a model of the
person in you know fitting the model to each point class but this is not
such an easy problem or you could you know manually sort of segmented at every
point again this is kind of painful fate so that an alternative solution to the
following its so well
a few more
what happens
when a person moves actually for the participants
this guy's
this our first
of this guy's body is about to fall into two dimensional manifold embedded in three
dimensional space
then the person moves
what happens well if you think about it
when you move your arm doesn't really stretch
it's actually a kind of rigid motion right your scheme so if i put markers
on the ski like here here
it doesn't matter what i do
the ambient space between this two
will of course change what like i'm would like this but the shortest geodesic distance
between them
will actually stays the same
o almost the same as the skin stretches a little bit of this so this
is an example of an isometric transformations that transformation which preserves in tornio
this persons on the manifold so to manifold isometrically equivalent
if there is a correspondence between them which preserves geodesic distances
so when you moved this is an isometric transformation of the surface of
now here's an interesting thing so let's see what
the new computer so this is this is a bunch of point practices data so
what happens when you compute
i can vectors
of the last operator of the laplacian matrix
it's part described in the
the first half of the dog
what happens when you computed on this day well each i can vector is a
function defined
all the surface of these guys but
so for each point
so if i take the furthest well the first thing that is constantly fighting the
second organ vector
this is going to be some function so so each point made point five you
may be minus point five and so on
now what is interesting about this is actually the third ranking function
if you can see the color
corresponds to the value of this function
so when the moving
the color actually is not changing
so that means
that these the well you here
this function was pointwise you know point t equals zero then five my second life
it's still
o point one
it didn't change at all
why is it useful well now
i actually have a function which doesn't change when a chair when they walk
so if i use this function of one function is not enough i want to
use several in general but if we use this function to to segment this guy's
body for example say that i'm only interested in the prox where this function is
bigger than point five
you can you can figure out how to do it
this segmentation will actually
go in time and state exactly the same and i will and feel exactly the
same in practice obviously not exactly the same but
but on the the set and the nice thing about it you don't actually you
just need to know this point clouds you don't at each time separately you don't
need to know anything about that so computed at one time
and you can see them throughout
the whole
time process that the whole time time scale
so that's
that that was kind of a nice application of this manifold i
this the what of neat examples i think you know what i'm going to do
i'm actually going to talk about
on how the heat equation
i think there were some more
this is closely related to graphics actually
let me tell you a little bit about the heat equation and the connection to
the because in a sense heat equation is the key object as i say
the laplace operator so the class separated in the heat equation that kind of go
keep question
the heat equation
it's basically
the following so
so let us form
let's for simplicity can be sourced considered an hour and a we actually interested in
the heat equation on the manifold but still get short so what happens in our
in our and
suppose you have some sort of
distribution in time zero u of x zero
so you have some key distribution
how does he evolved
so he actually evolve
according to to the what's called the heat equation
in the heat equation says that if you have a few of ecstasy
that's the amount of heat
at the point x at
the time t
then the lab class you fxt
is equal to the time derivative of you that and the heat equation
now how do you solve something like that well we have a good intuition about
how he goes well diffuses right it becomes kind of spread around
what does this intuition formerly well formerly in our and we actually can write the
solution of the heat equation
this integral
basically you FXT is the convolution of the he just of f of y which
is a new show he distribution
the shadows on the wall
in my hand
he was playing
and it is far from infinitely large
if i were this
so far away from its four centimetres
very close approximation will be infinitely large but if i'm here and there and that's
where i will be of course it is not
infinitely large anymore
so let's start then the graph
you can see but i turned it on
it's rotating now i have to put charts on the output should
was of and the graph
this is no charge has the same charges the plane
the plane is being charged
and here you see
the angle
try to remember that angle
hard to estimate the fifteen degrees you see the vertical
and if no i it's about
thirty centimetres away from the plane
and i go back
two fifty centimetres which is where i am now
c hasn't changed very much
go further out to sixty centimeters
the angle goes down a little of course it does
but not very much
and if i go far away all the way to mass avenue
of course
the force on this little object inversely are square because then
the whole plane would behave like points or
so i've shown you that very close to this plane
electric field
stays approximately constant
so if now we remove this
march because if you can you will have to
is also off
thank you very much
now we have the van der graaf along
so now we don't have the electric field falls off
as one of our square it's a very good approximation now
we can think of the charges being right at the center
i'll give it a little bit of charter and charts OK
so look at the projection
the balloon is now
or maybe thirty centimetres away from the center maybe forty
forty and is almost forty five degrees
now i go i double the distance i go to about
ninety centimeters
look at that angle theta
the angle theta is now down to o maybe ten degrees i will go back
where i was
this angle is about forty degrees
and now
very small
and when i go here
which is about
media and half
you can hardly see
there's any angle
only a few degrees
so i've shown you only qualitatively
that's the electric field falls off very rapidly
in the vicinity of a
uniformly charged sphere
and that it doesn't fall off
very fast if you are in the near vicinity
of a
the second thing i want to show you
has to do with the fact that the electric field
a uniformly charged sphere
here i have a sphere
which is not entirely closed
i can make it closed because i want to demonstrate to you that there is
no electric field inside when i charge is uniformly
and since i have to get inside an opening
nothing i can do about it since there is an opening
the electric field is not exactly zero inside
it's only true
if this is a complete closed surface and if the charge is uniformly distributed
but it's good approximation the opening is quite small
and what i'm going to do
is i'm going to try to this
the sphere and put in charge outside
user device
that we have not used before
but that's not so
he was now that
hollow sphere
going to put charge on their
let's suppose it is positive charge
so this will be positively charged
since it is is
the conductor as we will learn
i think the next lecture or things this week that the charge automatically distributes uniformly
only does that on the conductor
and now
to demonstrate to you that there is an electric field here
i will
i use induction
i have two
ping pong balls
i think it was conducting paint
they touch each other
on the influence of the electric field
this one will become negative and this one will become positive we've discussed at last
time you created dipole
the important it is the dipole
i separated two
i've negative charge the positive charge there
i'll touch
any one of these two balls it doesn't matter which one
with the electroscope and you will see
the discharge there
so i've demonstrated then the is an electric field outside
that sphere
now i will do exactly the same demonstration
but now
i put these two
conducting both inside
here they are
i parts that you just have to trust me that i really will touch them
and then i will take them out
are really satisfied with the actual performance that you're reaching
random search and try to sort of refine that a bit more
but that's that's a pretty solid baseline yeah
yes yeah that's another approach
works really well lab like me but yeah there's like hundreds of
students yeah less another yes
ok so actually that's a very good question any kind of ties and
so the question is about which should we use one regularization
or l to so i'm quickly start talk about
the problem of selecting the number of iterations for training
and building that l to one so there's this other hyperparameters
that barely mention which is the number of updates i'm going to
do typically we sort of think of it as the number of times doing
over the whole training set and one approach to be used specifically
for that hyperparameter is early stopping so what we do is that
we track at after every parts after every full pass over the how
are the training set going to measure the performance on the validation
set yeah just learning curve here i'm showing the training curve
as well as validation set after every epoch i'm reporting
what's the training sets performance
so as so the interesting for selecting hyperparameters but it's
a good metric to look at to debug and make sure you models training
but more crucially i'm going to measure the performance on the validation
set and i'm going to do that you know train another full epoch
and this again training a validation set performance
and what you expect this very basic you know
machine learning is that eventually the your underfitting
and there's a point in which the training
set performance starts continues getting better but actually
the performance on some new examples starts getting worse so
then you start entering the overfitting regime
the essential dynamic that's says going on here is that the gap
between these two curves we expected to becomes bigger and bigger
and bigger as you go and because this is you know usually
bounded by below needs to converge to some some i thought value
that it means eventually this curve goes up
so with thirty stopping which do you essentially track
the performance validation set and then once it starts going up
well you pretty much know you should stop training
so effectively you're not going to train to completion on your training
objective going to train until you measure some form overfitting
over the validation set in practice
the performance of validation set might be a bit noisy so usually
we leave some what i call look ahead that as you even though you
have an improved which affected the best performance it's
on the validation set so far for your run
you still keep going maybe ten iterations something
and then if after ten iterations that's a look ahead
number if it if you add an improver the best validation set
performance then you stop training go back maybe to your
best model and the reason i yeah regulation like one l two is
that effectively would this means is and you can show this like
more analytically and some work has been done and i are measuring
that or clarifying this link is because you start to weights usually
around zero effectively this is making its
this is retracting the model from going to far from its initial
as initialization so far from zero much like
l to regularization is doing much like one regularization is doing
so early stopping is actually good alternative to
regulation like one l to frankly in practice
i've not seen very frequently that l one oil to regularization
then it has to satisfy if you have a really basic properties which is called
reasonable right firstly
the length of empty subset is of course going to be zero
and if we have disjoint subsets
then the length of the union is going to be the sum of the lengths
of the individual subsets
this carries the multi
me and
a probability measure is simply one where
total length
of the whole space is going to be one
so the length now is going to be the probability of an event a subset
an event
the probability of
over the whole
event space is going to be one has has to indicate one is the probability
and it turns out that we can't really from most spaces that were interested in
for example the real line we can't actually define and measure over all possible subsets
of the real line
so we have to restrict ourselves
ourselves to count family of subsets that
terms measurable
and so that's what scholars sigma algebra so sigma algebra simply a family of subsets
of the set
OK theta such that
of course it cannot be empty we
there has to be some things for which you can measure
and if a subset is in our sigma algebra then it's complements has to be
in it as well
and then finally
we have a sequence of subsets
then the union is also going to be our
is also going to be measurable
the fact that this is sequences come important so you can't have
and countable union of things to any countable union of measurable sets is also measurable
and then finally
well it's not really about what's meant for a measurable function it in fact
say is that if you have two measurable spaces theta and delta
then a function is measurable if its inverse image is measurable for any measurable
subset a of the second of the of the output space
now let's us
history ourselves to probability measures and
think about what is meant by a random variable
and so that a random variable is actually not random at all
there is simply
a measurable function
OK so
the way you can think of this as the is is is as follows so
so how would you implement
a function in matlab c on c that in that just that generates say random
draws from
from a gamma distribution
so the way you would do is you would actually write down this function which
takes a sequence of
takes actually what we can measure how do you know what i wanted to
so his and his
and easier one so how would you generate from the galaxy and with the mean
of ten
tell me how you how would you implement civic
as of
OK yes so that's why so we assume that we have some random number generator
so in this case gulf a random number generator that generates zero mean gaussians and
then we simply add ten to it so if you think of the function itself
that you've just written is a deterministic function is or is not the this is
the function itself is fixed and it takes a random bits and they returns to
use random numbers from the distribution that you're interested in
and this is called the same way that you can think of a random variable
so the probability measure here
on this basis they turn common sigma sigma here's asking signature is going to be
our random number
and all random variable x is going to be a function which takes a random
number generator and spits out random variables random samples of this variable
and then finally a stochastic process is basically a collection of
and the variables so cx i one for each eye and the
the distinguishing property of
the stochastic process from say a graphical model is that
this index set
can be infinite and in fact can be uncountably infinite as we saw in the
case of the gaussian process
this turns out to be a tricky issues so
this is the how do even define this uncountably infinite number of random variables
how can even show that they exist and this is where
and there is a lot of which is what we try to deal with
we don't have to go into the system which is independent in fact if you
prefer to have
the citation should between the input and the output is that you is large enough
we just have that which which means that
again this then is only even by these external components out of the amplifiers which
means that the phi doesn't have to be perfect justice to have never again so
that this approximation again and it's much much simpler for instance to make
three sons
there exist also in very good for you
so the best
if a user is an amplifier which has
two inputs
and which of the game which is very large
which could be done which is very eyes which means that there is no current
flowing inside the amplifier
and again it's itself
so as i said it's high so you see a probably DB so it'd be
twenty log on the actual to put
one hundred and at the bottom
looks not to be so high that it in fact i was we start from
the idea and it's OK
and then how it works you just because it's on fire
you put a feedback network and it's so here i just want to is also
which means that i really enjoy this point
the fraction of the which
i would vote that and i will get an output voltage and then
if we make it a calculation the output voltage
you can start with the input voltage value for all this way
so the input voltage is just
this it's you
nine used up from the outside but i
the whole on the story also which is john for
the output voltage is equal to the
to this value minus
a similar but also if you fall of past
it's my it's a one plus two ten i
and then if you make the relationship between the two you find this relationship
you could use the feedback equation so in in the feedback equation with
you is the new
the values the function that
the input
this to just one
and then you have to find the
the same equation and what is the issue of the canadian
an ideal form new got to get which is infinity
and the washoe between the input and the output just
a short list of
so let's going to
the article itself
and coming back to some of the requirements of the
o which is in doing some child was very small signals and the order of
ten to cool summers and very cold so we don't tradition
she there
and then we have to make in this measurement of amplitude of time
and what is is more and more often in the in the detector now what
is is that element of signal so if you take big scientific dominated experiment it's
close to a hundred million spherical nature
state sequence to victories in several
it's between six
twenty million channel and holds that the genome it would be said well all the
cells the so
so when you have to do the given that you have to
to get lot of what are the public so
first of all we do you
however in the spatial environments such that you have to
to for instance if you are subject to additions and you have to be careful
very well
you you know it which is accessible on if it's not accessible to us to
be heavily
if the system is embedded inside the detector you want to have low if the
signal itself is very when you have to have a low noise electronics
if you put as much noise as in
it could be that you want to be fast all that you want to have
a lot of strange so for instance if you are not going to try to
understand the dynamic ranges
is one of the main issue of
together with no
if you want to talk to you want to have i also which means that
you have to to minimize ever
and of course you have to be low cost
so that they
you've got to be the cause and effect of the
a large variety of then it could be a small it's unlikely that it could
be a big big submodular set CMS pixel module it could be a full-time player
one of the football player of all time as you wrote about this experience
just before
so it could be
this big stuff which is
you could have required to get
so this would fill the
should almost the same always which is that you have got
the detector
and then we get some children that when a particular courses system so that you
that's the kind of course on the detector
it goes on point one people five
it said that all of the same size
fifty by
five formerly michael something like that so you have a very small capacitance i
two then people thought when you have
for subsequent questions
photomultiplier is depicted in the in the industry thirty people from organisations independent the john
but you can go from ten people thought that alpha so
that's the characteristic and it's important to know that the true density according to the
the altitude about one for year course on with michael to fully to to good
photomultiplier tubes which is wonderful to behold really get
and to the five to ten
seven hundred taught at the output
in shambles while so few thousand
you know
we can always move
signal by
by and process
source which is just a short play but are function
so i don't see anything on you don't see anything about i by as connectionist
eric thing in to not a they proposed the problem of of solving this as
an undirected and under sparse crowd
so you can actually post this
a graph property
so an undirected graph from and
the big problem but was that they and the big problem with this approach was
that if you view this PDF
as a graph
every node was interconnected with every other
there was no sparsity in the graph whatsoever
and so if anyone knows anything about the belief propagation lifted belief propagation behaves very
poor poorly we have a dense graph
so i propose technique to sparsify the graphs such as a kind of applied belief
propagation properly and
it works all right it's very slow because you've got another thing with loopy belief
propagation we don't really have any guarantees convergence
but all very interesting all very new
things so
the most straightforward approach another approach that could stated and we did initially was essentially
just basically find the maximum city for the maximum
for each patch so i've come to expect response here
i just look for the maximum point is
perhaps here
but if each patch and then i get maximum points
and then want to have these maximum points
i essentially just constraint that and i might have some wait for instance a beach
classifier got how strong the classifier responses at that point so that the case so
so around the are point WK might be very hard to i say around the
jaw point became of very low so i said just do a weighted least squares
estimate what appears like a piece that so essentially what i'm doing is that i'm
looking for the optimum position at each local patch
and then on this constraining to lie within the subspace so it's it's not really
good way to solve because i'm not solving talk cost function and canada's passing the
cost function into two steps and then solving but it's true it's and it's an
referred to this as exhaustive local search so now we had exhaustive search but exhaustive
local search
and so
but interesting enough
it doesn't work too badly
so this is a inverse dls so we can consider that i am
finding a lot of the time
so the jewel there
eleven illus sometimes does better
things like that but it really does worse
and it's it's it's getting a bit of a better generic performance
but it's of the suffering because we kind of got is really lousy way of
solving the cost function
we did some things and complexity o point touch too much of it but it
turns out that when we actually did analysis complexity you can think well exhaustive search
kind of slow
it turns out that we actually considerably
then some time ever
even though the gradient search but we still
can't slow the project so kind in between this somewhere
in our experiments we can get running about
eight to nine friends second
it's not about
even though we're doing exhaustive search
this is another point was that the nice thing that we have an axe to
explore this too much the nice thing is because we're treating each of these patches
separately and independently there is perhaps some scope here to do some parallel computing so
basically i could perhaps distributing exhaustive searches across a whole heap computers that need to
be done sequentially that can be done independently and they want to have the form
decisions confuse them back together and so we did some again we did some kind
of analysis and things and we can speculate that if we if we are able
to parallel compute we could actually perhaps get better the project
but again this to sort in theory
yes i complexity
and as we have some we want to we want to explore this more
so a major problem with the list is that finding in local minimum rather than
a single global minimum so it's far too computationally expensive
two exhaustive search for the global minimum
so one thing that we try to take advantage of and keep on going on
so obviously we kind of went ivory
but the nice thing about complexity and this is some pretty pretty pictures here
is that enforcing come convexity has a number of local is the properties like mean
like with global minimum
continuous and differentiable
allows me based methods so fast and this is the clincher summation of in convex
functions is a convex function
so if i can sure
pat responses
across my other sixty points are all convex and i sum them up the cost
function shows
my cost function will be convex and so i can solve
but the problem is that well at the moment my pet responses
is there a way that i can forces convexity
so that's what we did we basically tried to enforce convexity patch
so we basically tried to fit
convex quadratic
to each patch response
so this is what the visualization of it its
it's kind of looks like a smoothing but
it's not represented nonparametrically anymore it's actually represented parametrically is quadratic
and so this is how we represent
and this just through so these are the shifts so i've got a fifteen by
is just one of many papers by wainwright in short simoncelli where it's not just
positing some prior that you pull out of your head it's nice to work with
like gaussians but you can go out and measure the actual empirical statistics of natural
scenes and show that can be used to predict behavior in neural responses and you
might ask could we extend that kind of natural scene statistics approach to cognition
in some of the early work that was the a probabilistic cognitive science
the subfield subfields doing we do see that so here's an example of a study
that tom griffiths and i did where we give people these basically these textbook bayesian
statistics problems it's basically the problem of interval estimation
so you see
just to give you some these examples we set them in a kind of an
everyday setting where people might have wi-fi good intuitions so suppose you read about a
movie that has made sixty million dollars to date how much money will it make
in total or you see something in baking in the oven for thirty four minutes
how long until it's ready you meet someone who is seventy eight years old how
long will they live and so on each of these cases you encounter some phenomenon
has some unknown extent or duration teetotal at some random time or value t less
than teetotal and you have to guess the total from that one observation and we
can go and look at the natural scene statistics on the top here you see
the empirical statistics for these classes of events and then on the bottom you see
two things you see behavioral data the little dots
are are median subjects predictions of the the total duration as a function of the
given example and then you see the optimal bayesian predictions from the empirical statistics and
it's quite striking how how close this is i mean to get to get this
right here people have to do two things they have to be bayesian but they
also have to have the right priors and it's quite interesting but they seem to
be sensitive to the the different forms of the distributions for these different classes of
everyday events but this approach is going out and measuring statistics doesn't obviously extend to
the more cognitive problems that we interested in here so i can the case of
word learning what is the right prior what's the right hypothesis space it's not even
clear how to define that are going to measure in the world and not to
mention having a human learner brain autonomously figure that out
so we can look for inspiration to again classic cognitive psychology which suggests that natural
categories are nameable categories might be organised into something like a hierarchical tree data structure
saying with you no categories at different levels of abstraction so here you've canaries and
their bird bird and animal and so on but even evidence looking at population responses
from the level visual system the visual categories to organize that way
and we've been able to make models of of both adults and children were learning
with that same kind of idea so we can take for example these these alien
objects and come up with the tree structure that's shown here
such that the the the branch point the nodes of this tree correspond to hypotheses
of nameable categories and then we can define a prior based on the branch line
basically how perceptually distinct categories it's very similar to the probabilistic models using bayesian phylogenetics
so far from modeling distributions of properties arising from mutation and the likelihood just comes
from assuming the examples are random uniform sample from the labelled branch and then it's
pretty clear how to get this kind of behavior here where you see a few
examples that seem to clustering one distinctive branch and that tells you who for over
there in that part of the tree and we can use this model to make
quantitative predictions of people's judgments for one or a few examples and i'm showing you
just to see you can believe that we can make quantitatively accurate models people versus
this bayesian model for generalization of the new words from one or a few examples
the cluster different levels of the tree but i don't want to dwell too much
on the experiment because the interesting comes from machine learning are really how do we
get to the point where is this hypothesis space and prior come from
we built as modelers by asking subjects to judge in separate experiment to judge the
similarity of these objects and then doing hierarchical clustering but how does the brain do
it i mean in the sense that that's just cheating right it's we all know
that that is an infinite number of features you can compute from the visual image
and depending on which features you use or how you weight them you get very
different similarity metrics in the real question is basically how do people learn the right
notion of similarity or you might ask more deeply and you know it given the
similarity metric you can build the tree by hierarchical clustering but how do you know
usually building tree or other kinds of domains might be organised in other ways it's
not like everything in cognition history structure although it's amazing how often that seems to
come up with the natural representation so these are some of the questions that we
that we've been approaching and then you can think of them again this kind of
questions of learning to learn if you look at the literature and children's cognitive element
you can see the children actually do learn these things they learn what features of
objects to pay attention to forward learning and they learn to organize things into a
tree it's not there initially so for example in this method colleagues study the development
of the shape bias which is this which is this phenomenon you can see right
here you show kids say a two-year-old this novel object they haven't seen the backs
and which other one is that that's on the right bill pick up the one
with the same shape but novel texture material as opposed to say one matches in
texture material but not the same shape kids speaking english have this two years of
age but younger kids like stating models don't have this so somewhere in there they
learn it
and they learn other things a little bit older they learn different biases for different
kinds of words are entities like material bias
words for say non solid substances like learning toothpaste to the word honey or water
it's more about the texture properties of the material than any kind of shape for
these non solid substances so it's if you like two kids have to be able
to learn what counts for similarity but they have to learn different similarity metrics for
different kinds of concepts and again as i already referred to early on children in
learning words don't have a hierarchical structure categories but what's called mutual exclusivity this is
just one way to label each things like flat partition into categories and then only
later say by age age four supposed age two they start to learn that you
can have words like mammal animal living thing that refer to higher level categories
so in in some work that we did a few years ago with charles kemp
and amy perfors we need fairly straightforward simple models of these aspects of learning to
learn and apply them to carbon development but what i want to tell you guys
about this work that we've been doing which is more of the same kind of
idea but in the machine learning setting we can actually appreciate the value of this
this kind of cognitive learning to learn for the sorts of applications that that that
was interested
so here's some work that i've been doing with russ salakhutdinov who's post-doc at MIT
working with me and also with antonio torralba and we framed in the setting of
securing retrieving images from database but this isn't meant to be primarily of vision project
it's just that this is an application that many of us are familiar with and
work on the same idea could apply to speech motor action where you know we
want to do you want to be able to learn say a gesture from one
example or new speech sound or what someone's voice sounds like before you know just
you only have to hear someone talking for a short while to get their voices
so in the context of image database retrieval in standard problem is we want to
say curry with one image say however there and we want to we want to
search over many many images and return the other cows and not the other things
and what you see on the top is the kind of behaviour we'd like to
get in and that is the result of our our system's performance on that curry
but unfortunately if you just take a standard kind of naive similarity based approach what
you get something that looks like on the bottom you get some cows and some
chinese in some fields now why is that well you know the standard approach for
doing this was just one example fancy things you can do if you're allowed to
crew with multiple examples and learned discriminatively of just one example the best you can
do is something like similarity to you take some feature space here we have this
roughly fifty thousand dimensional texture texture feature space but also was introduced at NIPS in
the in the late nineties by devon in viola and this one works very well
in the more discriminative setting it's sort of the inspiration and basis for like the
viola jones face detector and so on but in this and it's sort of modelled
on the early structure of the visual system with recursively nested bore filters
in this setting though you have this fifty thousand dimensional feature space and an all
you can do is compute similarity to the query you don't really know which dimensions
count so something which match the grass in the background is almost as good as
something which actually matches the count another way to put this is at a minimum