and the most obvious one is security performance
select a small measure of performance
most people in the moment
by that
there are some applications things the computation service
where people have reduced internal security
because it makes the week-long job finish
eight hours earlier which is quite nice
so if look kind the details as the
the unique smallest that is you the configuration file eureka polk kind
this advanced over time as the point because the expensive we don't want to read
because we don't want to give you all the a single large binary you can't
so they got the idea for device configuration at the time your machine boots up
this is where learning
and it's
yes you this problem
that would cause i know your machine looks like i'm not going to look any
everything is done
then with the actual model we use
it is such that all the drivers using it sparingly it happens dynamically
at the time
each driver which is loaded time effectively get said well look like of a given
this device appeared this device appeared
listing all hard which present
so device driver authors don't have to do something different that the hardware
all right light
the idea that you have to do two things they want to do one or
the other never do so they never get it right
so we were making people life easier
so there is we've got a couple model where things appear
we have a question because if things that dynamically
the traditional unix model
was he have device file system
plug in this case
you create a device node lh a of the HDP
the distribution of ships with kind of standard
but nowadays device to appear and disappear as you have removed
so the first thing we tried think of death that the kind but file system
so the kind of you'll see it presented you with your device files
the problem with that you can't really really figure
so does this
its mission
if you want for example you want this to be swapped around fifty nine
you could do
so i didn't really work
the modelling use now is think called you
the kernel sends a message to
hough green
using hate this new hardware
and a set scripts called you defend normally do the work so well
it's hard disk it's this
because the device should create
see what they see two
create nodes
and it does not using rule files which are used space
and scripts are also added
so as an end user system and you could change the way this works figure
make it do what you want
that avoids the problem we have data for us
so we
the album that no then model we to an that
gonna like this
you asking things
into doing things the way we want
so now nowadays
o device are
we respond to events greater than you space
hopefully user space is interesting things
the namespaces dynamic is committed
i don't know
we were doing events
image object lifetimes again
internally in the car
we now
basic optical tail
which is basically a name is reference can hang everything else all
the kernel does do garbage collection there are lots and lots of problems with doing
garbage collection in the county
things like knowing the worst case memory use
the fact that
a real-time garbage collection algorithms are
very very hard
sort of
kind of research materials like cases
the basic reference counting it and we don't get circular references become very of often
there's only one normal things that happen in the pacific garbage collector
what the user made sockets file description c
the result special case or not
a total of all the people who designed it works
but we don't really need to go over work
these object properly referenced
means that
you can say well i'm using it not using its free when the last person
finished using it
so this does all this hopefully to do
things went free memory before you finished using it
and we use this to build generic device subject to build
PCI device or PCI thing
platform devices things that fit in the else
i suppose devices devices use devices will be all the classes and everywhere
and we have a single system versus system file system
which allows you to actually see all these values of configuration files all these devices
hope for the
the model of the dynamics no good just saying something is happening is
you have to make it is when you place so let's call change that was
just this
because all these things you're just to your size this use all ceased big files
in my service performing a double-sided disc you define can the violence
doesn't work i kind of want
so that's self is a hierarchical file system
uses the name space the k objects things or configuration
so it's really fast and things have real names and all qn numbers magic magic
constant they were assessed
we trying to replace the process other old things with
it's also dynamically extensible so every time you add a new try to create a
new node is the director
and so this thing can just browse it needs to
when you been used this
i mean these user space can not only to figure things that you can actually
walk says fast
sharp transition
and in terms of approximation
whenever smooth transition i can be much more sloppy with my approximation and won't hurt
me as much as the situation where i have very sharp transition in the conditional
probability function and that's a little easier to see if we just look at a
one d example so this is the one d example what plotting here is the
conditional probability of y one
in two different cases in this case where we have a smooth transition
around the level set one half and so you can imagine if an approximate the
bayes decision says you should have the threshold right here
and if i'm a little bit off my approximation one her much because the probability
of error very gradually around that one half level sets
the situation is different over in this fits very sharp transition or jump in the
conditional probability function the base
decision threshold is right here in a fun little bit off to the right or
left i'm going to incur a much larger area than i do whenever smooth transition
the idea here gets that the smooth transition the easier it is to approximate
with those two kinds of ideas of smoothness smoothness of the boundary of the decision
region and smoothness of the transition
in the vicinity of the one one-half levels of the conditional probability functions
that gives a way of
sir define defining class of problems of varying complexities in terms of approximation
so gamma is the smoothness of the boundary which you can measure in terms of
say derivatives and so that's often called holders this
kappa is the transition smoothness which could also think of in terms of derivatives around
that one half level set of conditional probability functions
and d is the dimension of the problem which also going to govern the difficulty
of learning
so there's an interesting theoretical result which is due to mammon and tsybakov which basically
says that for class of distributions governed by these parameters the smoothness of the boundary
the smoothness of the transition and the dimension of the feature space
expected probability of of all learning rule
relative to the base here
can never
decay faster than this function of that it's kind of complicated but basically what it's
saying is that for different values of the kappa gamma dimension you're going to get
a different levels of achievable
performance relative to the bayes performance as you have
increasing sample size is the main point here is that is an gets larger sample
size of training set size the air will go down in the parameters covering how
quickly decays to zero
this is i should also say that
over here what i'm looking at you you look at
we consider all possible
underlying distributions p which
are governed by these parameters gamma kappa d
and then you
consider the best possible learning algorithm you could ever imagine sensors are fictitious
it's strawman that we don't necessarily know how to compute but in principle we can
get access to these
minimax lower bounds in theory and tells us basically how good we could expect to
deal with any possible learning algorithm i'm not going to go into the details of
how to derive these minimax lower bounds but in some of the papers
that you can find on my website you'll see
derivations of things like this and and really quickly say that the idea is sort
of like you discretize the problem
the space of of classifiers into
a set of points
and hypercube and then you can basically boils down to a simple decision problem of
deciding which point on hypercube iran and that activity this lower bound
OK so
the word that sort of aimed towards this direction saying well can can we derive
learning rule that does as well as its lower bound suggest we ought to be
able to do
there is essentially two ways you might pursue this one is
by placing constraints on the underlying probability densities governing the classes and the labels
and that kind of approach is
basically shown that you can just estimate densities plug them into a classification rule and
you get the optimal rate of convergence and marries working in this work are good
examples of this kind of philosophy
the problem with this approach is that
making assumptions on the global smoothness of the density functions as a little bit heavy-handed
we don't really care about the density functions all we care about is finding the
sets for the decision boundaries and so
this of promoted by number of research is primarily starting with mammon tsybakov said well
let's make assumptions only and the smoothness of the decision boundary and in
the vicinity of the decision boundary like i was just describing above and then the
number of people have looked at translating
those ideas into
rates of convergence for different classification rules the problem with
this work that i'm listing here is that is primarily only of theoretical interest they
don't really drive prior estimation models
our classification rules rather well after was that simple tree
methods achieve the optimal rate in many cases and so
i know that a lot of learning theory is concerned so much with optimal rates
but when you look at rates of convergence it often can give you a lot
of insight as to why one method is working better than another and in particular
also one various found classification the weaker one
does not perform as well as the stronger one and we wouldn't really know that
in a nice mathematical way unless we look at these kinds of rates of convergence
so i'm going to focus on
the class of distributions of describe here
what do is the main assumption that all have been well described is that the
bayes decision boundary serenity dimensional feature space
and the boundary of the based decisions is a d minus one dimensional curve OK
so if you imagine it to be it's like a line or curve in
three d would be some sort of a two dimensional surface in three-dimensional space and
so on and so forth and one way to serve express that idea that the
bar three is most one-dimensional curve is to look at something called the box counting
and the that's going to mention is just simply say we divide the feature space
into lots of tiny boxes of the same size one over
m to the
and then you look at how many of those boxes
subject to constraints
what i discovery something almost
well magical which says that the recovery is actually completely exact
which is a bit surprising
and in fact it so exact that numerically exact because when i look at the
relative error that is the norm the the error between
the l two error between the original vector and the reconstruction is like something like
ten minus ten
tensor minus nine
six times ten to minus so it's
it seems to be
rather remarkable
this little experiment shows you that you can actually recovered
sparse solutions some underdetermined equations exactly if you don't have to
now of course we discussed another method at the beginning of this lecture which would
be to solve
xiao two problem
so i'm going to run exactly the same
code except there will be a crucial difference we're now going to minimize the l
two norm and now the l one norm
in this discrete so
the only difference was what you've seen
is that now instead of minimizing the l one norm of the unknown to minimize
the two norm and i'm going to run the same scripts
OK so let's do that
and now we get something has nothing to do is the true second just say
x equals zero just do as good as the other job
so what i see now is that while the original vector is in blue the
red factories in in red and they have very little income
OK so many many things in one norm works
minimizes the l two norm doesn't change
now i can
change the matrices are for example you going instead of having a matrix which i
did using gauss entries random problem i can make a matrix with plus and minus
one entries for example selected at random and that's what this piece of code does
someone to generate another problems with
we use
plus and minus one entries in the matrix i'm still going to have a sparse
right hand side
and i'm going to solve and one
OK thanks again it's exact so i can take out matrices i can take binary
matrices and when i saw this
minimisation problem it seems that in one gives me the right answer
that kind of stuff that is even more fancy
i can actually and this is extremely connected to what we'll see
in a minute
i can have very few measurements so sixty four measurements about effective dimension five twelve
and now
maybe i'm not going to explain the code but basically what i'm going to show
you i suggest very few fourier coefficients of
and how many for each coefficient i'm going to show you
about sixty four thirty two complex coefficients
and we're going to have
a vector which has thirty two nonzero components and now instead of making random matrices
showing you for you
coefficients of the vector x
OK now i'm gonna again have to solve this underdetermined system of equations which i
do by minimizing the l one norm subject to x equals b of course
so this is running
and again
it's always exact so we've seen a lot of different types of matrices we have
underdetermined system of equations the right hand side is sparse and want to minimize the
one norm there's this kind of a miracle that occurs which i always seem to
get the exact solution with no water whatsoever
the question
there's no was the beautiful thing about this saying is that i don't need to
know is it
as the number of nonzero coefficients
i just to minimize in one norm subjective data
there's no
our call information i need access to to be able to solve this problem
the method does not need any kind of side information that i do not have
i just minimize one norm subject equals b
now you pointing out in very interesting direction at some point this will have to
and that's the topic of this lecture
any other questions
he two
all right so
OK so the agenda for this kind of tutorial it is quite simple
i want to show you first because i think it's the tutorial so i think
it's important to give credits to people
and so i would like to start the first half hour forty five minutes discussing
a little bit the history of l one minimisation and discuss some of the early
in the second part of the tutorial will discuss compressed sensing that it relies enormously
on our ability to solve anyone's problems and the third party it would be much
more statistical in nature since we'll talk about sparse signal recovery from noisy data
OK but in the first part of the talk i want to show you some
i want explain some of the history
and explain some of the early use
of the one norm
OK so to to my knowledge is the first time in one minimisation has been
used systematically
besides the plus
i was in reflection seismology
and so
i'm going to give you a little sketch of what people do in reflection seismology
and show you how the
the l one norm comes up
so as you know many people on earth are interested in knowing what it is
on the ground
especially if your accent you would like to know whether wonders
gulf of mexico the underwater there's oil or not
and the way we do this to kind of in fear what is the composition
of the upper crust we come people conduct what they call it
seismic experiment
we're basically the idea is very simple
you have both floating on the sea
you can do this earth by the way and so of course it on this
is so
you have water underneath the bows maybe hassan maybe have fallen and so on and
so forth
all right and you are floating on the sea and you'd like to know
let's be nice book
and the way you do this
is basically going to create you're going to propagate a sound wave
through the years
right so you can make an explosion which here is pictorially represented by big hammer
so you hit hits the surface of the sea
typically what you do is you have explosions
the surface of the sea
and then use anderson waiver pressure waves propagating down the years
now the areas
is made of different stuff
so you have water that has a certain speed of propagation
which is indicated by this profile that you see on the right
then you have sand which has the difference is speed of propagation then maybe you
have oil which has a different speed of propagation and so on and so forth
some really
schematically representing what happens but essentially you're sending your son your pressure wave and it's
it again
and even the alignment we can compute a score
so this is actually this is what i meant for which we cannot use them
but there was
ban showed or
you can actually
exponentiated score
the sum of all possible alignments
and this is actually going to be
OK so i
i think i'm going to give one part is on remote homology and you find
it just like
this is an application of the school
and i would that
OK so let's summarize
can we extend to non linear decision boundary while keeping keeping the simplicity of the
classification one linear separation
so good kernel design is important for every single data analysis time when you get
some new dataset you really have to think through what i'm going to get going
to use they maybe on knowledge which
the string kernels perform computations in very high dimensional feature space is usually like
the size of to the power of ten y i mean depending on how many
along the motor armature considering and this can be based on substrings like
we can all they can be based on probabilistic models
or can be derived from some similarity measure
so i didn't mention kernel on top down which
on images and i'm which sure can have a look at shop lived there
machine learning summer school oil on bioinformatics and he talk more about
application of course if you know course probably on come about
OK i think this is for
i think
so what i would continue
talking about
large scale
OK that's thing
i don't really understand why a kernel based on graphical model cannot be
in the graphical model
why cannot be
this would mean that features which extracting doesn't
contains the information necessary for discrimination
so and you can show that this actually that
whenever you have the label of the latent variable in your perfect world for the
model and extracting features from this is actually
going to give you even
asymptotically without i mean OK so it has some results from google to that
and they have shown that
many extract features in that way
sixty one extension of the project and about one extension of whatever is very similar
many expected then the rate of convergence for the best classifier which you generate based
on the features
it's actually better than b
the maximum likelihood estimate the tube and they do on you know when you read
the model the country the paper
can you say a few words about
i mean so i thought maybe but talked a little bit about maybe it
so this is one kind of what very
so i mean you some hard to work on the
OK i guess you don't have to wait so usually kind of work on the
so at least but because are not
too many then and what you so but there are other approaches
you might to extract features like certain point of interest then you might combine these
points in it
the actually on
it's start about to talk about large scale data structures
so we had a spectral colours are not quite a bit so the problem is
how can be efficiently computed the spectrum kernel in general
so the problem is that the dimensionality of the feature space is exponential
we talked about some ideas and
trying to
so what i talked about already what thing were all to compute the new kernel
i mean a single element
so we just need to look maybe all came in which sequences he which appear
in both
so this has some general formulation which is called sort list approach language
so first of all
so we have to compute a the single kind commentations as fast as possible
but often we are only interested in computing a single kernel but we have to
compute a whole bunch of
i mean went the falconer metric and other ways of computing the more efficiently than
just competing every single element
and what you are the open to do it using a linear combination
so went the decision boundary actually looking like this is a linear combination of different
and if you would like to apply the SVM classifier
new test data set
then you compute quite a few of the elements
the first you are going to
start disagreeing but match
two the millimetre and
mismatching disagree
how long will how lonely to these be i'm gonna shout out i'm going to
say a change
these are be change
a state is OK so let's see how this goes remember to the millimeter when
you matching also doesn't work OK start
matching and green
so many
i have
you can UK should go
now i mean your your from west live in your experience in slovenia has been
very positive
five first
and i think we can we can learn a lot from
from the slovenian you think it's people so for the other countries as well i
think i
sounds crazy
i don't understand which
i have exact
exactly when i came
two play
i have actually
you know it's crazy
dogs must be there must be a lot mostly along
OK maybe
carry on agreeing mismatch
you they travel along
they they agree agree agree they agree that
the euro begin
politicians agreed to another
it's crazy i don't know why would don't think we should agree should change
the pressures
we should change the show which changes as the question no question UK should junior
start disagreeing but match a to the millimetre
i'm not sure that must
i'm not sure the UK should join
but in the end
current it's an economic crisis is this a good time
to be changed shortly stability
it is important
but maybe in the future but let's get past the next two years
you need to do anything
but they changed
the crisis
i i understand what you say i hate i'm just concerned
let's wait for one or two years
come out of the
the current crisis and then sure you i agree i think you know in the
let's look at this
politicians are generally
i agree
some of them agree with
well i think most of them agree with me
not the right time
yes they are always
always always pressures from
i disagree
the pressures from europe but who cares
there are always there always pressures always pressure
you know and
it doesn't mean we should do it
and just because
you in slovenia just because it with you doesn't mean it's going to work
we should join
it's not it's not is not a reason
to join the u
i don't know how to priority
why why would we
we're not the same
what different
do we want more tourists
i'm not sure
OK thank you
OK let's stop there
this stuff
always take to thank you very much
i want to get some feedback
let's go through these fall
faces what i'm interested in
is how it felt to you
so let's start with face number one you are both agreeing you're both matching each
how did that feel
so want to say is that it's it's like it's comfortable but is on the
verge of boron
two sweet
sweet it's everywhere
always is the number one
disagreed mismatch in four
is there any point in continuing the conversation
there's no point
you're not going to change i'm going to change with it's obvious
let's just stop
the conversation what i'm interested in is number two and number three
so number two
you were agreeing
but you were mismatching how did that feel
not comfortable
didn't feel honest
and even if this funny even though
the person is agreeing
the very much for inviting me to to be here BBCI
excited to finally see their magical bmvc and thank you for waking up early so
planned right ahead because yes i have lots of lots of stuff to talk about
some of some some new
so what i'm interested in
four today is to look at a single image
two indices see
if you if we restrict ourselves to a single sample in space and time what
is all the information that we are able to squeeze out from that one image
and of course we humans are able to do a lot from a single image
given a seen something like this we can say that meeting amount we can give
an amazing amount of information about the see for example we can not only say
detector you know the cars in the pedestrians like every you know all the algorithms
can do a different objects within the scene but it can also reason about the
major services on the scene where the ground plane where are the other major surfaces
we can talk about what things are walkable and what are not walkable where you
can go to and where you're going to like it to hit the wall we
can talk about that
the composition of the camera maybe the height of the camera that's taking this picture
we can even say something about maybe the weather and lighting candles illumination conditions within
the scene and we can even perhaps a which which country this this picture was
taken in and maybe even which city
OK so we were able to provide a whole story just given a single image
like this
of course now imagine if you are a typical object detector know your life is
pretty miserable you're looking at the world through this little peopole sliding people
and what you're seeing is not as beautiful panorama using something like this
this is what a sliding detect a sliding window detector sees in his little miserable
life and of course no no no no there's is no reason why
it should produce good results because given this
it's really trying the best it can and it is for it can find a
few of the pedestrians for example here's a pedestrian detector and but of course is
going to miss a few and more so embarrassingly it's gonna have rather rather strange
false positives here right for example here on the top of the lamppost but you
before you go and blame the object detector
i have to say that it's really not the detectors for
it's really the fact that it's too local it's looking at this too small of
over patch and not really seeing the big picture and to demonstrate this here is
some example for your visual system so is here is a very nice early impressionist
painting money paying in mostly that's a
this this this really
wonderful way to represent the
trains the train station turn-of-the-century train station you can feel the hustle and bustle and
you know the noise and everything and then you have you have the the cloud
of steam in the centre and then money which this had the steam engine right
in the center it's coming right at you it's just coming up advancing get to
really very powerful
the painting but let's look at the steam engine more closely look at this thing
this this the splash paint that that really looks more like a penguin or or
or of phase where the steam engine go
because it's not here the pixels it somewhere else
and the the somewhere else is well partially it's is in the whole scene
in in the connection between the different elements of the scene and partly it's really
inside your head and and i'm sure that h one of you might have a
slightly different so be it seems like a different version of the steam engine perhaps
connected to
particular steam engine museum you went to a child OK so
the point is that that
the pixels inside don't really tell you the whole story there is that extra world
outside of it that the influences your your perception of course at this point somebody
should stop me and say that this is this is not fair this is a
cheating example because after all this is i think this is impressionism this is exactly
designed to evoke an impression in viewers
but unfortunately the same thing happens in normal image and video data here's is an
example of
world cup football world cup of few years back to this is germany versus the
united states can to tell me something about this guy in the red box what's
his posts anyone can tell me the pose of the
of that
how we see standing
all right
right before left yes
he's looking
how his looking
it's kind of taking you know he's looking backwards cubic perhaps taking this american fellow
there are his the german body there is yes small big broad-shouldered man
well it some people say oh yeah he's a big guy he's tired i gave
this talk in germany and some some guys yeah i know this is placed so
and so the this the that has no head
he has no arms either
and his legs are massive pixels
so clearly something is going on that is not explained by the
the pixels of that little box
extra to this this box is is happening and and we are not really quite
sure what
but what it seems like is that it's the
considering the ceiling as a whole
is what's needed if we really to understand understand this this this image so
excuse me my plan but really what we need to do is think outside of
the bounding box
to be able to really
i do see and understand
OK and
worse than that not only do we need to reason globally about the image but
actually we need to reason globally about the underlying three d scene because of course
relationships within the image are not the same as relationship within the scene for example
these two red dots here they are very close in pixel space and they are
also very close and in three d space but these blue dots they're equally close
in pixel space but there are very very far away in seems OK so we
you can just talk about the two d image plane would have to deal with
with the three d work right because the problem is that
this is but a shadow of what is really happening right so we have the
imaging process you know your camera any painting your retina they always basically the same
thing i do have a beautiful three world on the left and then you you
projected onto a two d plane on the right and just obliterating whole entire dimension
it's gone it's it's it's it's lost forever right and then you just have to
go do that just after you have that that to as the computer to basically
the today biology has become a science over the last fifty years
and as a consequence we can talk about some basic principles we can talk about
some laws and then begin to apply them to very interesting biological problems and so
are general strategy
this semester as it has been in the past
is to spend roughly the first half the semester talking about the basic laws and
rules that govern all forms of bile biological life
on on this planet
and then the second half of the semester to begin to apply what we learned
in the first half to specific kinds of problems
and you can see some of the the specific kinds of problems including
the problem of cancer how cancer cells begin to grow abnormally
other viruses proliferate how the immune system functions of the nervous system functions are stem
cells and how they work and their impact on modern biology
molecular medicine
and finally perhaps the future of biology and even certain aspects of evolution
the fact of the matter is that we now understand lots of these things in
ways that were inconceivable fifty years ago
and now we can begin to talk about things the fifty years ago
people could not have dreamt of when i took this course and i did take
it in
in nineteen sixty one
we didn't know about eighty percent of what we now know
you can say that about mechanics about in physics you can say that about a
circuit theory in electronics and you can see that obviously about chemistry and i'm mentioning
that to you
simply because
in this field has changed enormously over the ensuing four decades i will tell you
what a great i got seven one because if i were you might try it
out to me later in the semester you probably would never show up again lecture
but in any case
please no
that this has been an area of enormous ferment and the reason it's been in
such enormous ferment is
of the discovery in nineteen fifty three by watson and crick of the structure of
the DNA double helix last year i said that we're so close to this discovery
for both watson and crick are alive and with us in metabolic lee active
and more than fifty years well exactly fifty years after the discovery
sadly several months ago
one of the two characters francis crick died well into his eighties and so he's
no longer with us
but i want to impress on you the notion that two hundred years from now
we will talk about watson and crick
the same way that people talk about isaac newton in terms of physics
that will be so because we are only beginning to to perceive the ramifications
all this enormous revolution that was triggered by their discovery that is the field of
molecular biology and genetics and biochemistry which is totally changed our perceptions of all life
on earth is actually organised
much of the boundary to which you may have been exposed until now
has been highly descriptive science that is
you may have had courses in high school where you had to memorize the names
of different organisms we had to understand how evolutionary phylogenies organised you had to name
learn the names of different organelles
and the biology falls for you in a field of memorization
in one point we would like hopefully successfully to drive home this semester is the
notion that biology has now
it achieved a logical and and rational coherence that allows us to articulate the whole
set of rules
then explain how all life forms on this planet are organised it's no longer just
a collection of jumbled facts
indeed if one masters these molecular and genetic principles one can understand in principle
a large number of
processes that exist in the biosphere
and begin to apply one's molecular biology to solve new problems
in this in this arena
one of the important ideas that will refer to repeatedly this semester is the fact
that many of the biological attributes that we possess now
we're already developed a very long time ago early in the inception of life on
this planet so if we look at the history of of earth here history versus
is given as five billion years
this is a thousand obviously
the earth is probably not that old is probably four four four four three billion
years but anyhow
that's when the planet first aggregated as far as we know
one believes that no other life existed for perhaps the first half billion years but
after half a billion years which is a lot of time to be sure there
are really begins to be traces of life forms on the surface of this planet
and that itself is an extraordinary testimonial we don't know testimonial to how evolutionary processes
occurring we don't know how many planets there are in the universe were similar things
and we don't know whether the solutions that were arrived at by other life systems
and other places in the universe which we may or may not ever discovered with
the similar solutions to the ones that have been arrived at here
it's clear for example that to the extent that darwinian evolution governance
the development of life forms on this planet that is not an artifact of the
or darwinian evolution is the logic which is applicable to all life forms in all
systems that may exist in the universe even the ones with not discovered
however there are specific solutions that were arrived at
during the development of life on earth
which may be killer
the structure of the DNA double helix the use of rivals and deoxy rivalries robots
you can calculate the frequency of one you know what the speed of sound is
three hundred forty
we take an equal one
so if frequency that we get
o three hundred forty
divided by two l which is o point five
i mean
and so to give six hundred eighty
so to speak give you six hundred eighty hertz
but the second
monarch have two
double that
so we'll be thirteen hundred and sixty years and so on
now this
system which is close on both sides wouldn't be very good musical instruments because you
sound wouldn't come out
so what people do they make them all
sound cavity
it open on both sides
like this for instance
is open on both sides
and even though it may surprise you
if we put a little
speaker here
we can excite the columns even in his own consistent in a complete similar way
than we do it here it is closest
and we get exactly the same
series of frequencies that i put you on the record
there also musical instruments
which open on one side and close on the other
so this is called an open open systems
and this would be called closed open clarinet close
i can also get a series of resonance frequencies even though here
the series wouldn't be exactly like this it's a little different it doesn't matter now
different but it it a little different but you get again the whole series
all resonance frequencies
so again you see that if i make the system longer
i get lower frequencies
if i make the length
one meter
then i will get the frequency
which is about four times lower than the one that i have there
which is hundred seventy words
and the second harmonic within three hundred
forty years and so on
so when you see an organ
in the church you see all these organ pipes
different lengths the one ones very low tones and the short ones at the very
and that's the way that these
in summons work
i have here
wind organ which i have demonstrated you before it is open on both sides
and because is corrugated
a very special way
when i blow winds past this
it will
going to
residents that's to say
went here is like a spectrum of all possible frequencies
it's like the bow on the violin
and then it picks out the frequencies that like
however if i increase the speed of the wind
i can try to
forces into higher frequency
so at low wind speed i'm more likely to hit
the lower harmonics at high wind speeds i'm more likely to hit the
i harmonic this one is seventy five centimetres long
it's open open
if i were able
two hits the
first harmonic
that would be a frequency of about two hundred and
forty hertz
i may not be able to excite the lowest harmonics
the first harmonic but i'll try certainly the higher harmonics are very easy to excite
and i can make you even this and simultaneously
two more than one frequency
just like the violin string
when you strike it
and simultaneously oscillate
in a combination of these modes
but this world is around
first start low
this maybe two forty
dance definitely weihai hana i i
this is what is the lowest this is
first harmonic
we're not trying to do here that you
two simultaneously tool
if you play flute
you do the following make holes in here
you take your fingers of both holes
and the effective length of the fruit
this is not going hide
you put your finger on this one
and the effective length of the flu this longer load
you put your finger on both
the effective length of the flu this long
you get an even lower
i have you very special fruit
open on both sides
you see the two holes
well first close to two
this is the lowest frequency
he played flute
which implemented making in some and longer
well short
i have another example here of an instrument
it is
open here
here is clear
this is my version of the trombone
this thing here
so this is the system that is like this
but i can move this in
and so when i heard before
frequency would be high
this is directly related to the legs
of this trombone
and if you learn how to play you can try to play
thank you
i all around us
when you drive your car
you may have noticed that all of a sudden you some crazy rattle somewhere could
distance that this defines the angular diameter distance other cosmological observables include the volume how
the volume of the universe changes the age of the universe and any distances
depend uponH of Znow in terms ofthe evidence for dark energy thefirst
evidence for dark energy camefrom the luminosity distance redshift or Hubblediagram and I
show this graph in the first lecture this isa graph showing some random notation
related to supernova brightness as a function of the supernova redshift andthese low redshift
supernovafaint objects are there bright objects are down there andthis graph is normalized to
the best fit lambda CDM model so you can do the statistics
and convince yourselfthat the lambda CDM model is a reasonable fit to the observations and
you can also just look atlook at ityou don't have to do a fancy
statistical analysis to realize that the Einstein-de Sitter model the flat spatially flat
as suggested by the CMB matter dominated universe does not fit the data so this
can be expressed and is often expressed in terms of confidence contourssixty-seven percent
ninety percentninety-five percent in the omega lambda omega matter plane so it's
important to remember how this is constructed one finds a standard candle in this case
type one A supernovae you observe the magnitude in redshift of this standard candle then
so that's the observations the magnitude and the redshift then youassume a cosmological
model and on the basis of this cosmologi cosmological model compare the observations and the model
this in this graph this the particular cosmological model assumes that W is equal
to minus one so it is not allowed for W to be changing with redshift and it
also assumes priors on other cosmological parameters H nod omega things like that omega
baryon what have you and on the basis of that you can see that
the fit requires a cosmological constant that this is the best fit contour and if
you take the flat value as suggested by the CMB is suggests omega lambda
of point six point seven and omega matter of about point three so the fit
within the framework of this model requires a cosmoillogical constant and the value of the
energy density of the cosmoillogical constant is ten to the minus thirty grams per cubic
centimeter a remarkably small number that the fact that it should be that small in
non zero is remarkable and you can imagine that's it's ill it's illogical if you
compare it to a mass scale or a length scale you can write ten to the minus thirty
grams per cubic centimeter as ten to the minus four electron volts to the fourth power or
ten to the minus three centimeters to the minus four power so if this is a
fundamental constant in nature then it suggests that there is a fundamental energy scale of
ten to the minus four electron volts or its fundamental length scale of ten to
the minus three centimeters it's hard to imagine those being fundamental scales in nature you
can also express the cosmoillogical constant in terms of the way Einstein wrote it lambda which
is eight pi G times the energy density and in this case the mass scale is ten
to the minus thirty-three electron volts that doesn't sound like high-energy physics to me corresponding to
a length scale of ten to the twenty-nine centimeters so this is why I call it
of the current text mining techniques and the real natural language understanding what people in
already for quite some
so what
look at the
what kind
discussed so far
the sequences
these sequences classical technique this using markov models
we can all see themselves
and i think is in fact
graphical models
so then speak about the
but conditions in
two of graph structure just she sequence
of information
and in this
so are
i was thinking about directed graphical models
bayesian networks for instance but i speak about techniques of topics
i think topic
which become
also text mining
this information
and this
the techniques of probabilistic latent semantic
and it
i want to go to the future
research directions
so it's it's
i don't know the
classification techniques to
go first
they didn't not
consider the context
so the context independent
but there is
the techniques are
talking about like that
of course well all the ones that
there should be
context c
which means that we
before classification
that's the only
feature vector to object
that you want to classify
but it
in this classification also depends on the values of the feature vectors
we have a knowledge
about the relationship between classes which
model for instance sequences are graphical models
and so we get these examples hidden markov model
conditional fees
so what
well it's actually probabilistic finite state automaton with maybe i
we can look
some examples
sequential structure in the
which i want to discard
and an example could be a text
in the sequence legal case like example of it
you've served as in the case my description of the core of the names of
the victims
use of france
some sort of being useful sections of the church fine examples include
so what
not all of
when you can follow a different path c
course data
the let
i mentioned
why the we could be mentioned in the first instance so you could follow
well defined
this is
to write this document
the transitions from
state party
document to another
has some probability of transitioning from
so this is a probabilistic statement was to
problem is
you could just
final state of italy
and if
document complies with all these elements of the states it would be
case of you
because graph of the document
but since we have a transition probability
is a probabilistic model
we also interested
so the image is emissions of symbols alphabet
in this case my
strings character strings that so that the system complement of documents which belong to that
for instance to see the
and also these images
after probabilities which are not
a few missions
often but also here you've so if the problem is often
so i think
i think the joint distribution between the six random variables
is factorised
in this way
this is joint injury problems
the next year so that is the probability of x one
given up because the has parents
time the probability of x two given all of his parents but just XY
so from the next given all of his parents
so this is a picture that drawn this is the assumption
that i'm making and this is the structure of a computer program
the computer program has each of these
undefined constants which control the conditional distributions and our job is to fill in these
probability distribution so
all that's left to left right down model is the values the table everything else
has already been specified misspecified structure of office costs by running track which is we
select depends the values for these conditional probability tables which is equivalent to specifying these
assumptions so the graph tells factorizations
the parameters in the nodes
graph the details
which is a specific
memory is so this picture does not specify at all
a specific model specifies the hypothesis class set of all
we want to go through
fighters would instantiate that you get to this position
probabilistic model
so this is the hypothesis class and within we select anything want by setting is
so the key point about directed graphical models is missing edges imply conditional independence
so surrounded by the chain rule we can always write the full joint distribution has
i could always take any joint distribution without making any assumption about it and start
writing in this way
it is the probability that one times the probability of x two given x excellent
times extreme given everything that came before
export given everything can form
and what does that have to adapt those in any crosses all these things is
that makes collector picture
thanks for here
doesn't have anyone except x two is
so our assumption going on sale crossed x one x three and x six those
no longer parents before
so could missing edges
correspond to conditional independence assumptions are
the conditional independence assumption saying that the probability of something given
many things is the same as the probability that a given subset conditional independence and
that's exactly what we do
that we crossed the conditioning
so the DAG is telling us that each variable is conditionally independent of its non
descendants given its parents once you your parents then the conditional on the conditional distributions
completely specified
and removing an edge into i eliminates an argument from the right hand side
this is a very important factor directed graphical models
right to to before we we get start
this is called explaining away
and it addresses the confusion of what people have when they start thinking for the
first time
if you look at this
graph here
you might think to to yourself well
x and z are unrelated
because there's no in between
many parents so
this is no only thing but
because they share a common child when we condition on this child when user value
x and z become coupled
so x and z are marginally that's true
if you just generate samples from the family of distributions is a graph of marginal
links and they can themselves be type of the network so it sort of worth
realizing that there's a kind of hierarchical relationship that one the link layer
may actually itself be network can consisting of multiple links but from the point of
view of the level here is just a single link modem connection to some point
we can send a message of
what i want to do now is take you through we're going to switch gears
a little bit and talk about
so the next piece that i said that we needed to address which is this
issue router
so i said we're going to talk about forwarding
there were to talk about something else called routing so
is the process by which we build up
our boring
what i should here was i just sort of told you what the values that
you go in the forty tables should be
i didn't tell you how they are derived where they came from
so in this case the simple network is relatively easy for us to
by hand sort of come up with a set of possible
four it has that seems reasonable but you can imagine that this thing if this
network it scaled up to a million nodes that's not something that we want any
individual they have to do
no person should have to configure all these routing tables
so instead of all these forty table so instead what going do
it is we're going use this process called routing in order to build these forwarding
tables automatically
and what we want we really want our routing protocol to be three things
first try to be scalable
and the obvious way in which you want to scale the way that just said
we don't want to have to have people
we want to this thing to scale up to say a million nodes are several
million nodes and be able to continue to work we shouldn't have to people sort
of involved with configuring building up these forwarding tables at every step of the way
we also wanted to be robust so by that i mean
it should be tolerant of false if a node fails in the network
network should eventually discovered that node has failed and be able to forward packets around
the failure to be able to compensate for the failure of it all possible
finally we want this routing protocol hopefully to be distributed
so we don't want to have to have one machine is responsible for setting up
to forty people and all the other machines don't have one machine that needs to
contact all of the other nodes and collect information about what all of the links
are an example of those links together into one global for scheme
and this really gets at the scalability again
what we're going to do what i do is to take you through the process
of routing before i do that i just want to do is take a quick
digression we're going to start off with a very tiny networks and this and just
talking about a very simple BBC network which is so you guys don't feel like
this is completely unrealistic i want to show you that in fact the internet somewhere
at some level started out like this too
we're going to do in the course this class sort of build up from these
very simple networks maybe look the way the internet the first two schemes that are
more like what is actually used in today's production
one back on you guys
OK so this is a picture of what the internet looked like in nineteen sixty
nine so
you may not be able to read the labels on these things but there are
these there are with looking at three notes here this is UC santa barbara
on the coast of california
a sort of central california are southern and central california this is stanford research institute
as our i
which is the variable
this is utah
and this is UCLA so this was this was this are which was the precursor
to the internet the sort of the very one of the very first of these
and that can be high school
and then we take the rest of the thing going to look at some point
and so on
so this produce was born i
because we think that one
we know that this sequence of high
has some one because the focal length of the biggest one
that is called the stick breaking construction
and basically
it's a very direct construction of this
probability measure g
i would say that
the corresponding to each
i a we draw the corresponding to sparky from a base distribution
sample of
some examples of the
draws of high
so the height corresponds to i one i two i three
and this is the value of y
so this is
as free independent samples from
from the stick breaking construction
i i notice that
they need may not be
strictly decreasing
but generally
beyond the value of pi very small
most of the non-fatal values of i think
the first thing the
o thing with
i guess i didn't show that you could actually about what nations of the dirichlet
process and get from that the stick breaking construction
and what the romans show in nineteen ninety four is that bad
bankers but from the stick breaking construction
and you can prove that the random probability measure which is constructed satisfies all the
properties of the dirichlet process which means that that is the
this very constructive
of the existence of this process
so we have
three different representations of dirichlet processes as well as the iteration process
so there
the chinese restaurant process and then the construction
so all this actually
if you have a different understanding of what is this object of dirichlet process
and in fact they only two different rhythms as well
any questions
i guess so and with the
the ways in which you could model data with dirichlet process
the first question
could deal with it
the question that the estimation recall that in the case of that the estimation what
we did was what i think we do is the following
distribution g
random distribution g from the prior
which is given by dirichlet process
and we see that are actors drawn from g
the idea
that doesn't work
do people know why
only on
anyway actually can probably be
the problem is that since we saw that
draws from a dirichlet process a discrete distribution
and this despite distributions both actually happened and so we can only do depth estimation
if we use the model that
so the solution is simply to take our
and convolved with a small
in this case
the coverage is simply with a GMM we
integrate the act of
they is the distribution on axis
which is a small distribution parameterized by theta
we simply integrate with respect to g
and they
and that
you have more than of x would be more than one
and we use that our
i thought
as the construction of the density of our dispute
that underlies the act and this thing has
and so that the
she has this
representation at the bottom of the ocean
we know that acts it's all basically it's the mixture
as of the date first
where the mixing proportions i given by higher
coming back to this
this is the bigger the actual you know where this other random draws from
i was
prior over the density
in this case we use a
so the with the mean
basically with given mean and covariance
well base distribution is out in the which
and you get prior
u and sigma
not so on
from basically
and we
pick a random height uniformly filled with sampling points underneath the screen somewhere
now what we're doing is with some points uniformly and the green curve if we
toss out full ones that aren't underneath the blue curve then will just be left
with samples drawn uniformly from the because the algorithm is a sample of the public
rejected draw sample is underneath the we keep it and we have a sample
this is this is pretty general the only technical requirement is that
you need to be able to bound
this function because you need to build construct this thing will be above it everywhere
the problem with really is it seems a bit wasteful because you do all this
computation and then if you have a rejection you just sort of straight away you
get nothing from it and potentially you can spend most of your computer time just
sort of
computing these functions and then doing nothing with the computation answering
so this the trick that means that you never have to reject samples if you
if you're in regime where you can't draw samples from the distribution you want to
but you can draw from some of the distribution
important something is the trick that allows you to just sample from the distribution you
actually want to instead
you have an integral to solve this is what we want to estimate and we
multiply by q which is the distribution we can sample from and we divide like
you say this is just multiplying by one as long as we never divide by
and so this is an identity
and now this is just an integral which is an expectation on the key and
the function of the whole object here
so now we just apply simple monte carlo we sample from here and we evaluate
the rest of the underground
and what's nice about this trick is actually
you're integral to need to be an expectation in the first place you'll notice here
that nothing about this relied on
p hitting distribution i think FP together being integral into ground that just sticks together
you can do that with any underground wouldn't have to be an expectation
so that's the that's a great question how do you choose q say i've said
you can choose any q like one that you can draw a sample from the
song as we don't divide by zero so the technical requirement but
it's probably clear that some cues are gonna work much better than others and so
the sort of the question of why and how we might say
i mean
if we had an input space and
this was that true distribution
and you know we're interested in the average of some function which run
run through the space is well then clearly
if we pick the distribution had most of its mass over here then sample theta
here i'm going to tell us much about the expectation of this function under the
say were going to want to distribution that has mass in much the same place
something else you want to really avoid is
making q small when p is big say for example imagine what a variational if
you know about variational approximations what they would do is
find mode seeking to that defended against an approximation to this
under some cost function i would physicality and around the tightest made
now that means and very rarely gonna get samples over here
so now if i do
very occasionally you'll get sample here
and now evaluate the importance of the sample
an important if p and q
OK so now in the tail of the gas in q is
really small
and p is quite big and the importance of the sample ends up being
absolutely enormous and so that means that in this empirical from my sample
maybe one of the terms will be hugely bigger than any the others infected drawn
one sample
say what you want to do is constructed distribution
roughly covers the distribution and make sure that it never really small where there is
appreciable amounts of mass it's fine to have
UK distribution have to tell whether a name as because you're just occasionally get sample
out there and give it no weight and
the wasted do that but nothing blows up
so the question is in rejection sampling we sample from the song distribution and sometimes
you say
o we sample here too often because our q is a key compared to piece
all thrown out and here we just after rejecting because we downweighting the bit but
it looks much the same and
it's just slightly more efficient in that it soft so if we are not interested
in the samples themselves were interested enough expectation then
its lower variance too
attach real numbers every single sample you've got to make a hard decision if i'm
going to wait the sample by zero one so if you compute the variance of
the estimator this turns out to be more efficient
the new these
there's a huge huge huge
which is what we call
so if we can bound the function so the biggest thing and we know
the extent of it we could just have a top hat like that if
if p with something like calcium as infinite
the uniform distribution would have to go out and then it would be improper we
can touch actually sample from that the right if the distribution has compact support then
you know maybe from distribution would find it depends on the problem sometimes you have
clever tricks way you know really tight bounds of the function in some places and
they're also adaptive rejection sampling algorithms that sort of conforms
a really good approximation for you on the fly
on the previous slide i assume that we could evaluate both p and q
and that's not actually always true say
I could see what was the best way
so the question is how to find these images and I cannot puzzled about that
for quite a while
and then as a colander holiday do it I I solve Lord of the pattern
and I saw the connection between these
equation these equations with matrices carotene
and these equations with these differential equations that we looked at in a later lecture
so the differential equations the differential equation that we looked at was
what's the connection of minus so was the connection between the differential equation the left
side and these matrices
but see these matrices are in words what what kind of matrices are we seeing
what we're seeing a typical role of these matrices minus 1 to n minus 1
and yeah and what that those 3 numbers for jumps to mind when I see
those 3 numbers
it's a 2nd difference
where here we have a 2nd derivatives
and we have a minus sign actually
a minus sign here to the the true 2nd difference would be 1 minus 2
1 and we've strikes which those OK now
what that I had several of wasted to approach the inverse solutions because the question
of the universe
and so let me that really take easier 1 1st
it to say how did we get to the inverse of that
and and the way
a good way to get to the inverse of that is starting with the of
course we gotta get there course every we can check it that works but that
doesn't seem quite fair so
let me
I take that matrix
and factory
remember how it factors so so of the concentrate T for just a minute to
give a direct way to deal with the effect to be slightly repetitions that that
matrix T
factored into
like all all good matrices factored into
upper trying here we did elimination
we ended up with some upper triangular you and the lowered it turned out to
be you transpose you it turned out to be
I don't know if it's best to look at them again
you transpose you will you ones on the diagonal pivotal all turned out to be
ones and minus ones just above
and then it's transposes ones on the diagonal and minus 1 is just below
if I multiply those matrices
I guess
the alright
so that the idea was OK maybe we can invert those pieces
and we can
so let's now we're now so that was T then the inverse was
the inverse of you
times the inverse of you transport
and so if I now want to invert this guy and put it here
0 my god
what's the
what's the inverse of this 1
let me make it be fill out it's
I want there's you
so I wanna put its inverse comes 1st
so what we've done this before but do you remember what the inverse look like
0 I have here a trying upper triangular matrix
so what can you tell me about its inverse
upper triangular
this is the difference matrix and its inverse will just be some matrix
this is what turned out to be the inverse
and then there's inverse of that was there transpose so it's now
some now
so that that's all quite
quick to check
I mean
even more quickly here but it would be quick to check and that gives us
our answer right what I take it if I do the multiplication of find the
I just gotta multiply those guys OK I get from that is that a good
and that times the next 1 gives me 3 1 produces the 3 then the
than the 1 that road times that column will be the 3 here I get
this formula
no problem with the
so that's right
so I I guess I fill it with the we
could legitimately say yes we know only got the discovered the universe we
found system that produces
now I change over to
it was not so easy
this method
triangular factors but their inverses will take a little patience
not led to but they're quite quite attractive still but then multiplying the 2 factors
together takes even more pictures
so I would like to think of another way
to deal with inverse so this is really my principal job how to deal with
1 way would be the triangular factors invert them multiplied by
but to
somehow we're not wouldn't really see what was happening here OK so now
now so now I can decay
right now I have to
2 approaches decay
today was easy
so 1 approach
OK and they tell you 1 approach that
well that I'm that I'll describe a little bit but then it will be an
important step in the Kalman filtering updating least squares so it sort of links to
last topic on my
that this is this occurred to me on the airplane actually
what's the difference between well 1st of all let me that just look at the
figure out what the difference I to compare the inverses of T k
that if I compare
you don't have to let's suppose we do for simplicity
let's assume
that for each class separately
the distribution of images and blood factorizes so the independent so what that it says
it is practical the people who have cancer
then the variation in images amongst the cancer people in the variation in there
blood results are independent of each other and have a look at all the people
who are normal
they also have the same property the variation images the variation in blood tests are
independent of each other
obviously if i combine them together they're not going to be independent because
you know the the people have cancer will have certain kind of images kind of
blood test people at normal have different kind so the population in general they won't
be independent which is going to see the independent for each class separately so that's
our assumption
and that correspond to the slammer graphs says that
as we think of as in the generative model we say there is some probability
that you have cancer
described by this note if you have cancer
then there's some distribution of possible images that that's associated with you and the some
distribution of possible blood tests and equal if you don't have cancer this some different
distribution of images and of blood tests but each of those classes separately these are
independent so
as mentioned the separation yesterday if we look at the if you look at the
polls in this in this very simple graph those apart from this node up here
to this node on the path it goes through this node in this node is
what we call it tells tale note because the arrows pointing away from the node
and that node is observed so if that the d separation
grew slides even had yesterday this is no blocks that path causes these to be
independent if we don't observe this if this node is not shaded then the path
is not blocked and they're not independent
so this seems like a reasonable assumption
to make
and so
what we interested in then is the probability of cancer once you've observed the image
data and the blood data
and from bayes theorem we can write that is the prior probability times the likelihood
now we can use our assumption factorizations factorize this
and now if we multiply and divide by p of ck and then use bayes
theorem again the other way
what we have is is this so this is the proper posterior probability of cancer
given the image data that was one of the engines we built two years ago
now along came these new blood tests so we built a new engine
inference engine gives probability of cancer given the blood tests
and we can combine it with the
image data simply by multiplying the posterior probabilities and dividing by the priors
and of course that's a rather simple example of combining two modules together using probabilities
are sort of common currency of courses in the framework of graphical models we can
build much more complex models and build lots of different modules and combining together i
showed you
it's actually very complex example in the asthma
the study which was my first few graph today in fact
OK so lots of advantages too
to using probabilities
i think i move on to slightly different topic that any questions
band think we've covered so far but
it is
probably not
right OK so
dmitri there's two separate question the question what is your machine bridge causes real probabilities
in some sense what would you what would you do with the peaceful one thing
to say is that if you are going to associate
subscribe to feeds out of wiki like give me
all the papers written by a certain person certain topic areas and in the system
just i want my RSS reader to pick it up and really be informed and
the other stuff so we are right now britain and the active project on having
more export formats so i call was one of the new ones are created hours
as we also create weak another expert from this kind of data came out data
for geographical data so those are very specific export formats just showing that
we have to semantics in the background to understand what the pages are about you
can exported in the form today used by industry so that she was spread the
outset tools
so one of the nice things i hope i can show you that later on
semantic that there are are few
let's try this out right now
so this is an article about the park and i hope i will have access
one now this is the
events listed decide the upcoming events that next on the list of quasars in manchester
first during ESWC starting today with several supplements like this is the same as surgeons
on LDP's brain it's been two weeks than experts and so on so this is
directly big information
if you click here
you can subscribe to that i kind of feel
two years
outlook for example
another way to
half that
let's hope it loads
so what's happening here is actually that i have created google calendar it's taking the
i calendar information out of to be keep
and displaying the who can get which again i can integrate it in HTML page
well i have been so this is not the same information that we have to
just taking the i can export in this plane and the nice can
so we see the ESWC starting today is going to find
i get probably you knew that already
first a sorry
here we have yet invents direct thing the deadline several conferences so we have on
the content the
rules conference coming up
so this this one of those nice hx school calendar which is we just go
to the next month this information there and so on and so on
it was about
yes the semantic media wiki is pretty bad product right now
so one of their
goals we have set ourselves for active project but we don't promise anything this area
is that we are also able
to change information and to add information from an external source so week is much
much better about that we are
so OK
so we don't promise that but we hope to achieve that there are several problems
of them in the media wiki system
but we hope to somehow solve the problem is actually
this is a
well known
go one
if you have great ideas about it so everyone discuss much as because this is
one of the things we really have problems of solving it's the
the major problem is just to illustrate why we're not having this right now is
that in semantic media mediawiki
every annotation
it is based on the wiki text
and this human readable and you edit the wiki text and now have about this
and then you will uncover so that's good falls new it's very simple it can
extremely fast because you have the part of the fuzzy is no problem
the point is that the real problem with this with this same type of BBC
is the poets it's what's inside channel can cannot can make it out of the
reach detector
there's a number of children with this kind
flash flash ADC where in fact you put two
flash one for the which we take the most significant bit and the other one
which became the only thing you can then you have to make the grid so
have the typical performances four to ten bits can go up to one million out
you are using less because you have left left the number of combined actually less
than the previous and so you see for instance for fourth place for which would
be in a bit
you will have thirty comparators instead of two and five
but then were
you have to to treat you as you have some
some of the literature which are tricky to be done but that's not something which
is quite
often use them very often uses the pipeline ADC upipeline ADC is there's something which
collect and which is calculating when beta tells the story starts with this saying is
the signal in the first half of and also one half and then to use
the most significant bit and then use the talk
the services that you and you continued like that until the so so the point
is that you you have some time between the input and the availability of the
output which is
and time is a number of stage
you save a lot of people also settled in our local and you can still
be quite fast for instance you can get twenty to fourteen years for something like
two hundred one
it's quite
successive approximation and that's also something quite simple it's just that you
you you have you make delta converter on the new you just sweep this and
you just make some did that input to your that can you compare the output
of the input
and when it's equally says that's it you can get
resolution of the order of ten to twenty feet in in out conduction sometimes is
quite long for a very long
which is
already later concerns come back to that
and francis is of something
well something that
the thing is that you we have seen that we have this quantization their
when when we make an agency
and then if if you are indices is
it is somewhat similar to frequency of switches sampling we not
then the is useful frequency of the signal
then what you can do is is to destroy the american villages that so and
then there is no quantization noise will just use
quite a lot
because you will just take the partition the which is the fraction of you if
want to that over sampling ADC
which which would using the noise ratio again for and indeed the four and indeed
the if you sample you can increase the the signal to noise ratio
and that's the phi function of the sampling frequency with respect to you
because if continue interested in
and you see that for instance you could go from an eight bit ADC two
it would be reasonable sampling of two hundred and fifty so if you want to
know if you have an eight bit ADC which is able to learn at twenty
and you will get it will be that when you get it back to shifts
so that
that's a good thing in fact then based on that you've got to see that
the ABC so i'm not going to detail about what is important to know is
that with this kind of
then you can you very very good resolutions up to twenty four bits which is
immediately good but
the question
the of something which is quite high
so there are a number of formulas fuzzy dice
important thing for the ADC when you have something you else known is is the
shannon doing that you probably you know which is which says that
when you when you samples
this signal
you can see that can be removed
in an inner product
in the first of its input space in two dimensions
input space
with the
the scalar product of x
and ex-prime
and you just have to square
with the square of this quantity you get
scalar product
in the feature space
this is very nice
it means that
if i need
some projects
in the in the
i can use the competition not in this three-dimensional space but again the competition is
two two-dimensional
it could input space
just to give you some notation my powerpoint slides are
all slides that i've previously is changed so that only people point sources for air
so so it's not really nice but can get used see we
so that we have a continuum and that was
for the cat in
OK so now what you can say
it is only can we generalize this idea here and you can imagine that you
have some number
you can consider all the polynomial of the from the scalar product of x and
x y
the power of n
the game you will you will be able to compute
so by definition you will be able to compute the
it's kind of product not but move
in this case again
this competition will correspond to some function phi
the function phi fact maps into the space not sitting down to the space spanned
by the by all the products of the input direction so you are going to
use this idea and made yes but of all the
so this is a nice example of the transformation
but if you look at at
dimension of the space
in fact it's very large and if you consider that was input space you have
same dimension d
and end
is four
off you
if you come across
then you have to do the dimension of s goals as the
the core of and so it's is a we week
huge space we are using here
at the low cost because we're using
as this scalar product in fact it
the input space so this is a nice example
when you get it can
has a very complex there we
it also action which gives you a very nice representation of x that you have
not the complexity of computations
so we define space of higher dimension was the classification problem is easier so of
course what we want to know is what does the functions of value for x
x y that
verify the nice property
to be returned as inner products in some newer presentation space
because if we are able to deal with such function
then we will be able to compute inner product this
eventually huge
this is a huge feature space
we use some function
OK so here's the function
it was the function
was this character products causes the function in fact you can get
it is this kind of approach no looking going to look it was
the class of functions that low to have this kind of presentation
it's kind cool
so these functions are called positive this defeated candidates
and in fact semi definite positive comments but as i have
i noticed here usually people just forget this
so imagine you have a function k
cartesian product of x phi x
that go to air
this function is called the positive definite came in
there are there is the following property
four for any n stereo two zero
for any choice of objects x one to x n
in in
set x
and for any choice of real numbers
about the student using my university la sapienza OK this is the data about a
about the engineering courses in particular in
actually we have only fragments of the database and the
the database contains essentially the data of the students from a ninety to ninety eight
OK so you will not colonized student because we have anonymized
this unit u
you may recognise the name of some professor
but please forget them when you walk out of the k
OK so here you see there are a lot of relations OK
a lot of relation and let's look at the map is OK so first i
want to show
some easy mapping OK so let's look at the mapping for students
for students
OK so this is the mapping for student you see
you see here
what i'm doing
i have
a in this case we give people OK is simply says take the identifier from
these relation over here
OK and this state
is the concepts you ontology OK the consisted ontology and the
you see that we use this should be
OK so this is really divide OK after existing
it we get out of the people carry
and we use it
to generate a new object OK this call
students all over that article about
that particular what this is about the way then a this term is completely out
OK we don't kill
OK so this is just
object identifier
of the particular student in the relational database of cases they objectify using the ontology
for that particular
for for the student in this in this in this table
OK so
this is a very nice marking OK so one relation with just one people to
we put it in a way we use it to generate object in the in
the student
concept of class about all these things are not so nice so we always so
let me look at the
OK so
this is the same shape OK located is really
over the database OK it's clear the database we extracted one of the activity particularly
the code
OK we use
the code to generate
the upset of for professional OK this is the output of the corresponding to be
OK by the way at the same time
i'm also
and also
put in some instances in the end of
a property
OK that i can capture from this
from this quickly now i want you to look at this is quickly
OK so this is a very nasty
it's quite quickly
OK if he and
in this database this is an operational database we recognise a professional has the been
because it is this field
put that now
OK so that it is now
they used to be
so you can make sense out of this thing you have to talk with people
that database to understand how you
you might be OK this is always like that
that databases that in operation OK so these are not you know in are not
nine databases for doing ontologies area databases and activities that ability since the seventies OK
in in the years stratification of the open and this is really about
by the way notice also that they need a regular expression over a stream
i understand
these guys in the
a is the dean of loss of yeah OK i have to look at this
OK inside this thing to notice so this is very nasty
OK so now let's look at the face of
so we get profits
we get professor at the same time we get also
from what you want to actually we are interested only in those profits colours are
being so we essentially take this perfection out of a these people are professional here
so let me let me see also assistant a assistant professor
he is the assistant associate professor
as a professional actor in another table OK after this is a different database OK
these are only professor
a professor by the way
we don't have all information in particular we don't even know
o what a what university OK although most of them will be of so is
so you see now
that i'm using
OK by the way i know that this professor not decided so i can use
i can generate object in an easy way
OK for both of them so for this guy i think the cold
out of the stable for this guy technical about of these other people OK
offaly this should work and now let me see state
i mean
i think it's by some provinces
yeah this one
so this is
this this property over here
so the students
it's been advised for the graduation essentially got students what is being advised for by
the professional game
and actually i do we get this pervasive is professor called when i actually get
the professor got from the face OK and i have to
you see this we again is nasty because in the table advice so i don't
have to call it but i was so i have a it with degree in
which i don't have to call the face of the they just the first name
last name so i made up the code on the fly
OK and by the way i can think this professor out of
their professional debut all the perfect so that they so these are the assistant professors
so i see i have a union of two conjunctive queries over here
OK so let me show these are the ones and this is the last one
they are good enough OK