to the thirty second different patterns available to me to map to whatever subset of
the full integer range i want the easiest thing to do is just go from
to the negative thirty first feature the positive thirty first minus one
OK zero in the middle that's why breaks it symmetrical a little bit
when i go
concern myself with floats idea probably more used to doubles but this just a small
small version of doubles
i have
four bytes available to me to represent
floating point numbers integers with that small part following anyway i want to do this
is way really works for me just invent an idea here
pretend this is how it works
but i strongly boxes yet
i could do
let's say i have assigned it all represent that appears cluster minus
and if i have thirty two bits you by default
think about being some contribution to the thirtieth two the twenty nine ground career contribution
of two to zero and is describing all the things that can adopt zeros or
ones to represent some numbers
OK but i want to close to be able to have fractional parts to be
moving the fractional direction and so you know what what my sacrifice
to the thirtieth
and like the one that actually the contribution of the negative first
i'm just making this up i wanna make it up opposite the weight of the
last seven times topics but i'm moving table will really be the that the representation
for floating point numbers
if i happen to have thirty two bits right here
i lay down this right here
that's not the number seven hundred number number number fifteen anymore now it's number seven
point five
so it makes sense
OK well thought-out very useful if now all you have are integers and half integers
so what i'm going to do
as i'm going to stop trying things about that britain was just assume that rather
than the last bit being contrary into the negative first let me let that be
a contribution to the first and that that the convolution of two the negative two
so now i can go down quarter fractions
does that make sense
what i could do
as i could make this right here because two zero
the negative ones
two the negative two three four five six seven eight
two the ninety nine
and if i wanted to represent
i'm not going to run works on the shoulders of another this part would be
then i would use the remaining
nine bits that are available to me
OK to do a good job using two contributions to the negative first into thirty
two seventh to close as possible to point one four one five whatever is
make sense of
it is actually point to remember that because using a finite amount of memory you're
not going to do a proper job
cut representing all numbers in the infinite and infinitely dense
the real number domain
but you just assume that there is enough bits dedicated to fractional parts that you
can come close enough well without not really impacting we're trying to do
OK i put up four at some places are something that just looks like a
OK that makes sense
it turns out if i do it that way in addition
works fine so i had two point five contributions in ripples to give me a
one night carrier one it just works exactly the same way
that make sense
OK it turns out that this is not the way it represented but it is
technically original way to do it and when they came up with the standard for
representing forty four numbers they could have gone this way they just elected not to
so what do now is going to show you what it really does look like
it's very weird thing whenever they can interpret the thirty two bit pattern anyway they
want to as long as the protocols clearance done exactly the same way every single
so could i attended a draw figure
and leave it
organiser for rectangle
because i'm not subdivided by perfectly
i'm going to make this
assigned i you want to represent
i want negative numbers and positive numbers are floating point to have an equal shot
of being represented kind
that's one of the thirty two bits
to make sense
the next
eight that's
are actually taken to be a magnitude
i said that we should discard an unsigned integer
from here
and the remaining
unfortunately it really doesn't work unless
the images
very simple so for example in this image
you have these sort of two
triangles and upper triangle lower triangle well separated by boundary except for this weakness and
weakness is sufficient to
because a garbage result from from region growing likewise if you have a black circle
like background
you can get fine segmentation with region growing but once you add noise
you're in all sorts of problems even small amount
more recently the graph cuts approach has been developed for seeded segmentation
it's great it's fast has a probabilistic interpretation
but there are some problems with the for for example
the goal of graph cuts is to find the minimum boundary
so for example with the same
image so we looked at what the
upper triangle the lower triangle
if you just input a small number of seats the minimum boundary separating blue from
green or blue from red is just this little
boundary surrounding the blue c
if you have enough
seeds in order to
such that the surface area exceeds this weakness
you can
actually recover the weak boundary but
when you have four connected lattice
in particular you get these
these metrication artifacts reason being that the cut going
down over is the same as going over down
or even going down diagonally
and for connected graph
this problem can be improved by adding more edges but that increases the complexity in
the memory
additionally with graph cuts you are somewhat limited to two labels you can have more
labels but
your ability to get an exact solution is erased when you have more than two
so it it's
into this gap that i introduced this random walker idea
the idea was basically two
capture the good properties of graph cuts segmentation algorithm overcoming these difficulties
and now i'm going to go through it in detail starting with the the concept
so given
a set of seeds to indicate in this image of four objects green yellow red
and blue
the idea is
we could ask
and now we want to label every other pixel
we can ask so for this pixel we want label it with one of these
we could ask if we
release the random walker from this pixel
o to wander all of the image
with some probability will first arrived at green
some probability will first write yellow
and then if we knew the probabilities
we can assign this pixel to the colorful which is most likely to send random
the impact of the image in this case
is to affect the walk and tobias the walker to avoid crossing intensity gradients or
some kind of feature gradient
for those of you ruined by hollywood i put a little movie together
if you have a wide circle of black background and you put to sea to
blue and red one and you want to query this pixel
he released this particles in brownian motion or random walk
and you'll see that it may
come against the boundary the circle
i would be very unlikely to cross into it
therefore eventually annulled it may take a very long time this walkers almost certainly
going to arrive at red before arrives blue
consequently this pixel will be labelled red
you probably should have a feeling of this based on some of the other talks
that we've seen
but these probabilities can actually be computed analytically
with an deterministically without any
simulation of random walks any kind of money carling
so just so we're clear about what
the album is doing we input
image with seeds to indicate
we want for objects
green red yellow and blue
and then we would like to produce the labeling for every pixel
of one of those four types
so what we do is we compute the probability that each pixel
send the random walker green
first we compute the proper the
probability for each pixel at its centre and market red
first to yellow and then to blue and then we assign these labels based on
whether or not
we color the pixel with
whichever label it's most likely to send random walk
in practice it looks like this
a user would input an image
paint some seeds
and then in real time you can iteratively
calculate these probabilities
this is the real time
screen capture
and the
segmentation looks like this
which can be corrected by adding more seeds decide
that's the concept behind the organ but why random walks
what's the value
taking this approach over
some other method for assigning labels
and there are basically two
reasons one is we boundary detection and the other is noise robustness
so this
it's hard to see here what this is supposed to show
it is a solid
and a solid circle except for a gap here
is is missing
and what i was trying to show
it is if you were trying to label this pixel just on the other side
of the gap
new release the random walker there
even though
there's a gap in the
random walker
it is more likely to get inside the circle
here than without the gap
because of the motion of the random walk and the wiggling jiggling
of the walker
it's still
more likely to
arrive at the red sea than it is to get inside the circle to the
and so
with sampling so the idea is you always re-arranging variables so you only sample the
low dimensional variables
and then you integrate out
the other ones
in mapping that's what we do
we only sample the location of the robot
which is a six dimensions it's small thing
and then the map which is this humungous or one thousand dimensional variable
we integrate out analytically
so there's no error introduced
another application of this
was quite popular especially when as was an english strawberries
it was diagnosis where you have a continuous signal that describes how the
you know internal states of the robot
and then you have
discrete signals which indicate like my left we'll is broken miraculous programs that whatever
and then there's some
observations of the robot makes
like what it is with respect to this
in the morning
the type of models are what people will jump markov linear systems
well you have
a discrete distribution that tells you how the discrete states evolve over time
let me just actually retrieve that
so you have these continuous operations
you have
continuous internal states like your car you current voltages et cetera
which are the states x xt
which could be a very high dimensional vector
and then you have these discrete states like you know my my will was that
go on supporting evidence and so on
and the goal is to come up with an estimate of the discrete state
for example might try to diagnose with that i i have
hard problem or not
if i'm sitting on my if i'm just sitting here on my chair you looking
at the support
and my heart beating very fast
then i probably want to diagnose and i have a hard problem
if i happen to be catching waves there
and my heart is beating faster and you probably have from so knowing the in
terms of internal state
no internal state like the heartbeat that you're trying to estimate from whatever environmental variables
one predict and your chest helps to
come up with the discrete state which in this case is
yes i have a hard problem or no i don't
and so
that's how the system this model
and in fact the same is used here for slam
so you have these discrete states
that he it could be in a state and slums that actually happens to be
the location
x happens to be the man
and then you make observations
we have a switching space because what happens you have a linear system of linear
gaussians this system
but the matrix is that you have
the transition matrices
depends on the variables that she
it that is binary then you have two possible ways
and one day might mean that the players running for another a means that the
player running slow
and then you need to be able to estimate
x for both of those conditions
the matrix
the parameters are usually assumed to be known but there's sort of some ways some
e ways of estimating these
the naive algorithm would be to sample z
the sample x and then to use the likelihood of a given accents
first my part that not that the trivial particle filter
and that's really bad because
sampling from a very high dimensional space
and you get into trouble
what we try to do is exploit the conditional independencies that i mentioned before that
if you have access not and not
given the observations you can rewrite it
in this form can pull the conditioning arguement
and so on so that
given the set
and given the why it's possible to compute the y
so all you have to do is to estimate
p of z given one
in particular
how many of you have seen kalman filtering
so common fault is what you do in this model when everything is calcium
so common filters as an exact
numerical so the analytic solution
dynamic system when everything is gone
linear and gas
so in this case the reason why things are not linear because of that he
but if we knew zt
if you knew city then you would know a and c
and in your back to only having these two equations so you have a linear
constant system
so that's the trick
you condition on something that makes your problem simple
so if we exploit that fact then
this guy is nasty because we don't know the set but once you know this
that so if you have to compute that sample the sets from this distribution then
you would have observations and set and this we know how to compute analytically
it's just the kalman filter equations
and and that's pretty much what do we do monte carlo approximation of the z
and then we get the distribution of the axes
we know that again using margin condition marginalizations just this distribution and then we think
this multicolour system and replace it here
and we get
an estimate of the effects not to t which is an analytical
in this section mixture of gaussians
because bridge that you get different graphs
basically what our looks like this if you haven't seen coming of this approach is
very very scary
you say the labels and you give you a nice XML representation saying this website
is about ontologies it is about the semantic web it is about RDF knowledge representation
in artificial intelligence conferences and
well many of the things
this is
of what is important
but this is starting to be useful i mean there are
very nice applications you can show you already thinking of five or six application you
can already use can already built just using this simple URL into your javascript one
one application which is called semantic jornal which is a very simple thing whenever you
you writing an article for john all of blog anything you can add the semantic
search button
he's writing an article about
the art of war elephants and
and whenever he this is but then it sends a request to this API semantic
i can find the categories so here we get literature is the out of one
what are literature since two
if you don't get it
action i mean it
and from this category since it is what categories you can get into web directory
and find documents that would complement your article documents back and you can use as
reference or you can use to add additional information to write your article is overly
simple and i would bet the guy didn't take more than fifteen minutes to actually
write application
the second
sort of a like this i would like to show is open calais semantic proxy
it is one is very very famous and is the guy will be presented they
we don't say this is the semantic web
but we say
this is an overview of is is the a preview of what may look like
a few years using these services are very simple or
kind of name entity recognition service you give it the the URL of a web
and it is you
what sort of person there
what technology can recognise what event what cities places these companies
organisation even medical conditions
this one i run it bit before it is finally this wasn't supposed to happen
so basically if you go to you can see anything like if you could do
particular web page
here again i put the URL of
this is the web site of this tutorial rooms
and what i get is about
this is true it seems
it recognizes many people
can i join
five are shown here
and again jamie
jerome euzenat
in the
in the coming ice technology
that semantic web technologies knowledge management RDF industry terms many of neuron
if you want to use it programmatically in the same principle as the older you
get the particular you rarely get the key
but you get from when you registered to the service you can say
nine using this but it's fun
but you want RDF as the result
and then you put the URL of the service in that case i change i
put my webpage
and then you get a list of
died things
it recognise person like for example kind come out as someone recumbent
organisation university of nancy open university technologies like artificial intelligence fuzzy logic
the country's france united kingdom company is going to be made in the journal of
logic and computation
and mechanical condition can so i don't have cancer be reassuring
of course it is not
in fact you can see here for example but it
recognise milton keynes as being a person
why actually it's easy to see the thing which makes me very upset about it
and recognise me as person
i mean my web page
could actually have for me that was the minimum you could do some other things
are not particularly good
but this is a very good starting point and the nice thing is that you
don not only have
set of entities it even give you back the text
annotation within the text of what it does recognise so whenever i mentioned that we
come untied states
the bits of text in your text is the person can find relations like this
one showing application for this one because there are many
and they actually have a gallery of all the applications that have been built on
top of open calais framework from which semantic proxy
is about
and i get directed to
the second category of things which is even all
about using the semantic web
the second category is about this then
that goes to the web
crawley it to find out if document RDF data and different elements index it to
provide you with the ability to access it and to exploit it
that's why i put a nice lighting things around there
that means that
whenever this
since then i've done what we have to do
and your application can use keywords can send queries in park can ask for the
metadata about the data
can i ask for structured query
and obtain
location of RDF documents where they are can obtain actually is the content of the
RDF document can explore all the semantic that is on the web
to your typical set
all right so there was they ridiculous weighted decompression it in all the very large
bin bags full of tickets that you wrote things on the two sides of the
our compression hand and compression algorithm
for the next two lectures we're going to discuss
data compression how would we compress
bent coin
practically well that's actually a homework exercise i said boyish i'd like you to work
on that but will carry on working on other approaches to
related problems and i'm going to talk today about
they methods doing data compression called symbol
and the idea a simple code
is it something you could apply for example the english
or to
any language that involves an alphabetic characters were some characters are more probable than others
and to make life especially simple to start with i'm going to pretend that the
probability distribution for every character is the same every time and that we know the
andy will usually assume that non uniform so here is what the distribution could look like
here's an alphabet of twenty six characters plus space twenty seven in all
and a probability distribution over those and you can see space is the most probable
character and we've got eighty aiello iron age are sachdeo all that's sort of
stuff so it's that this is like an english-language distribution
and the task now
to give
a codeword to each
symbols in the alphabet which
of these
elements of the alphabet
and here's an example of what those codewords could look like we're going to encode into binary
andrew given you a codeword four zeros andrew c z the code one one zero one the
one spaces got zero one
that's an example the code and the way users symbol code is you take the
source file and to replace it by the corresponding code words in order
concatenated with no punctuation at all so the receiver won't be able to see where the boundaries between the codewords
a simple code is going to be a man
from each symbol
x in your alphabet
we call it see
x and see if x is a binary string
that's can see here can be
any length
and the way you write in set notation
zero one is the set with zero and one and it
and zero one set the plus means the set of all strings of any length
made of zeros and ones
but may be familiar to those who have with computer scientists
let me give you another example zero
the the power to
is the same as the set of strings are zero zero one
on the
and one one
okay so that's just a little bit about station
a simple code is
a mapping from symbols to
binary strings
and then
the way symbol code works is we encode
the string about complex one x two x three
by concatenate thing without punctuation
because the correct one and the code
thanks to the to the registration
i just give you an example
if we gave
eight codeword
he the candidate zero zero
and see one zero one
the file containing be would encoded has one zero one zero one zero
so that's a fairly simple idea
but now we need to get our head around this symbol codes understand and theoretically
ant understand them practically and these are quite important because they're quite widely
used especially in
in history
so the questions we want today other theoretical question
how well might pay symbol code before
and what anticipating here
a sort of computer windows systems that lived on your desk rather than on the
screen so you would have overhead camera and projector mounted on the roof and then
your desk as real objects on a piece of paper and pens and all sorts
of things that you keep passports apparently that you keep on your desk
you will be able to we use your hands to mix the real and virtual
objects for example you might have replicated the effect of having scissors photocopier glue and
so on and make up the news letter of two departure and so you might
be making this newsletter past and electronic content partly real content be nice to be
able to get a paper copy of something and just sort of do that with
your hand to delineate the picture then slide the picture of
the newspaper
the source newspaper onto the thing that you can positive and then
all of this is my friend mike is art exercising some of the software that
he designed that was supposed to follow hands effortlessly and you see it's i'm going
to explain you know sort of two lectures down the line what that was actually
doing but you see we've got something quite robust here that works on the desk
and in
free space and so on
another idea that i think is going to become more and more important i mean
there's technology out there for
having meetings across the web where you
can talk to somebody with
audio but they can also see you and you can also manipulate documents you might
be talking to
several people simultaneously
it would be good to maximize the visual real estate that you have been real
estate you have on your on your computer and the bandwidth for transmitting that so
here supposedly if for eager graduate students chatting to me about the latest idea
if i use a conventional webcam
this might be what they see
and actually will be this picture reduced in size using current technology anyway by perhaps
half or even worse
so wouldn't it be great if i could track if a sufficiently well to make
an automated cameraman so this is the scene on the right is made from exactly
the same raw material that you saw on the left
but with automatic framing digital zooming panning pan and tilt
whatever you do it's got to be reliable enough to operate not just for a
few seconds like i'm illustrating here but over several minutes and this is something we're
working on in the cambridge microsoft lab we have a project recall i which is
using stereo vision because stereo is so robust that separating foreground and background it's not
say that you can't do this without stereo what i'm showing you here the results
of a program that does this without stereo at the moment we are also working
both on stereo and mono
face detection and tracking to do the same job and we're kind pitting them against
one another we know the stereo will work on the other hand are we going
to be able to get the world to start buying stereo webcam maybe we can
but if we can do the same thing monocular then that will make me feel
like for the marketing men
a lot easier because then we just need to provide software downloads that have the
tracking embedded in them
we played also in the same context with putting speech vision together so he is
a couple of my colleagues who are working on this technology in a different kind
of track at this time tracking the head in a way
it actually takes cues from the speech so as well as a camera a pair
of stereo microphones and the might the microphones are using effectively time of flight to
work out what is the bearing of the person who's talking
and using probabilistic fusion of the two kinds of information the audio
bearing and the visual information we can make quite a robust system that will
the picture of the person who's talking
yes if we had sound you'd be able to hear the conversation but the conversation
turned out to be somewhat fatuous they didn't realize i was going to record them
so they much prefer that i don't show
that you hear what they were saying
and another application is surveillance would be very useful if you could keep track of
people moving around car parks and alert some security man who has a hundred cameras
to monitor when there was something interesting one of the screens and many people are
interested in this idea
important application is like reading it's well known that for humans
your accuracy in understanding speech is enhanced by having the motion available a program by
some berkeley researchers
while again now that i was able to track moving lips and get back to
the idea of the track
OK so i thought i begin by
sort of positing a rather dull
method for tracking and we can you know for it away and replace it with
something better so you know what's the dumbest thing you might do too
to track a moving object will
this idea can be so down because it's
in nineteen eighty one it was considered quite reasonable thing to propose because in canada
people still use it in various forms but the idea is that you have
and image i fx that you just saw
and some templates tnx supposed to be a prototype for the object that you're you're
looking for and so you can imagine trying to do some simple
direct matching of the
image that you just saw with the with the template
and so
if i
take this image i have x and then expand i x plus the two first
order where the is a small displacement and i now compare that with the with
template in the
a position that i currently believe it should be which is you know so i
think these being a small displacement value is not necessarily small and now supposing i
minimize this
sum of squared errors which is summed across the actual colours or intensities of pixels
and then i can
get simple
closed form solution to this minimisation
and of course
i'm exploring an energy landscape which is somewhat out of my control so i don't
know whether the methods the previous talk can help here because you can't talk about
whether or not this problem is convex i mean i can easily invent templates and
images for which the problem is in combat complex imagine template of of stripes and
an image of stripes and is going to be a kind of click every time
the stripes in the image can side the stripes template so you can you can
see it's going to be very easy to make numerically nasty
problems out of this
but in any case to solve the
local minimisation problem is not difficult it turns out that i take the
these gradient
i had this great either axis is the intensity gradient of the point in the
image computed every
o point x in the image how would you actually do that practically well you
might think of doing it with a finite difference approximation just taking the difference between
neighboring pixels but everybody knows that who does this that that's not a good way
to proceed because of sampling artifacts the real world is continuous and the images just
to sample version of it so what safer is to filter the image first with
is OK then the probabilities would be one of the thirty two
and i would gain five bits of information if i observe the outcome of that
of that run of our OK
so what you can now see is that
you can now see is that
unlikely events
i'm going to make this a number large
and therefore going give me more information according to this rule than than likely events
so this is shannon information content
now what is the entropy
well the entropy is simply
the average
shannon information
that's what it is
so how do i computed
well i basically observed
OK i
and then i sort of say OK but how many times and my going to
observe a i a well i'm going to observe BPI times roughly right and so
on and i just and i just performed
the average OK
and then you just you know you just take the minus here and then you
get the usual the usually familiar form for the entropy that you're all familiar with
sometimes we write the entropy in that if you take the natural logarithm
but i find it confusing
so how does the entropy look like
here's another figure sum from david mackay's book it's really worth reading if you're interested
in information theory
so let's take a coin
let's take a look going OK that doesn't have a fifty percent chance of falling
on each side imagine we could sort of loaded on one side with with heavier
metal plate or whatever and we can sort of because sort of
i just the probability that is going to come out hence OK and we consider
making range from zero to one missing from zero percent to one hundred percent
for all these values we can compute the what the when the shannon information is
of observing the outcome
heads right
so if the switch were with the here now
i think i've done this or this is sort of the other way around if
basically if it's
if it's very likely if it's very unlikely that is going to be heads and
they observe heads
then i get a lot of negative a lot of information here OK
and if it's fifty fifty
i get the least information
not surprisingly if i compute the average compute the entropy
actually the entropy behaves the opposite way around it doesn't behave that way and you
can intuitively why right this some sort of trade-off
if something extremely unlikely is very informative that's very nice if i observe it but
if i'm interested in the entropy i'm interested in the average amount of information i'm
going to get the then that very informative things
is going to come in very very seldom right so when i perform my average
is going to sort of varnish is going to be sold in it
OK so that's sort of the
the confusion earlier with what's more informative zero point one was your point five it
depends on whether you're talking
average information or whether you're talking sort of the information you got that instant condition
on the fact that you observe the unlikely event OK
entropy is
the average information and you can sort of see that if
if you know that the coin
you know
sort of
is very bias either way
then then the entropy is going to be very very low the uncertainty is going
to be very small
the answer the the entropy is maximum
when when the probability of heads is zero five
so this sort of satisfies
the two first axioms right
one of them is if we observe an event that certain OK
we knew already OK
it sort of it always rains in britain so i go out and it's raining
no nugget of information
now the day i got inside i'm going to take global warming seriously
and then the other thing is that in general the maximum information
on average is carried by uniformly probable events
OK so let's now
that's now think about the third axiom the axiom was
about the additivity
all of the information given by independent sources OK
i can actually compute
the joint entropy so if i have if i can again be the joint distribution
between two random variables and i can ask myself
how much information does that
those observing the outcome of these two random variables give me
on average OK that's going to be the that's going to be the entropy
now what you can see that if we start by looking at the shannon information
content again so we don't take the average it OK
i was simply use this equation all right
now what you see is we scenario that if x and y are independent i
can actually read them as the problem right
i can p of x of y and therefore i can actually be composed
shannon information into the sum of the individual shannon information OK
so basically
shannon was a clever guy
he came up with an equation that satisfies all axioms OK so it's not an
arbitrary thing to take the logarithm of one of the problem the probability there's there's
there's a number of powerful reasons why
you want that equation and not just any other equation
now quite trivial if you were to take the average if you were to take
the entropy you would have to take the average over the joint p of x
come y OK of this quantity here now you can see that if it decomposes
you first you get sort of two averages here and
the distributions can be factorized or the independent then
you're going to sort of have
here the sort of
the integral of p of x p y times the ceremony to p of x
y ten that term but because in each of the cases you have one of
the variables that is only in the distribution it is not in the term integrating
then you can just
take it outside and killing
so basically the
the previous space that is it's when cells were over here
if the cell was over here
and we have articles and there won't be any it will be radioactive labeled so
what we're really gonna that's now is the following
these cells are all advancing through like this they're dancing in the n phase
when does the first radio labelled cell
get after we release the hydroxyl when does it get
when we first seeing cells like this
and the fact is after five or six hours after release space then we begin
to see cells like this
which have chromosomes on which there is radio with which the israeli activity associated
well keep in mind that when cells move through the s phase here
this is when they incorporated traded finally into the DNA
cells can incorporate finding here
they can incorporate incorporated here
you can incorporate it here
so we can allow ourselves to incorporate a little bit of trade finally we can
freeze them in here
well given the little belt but it really is commonly get into the DNA here
and then we'll have ibrox area very shortly thereafter and freeze the cells right like
this so will be the doubly radioactive by virtue of having dwelt here different pi
times in the s phase and we have hydroxy area then
the cells that are already in s phase and incorporated benefited finally will remain as
face all the other cells which were when we have the hydroxy urea over here
they will go all the way around here
they will move all the way around the cell cycle they might have happened to
cooperate with but finally before we have the hydroxyl real they'll get trapped over here
so the only so the cells that have pretty and finally they will be scattered
at various points in the s phase we remove the hydroxy urea
that allows the cells to escape from this phase and move all the way around
the here and then we begin to look for seeing when cells get radio labelled
is clear now
a little clearer
let's begin to ask how this is all
coordinated what determines
how cells when cells will grow
and when cells will not grow so let's go back to war depiction of the
cell cycle
how what controls all this
what determines when cells can move around the cell cycle
in our bodies
so we have roughly three times ten to the thirteenth cells
i don't know that number i mentioned before
it's a pretty interesting number it's probably the not
the most interesting number
by now far more people are interested in the number of how many games
the red sox have won or lost but it's to number anyhow
how many cell divisions to we go through in lifetime ever talk about that
how many times with the cell growth and division cycle in human lifetime
life time and the answer is a human lifetime there are about
ten to the sixteenth cell divisions it's staggering number
ten to the sixteenth in one human body in human lifetime and if you figure
out what that amounts to i think it's something like and you figured out yourself
i think it's month something like ten to the seventh
cell divisions
in each second
so each time i'm talking with you i'm going to go already gone through any
one of my sentences and by the time my long-winded sentences finish i probably already
had a hundred million mitosis happening inside me
maybe even more
because sometimes my senses are really long
so imagine that tend to the seven
per second you can figure out the number of this is the lifetime of let's
say you live seventy years
you can do the math how many per second
a lot of that's going on by the way in the bone marrow and in
the gut
because in the bone marrow constantly replacing a lot of your red blood cells you
have lots of them but they only last for one hundred twenty days so after
one hundred twenty days of red blood cells
is is broken down into getting red blood cell in its place but obviously have
more than one red blood cell in your body the same thing happens in the
the cells lining
the got those are called epithelial cells that line the surface of the guys and
they are constantly
being slapped on the wall of the
why because it's not so nice to live on the wall of the is not
very pleasant environment and the cells are therefore costly got gotten rid of because they
have a hard time surviving for extended periods of time those cells live only three
or four days on the wall of the
so when you go to the bathroom and i don't mean to be too graphic
but number two a significant proportion of what comes out
the bottom is actually cells been sloughed off
from the epithelial lining of the gut and what the proportion is it something like
twenty or thirty percent about half of what comes out is actually bacterial
in the in the feces
we're not going on now so you can can absorb all is right about half
of that almost none of the bulk of the feces actually ends up being what
you eight
most of what's right and left ends up getting compressed to a very small amount
of solid matter so most of what comes out is is not with what came
is not the process exposing food but things as i just mentioned
and by the way here's another unsettling statistic
it's not so graphic but it's unsettling if you think about it there are more
bacterial cells in your gut
then the rest then there are a million new carrier cells the rest your body
they're taking over
more than there are bus in each one of our bodies
go figure that out
why am i going on this long excursions
well only he knows
he's not telling but
there was a reason behind it
the reason why i'm going in this is to impress on you the fact that
it's really important that the advance of cells through their growth and division cycle that
we just talked about here
very carefully controlled because each one of these growth cell growth and division cycles is
the opportunity for disaster what kind of disaster well if the cell makes a mistake
in its chromosomes it might die
the death of the cell in our body is not a disaster
i just indicated you there were
we're making ten to the seventh new sells every second but
hopefully we're making exactly the same number of cells that die
go back to the beginning
draw this parallel to be and so here's the and again just the line of
that same slope and now what you should use
as the simplest improvement on oil is that it is to take the average of
these two because that's more likely to occur
then a and will
which is sure to be too low if the curve is convex
in other words use this instead use that
so this is our better slope
OK what will we call that slow we call it anything with the equations
for the method b
well n plus one is
done by adding the step size so here's my step size just as it was
just as it was before the new thing is how to get the new value
of y
so y n plus one should be the all the y and
plus h times
not this crummy slope a and
but the better the pink slope
what's the formula for the pink flow well
let's do it in two steps it's the average
of a and b and
i didn't tell me or i didn't tell you would be was so you now
must tell the computer oh yes by the way
if you remember the day and was what it always was
the interesting thing is what is b and well
to get BN BN is the slope of the line element at this new point
i would like to call the new point i don't want to cause y value
y n plus one because that's is this
a period is going to be the y n plus one all this is temporary
used to make another calculation
which will then be combined with the previous calculations to get the right value
therefore given the temporary name
that point
will call it is not going to be the final the real y n plus
one we'll call y n plus one twiddles y n plus one temporary
what's the formula for it
well it's just going to be what the oiler formula original oil formulas can be
y and what you would have gotten if you were calculated
in other words the point that the oiler method produced
but it's not finally the point that we want
now want have to say anything else i didn't tell the computer would be and
was OK
b and
the slope
of the direction field point and was one the computer knows what that is and
this point y n plus one temporary
so you
make a temporary choice of this calculate that number and then go back and as
they were correct that value for this value by using this better slope
that's all there is to the method except that give you its name
well it has three names for names in fact
which one so i give you
if the shortest name is point
but nobody knows
announces that correctly
so it's always method
it's called also the improved oiler methods
it's called modified boiler
very expressive word
modified oilers method
and it's also called
or k two
i'm sure you like that best it has the star wars sort of sound
rk stands for rock kind of
and the reason for the tool
it's not that it uses to well it is that it uses two slopes
but the real reason for the two is that in a second order method so
let's that's the most important thing to put down
if the second order method whereas oilers was only first-order methods so this is a
so why is method
four RK two let's write the shortest in the right is the second order methods
that the error
varies with the step size
like some constant there will be the same as the concert royal about that
times age square
that's a big savings because it now means that if you have the step size
you're going to decrease the error
by a factor of one quarter
you will
a quarter of the year
now this is the great why should anyone using the well
i think a little second
the real thing which determines how slowly
one of these methods run is
you look at the hardest step of the method and ask how long does the
computer take how many of those hard steps are there
now the answer is the hardest step
is always the evaluation of the slow evaluation of the function
because you know i the functions that are in common use not x squared minus
why square they take at the page and have this coefficient you know ten vessel
place numbers
whatever the guy
the engineers doing it you know whatever their accuracy was
so the thing that controls how long method runs is how many times the slope
the function must be evaluated
four boiler i only have to evaluate it once
here i have two evaluate it twice
roughly speaking the number of function evaluations
each will give you the exponent
the method that's called run kind of fourth order will require four
evaluations of slope
but the accuracy will be like age to the force
very accurate you have the step size goes down by a factor of sixteen
but you had to
do it for you to evaluate the slope four times suppose instead
you had
i have
four times this thing what would you do that you would decrease it to one
sixteen what it was
you would
increase the number of functions evaluation need to
you would have
decrease the by sixteen so
in some sense
it really doesn't matter whether user very fancy that there
which requires more function evaluations studio goes down faster
find theta i can replace by the cosine of the the one
and so i get you know detentions of data one
and so if this is the tangent
of data one
that is under these conditions
we have met
the condition that i was looking for that and that was on the percent
linearly polarized light
so this
is the secret
getting hundred percent polarized light
and this angle
it's called the brewster angle
so if we for instance look at the transition
from air to glass
glass has a index
of refraction
approximately one point five
fans on the kind of glass that you have
if i go from
air to glass which is what i was doing my demonstration
and the tangent of the angle is and two divided by n one
this is class there's one point five
and one is one
and you will find that the brewster angle
they have rooster
it turns out to be about fifty six degree
i can also make linearly polarized light by going from glass to air bouncing out
of this way
and of course i have to invert this
and then you get a brewster angle
which is smaller which is thirty four degrees but since i will do it was
from air to glass
i wanted to concentrate on the fifty six
degree angle
the way i'm going to demonstration
it's right set up here
we have light
like being
that strikes a piece of plane parallel glass that's all of this is nothing special
about this piece of glass
so the light comes in like so
and here
i have a piece of glass
it is the angle of incidence they one
so it's going to be reflected in this direction
by this and is also state along and something will go immediately is angle theta
two which i don't worry about
i want you to see that this
become the percent polarized as this light comes in
this component this component of equal strength
if they don't want is fifty six degrees or somewhere in that vicinity
this slide is now on the percent for
and i'm going to projected onto the screen
and i'm going to convince you that it is indeed polarized
you cannot use your own polarizes to see that
because the lights in this being
is going to be
one hundred percent polarized
once it reflects off the screen it no longer is so you cannot you should
polarimeter so i have to use my own parameter
to show you this
so we can turn the light of their of the overhead thank you very much
i will
turn on the
the life of my
like being there this and i'm going to make it very dark for you
so that we can see that very well
so to light
comes it is direction hits the glass
and the angle of incidence is now about forty five degrees
i purposely didn't make it fifty six yet
i view a large sheet of polarized one of edwin land or arises and i'll
rotate it in this b
you'll see this partially polarized not yet on the percent but it's already partially polarized
so is already in balance between the two perpendicular and parallel components
so if whole it into being
and i rotated
you will clearly see now
it it is much fainter
and it is now
now i will go for the fifty six angle fifty six degree angle roughly
so now
i rotate my
notice i can kill them like complete
one the percent linearly polarized i may not have the angle perfect but that's okay
you get the idea very close
totally dark
now you see the light
all rights in this election
now i can kill it
so it is quite remarkable thing
that if we reflect light of the dielectric
that we can
one angle in one language only
which is the brewster angle
we can turn it into a hundred percent linearly polarized light
does not apply to conductors
the behaviour of conductors is very different from dielectric success such as water
and glass
you can use maxwell's equations of course to study
reflection of electromagnetic waves
but you get very different results
so never expect to get linearly polarized light responses of metals
i have you for your pleasure
the metal sphere and i have
glass sphere
and if you still have a linear polarizer is at hand
you can now our little later just hold them in front of your eyes
and rotate them around
of course you're not seeing the light at the brewster angle the chances i
that some of the light that is reflected of this class that you can clearly
see this partially polarized you can see it
the difference in light intensity as you rotate it not going to see that of
this metal
i come to a very
there is a third way that we can make on percent linear polarized light
by the scattering of unpolarized light
we have to scan of very fine particles preferably
tens of micron
dust particles will work very well
the theory of light scattering is extremely complicated
but i will be able to convince you
that if i scatter the light
over an angle of ninety degrees or comes in like this this carries over an
angle of ninety degrees
that it becomes
one hundred percent linearly
i will stay on the centre board
suppose i have light coming in
like so
and i one light photons
concentrate on one
to start with and it happens to be that light photon
is linearly polarized in this direction
so in effect it was also like this
later we're going to have all the directions that we want to just pick one
and here
i am i find dust particles
and these dust particles of electrons
and the electric field
passers-by by
these electrons which charged
i going to oscillate in this direction
they're going to experience acceleration
which is the force that they experience divided by the mass
and therefore that is the charge that they have
the electric field divided by the mass
so as the electric field vector
this electric field component oscillating with frequencies omega
passing by these electrons they themselves
i going to oscillate
with the frequency omega
and this is the force
they will experience this acceleration
notice that the electrons will experience away high acceleration than the protons
because the protons have amassed which is
more than eighteen hundred times larger than the electrons so whatever follows
it's really electrons that do the job and not the
so we have
charges that move up and down
and now comes the question
which we have discussed earlier this is just simply too
and not a lot of this is again trying to take us towards concept which
are in some ways more natural are interesting how would you know which which to
us doesn't necessarily mean higher dimensional data although it might but often means datasets with
more interesting structure the kinds of things that that human cognition is really good but
traditional statistics is is not really but i mean to be basically the same kind
of thing that jeff was talking about
so here's here's an example of a more natural dataset that you might use to
study human concept learning categorisation and generalization we have a bunch of animal categories here
and here along the columns we have a bunch of properties these are not really
perceptual features of the kinds of things that you know if you go with your
child going around the zoo or reading a picture book or something you know you
these are the sorts of things that you can notice in your perceptual data and
the adults will often point out and say look about one that one eats bugs
or something eats bugs and so this this matrix represents one naive subjects
semi naive subjects judgments of
for each of these
species whether or not they have each of these properties and there's actually i think
i've only label every other property there's something like one hundred twenty properties in
and a lot of
a lot of cognitive science work on categorization has been done with animal species both
categorize categorizing things into species but also categorizing species into higher categories just so what
happens if we take this data set and just run regular mixture model on it
will just try to discover an unsupervised way the categories that are here
well this is the result of running CRP mixture basically a dirichlet process mixture where
we get we don't have to know how many categories are around we discovered these
four categories which we've just reorganized the rose to group them the animals according to
the categories discovered by the mixture model have also reorganized the columns so that the
ones which are cleanest are over here on the left those of those are also
the ones which have the highest likelihood basically under the model because the
the multinomial which in this case is the binomial basically wants to have features clean
within categories and essentially what it's doing here is it's looking for a way of
chopping up the the objects
into categories such that as many features as possible are as clean as possible and
it's making a trade-off between wanting to put things into smaller smaller number of categories
that's coming from the chinese restaurant process prior and won in the categories to be
as clean as possible and that depending on exactly how you set the parameters of
the prior you can get very straight as you can you can always make the
categories really clean by making them really small or you can if you can make
them really begin to have a few categories if you're willing to tolerate some amount
of messina and how the features are spread spread out within the category this is
this is a pretty reasonable compromise so you can see that forms the four categories
are these large taxonomic categories like the kind of things the biologist my talk about
who's interested in in evolution or categorizing species these ones are all mammals
including things that are
somewhat atypical animals like bats and seals
these ones here are
reptiles and amphibians these are birds
these ones are insects and invertebrates
and that way of organizing the animals makes a fair amount of sense of the
of the features you can see also the features that come out clean are the
ones that do that
you know traditional biologists would use in trying to classify species of things like having
a peak have having bones has long has tasks is the k nine is officially
road and is warm-blooded
sort of deep anatomical
physiological properties
the course
about just wouldn't take is a k nine as a feature that would be kind
of a little bit too you know to achieve learning these things those that might
be something that somebody might come our is official something
so those are just treated as data here now there's all these other features over
here which are not the ones of traditional taxonomic interest in biology like lives in
the grass or makes loud noises or is large or is yellow and so on
when you organize the the animals taxonomic lee these just look like noise that's what
biologists don't pay attention to so biologist might who's interested in classifying things in this
you might know the the the whole point is to do a kind of model
based feature selection and to be able to say well
these features over here are interesting maybe somebody but they are not informative about the
most useful way to categorize these objects and acquire basic question though that confronts us
when we do a lot of interesting certainly i problems for a lot of real-world
machine learning problems we have all these features we might measure another anyway one way
of organizing the domain the objects many of the features are going to look like
noise and so the real question is are these really nice or maybe there's some
structure there but it's just not the structure and by finding a single clustering like
this were missing that
so we we propose to model which we try to
if you like assessed whether there are other forms of structure maybe maybe maybe
one of the way of clustering is things are any number of ways that that's
actually a nonparametric model where it's going to consider ways of incense grouping the features
into subdomains each of which might support a different way of grouping the object of
the rows so i will tell you about the the math too much of this
but i'll just show you a picture and talk qualitatively about the matter if you're
interested you can you can look at the paper by pat shafto and others
the model is called cross cap for cross categorization and the idea it's and it's
interesting kind of nested nonparametric
model in which at the top level you have this
this nonparametric mixture over the columns of the features so it's again it is there's
probably some version of the dirichlet process that this corresponds to
we do we just use the chinese restaurant
process combinatorial
prior over these guys to basically consider all consider all possible ways of grouping the
columns into subsets which tends to prefer a small number of subsets for this
dataset here the model finds usually there are two or three
systems of categorization or two or three clusters of features where each feature each cluster
feature is then exposed explained by different way of clustering the animals so within each
one of the partitions of features the model defines the different dirichlet process mixture over
the the objects of the rows so it's like one high-level one that goes by
column and then within each cut of the columns a different one by road
so what we can see that the model finds here is it finds the kind
of the biggest set of features that the dominant position is just the one that
the regular mixture model finds its taxonomic organisation and again it's it's being supported by
features like having bones are laying eggs are being warm-blooded are being a mammal
but then there's there's two other subsets of let's talk about this one first
this one here
well will look at the work of the organization the animals so one category has
leopard alligator pie
another one has seal dolphin frog jellyfish octopus penguins
then you have a pinch single owl eagle dragonfly back
grasshopper and PC monkey gone austria so this is this is pretty interesting right can
you see what's going on here
how would you describe this
what is very much not taxonomic right because you have a mammal a bat and
insect dragonfly
a birdie eagle
or you have here you have a seal and dolphin are mammals in their with
invertebrates and
birds like penguins
basically where they live right so these are all things that live in the water
if a given probability distribution respects
conditional independence statements
that are given by graph separation
in some
graph g
then the distribution will
according to the graph g as given by the problem over the clique
of arbitrary non negative potential function calls
and also why this is important well
it is important for the same reason that it was important to with bayesian networks
over here
conditional independence statements are usually what is known by the expert by the domain expert
is usually what you can see from
and the expert needs the model in order to compute things in order to be
able to
perform creates on the probability distribution p of that
right and in order
for both types of graphical models
bayesian networks and markov random field
we have a relationship between the conditional independence statements
some simplified algebraic structure of the probability distribution
in terms of
it can be represented in in terms of ground
so in both cases
we have
classes of
probit models
that are obtained from conditional independence statements that are mapped the two
lack of edges if you will
in a bayesian network in the directed graph or
in america from the field
because you precisely how
conditional independence statements when you pull off
and the edge
one of these drugs
and the particular type of
the simplified algebraic structure is the factories
it's related to local pieces of the graph at what are the local pieces in
the case of bayesian networks
the child the
in the past
the local piece in the case of markov random fields is the clique
right so
the factorisation of probabilistic model
four patient approaches
these effects precision over
factors of
that depends on the trophy fish set of
the markov and feels it depends on all the virus initially
but there are also important differences and should mention them here
let's keep them in mind all the time
first and this is something we have already
such previously
this set of probability distributions that can be represented
actually as a perfect map is rule system as a marketing tool is different from
that so that people can be represented as the vision as
they both are expressed in terms of factorizations but you have noted that in the
case of
a marker were killed we have
and normalisation
constant c
that needs to be included in the factorisation because we want to allow for arbitrary
c of xy
so we need in the case of markov random fields
is normalisation function
he is also not a major problem learning for example
they want to actually perform learning on market hill because you need to estimate this
for some
complex macromolecules estimating this one is very
very tissue
the local pieces of the vision that according local factors
they are probability distributions themselves remember that
in the vision all
you have as each factor the probability of a child given parent
but for microphone it's
it's a non negative function as well like probability function
but it's not necessarily normalized to one
it's just a function that gives you some number which is negative number
so for each tissue
we have
measured some expression of
of proteins so for example let's say
on the on the tissue
let's say for the
healthy tissue
this is the healthy tissue we measured
g one the expression was low that means protein protein
expressed as a result of a group of gene one was low
gene two is high
the gene three is low
and for gene four is high
so so that's how it's all expressed in i know we have to start
so so what you can see
in this example is that
i hope you can see the colours
there is this one this box
this shows you
these these
this tissue and this tissue
i have
common pattern of expression low high and low
and that
combination never appears in the one
so what you can say is that now i observed a contrast pattern which says
gene one
expression is low
gene two expression is high
gene three group of expression is low
so that we see
fifty percent of the tissues that we look at
i'm never happens here
so therefore we conclude that
g one equal to ldt equal to g equal to l
is an emerging pattern because somehow
what differentiates these two groups
can not in each case
but there is insufficient evidence to believe this is an interesting pattern
so this is the real data
so this is that it comes from one of the published
that in nineteen ninety nine in colon cancer datasets
there are forty
cancerous tissues and twenty normal
so these are all gene expressions somehow the gene expressions are grouped into
i to these things there's about two thousand
genes and then they were reduced to
something like two hundred fifty or three hundred groups
because what they found is some genes were expressing together
so so for example
a groups of genes which labeled as you know one
one last
four miners
one two plus one thirteen plus the appears
a hundred per cent
in the colon cancer and never appeared in the
in the other case
so so you see that these patterns are incredibly dominant in the colon cancer and
this is
in in the in the in the cancer case
and in the normal case
these are the dominant features
so you can see that there are quite quite substantial
and these patterns
might actually indicate something to do
the disease and that's the kind of conclusion you could make here
so what you want to do is to find the minimum set
the minimal patterns
that appear so for example it's say a
you find the minimal
in the normal tissue that means
this pattern appeared only in the normal tissues and never appeared in the cancerous ones
so it so this could be an indication for
you know somebody
trying to come up with a drugs
to see that
properly expressed gene groups important for normal
so functioning
but they are destroyed
in the case of
colon cancer
so you make a hypothesis if i can restore them some
can i can i cure cancer that is the kind of hypothesis that could have
or the other way
that is we follow a group of genes
very active in the case of
patients with cancer
these are the bad genes some of turned on the should not
is there a way you can suppress is there
why do that can either the things
now the interesting thing is that you know in medicine you know they
you already have a good knowledge of how to turn on certain genes how to
turn off by using drugs
because what happens is they might have studied
some drugs in the context of some other diseases
and they find that same patterns of genes are common between diseases so therefore
sometimes it is quite easy for them said well we know that
this particular drug certainly can turn on this gene i'm going to block the particular
so we know that we have already gone the child and we have good evidence
here we're going to mister straighter and so for example in the FDA in the
no food and drug administration
you know this is the body
it has two
give approval
before medication is available for large population
so generally what happens is from the discovery
to the properties
could be ten to fifteen years
and the and the two and there's a lot of hope here is that if
there is already drugs that have been approved by the FDA
the clearances are much much easier because they already have studied these drugs
then all side effects so therefore they know what the safety margin for these studies
so they have very quickly they can administer these drugs
and then
if the drugs were
they can bring the drugs very very quickly to the
to the practice
so people are incredibly happy with this kind of model so if you know exactly
what's happening
and if you have a prior approval for these drugs
the daily medication is
very short and also the expenses that don't require you know sit typically they say
if you discover a drug that works
usually need you know how to build a billion dollars
before the track could be a problem
and that's why medications could be incredibly expensive because the the long period of waiting
lot of money and still there is a lot of risk sometimes
they go to the whole scheme
and then
five years later they find that the hormone replacement therapy
it has very high
correlation to cause cancer
know then
all these billions of dollars this painting studying and millions
of women having these
you know
this the this therapy
probably would go class action against the companies because
they have not done a proper job so lots of
conservative so this can this could kind of health
and also was talking to some of the volunteers they say that you know when
try to study these things
they don't
you know like for example a lot of nice they can actually manufacture
with a different kind of genes they can knock off exactly
what kind of gene to knock off and watertight on and so forth and sometimes
they can turn them by giving
some drugs
so so they can study very carefully but the question is before they run experiment
they don't really know which
adding to that which is not to bayesian problem by itself
if you start using a complex
prior distribution
which may be the result of
previous observations that are too numerous to compute the prior
which is the posterior then i had
to the to the complexity
this information and using it makes more sense
crisis as you can see how
trying to do so
thank you
you know
patients when you want
she that
OK let me ask you questions and google scholar
no no one
the difficulty
when you a zero
to do inference is that
you have want here one
he use a european
for the the only thing you want
and when i was mentioning this competition of problem
the point
that's block inference
from the
all that
first we work on the parameter space here the
nothing like the regular euclidean
or the
we have three
that are either composed by kind of very weak information
although the model itself and
always c they're easy area
model autoregressive before he
but where
the truncation of the space which is totally
normally do
so first you may have to
to do inference with a lot of of barriers so when you go your space
you blocked very quickly if you go straight
to take an example
the second difficulty is f of x given seed itself you're given models
the model is the result of several
integration of and or interpolation or simplification but actually
complex ification rate rather for censoring is one example you don't have the data itself
but some bits of today and so itself is integral
mean that that you know that is in the part state
so maybe an integral in dimensions
y one hundred to one thousand
the difficulty when you use this object is that upon
you pick by
the bayesian but if you
i did indeed and you want to use spread information so your prior information
the induced
already complexity
in pile
the first example was the constrained parameter space
if your prior information tell you that cedar is there and not there
but of course we have several levels of information on one level of prior information
is that you may have
earlier observations
and your prior observations
prior distribution maybe
already the posterior
and so it may be complex based
another level of complexity is that you will use this as the truth
probability distribution
so you will have to compute quantities based on this distribution
so we want to compute for instance in expectation based on the for show
and its expectation
if you are not mention friends and maybe just not computable because either the numerator
is complex or
we cannot compute the denominator
and this is just
is just
example but after
if you want to do testing in a bayesian setting use bayes factor is a
basic tool in bayesian inference and bayes factors
if you can use the the
and i've got a little problem because
because i only graph something real
or they
i think a little bit better more about these to see what graph OK well
my graph what what what is that if this is the input what's the output
that's my question
that's really my question
if if if my inputs
this is the vector of is is
this is pure
pure frequency
what's the output
well i just like in the formula
and figure out the output
this work
is easy right
OK XML
is either omega
taking up your frequency
and what's x of n minus one
eight the omega
and minus one
what the filters sewing
to this peer frequency
and now how do i want to write that will how do i want to
could estimate the images can be the only again out of it first
so what
what do i get times in the the omega and
well one half
and with the other one
half of
i only
well there is the most important functions
that's functions got it
it's got the total information about the filter
it's got because it's
shows us the half-and-half
and this is the
and i call it h using the same letter h
of omega
well actually
i use capital x of omega
the transformed
of the
discrete xis
is my notation consistent i believe it actually is
this a troublemaker
is this is
nothing but
troublemaker is nothing about the song
of the feature case the mind's i k
jumping from example whereas i happen to have been doing really clear
what would be four
different for any set of numbers
can i say what i'm trying to say in all one sentence what's up
what's up is
this formula
this convolution
in time domain
goes into
a multiplication
in the frequency domain
there is the a big deal
that's the most important formula in the set
so in the time domain we have little access we have little h is an
outcome little the wise by
in the frequency domain we're making axes features we multiply ordinary multiplication
because we
in the transform domain and outcomes big y
and of course this is the way to understand the filter
and often times but would never have
matrix at all
this is that
like sensible
what what is this
i mean
the first page of or the first two or three pages of the wavelet but
check this
i just checked that if
we started in the time domain
and we define
transformed the capital extrapolate capital y
the convolution in the time domain gives us some location and frequency
most important foreign certainly
so this is what we ought to graph this is this is what we graphs
but it's complex
here it was
it's complex numbers so
what's the best do
great graphics make it
so that now we finally say what are we graphing i'm going to grasp the
once one stage will have the full sample the other state subsample
so you may have a situation where the quite a face as the four
number of participants
and then you select
is one of those
selection for random on random
people to go in your
qualitative phase we interviewed him focus groups can have as well
when you have those for combinations in you
combine it with with its concurrent sequential
you get eight different
types of relationships you can have
and featured those you select your your sampling scheme
you have the twenty four
OK so that's a really quick created action to make it stop
research design philosophies design probably the most developed area in mixed methods there lots of
designs out there
people like john crystal
having great works are
tajik always teddlie and several others jennifer greene
this is what can
again couple of this manuscript
this article
if you're interested
the basic you look at level to make sense
time orientation emphasises three key points
so whether it's partially mixed
well you mix because sometimes people will collect quantitative data
quality data
analyzed separately but then makes them at the end that's more partially mixed might be
fully mixed with the is very interactive all across
most of the phase of the study
time orientation have you seen before concurrent sequential and weights
emphasis is equal or o one is dominant
khalid to that with the
a different combinations so you can have
the collection in birkenau
his wife lisa have come up with six
major data collection strategies for example you can mix open and close and
death threats interviewing
a priory imagine flowing
standardised open and close any questions
that's the first four
standardised confirmatory less explored started to explore observation
you can also combine numeric make documents
ten is actually going there in their hand in there
latest book
i have extended further
they come out with thirty six
different data collection combinations
that's a really actually really really good chapters were in chapter if you if you
if you're interested
research design because
data collection because that's really cut it
the stuff that they have in their
so then we want to start nine
which is data analysis and
and doing this week is what we're going to focus most on this is one
of the is to determine the most struggle with
to do data analysis
had the analyse have called data have chordata what i do with a lot of
time you might be strong alignment but not strongly of and that's my one promise
you have
quite qualitative was mixed methods analysis
we combine concurrently or sequentially
the analysis of quantitative
and qualitative data
might be in the power law way might be sequential said might be integrated
so that's the fundamental principle of data analysis
and in two major goals for
folk and for that mixed methods one might be legitimation
so when there
we use what about the other
the second of the representation
we want to get more at your data
we might use both in the same study
there's a couple of times you have a lot of literature quantitizing one
and that's where you convert quantitative data
to call quality site is we collect qualitative data to qualitative codes
so you might have themes and you count the themes or you do all kinds
based on your qualitative information
or you could have quantitized qualitizing
which you go the other way so you have quite a data
and from there
images qualitative data
and findings
so for example you could you could form a profiles conati profiles
that's where you
based on numbers that you get from quite a phase
you build the picture story of the person or group of people
so you have the load profile
and this is ten tuchikoi in the book and ninety eight we have detailed narrative
of course people based on the most frequently occurring
we may be based on the average
number of attributes
you get from the quantitative data
could be you do more realistically
comparative profiles
it is where you compare one analysis to another
o normative where you might have some normative data
so you have an instrument that yields norms
and from there you compare them to the norms and then you build the picture
from them
so if you do in forensic psychology and so forth
you might use normative profiles if you're trying to build the profile of a serial
then you might be using such techniques
within five seven steps major steps in the mixed methods
they do not process
you use your data it is the quality of qualitative data
he might use things like this gives statistics for your qualitative
what factor analysis
and the quality may use export market analysis
a memory
i also started we got funding from three different foundations to do a small study
this and we're trying to get
bigger finding out of a large scale study but in this study we took veterans
who are obese
we attempt attempted to get them to lose one pound per week for sixteen weeks
that's our goal
and every month they returned to the lateral connections they kind
four way and that's very important to explain why
so if three conditions with the control condition where they go to the
nutritionists and they get advice about how to control the rate that's all
and we have to
experimental incentive conditions
in both of these conditions they monitor their weight every day and every day in
the morning the phone in the weight to our administrators
and in the evenings we send them back we every each guest pages
text pager in the evening we send them message telling them
OK telling them
what's happening
and we have two conditions of lottery incentive condition on the positive incentive condition
in the lottery condition
it's the
the same scheme as for warfarin
this slide is missing but i imagine a graph it starts with subject's way
and you see the line where there is
one week
and both of these conditions as long as they stay on the line every day
they get payoff
they go over the line not losing as much weight as there supposed to and
they don't get a so
in the lottery condition they only receive lottery payment if first they called in the
way that they
and second at below daily weight loss goal
and we transmit the message about whether they won or whether they would have won
the lottery
based on whether they are weight is low
every month they come in and check we weigh them on the laboratory scale
and if if their weight isn't what they told us it was at the end
of the month they get nothing so that's how
make sure that lie to us
in the second that we also decided to try and new incentive condition was called
positive deposit contracts
in this they can put money down toward weight loss the beginning of the month
we match them one to one
they can put anything from penny down to three dollars a day
so they put three dollars a day and every day that they are below weight
below the target way they get back six dollars but there but the target weight
they lose their freedom so we're trying to plan loss aversion
and here are the results so far in the first month
the control condition not the
one seven six pounds
in the addition they lost five point seven pounds in the past
contract condition they lost seven pounds
if you look at the percentage attaining the first monthly weight loss goal was to
lose four and seventy one percent in the water conditions
one hundred percent
and the deposit in this you can see that are
initial conditions
only seven percent
achieve the weight loss goals
we're now four months into the study
and the results continue to look very easily average weight loss over a four-month period
still writer one to control
it's an average
four thousand four pounds four pounds per week
sorry for lottery conditions and
also found with the possible conditions
and the
meeting the goal is those figures are similar
i think i'm going to not tell you about
save the savings plans and less
it's not my fault
a while ago i was at a investments
bank and they said
why do people not safe for retirement
how can we have we make retirement real to people can we get them to
realise you're going to have a miserable retirement they don't save money for retirement
so this can be seen should we scare them should be presented with gruesome images
of for retirement
or should we show that like wonderful images and after retirement i said that you
just think you are totally wrong lines
what you need to do
is easy get daily incentives for saving money
is the announcer familiar themes say
it's amazing that is
that the median family
united states zero stars even in retirement plans
and but the average
family in the united states spans across four thousand dollars
so the average distance four thousand dollars gambling
it doesn't take into account to get back
i was putting i did this i was put in
later or the not so i was pretty
what does there's no room for
at a certain point is if you use it can be put in because size
already in there
so you would edit inconsistencies
along stage
and every stage was kept constant union is also considered
what's the canonical
the canonical model
the set of all maximal consistent what do i do
i say
remember this was wanting me to get one
x star which was a maximal consistent extension of gamma rule enumeration and compute all
maximal consistent extension of gamma which just means
all permutations of your formula
it's not empty white lace one that's the whole point of the investment in existing
steer there's at least one
let them be the set of your world
so my worlds
maximal consistent
in this
so i'm going to draw them
i'm going to draw them like this
the world in the old days it was the point
now it's an infinite set forth
it's got nothing to do with constructive
i'm going to say
OK let's use the notation that i'm using
wn one is a
i've got a set of nonempty set of world now i
on the
what is it what does wrcv jumbo say when can i put an arc
from here to here
in working mumbo-jumbo
and this is the whole point of the construction
you can say is one sentence
to the brain
the condition is up
it's conditioning work
sorry so
you're using words like true and necessary i want notation
one in in terms of set membership
because i don't have notions of necessary at the moment right on defining the model
no that's not true
you're on the right track and being a bit other people to pick up on
you're on the right track
are being boxed
this sentence matches that definition
it's being a set of formulae using
what's the set of formulae
the set of all five
the guys are in
but what i have a they're all they have to be so in other words
all it says is you find all the box formulae that are in here
although there in their box which is what you're saying that all the things which
are necessary to
how the support region is moving and we cannot have that before that local regions
do tend to move in a similar way and if you if you can parameterise
had moving semi-final or even translation
if you parameterize the moving then you can come get and m heads are better
than one thing going on so
maybe one or two of the pixels are noisy but if you look at enough
the pixels you can get a pretty good idea of where the areas move
so let's let's walk through the solid
what essentially i have here
is my source image
and i've got to the ground truth so the ground truth
is p plus delta p so
most likely change notation here so p
in terms of lucas kanade a is my initial guess
actually this would be more instructive to do this way so p is this i
run from my apologies in space and time and i'm not going to get an
approximate idea where the object is but i know exactly where it is likely to
have a good ballpark region for the lucas kanade have guys from says OK
it's approximately here but i know there's a lot of noise there's a lot of
what error in this estimate
so what i what i actually do
so going back to this
is that i see that i can approximate what the truth
aligned image looks like this is my starting this why
i noise EP
things and i want to find the delta p which will essentially
refine or improve
my current IP
OK so what i did to try and so this is essentially i i assume
that approximate this ideal and image five
the roughly misaligned image
and obviously
a rule of thumb with this is again we go back to the pixel coherence
you might say well how
well one doesn't have to be
and you can't obviously there has to be some pixels within that implied that are
in a better in a spatially local area so not all the pixels so you
don't have to have been entire template perhaps like what someone has two pixels one
but they have to be some pixels in there that can actually have a region
that can be reasonably predicted in terms of movement selected so rotational scale and things
like that some of those pixels have to overlap so obviously translations roughly wrong here
the aspect ratio is wrong here the scale is from here but the pixels to
overlap with what the true alignment to understand what the true trawlermen i one element
the next thing i do
it is essentially
i is
again i look to the first order taylor series expansion
but instead of just applying it straight i apply a
since reagan high school maths again on the train
and essentially allowed to
it is i get the gradient of the image we already covered that there a
different number of different ways of doing this
and this notation here might seem a little bit strange you guys you might want
to know what's going on here i know what's going on here
this is the source image
this is
i mean warping being the source image for my currently which is kind noisy which
is which is with which is noisy and then i've got this part and the
name of the group
and essentially this part is essentially just the x and y components and every pixel
but the x and y components of every pixel
from the source with respect to the source image
so what i'm really saying here is that when tackling these gradients
i don't
so there are two ways to calculate gradient if you kind of being heuristic what
i could do look at the source image
i could what
here such that my images i like to invite
architect gradients
but what i'm saying here
is that i want to calculate gradient of the image with respect to the original
source image so what i have to do actually is i have to take the
gradient on the source image first so take the gradient of the source image for
in the x direction gradient and sourced in the source image in the y direction
and then i will both gradients and this is actually very you have to get
the story right because if you can't i mean it's very tempting to say well
you want cheaper from a computationally just to kind of what is fact great here
and here
but actually the grid would be completely wrong and will go over what's the case
and actually
there's some advantages to doing that disadvantages but you'd actually have
partial derivative with respect to the wall of z
zero because there is no p they're all because you have removed p because he
this is something very special here so
is it is economically and you guys will come and go over that a lot
in the original lucas kanade i was extremely important that you took the derivative of
the source image first then what rather than actually
warping the source image thing getting gradients so that's the first
now the second step is you've also so essentially got gradients for every single pixel
in the image
but again we saying well individual pixels are really noisy so i need some way
so to say this is an by an image
i've essentially got two in square degrees of freedom in terms of where the pixels
so obviously one nice thing to do would be to constrain
and this is the constraints of how all these pixels so to say i've got
it is defined
as the integral
of f
dg during a certain amount of time
that's a from zero
two delta t
now every because i made
which is also
dp dt we've seen is now several times
the rate of change of momentum and so i can substitute that in here
and so i find them
the integral
one zero to delta t
the community
the team
and that makes me move to the
domain of
so i have
now simply the integral
over the from some
momentum p i do some final
well meant and f
so that is
the final momentum
the initial moment so what and imposed does
it changes
the momentum
there is a force that acts
on something for a short amount of time could be a little longer as you
will see was rockets and that gives it a change in a moment
if we
i have an object that we drop on the floor
so we have an object mass and
and we drop it on the floor
and we let it fall over the distance h
that is going to hit the floor
with a certain
speed we know it's down to velocity
and that equals
the square root
of two gh
if this were a completely
elastic collisions
which depends of course on the quality
of the object and it depends on the quality of the flow maybe it's super
bowl on marble will be almost
completely elastic
the ball would bounce back with that same
and if that would be a completely elastic collisions
then you can see that the impulse
that's the ball is given
that is given to the ball as the ball hits the floor to floor is
giving an impulse to the ball
and that involves equals two and three
the ball changes its momentum
it was first
MV in this direction and out and in this direction so change
it's too
and the solar impulse is given
to the ball
now if the
collision were completely inelastic
then the ball will just say
like a tomato i throw tomato on the floor goes
no speed anymore when it hits the ground then of course the impulse would only
be and
because then it doesn't come back up so there's no the change in momentum is
we have here too
balls that look like
they have a mass of o point one kilogram
so and
equals o point one kilogram
and i will drop them
from the height of about one and a half metres
and that gives them the speed when it hit the floor
of about five and a half
meters per second
so the momentum
changes to envy
so the impulse
equals two and
is about one point one
and that would be
a second
that means that
if the collision time
isbell thirty seconds
that the average force
actor camborne this ball
during the collision was the floor
in impulse divided by
delta t because remember that what i definition of impulse
so i only impose we get a feeling for average force
and for the ball that i will drop on the floor we done fast photography
i'll show you
some results of the fast photography with the different ball but nevertheless
we did it was the ball that i will drop on the floor very shortly
which is this one
that in fact i was only two millisecond it's hard to believe in full millisecond
entire collision occurs
and so if you substitute in you know too many seconds
you get forty
average four
fifty newtons
just imagine
this ball
has a mass of o point one kilogram
weight is one newton
and during the impact it weighs five hundred fifty times more
what an incredible weight increase
and the average acceleration their experiences during the impact is five hundred fifty times g
people play tennis
and they have species of hundreds of miles per hour
these are way higher than we have here ten times higher
and so the
weight increase
is even more
now if we
collision were completely inelastic
so that if
it would tomato
or nag and this one wouldn't come up
the average force
would still be approximately the same the reason being that
impose will be half
but if the impact time also half
and we impose one half that of course
the force the average force will be the same
very high
but for a short amount of time
so i want to show first want to show you now the
these two balls one is almost complete
elastic collision with the floor
whether this is a complete elastic collision depends not only on this ball whether this
is super bowl it also depends on the condition of the fraud this is not
a very good fraud is not marked
so when i drop this one
it doesn't come up to this point here
so it's not completely elastic collisions
but it bounces pretty much showed somewhere in completely inelastic
completely elastic
it's not bad
right it's not bad
now this one
what it
looks like
but they don't
this one is completely inelastic goes to the floor
and it goes clunk
this is a small one
but that's it
and sorry impact times