right done by chris pizza his group so basically it's alive sparql endpoint the whole
complete RDF data inside the wiki and you can just create so
it's also available on semantic web dot org and as you can just go there
and sense parker is the biggest getting information it's a bit complicated set up
it's well documented again but nevertheless it's
because you have to run it in the back and take a lot of space
on your hard disk because the database gets pretty big but you can do it
was pretty cool
one very nice thing is the semantic forms which is actually developed by your own
current west example accidentally earlier in the in peter for example
i want to show you where
interesting semantic mediawiki installation it's going to wikipedia
it's not done by as don't blame me it's
semantic media wiki about
popular them in
and the
it's numbers and company in new york actually
and the idea here is that if you have information about r
on the subject of the pages
know i was
i think it's definitely not politically correct but i think that but i actually think
that they have done great work on the user interface and thing so what i
really like about the pages of the content i liked what i have done with
user interface magic behind it freely shown that semantics
it can be used even if just thrown out in sixteen year-old boys
and what you have here for example is all the information you have about development
as in this example her birthday behave
sign how everything is available in RDF you can just go to the page load
in the RDF you can either features of the analysis but you can sort them
by these features you can that you can find similar chicks result based on the
semantic information in that case there's a lot of UI goodness for example if you
go changing these kind of pages
and this is the way to semantic forms can
you actually don't even have to deal with the whole semantic media wiki syntax
the only change that is form based figs and everything else happens in the background
completely transparent for the user
i can just choose which colour vision belongs to ensure the birthday
and other features that she has and in this case it gets updated automatically in
the background and it's hidden variables and this is very close to your question earlier
because the have a system like this
which is hiding
the syntax from each
i can actually also created what it's able to do it automatically because
fields and can change it anywhere like
and semantic forms also an extension to semantic media wiki they can be freely downloaded
than using your page so
there's nothing
happening here that's not available in the
and it did things open source and is available by you in this case here
for example the pictures is hiding a lot of the
syntactical complexity in this case
the question
they were
on the one hand
the interface is completely created inside the wiki
so you don't have to
know PHP HTML CSS and so on
you just have to learn to biggest and which means if you know this kind
of stuff doesn't help you all
so you have to learn the syntax for creating farms and so on
after you don't
it took me about
i didn't read semantic from succession myself so hard to learn it and in order
installer you it and have been implemented to me about one hour
category for example
to make it look nice and to make it fun to make a function of
this kind of stuff
it but the problem is that media week it's is already quite technical if you
look at the template syntax
it's really complex in this case
writing in new from scratch
it's hard
copy and pasting and changing the way you like
that's possible and pretty fast
i think that in this case you need someone actually who
is willing to do the technicalities
and also later the garden the wiki so it
i will not happen with simple uses it would be able to be able to
create forms on the fly to create this kind of information to this is more
and we can cite
computer network management so we will get back to this application later
another example is analysis of telecommunication calls
so as you can imagine
telecom companies have operational systems to
make calls were
and they can
store began
history of telecommunication calls
we want to analyse
and if they don't they also many telecommunication calls that if don't and i on
the fly it won't be able in the future
to analyse this kind of data
this is typically an example
we want to do
supervision monitoring
and this so much data that we have to do this monitoring supervision
on the fly
so use an approach
with a history
so it's the same kind of the same problem appears with the the internet applications
so for instance in rising data generated by
the bay
query on google recommendation system so
we want to be able to have a recommendation systems on the fly
when the
a different say have all and this automatically
it's the same for
clickstream analysis
another kind of application is monitoring all
power plants this is one example or in field installation is the same for instance
in power plants you have a system for managing
the power plant
and the the system is based on automatic
which makes the system work there's controlled
and it works
OK and there's another need which is the supervision
monitoring of the system
trying to understand the system goes well
if there are some three years
trying to explain the failures
in this case as well
the amount of data generated by the operation of the system is very high
you can imagine
seven thousand seven hundred to get to censors everywhere in the poll
this is the first kind of applications
real time monitoring of information systems
there is another kind of application
which are application
basic data is streaming data
in this case for instance in
when you want to
do fraud detection
for instance in the system
nothing in english it's not the
ATM machines
and in stock market information
so i we get back to to this example
all these systems
that the basic application needs
two processes directly this week
the work and going to present you
and answer to be generic tools for doing so
instead of building at
programs specialized programs
so i summarise in this slide the differences between
standard data processing
i mean here data processing with standard database systems
this is a data stream processing
i mean here processing data
with this
three approached on the fly
so far
monitoring and business intelligence applications
when you have standard the data processing
what you do is you
i feel
data warehouses very large data warehouses and then you like queries and data mining to
the data where
the problem is that
in some cases they are so much data but the data were would be
too high
two large
what data stream processing technology
it will provide the possibility of querying and mining
on the fly
and still working the querying and mining on detailed data
four applications with basic streaming data
today with on the data processing technology
usually we work without any database system
capturing the streams and producing new streams
of the blood
and what we can expect from the data stream processing technology
is that
it's going to provide generic tools for processing such
training data exactly
the same
what happened with databases
which provide generate two
to deal with to manage data on
so let's
let's go deeper into some
we're going to have a look at for example also network management stock monitoring
and an imaginary one which is the
in world
the network management
the problem is the supervision of a computer network
so the computer network
works of the right
every day
we are not trying to make it work
we are trying to monitor to analyse
times the cardinality of y
now if i had a graphical model
the dependencies
we also had long range interaction
and this will become order of elton y square
if i had three times interactions they get the three up here
so you can see that very easily this gets very expensive
more to the point
if i had some very long range interactions there will be completed short
those long range interactions i would need to carry around with me
so there's something called the weight of the junction tree
not gonna going to find this in much detail but as soon as he will
go to implement something like this
you will run into it
so basically what you want to make sure is that a junction tree
o thing junction trees correspond to fast algorithms
that junction trees mean you can't resolve it
a lot of variations on this theme so for instance you can have variable length
boundaries and you will get something like this in a markov model
you can really go wild
in this case
explain what i did before
the only difference
so whatever
on is
because i was working wonderful
a connection lost means it follows the game
and i mean
you know that radio four and i
a study
it's a microsoft product
anyway so all
all time he is the difference is that
right the first significant first but
that's really the only difference k
any questions so far
that's what we did
we just do this
i mean we need linear storage
so how can we go
much fancier things
we could use considerably more complicated interactions
like what we have here
we can use really fancy labels
but very mine
the fancy landscape
the bigger this quantity you get
so if you got to really complicated model and maybe ten different labels
input in different labels maybe you can only have three time interactions
if you don't find the labels you could maybe afford into interaction
both of those would require order of one thousand
storage for instance
was two to the team is about to thousands and so is ten to the
so bear in mind that if you go to very fancy labels it will cost
you very dearly and implementing things
things get really messy as soon as you go to the two dimensional structure like
and placed in that case i'd actually recommend that you go and use the conditional
random field and sample
much cheaper
what we have here
dynamic programming
basically is like something like that to be
linear time and space if you do it right
and you get actually fairly nice structure estimation from
web page ranking
this is the end of while day
question so far
absolutely right you could
you could do you could start the recursion from the and then peel of things
from the in
for the last term
you would have it off while plus one in wales
what about what would happen is you could start feeling of things from the and
then you will get the first first
so you can either have forward backward algorithm or backward forward algorithm
it doesn't make computation much easier
obviously when you implemented you could also implemented from both scenes
so in america analysis this is called the bayes algorithm
burnett both scenes
so if you google for baby and
as solution of linear systems you find exactly that
good now
this is another instance
fairly strange loss functions people might care about
well we can go and the structure estimation to get some good reason
so the idea is
at least very
character way of looking at what search engine does
got a bunch of documents the i for the query
maybe also know something about the user
and so now if you want to do is you want to find ranking of
this is the most relevant documents come first
and let's for the moment the same
good ratings of the web page is going somewhere from zero to five
these might happen because
in the case of the star it
a company actually hired
essentially people in india and china
to sit down and for this query in a bunch of web pages related to
each other things
so that's pretty good
that says that in the best case quicksort is going to do well
how about let's suppose this split
it is always
let's say one ten
nine tenths
k one
ten times and
nine tenths timestamp
i suppose it's always
the case that
in that case are we like here we are lucky
displayed is really skew
we're clearly going to be unlucky
right because as
they want an
there's really in the middle it's analog and what do you suppose it is if
one tenth
to nine is that what you're unlucky
who thinks of little democracy here OK who thinks that that's the lucky case
OK i was can be fast and time and who thinks it's an unlucky case
OK so we have some great on who didn't vote
o on
come on
come on picture
it's always better is always better by the way too
say yes or no and be right or wrong because then you have some emotional
commitment to it and you remember better
OK around is sitting in inquiry
OK you get no
you know manipulate your own emotions well enough to remember things well
so those people who voted win over the people who don't know whether they're right
or wrong
so well let's let's take a look so here's the recurrence CNN is equal to
t one ten n plus t
nine tenths and
and we assume that this is
this part here is less equal to some CN
in order to analyse the soldiers to recursion tree for this
and c
this recursion tree
three years
that's equal to c
two one ten
eighty nine ten
now we have again c and the top
this gets complicated right as one can see
now over here we have
one ten and then were plugging into the recursion again so we now get to
one hundred
and over here we get t
nine one hundred
over here we have now
nine kansas city
that gives us here t of
l nine
one hundred and again
here we get t
eighty one hundred
and we keep going on
this equal to
probably all this
c and
one ten c
that is why we have one one hundred c and
that keeps going down until we get to order one down here
and over here
we have
nine tenths c
here see this is mine
one hundred
c and
this is now
nine one hundred c and this is eighty one one hundred c
and these things keep going
so they get banned or the one with the leaves are not all uniform depth
here right
in this site is way further up
then this side
right because you're only going down by nine-tenths each time
so in fact what's the height
looking for which the length of this path here
following this path down to this we might take the leftmost fine
somebody raise your hand
log base ten of
OK log
they ten
OK because i'm basically cutting down by a factor of ten each time and how
long does it take me to reduce to one that's the definition if you will
of one loggers
OK log base ten
OK what is this one
but this path
going that way
o lord they of and
log base ten over ninety
because we're going down by nine pence each time
OK once again essentially the definition of band
and everything in between there is somewhere between log base ten of and and log
base ten nine so that
OK so everything is it in between their
so now what i can do is do the trick that we did from merge
sort in looking at what the evaluation of the system by adding up what's
what's the cost to the top left
let's just see and
what's the cost to the next level
and what's the cost to the next level
c and
so every level we're still doing the same amount of work
and we take that all the way down
the last level so eventually we had some point was not equal to and where
we get getting things are less than or equal to c and because some believe
start dropping out
OK starting at this level
we keep getting
so we basically this part is going to be log base ten and then we
start getting things are less than or equal to c and
and so forth
until finally we
get at all
OK so t then
this can be less than or equal to
c and times what's the longest
this could possibly be
log base ten
so i can nights and
OK plus
the last class we talked about the brain
now let's talk a little bit about some foundations
so today
on monday
i want to talk about two very big ideas
and these ideas are associated
with sigmund freud
and b f skinner
and our psychoanalysis and behaviorism
and i want to talk about psychoanalysis
and behaviors next week
now one of these things
one of the things that makes these theory so interesting is there scope
most of the work going to talk about in this class most of the ideas
are narrow so that was somebody's that somebody's idea
about racial prejudice
but that's not a theory of language acquisition
we'll talk about theories of schizophrenia
but they are not
explanations of sexual attractiveness
most theories are specialized theories
with these two views are grand
here is the theories of everything encompassing just about everything that matters
day-to-day life child development mental illness religion war love
freud and skinner had explanations of all of these
now this is not a history course
i have zero interest in describing historical figures in psychology just for the sake of
telling about the history of the field
what i want to tell you about that is i want to talk about these
ideas because so much rests on the
and even more importantly
a lot of these ideas have a critical influence
on how we think about
the present
and that's the
for better or worse we live in a world profoundly affected by sigmund freud
if i had to ask you to choose the cycle name a famous psychologist
mostly freud he's the most famous psychologist ever
he's had a profound influence
on the twentieth and twenty first century
some biographical information he was born in eighteen
fifty is he spent most of his life in vienna austria
and but he died in london
and he escaped to london soon after retreating there
at the beginning of world war two
as the nazis began to occupy
where he lived
he's one of the most famous scholars ever
but is not known for any single discovery
instead is known for the development of an encompassing theory of mind one developed over
the span of many decades
he was in his time extremely well known
celebrity recognise on the street
and throughout his life he was a man of extraordinary energy and productivity
in part because he was very serious cocaine addict but also just in general uses
the high energy sort of person
he was up for the nobel prize in medicine and literature
didn't get either one of them
didn't get the prize in medicine because albert einstein
everybody loves albert einstein what albert einstein really wrote wrote a letter because they have
opinions about the nobel prize well let's think don't give the prize to freud
he doesn't deserve a nobel prize just a psychologist
while is almost universally acclaimed as a profoundly important intellectual figure is also the object
of considerable dislike
this is in part because of his character
he was not a very nice man in many ways he was deeply ambitious
the cause of promoting psychoanalysis the cause presenting his view
in defending it any was often dishonest extremely brutal to his friends
and i'm terrible to his enemies he was an interesting character my favorite freud story
was as he was leaving europe
during the rise of the nazis
as he was ready to go
to go to england from i think either germany or austria
he had to sign a letter from the gestapo gestapo agents intercepted
and demanded he sign a letter saying that at no point in even threatened or
harassed by the stop
he signs the letter
in any rights underneath it
the gestapo was not harmed in any way
in fact i highly recommend the gestapo everybody
it is
he had a certain aggression to him
he was also he's also disliked often hated
because of his views he was seen as a sexual renegade out to destroy the
conception of people
as good and rational pure beings in when the nazis rose to power in the
nineteen thirties
he was identified as jew
was devoted to destroying the most sacred notions of christianity and many expect to some
extent many people see in this way
and to some extent on this accusation has some truth to it
freud made claims about people
that many of us
maybe most of us would rather not now
well OK
what is he saying
well it's
if you have somebody who doesn't like freud what he said bill describe some of
the other things he said in in fact freud said a lot of things some
of which were not very rational
for instance he is well known for his account of phallic symbols arguing certain architectural
monuments are
subconsciously developed as penile representations and related to this we developed notorious theory penis envy
and penis envy is isn't an account of the developmental state that every one of
you who was female has gone through according to freud and ideas that you discovered
at some point during development that you lack the penis
this is not this is a catastrophe
and so each of you inferred
at that point that you've been castrated you at once
happiness was somebody had taken from you
you then
turn to your father
and love your father
because your father has a penis so these are the penis substitute you reject your
mother was equally unworthy due to her penis lack
and that she serious psychosexual development
now that the sort of thing you know about freud you're not going to have
a very high opinion
of him or his work
at the core of freud's explanation the more interesting idea is is a set of
of immense intellectual importance
and the two main ones are that's the two main ones involved existence of an
unconscious motivation
and the notion of unconscious dynamics are unconscious conflict
which lead to mental illnesses
in so social social construction part of this is very important
so that means that somebody has taught us what's food while our family has taught
us our culture taught us but the food industry has taught to what food and
what's not for but not only that they've taught us what constitutes healthy food unhealthy
they've been very influential in teaching us how much of things we should eat
and look at that in this commercial that you're about to see
and also the social context this
who's deciding what you should be
and here there's a very male-dominated thing you'll see pretty quickly
and what you see in this is that this man has been told in men
who watch the obviously email or in the sort of thing that that i've seen
watching sporting events in the life this very interesting theme here and this not too
hard to pick up
so let's play this
so we may need to have a high volume on this because this is pretty
now this is needs a more by k
and again volume
OK i try to correct this problem
you know it's possible i've got my own
i have my soundtrack
the there when again any volume
let me try it again
here we go
all right so what are what are some of the things that you pick up
when you see something like that
i mean there's obviously the manly thing what what messages being given to the men
who see this yes
OK that even healthy is a girl thing to do
correct what else
real and many me that's correct yes
small portions are bad that's right yes
OK all men wanted because they're variety of men in their yes
OK the man the man is in charge of his dietary destiny he's making own
decision as you said
no woman is going to tell them the key ch for that you may have
missed it but but in the song there will show this later in class again
but in the song they say that i want you kesh anymore and go by
the total fluid things like that yes
OK that's right i mean it's well it's it's it's not said directly but that's
inferred isn't because all these are you know they're doing almost all kinds of things
and there eating the texas double whopper that they're not showing them killing over from
the triple bypass surgery
right here right because you waste your money for by these walls portions the healthy
food that's exactly right
OK longer sit-down meals are necessary because you can just go by it all of
a sudden OK you guys role right is an interesting how many messages are embedded
in that short advertisment
and it's done with song it's done visually all sorts of things are embedded in
there and i'll show you some other advertisments later that are oriented to man make
that same argument that
if you're a man nobody is going to tell you what the
burger king mine but nobody and so that becomes very interesting theme in these advertisments
so that's what that's and we could show you dozens and dozens of these sort
of things we will over the course of the class each one of them very
OK the next one and like to show you
is the KFC ad and this ran fairly recently i know if it's still on
the air but and fairly recently look at this and then we'll
analyse the themes in this
all o
here in the
OK so
what's embedded in this manner
KFC and now
now is healthy right yes
OK so there was the family theme here that now the TFC is healthy it
becomes something the whole family can enjoy yes
OK it still tastes good despite not having transferred yes
OK you don't have to change things because it's now built into the healthier quote
healthier versions yes although in that
OK so again please
those were exciting their kids this is there yes
is more important than family right and what about what about how fast and how
the sort of lack of control and now i can kind of binge on are
you don't that the weight of the family sits down to eat
it can be an accident it's an african-american family
depicted here so there are a lot of interesting things going on in this little
video clip now there's the political
in business history this because KFC is is larger companies it is owned by larger
parent company believe it or not called yum brands
and young brands owns owns other food related chains like talking about all but yum
brands responded in a very interesting way
when the call to remove trans-fat first came out
and they were pretty slow off the mark to do something about this and it
was after
lawsuits were filed that they actually made the change but here they are boasting about
the change
presenting the
the picture to the world that well look at what this wonderful thing we did
we took out trans fats and now you can eat as much of it is
you want is they don't say about one could infer that from the advertising and
the fact is food is healthier if it has less transfer but it depends on
what fats swapped out for because if you you put a healthier fat and then
it's then you get a certain amount of improvement but if you put less happy
healthy family and you get some improvement but last but also switching out the trans
fats from another kind of that doesn't change the calories are all still has the
same number of calories and obesity is a huge problem in the united states especially
in the african-american community and other minority communities
and so to imply that now you can you all you want
you've been issued free to get if you will
some people might consider
not the right message
when we think about the way food is marketed
we have to ask ourselves how are these messages frames
who would have been targeted what the message is that of course what the impact
is and you guys over the course of your life have been exposed to an
number of food messages an enormous number
so far greater than i was when i was a boy
and they've come in different forms
when i was a boy there is one form in one form only
and it was cartoon it was on saturday morning cartoons there was advertisments for foods
on that it was mainly for sugared cereals
the boy
if you think about your advertising landscape
so much different than mine was
how is it different
no no no
and i
they patients
she is
you might national
or two
the story of conscious mind
one of
what for
also company
it was before
and so i
do of course
this will not be
the going
but i mentioned
four for
also on what we want our
four i might
all right
of the core
and what happened now is
what do you worry
o was
in the world
well is the world
o conference what kind of different cultures
it is important
what you want
one more thing
but that's the problem
o or one we
thank you
four or
well a lot
one or
don't launch for i come look for
of this one will
o information
so what is the problem
in my opinion
where is complex
this is line
knowledge are
we have to use proper
you are right
what's going on in fact one
the investment
to play it safe
we are going to try to have an analytic solution and then use the lasso
penalty tool made to see the coefficients of those base letters that were not helping
at all
and i guess summation now now
this organisation is going to be the in a very very very large space
and so on
i think this is the first time that i cited reference for you to identify
as possible the reasons for solving these for our idea of loss functions
so now let's look at the traditionalism methods and what i have here on the
right is the template that we just
this cost
and so
bagging ordinarily for regression was using the square loss absolute
two lonely seed or in the case of bargains and so if you look at
these if absolutely zero
there's no memory
so if so n minus one
become CEO and when we
well that here there's no memory
so every tree
that is added into lagging has no notion of the all the trees that have
already been selected
and it is in our tool
the sun namely
have some balls
without replacement building and buying formulation actually called for bootstrap samples of size n
a bootstrap sampling with replacement and it can be shown that is equivalent to half
samples without replacement
so so it is an or two in the case of bagging
data base learners
with typically a
trees and in particular they they have a large and growing trees
and then we see when we get to market
that is why
there are situations where this is not
the best thing to the coefficients
the coefficients in bagging or simply one over
namely the the average they are not fit to the data so bagging doesn't have
the post processing of feeding the coefficients to the data after the trees have been
selected just simply assigns the same coefficient to all the trees
in other words what bagging is doing is doing one of the three possible perturbations
it's perturbing that i distribution
because he has
no memory
a bagging is parallelizable because every tree
that seems have it's built every tree that is added to symbolise bill without
concern for the trees you could literally
it's funny every
many of these are main problems entirely from machine and get all your trees back
so that's an advantage
in our you can play with by using the i've read package and we've seen
the iplayer package that is the hybrid that come
let's let's look at a little example of bargain in actual
so very simple that said
from there from the
ESL book the DSL is the element of statistical learning book dissect classic in our
and therefore references etc etc in the back
and so this is one particular example from that book so very simple it's five
the most strongly correlated don't stand
standardize normal variables with correlation of point nine five
and then the response the world is so i two class problem generated according to
this rule
and so
so again the response depends only on x one
we building the response ourselves and so if
x one is less than
in this understand that i also it gives you a sense of the range means
and one standard deviation
so even if the
algorithm which is called the billiard which
which which run long enough will find the
posterior mean that of the posterior
and to again and again comparing it to other algorithms
which were proposed for problem by happen winter
and we find that amongst all the organs on this problem
it is problem but after on this problem you get a very good accuracy from
the it's also very fast
and around the sun
so if you read my thesis i run this on various other problems and you
also get yours very high quality solutions even larger problems in a very small amount
of time
the main problem in terms of practicality of this algorithm is that i'm using a
full multivariate gaussians my approximation which will get huge if you lot of features if
you have two thousand features to have a covariance matrix of the two thousand weight
so one of open research problems is to try and use a less complex
representation of the gaussians so some people have used bag gaussians which is obviously one
extreme and that works fine for using a huge amount of coverage information do that
so interesting idea would be to try and use a more structured
approximations of covariance matrix in which is not just diagonal and not fully
i haven't seen anyone tried it yet interesting opportunity
to get to scale to bigger problems
meeting ones with lots of features
OK so
what about kernels
so you can apply this album with kernels as well
in fact
what you find is that if you look at the BP updates for this problem
the only depend on inner products between data points
and so if you want to play kernels all you have to do
actually my thesis you can just take you can just literally take all of the
equations you had for the EP updates and just find everywhere you take an inner
product and replaced with some kernel function
and you can use actually cries
so this allows you to
if it
linear decision boundaries so in this case i can choose
for example gaussian kernel
and i'll get decision boundaries that look like this
and the difference in his decision boundaries this time sharing the same data set
three times
just fit using EP
with three different
kernel with three different six
in my kind of functions
and that gives you a different different roughness to decision boundary
so this would be a small panel with no big
and again you see using the same IP over them but just replacing every inner
product with the form on the right
but this is an interesting question is how would you choose to grow it
right now because we were in a bayesian framework we can use bayesian model comparison
to to with
we have to invent any sort of new year's text issues kernel with
and so
as chris showed in this talk the way you can choose models in a bayesian
setting is just compute the posterior probability of that model
and the posterior probability of the model
is simply
this is simply the probability that the model assigns the data
integrated over all possible parameter
so essentially what that means is we pick the kernel
to get the posterior on w for that particular kernel
right and duty we compute the probability of our training set having interviewed out all
the possible way back
i can explain what that means geometrically
suppose i have
my sphere again going back my fear which gets caught
by my training data
and i have some posterior distribution which is in
in this in this simplified situation the
model evidence is simply the area of the region
because that's that's literally
the integral of all of those indicator functions so the probability of the data
in my in my simple case
it is just
times the product of all those indicator functions
so this is my model evidence
and also also saying is what's the probability that a random weight vector drawn from
my prior which satisfy all the constraints of data
just how many characters or the on sphere which satisfies the constraints
that's essentially what that area competitions such as the area
of that
these young here
that's your model evidence
and the next byproduct of EP is that you can get this model evidence out
and i would argue the former for that little bit there
but essentially as you as you running EP can get you can compute these normalizing
constants theta those messages that you can hear it and you can put them together
and get a good day an approximate model evidence for the entire model
so essentially you sort of collecting where every time you clip those multivariate gaussians at
each stage you can remember how much mass to take the ball and keep track
of how much mass is left
in your in your and your posterior essentially
this sort of intuition of our
and so what we do is we keep changing the kernel
and by changing the kernel going to change these hyperplanes because essentially we're changing the
data set is we're changing the mapping pointed out there so we can change the
way these hyperplanes are arranged in feature space because the changes in different kernels
and give different areas
on the sphere
and so i will use that
will compare the size of those areas to pick the best kernel
it's essentially what bayesian model comparison is trying to do so
in sort of an intuitive sense saying she was the kernel where unified chosen my
decision boundary randomly i would be very likely to separate the data
OK so
for the dataset but i showed you earlier this ends up being the highest probability
which is what i think is a bit intuitive i mean so what it does
is it uses the kernel
which is reasonably smooth
and the reason why you want to be smooth because if it was a random
smooth decision boundary i have a better chance of suffering the random complicated country
so if you're actresses talk in bayesian model selection is essentially the same argument there
program because i'm telling you i'm not sure what
you know
anyway it's interesting to think about the a bunch of nash equilibrium so for instance
so think what the
this this is this is
this is an equilibrium that the splitter offering dollars using seven dollars an equilibrium if
that user has been accepted although there is no reason for split off from more
and at this point is going up dollar
and that jesus doesn't want to do that
offering two dollars accepting two dollars also nicolas offering three dollars accepting results in
these are all equilibrium
if you're you're here there's no reason neither player the standard previous so that's why
it's kind of interest
you see that
is also
the reasons why
o thing
i mean it's for me to it is actually glory have different
you know in some sense correspond to each player acting in a more aggressive manner
and the other and
you could
one way might analyse this is if you also
use something called utility theory where you say well how much is three dollars were
how much does it work with the happiness they get from three dollars kind of
depends on how much money you have already if this was if this was thousands
of dollars so was one thousand to two thousand three thousand is actually change the
way people play
you know if you think about so i'm not going to go in that direction
but it's kind of interesting things
OK one more thing
in game theory is so we can also help help minimax optimality can also help
us to think about posting this slide is an indian outside just to put it
so this is the thing about this thing so everyone familiar with this thing
so imagine you have an algorithm that for any distribution or things like the available
for instance for any probably feature weighting function with some datasets this algorithm is able
to find the rule in some class they get less than forty percent from the
boosting languages as the weak hypothesis OK so i from is that a large data
for any weighting function over that i have semantic algorithm is able to find the
rule they get
are less than forty percent
then with adaboost does is it gives away to use this algorithm
it basically runs the algorithm on uniform distribution gets back to rule reweights the data
around again it's back rule reweights the data use it in a way that
that has the property that by taking those rules and using a weighted vote of
the rules you get that we all have here going to zero
OK so it was nice algorithm that can like you take these rules and combine
them way
and one thing that's interesting to think about this is a weaker statement native but
imagine that you are kind of trying to come up with adaboost and and you
might want to think she is even possible to do this
i mean
how do we know that
i'm guaranteed for any weighting function over the dataset there exists a rule in my
class as they are less important some assuming that
why should that suggest it's even possible to have a weighted vote was very close
to zero
before we actually tried to come up with adaboost you know this is asking the
so the nice way to think about this is again
so the
this is the
i just picking some numbers less than fifty percent of the with boosting the rate
at which this goes to zero the number of times you have to call
the algorithm
it depends on the gap between these AR fifty percent
so for instance if they all have their less than forty percent of the gap
between one
roughly you have to call one over that's where number of times
one of the gap roughly
in order to get
one can get squared loss
what happened to get this area down the so so that the the rate at
which the school stands can depend on how much better
fifty percent
but if you for just taken
so here's how
so we could use a nice way to do this is a zero sum game
so imagine that and the copyright on my examples of the set up and down
here i write all the hypotheses and i
in my hypothesis space
we made
and have the entry here b one
if this hypothesis makes a mistake on an example in zero to get the correct
this is like alot matrix OK says this hypothesis does or does not become if
they can give an example of big matrix the thing is i think that's the
thing about the matrix
so what we're we're assuming we we start with the assumption that for any
waiting for any probability distribution over the column
there exists around
was cost around that one the algorithm a will find
this cost is less than point four
because the cost
distribution is exactly the probability of making a mistake
we assume the star which was the free distribution over the examples there exists a
hypothesis in fact the algorithm finds one those there is the most
twenty four
let's see what is the minimax theorem tells the minimax theorem says if it's true
for any distribution over the columns there exists the road cos most point four that
means there must exist the distribution of the rows
so for any color the expected cost is point four
now what does that mean for us
OK was just interpret the minimax theorem in this context so
OK so as so we are given a pretty distribution over there
problems are just around the the most point four that implied by the minimax theorem
there is the distribution over the rose for the first caller expected customers point four
particular what that means must exist a weighting function over the reals
distribution weighting function
that was the mean of expected cost most point four
it means that for every
for example for every color
the about
goes at least sixty forty in the right direction
the reason for the pick one of the ages from distribution we have at most
forty percent chance of getting the right answer another way of saying that is about
sixty forty
that makes the whole world
see that normally minimax thinking and this is the probability distribution and
we're saying it is the point four chance of making a mistake if we pick
one random but equivalent to saying that if think of it as of o
the vote because only sixty four right
good so what does that mean
oh no no no no tried
i can make a difference
and there's nothing
so what does that mean
that means that there exists a weighted vote of the hypotheses that gets everybody right
to say
i'm just going
the new approximation of these approximations are going to come up with an approximation
of this guy
and to web is this approximation is very simple
these probability distribution here
because these things are just point beta distribution OK we can
and guys on i'm going to
and times
from these distributions
OK so i'm going to sample from the discrete distribution and time we sample times
one that i'm building
basically my new approximation is the on pierre called
the reason the value of k
so why does he do the job
why does the genome unforgettable that
it does the job because essentially
if you have a weight which is quite high
the policy assumes so omega and
i notice is is i value then the probability that when you're gonna resampled capital
times from these discrete distributions the polity you going to make the
number valuable
the particle i know it is quite high so the possibility can copy multiple times
the particle i know it is quite high so that's why you can multiple copy
most likely online
on the contrary it is guy
basically small
compared to one of and then essentially when you're gonna resample capital and times when
this guy you might be
you might be kind of lucky that is well you might have been nice guy
on you might have basically
you might have kept one of the particle with the lowest
so you know completely best actually you can keep some particles with low weights but
it quite small possibility most likely does more weight it that survives to this was
sampling scheme in this part in this new approximation
you have got rid of all those particles with low weights OK so it's really
very simple idea
now also
if you look at it now
we can see that the article is becoming a real mess because now seen
everything we've done
was such that
the particle we writing where statistically independent all those guys with independent samples from q
OK that's all but now you have been we have in case where you resample
n times from this
so at this level
the particles are not independent anymore this new resampled particles because it for this new
particles denoted should be next this new particle this was sampled particle it's true that
you can add xt that i which is equal to xt that g four different
from g
OK so particles
if there are no more statistically independent case so i don't think it's becoming much
more difficult to study because you can forget about all this time that limit to
but never mind we can still do something
what does it do graphically
and that she was acquired graphical or they should but
the that actually so remember what we are doing assume for example you interesting in
approximating this guy using your importance distribution
so you would sample n particles
according to sample according to an importance distribution
then you with the reweights each of those guys according
the weight which is proportional to p of q
and then what you're doing is that now you have a weighted sum of the
mass on the resampling operation simply consists of sampling capital ten times
and these
weighted empirical measure to obtain capital and new particles which which all have the same
weight equal to one and
OK obviously
basically this guy for example it has multiple copy so you see i put it
kind of as a bit bored but is actually simply because this article has been
copied multiple times
that's it now if you look at the resampling thing
OK so it's the kind of
way to focus your computational really falls in the right region of the state space
but clearly
what you should be clear about is that if the importance sampling was bad
it is not going to get any better OK because these
and can way something approximation if you think about it it just introduce additional notes
the fact that for example
the dead sea on the twenty right my my good by my my importance sampling
approximation if the sampling it doesn't get any better than this is to keep that
in mind the key
well of particle mid-atlantic ontological calorimeters to come up with clever importance distribution you can
to kind of overcome the the ambiguity that we have from the column
now i don't know what the organisers thing but i think it might be a
good idea to give you a three three-minute break at this point because it's like
you know can any human really concentrate for an hour and a half
you know you could stand up to hug your neighbour do a handstand or wheel
and then we start again three minutes
OK so
now i want to think about
how are going to deal with this
the idea of making joint decisions and to exploit the fact that the objects that
with segmenting here are expected to be to possess some coherence it would be very
surprising if adjacent pixels very often had different labels that his for foreground versus background
you really wouldn't expect to see a chess board of foreground background labels you know
the brown squares being foreground white squares being background that would really be go
counter to what you what you know about the natural world and the the typical
properties of objects in the natural world so
you know we'd like to
link up the decisions between
and so
when making a decision about this big so here
will be good to refer to
you really quite a lot of the pixels in the image maybe over quite can
some considerable difference distance because the degree of correlation about object identity is likely to
be rather large in the image and if you can delivery took a picture of
of an object and very likely that object filled a large proportion of the image
in maybe half the image in which case you know is it going to be
necessary to communicate over half of the diameter of the image because that really is
an awful lot of a little north of communication of of pixels so
you know potentially
you know if there are a million
pixels in the image then there might be a million million connections to make you
know perhaps not by that many but order of order of a million million connections
and that is not going to be practical we can do a thousand million things
in the second on the computer a million million things is going to take a
thousand seconds sounds like we have to do a lot better than that
and so
what i want to talk about is how to exploit markov models to do this
much more effectively and
i guess you may have had to have been lectures lectures on markov chains and
markov you know how much is being
my model so you know i can go through the next few slides like movie
and it'll just you know excite memories that have already been laid down in your
brain from from previous lectures and but you know my first movie is in the
first order markov chain you know the simplest model model anybody knows attacks briggs example
the weather today condition on the weather yesterday it's not so funny actually the you
know two kinds of weather in britain there's this kind of this kind and
and you know you make a little two by two matrix for the conditional probabilities
of the state today condition on the state yesterday OK i can i can run
through this contact and then when i want to do
the state today conditional state say two days ago do i make a new mark
of you know new conditional matrix probably makes for that no what i do is
just use the same model assuming some translation invariance through time and just drop the
same car conditional probabilities down between tuesday and wednesday in the same again between monday
and tuesday in each one is two by two matrices and i raise the two
by two matrices to the cube to the for power because multiply this one by
this one by this one and now i've got the correlation of thursday with respect
to monday
OK this is i'm reliably informed by zubin is all trivial to you guys
and you know the second order markov model predictive text here is that goes in
practice predictive text can needs to go back to tokens not just one token to
actually get anywhere close to kind of superficial model of a vertex so now if
you want to generate city sentences at random i guess you've all done this kind
of thing
you started off with three words on the two guess enough and then you draw
around from the third world word from your
dictionary of probable you get the city the city random sensors this is simulating the
try try word model of speech they can protect small
and you know you have to dash of if you had dasher
yes you know better is all about exploiting rather beautiful way these kinds models
and in speech they use these kinds of
they use markov models in
i guess basically similar way but of course the the tokens in the markov model
are not words not because you know life is not that simple you have examining
a signal like this one and trying to decide what the word is so a
typical word model consist of a series of states which are just kind of time
like phases of the progression through the word and so
then we have a job is serialized object which is in the payload
to carry both i code in our data
OK now talk about the security framework
first of all a few points to make his security in general was
never solved problems
does have a well defined framework in which the
holes or
aspects that relate to security are laid out in the final
and we'll discuss the framework
the document is called security architecture for active networks
it's a working group to draft document sandy murphy NAI labs
maintains it
there has been maintaining it
and there's
information on the mailing list
if you want to get it
was that was on the level abstractions obviously there's no security policies
there subjects which act on objects and their the actions which take place
if you go to RFC twenty eight twenty eight no legacy
IP document
they define different types of attacks
unauthorized disclosure
deception disruption
usurpation of assets
but in an act what changes and active network is we have our own
different types of assets now
with our new paradigm
there's obviously the node
his execution environment
the person sending the package and there's the active code
travelling through the and and modifying
the operation of the network
so if we take these assets and look at how one can
impact the other
this is just kind of i don't threat table here
so this column
can see threats from
these columns over here
yes meaning yes you consider threat
you have the code
from one active application could try to interfere with code from other active application if
there were no
security or resource bounds in place
but to take that a step further the framework has looked at the state of
where we are now
in terms of protection
so again if these folks in this column
we try to indicate how well they can be protected from components in this column
and the not really is
indicate current research is still going on in that area
for example
we start getting down to the EU especially the note
if the node is corrupt he can pretty much do anything you want to
to anybody that's flowing through
whereas one EE e
the node can enforce pounds on one EE e
interfering with another he e
so if we look at the steps in the life of an active packet they
relate to security
we can see these these steps going on OK so starting with the packet being
received at the node
hop by hop key identifiers taken from the package
they just in denote
and it's integrity cheque
to make sure that the package is OK if it fails the packet simply dropped
next we have to know which either the package is going to go towards
or to be executed with in
and remember we have the channel so the
to do that
so the main filters applied to find out which domain and therefore which channel the
the packet is assigned to
within the end up options credentials can be placed
and the credentials there can be multiple credentials to allow
activity for the code to do
various predefined
so these credentials have to be verified
and the way the framework is defined now
if a section if one of the potentials fails that
that event
can not occur
however all the credentials which passed
those events can still
still have to go on to the package even though some credentials failed the package
can still go through
and continue
twenty four hundred metres
the pressure is three-quarters of an atmosphere
according to this equation
water doesn't boil there on the degree centigrade here at sea level it does
but it three-quarters of an atmosphere boils at more than ninety two degrees centigrade so
you can never time
you get a soft-boiled egg you can have time to properly because you used a
hundred degrees centigrade effect the kitchen their tables
which indicated how long you would have to borrow potatoes
get and what you want to
ninety degrees centigrade that's all you can get you can go in high
mount everest whatever
seventy two degrees centigrade there's no way you can get yourself there's some real hot
food so will pressure-cooker there of course
if you go to thirty kilometres altitude
you asked this equation with the pressure is this one
f of an atmosphere twenty seventeen millimetres mercury
water at twenty degrees centigrade would boil
at that altitude
i want to show you the phase diagram
of what
this is the phase diagram of water
and what i want to do
is i want to
take some water
and bring to an altitude
of about
thirty kilometres
twenty degrees centigrade should start to boil
how do i know that
this is the phase diagram for water
zero degrees centigrade on the degrees centigrade
this is pressure in
millimetres mercury
the scales are not very clear
o we have
they a forty from the web form
if you
take twenty
degree somewhere here
and you have water
at one atmospheres
and twenty degrees which is what we have in this room
and i'm going to
a lot of pressure on it's going to put in the bell jar there
i'm going to take all the air out of the pressure goes down and down
and down
but the temperature is not changing
you go down
in the liquid
these liquids
they liquid
this liquid
this liquid until you reach this point
and then
you have coexistence between the gas and liquid called the paper in the case of
and and that means it will start to world
and that happens
looked up
at the pressure of about seventy millimetres mercury which is equivalent to thirty kilometers altitude
so we have here some water
forty here
when the bell jar
this is a
nine teams
century vintage
of the bell jar
very slow
i will take at least five minutes before we reach that low pressure
you see here
the wine glass
it is
and we'll keep an eye on it on and off
so when it starts to borrow
i can even read the pressure
that's not so important i want you to appreciate the fact that if you have
long enough
through the line
we're gas
and liquid and coexist with each other
that is our definition
warning so let me start the
one thing
and in the meantime
polynomial just as transformation you can basically you can eliminate this guy and put it
up into the objective
to symbol manipulation basically
this is being minimized so
this is being minimized so the minimum what happens is this
because if you move this so there
this is going to be exactly equal to that site so we can eliminate the
slack by just putting it
like that
so this is the discovered the cleanest formulation of
the problem is in my eyes norm
this thing
which is essentially a year
hinge loss and
the constraints in london
then in force
this amounts to one
the question yes
what about the method is use
could see
and she
did not same user
they're not the same as
well OK
sure sold a little bit like the alphas in this in this but there are
going to be
much less sparse
continuous so so so for their somewhat sparse
you know
so all
there are
sure so the concentration cell talk about that this is
it is important so to that being
OK so i slides but later but that would be sort of a greedy approach
where you just basically have occurred w
if you do the max and you add in the constraint writers constraint generation you
know column generation is latin for is a bundle methods this is
also related to that so that i mean that's an approximate method the problem is
we keep re solving this QP
multiple times and people have suggested this is exactly what thomas hoffmann and his students
did and so on and so
it's a feasible method is just
i think it's much slower we much slower and you know if we
the goal of this was to write the entire problems
in a polynomial form and then you have
all kinds of options
try to solve it right so when you have discontinuation you're sort of stuck to
one approach when you just write down the whole thing explicitly
and small
you can use second order methods you know you can use MEX three can use
whatever interior point methods to solid fast et cetera et cetera so so there's advantage
of reading the entire thing declaratively as a small
programme because then
now you can
used entire toolbox as opposed to sticking to particular method
from the beginning so that's advantage and
so this is busy this this form of the the kind of done right so
all you have to do we have a structure problem you write down the LP
for it
take the dual
me this qpis to get into only
you know a mosaic
or c plex or
what are your favourite optimizer is
and you don't you don't need to write any more
could really just need to
the second feature functions right down the LP take all
and the problem solver idea general kind of toolbox
like like simplex or music that will solve structured prediction problems for you
same principle
a clear
so in practice of course you want methods that actually
optimized for particular structure much better and something that i worked on
quite a lot is trying to exploit the structure and this QP
to do this so these things faster than off the shelf optimisers does but but
the the convenience in high in being able to write something down declaratively and not
the only algorithm we know the runs in less than n log n time
counting sort so we better use that one
sort of bootstrapping get an even faster more general could
just erased
the running time counting sort
in order k plus and
remember that
in the range of the numbers is one to k
or zero became minus one
so we can when we when we sort by particular digit we should use an
organ algorithm because that then this thing will take an organ for one round is
going have multiple rounds is going to be worse than organ
so we're use counting sort
in each round
counting sort each digit
and we know the running time of counting sort here is order k plus and
OK but
i don't want to assume that my integers are split into digits for me
that's sort of
giving away too much flexibility
because if i have some numbering in whatever form it is probably written in binary
i can cluster together some of those bits and call that a digital
so let's think of our numbers in binary so suppose we have n integers
and there some range and we want to know how big arranged they can be
so let's say practical
way of thinking
you know we're we're in a binary world so that's so each integers b bits
in other words the range
from zero
to be
find someone else in my numbers are
nonnegative doesn't make much difference if the negative here
OK so i want to know how they could be i can handle
but i don't want to split into
let's think about i don't want to split into
bits as my digits
because i would have to be
and i would have to do the rounds of the sound of the number of
rounds this album is the number of digits that i have each one cost me
let's hope for linear time
and indeed
if i use a single bit k is too so this is the order
but then the running time would be order and per around and then
there are b digits
i consider them to be bits those or and times b
and even if b is something small like log n if five log n bits
them these are numbers between zero and minus one already know how to sort numbers
between zero and ten minus one in linear time here spending on log n time
so that's no good
instead what we're going to do is take a bunch of bits and call that
a digital
it is the most basic we can handle was counting sort
so the notation would be
split each and integer
in two the over are
are bits long
other words i think of my number is being in base two dr
and i happen to be writing it down in binary but cluster together are bits
i get a bunch of digits in base on the
and then there be over digits
OK so this be over are
is the number of rounds
and this base this is the maximum value i have in one of these agencies
between zero and two the are so this is in some sense the k
four around a round of counting sort
OK so
what is the running time i have the over all rounds
so be or are
sometimes the running time for rounds which i have and numbers
my value of k is to the are
this is what i read this is the running time of counting sort on this
this is the number of rounds
so this is you are
times and lost two to the are
and i am free to choose are however what
so what i'd like to do
is minimized
this run time
over my choices of are
so any suggestions on how i might find the minimal running time over all traces
of or
techniques not necessarily solutions
so when i say this because its asymptotic but forget the big over here
how do i minimize the function with respect to one variable
take the derivative so i could take the derivative of this function
by are differentiated by are set to the equal to zero
and that should be a critical point in this function it turns out this function
uni modal and are
and you will find the minimum
so we could do that i'm not going to do it because it's
it's a little bit more work you should try to home
and that the group velocity is the omega dk
and so
there there's no such thing as one phase velocity
for non dispersive medium there's no such thing as one group velocity it depends on
the curve only covers this case
so you have to know what we call the dispersion relation
in order to stable to phase velocities for what frequency
and this person is extremely common in physics
if we take deep waterways
the water waves
i would imagine that what is meant by that is that
water is deeper
the length of your wavelength that is probably the
operational definition
it's very
this process
the dispersion relation which
i will not arrive
i didn't arrive at you for the strange
omega square
equals gk
is just the gravitational acceleration
please as
divided by rho
times k two to power three
and as
it is the surface tension
which is full water
about one point o seven two
four meter
i don't know whether you've dealt with surface tension into one
if not you just can accept this as
and the density of water row
is about a thousand
kilograms per cubic metre
of course is a little different for seawater that
nice number sort of tool to use
now this ester is only important
four very short wavelengths
if you take the case that land on
is much much larger than one centimeter
then i can show you that the astronomers
so let's take lambda equals one leader
like that is one meter
and k is two pi divided by line that you can calculate
about sixty two in as i units because g is nine point eight
and you can also calculate now
s divided by road
times k two third
remember case two pi divided by that
and this now
is point zero two
very small
so for this case you might as well before first first order approximation forget that
so you can write down now that omega
divided by k
which is the phase velocity
in this case
comes out to be one point two five meters per second
the the
and what you also find and i will show you that
very shortly that the group velocity
is half the phase velocity
and so is half this value
and if you want to know what frequency
one is hopping up and down
the frequency of course is the
the phase velocity divided by lambda
that is about one point two five hertz
so it's a little faster than one oscillations per second
if we have the case the latter is much larger than one centimetre
i will continue here
the lambda is much much larger
and one either
i can use the
the dispersion relation
and i can calculate now with the phase velocity and group velocity is in general
so i know now that omega
to high degree of approximation
is the square root of g k
i forget the ester
and so we got divided by k
which is the phase velocity
it is therefore description of g
divided by k
we agree
and notice
that this is
therefore proportional
due to square root of the wavelength
because one of k
so what it means is that the larger the wavelengths
the higher the phase velocity
let larger k smaller the higher the faithful
what now is the group velocity
the group velocity is the only god came
so you take this one then you take the derivative
of the square root of j g times k
so you first get you one half
and then you get your square root of g but now we have to divide
by the square root of k
so you get a times square root of g over k
but the square root of g over cables the phase velocity so is half the
phase velocity
that's what i
already anticipated here
so for me
one way in which are much larger than one centimetre
you see that
the higher
the lost city
the larger
the waif-like
and you also see that the group velocity is half the phase velocity
let's now take the situation
that lambda
it's a much smaller than one centimeter doesn't even have to be all that much
just smaller than one centimeter
then it's the second term
that completely dominates
so now you get that omega square
there were very good approximation is as
divided by rho
times k two the third
so now the phase velocity
which is only god divided by k
is now describe wrote
the second
all of
three role hundred
they are
after the war
for each
and we will
prior to
you might want
for all
there are one or
this more
the same problem for that
u s
this is more probable on
there are two
one is
the problem
alright which
i think
the graph
these of of the
there are no
so o far
what food is all about who has taught you what constitutes what's acceptable to eat
what's good for us
and there are a lot of interesting things that the food industry has trained us
to believe that experts say may or may not be true
because the product has the word fruit in its name
doesn't necessarily mean it actually has fruit in it
now is that deceptive is misleading all these are very interesting questions
and this causes i said well emphasise psychology biology
in politics of so let's talk about each one for just a moment
first of all what you choose to eat and what the world chooses the which
has enormous in fact impact on the public health on the vitality of countries and
even on world politics with the recent spike in food prices around the world that
you've all heard of because of rising energy costs the the corn ethanol conversion in
the united states and other things like that is really changed the world landscape and
a lot of interesting ways that help some countries and her other countries but it
certainly has changed the food landscape
so those are very important political factors this talk about psychology from any you guys
have been trained by your culture
define what constitutes the flu
and food is associated with feelings
some people only when they are stressed some people even more when they are stressed
some people the less when they stressed some people eat for comfort some people get
enormous psychological gratification from food other people couldn't care less they have to be reminded
so what's the difference in there
now how many of you when this is gonna show of hands how many of
you would say you eat more when you're stressed
and how many people would say you eat less
OK looks like about a fairly even split was in which is interesting we've done
some research on this in the past and found that men and women differ in
response to question of course the level of stress matters and even the type of
stress people are feeling is an academic stressed social stress and the like
that depend that determines in part how people respond with reading so psychology is a
big player here
we like certain foods we have positive associations with them because of our families
in all these red and marketing of course all these factors come into play in
shaping how we feel about for
by biology biology is an obvious player how many of you would say that food
can be addicted
maybe three quarters of EU law that's alot now actually the science on this is
pretty new and very interesting we'll talk about that in the class but for those
of you raise your hand and just tell me what do think what makes you
believe food can be addictive
somebody telling
OK so withdraw always the possibility we food for long time and the you stop
what's a high sugar diet or something and withdrawal symptoms occur will that might be
the actions occurring well says ideas about that
something else had and a lot of interesting reasons we've all heard the topic the
word chocoholic sugar addict we hear the words withdrawal and things and that becomes an
interesting part of the biology of
but course food has this cascade of effects once it enters our body it starts
even before it goes in our mouth we sense for coming in that sets in
the year series of metabolic and biological processes that are very interesting and then of
course once the food gets in the body there's lots of interesting things some good
things and some bad things and so we'll talk about what people are eating we'll
talk about what's good and what's not good and with the optimal diet might be
so are a few the topics that will be discussed in the class first we'll
talk about what you need and why
and what the world needs and why
how much is psychology how much is biology how much of it is world politics
all these things are very important players so we'll talk about this and then discuss
what what sort of things are shaping your diet but also the world's style and
the reasons behind the we'll talk about whether food could be addictive as i mentioned
just a moment ago we'll talk about whether for and promote health of course you
can if if done right
i will talk about the specific properties of food that promote good health and what
can be done to increase the opportunity of food to improve the public health international
an international way
will also discuss what we perceive food to be
and what we perceive is promoting health and that may be quite different than what
actually promotes health
are trans-fats battery trans-fats good for food never had transferred in it but it gets
labeled as having no trans fat that increase your perception of how good their food
is for you
and so the perception is really important here
will talk about genetically modified foods
if any of you who have come from europe will care alot more about this
issue in all likelihood than the americans
because it's been of much harder topic in europe european governments have taken stronger action
our good way of combining the prob is a good way to explain it
get some
some reasonable classifiers for example
the regularized fisher discriminant
regularisation is important as i said that we go to the paradigm
celebrate already and i'll go through several paradigms
well i mean there's there's different positions where this is possible and
i think it depends very much on the type of artifact
so there that this very simple things like you would like to know what other
bridges between
the electrodes because they measure the same thing
because this conductance between them and then you get some singularities
and so on so forth so so we have this different stages that you can
well so if we do RCA a it was on the walls
OK so
i mean this is the problem in this is it's it's somewhat also in engineering
problem so we we have to find for certain subject we have to find a
good and
robust way of
you getting this whole thing to work was the subject might mean that we just
made all these these kind of features because it does it's of no use as
as shown on the on the
comparison sometimes black box
with the game that you can get is is very low for some subjects so
we really bother using those and you would use ESP only
so the bottom line i think is is after
these twenty minutes
we go through a protocol which allows us to to get these individual spatial temporal
filters and so on so forth and already after having only two blocks we we
we try to see you know what kind of subjects this is and maybe some
occasionally we can we can say after two blocks that this is an illiterate
for BCI
at this point it semi-automatic
it's always you want to double-check so even though we have some means to do
it fully automatic we don't
really do it because it's it makes some sense to to to double-check whether so
to say the physics of the physiology is correct
but i think
i mean i think this was remarked and also and we all i mean machine
learning does not fully automated software that we give somebody we always have on
you know
point sort of points where we have to see and we we have to cheque
and interfere
and it's the same hit i think the same way
so just
i would like to
to have you
jointly with a little
all the calibration session
so this means relax
starting in a three to one second
and when you see letter at you imagine
moving your right and left end
why the up
and then you stop
when the other is not there anymore
OK so this is the random sequence
and it goes rather fast
this real time
should forget to relax
this is the typical and you do this for twenty minutes
and i think this part is really the bore most boring part of the experiments
so i have a small children so when
i had the
rough night
when i sleep after the second block
so the data amount is is very limited i think the that the one of
one of the experiments i i've done maybe five experiments in my life and one
of the experiments i've done with only five minutes of data
well i mean i pay them postdoc salaries and
and OK i mean it's something i mean we also have a journalist that come
and they
i just want to experience this and we don't pay them anything
also some friends
for example