coming here
and we can commend the telescope from here we can orient the telescope we can
drop ballast
very important we can terminate the flight
so we read that save the telescope and it starts drifting out over the ocean
because the balloon start
going with the winds at the altitude of hundred fifty
thousand feet
and those winds can vary anywhere from twenty thirty
miles per hour two up two
a hundred miles before we we try to fly only during the
they that the
when is low and that's the case in the spring
and in the fall we call that the turnaround
winds at these altitudes
twice per year
the change from about one hundred miles per hour to the west two hundred miles
was to the east happens in the spring and fall
and that's when we try to fly
when the winds are very low when they are in the process of turning around
we follow the balloon at low altitude five six thousand feet
a small airplane
i'm sitting here on the airplane
this is the typical airplane that we used to
hope from airport to airport
and stay as close to the balloon as we can
so that we can give terminate command and later
we can
recover the payload
which is an eventual by itself
in australia it is much harder than in the united states this was pass
but in australia there are no
airports in the desert and sort it is way harder to help
from place to place
i'm taking into australia now he's alice springs
when we launched this flight
in the days before we
had balloons
weather balloons test balloons which we drove up two hundred forty to fifty thousand feet
and then we probe the wins at that altitude
and the
people who did that
good reasons to believe that the balloon would you go sort of in this direction
well maybe here but in any case it would go north north-northwest
and so we look all these radio stations in australia
to look out for the balloon wave radar reflectors so they could give us an
early warning
because between here and here there are really no air
o ports
so if we follow this by airplane
you can land during the day at some
but really there are really no
no runways so that's pretty dangerous at night you could land here
so we were hoping that these radio stations would give us an early alert to
tell us where the balloon is
what happened however the balloon went straight down
and then was sunset so we don't know exactly where the balloon is at sunset
we can see that we
of radio contact was it
so we were flying close to it
and then at sunrise we picked it up we could see it
and then here when it was getting close to forbidden zone because there's
commercial flights here
we cut it down so we gave the air the radio command which separates the
from the balloon the balloon is very brittle it's very cold there
the balloon shatters
breaks in pieces comes down
and if everything goes well then parachute
brings the telescope safely
back to earth
this is the person that we contacted during the flight
try to
draw the attention of local people
you do that by flying which you airplane low over the house this person live
in the desert and its nearest neighbour was some seventy miles away from the
he was crazy
he was always drunk
he was shooting kangaroos in the desert
there's no windshield here
you will drive sixty miles an hour
and then he would change his kangaroos and shoot him
any other crazy games
which i didn't like at all he would put the dog on the roof
he gave me a demonstration once i was with him in this track
and he would drive sixty miles per hour which slammed the brakes in the dogwood
chemical through the air
and then he would say you can teach an old dog any new tricks
we encountered
wonderful animals during recovery
koala bear
quiet peaceful
very lazy online
most into one students
and then we got close to the payload
OK so they're gonna hafta
to get to the payload
there was this nasty glamour
he was about six feet long
let me tell you i was really scared it scared the hell out of me
but of course i didn't want to show that so i said to my graduate
student there's no problem these animals are harmless you go first
and he did
and it turns out they are harmless
and during the entire four hours it took us to recover the payload get on
jack's truck
this animal was just sitting still didn't move at all that is his way of
thinking that
and we don't
see him them
beautiful animals these quantities
aborigines eat them it's very precious full by away
so here you see don brooks who was an american who came with me was
an electronic experts and this is alice which was the wife of
you see the payload here
from all over
but it's in good condition
the crash pad
is there are purposely to protect against impact
get lower decelerations and of course it's OK to
crashed bad
destroyed that's the whole idea
and and then when you come back a few days later analysis brings it's there's
nothing happens every analysis brings
nearly all in the ground
so it is front page news perfect balloon launch
and thousand what's the start of the space probe they call it the space probe
i had a long interview with this
with this news reporter
and i told him that the reason why we have to go high is because
of the absorption of x-rays into the atmosphere
but the article didn't get that across
they said they fly balloons because then the closer to the stars well
i suppose it is close enough but it's really miss the issue
of the absorption of the x-rays
which of course
that's the reason why we have to go up not
because we want to get closer to the stars
so now
go back to the blackboards
if i can find my way
so between
nineteen sixty six and roughly
late seventies
i had about twenty successful flights
from the united states
from canada
and many from
australia now we also had some problems we had some bad luck
twice during my flights the balloons spot seventy thousand feet that's the trouble cause
very cold minus seventy degrees
there jet wins
and a bit on the balloon
and then the balloon burst them when that happens
we don't have enough time to terminate the flight we can separate the parachute from
the balloon it happens all of a sudden
and then in general
the parish gets entangled
and then you get a free fall solely payload is entirely destroyed in that happened
we were lucky enough that several occasions we made some
well quite
here's the gentemplate four
the predicate extent cardinality which i probably should have given you more information about so
let's see if we can
no matter how long can i
OK so extend cardinality
predicate relates
a set or collection
two an integer so
it tells you how many elements are in the set
if you have an assertion
of the form extent cardinality
a b
you want to
i realize that in english as
its cardinality is b
eighty has be elements
with this one
are one
are two
no no
and it is all this
all these
functions that described
phrases fun
an arbitrary number of arguments
results in the concatenation of all
the term paraphrase find
just just paraphrase
it's argument are in the best possible to paraphrase on and he
paraphrase this as a noun phrase
so this means
i realize there are one thousand nounphrase
like its
turned into certain constraints
under the third
and have the word
it has to be the subject and you
i want to have the word to agree with
this initial
this is singular then you want a singular form of having world and you want
this indicated that the initial subject
this is very
specialized knowledge that i don't
i encourage you to acquire must
you're really serious about writing ten gentemplate but just to give you a sense of
how this template represent
so that's what that's like
in the sentence with the
the transition from one
the second element is
former the that agrees with
they are
now free to translations
there are two like
this is the
the string known by form of the word member
as one known number
then the number that would be singular has two
numbers that
four lot of this work will be
so you
generally these gentemplate assertions are handwritten but in principle they could be derived
there are some rules that generate
the template solutions
i want to go on
because through this in detail but it's just it just shows that you can derive
these two templates by
kinds of semantic predicates i also wanted to talk about
so remember
picture which is one of the detail two groups from strings to concepts
there are two
kinds of morphology
the plural as that goes on
dog to form the plural of dog dogs that's inflectional morphology
the string down and this training dogs are both forms
of the same word
with derivational morphology
you take a word and then you have add suffix
four prefixed to it and then you get a whole new word
which has its own set of forms
two strings are inflectional variants
the word dog
i wonder and wonderful
are two separate words that are related
by derivational morphology
inflectional morphology generally
has to do with ten
person number and gender
inside there
there inflectional suffixes don't correspond to reified individuals whereas you have like meant the suffix
you know you have no reified suffixes inflectional suffixes can and there
content is indicated with regular assertions which also
and then you have rules that attached the
the suffix two
the base
you know that the infinitive form
some more
some string
the five
you get past tense forms
of the same word
that's how inflectional morphology was uses
english the fixation from
and evaluate
the EP on in a smart way
it's not just that
he only played
the game you don't get eighteen you get it
so it so it's not just truck at each some
fulfilling do with you
same as well as
yes place
place to place
but as class
classes but apparently not as we just learned
those don't contain the suffix
so the search
the you have to assert those forms directly
so we have these are
this is the inflectional suffixes and how they represent represented
with derivational morphology
you have a suffix and it changes the part of speech to words taken barriers
that verb and meant and that makes it now
fascination one teacher both
the verbal noun from taken over many now
so basically what is also found is a lot of
constructed thing so basically we started from
seeing how traditional what conditional independencies
then we suffer very simple example with only three miles that well conditional independence will
generate a small factorizations
then what we need is that well we just constructed a set of conditional independence
that will generate the value of use general factorisation for the joint prob
right in particular was so that we have a name for the class of models
they are called bayesian networks OK
of which particular cases
markov random fields and
those are not michael hughes
hidden markov models and
filters and
all this
states simple state space models and factor hidden markov models in order
so now we will start to
look at the more and the theory OK
in order to scrutinize and try to understand exactly how
his universe of conditional independence statements
relates to the universe of the representation the factorizations
the joint approach
so basically
what i'm calling it is
conditional independence they well
that's what mentioned previously when you for some given set of conditional independence statements
it does not mean that the conditional independence statements
of the resulting factorizations
we only do all the time
and pulls in order to obtain that for position
they are sufficient to obtain the factorisation but
the just not
the punishment
particular we introduce the what
i just called here a convenient set of conditional independence
each way
according to size the way that
the expression for the joint probability distribution just arise naturally
the question is how we do so
conditions and yes
we happen
what will actually and then you may as well
if i am
design i want to design the given graph model for represent of factory works so
gonna make sure
but i know
all the conditional independence statements that they assume
because maybe
i will
i assume a set of conditional independence statements
two in by another set of conditional independence statements
no working with
joint distribution that arises from that set
but when i'm working with the try
i'm also working with the model
that respects
another set of conditional independence statements that i haven't
written down in the first place
OK so i need to be aware of
all the
consequences of my initial assumption
so let's
try to look into this
how we characterize its
what's the smallest size of vision that that's an interesting well
three node
because if you have three and all you can
you can study conditional independence right
because for conditional independence you need
three five
so let's
try to do an exhaustive study
green old
vision that would be a
which sense let's study the conditional independencies in this business
the second let's study this factorisation in is
because we always talking about these twins of expectation we have here the set of
conditional independence statements have here
the fac torisation arise from this condition
we start with a very basic types of vision
you only have three no
and if we give the precise characterization of these equivalent if there is any
only appears in my objective function in the form of an inner product or scalar
so indeed this brings me to the elaboration of my support vector machine
namely what i can do
if i have a dataset which is highly diminished not separable
that can make my data into a high dimensional space
by replacement okay
by mapping function
if i man data from low dimension to high dimensional
the other thing i always if i go high enough i'll be able to separate
the data OK
so just to illustrate the point
if i just in two dimensions OK and hand
plus minus minus plus in two dimensions i can't find hyperplane which separates two types
of data but if it is in three dimensions OK and these are sort of
in the board
and these are sort of like a minus here
currently doing it but then circular OK so have pluses here
and the two months here
like an easy but some hyperplane that separates the two to two dimensions i can't
find hyperplane separates in a three-dimensional world these minuses outside the board i can easily
find hyperplane will do indeed have
formatting to high dimensional space
then i will be able to separate my data
and i we have a problem OK
i will do that for
my data is in the form of the dot product the product and this is
must have a mapping function
the maps made from my input space into the high dimensional space which i call
feature space
this is a mapping function
and i quantify likely high dimensional space mapped to a feature space
and one thing which must be true
about the space map into
isn't there must be a hilbert space ten textbooks cycle here it can be pre
hilbert space in the product space k
but what i was down to
is of course mapping in the party of so the space map into
and in the product must be defined so must be an inner product space so
he pre hilbert space
the one thing that may be bothering one thing is important courses
if i'm gonna mapping the high dimensional space and must have some mapping function
one of in very simple cases polynomial kernels i could actually figure out what the
mapping function is
but one of the curious thing about the kernel methods is i can
man into high dimensional space
without actually know what the mapping function is because if i defined
a functional form
from the inner product in high dimensional space it implicitly defines a mapping function but
i don't need to know what the mapping function is
in other words what i'm saying here is the following i had an part and
this is my map in the product
and if i define certain types of kernels they implicitly define certain types of embedding
but i don't need to know what the embedding function is OK
i just find kind of it's OK
and i just define a mapping function implicitly define a high dimensional feature space
don't need to bother what that phi x is
it just doesn't matter
so the don't bother and the could this object here is for the country
and it is therefore the inner product in of the pairs of points in feature
you don't care about the mapping function yes
however which are also seen before and this is not quite right we need to
do or you don't quite understand how to to use the test
born on right
she is writing this incredibly hard task but some sense the constraints are somewhat relaxed
and it's easier to get away
on the things
OK so
so in two parts
p on
it seems is so how does this relate back
so just look at some of
and people here are
the universe
you have
so is is one of of the
we have
the predominantly
well right after work war
representation of
this framework it can come on go
so there's no need
for example see
personal life
i didn't want to just
by the HTML pages
please contact your first place
for most people
the small
let's more for me because he has forms slide that had
it's cool
he has in a series
well for
what are some of the problems very
we set constraints on the syntax of the language
government can define this email
pos tag
had little little
these are little
british marks interaction
in our
the recent years
one of the four
so he e
services small
four on information that generation size so that small
well that's what are already right
the deed
he was he he
which is the
BC xmlschema scheme to
so this is
just this very minimal level performance
are you
it is like all one more time now
so there
penalize how much i relaxing so i want to
minimize the sum of slacks
and then i have some smoothness terms
that's that's SVM
now you can turn this into an equivalent form that's
that's an unconstrained optimization problem
writing a strange objective here so now concise go away but then you have this
objective where f x y is tricks plus b
and then
this class means
we take the
maximum of
this value or zero so we truncated at zero
now this is why times as your prediction is known as the marginal basically says
how far away is your prediction from the decision boundary
and it should be possible
if you correct things correctly
if you classified things correctly
you know if it's an active u
classified things wrong
in this
is known as the hinge loss
so we turn this into this is the loss function this is regularizer
turn it into a risk minimisation framework
so that so far is the end
let's look at
the ways we can put in unlabeled data
now we do not have labels for the unlabeled data but we can pretend that
we have been pretending other methods so let's pretend that
the sign of my current function
applied to acts
that's my pretend label for acts
when x is unable
now if you put this into
pretend it's label point and put it into the margin formulation and the hinge loss
you see this
OK so this is my pretend label but my pretend label times fx is simply
the absolute value of f
so you end up with this
hinge loss now turns into something like that
very easy words simply going to stick them into the SVM
so the black part is the standard SVM
but i'm going to adding another term which is on the unlabelled data
and those are
you can view it as the corresponding laws for the unlabelled data
so this is the objective we want to solve
but what is it exactly
so here we go
i'm showing you you
the hinge loss
on the labeled data points
this x axis here is that the marginal
remember what i said is if it's on the positive side you have predicted correctly
and in fact
the hinge loss the new term that's the loss incurred in your prediction if you
want to
incur no loss you actually have to predict things not only correctly but confidently so
it has to be bigger than one
and then when you're not certain you start to incur some
penalty some loss
and why you predict things wrong you really encourage loss of loss
now let's look at the corresponding unlabelled data term
that one i call it had lost because this function looks very much like a
this is a dax instead of y fx because you not know why
now it looks like that where it's zero outside minus one or one but it
has had
minus one and one and it's very large actually at zero
what does it mean if you look at our objective
back here we want to minimize
we hope that every unlabelled data points will get a zero here
that means
every unlabelled data points
should be far away from zero
at least minus one or one way
what's zero well zero fx it was zero that's the decision that's the linear decision
so this
geometrically really says that i want my unlabelled data points to be outside of my
marginal outside the gap around my decision boundary
OK if i have only with data points near my decision boundary i will incur
some loss
so i don't want that
so that's
so that's the intuition behind some surprise support vector machines you simply want to sticking
that term unlabelled data to make sure that all the unlabelled data points are far
away from the decision boundary really it's the other way around it should be that
you're just your decision boundary that that you will find is far away from all
the unlabelled data
OK so that's the intuition
there is often a somebody here which is that
if you do that if you
optimized this
in many cases
the as and being very unbalanced that means that the prediction
it makes usually for the majority of
classification makes will fall into one class
and as a heuristic people come up with this class balance constraint
which says
i want
predicted labels
using this have
crossfire on my unlabelled data
if you look at
so because this is zero one you average them you it's essentially the fraction of
positive labels
you want this to be the same as the fraction of positive labels in the
it has always zero
i've also drawn in here all the shortest paths
this is not hard to do is we're not going to talk about two much
in this class but it's mention little bit more detail in the the textbook
there's something called the shortest path tree is something good to know
that if you actually want to compute shortest paths
in this class we mainly worry about the weights because it's pretty much the same
the shortest path tree is the union of all shortest paths and in particular
if you look at
vertex in your graph
and you consider
the last edge
into that vertex that was relaxed
among all vertices u
you look at the edges UV so was that the last one relax so just
look at the last is relaxed here you put them all together that's called the
shortest path tree and has the property that
from s to everywhere else there is a unique path down the tree
and it's the shortest path is a shortest path that we found
OK so you actually get shorter spans this algorithm even though it's not explicitly described
it's mainly talking about the shortest path weights
algorithm clear at this point i feels like it's doing the right thing you can
check all those numbers are the best hands
in our and proof that
so the correctness
so the first thing i want to prove it is the relaxation never makes a
if it ever sets dv to be something
i want to prove that is always an upper bound on delta
so we have this invariant
is greater than or equal to
delta as comedy
for all the
and this invariant holds
at all times after initialisation
it does not before initialisation isn't defined
but if you do this initialisation resets to zero and everyone else to infinity
and if you take any sequence of relaxation steps
and this invariant will hold after each relaxation step you apply
this is actually very general one also pretty easy to prove it holds not only
for dexter's other before a lot of other organs will see
these pretty much every other than we see one involve relaxation
and this is saying no matter what relaxations you do you always have a reasonable
estimate in this sense is less than or equal to its
greater than or equal to the true shrews pathway so she should be converging from
so that's the lemma
let's prove it
any suggestions on how we should prove this lemma
technique might we use
was cut-and-paste would for optimal substructure
cut and paste
he sort of what's going on here but not
not exactly
something a little more general
just intuition here doesn't have to be the right answer
so many answers are correct
i have possible purpose
i'm not going to write induction here but is effectively are using induction and that's
the answer i was expecting so this induction already in time going on here say
after initialisation should be true that are base case and then every six relaxation we
do which still be true so assume by induction that all the previous relaxations worked
and they were own to prove that the last relaxation whatever it is it works
so for system base case
so this is after initialisation saying initially
initially we have to ask
equal to zero
and we have to be of the
classical scaling to this
so what you end up with
this picture
which located
after weights
make it look
one of the south also
hard to get properly should be flipped over is also a reliable source like
so this is the picture comes out and
there's so much in distortions what
basically what's happened is that the places to reflect the road network in britain so
what we have here
these towns
are all on the motorway called the m one
these are all along the one on the the side of country called them six
this is what we call them five and so this is the way to
two to do so
what's happening here is the
because the routes recommended along the motorway because that's the fastest
this is fortunate as a short time
what happens is that line or not the geographical position not size geographical positions but
in positions that are related to
what was equipped to drive from inside and that's why i can see why signaling
network because of from program but
this is something that this is happening is
if you actually look problematic approach so bear in mind this is the transpose of
this is
this is the west of the country and this is this the country because it
happened to flip it that way round
you have no control over the region
well this parts of the country
is land
on this
it's a
and they are not so what happens here
if you want to this place carmarthen
so for that you can't go
state and because the season
so what we have to do is go back to the second down here
so what happens here is if you actually look the problem
you find the
this line of terms should really of the time
geographically but because the distances to
this part
than the actual geographical distance
this is all being pushed down
further away from here is
if you want to know more
so this is being pushed further and
in order to
much the distance is the distance is the which is what
works best
but i would say the things that i can see are the ones of to
much the motorway network and its distortions life
thing further away from carmarthen it should be
but this is this is this is a map that reflects the road distances
what was
so there is
scale into the same problem x the distances
the distances
what you're really trying to get is the same old
so the same rank ordered distance is not exactly the same so you are saying
that there
the oldest is the assume that you have information that says the
a and b for further apart than b c things like that so you to
where the distance on the map from a to b
is bigger than the distinction case well it
measuring the similarity between head is
less than
the similarity
but just trying to match the ordering of the dissimilarities
the distances that you draw on your
let's so
the basic problem is sometimes called chapel to shepherd crystal scaling because
they sort of
cluster analysis which decomposition
this analysis is trying to find groups amongst objects trust which objects in all sorts
of the the same basic ideas
so so that have indexes as the inputs as before
what we want to do is try and identify how we got concentrations of observations
in certain places
two types
are hierarchical which means that
if we have a
clustering that has
two clusters in the clustering has three clusters in is hierarchical
then the three the solution must have been obtained by splitting one of the two
clusters in the two cluster solution
so that you all the way you think is together with three clusters to two
clusters emerged to the three closest together
and gives you two new clusters
non hierarchical as
at all on that you can have
two clusters and the relationship go to cluster part of relationship three closest to the
hierarchical long
it was often used because it's quicker computationally and the two trips to building hierarchical
classification of clustering one is
you start off with all the values of the point separately and used it together
so you say choose to stick them together
so i suppose you twenty observations
you choose to
put them together that give you a nineteen clusters
and then
take nineteen clusters and stick to those clusters together to give you a eighteen so
that we
all the other way around the start this one cluster
i just put it into
and then that the two clusters say one or other of those in split into
so it's not a good hierarchical
it doesn't have the answer but that we quick
computationally the various ways of deciding what the distances between those clusters which are written
down here described in more detail in the book about three times
going to rewrite it
with the carried along by itself
and now what matrix goes on that's times the
if you could say
this this forum is like how undo elimination has had a reversed
starting from here what do I do to get back
and it just turns out better to have
that all the data to have the matrix on 1 side like here and so
what matrix try I want to
the inverse inverse that's the key point right because because security was here and so
I multiply that through an example
the times the CPU time KGB me the you if I multiply through by the
inverse of undo the elimination steps that knocks out the thing puts it here so
so what I'm asking you is what's the inverse of the mass
and you know what the inverse of that
it's gets the same matrix from the minus there can we see why that would
on we could check that that's so write it down
2 1 0 and that's the minus half and I claim that this is this
is the inverse but now I'm going to call it its lower triangular and this
is the
and this is of course k
at I think where it important like we were coming quite a bit here in
In our but
we can use the Y inward sort of why the inverse matrix
the inverse operation
should be this guy with a sign change
and at the same site you can check that that matrix times that many cruise
gives the identity they they they are inverses of each other but we added half
we take away good good good exactly
exactly that's that's the word I'm looking for
this step added a half of this wrote that
and so if we want to inverted what I'm doing
subtract half of this role from the numbers right
back to where we were OK so I'm happy to have it on this side
actually I'm happy for multiple reasons
yeah which about what the media that we just saw emphasize that this is a
great place to have not only 1 thing I'd like to improve here and tell
and that is
that I've lost the symmetry
this was a symmetric matrix that that's 2 important properties to give up on
so I was like to my factorizations
should be a somehow symmetric factorisation
and the 1 way to do now I'm totally happy with
and now another factor out here
a diagonal matrix it just shows the pivots 2 and 3 halves
the alright so that's an easy it's nice to have a diagonal matrix
could be better than that and then
I got something like
so if you see what I'm doing is I'm taking this matrix
dividing that row by 2 and dividing that by 3 halves so that I get
this simple orthogonal matrix that only has 1 there
and of course it's going to 0 there now now you just tell me what's
there and really
social what did I do
I that just divided into the 3 have just came out so that was this
row divided by 2 divided by the pivot separated out the pivot so let me
with the 1 on the main diagonal and what's here
minus the head right because the 2 will multiply minus haven't give me the minus
development give you a chance to look at that because I'm going pretty quickly
that's the form of a woman
of no completes now
that's the form that
that we're shooting for
the matrix has been factored into a lower triangular
1 that has these multipliers it
a diagonal that has the pivots it
and then upper triangular and what's special about this upper upper triangular
it's the transpose of the lower
so that this factorization is now
symmetrised space we've got pull out the diagonal and we were left with the transpose
of the 1st
and that's great I mean that's the right way to have a symmetric matrix because
I made it every l times the impact
the next
several hours
are going to be about products of 3 matrices
outside factors are transposes of each other
that's always a symmetric result
if I take a matrix
time something in the middle
times the transpose of the 1st
that has not not matrix product is symmetric
and in this case the factor is lower triangular that factor is diagonal so long
that's great
but can we just checking can we see general fact white I claim that whatever
l and might happen to be
that products of this this triple symmetric triple product you could call it
produces that was is the result of a symmetric matrix how can I check that
the result is a symmetric matrix it looks kind of
I think it's transpose literary
me right
we want to know if something is symmetric
tickets transpose and see what
if we get again
In the case we got a symmetric matrix OK so it takes a transpose so
this is like offline here because there was a wealth or I'll put it in
here and so what is the transpose of this thing so I have a product
of 3 things I want to transpose
so this is
this is a little chance that the result is always symmetric
OK what happens when you take the transpose of several things multiplied together and you
take the transpose of
what's going on
all along this line
so i was our equals one we get
o along this line at this rate
he was there already
you see what's happening as our goes to one well it's true that this
went to zero but this also went to zero in fact faster
the thing is going up
now is this one more
the place here in the circle is the centre what's the what's the value of
you at the center of the circle
what do i get free you have the right here at the centre
there are zero yes all this stuff is gone i only get
one or two pi and what's interesting about the answer one or two pi
was one over so you at the centre zero zero
there's one or two pi
and then what is that what's the message there
it's the average of view around the boundary
and this is like always true
that the solution of classes equation
at any point
is the average of the
we have our around in a circle
so at that point take any circle i could actually take other circles
there's the centre
well you have my OK in saying that one or two pi is the average
of the delta function that that ask to to
distributed over the circle
what would be the solution suppose there was a constant all the way around
i suppose i suppose in the case which should have different boundary conditions for the
battery condition was you equal one all the way around
what would be the solution that
i'm looking for something that's all the possible creation and it was you know it
was one of the whole boundary
we can tell me that right away
it's going to be one the cost what are tell me is so suppose you
were the one on the top half and zero on the bottom OK what would
be the temperature
for me the temperature if i have a circular
block here and i he the top
semi circle to one
and hold the bottom semi-circle zero what will be the temperature
say at the centre
it would be a half and half will be exactly be the average value of
one and zero ground sort
actually it will be a half of the way along here
what it will be
and the rest hold
we can figure out some formula but it won't be
totally simple i think will be
completely simple anyway
we're in a position to solve
plus equations
in a circle
this by knowing this answer for the delta function
i could and and so that the key points to maybe mention or
our first that and the value in every point will be the average of the
values any circle around that point so
the solution inside is
there's a maximum principle that is worth mentioning the maximal where will the maximum value
of u occurred
if if my statement is true which it is that from the pluses equation the
value at the centre of any circle
is the average value around the circle now saying look at the big circle where
will the maximum value of u
someone on the boundary
you could occur inside
this is the maximum can occur there because it's the present value of the other
point is the average of all those
so there could be bigger than all these points
and those could be bigger than all the points around them
so the only place
can be biggest
is out of the boundaries well of course in this example is really the biggest
it's it's almost completely
but so that's the general
interesting fact that this maximum principle and of course it makes total sense if
now delta function centred at would put sources
so this this maximum principle applies to any
and the
any EU equal
he is given on the boundary
on boundary
so it's totally natural suppose i have my circle
and i hold the boundary at certain temperatures
and what would you tell me about the temperature inside
it's going to be in between right
the temperature inside is going to be in between if i all the time varying
temperature here maybe varies from three degrees to fifty five degrees and inside it will
b somewhere between three and fifty five an not accuracy see of fifty fifty six
degree temperature inside if there are no sourced
that's one thing here no sourced
so i've got to have had the chance to dimension the maximum principle and the
idea that i could
the temperature will vary according to whatever i like on the outside the inside it's
a lot smoother
one of the
there we have it we have a quantitative relation between energy and wavelength
one EV is tantamount to six meters
we have a quantitative relations energy and temperature one EV is ten thousand degrees
so if you like to say if i had something ten thousand degrees i have
the potential to be able to resolve things on the micron scale
what do these things may well let's see
i showed you a moment ago
the scale of distance on which various things you might want to look at are
and so we could see them with ordinary light
i've now added to that list
what the
energy corresponding to these distances is
using those numbers that i just showed you
and you see that the wavelength of light corresponds to energies of the order of
and EV
and we'll see in a moment or two
even more about this
so if you want to source that will provide you energies on the EV scale
it will tend to produce light is visible
the distance scales to the atomic nucleus
turner energy terms to correspond to
hundred MTV to achieve a
so if you want to probe the atomic nucleus you need to have been of
the order of the gv
and that is where we were fifty years ago
the highest energy accelerators and a few gv
they were able to study the atomic nucleus and how it works
if you want to get to distances
of ten to the minus eighteen metres
the distance scales with the quarks inside
the protons and neutrons live
you need to have any scales of the order of
TV which is the energy scale we are now to particle physics so you're seeing
here now for the first time how energy scales in particle physics correspond to the
distance scales you can resolve
if you want to get to what's called the plank length which is
theoretically with quantum gravity takes over
this the scale of length that you can form using planks constant of quantum
the velocity of light in relativity and g gravitation
that corresponds to the march thirty five metres
and resolved that you need energy energies of ten to twenty
and if you want to know how far away that is
starting from an EV
then the LHC isn't even halfway
so it's out of all possible ways of doing our experiments on so i shall
be working and talking only north of the TV line
let's go back to my original
little picture
we show the universe in temperature energy and time
and try to
put these ideas together
to see
what is really telling us
so out there in the space is it's very very cold three degrees kelvin
the thermometer in the middle
energy scales
and the template is in blue next other the thames that correspond to those energy
scales as i said one EV correspond to ten thousand degrees which indeed is what
we've got to find the EV
on the scale that ten thousand degrees next to it
one cave corresponds to
ten to seven degrees
and these
numbers begin to make sense because you see that the sun
the heart of the sun ten to seven degrees
the seven degrees
a practical nuclear physics laboratory is nuclear fusion going on in the centre of it
and the energy scale of the nuclear reactions taking place are typically on the cave
the sum is burning temperatures typically of those orders let's go back down to the
bottom of the thermometer
we started off with millie a little and
millie electoral-vote thousand electron volts
is the energy scale which corresponds to typically room temperature in fact one fortieth of
electron volt
corresponds to room temperature
now put your hand on your head from moment and you'll feel warmth
that warmth is being produced by your breakfast
when you eat stuff
and a little bit of e equals MC squared in your cornflakes or bread or
whatever you had is being converted into energy
it is
chemical reactions taking place
in your body
where the molecules
are rearranging themselves these reactions are acting on the melee EV scale
and the temperature is energies that are being produced on the three hundred degrees
the scale of kelvin that's body warmth
now if we turn out the lights in this room
we wouldn't be able to see each other
but if we had an infrared camera
it was show us all sitting here by the infrared radiation that we're meeting
because in
length scale
temperatures of three hundred degrees kelvin corresponds to the infrared wavelengths
the the electromagnetic radiation
so begins to hold together room temperature
chemical reactions of molecules
infrared radiation in wavelength
if you now increase the temperature what happens
well the wavelength go down into the infrared radiation you now move into the
visible region if you turn on for example
bar radiator
the first you will feel the warmth and it'll start glowing red it gets hotter
it will glow red yellow as it moves through the optical spectrum these like sunshine
because the filaments are many thousands of degrees
they are the temperatures
where the energy is on out of the order of EV
and the wavelengths in the optical region
you're not getting the individual electrons in atoms being excited at the atomic level rather
than just the rather loosely bound molecules
if you nothing to your atoms
the temperatures beyond ten thousand degrees what happens
all the electrons in the atom
after being given so much energy
the temperature
but they can no longer hold themselves out the at
of the atoms become ionized
the former plasma
electrons and protons flying around independently
those are the conditions you find the sun
by the time you get some sense
but it's all pretty simple
so written down and say
what they really mean is for properties
the first one is pretty simple every node is either red or black
that's the hence the name of a red black trees
so the color field is just a single bit specifying red or black
and red nodes i'm going to denote by double circle because i don't have a
color chart here and black nodes will be a single circle and you probably have
colored pens either so save us
some grief
credits double circle
black is a single circle we search for black nodes in some sense right nodes
are pain will see
OK so can property
is the room
and the leaves
are all black
and i'm going to pull little trick your
tree binary search is a little bit differently than we have in the past
normally think of the tree
as of nodes each node could have
zero or one or two children something like this
i'm going to imagine a pending
every place where node does not have a child i'm going to put a little
dots here and external which which i call so normally these would have been these
items and is going to have to every absent
child pointer a new belief this will be my leaves these are really the nail
pointers from each of these
so now every internal node has exactly two children and everybody has their children
so these are the doesn't refer to these guys are black
and the is black
according to rule two
now the produced a little bit more interesting
the parent every right now
is one
so whenever i have
right now
its parent has to be
black a single circle
so in other words if you look at
path in the tree
you can never have too red nodes
consecutive has to be
can most often a red black right back you can have several blackman's consecutive but
never to that's
and then one more rule
this is a little bit more about such hands
so if we take a simple path meaning it doesn't appear vertices from a node
has access to a
descendant leaf
all such as all descendant leaves
have the same number of black nodes on
so let me draw a picture we have some tree we have some node x
looking at all the paths from x
down to some descendant leaf down here at the bottom of the tree
all these has should have the same number of black nodes so hero drop each
one has
black nodes leaf and three about it
we know that these from property three these nodes don't have at most half of
the nodes are red is whenever whenever another parent must be black
but i want all these passive exactly the same number of black nodes one cell
see here is that the black i didn't really
the rooms are already here
this should be the same for all has but in particular the count i'm interested
in does not include x itself
OK so if x is black only calling the black-eyed so the black box is
this count for
and even if x is black
the black eyed for these are just some minor
to get all of the
algorithms typically so let's look at the example of a red black tree
so i training example and also why we care about these properties
if you put all the UV light again two responses
if you look more carefully you can identify the best first effect is simply family
take due to the dominant heating of you die
with the laser light source
in the network and the second process
actually is
this is cis trans of francis i summarisation process if you put up the light
from the effect and then this is france as summarisation process
works perfectly as predicted more or less biased the simple model just discussed
however if you look at the time scale here it's thousands of seconds
of course the question is whether this might be suitable for
and artificial muscle would be a little bit too slow
it's not an argument
because it's when known
these molecules cute that we use for the census friends i summarisation process
can be nicely modified and you can get very fast response within milliseconds and for
example very recently peter p
published a paper with these networks
he which shine light on these samples and the reaction time was within milliseconds
the brothers where
on the water surface and
the area
well the light shined on
into the dark and therefore because this paper a fast liquid crystalline elastomers swims into
the dock which if find here in there in this paper
another interesting aspect
the optical properties of liquid crystals and you just one example
i think one of the most fascinating
the properties of the so-called karen the medical cholesteric phase is the selective reflection of
circularly polarized light
cholesteric phase of current nematic phase is simply continuously twisted nematic phase perpendicular to the
direction twisted
and due to the helical structure
this cholesteric structure reflex circularly polarized light where the wavelength of reflection is directly proportional
the periodicity of this helical factor
the problem of course is when we look for elastomers
can we prepare
such a nice cholesteric last summer with these
optical properties
liquid crystal elastomers
let's for example start with
system where we have
correspondingly corresponding nematic phase with the paul a chain confirmation
in other words locally polar chain confirmation
then we see that due to the helical structure the over all chain confirmation of
such a network which should behave like
single crystal
a global chain confirmation should be oblate
in other words to realize such a microscopically orders sam
we need an over all obligate chain confirmation as mentioned in the beginning
and this simply
means that you have
to do either compression uniaxial compression
or by accident information
unfortunately both experiments are extremely difficult to perform you would see it in the moment
the next question of course is when we take our network if we introduce action
global optimal chain confirmation do we actually see
such as spontaneous twist which causes the helical superstructure
in other words this the this coupling to the network
we succeeded in getting these networks
and here you see a small sample of such cholesteric network the reflection weight links
should be
in the
a yellow to orange
immediately can see that this is not a nice reflection colour
which is expected for cholesteric phase nevertheless the concept works
at least get
or perfectly ordered no a center which is interestingly microscopically or in other words everything
seems to work
now when we take such a network and when we additionally
by x information or uniaxial compression
then of course this means that the helicopters structure is compressed of the network which
caused a ship of the of the wavelength of reflection into the blue region and
this weekend
and if we
properly measure the wavelengths for as reflections
and if we measure the thickness and the change of the thickness of the sample
then we see that this an find information
the helicopter the page with the macroscopic dimension of the network by the way here
you see that you never realised to get the nice by x deformation
it's also
a company with shear deformation in the borderlands of the network
and it's much
difficult to realize such a perfect by excerpt information you need at least many many
claims to get the perfect
the formation of the network
when we analyse nevertheless when we analyse the wavelength of reflection we see
that there
reflection bend of our networks is extremely broad
here in comparison you see the same system as the low wall must liquid crystals
and the width of the reflection bent is extremely narrow compared
to our network the question was what's the reason why don't we observe such a
nice orientation of the system there must be some people and here we get such
get some
nice help
from michelle meet all the
he has done some
electron microscopic pictures of our
polymer networks
and you could see
that we do not get a nice orientation of plains of equal director orientation but
there's obviously
on the relation with in this typical cholesteric structure
let me explain this dark region simply mean that our right like molecules on average
looking in this direction like regimes
parallel in other words here we have this helicopter structure
we see the clear
periodicity of the cholesteric phase
and this should be
and i explained which can be observed for low molar mass system following network we
see it doesn't work
question was what's the reason and it's a long story to make a long story
to get perfectly ordered systems we completely change our chemistry and start with the chemistry
which was already
test part of the system by fiat always and russia
and the order of ten to the university of mines
we took
of liquid crystal and polymers
some functional groups
the system begins to condense into this are well defined is larger but the entropy
is smaller and therefore this cause fluctuations are negative and hence the cooperation from expansion
goes negative
so there are three of the sixty four numbers that easily rationalised in terms of
predictive non-animal is one of the more dramatic things is that this is the essence
of this argument relies on two lengthscales of potential
liquids with local tetrahedral symmetry such as silicon
and so can
two of the most common
things on should also have a liquid liquid transition in very very recent work in
nature physics
and elsewhere shows that seems to be the case
how can we tested this experimentally this experiment never simple and
we learn in
in the matrix that that that if we look at the phase diagram of a
simple flow could point
the to
critical point the first order line but the one nothing is singular that's not strictly
true nothing may be mathematically singular but if we make any quantity that susceptible to
the proportion the fluctuations let's take the specific heat here then this was severely rises
and drops
very dramatically and has appeared as we crossed the we demand with the binary recall
few was the locus of the maximum of correlation length and what causes rising fluctuations
is to right the way to mine the system is
mainly of fuel liquid clusters inside sea of grass
on the right and the it's the reverse if fuel gas clusters into cyrillic and
here is the maximum of correlation length is the compensation point between those two scenarios
how to make this experimentally and the coexistence line is very difficult to see
but the winter because of of metastability but the world is very easy to see
and now it's very easy to see all
to be honest because they're all alone
temperature of homogeneous nucleation of by
using manual confined water
the hydrogen bond network cannot form
and therefore the system does not freeze homogeneous nucleation temperature an example of very recent
work recently submitted to nature physics is the analysis of model matches for transform infrared
experiments in which one can actually play as a function of temperature the relative population
of this low-density liquid right
the geometry is and you can see there already roughly
the temperature of maximum density four celcius to begin to be
the significant number of droplets of the low-density liquid is the compensation point when the
system crosses the line roughly two twenty five
and a saturation of our temperatures
this is one of
perhaps two dozen reason experiments carried out in the last year or two by my
much in messina and by chan
at MIT
which all
converge and providing fourteen pieces of evidence favoring this liquid liquid phase transition
one will always has to worry about everything one of the biggest one about
all these experiments is that there are carried out in a confined geometry which means
the walls are so it can affect the nature of the way
in particular the water and even pure here so can well so i can well
and therefore experiments have been redone for water near proteins and in particular
there are places lysozyme and DNA and what one finds is not surprisingly is the
famous protein glass transition which means the mean squared displacement suffered a major key at
a temperature of around twenty
and similarly the characteristic relaxation time and goes across from not years fragile behaviour through
i mean strong behaviour
at the same temperature
these experiments have not been reinterpreted not in terms of protein glass transition in terms
of the cross-over
in the properties of the thin skin of water that surrounds the biomolecules from the
predominantly high-density liquid local configuration of the red line
to predominantly low-density liquid configuration below the window line
so let's summarize this part of the talk what is complex because the
charged the that comprise water give rise to a phase transition line separating two liquid
phases and terminating at a critical point the fact that critical point is the paternal
these are usually called the critical region around the critical points and that perturbation gives
rise to the anomalies of one
about this is was first found by simulations of a graduate student at is now
confirmed by experiments
the protein drug transition is not protein that does not transition but rather crossover and
something i have not talked about because it's very recent
just reported the gordon conferences shares worker modelling now
showing that the low-density liquid is very relevant in nucleation because the first beginnings of
thank you very much for this flattering introduction and thank you all the organisers for
inviting me here
it's actually quite special for me to speak here in oregon because i spent some
time in oregon as a student going to school year so it was the first
time that i really got to know american
i feel a bit like student again in oregon
so i i i decided taste
the title of my talk and talk about
four things basically components
some applications of kernels i'll talk about something called kernel means will come later
will become clear later what i mean by this and finally i try to put
things a little bit into perspective
most of you probably heard about this thing called the kernel trick
by talking about how this country has evolved over the years how we thought of
it at the beginning how we think of it now it's also a little bit
related to the
the actual content of this talk so part of this talk will be
well known to most of you know try to cut very short it will be
may the first five or ten minutes so if you sleepy that's that's your chance
afterwards are talk about some applications that some of you may have seen others may
not have c
and finally they don't talk about something that i hope maybe the majority view hasn't
seen yet
these are the first
five or ten minutes not so start with an example of a very simple pattern
recognition algorithms where we are given two classes of data the classes and the circles
and we try to classify new point x based on whether it's closer to the
mean of one class
denoted mu plus so this is the mean of the one class or closer to
the mean of the other class denoted mu minus which is over here so obviously
this induces a separating hyperplane is the decision function
with the normal vector that's the vector connecting these two class means
but of course this only solves problems that are linearly separable
and the kernel approaches then to preprocess the inputs with some mapping that takes our
input domain into a dot product space and then we work in that space
what is that helpful what can that help here's an example of a two dimensional
classification problem separating these crosses from the samples we assume the true decision boundary this
is this ellipse but we don't know what we only have the data now if
we pre processed all points by computing all features of all the two product of
order two
and then this problem becomes linearly separable which you can see by reading the ellipse
equation in these new coordinates
now the trick comes in when we see that if we take two such points
x x trying to two-dimensional points we mapped them into the three dimensional space using
this prescription when we then take the dot product we see that this gives simple
binomial formula we can simplify it right is the square the product in the original
so that's an example of a simple kernel we can compute the dot product without
going into this high dimensional space same thing works for n dimensional inputs and products
of order p
in this case we end up with this polynomial kernel
physically something similar works for all positive definite kernels of the notion well known in
mathematics and whenever we have such a positive definite kernel we can prove there exist
some mapping into another space so mapping five such that the kernel computes the dot
product in that space
in one way of visualizing the mapping is by thinking of it as a mapping
into a function space
so we define the mapping to take up input point x into the kernel centered
on that point x o for instance if we used a gaussian kernel then this
point x would be mapped into a gaussian function
sitting on the point x
another point prime will be mapped into goes in and all space will be defined
to be the linear how complete completion of the linear i love these kinds of
maps functions
and then we have to define what's the product in that space
and we have to define it such that it satisfies this equality because we want
to compute the product turns out this works we can define this it's defined we
extended linearly
and we then have a kernel that computes the dot product in this function space
in one of the nice things about of this kernel is if you substitute came
here and you do the same thing for linear combinations you will see that the
kernel represents point evaluation on these functions so it this i mean if i have
a function in that space so this
at this point it's just abstract element of a hilbert space if i want to
know the value of this function at some point x the only thing i have
to do is take this other element of a hilbert space which is the kernel
sitting on x
compute the dot product between the two
and that was my point evaluation
and here i have one
this one
the velocity v one
and and this one has velocity v two one-dimensional problems
a warm-up
the plough into each other
they stick together
i put some good ones
and so to stick together to give you have to accept that
this week
the direction of increasing x
before the collision
i have a certain amount of movement and i can do is on the horizontal
which is frictionless i can do it on the ice surface which is nearly frictionless
and i ignore and drag
so this is the situation before
so the momentum that i have before
he calls and one v one
this is my plus direction i could support vectors over there but that's really not
necessary because it's a one-dimensional problems
plus and two
the two like that
my guess
that's the momentum before
now they stick together
so when they stick together the total mass is in one place and two
and then
their velocity
happens to be the primary often gives
the prime the situation after the collision occurs
so now i can apply for the first time the conservation
of momentum
the momentum before must be the same as the momentum afterwards because there no
external forces on the system
when they collide you better believe it that their internal forces us to believe that
there is good
and it goes on in a field of forces both of them the momentum of
each one individually is changing but not the momentum of the system as a whole
so this equals
and one
plus and two
the prime
so if you put in some numbers
suppose and what
equals one kilogram
and the one
five meters per second
let m two be two kilograms
and that's the to be
meters per second
and you see since both in the same direction momentum here is five
six is eleven
so this is eleven
and this is one cluster with three
so that's three times the one prime so v one prime
it's eleven thirty meters per second sort of conservation of momentum
tells you what the speed is after
when we deal with collisions the velocities of the object before the collision are on
you see here one
you see here the two
the velocities after the collisions
by convention are primed
you see here
the prime
now if after the collision
object one object to
the different velocity
we will call it few one prime
and he two prime
now in this case
we're dealing with an inelastic collision
so m one and m two are stuck together they are merged so it is
to just call it the prime
you could have called it three one prime because we want prime is the same
as the two prime is the same as the prime
and during the next four minutes you'll see
that a few times do i call it the one prime i wish i really
had it would be better if i had just used the prime that is unique
and sufficient
now to a certain amount of
kinetic energy before the collision
and of course we can all calculate the kinetic energy
before the collision
that is one half and one v one squared plus one half and two v
two square
one half
and one of
one square
one have
and two v two square
which is it
you can do that as well as i can
if you have to
you'll find twenty one
o point five
trail to taking the number
now i want to hear from you
what do you think
the situation is worse economic energy after the collision
don't look at the numbers
just use your intuition may be wrong that's okay my intuition is often wrong
so it was a certain amount of kinetic energy we had this condition
and i want you to tell me what you think that the kinetic energy has
perhaps increase or decrease
or maybe
the kinetic energy hasn't changed
o things the kinetic energy has not changed
good for you i see some parents even
things are getting energy has decreased
even better for you
it is a professor of physics there can go wrong there
and the things are getting energy has increased
no one things that they a amazing
let's take a look
kinetic energy
the collision
that would be one half
and one class and two
the prime squared
what we agree
the right this
different location
this was the twenty one and a half
well you can do this as well as i can we know be one prime
minister's eleven third
you will find
so what would be a reasonable
the fourth
well let me
what the right thing
it means that
every factor and s
one of my
but i want see what
well the
the last four
are you
all right
we're not three
the line
the white
it's not like four
the article right
you can tell me about here
in the last quarter the year in the war that are not
well i mean
forty five three
like four
the fact that even more
you tell have the
in fall
the whiteboard one more
for sure
what was
what about the like bull
for me
one the other
but also
why not
in the plane
really all
a line the are
or the
now we
the line of the article
orthogonal to the whole planet
right now
the line they are orthogonal to
there are
when the line the origin orthogonal to a different the are well
that is the case that we all
i have a clear picture they
the two lines that need not be free
they have only
so that for the
like the simple case i'm talking about the one
the other place they only needed there
and there are
so we now know what i mean
four two
so they be orthogonal and now i want
that is true for the role played
OK that
o right
o point o
now how i know that
but you might be right
that means that the
the piece
this the right thing
because cutting the whole
two perpendicular
OK so what
well when i got
i work with
all i know is that all
no factor for all
a equal the
well the the the the and
x all
then they are
so why
there are
the right
if i write down a which is all i know about
i just wanted to see
that telling me
the just that great right there telling me
the role of the right
there is a row of
grow r
and multiply
and produce
right now
it perpendicular to
and if see want
because the way telling you
that role was a
multiply that are not quite right or one of the product with reduced the
so is orthogonal
the first row
and the
two of the
o and by doing that
not all the around
so we
and this is actually quite i mean sometimes is one of the reasons
but people introduce
exponential family distributions
namely maximum entropy estimation
i mean really really loosely speaking entropy is based on the number of bits that
you need to encode random variable
and while we can define it as
the expected value of the negative log p of x
and we just zero of serie c
so it turns out
but the density p of x
which satisfies the condition that the expected value for fixes critical in nature
with maximum entropy
it is of this form
d theta
g of data
because it
who has seen this fact before
four five people
well who want to see the proof
OK so basically in the break
five minutes break when other people can go to the bathroom you'll get to see
the proof
one of the crawler is is
maximum entropy
distribution with the given variance
the gas distribution
because the
so i will get a distribution which looks like mix
is proportional to the equals
he to that
some parameters
the ten times
x squared
minus g
alpha theta
because this is the same guy here
now i have a normal distribution
they want to play around with the mean two
i might want to say something like the expected value of x
it's critical then say maybe two
so i would get theta two x squared
theta one convex
and off we go again
if i just want to play around with the mean
just required the expected value x is critical density two
i would get if you fix
being over
theta time six months g data
i could then say well you that should be the case
to be
in the domain of integers
well then i will get the different function g but that's the only thing i
would change
so a fairly powerful mechanism
how to turn conditions
on expectations of random variables
into distribution
entire conferences
on well one how to do this efficiently
conference called it
now in fact
as it will turn out
this is not topic of this talk but it's quite
an amazing thing that
you yes not tonight
you don't just know
exactly that the expected value of some of the books
so i mean
but it just
minus mu but this norm
is less equal than some epsilon
and you want to find the maximum entropy distribution of that
you will get an estimate
which will not be a maximum likelihood estimate
but a maximum posterior system
then you get bayesian estimation of this
that's all i wanted to say about that specific thing
it's actually put to practical use
i mean these are all really nice things to know
in order to know that well you the world is all sane and all the
estimation algorithms lead to something quite similar
now let's actually put to practical use
let's say we observe some topics one three exam
which are drawn from some distribution pfx parameters by theta
well i could going compute the likelihood
p of x
practice y theta
which is
big product over all my observations off
individual probabilities
this is the
always the case if all the excise are drawn independently
if they were to depend on each other i couldn't just write the
joint probability is the product of the individual probabilities by
since there all drawn independently is i assume
that's the case
we know
well this is an exponential second push this product inside
and we'll take it is
each other
and then the sum of the form of
in here
and they get in times your data
further in terms of this expression just in time shifted to
let me
put those intermediate calculations upon the watchword
p of x
parameterized theta
is if i push this inside is each other
some i going from one to n
following a fixed online
inner product with theta
in times g of data
a very happy with this equation
was unhappy
now it could
if i want to
i find that theta
which is the most likely theta explaining the doctor
explaining x
well i would go
and compute
all data
p of data
p fix
the transport sector
which is of course the same thing
the argmin
that may help us
for example
with an inductive argument in order to obtain generalizations for an arbitrary business
so why don't we started doing
that's exactly what we are going to do
so the question is how does bayesian africa
it's a very simple reason
it's got only three no
and i want to ask the following question
he's is a independent of b
that's the way
so this is just notation here for independent
i just want to ask where a is in the independent
you know to check that i check if this is true
so let's look at
what's p of a and b
well i guess you i have the joint probability distribution for the model
so p of a b by marginalisation which is the creation cool
observation and they can give examples of the two possible the quite
by marginalisation we are something out on all
instances of p
of situations c
of p of baby p of the these are some of our CEO
but p of a
is given by the factorisation of these bayesian network
which is the parent the children given the parent
the product over all
so what's of ABC's p of a
times p of the given a times p of the given
and i'm something on c
immediately a observed that there is one of these factors that does not belong on
the doesn't depend
his first factor does not depend on the exact constant factor for c
so what can we do remember
the distributive law
let's just use the distributive law
in pull the spectrum of the sun
that's exactly what we get here
and now we only sample c
these quantities
which is basically p of the evening
that's our conclusions
these quantities here p of ten p of the given that in general is different
from this one
he of be given they had to be
i had to be itself
i mean basically
these on hold in general
in this graph
and that makes a lot of sense why well we have to change here right
we have to abide these has some dependency on the one
and some dependency on this one
so it is natural to expect that you will have some dependency on this one
so these two violin not independent in general
now the question
let's assume is slightly different although well let's assume that you actually observed these viability
and let's ask whether these two are now independent
so now we are looking for conditional independence
you want to ask the following question is a the condition dependency
that's the question
are you the conditional independence
well what we do
i can
where the
is the condition that be given scene by the
by the fact position of that
and they also have these
very factorizations
let's first check whether this factorizations
it will be applied to conditional independence
these graphs
so the station to this point
what you want if you're out is the full
these graph has a given factorizations
it also
implies conditional independence and conditional independence
so what will see that these factorizations here
i will imply
the article conditional independence there
particular condition the best for the graph
and now
that's exactly what we're going to see that happen
if we factorized these models
will think he of a
and if you give them a times appealed the
now the question is
does it imply
this independent
in fact position implies this
so let's start with some definitions
these definitions are the
but in the sense that the dynamic system theory is well developed a theory which
was studied very well after the second world war around the second world war we
have a huge number of results concerning me meaning being systems but also non-linear systems
and also very formal definition of what the system uses a sort of axiomatic definition
for a one hour and a half talk i decided to move towards more qualitative
definition of the system to just perspective of
this theory approach to the study of
systems some changes over time
so this is the nature of a system is the physical and
but not necessarily physically listening which can be manipulated with actions which are called inputs
and that is the consequence of the action measurable reaction called output
this is in general definition of the system which is used in dynamical system theory
what is new addition with respect to this definition
this is the definition of dynamical systems dynamical system is a system which changes over
time and what very important is that the output does not only depend on the
inputs but also depends on the current state of this is
so on the system history
this means that the system is in memory actually this makes difference with respect to
the standard systems so i mean this is a system which is not dynamic system
in which the output is just the function the died function of the input so
if i take a friend and you give me
give me another key
so this is not really dynamic this time inside just cause effect relationship then it's
dynamic system friends remember that very strong and can business so
he avoid to to keep min thirty two you can sell
here's a memory actually
and this is the notion of the dynamic systems are dynamic system is in
being more serious disease
a simple example of what is the dynamical system
so the example the following we have simple with we just lens in
one switch
so this which is a actually can be on on or off zero or one
the output can is a bit but the basis of three different the configuration we
have two lanes
so i'll put one is the one on
the output two
is that two and the output three is off so both of them all
it's not possible to have both of them on OK
the overall system is configured in order to to have four states and we can
commence the
how the system is working taking a look this diagram
so let's start from state the number one and also this diagram
this one just minutes space and improved
one state and out
it's probably more simple start from these examples from this diagram here
so states x one means that we have also
that we have lamp on
i loved one or state x two
it is often
they three
is land so on
think it's for ease of
but this is the worse on in this way
if you are if we are in state x one
which is number one on
then we apply the switch
so we switch it on basically we have these input we move from x one
to x two
x two means the land is often
then from x two
we can only apply
input u one which is switch off the
and we move from
the state x two which is often state three
which is the last two is on so it's like a is is something which
is very similar to our theoretical and memory on
the mobile phone or any device which remembers what the current state action so
i contains click on and off on this week and they change the configuration of
the land first two of then limk one then off the land to then often
so this is a dynamical system
because the output does not only depend on the input but depends also on the
past history
the game
another definition of the dynamical system is that it the dynamical system is a process
in which function changes over time
according to a rule
it is defined in terms of the phi hill current value and the current so
what's important of the example