your body about columnist storage
you worry about networking
because lots of data moves over and data movement is a huge part of the cost
if you're concerned about machine learning
you might not care as much about forty tolerance you may be okay if i
give you a good handle on fort venice because many loopy algorithms the major algorithms
allows u
to deal with the fact that some piece if your computation just went away
you will have to restart and really do exactly the
you can rely on good convergence properties good sampling properties
local data cache and turns out to be critical
right of local iterations but some global sink
can do just as well as global iterations
low latency networking
becomes important here
it's not high-bandwidth network
the amount of data is not the issue the motive communications how quickly it has to happen
this issue
if you think about it and by
right it's very different from
how do style data-driven bottles
it's communication driven by was
how do
well you can run it ninety eight jobs not on a dedicated in its basic cluster
but on the map reveals cluster
on you know the cluster
there's sort of way we are
trying to take things
today if you look at these various phases
there is
a wide variety of tools that are used in practice
for example formation
the sequel systems mapreduce
four the modeling as i said
precisely because this is inadequate people at the level of specialised systems in memory optimisations like spock
graph-oriented schemes like graphlab
and by
is well known
let someone else as well
young officers the possibility
of unifying how we build these
and the question in front of us
can take this further
like the refactoring
of the order
mapreduce systems
the began that you are
hardly carried forward in the same space
at this point
hopefully you'll understand the machine learning applications
the only under the hood
i haven't done a systems challenges
building these silos
doesn't want any good
the motivation forest which we plan to open source is built by
folks in microsoft's mostly
in my day mostly
we are planning to open source is in the next month or so
it will also be demoted
really mean
and we have built several things already
we have built from scratch
a version of mapreduce that is capable of running
is not intended as a replacement for the standard mapreduce it's a demonstration of how flexible the system can be
we also implemented several machine learning algorithms
today i'll talk about linear models only
but they've been doing many more
for those of you who are interested in research on florida where
you could use grief
as a platform for experimentation four year of research perhaps
okay and in the statistician make the point
this is roughly that's that's right
you're trying to provide horizontally that extends the yarn surface
in the examples and will give you illustrate grief
keep in mind the following colour coding
the yellow
this control control plane
quite a lot what facilitates
the really messy called of keeping track of thousands of your tasks
right which task failed
what state it failed
when started
do i have to restart entire draw
control flow can be a real issue
so we try and facilitate this
the actual user code that supply as part of your job you'll see an orange
at the computer resources the reef gets through you are you'll see colour coded
in blue
so beyond the control flow
that is what we begin by illustrating
these provides
extensible libraries that's
allow you to have a storied services network services state management services
and it has a dependency injection framework called band
that allows you to mix and match just what services you need for a given task for a given application
this is a
they are all of the
so it's very easy to deal with these issues them all the time lol
this is all will
that is really just the face down computation
if we take a small station to some function
we we can say no more than two steps of these operations
we see that he would say
nomination they want to
two d
if we want to see
so a lot of goals
he's going to operations that he mentioned them all the time so the
so so the
the relationship between
the computational complexity of the world
and the statistical lab class
which you still have the problem is that
all right
all right let me you
or how i used
this is this is the result cells
this is a very useful one
to the east and
so you can
even more
and also one
these classes with real or something
you know it's all really very simple to get this
very very
so instance
an example
in recent
this is consistency
that is
was actually really
it's the basis of
this list is it
so when there a service
which is
the result of
for that
the whole system to
the first lecture but i can repeat it so
that's one way to define machine learning machine learning is concerned with developing
the developing algorithms that learn from experience
model of the environment
from the queen knowledge
and i mean
so far so good bugs
what distinguishes
machine learning from some of the fields that you really want to use this model
for something
and something to be means for prediction
OK overview comes first then some philosophical issues than bayesian sequence prediction then i come
to this all element of universal inductive
inference schemes
and then the slide
digression because this is
so applications or alex would say then or in analogy i would say this is
ten months theoretical this work
remember alex always told you that our work is applied if it was theoretically
so this is
this is an theoretical this work then but it really works well in practice
if you can
and then about the universal AI
OK you will see that
so some philosophical questions around induction
i mean induction
i mean inferring model
from data roughly OK so
you can ask i mean does inductive or
inductive inference or doctor prediction
they use this models propagation i often do not distinguish between
these two things
so one question is first i mean does inductive inference work at all
OK it seems so
but then you can ask why
and how
in the bayesian framework
you have to choose the model class
you have to choose the prior so how do we do that in a generic
how then we can do optimal decisions if nothing is known about the environment
and finally for instance
what is intelligence
if you want to work on a i it's good to know what it
OK let me first give an ontology to different field i mean i could
but benefited let's take complexity theory because you probably know that
so what is the goal of complexity theory the goal is to find
class i were them
for solving problems
to show lower bounds on their computation time
so if you i mean read the statement to look at the literature everything is
rigorously defined and what is an algorithm
during machine problem class computation time so
nearly everything is rigorous
OK but most disciplines start in an informal way
and then it's time they get more and more formalized and
absolutely rigorous and then maybe even maximisation and then a few months in a certain
look at probability theory may you measure theory
it's not the kind of axioms and then you can do all kinds of things
OK for example set theory started informal way then you but the russell paradox the
set of all sets which do do not contain each other
and some point to formalise the axiomatized in our our
at least from conceptual point of view logical reasoning proof theory probability theory infinitesimal calculus
physics to conserve energy and temperature
and quantum field theory so all apart from the last if no rigorous mathematical formulation
quantum field theory of all developed in the nineteen thirties and
the most important theory in physics and most successful
still not rigorously mathematically defined
but it doesn't really matter in this case because able to compute numbers
OK so
so now let's look at machine learning
OK so machine learning OK repeat myself tries to build and understand systems that learn
from past data
make good predictions are able to generalize maybe act intelligently
so many of these terms are vaguely defined or there are many alternative definition i
mean what does generalise meanwhile good prediction means
understanding and so on so it would be nice
and probably very useful to have a formal
general definition
well characterisation of machine learning axiomatizations
i present a classical example plus from
seventeen hundred something
so he asked what is the probability
that the sun will rise tomorrow
so what you have so far as you have seen the sun rising every day
i mean it was cloudy sort of i mean you can still see this light
it's not about
clouds or
and so on so we have seen this on raising awareness in the days
and he asked me what is is the chance to the greatest tomorrow
i mean it
good to know
so i mean if it not raise sort of your sources to stay
OK so you i can think of several answers so you can say OK p
is undefined because there has never been an experiment that tested the existence of the
sun tomorrow
thank you
now the answer would be people one
so when whose first invited me to be a one of the speakers
at this conference
my initial reaction was
it's about time because they been coming this conference for seven or eight years and
i don't know why no one ever thought of inviting me to give a keynote
talk before
so this is long overdue as far as i'm concerned but then a little bit
humility crept in
there's a little bit of me
and so i decided in in
in repentance for my initial reaction i should
actually admit to some of the mistakes i made
over the past several years
so i think i'll give you a little bit of my own personal history just
to set the context
and then i'm actually going to go through some honest mistakes that i made when
i was following you everything and was very comfortable to predict
the failure of various technologies
and hopefully learn some lessons from the mistakes i made that we can all benefit
from and then i will attempt to do it again
and we can see at some point whether or not my
predictions are true
so a little bit of personal history i was born in new york
during a period of turmoil and change in the united states my parents are both
civil rights activists
but very early on i was really
i believe myself to know everything
and my mother tells the story of how
i refuse to watch
in the early but rogers TV show
because i insisted there was no air in space
in second grade this true story
our second-grade teacher gave us arithmetic problem to keep us busy for a few hours
you may have heard this story before in the context of the more famous mathematician
and i but honestly i didn't do this
very quickly
surprising the crap out of my teacher
except that i've got the wrong answer
sorry my life so how did i do i want to share this with you
as this is true maybe you believe the story if i show you how it
actually happened so i started writing the numbers down
and as i started adding them it occurred to me that this number was going
to keep getting bigger and bigger and it would probably be easier if i started
with the bigger numbers and work backwards so that
when i got to the and i'd be adding small numbers to be once instead
of being numbers too big numbers
and as i was writing it down on my piece of paper i just so
happen to notice
you know the first five or so numbers writing down backwards lined up perfectly in
some two hundred
with the pair
in the beginning so i literally having come up with any particular formula for this
i just went on my piece of paper and wrote down all the numbers from
one to fifty
and then backwards wrote all the numbers from one hundred down to fifty
noticing that they sum to one hundred and then counted how many times it happened
but unfortunately i counted fifty twice
so this is the kind of thing that i do all the time little little
flashes of insight mixed with the a complete lack of rigour
so anyway my teacher maybe go back to my seat do it right
the first prediction of the future that i made was in nineteen seventy five when
i predicted that i would marry for forces majors
how many people remember far majors
brings back fond memories
now i'm going to launch into this sort of admission of failure part of the
talk and i just want to make sure that everyone understands that i have a
because some of you may feel insulted by some of the things i say and
i want to make sure that you understand that i never insulted group of people
are less i consider myself part of that group
so all of these insults i consider insult to a group that i'm a central
part of consider myself central to
so i'm really talking about myself
so how did that what kinds of predictions that i make
so i started out at RPI in the early eighties as a system administrator i
was the classic kind of system administrator that revels in his own esoteric knowledge and
insults everyone who doesn't
no those things so we had at that time
a unix system that had been
usenet email protocol
which was just having for hackers and system administrators because
you have to have the most esoteric knowledge imaginable in order to be able to
send an email message from one person to another you had to know the modem
connections between these unix machines because the way the mail was routed was basically you
computer called up another computer and how to finite set of computers whose
phone numbers in new
and you literally had to know which computers do about which other computers this was
known as the past
and if you wanted to send me
email from say bell labs
you had to know
that the bell labs computer talk to have a computer some other university which talk
to another university which talk to ours
and then the last thing that was my user account that she
so this is fantastic but i was not so stupid as to think that this
was a usable technology
so i predicted that no one will ever use email
i said over and over again in a that time growing community of
fans of networking
what right
it what
he wanted
these are our
well we it
who we are
i been
the same
we don't know
if you add more
the common prior
you can read more
we use
or one
we you
the people are
he said it
all right
o five
i'm not on
in the real world
the game
as the first step
before we get into the current what the velocity of the electron
it's phenomenal
it's an incredible
so v then becomes i was one hour
so i get the square root
again e squared up here
i am goes downstairs
four by epsilon zero
and i have you and are
and i told
you know what is an old capitol are you know what
four by actually non-zero is one over four pi actually non-zero is famous nine
the power nine times ten to the
o nine
so i can calculate obvious
and if i stick the numbers and if i did not make a mistake
and i find about two point three
i'm ten two to six
a second
the high-speed five
million miles of
if this were straight line you would make it to the moon
in three minutes
five million miles per hour
it one goes around
the problem
now i have to go to the current have to find out what the current
so the question that i'm going to ask now is how long does it take
for the electron to go around
all that time capital p
is of course this conference of my circle
divided by the speed of the electron trivial even the high school students in my
audience will understand that one
and so
i know two pi r is because they know INNOV and so i can calculate
the time just by sticking in the numbers
and i find it is about one point one four
five ten to the minus sixteen seconds just met
how small that time is cannot even
we can't even imagine
what it's like it goes
ten two to sixteen times per second around
there's a huge
one point one four times ten to the minus sixteen
really should have one point four times ten to the minus sixteen
because it doesn't make much difference but
in case you substitute in the numbers
is one point four
ten to the minus sixteen
now we still haven't
i found the current current almost there
because when you look here
this is the electron going by
and every one point one four ten to the minus sixteen seconds leg goes by
so the current i that's the definition of current is the charge per unit time
so every
capital t seconds the charge he goes quiet so this is the definition the current
so this current and
that you have which is simply due to the election going around the proton
is about
one point one
times ten to the minus three
that is mind boggling
many and here one electron going around
represents occurrence of
and of course they have the magnetic moment you
that is i times a
we already calculated a
and that we also have the current i
and so
we now get that new
is approximately
nine point three if you put in all the best and most correctly times ten
to the the minus twenty four
and the united support employees
this is current is a has nothing to do with that a this is an
NP is careful this for me this these are uris
and this has the name
this is called the boar
what we can understand with our knowledge now
but you can if you ever quantum mechanics
the magnetic moment
of all electrons in orbit can only be a multiple this number nothing in between
one mechanics which has its quantisation
it's not in between the two or
it includes even zero which is even harder to understand
could even be zero
in addition to
the dipole moment of the electron going around the proton
the electron itself is the charge which begins about its own axis
and that also means that the charge is going around
on the spending scale of electrons
and that the magnetic dipole moment is always this value
and so
the net magnetic dipole moment of an atom or molecule is now to vectorial some
of all the dipole moments all these electrons going around means orbital
than ten dollars so very small citizen surface
and this kind of a scalability issue as a pretty fundamental issues about the nature
of the algorithms and these kind of scalability issues are very important in particular for
pattern recognition
OK so let me explain
quickly what's the idea of super resolution the is pretty simple that we take the
example which is the first example where that was done in geophysics sparse spike deconvolution
so the idea of sparse spike deconvolution is that you know that the input signal
priority should be a set of spikes
OK so it's the sparse signal which is the sum of the is now you
have the convolution with the filter you and you see here it's called the way
now that's what you see over
and these weights let's kill the low frequency and the kill they have high frequency
so the fourier transform of the dirac is far basically
lot of information here here
and every or it's impossible to recover
not superresolution claims that you can in fact if you look at the problem
what do you have the data are just in fact a linear combination
of the hough vote by you you get you translated that's what you see over
there is very simple if you do that these things
well you know there is zero so that the issue here
first iraq second and third year i
john OK so that's the simple idea of super resolution
how do extend so the idea which is behind is to say you have a
dictionary which is a family of functions and the prior information that you have on
your problem here is the fact that you signal
has a sparse representation within this dictionary so that's the way you incorporate prior information
now if you look at your data now the data which is you have plus
noise can be written as a linear combination
of the dictionary elements which have been transformed
by the operator you
another term which is basically the error terms
now what that shows is that now the data has also sparse representation but not
in the original dictionary in the transformed dictionary which is obtained by
the function transform
the problem that you are now having is that your original dictionary for was for
example an orthogonal basis like the hoc basis but here you are going to have
more than that they all the space of dimension q so now we have redundant
and now we are facing this problem of decomposing a signal in redundant dictionary
so the idea is you are going to take your data
and you're going to
try to find the most sparsely presentation you can out of your
transform diction
and what you hope
is that what we call for a set of coefficients
precisely corresponds to the approximation support of the real function because
what we call the
two inverts
the function
you're just going to say oh i observe u phi p
so in the original signal what i must have had was fighting
here you're using your prior information because you is not invertible so they could have
been many other functions but since you know that f is sparse in this basis
you've decided it was fine
that's all very well indeed out of the
you've selected
the appropriate function for so it's a pattern recognition problem you had to find the
appropriate part of
after degraded observation OK
does that work
OK let's look at sparse spike deconvolution
this is an example an observed that would here here's five
those close to the
this is your data
with the
you do decomposition in your transform dictionary minimize now one norm and what you get
is what you have on the right
what you can see f till estimator is very close to f
at the beginning
in this region
now despite
you completely messed
now why is that the case because if you take what you're working working out
of your way translate
well that's what you cannot recognise anymore
you can detect individual events and your
OK so what is actually that shows that in order to be able to do
these kind of things
so this kind of pattern recognition version you need to constraints on your
dictionary often
and this constraint is notion of you got here
what's the a again the idea is out of the data
you're going to decompose that in the transformed dictionary
and you want to identify the approximation support of
the first thing you need is that if you have a fast decomposition of
the elements of
the question is which of those is the best
well if we look at it in a probabilistic way
we can actually show the decoding three one appeals dismissed intuitively
this one is actually the most probable
so much as well that
so we wanted to it is calculate the probability
any given model
produced the observed sequence
and we do that with reference to all of the possible sequences this is the
all the possible sequences
but that model could also produce
so if we assume
what that the sequence was the results of model
six single bit sequences
and the original knowledge of the system is the bits can be placed anywhere
i can overlap
and we have to consider
it's a perfectly good decoding this sequence how many of the sequences
could this model generated
and the answer is of course
we can place each bit
one of ten positions
allowed to overlap
so there are ten to the six possible sequences this model could have generated
the question is how many of those sequences
look like format exactly sequence we observe
that gives us a measure of the probability
this model
generates or explains the sequence
because we can interchange their
and we can commute
he's been warned that changing our sequence
you can see that there are going to be six factorial
sequences generated from this model that will match
so the probability of this model
the probability of the data given the model
six factorial over ten to six seven twenty seven million
that to probability is point no no no seventy four that's
everyone OK with that
so if we were to actually
run simulation
from that very moment just described the
we should find this is the proportion
it actually look like that of say one example if you know convinced
so just following after that
model two
three two bit sequences
we have to place three symbols
and one of only nine positions as nine q possibilities
we can permute them
in three factorial ways
so we have six o seven twenty nine
to one or type two
on this intuitively appealing sequence
seven ways of placing this
yes some laser placing this
nine ways of placing this
but only one of these generated sequences
is the precise hit
we won
this is less complex model
because only the only one in the set of matches
the set is only sixty nine sorry sixty three large
so the probability is one sixty
o point one five nine
so the simplest model
because we consider
all the other possible sequences
it is more probable
so all three the data equally can't separate them in terms of how well they
fit the data
if we take account
all the other possible models they could match
this one looks more probable
we do data mining course
we don't normally
it's not a case of model either fits the data
the data perfectly or doesn't
use these is the degree of accuracy
squared error misclassification rate something like that
so that's why introduce the full model
which is why we look at
and over simple decoding
which seems some form of our
so this decoding the seventy three possible places i could place simple
generating set is only has three
elements in it
but seems to bits of our
and and i'm going to seem very simple noise
he says i can place those two bits anywhere that any two bits
and i went the same it's white
so the possibility
different areas i could given the could be too
tend to use two or forty five
the probability this model is one
three times forty five hundred thirty five
and that works at this point there will not some form
the over simple model
doesn't quite fit the data
is less probable than the relatively simple model
it does so you can say hamas this probability calculation
automatically imposed trade
but interestingly there was simple model is actually an order magnitude more probable
and the most complex model we have
the escape probability calculation
this automatically
if you like
built in occam's razor trade
occam's razor trade
it's assigned low probability too complex model
because they had to take into account all the other sequences all the other data
model that accurately predicted
and it's also
signed low probability to over simple model
based done that
because it had to introduce noise model
not to appropriately explain the data
and that noise model
then the space of all possible data sets it could still observed again gets expanded
because of the noise assumption
so i just want convincing case
you know maybe you don't believe that maybe that means calculations
i just have a quick simulation i can say
well we just simply empirically proven
those numbers in the last slide
i'm just going to do with a few lines of simple model you can see
yourself you so minded
we just going to sample from those four models more just verify this values
so this is just six placed random almost write the code and you had
good luck to you probably
this is three two space random for t
on the eighth with two randomly for
and every time symbol actually matches the target sequence of flashing white i will consider
i'm just really stimulating
exactly what you might think
if you just wanted to prove that
i think
so we just a ten thousand samples
and what is simply count how many times they generative models that simulate models that
as you can see
if you have the more convinced
model three
much more probable
ten thousand times it hits the target sequence predicts it explains it
so far more than the other models
the red lines are the theoretical values and actually much formal knowledge expected
the model for
the noise the over simple model doesn't match the data with noise
still predicts the target sequence from all the complicated model one
so have the written down much in probability distributions are really done any probabilistic manipulation
done anything by counting sequences
but this example is basically bayesian inference in disguise
and the reason is
it's because we calculated probabilities from models
take into account
all the above
that's the data those models capable of explaining this is the essence
the way bayesian inference implements ockham's razor
penalizes over complex models
i apply the disjunction rules which state is
one go and the right branch from the other
this is the left branch
it is the right branch and copy everything across
that's what the external
OK so this is x
this is the next
and now the contradictions on both sides
kids that they
i i made up you didn't question when we when i told you about necessitation
i mean you you see what's going on basically what it's doing is it's creating
a successor world
read the bottom guys that success that makes the diameter
this is the world that makes the diamond guy true
and this makes the boxes well you have to take all the boxes across the
junction box
we assert that
in a moment of get their money
usually in tablet formulations you don't see multiset that's because they don't do it properly
OK i want to do it properly
there is a k
there is a closed k tableau for this guy
OK so what does that mean well theoretically has all show you know what it
means is that
the negation of this formula is not k satisfiable
why because this formula is valid we know
i'll get onto
OK so more examples
same rules
this is an instance of the t shaped box p know implies b
the previous slide show you define negated i get is
the only thing i can do is apply the and so i apply
now i'm stuck
this thing has to be driven by diamond and there are no diamonds
OK there are disjunctions and conjunctions and there are contradictions
so what do i conclude
this tabloid
not closed
i tried one and it didn't come
over here the same thing
push negation normal form
there is a conjunction applications
i've got it done formula so i can apply the diamond rule strip a strip
off the outermost dominant expose this guy
take away the box
support of the outermost i mean there are no boxes
and now i'm stuck kind of doing things
OK so that tableau
the club
but i claim there is no
because k tableau for these guys
had i go from one
i just tried one
and now i'm saying it doesn't matter what you do you won't find clients one
how to make that leap
that's one way
but not it's much easier
it's completely deterministic i had no choice is
what could i went in negation normal form
and that's all i could do so there is only one template that i could
sit here what can i do i couldn't do anything
right it's completely deterministic
because this doesn't hold in general right so
we'll get to that in minute
they were more examples of tableau now your question about six
and this is the proper way to do
proof theory
but most
tablet systems in in the literature don't do that
do don't want to keep that anymore
let's get
you know very well
is that blood
and now i'm going to do
this proved a couple of lemmas
so if i semicolon x has a closedk tableau
so let's call phi semicolon x
right i remember so what i'm going to do is i'm going to take it
for five semicolon x
so if there is a closedk then so does phi semicolon x column y four
how my going to close this tabloid
just going to do whatever i did hear and ignore the stuff in
OK thank know this stuff and why
it just gets carried out
as this
right the stuff that i don't want to take statistics carried down
and sometimes here some of the boxes will come across but i can keep doing
that just ignore this stuff
it's not quite as easy as that but that's the intuition
OK what does it say
is the intuition here
we have a closed tableau already then adding extra junk at the root
this new ball okay if the ball that we drew is not of a special color
then is of some color drawn from H then we will note its color and then
return two balls of that color back into the urn okay so basically whenever we reach
into the urn and pick our ball with probability alpha over Alpha plus N we're
gonna pick a ball of a special color because we start off with alpha balls
of that color of that special color with probability one over Alpha plus
N so basically this is the probability of picking one of the balls out from
the urn and we'll pick ball I basically okay yeah so this is kind of
the the interpretation the metaphor for this urn scheme okay
so an interesting property of thus earn scheme is that it has this clustering
property right so basically if you look at N of this variables theta
one to theta N then you notice that because each of the thetas can
take on the same value as one of the previous thetas they will
take on they could take on less than N distinct values right so the
total number of distinct values is given by big K and that could be
less than N okay it's at most N when everything has a distinct value but it's
it's a it could be less than N okay so we can think of the distinct values
let's call them theta star one to theta star K then we can think of this
distinct values as basically defining a partition of the index set one to N
alright so that if data item so that data item I is in cluster K
if theta I takes on the Kth distinct value okay so this defines a clustering
of theta one to theta N and if you look at the induced distribution of a
partitions of one to N this is called the Chinese restaurant process and this is
now gonna relate back to the problem of model based clustering so we
can think of each theta I here as basically the parameter of the cluster that
data item I belongs to okay and they're at most K different clusters among a
data item of among a data set of size N okay
and it turns out that in the case of of coarse model based clustering this
notion of the partition of the data set one to N indexed by one to
N is of course gonna play a central role in the problem of clustering because
that should be the output of our clustering algorithm as a partition of our data
set okay so that leads us to the Chinese restaurant process to before I start on the Chinese
restaurant process I'd like to discuss be a bit more precise by what I mean by
a partition okay let's say that we have a set S big S okay so
in this case our big S consists of six individuals alpha Alice Bob Charles David Emma
and Florence so a partition is basically at this joint's family of subsets of S
whose union is S okay so here's a petition okay so it consists of a cluster here
of alpha and David of Alice and David another cluster here of Bob Charles and Emma and another
cluster where Florence is by herself and the set of all partition of S is gonna
be denoted by this script P of S okay so that's a set of all partitions
and basically a random partition is gonna be a random variables that take on values
in that set okay and particularly will we'll working with partitions of of S where
S is the index set of our data sets so it's gonna be one to
N okay so and that the typical notation here is this square brackets N okay right so what's
a Chinese restaurant process it's basically a random partition okay and here's a generative process for the
random partition okay so imagine there's lots of metaphors in Bayesian nonparametrics is
part of the nice fun thing about this area in in this metaphor
imagine that we have restaurants okay of a Chinese restaurant with an infinite number of tables
each table consider infinite number of customers okay customers are gonna come in
one at a time and sit at some table okay so customer one comes in
and will sit at some table and we can just call that table one okay
and then a customer two comes in can now decide whether to sit with customer one or at
new table and customer tree comes in can now decide to sit with custom one customer
two or new table okay and each of customer has a decision to make and basically
the probability that a customer that just comes in will sit at table C
is gonna be equal to the number of customers already sitting at that table divided by
Alpha plus the total number of customers sitting around all the tables at that point
in time and the probability that the customer will sit at the new table is
gonna be equal to alpha divided by the normalization constant
so basically how does this Chinese restaurant process define a a partition basically
there's a term like that so what's the idea so
if you if you are
in this country space on the robot wants to get to this part of the
space and once or that part of the space
you could just discovered that the state space by
as we know that our
so it's enough and and OK so if you discretize than wealth
you get some resolution and
again the longer so
and this doesn't work for the reason i
they cannot work due to his chances like this
so what do you do
so one problem is discretisation is that when you try to uniformly colored space and
as i tried to show you
if you
ridiculous accuracy of one or excellence and you have a high dimensional space in order
to have job someone the cattle
it can be a better option right so that's the idea
so is enough
doing uniform discusses at this position and what you do is that
uniformly distributed uniformly at random select some points so you do at random discretisation
so the question is about was the finite MDP in the case when
you do a uniform grid escaped isation
and we had this
so this is this is the contour plots or so to say i have the
density function of the
the next distribution and if this that then you get something like this so here
the trail of as
correspond to higher probabilities
and so you would get a discrete problem representation and if you do a uniform
so how do you do that
if you have this wrong
so that that's the first problem if you want to have this random discretisation
again what you have to do is just to look at the monte carlo literature
basically if you want to compute
and ultimately value function what you have to do is that well if you find
a problem some over the next state and you do you want to use value
addition you some over the next
if you have it continues
space and then the song has to be replaced by the so the change
this is integrated with respect to the next state y
and so
you want to compute in the rest of this form so hard to compute in
the as of this form
but you can use weighted importance sampling
so imagine that you're at a certain point
and you sound puts some other points may be uniformly at random
then we learned from almost all that you could be waiting for downsampling
so this is what you do exactly so in order to approximate this integral here
which is
if you're primary interest
basically you just you know computer
this is some of the products and divided by the sum
and that's going to converge to this integral
so that was waiting for something
is not clear
does any does everyone see that
so you know this is just the last large numbers so you divide by and
you divide by here
here by and so
this is the probability distribution so this is going to converge to to just one
and this is exactly call that into this in
OK so
so far so good
and so what what do we think that this might avoid the curse of dimensionality
well you know in high dimensional spaces if you want to compute an integral is
also what to learn from numbers four
you could really interested this sampling saying then
this is going to come independently
at the rate that is independent of the dimensionality of the state space
that's fine
so far we have a good track
and so what do we do
the way they are going to discretize the NDP
is that
we just compute this this creates a transition probabilities so you have this base points
x one and x and so that's the there on the grid that was laid
over the
state space
so that we want to come up with the discrete MDP
so what do we do so we can't we have to compute some transition probabilities
and rewards
the transition probabilities
i going to be
just this normalized transition densities so
if i had stayed xmj
i two action a what's my
density at a point x y z is given by p i and
my transition probability and the discrete problem is going to be proportional to the
when i do this
i'm just
pre computing what i'm going to need
if i want to execute
value iteration so he invented tradition
i will need to compute this in right
instead of computing that in that i want to use or santa claus
so right now or something because it will be the same sample set x x
suffice it of y phi
so i is here via five because that corresponds here to the next state
but in the random discretisation method you just had this random great
and you are using that sample
in all steps of a iteration right so that a set of samples is uniformly
or the state space
so it just satisfy this condition
the same condition is here
so just saying that these acts suffice if these are acts of phi
then well what i can do is that there is enough
during this island dividing this by the other i could compute
does this ratio first
we can show that if we are able to maximize that
to find the best
the best thing here the best new set of parameter
then you can show that maximizing this
the likelihood of your data so the goal was in the intellectual to find the
parameters theta that maximizes the likelihood p of x given theta and there's this iterative
way that tells you
but if you're able to maximise its expectation
then you maximize also
the likelihood
and here in fact you see the e and m steps because
computing this is in fact doing the e step it's the your computing the expectation
over the hidden viable and doing that is the same stuff
hi i am not sure if i have time to
two two weeks there is proof
after that and i'm not going to explain it may be it's on your flight
at least some of the slides in some slides in my website but i don't
have time to to go
what i would like instead is to to provide you intuitively of holidays that apply
gaussian mixture models so
what i said
we first need
to decide what is our having viable and as i showed you already graphically in
that case we're going to decide that the hidden viable is
that we're going to assume that each point was generated by only one goshen and
we want to know which washington
which points and this information is is going to be are inviable
so let's go back to the mixture
model so we have a mixture of gaussians which can be expressed here as a
weighted sum this is the weight of each caution
and this is the likelihood of it to goshen so this is the the gushing
pretty and this is the way
so it's the mixture model
i'm going to introduce this is viable so i suppose i know
i know which caution
a generated which point so it because i know that
four four while i can define this variable which is q i g
which is going to be one if russian j
o point
i mean zero otherwise so i can just have these big matrix q
which tells me which gaussian generated which point so of course i don't know that
but i suppose i know it
if i know the information then i can compute
the joint probability of the data
that information
the fact that i know which caution generated which
o point
by being the product over all the the examples
and then the the product of all the gaussians of
the priority of the goshen x two two this value which is one or zero
and the like you would to the part of this value which is one or
you have to understand is very very carefully these two value one effect to these
two powers or zero and one so when they are zero this is equal to
so when goshen
goshen j did not generated by i
all this is equal to one so it has no effect and when goshen
j generated point i then you have the weight the probability of goshen so in
the end you do have the real like would if you knew that information so
this is equivalent to the mixture model
mixture of gaussians if you know this information
now it's as as you so this auxiliary function that we thought
works with the log likelihood so we need to go into the log space so
we take that we're going to log
that's very useful in fact because of the products because
sons and the power
come here and this form is much easier to
to work with
i'm going to have to plug
my theoretical into that stuff so i defined again this auxiliary function which is the
expected value of the log blah blah
i just plug my question into inside this and because expect that
it already viable q
in fact the expectation of the sun
you can always showed is going to be the sum of the expectations where it
applies so in fact the only way are the only positions where i think you
are here and there so i'm going to put the expectation over q only so
i have put all my expectations
in in one place where it matters
and in that very useful because now so the goal now is to maximize there
that's the only thing i can do to maximize in fact two to work out
what i to expectation terms so i first need to estimate the expectation terms and
now i'm going to apply in basically and i'm only going to need to estimate
and this is basically
to estimate whether
that goshen
j a
whether goshen g generated the point i so
i'm going to estimate this according to my training data and i have when i
have used to make them going to modify the value of the parameters according to
the i don't have time to show you do mechanics
give you results but
it's very interesting on the other hand
i i really don't have enough time for this but in the end it's very
it is very simple and you can express each of the parameters of the mixture
of gaussians which include the mean
my talking about just the usual sort of knowledge right common sense knowledge that we
have is tweety bird can once the chair of the object in front pick up
the phone calls number what's the probability that my my wife of pick up and
so on supports can block a stack probably be so i want to be able
to represent these kinds of knowledge representations
but are not
classical sort of a representation of a major connection to what i've been talking about
prior to this is not immediate let me make sure that you are grasping why
i'm going in destruction
reinforcement learning is about agents interacting with the world is up to represent knowledge about
the world knowledge of all sorts of things and we want to think about very
flexible which sort of knowledge like these
and this should be clear and it is impounded that are really good way
two together and so we need to think about knowledge representation a fresh and again
and again so
the key idea
is the following is given the key idea behind what i'm doing is actually really
old idea the the the the novel part here is the these is
the computational aspects of the intuitive idea is very simple you know how to cut
my hand and i think up to you and a lot lot lots meaning to
you and one can build a knowledge base in system as i write symbol cup
talk about
you know the fact that you can put water in cups and you can you
can you can you know what panic up and so on so forth right way
to do it is just so
not have any sort of notion of couple directly but instead
they represent the knowledge about cup in terms of observable outcomes cup so for example
i might be able to predict the effects of the so object in a certain
way and here's something if i do this i hear something if i drop it
something for poor water or licey things that's all right so a cup is that
is a is union of a set of predictions i can make about the car
or or another way of saying that we are using is that a cup is
essentially a set of answers to questions i can ask about this
and so i think about representations
there are in fact in effect
knowledge representations that are answers to questions one can ask about objects in the world
how big very precisely a good mathematical in just a minute or two of us
so what
going to come
the all of that but yes i'm limited by the language they speak so so
the point is that i can ask questions entirely improper times get at time
because the precise in the future but i don't think you can
so what causes mean estimator
right is going to be
when you and
this time
image or so what i mean is so i mean
and this is exactly
so for example physical world
you all
the last where
right now i focused on the ball and what we see is is is is
where the square focused on this and
full or whatever that's where we want to that
people who live in this direction and keep the direction some probability may operations
so how long it
this is in practice would lot
the classical way modelling it so a physics based model after all of the environment
policies that i'm actually equations or with this discrete versions of that and so on
that's one way to model this environment and you can make any answer any question
about its environment once you've model like that is an alternative way of thinking about
the model
a model that instead of having this notion of ball and i is instead captures
knowledge in the form of answers to certain questions so here kinds of questions so
music which so this bottom diagram represents questions and answers to questions so these are
the questions for example you know
this square being black is an and is is is the answer the following question
if i move down one step my i
what's the probability i see the ball and it's a very high probability that you
see the ball because he don't have the ball in this case is moving down
if i move down two steps two time steps the ball will be here with
high probability so i see the ball with high probability
but on the move right to the ball moving down i wanted the ball
and so on so these are
the square here represent questions and the grayscale image in it represents the answers to
those questions
so i'm not sure yet this but giving you and anticipating the following thing is
that having a notion of ball
and i was going to have representations
in which the
representation of knowledge is in the form of answers to these sorts of questions
there people just a few more slides no free so now
this let's see the system in action right the ball down as it was moving
in the i moved right words right now
it's basically saying look i can't catch up with the ball
right because it was moving down
every time will keep moving down i can't catch up with the ball
in these in this much space and now you can see what it's saying is
that if i keep moving right twice
i'll be on the ball with high probability i down after that able to follow
ball sort of predictions it's making
let's let's make this let's use mathematics and the mathematics helps the let's go towards
come back to this so
i'm going to
think of an alternative representation
of the notion of these slides are not in here
so if you give on slide because of their and here they were not being
this is this is the slide in the first day so ignore these slides
i think
as you
well maybe it's in there may be some possible
i don't know
it's possible it and then yes i see it and they're okay good
so should stop rushing and go slowly
what i'm going to try and do today
in the rest of this talk is try to give you an alternative model an
alternative to mdps and pomdps
have notion of underlying
hidden state
which you never get to see
is it is the observation so if you think if you know a tremendous palm
diffuser HMM actions
four is just to the left palm deepest you i'm going to show you an
alternative way of thinking about the model in the world which doesn't use any hidden
variables and as powerful as part b
so that's my goal
in the plane
will be and i can vector and what will happen when i multiply by p
what i project vector x i i i called b here because this is our
familiar picture but now i'm going to say that b was no good for for
the for our purposes
i'm interested in
in the vector x that's actually in the plane
and i projected and what do i get back
x of course
doesn't move
every x in the plane
unchanged by p
and what's telling me
that's telling me that x is and i can vector and it's also telling me
what's the igon value
which is just compare it with
the idea of multipliers
so we actually all
now i or the other
i expect you should be because i would like to get free time in three
i would like to call for three hundred ninety two
playing one
so can be not
good what's the right i mean vector
that's not the way
good morning everyone
per second
yes because one
so that the
another here
right there but here
one of the project i
so there is no space
px not for those
or zero
and the zero
so what
my question is one of the four main
i we we know projection matrices
we can write down
that a fraction of the universe transport
well from from the page
see what are the idea
are these limiting the second example
permutation what about all
zero one
can you tell me to
so you will just soon enough so i would like to do
these couple of examples
see the picture before we
before we all
going to
system where that need to be expected because
and why
so what
the same direction in his body like this
i mean
x one x two rights which is
for the two components of s
the vector
with its
x two x one with permuted
turn out to be
multiple of o x one x two restart
can you tell me and i are here for
people one
only one factor that i want
so what you would like know why
so that i can find a permutation
that would be
one one
OK thanks
that be alive because the right
i one
one of brain
that's what i but there are two by two matrix
i think i'm going to
what about what where
maybe we just like
there actually this one thing is going to be about
my my
it's not like
i mean
and i
it's going to come
so i want to
which reversed
i want my real
so what
no one
that's what i like a
OK want one
let me what
can i
like john
well i
the a
i repeat you the conditional independence that is not obvious from the graph this in
the probability can you change the graph so that it will be obvious from prior
right it's a good question and in general you can't in other words
the graphs that i'm described not sufficiently general to be able to represent arbitrary sets
of of conditional independence properties you say the question
right list the conditional independence property for and try to construct the graph that describes
those i think that's really your question and in general you can't go in that
direction i'm going to show you some examples of
for example directed undirected graphs there an equivalent they can't be mapped into each other
and there are yet other distributions sets conditional independence properties which can be expressed as
either directed or undirected they can be expressed as a chain graphs so the answer
is no in general you can't
capture although conditional independence properties in in the graph
any other questions
OK that was example number one that's good example number two
so this is the tail to tail case again we got three variables and the
through node c
and the half is called tail to tail because the tails of the arrows connect
to node c
let's right the joint distribution
well it's PMC given
he is a given its parents which is c so that that fact
and then you be given its parents you see so that that fact so that's
the joint distribution
and again is the missing link is no link between a and b
so this is not a general distribution it's just it's sub family of distributions
what happens now when we condition on nodes c
all we have to do
it to divide the joint distribution by pfc
so get the thing conditional on c and divided by p c
another piece is just cancel
so it's very much max to do you can see that at some point the
screen you can see that it does indeed factorized into the product of conditionals so
in other words the this family of distributions y conditional on c
i get a vacancy times p the given c so a is intended to be
given c
so one of the title should be c if c is not observed
again i have piece of a and b is not equal to
and again you can see
if you
have a common being some of the sea when you some of the sea
these two factors get muddled up general function of a b not to products
so again we have
again we can
express that graphically
by saying that
a and b independent from each other because of half the next eight
but when we observe the it blocks the path causing these
nodes to become independent
so again it's just like the the undirected case simple graph separation
now the sort of thing this is the case which distinguishes directed graph from undirected
graphs and is the head to head
OK case
again got three notable missing link
but no c is now head to head with respect to this path is that
it has to be harassed touch the no
the joint distribution is p of a given nothing he would be given nothing you
see given its parents a and b so that's the the joint distribution
now suppose c is unobserved
p of a common b
is just
some of the city of a b and c
by some this c
in the first two factors platypus some
and the idea some of the factor because that the conditional distribution is normalized sums
to one
so it follows that p of a common physical to p of a times he
it was the other way round
a and b
are independent of each other when i'm not observed
so what happens when we observe c
well we observe c
that property is not so when we condition on c
so if you go back to
to this case when we condition on the
we divide by
here see
but we still have this factor which is the general function of a and b
it doesn't factorize into product in the function of a the function of b
a is not independent the when we observe
in other words observing see unlocks the path so exactly the opposite behavior observed no
blocks the path causes a and b to become dependent
something else which i will improve here mathematically but all motivator in the minutes i
think it should become intuitively reasonable
supposing i had a graph which looks like this
two know here a and b
and c
and i have the a descendant
called so descendants just has the obvious meaning that i can follow
is apart from c to d going in the direction of the arrows is called
the descendant
so again
a a is independent of b for this graph
now suppose you observe the descendant
well the descendants
is observed effectively what it's doing is propagating some evidence to back up to node c
and changing its distribution and that's causing
that's it for this particular observing c
it causes
a and b to become dependent
and i'll try and motivate that with an example rather than
worrying about mathematics but you could complain about that on a piece of paper if
you like by
so here's my example to try and explain what's going on this is sometimes called
this phenomenon sometimes called explaining away
so this is all to do with head-to-head nodes in directed graphs
so let's have a simple example let's imagine that i i take a photograph of
an object
i'm gonna particular pixel
i mean look at the color of that pixel
let's say that pixel happens to be a blue colour
well i can model
the process of observing that blue pixels using a probabilistic model and i can represent
probabilistic model graphically
simple example of what we do in these graphical models in machine learning
we know that the colour of a pixel is determined by two things it was
determined by the colour of the light which illuminated it and it was determined by
the reflectance properties of the physical material that the surface was made of
so for example
they could look blue because it's made of the material and illuminated with white light
reflects the blue components absorbs about going
it could be blue because it's a white piece of white surfaces illuminated with blue
but it can't be a piece of red surface illuminated with red light because that
would great
so when i observe the pixel i get some information about the colour of the
surface and about the colour of the light
but neither is determined completely
so i can represent this
process by little graphical model in this graphical model reflects the causality
of the process by which the
pixel got its color
so what i'm saying is that i'm going to choose the colour of the lighting
so there's no represents the color of the light source i choose that from some
distribution already dies not pick
a value for the colour
then completely independently of that
i would choose the colour of the surface
of like the real solution to the exploration exploitation problem the various kinds of approaches
to this
one of the relatively recent paper where they talk about the beetle algorithm is considered
the state-of-the-art they they use the latest ideas from solving continuous partially observable markov decision
processes to to reason about how should i after egionact so that its
improving its understanding of the environment as it goes
i can exploit various sort of ideas and parameter tying these two states actually have
the same kind of distribution so we can learn about that together
they demonstrated in various kinds of problems it was getting what appears to be near
optimal exploration of five state leagues this by state domain five here is slightly larger
domain from the comes from more realistic setting that he didn't do it nearly as
the biggest so basically it's not really
the planner the the solution here is actually outputting an entire learning algorithm right fit
in a bayesian setting there's no learning right there's just you know observed data and
so the the dispute has to kind of truck long and then spits out an
entire strategy for dealing with the environment of a certain size so that the learning
algorithm now encoded inside that that that plan
so you can imagine that's going to be really hard to do in a very
general setting
it doesn't have a lot of the ability to computational and so i don't know
if it doesn't
doesn't scale very well
now you can say we get away from this a little bit and talk about
instead of bayes optimal really trying to maximize it what about new ways of optimal
this is kind of like the PAC MDP idea that i talked about before but
we're going to find mistakes a little bit differently we're going to say an algorithm
is near bayes optimal
if the number of missus oh sorry it makes a mistake if an action is
taken has value that's very far from what the bayes optimal
solution would be
right so it doesn't to solve it out and it doesn't have to get right
on every trial but it has to get it right on nearly all the trials
and what call during show this year is that of
at least in the case where all the states are separate little bayesian learners
all you have to do is keep at this bayesian exploration bonus you one over
and for each action has been taken in times this of course is going to
zero is you take an action many many times this this this bonus goes to
zero the for actions that have been tried this bonuses is substantial and causes the
the algorithm to choose those actions and learn about them
so what they showed is that this this bayesian exploration bonus idea it's very simple
it gets too near bayesian
but what's
but as kind of rock my world it probably will rock your world nearly as
much as my but nonetheless
this is the shattering make this idea this being near bayes optimal is not the
same as being PAC MDP
right so it's apparently but they seem so similar in so many ways
but there's examples and questioning showed one in the home shared his thesis where
this is really really little simple MDP with two different reward values and you have
a prior that says maybe there are roughly equally likely
when you get but there's two different models here action one gives you a half
with certainty action two
in one model gives zero
any other model gives you just a little bit more than half
but no more than half the to be epsilon optimal you have to try and
in fact you have to try infinitely often infinite but bayes these optimal what do
it these is optimal basically says you know i could do that by the time
i figure out that it's any good
you know i'd missed opportunities for reward and so it actually sits there taking
why worse than epsilon optimal actions forever
which really bothers me and then i decided well maybe i don't really know what
reinforcement learning trying to be
and then i was reading over my daughter shoulder when she was reading a cartoon
book and i realize this is well known in the literature
so it's this is the calvin hobbes good cartoon actually just calvinism this one so
so just to set up three calvin has has just discovered time travel which by
time travel here has the cardboard box your time machine on the side of it
instead of doing his homework and what he did to use the time machine to
from six o'clock necessary six thirty his at six thirty creating a time machine he
goes to o eight thirty which is bedtime
by which of course by then he must have finished the homework so you get
but there is a similar to classification is where the prediction space has structure for
instance labeling document this document pixel data mining and also with machine learning and or
charlotte clustering and or some of the EMI and or some of those years and
there is some connection between them they are not independently
the difference between countries your decision on what the classification is whether the connections between
the labels are part of new data
or part of your task
which makes it even more
in ranking you will be on the yes and no i have some linear ordering
an interest in europe and america page of course if you have an administration you
can use it to rank
and if you can draw and you can decide whether not
number one should we do with results has still not
what did she say they usually you don't know this
show you india after non with with a connected i the is there a website
that you know that
were many much much information related mining is for post and another thing they do
is more similar to all sorts of things how much money are not only minor
one of the questions i posed really only once a year later you is what
by using
and if you if you have if you know anything about statistics and data analysis
statistics you wouldn't be suppression that our
high up there
and this one is even more useful tool they would mention
and know what find had
do it
would have data or of course tag dominance whatever the openoffice
and outlook
i dont start analyzing data without having seen it yourself
have a look at it be aware only looking at that time tiny tiny tiny
portion of it but still have a look at it
at least not less
let it go away
or open it in excel or this have a look at it
well actually you
we will see many many things that we
that is that we try to come up with
things that are similar to each other
then you interested in
another point is
the we have and one for
in sense if
could actually that structure
so we don't want any
stefanie observations will stand up and say this information to me because they are too
many different places all of them
let's find
this time
one of them somehow
it's in that case the similarity for instance marketing you identify common characteristics of parts
of the population
get smart section definitions of what's going on
produced by moving clusters single point many times boss once this
and economics
many times divorce
once magic that looks like this
you have give him
there something like this not magic
well maybe you can i can
o devices because something like this about magic to that that it him everything about
it and it's not that easy
so what we see here here we have seen became is how we
i'm not a we will see later on but there are many more here popular
many spectral clustering was mentioned two
when there so many other is different ways of doing the same
no different ways of doing similar things with still
what is the best
so actually
they serve shown before
such a variety for the time being
and at what point those interest strong and
restrict freedom
then going back to justice harlan
recall that he said that the intervention had to be safe
and so i come back to work in another balance
what disease risk
threat of half
balanced by what assurance of vaccine safety and efficacy
a universal recommendation for vaccines
or even stronger mandate
are required
now this is a good point at which for me to point out that safety
is relative
it is not absolute
and that in medicine we
can reject but not prove
the null hypothesis another words
you begin a study by saying there is
no association
a vaccine and an adverse event
you then do a study and if you find evidence of an association
you can reject the null hypothesis
because you found evidence
what you can do is prove the the null hypothesis is a hypothesis
you can prove
there is no association
between an adverse events and vaccine
so you can
prove absolute safety safety is again irrelevant issues
and i would ask you to think for a second about the old
rotavirus vaccine is no longer on the market was called roller shield and it was
withdrawn from the market
about nine years ago
and with the vaccine we had a million individuals vaccinated
about one hundred got sick
he died from the disease
or from the side effects of the vaccine
and one died in the side of this vaccine we're intestinal obstruction called deception
without the vaccine
about sixteen thousand will get sick
and about ten will die
from the effects of the disease
and the point and this vaccine was then withdrawn from the market
as unacceptable in this country
and the point is that i'm trying to make here is that if you are
for the deaths related to the vaccine you also culpable for deaths
that have occurred when you withhold
so you are on the importance of the land
so we come back to
the fundamental question which is what should be the balance between the state's duty
to protect the public health
and the individuals right
for free choice
now let's look at how that plays out
the way we have restricted freedom in this country is through school immunisation laws and
the modern origin of school immunisation laws just up the road in los angeles
when there was a major league out
right in the nineteen seventies
there were deaths associated with the numerous hospitalizations and they're very courageous health officer
i decided to exclude children from school
if they do not have a proof of community
some fifty thousand kids were excluded from school
but most were back in school within a few days
that was kind of of the beginning of the school entry immunization loss
quickly multiple states
enacted such laws and some of them and forced them but not all
common traditional architecture of the web to actually do this to to enable this lincoln's
publishing of structured data and because it is those allows you to to discover thing
unexpected things in the same way that the web has allowed us to move from
one one website one document to another on
so the this is growing at an incredible rate and looks like it the trend
will continue and there's an increasing number of
applications that
that exploit this what to do something useful for the end user or talk about
more than that
in two thousand nine what can we expect to see both exists even more data
sets that cloud is is getting increasingly hard to for richard and his colleagues to
actually manage the you can see the errors all kind of cut across each other
and that's just gonna increasingly hard when we won't be able to represent any more
in in just one
one image there are a number of tools which you can use if you want
to publish stuff you can which said you can roll your own or you can
use one kind of rappers like d two r server triplify
and there are a number of kind of a growing number of plugins for these
what deployed services like drupal and wordpress
so much so
so it's all good and we
the work and implementation issues and getting well practiced how to actually publish stuff and
if i will feel more able to two
get involved in this kind of thing having been tutorial but this is a research
perspective is the number of
thorny issues which we really need to address and which provide nice opportunities for people
looking for interesting and kind of exciting research directions topics
like is already on the
the range of link algorithms which are being used is very limited and the algorithms
themselves very primitive really needs to do some better work in developing
the link algorithms which we familiar with them well practised in using and
the good news is is loads and loads of existing work on on stuff from
the database community we just need to get better looking at that and see how
we can use this in in the web context and see how we need to
adapt to this new article was rather well complex
hypothesis is that we have validated this experimentally is that users
i just want to see one RDF argument about protecting their want into it if
you have any particular topical entity seven counterculture i just don't want to just see
one person that once you have a broad overview pages i can find out information
about places to eat all maps of the area blah blah blah and what culture
is the
the kind of central entity that the the and the and browsing
that's the hypothesis and if first theta really validate experimentally but if this
is why do we need to progress from the user interaction point of view and
there are lots of these
thorny issues which the semantic web
community has been
working on the two of we to do more work in these areas particularly
in particular the consistency and trust in quality
being a kind of fairly relaxed approach until now in terms of how the data
in the linked data cloud is licensed some of the data is about is is
a republication of data that has the already published under said license
that lighting effect is always expressed explicitly or even expressed all and this if people
are going to feel confident building applications that consume and use integrate this statement to
conf about the terms under which they can reuse this
that means we only to get a lot better
making explicit statements for all the bits of data published about how those lies
papers from the linked data on the web workshop this year in beijing
about the open data commons
framework licensing data and we can also say that provide some
direction for how approach these issues is also
commons which is useful for philosophy it works but one
i think i will mention stages there's been a tendency to license data using for
the creative commons licenses
this find a blog post but if it's data
factual information then you can't use creative commons licensing that stuff you need to look
at something like the open data commons PDDL
the legal framework for which it based just doesn't apply to data so
i think that was the
this is for you
explain what is supposed to be
the model for the same using these boards
maybe that was the first thing to happen
the second world war
the hgplvm prior
right yes
so let me show you
it's simple to use
we try to
although this is a very simple works
and this is the only for
some joint
and then we use is the result from the use of the word
that is one of the
we minimize the creation of the signal to reach so that you don't have to
do with
or as
there's a lot of this is i don't know
so this is the
many of
o thing is
so we can see what you want
one is first so you see the
first of all you have
this is the first
this is the
so we use this small two five c so this is one not the
here for two
because this is what to do
and because we can
brennan also
o point of view
this when you start
so you get sounds like that
this is because
if you
so this a list
the same process here
from all of this
so one of the things that this
when you see some observations and what is
so this is an example where the whole
but i think of it
the reason for that is that
so you can see
i agree that
one of the things that we
is that most
this is a sequence of interest most and you know it was have started
so i was looking at
and yes
other side of the world
so far all of these sequences
similarly used by the
we have
so i
percent b
that would be that
with respect to use of the sequence is so supposed to be
and also
so this is the
o five three
so it's a
and the different colors
here is that it's very
last year and you get
one we go
far from the training because the one that is not
let's war