by fours or whether it just
go with you say OK i can do sixty four
i can deal with sixty four nonzeros
we're going to go down well under sixty four
and of course
four higher and
pays off
OK so what are these factors
well these are the identity is this is the identity
of size and is sitting here
and here
and here is the diagonal matrix of size m and here is its conjugate i
so so i have to say what is diagonal matrix
the matrix
w square
w to the n minus one is diagonal
or maybe it's just that this is conjugate is just minus
think it's just
OK i'll come back to that matrix this matrix is the
it is the permutation that puts all of
even coefficients zero two
the this permutation p here
p is p takes the numbers zero the
this is in order that they come
and and produced puts them in the order even the first to o two four
one three five seven
so it
evans before so in other words this FM acts on that evening
this is
and this
this half size transform acts on the odd in this is
did i really should have
i mean
you know what i mean
so this is p so so the matrix has one in that position one and
that one and that one that was that's the zero second fourth and sixth then
one in the first third fifth and seventh
that would be the eight by eight
well sorry i jumped ahead to a by a here
and but that's it
and there's the
why don't we
just to be sure this is the key
can you tell me what it will look like
breaking up
so while it's
there's one more key idea here and what is it
if i have
so if i have if n is one thousand twenty four let's say let's let's
take that as an example to to the ten
i'm i'm using i'm doing the FFT radix two it's actually the only one i
shmuel winograd created by
number theoretic tricks
efficient FFT is of
prime powers
porter minor they are these are the very opposite of prime these are probably the
most used so suppose that is to the ten
how many
how many modifications so so
how many modifications will it take to multiply just flat out by the matrix f
of this order
so the operation count
it would be what
what's the number that we're trying to
trying to improve on
so if i just multiply then by n matrix by a vector phi just did
this or that this
and i am i am in terms of i got to in square right
because i got an terms in each sample and of the the ants squared entries
in the matrix
OK so
so i'm trying to be dense square
now i know and what does the FFT lead me to
i try to
so this single step
let me that happens square
cut it in half
and i won't count that because of the just adds and here is just one
and over two
this is at
multiplying by those both multiply the same
of zero convex to the right of zero so you know very well behaved function
but with this
with this function you can take you know a combination of just three of these
these tends to
two nonlinearities and and get into the VC dimension and the the trick is you're
hiding the sinusoidal
in inside this still
this can only and so so then you can subtract two pieces out there that
have these nice smooth properties and
the other picture here right you know he is the difference between
between the
the standard sigmoid in the dotted line is this one that's hiding a sinusoid in
that when you take the difference between two of these things you can extract the
same k it's it's very very sparse and very small level but with thresholding so
the magnitude of this thing doesn't matter so we know again we have through the
size of having infinite VC dimension
OK sorry i mean i guess i should
step back this might be some cause for concern right that about the
here is that the here we're talking about the VC dimension it's the right notion
of complexity if working minimax setting and yet
you know when you look at this picture
if we were to do some sort of a gradient descent optimisation over
the quadratic criterion using a class of functions defined in terms of this thing right
we're never going to be able to see those small wiggles
seems quite unreasonable and so the distribution that gives us
it exhibits the difficulties with the the infinite VC dimension is one that is exploiting
those small wheels
in the threshold the class
o point is the optimisation problem
that that we want to solve that is to find the function from from
this class
right that that minimizes the empirical error of the threshold function
that's a very difficult optimisation problem
and so
you know this is not this is not a practical course concern for this class
of functions
right because because
we we can solve the computational problem for this class to minimize in particular so
we'll see later when we look at a large margin setting we optimize different criteria
were not optimizing
we're not minimizing empirical risk we're not trying to minimize the number of mistakes we
when the threshold functions are optimizing some smooth
criterion involving the real valued function
the left here itself
OK so in that setting
our optimisation
is not able to exploit all the that exploit the full power
of this threshold the class
OK we're working with a slightly different
and these kinds of negative results point out
you know that if we were to to work with the right criterion would be
in trouble
we'll see later that when we work with something not quite the right criterion you
know we get around this kind of difficulty
OK will see also that the general results about to tell you
about to show you these
results about parameterise real valued functions are useful in in that setting also we can
build up estimates of the rademacher averages for instance the complex classes in terms of
VC dimension estimates for simple
simple class
these results are important even in the the large margin
OK so let me tell you i need one
technical definition two to explain the result that we're going to
so we're to look at
for for these thresholded real valued
and you and i'm just broadening things a little bit
to include not just a single real valued function parameters now
i've i've called i instead of instead of theta not just a single real valued
function but we've got k of them and when combining them in some fixed y
with the boolean function
OK so there's no
i just want to make
make my classifier actions a little richer
in particular so that we can include a certain
model of real valued computation
and relate the VC dimension to the computational complexity of calculating the value of the
OK so i need this extension to do so so let's look at the definition
we've got some class g of real valued functions
right and and all these functions that we're going to consider a continuous in their
in the parameters
these are all a and we've got some
class of boolean function
so we've got some boolean function g
right so this thing and that's from plus minus one
OK OK of these these signs two plus one one
and then we compute the function in a class by first computing these k
distinct functions parameterized functions and then take some fixed boolean function of
right so
you know why am i going to this generally let's look at
because the
it's very typical example we will see one more later but here i want to
look at functions that can be computed
founded time under certain model of computation
OK and that fits into this model of i i guess i
user nomenclature so this class boolean functions that we define down here is called the
k combination of threshold functions from
from g this present class
OK so
the the class
the class i wanted to find
is it a combination
official functions from the
the class of polynomials
right polynomially parameterized
functions for some value of k so let me explain the model of computation he
was talking about how much time it takes to compute the value of the function
so we have a parameterized class d these are the material parameters and let's say
x is is represented as a vector in rn
and we supposing that this
this is now a plus and minus one
valued function was saying that this thing can be computed
in no more than t steps
one of the following types
right so we take as input
then b
assigned this value g
output b
the action
and then
repeat this until
the reason
OK three which is also implemented by the the same enjoy
protection of sexual person
it it should
that's it so
not in that way
treatment of patients from as as far as
so far away
and at least one goal
allows us to record at least one in this
one goals
this will be
as i explained essentially the formula
is the same
it was simply
is not the can be
is probably the
existence of structure prediction
and join intersection process and he played form rather than simply asked whether there so
well that this is basically
the core well satisfies
seven days
we have an increase in sequence of these four class every conjoined g
the satisfiability
you seem like reasonable competition case
gerard of these
that eliminating everything else
but it was for the
last time
and then there the intersection
go to the goal states and
six of them
but OK
these form the simple case said
you can see
how good is the second that this
useful much much worse
and the
the reason is simply
on line these problems
sets of states that are reasonable by even more
actually there is much more information
needs to be much more than one needs
but so that so
what we are doing not what work
you will need to find one black
i don't know where you
the benefit of this
because we can this be fixed point condition what he's doing
we know
when you have with which
this approach is not as
scalable set approach
problem is that the former
class three is set here
they go to to be
the main reason is what i already explained
that the
it was like operation the worst case
can grow
number of
variables i
and this is no general way starting that doesn't happen also practise some kind of
growth is slow but some other kind of problems because three
the very
simply by
using this
it's not methods
OK one can run out of main memory supported by
memory like in sectors
one thousand eight
you you know what
only days in which he scored much better and is that approach is
number reasonable space is actually quite small
one is really high number of accidents two weeks so let's say this only
a couple of thousand of fans states
that are reachable by one needs hundred factors which
because of the very high planning is that the prose might fail completely but the
formulas in this approach states what's more than one
one of the problem
but the
usually there is that in those cases it is only a small number of states
one would be using logic
in one
what would be using the
it's certain
and not just what all
OK and that really actually brings us to the last topic
i'll go through this world weekly i'm not going to be playing with this and
the main ideas what is there
i started elected by sorting the transition graph using the many problem in the simplest
so given a bunch of data x one to xn sitting in the high dimensional space
you want to project you want to say project in the one dimensional space are
and find numbers y one through y n
each y is just the projection of x i
so you want to find
y one to y and to represent york high dimensional data x one to xn
and you want to find the projection
that maximises the variance of the data
here i assumed that all the exercise i have mean zero and so automatically the
wise have mean zero so that the variance is this particular formula which is the
sum of the squares
i mean you actually have to the mean subtract
to do that for the correct
definition of variance but i just as in the mean zero here
so you want to find
that w that maximises the variance
and it's fairly easy to see that
the sum of the squares of the wise
ends up being this particular quadratic forms
in w
so you want to find w that maximizes this particular
quadratic form
and that gives rise to earlier it's like question
and then leads to
finding the leading i can vector
the data covariance matrix
so i'm sure all of you have seen this
there is also something else which is the way to interpret principal components analysis
what principal components analysis is doing also
in some sense
he is
the best
linear subspace to the data
office certain rank over certain desired
let me just write that
so you have all this data x one through
consider some subspace h
consider the projection
on two a talking projection onto h of x i
and consider this
least squares
and i want to minimize this
overall h
this is also essentially the same problem as principal components
so what principal components is doing
is trying to essentially fit in this least squares sense
a linear manifold
to the data
so this is a very classical
widely used
you could think of it also just like the mixture of gaussians is very classical
and widely used and is the simplest instantiation of
structure probability distribution
PCA which is another classical example and widely used can be part of
as the simplest instantiation of fitting in manifold to data
but this manifold
is just
a linear space
so what was what is the more general manifold model say
suppose data does not lie on or near some linear space at all
suppose actually the distribution of the data looks like this
well you can clearly see the debate seems to rely on some
set which seems to have only one degree of freedom
and yet it's not obvious that lies in some linear space
so the line some dimensional space
so what happens
if the data looks like this
can you actually
to develop some scheme where you could unravel the structure of the data i realized
that there is one degree of freedom in the data represent the data appropriately
without trying to either fit some linear subspace to something that looks like this bit
aligned with the score
anything else you might think of
so let me give you an acoustic example which is a mark of three
ends up with the distribution of data that looks more or less like what i
just told you OK because the picture they put up might seem artificial it might
seem that i just made it up to make some abstract point so let me
give you an actual example of data is generated by very simple physical system
then yes the physical system
it's an acoustic tube of length l
and i blow puffs of air at one end of the two u of t
is the exciting asian of the steel so puffs of air at one end of
symmetry of
certain problems are yourself and really a very quite is quite far reaching we're going
to do it
well actually have a few occasions due to go to to go into this but
but the light-touch are underselling just give you some indication where the subject goes
right now
one of the mathematical description jas
now that i've said so far i'm sure is new to you at all
you just have to trust me that at some point before you know it some
things i say to you will be new
i hope
but what of the mathematical descriptions periodicity again the in the two different categories say
the numbers one is the associate
with either either phenomenon is periodic in time or function or for phenomenon periodic in
space for periodic in time for periodicity in time
you can use the frequency
all right frequency is the word
but you hear most often associated with the phenomenon that is periodic in time use
the number of repetitions the number of cycles in a second say
if the pattern is repeating one of the partners
and finally that term sort of undefined sort of a is the number of repetitions
of the pattern
in one second or over time
all right
that's the most common this descriptor mathematical description of a phenomenon is periodic that's periodic
in time for function for my periodic in space
you actually use the period
that's the only word really in use in general for the particular well one thing
that i
for periodicity in space
use the period
that is sort of physical measurement of how long the long longer pattern is before
how write the measurement of how
whether it's length or some other quantity measurement of how
we just say how big the pattern is repeated
they're not the same article
every different fields
they arise from different sorts of
is probably too strong statement but i think i think it's fair to say that
mathematicians tend to think in terms of mostly periodic they tend to think in terms
of the period of function of the period is the description of periodic behavior
whereas engineers and scientists tend to think of systems evolving in time so they tend
to think in terms of frequency they tend to think of how often
a pattern is over a certain period of time that's
but everything else is that same has to be qualified to get tired of qualify
every statement so i'll just leave it at that
of course
the two phenomena are not completely separate not always completely separate they come together periodicity
in time and periodicity space come together in for example wave motion
all right that traveling
disturbance traveling periodic disturbance
so the two notions aperiodicity come together
two notions here periodicity concrete bridges in space come together
in g
wave motion
understood very generally here as a periodic as a regularly repeating pattern changes in time
and movies
more jumps up a little bit i think are
so a regular
a moving results regularly
moving disturbance
like group professions for the quad
they're everywhere
mostly moving right now
there again that the two descriptors come in the frequency and wavelength so again you
have frequency and wavelength
and wavelength usually associated usually denoted by
this is for periodicity in space for periodicity in time frequency
four periodicity in time
as the number of times
so last lecture was arguably the most important
all my lectures
we saw how it changing magnetic fields
can produce current
an induced electric
the induced EMF
and finally express that
in his famous
law famous equation which you see there
on the blackboard
you select the closed loop in your circuit
link is OK
your attention open surface that closed loop
any open source
is OK
and you don't get an EMF in the loop
that's the time derivative
of the magnetic flux through that surface
the minus sign indicates
that the induced current itself
it uses a magnetic flux that opposes
the flux change
and that
we refer to as men's law
i will expand on this
a lot further
let's start with a
conducting look
a magnetic field
this is the conducting loop
but the dimensions the y
and that i have a uniform magnetic field
medical field b
it's like so
i choose
as perpendicular vector
two my surface this surface by text that closed loop
i choose it
pointing up
so the angle between the a and b
you say that the the
is uniform
so the flux
five b
it is defined as the integral
of the built the a
over these open surface
plus or minus with zero
phlox has no direction
so to flux
in this case
would be x y which is the area of the loop since the magnetic field
is uniform
it's very easy to grow
then i get
the magnetic field b
and then i get the cosine of the angle
so now according to faraday
it is the time derivative of this quantity that determines the EMF
you can do that in several ways
you can never be
change in the magnetic field
this is the area eight
of the loop
you can change the area
you can have the eighty
but you can also change data
you can have it is say that dt
and i will look at those today
this number here the way i've chosen ninety eight
is the positive number
if somehow
this number increases in positive value
the induced current that is going to run
i will try to create a magnetic field to oppose the change
so in that case
the flux which is now positive is getting larger positive
the current that's going to run
will be in this direction
that's lands for you
so it creates by itself
this current creates a magnetic field in this direction
and if the
magnetic flux which is now positive way have defined it
with decreasing
then the current
we got a lot of a around
last time
i did several demonstrations by we changed
we had the
and there was one particular demonstration
the blue your mind
and that you will tell
your grandchildren about and that you always remember
i hope
i'm going to change
and i'm going to change
the area
also give me then
induced him as
and therefore
induced currents in two
a closed conducting look
so let me
make another drawing of the
close conducting look
it has
lang's y
in which x
and i'm going to rotate this
my idea is considered three-dimensional
i'm going to rotate is about its axis
with angular
frequency omega
omega is two pi
divided by the period period time one rotation
normally we choose for that capital t
i don't want to do that today because you can compute you was that's why
so i'm going to rotate is around
so the angle theta that you have there
say that
then becomes theta zero
was omega t
going back to a to one
and i choose this state zero such
t zero
i choose my fate to be zero
and so i have nothing to do with data zero
so what now
is the magnetic flux
this is my look
i have to commit myself to surface
well i'll just use this flat surface
just like i did they i chose the flat surface
i'm free to choose any surface by not taking the flat one
and so the flux through that flat surface
is there the area which is x times a
x times y
that's the area
of these look
and that i have
in in the in the juggling usually learning machine learning general john fourteen classifier ignored
know this is called the model
this is called the model and
if x is uniform
which is often useful if you want to go
this the margin is just the
if x is unique nor the margin is just the distance
you can see from this inner product is just the distance between
x and the hyperplane defined by w
either way you want to see i i i mean i can think of executing
and then that is because the market
OK you know you can the
you can think of none of them scale this is another definition of margin
good so now let's see so if the margin is negative nine make mistakes so
if you make a mistake then you would like
to make the matters more positive on that same example that cause you to make
a mistake with the current classifier so got it how the model changes after we
made enough
on the same example
now let's look at the margin why
x p
so this is what you see is the margin of the same pair
but WP is that WP minus one with WP has been computed according to this
rule but this is pretty creek CA
why the w three minus one
plus y p
next you
and this part of town
why do you all think NYT that minus one for all x the
last YTY squared is one
so is
just x the
just suppose xt which is the norm squared
so now you see that the update
pensions increases the margin
by an amount which is exactly the description of xt
the weight
so it this is not guaranteed to be stopped it doesn't is not fully correct
doesn't guarantee that
if you see the same example again you're going to be correct going to classify
it goes in the right direction
because it had the negative the negative margin driven by post or
so now
you may
you may wonder how we are interested in seeing something more
useful about the properties of the guy
the the
so let's look at so suppose
so now i suppose that we
the first the first question to ask is is the following OK suppose that we
have now
which is really not separable
suppose now that we have
find extreme
and this is linear linearly separable
it means that
which means that there exists some u
such that
why he
thanks the
always begins zero
for all
means that some of the plane such that
all the positive examples in the stream dataset lying on one side and on the
negative examples lying on the other side note now
you may assume that you would want to ask what happens if i
cycle disagree on this
all right if i run
this protocol over and over
it will be hard to find a linear separator
and if it doesn't find policy so i mean how many times i have
make an update to find out the minister
none this this is the linear programming problem
so you want to find actually
you only have a set of constraints you want to find a point
in b the
in the feasible region
the objective function will come back to this little later so you might think you
can solve this by using a linear programming package but this is a simple and
incremental way of farming
so it is not the biggest problem but it deal really is having a very
simple way
of the weight and being able to analyse it in in
in a simple way is what it's all
so that's find any such u
in this talk i will introduce the problem the problem is and what is the
importance of this problem
and then i'll talk about the
model which we have proposed the challenges she faced by this morning
and the experiments how evil the experiment was the setting for the experiments and results
which you can
and some future work
but fifteen years computers and that have revolutionized the communication people can connect with each
across different time zones with the geographical barriers
and this has created a human this measure of social interactions which is call the
social network
as you can see in the
there are different services
which revolves around the world a better name
which has been catalyzed
this communication
and by the use of user interface and the stuff like experience these services like
friendship networks blogs wikis
collaborative tagging and media sharing
in our research focus blogsphere
block says could be individual or community
four individual blog sites these at all and maintained by individual users as compared to
committee blocks shown in writing by a group of like minded users
and the community blog sites more like discussion forums and discussion boards you can see
a high degree of group discussion and collaboration
there is an individual blog sites there are more like personal account you know that
is an almost negligible group interaction
we focus on community blog sites
to find these influential bloggers
it's considered of physical set scenario where you are trying to buy a digital camera
if you want to supercool gamma with all these great features
so in the physical world what you do is you go to an expert on
your talk to your friends who
get the reviews and feedback about this problem
in virtual world you
world online community and try to find out the feedbacks of this problem
now there's so many communities online in so many users they're giving the feedback about
this product so
which one you should go was feedback should follow that is the main problems
so here we introduce this problem
inspired by the analogy between this real world and blog communities we tried to answer
influential bloggers
and who are these can we find them
just active bloggers and influential bloggers for the difference between them and
can active bloggers influential influential bloggers b
active all these sort of questions
other applications for influential bloggers could be
that they could be more cynical easy spread the word about the product
and they could sway opinions in government policy and campaigns
the customers they could be really helpful in customer support and troubleshooting
i have really valuable feedback the products which can be used different companies for market
research surveys
and technorati published a report which said that there are eighteen point six new blog
posts which appear every second so you need to find a representative always so that
you can look at the end it's just not possible to look at all the
so these influential blog posts could be the representative articles
searching the influentials
as i mentioned we have
active bloggers and we have infringed bloggers an active blogger is easy to define the
based just on the volume of postings he has
and these are often listed on the blog sites
i don't necessarily influential that's what we want to find out and according find influential
by the
posts he has submitted
obviously it's a very subjective concept
what kind of statistics can be collected and how we can use these statistics to
give the influence of this blogger
and actually we use
four different statistic which we call social gestures
first is the recognition which is given by the incoming links on the citations
the more influential the referring posts are the more influential the referred forwards becomes
an influential bloggers replaced by a lot of other bloggers answers again is activity generation
which is basically the volume of discussion e
it generates which is given by the number of comments he opens on this blog
the third is minority which is basically the
number of outlinks he's using the point in order it is
we have done study is all ideas exert more influence so if the idea is
not really
it might not be very influential
so we give this by the number of for
o thing sees using some of the large number of outlinks suggests that the blog
post refers to several other blog posts hence less knowledge
in words which is basically hollywood blockbusters
right now using the length of the block was but there can be several other
measures like linguistic analysis
you can use to gauge the
how good this blog post is
when you combine these different social justice and then come up with the influence score
four about post
OK can have the wiki
or or
measure goodness to play for me i thought i would prefer the smaller blog entries
concerning the abolition of the blog posts so you don't have an incentive to write
longer blog posts so if you're writing a lot of content that means you have
some insight is undertaken got lot some text and that could harm the more and
as you can see in the for for the slaves we have various parameters one
of its these parameters are can use these routes to adjust these parameters the contribution
any better
when we see all colors proposal later brain
that's why
it is not true
it's the surface of the outcome
only read
and here
that's what
we say nothing of course
should be second with that so think that you can see
and so in here the light is polarized in this election
you be polarized this reaction
and i can show that this power
i have here polarizing sheet just the way you have said you can use your now
and you see here
i let the light through a polarizer
killed almost all the light i think it's close to ninety eight percent are
the same year
and let the light through
and i rotate
you see i killed the line so that means that right in this direction the direction of polarization of tissue
it's like so
and here
polarized this addiction
cannot like this
so you're not looking at the rainbow
that you're looking at something
it has all the ingredients in it
that explain
the next time you see a rainbow
it will look
very differently to you
i predict that you will check
whether the red indeed is only outside
it's a disease
and i can no longer cure the disease
and note of the can
you also try to find the second
are you will check the call sequence of the second very different from the primary
and what you will probably do if you have a linear polarizer on which you should
you will probably want to check the polarisation is kind
which is quite remarkable
and all the joy and fun
you'll get over and above the everlasting beauty of the bauhaus
you will see much more
then people will not have this knowledge and experience is therefore necessarily
rather shallow
new knowledge heads it never
every set facts
i want to change
direction and finish this lecture with
talking about sunsets
ask the question why the sky blue
and why sunsets red
the sky is blue
four very simple reason
that in our sky
are very small dust particles
and even
density fluctuations of the air molecules themselves
and the lights
can scan all those
has nothing to do with the geometric optics scattering phenomenon
and if these particles are very small
talking about micron
few microns at most
then the probability
that light
this get
is inversely proportional to the wavelength of the light
the power forward
and in physics books
we call this
ratings can
now blue light has a much shorter wavelength than red light
and so if you take the ratio of the wavelength of red and blue raised to the power forward
depending on what you choose for the wavelength
you get about seven
so the blue light
sportscenter about seven times more likely to scatter then the red
anywhere from five
to ten
so imagine now
here on the ground
here's the atmosphere
and let's say the sun is in this direction
so light comes in
it's the atmosphere here
you're standing you
this light
enters the atmosphere
the only way it can continue
if only scattering process
and so there is some light comes to which
very likely that that's true
because it has seven times higher probability
be blue
and read
but not only would it be
blue in this election but this slide here
also sceptics
also comes
and so the blue is highly favored over the on colors in the spectrum
and that's in a nutshell
the reason
this guy
is broken
it is essential though
that's particles which scattering takes place
is small
preferably one
what to microns
if the particles become larger they tend microns like
small water drops in clouds
and there is no preferred wavelength anymore
what becomes independent of the wavelength lambda
that's the reason why clouds are white
because all the cars
have a similar same roughly the same probability
to be scattered
i'm going to tell you before i do a demonstration to show you the blue color
i wanna tell you something that i will not
some of you may know
but i want you to
no the fact
if the lights
scanners over an angle of ninety degrees
this approximately the case here
then the that this scattered is also a hundred percent polarized
nothing to do with bruce like totally different from
and the reason why i mentioned that because now you can actually start testing your
polarizes experiment i going to do
if it is not carried over ninety degrees it is partially polarized
a little bit
until the end of the ninety degrees
strongly polarized so that means when you walk outside after my lectures
you look at the blue sky let's assume it is blue
and you look ninety degrees away from the sun which is a great circle in the sky
you can pick any point
you look very see by rotating a little polarimeter
that light is almost hundred per cent
but it's an extra bonus i want you to have
to appreciate the demonstration that is coming up
in astronomy
we see
this blue light
often from stars we don't
have any
dominance in blue lines
very bright stars
has the water that there are not given that
i so that the loan was what
you can compute that using
these probabilities will obtain zero point forty tree
however if i now no
it has rain or not
let's say that i know that it has range then the probability
the sprinkler is on given that
the grass is wet and
it has range
it's it which also can be computed using these properties
it's much more
which goes with our intuition that
if i know that has range
now the property that's my neighbours have watered down on it's much lower
so that's the phenomenon called explaining away so if i see ISO
i see
one the child then this is to become dependent and sewing
seeing that one of the two
will influence the computation of
of the probability of the other
this now and have shown this conditional independence seen on move
this small tree
this can be generalised to
any sets of not so this time we have like
conditional independence between sets of nodes is given
as set of nodes
so let's have
the poetry set of nodes a b and c
so for example here i think a as being a
b is being b
and see as being
the rest of the of the graph
the property of this
separation so i is
is said to be
the separated from b
by c
if each bus from a to b is blocked
that is
but there is
at least one and in the past
such that
now that is
head to tail or to tail
in the bus
and the another is in c for example
this one
is the
data tail
he's not observed
that's makes
that makes these two
not independent
or the other the other possibility that we say that
any passes block from the from a to b is block is to say that
there is another in the past so that he can e
who is head to head node
nader not nor any of his descendants so and you know we're not is in
here we have again this example e
blocks also the bus
does it look
no because we have an observation
so one of the descendants is observed so as we've seen before we have explaining
in which seeing these make that a and b are dependent
well in this second graph
f is observed which makes that he's
his blocking
the past between a and b and this in this graph is a observe
then a is conditional independence
of the given the rest of the variables
this usually because
this is useful i mean because you can write
you can see
the set take a set of variables
the rest of
the variables conditioned on this one which helps in in
and computation
most among mosses is that it
OK so
examples which you know
and which used this this this separation
this conditional independence property as are for example a face
in which
you say that you have example in
real examples of of
d component
and the lord said that
we have two class classification naive bayes
and let z be the random variable representing the classes
we want to take the decision
what is naive bayes taking the decision that
four for a new example the class
is the
is the one that gives me the maximum
of the
the joint probability of the examples time
the class
this can be decomposed
no money as it just using for the word for the
as the probability of the input given the class time the property of the class
and what's
what's the the naive bayes assumption is
as it can be seen here in the graph
do better than x one
so one particular type of structure you might want to have this band limited is
but you could also be sparse in some domain
now nyquist version number two would then be to say oh the band limited sparse
but otherwise let us be completely random
so only sparse
no other the structure and then again you really cannot do better than x two
this is smaller than x one and this is a really nice and important result
but i would argue that i guess we're not quite there yet because natural images
and probably also all sorts of other real-world signals i mean they're probably bandlimited i
mean at least you're going to you information that this young band
there are also approximately sparse that's why many
you know coding algorithms work
but beyond that they really have much more exploitable structure and that's what you can
probably also use to then even do better than x two for example in natural
and if you want to so
how this works and you just cannot prove it at the moment and you can
also do is sound empirical evaluation and then you know if you don't favor your
method in the in the in the way that i probably you can convince people
that this works
i guess that's what we did in our study
let me conclude
if we measure
real world things like natural images we have we should really be sure that you
know if we draw our design brand
using some
distribution like uniform that we actually
why these
the current axis and then we do convex simple convex reconstruction i mean we took
the lasso but you can also take basis pursuit of six select maybe a couple
of other methods on his way to the optimal in the sense that it meets
minimax lower bounds
which have been proven for sparse signals
all other things completely random
but then if you really working with natural images then you
i mean you can go to that of natural image statistics and they basically figure
out is that they are sparse approximately but actually that's much beyond sparsity which is
not random and which is actually pretty robust and that allows you to
so to do something which is basically impossible namely to robustly choose if it doesn't
much better than the next two for example
so here is one very important thing i don't know whether that really came across
so far
o method it's not that i'm just giving it all these prior information that people
know about images all method starts from exactly the same prior
estimation information there
the lasso reconstruction
it's exactly the same prior than what these guys take the lot prior for reconstruction
but the important difference is that it just takes that prior together with the likelihood
and it does more with it it's it's not only maximizing the posterior just a
little bit more
it's using the posterior to actually choose good measurement architecture
and i would say i mean i would conclude from from this study that
it can really help a lot if you optimize the measurement architecture for your domain
of interest i guess whether i can really only say that from natural images that's
my domain of interest but i would
conjectured that holds true for other domains
you can do that
with very little from prior knowledge
but but that really needs a little bit more than uniform random sampling you need
to do something which is experimental design i mean you just need to spend a
little bit more work
thinking about how you optimize to things
the last line
is that OK we did this in sixty four by sixty four images you can
scale this up some recent algorithms that work say images
including this kind of
sentence into some
and as we can
all unbounded others
has universally quantified so we can skip these
four also
have in this case
to say we just said if there's something is about do something
four or
and the type quantifiers is an existential
so there exists
he left his keys summaries
where the police are looking
example of this
how we write this cycle
so we use
there exist
same as before
that all this holds so
person this person is a person this person
it is located on this chart
so this is the same as this sentence here
is it in a rule
here it would be for example
the for all persons
that person is actually
there exist the lower so
lower level the first
so this
this would be a really
using an extension of twenty four
and they can be taken
it more for example consider exist exactly so must be exactly five instances
this decreased it and so on so
it's possible to elaborate on this
that's true because
if you can't cite walk
you've been following along the first
you all know
one of
a free for find between one finds that by the end of the soil
that this introduction to the cycle in which you may wonder why we're talking to
about the psychology language when you're going to be producing semantic
f of the stuff in you have using RDF and so forth well the main
reason is that it
o although this has some school this syntax it's a lot easier to understand
the so just in terms of dealing with the dealing with decisions
four to express in words and it's also useful to know
a little bit about attracting
inference productive content out of these
and so i come to terms
now i'm going to give you an overview of all things that are contained in
in inside and i think it was a little bit of time just connecting to
the site looking up some terms
see what's in there and see whether it's called the sort of content that you're
interested in the projects they before
all of it
has about ten thousand fifteen minutes
so things relating things to each other like this for example which can be used
to make statements like lights is friends with carbon carbonic or force
or false statements like like his friend
george w bush gore or universal statements about mccain like everybody is his friend for
these claims
and also three hundred thousand concepts which is listed cover of the terms that's generally
come up in
news articles and being
taking news articles with these terms recently
and about the musicians now most renowned musicians and in
the site
so what you get is the decisions which required to specify the text momentarily turns
and to give you the information about the sun had
why is the first and then amounts to i think about a million assertions not
many are in the full KB and in particular there are very few
the such called which make generalizations in
openside but
compatible with side so if you decide that you want reasoning then you can do
a inside the new can move up from the two research
do more complex complex reasoning
this is an overview of the types of knowledge in the knowledge base
about physical objects broken down say to living things and the living thing is about
the relationship between the pace of life forms and their relationships going down to
relationships in ecology the relationship between these organizations
and with their environment
and the environment as opposed to geography with
you know the content of the earth and the solar system and types of core
the kind of wave that you get is really not very much of a plane
wave we vision
the only case this
both goes to the moon
and then some of it comes back
reflected of these trader
corner reflectors and operators light
laser light
two times ten to the seventeenth photons roughly
in one of these policies only one
comes back to ten pulses
not much comes back
but it's enough if you integrate it
to get an accurate
this is the combination between us and the
corner reflectors in the
accuracy is about ten centimeters and the goal is really
handle on the precise orbit of the moon
i can show you this corner reflectors
the way they were
built on earth
and then i will also show you an optical observatory
as it is
sending out these
quarter nano-second pulses
laser light to
the money
so this is one of those
corner reflectors
they are designed in such a way that
if light strikes it
in a certain direction
that reflects the light in exactly the same direction back one hundred eighty degrees
very clever design
so the next slide will show you
in texas
mcdonald observatory
standing here
short brief pulses of laser light
to the moon
and what you see here is simply
kind of like of the dust in the atmosphere
and then only eighteen a little bit of that comes back with that is enough
to get the
distance to the moon
there are
on the moon
there's enough for this slide to
i on the moon
several cameras
they were left there by surveyor there's small cameras
the lens i think is only two inches across
and they keep an eye on the order of all the time
something that you may never have thought of
if you were on the moon
you look at the earth the the earth is there say
that an hour from now
it would still be there
and ten hours from now will still be there and ten years from now
it was will still be there as seen from the moon
never moved of course it rotates about its axis
you'll see that
we also see that certain parts of the earth at night and others are
that's different but it's always in the same direction so it's very easy for these
cameras to keep an eye on it so to speak or you have to do
is to aim them
in one direction you never have to change that direction
imagine that you and i will now on the moon
and we were looking
the earth
you for instance would seem curious as you see here
is north america
and this part of earth happens to be
very light
and here is the night
and this is the moment
that these cameras
are going to take a picture
of the earth so you expect to see a lot of light here
you expect this to be night
was no we are
you may think
there's so much light coming from new york
you may actually see new york that
so four types of distances in fact related to the to the first few
which is to you find this time an infinite
a set of measurable features
what's the point of looking for an infinite where we see a bit later but
for example if i look at all the possible
of subsequences
OK with the number of possible subsequences is infinite because it's a must or itself
so anyway for trying to count it on this feature space without having infinite feature
space even if for each
individual string
the number of
values different from zero is going to be finite
but still you don't have an infinity of possible infinity but at the same time
you can describe things as an infinite space
and you just do distances and if it's just you can define the distance of
the feature space and that's what you meant
and i just
give the edit distance and then they pass on to which we can
edit distance defined by of levenstein in nineteen sixty six and algorithms or typical algorithms
or from pregnant fisher nineteen seventy four there's been a a lot of things that
since it is very important and the to describe this mister levenstein sorry
there's always the mystery of what is it
so that the so this is really important this is what we're talking about strings
this is these are the top distance the distance it is mostly used because of
many reasons one of which is that it does take into account things like the
OK when you type the text and you know very very careful you don't forget
to let eventtype twice the same letter type one letter instead of another so all
that sort of noise you want to be able to
it to talk about it and typically you want to talk about it through the
edit operations the edit sort of mistakes you made between the road texture whatever you
typed in biology is the same you may have the real gene and whatever happens
transformations things have appeared in certain positions there's been some transformations were all this is
also described by by the statistics
so the basic operations of three insertion deletion substitution
and then sometimes people invented and things like taking two consecutive characters and saying well
you know i've talked one before the other side of the other way around that
happens when i want to talk about it here
so it can be described in terms of rewriting rules just for the mathematics we're
not use it here
and the idea is to say that we can't see much because
strange so that the idea of the matter is just to say that we're taking
a strange
right now the only thing that happens is the letter disappears in fact today seems
to have disappeared already shouldn't have here there's an insertion of a letter a
and here letter a has become a letter bee if you can't really see
exchange with the colours
so examples where the three operations can be described as follows right CC
and typically the idea is to say OK we're not going to have just one
operation because in text may have been various operations that have
he made to transform first x into the second text
so we will consider what is called the reflexive and transitive closure of this derivation
saying how many operations have we had to to do to go from text one
now then if i take two texts there may be various ways of modifying text
one to get to text two
prior to compressed stored by an insertion then delete and they're not all equivalent
so what the levenstein distance tells this is average time
distance is the smallest of the past
that allow us to get from text one two text
behind that there is the idea that the smallest is the most probable is that
all come idea although is not entirely justified is just the weight is defined we
will suppose that there are various explanations of how text what became text to the
shortest path is the one that truly came through this
in this case for example from a b a two a b where we can
see that we can do it into operations one operation consisting for example raising the
b and the second one that we've got a a a and then the a
the last a becomes b
that's one of the possibilities but there but there are others
now then this is the easiest cases in the case where every operation has got
the same cost and the cost is one
it is the co operation while is what normally people use the police when doing
mathematics or atleast when they describe the
so it it is represented by confusion matrix saying that to go from a to
a cost zero so basically the operation then teams operation coast zero doing nothing or
zero going from a to b
meaning substituting the a by b will cost one
and then a two lambda the last column
lambda means the empty string so h lambda means raising the deleting the a lot
of course one the cost
and you can also see that inserting in a the
here inserting a here
and i will also cost one
but it's not the only confusion matrix we can have a confusion much problem this
is not a mathematical one
and this one here is the typical sort of confusion metrics used by the biologist
you find the different proteins and you will find this school this is what they
call the blows from sixty two metrics
which in fact if you're looking at it is giving us some negative and some
positive weights and it's even giving us the weights on the diagonal saying that is
present the whole thing again
i would like to
go over a paper by sings lab NEC
and how do how and how to extract communities using factorizations
this attempt application in particular
so here's the full citation
structural and temporal analysis of the blogosphere through community factorisation and the main idea is
to use tensor factorisation to identify graphs over time
so it so we can also think of community is the temporal aspect so
we want to describe the intensity of a certain community at any given time
and to do it too
and the temporal aspect would requires intensive methods
so the results of this which
well able to identify several communities one of them being the hurricane katrina community and
here's the intensity of this community over time luckily hurricane katrina be
probably this was right after new orleans got flooded because we
new hurricane katrina was coming over here and then after that there was news related
to that
they also
upon status community
and this has all this is a much smaller size compared to hurricane katrina community
because there are fewer people that are interested in
in this blog sets and this was started with the post by by david sifry
on august seventeen to o five after spike was
and there's a lot of us to generated by that
so next what sort of anomaly detection can we perform and so fraud detection is
another emerging area for graph mining
and so
i'll introduce and fraud detection on e bay and a little bit of work related
to spam detection
so even a fraud detection there's no pro project and the full citation is here
and so is it the goal is to detect non delivery fraud that is the
seller takes takes your money and then disappears and you never get your digital camera
and so
if you if you knew the graph of all of
feedback that people are given who you choose to
to buy from
so we can actually
use user the tripartite graph and
but they they were able to identify three types of nodes that is on his
nose the fraud nodes and any accomplices
so we have so we have the from fraudsters up here and they don't actually
interact with honest people very often the most of their
feedback it comes from all these accomplices
any accomplices himself never perform any fraud because then
the whole project would
would just be be revealed that they do they they do
give high ratings to process to some prostitutes to be for instance they might sell
a lot of light
items that are sold for dollars something like that
and so
so the
the way they are able to identify some of these people is that they use
belief propagation and the intuition is that if i'm honest in my neighbours are either
honest or their accomplices and if i'm an accomplice my neighbours are either honest fraud
but different frost and then my neighbours will not be honest
so they use belief propagation using message passing and find the converges to some probabilities
of of on each node whether it's honest and accomplice or fraudster to
yes i i i i i just love this project they sent me a plus
plus plus plus
it could be either because i'm it's always the binary they give some men they
may or may not give some into some content to the actual review but there's
there's a binary
good or bad
on each one
they crawl the bay
they just do they just use the standard crawler and there were some
the it was somehow legit even made in evading complain about it the matters like
but i think that
there's there's some API
the EPA has
yeah i don't think the
so i think that they didn't really have this labelled data
i think the baby was pretty thrilled with what they did find
o means that you reviewed them
but you buy something from them and then reviewed repeated the transaction
so now quick application the patterns we
we've discussed to spam detection
so this was claridge are java
in two thousand six so they
there is no no semantics
and cookie came along in about fifty
o five o thing fifty four i've got the details at the end of lectures
if you want to look and he said well
this is really the modal logic of graphs named after so cricket
what are we trying to do
we're trying to the and these notions like truth and model
model with the d not model within a
what we want to do is trying to find the notion of when pfizer logical
consequence of gamma and prove some properties about logical consequence
OK and i'll try and wrap up by about ten o'clock today if i can
again this is not the lecture which we should be taking
shortcuts right so if i go i will just delay the break little bit of
something i had
you're amenable to that
what secret key frames
it's going to read somewhere that first
so you've got the indian already
could keyframe is that the graph WI i
so instead of using VE
the vertices i'm just going to use w
and these these are is subset of w crossed over right so w can have
a set of points
w crossed w is the complete graph where you put all the edges it
and in our is just you go back and delete some of them
so hours just to
could keyframe is just to directed graphs
what's the valuation on a kripke frame
well it's the map it looks complicated but it's not all of these is
so now i'm just going to rename these guys just using these
now is in w so i'm just going to go back and rewrite these W's
we are using the same notation
and now what's evaluation
is a map from every atomic formula to true or false
i the truth
or else falls
at every point
simple way of thinking about it is this image where this point you just write
out the atomic formula that he not p one and p two dot dot
and then you go through and and
you just decide
is it true or false
maybe it's true maybe it's false whatever
OK when you do the same thing over here
for every dollar valuation says if you give me a world and i'll give you
formulae that at the of atomic formulae true there
here we are again p not p one p to the top and you evaluation
might be different so i suppose it's which is exactly the opposite that's perfectly legal
you more world you have the more variation you can make
is that makes sense
doesn't make sense k
OK w is the set of worlds
OK so it's the vertices is
right so this is called the point is called w no
the point is called w one the point is called w two
and pain or
our language of formulae
OK i remember up here
at the top
they with the atomic
so what i'm saying is that we build formulae
out of these atomic formulae p not p one p two
they can't be broken down into further
OK and we build formulae
using these connectives
OK so we have more and more complicated formation treated like this
and we go so in classical logic which you've seen before what do we do
what we do is we take evaluation
the same
just ignore this for the moment we just take evaluation and say
they know what is true
o p one p one is false or whatever write in classical logic we only
have one the evaluation
in modal logic what we do is we just
bill that over graph what we say saying is
imagine you have valuation of the atoms to true and false
right now you have a kripke frame which is the graph
two separate things
OK so
syntax was formulated
chris keyframe is sitting here
so the word frame should be see inherent semantic
it's just the graph
and now we're tying them together
so w r
is the graph that
w is is the graph
OK that's sitting here
as the frame
and the evaluation
there's a valuation here
whenever you give me a w
and one of the atoms so this is your european or p one p two
so so that's the trick here
but we do so so we have a practical question here
two question about specific values for these unknown parameters these are numbered
and the way you will get this
it is
what's called analysis
hopefully this is
this is the tree
so this is sort of an aside this is why it works so there is
general model
so that's the general linear model
there are algorithms out there so could take this into r
so it's
please give me the estimate of the basis of called the these so hot
and then what you have is
what the model predicts the output should be
for each y michael fifty values so that is
i would say yes to beta zero place so that it is the place sacked
the only with plugins of all these users and then take original data feed through
the system to what we get to the end
and that we call fitted value from model
we can compare
the city value for money
one with what we observe one of the different
let's call the residual
the size of services
related to
you can explain variations related to these that solutions that got flow right to those
what we would like to estimate is the variance of those things i would like
to estimate sigma square which
it was written down in the previous slide
including the
but any linear model
do is you take use residuals square
and divided by
but the number of data points x and
the number of pages you go out there so here we go
one b so that and and b in here
so that was an plus one
so be zero beta one beta and so that's what that was so one peters
and take away from the number of data points you got
that's about formula gives me three
i will give a decent estimate of sigma square
now the service
it will given decent single square in
this model one model
if this model fits the data correctly that that will be a good estimate of
sigma squared
if you don't want to talk about something distributions this is sort of information that
you can get about something obvious i want to know
well the properties of this thing that square
which i can work out
this case is calculated from the data
calculate because i want to know about six square but also about the behaviour of
this quantity
under different scenarios so that's what they something distribution stuff is about how
what's going to happen to this quantity that can tell from the data in general
what i know from statistical theory is this
if got the right models
so it's correct is a good predictor of what's coming out there is a square
will be a good estimate of sigma square
a single word constant that's the building to hold on to a fixed value
if got redundancies that is inputs they don't actually affects the output
the related to the output then
i would still have good estimates that was quite so if i use the same
sort of formula
to get the best if i knew the my model
things are important missing from it so this is where we're going
does not include one or more inputs that it ought to things that do affect
the output some of those things out there
now what happens
as square
i will not be a good estimate of square in fact it will be big
bigger than it should be
at the beginning
we need to be bigger than single square is that's the point so that we
could estimate so is trade
i can compare
two models can take complex in other and input particular inputs to the model
adding the
the estimate of sigma squared change
but you know that
that was basically happened is that the input needs to be included in the model
when i first went to the estimate things square to high that i didn't call
variable and maybe come down to the right level
so that's that's what we're trying to do so
we decide which actually should be in by looking at what happens to this quantity
ask where does it go down or what are well
how much does it go down when you add to the sum of all when
you drop
inputs from the model
OK so that's the general
let's see how it works in the case so we had to model
which was
which is the same as this but i had a little bit about
it's like this model
but it was
is that have all these bits about treatments
so the difference between the model that we're about to look on this model is
that of course that we're looking at is politics
blue these from the model
fort to get to their effect if forced beta b beta c beta beta are
from a those all zero that's the same as excluding the inputs
from the model because they don't have any effect if i got them so
so first of all the thing is if
lastly this model
or you can say is like saying
but compared to model i just had with this model
where they just they
terms to do the treatments just don't exist about to do the different blocks
so hard to compare two models i can
bring in the impulse to do the treatment and see what effect it has upon
my estimate of
so do that this is the sort of output you get from one you get
from our which something like this so
in this output
the quantity that was going to ask where is this thing
it's the residual
i mean square in this table
so when i look at that was the change so this is just a single
so look at that
influences on ordering and actually what favors
what favors crystallisation
factors favouring crystallisation remember we're not talking about perfect crystals here we're talking about local
warming over certain lengths of chain which give rise to some
strengthening of the material and so i'm just going to go back and revisit one
two and three above
i'm going to ask how composition hottest actors city and how does confirmation and hands
crystallisation so first thing was leaked composition
the way to favor crystallisation is to make
materials more nearly uniform the higher the degree of uniformity in the poll were the
greater the chances are that it can zigzag back and forth and in a predictable
manner set up these zones of
crystallinity so self this is a city straight chain of a linear chain polr if
it's made homogeneous
of the same composition than the chances of its folding back and forth on itself
and setting up this local
sort of semi crystalline
semi crystalline regions are greater than if the polymer has some random variation in composition
so the factor that favors crystallisation is
having a single composition so homer polymers are
much more easy easily crystallized so as an example polyethylene oxide can form crystalline polymers
were as if you take the polyethylene oxide block copolymer was a poly
propylene oxide the second case is more likely to be amorphous
the second factor one look at his tactics city
texas city you know you've got three forms of texas city ISO tactic send tactic
in a tactic and one that's more readily willing to pack is going to be
ISO tax
so i so tactic version well
be favoured
standpoint crystallisation we have evidence that i ISO tactic
i tactic
polystyrene is a highly crystalline so you see some of these hard polystyrene containers
they are predominantly ISO tactic whereas a tactic
a tactic polystyrene is dominantly
so there's the influence of texas city and the third one is confirmation
this confirmation that we've got the linear chains you've got branch chains and we've got
crosslinked chains and clearly following this paradigm the linear chains
our favourite
when it comes to
the formation of
ordered structures so if you look at something like
high-density polyethylene
that's shown here this the
the opaque milk jug this has a high degree of linearity in the chains whereas
branching or crosslinking are going to make things very difficult from the perspective of forming
crystalline structures
and in fact here's something that's volume versus temperature should remind you of the unit
that we've discovered in silicate glasses we see
but the
cooling curves here at two different rates and fast cooling has the in the curvature
higher glass transition temperature than slow cooling and similarly the with fast cooling there's a
higher degree of quenched in
three volumes so all those ideas apply
the other thing i want to look at now is on the basis of what
we've seen so far what are the properties of polymers and we can tailor things
to a great extent but there are certain properties that that they are that they
all share
so let's
the document goes
the first one
electrical insulators
whatever as why we have to look at electronic structure here we have strong covalent
bonds up and down the backbone and we have
o relatively weak van der waals bonds with some hydrogen bonding in between
no case are we looking at free electrons so
covalent bonds
these are interesting
molecular bonds
with covalent bonds we have electron sharing we have octet stability and the electrical
former group because
the group g
of natural isabelle in
so it doesn't matter whether you multiply things
this subgroup is always normal
so that's why
the union of the set of cosets
former group but
they form a group under different location
which is this one here
so you can see this example
you can construct this by
o to blind
all the multiplication table for this
for this group of this set
here is to show that the whole group
the group's itself
they are
the abstract things
this is one
one way that the group may appear
it's true you know
in takers
a number model and
you know its motherland because when you multiply one this last element here you get
this one
this cycle
this is the same group
represented differently
here you have the roots of the unity the
roots of the unity
and the multiplication is complex multiplication
so the core sets here
if you take this
white said here as
the subgroup h
the core sets
you get is
multiplied this
so group by one gen generate generic element of the
and you get for example the green one
you multiply again get the red
if you multiply again you go back to each
so you have done
in this case you have the three cassette as well
and it's the same thing abstractly the same thing about how you you implement the
multiplication of the action of the group was different
what defines the a group abstractly it it's stable occasionally fly to be get c
that's more that's
it doesn't matter if a certain number of symmetric polynomials
and it doesn't matter how you do the multiplication can represent the action of the
group elements
as much tricks multiplication as the differential operator
there are you know many ways to
do these things
it is open
only the group itself the abstract thing that's important in terms of
of the the more fundamental properties of the graph
OK so this division the result of this division here
i wrote
this single gene of
eight zero
the result of this is
number of course sets
so this is the generalisation of the
so you get three courses
but this case is when the subgroup is normal
this article is not normal
you get
the division you get
you get and i'm watching this page
and i went into space is just avoiding space which every point looks like
you know the sphere and pointed shoes has the same in the same vicinity you
differentiate among them
it's boring because nothing happens that not the whole there there's you know it's just
small just like the whole space the euclidean space not any point it's if
you know
everywhere if you were there you if you don't have any references you cannot know
where you are
so these are
our example from would that's why it's called the more genius
the the collection of all cosets which
another another way to see them
they can be used to as it as an active equivalence classes can be because
it is the same thing but you can you can relate to them for many
and this is one way to see the course is for example given a set
i'm using this set this line here the set x
and relations
of this this is the definition of equivalent class right now given a set x
and our relation with the single year for relations seem to other
the equivalent class is a class of an element of x
is given by the
equivalent class of x it's all
belongs to
x and y have this relation to find is an abstract definition
and here's an example
free energy throughout the hierarchy
but the coupling but the world is absolutely very very important and and that's basically
what i description here to the oculomotor reflex arc
but you can profoundly change or imports
just by moving they are moving what you sample so prediction errors
in certain privileged parts of of the of the brain
namely those that actually control the deployment of your sensory something organs
this sensory receptors sensory epithelia
they can they can minimize prediction error in one of two ways they can either try to
these predictions or they can just go and change the sensory data
so this is absolutely crucial in understanding these actionperception duality here's perception is certainly caused by
what is sampled to actually sets on the which forms the basis of the prediction
because you're actually something what you're predicting so there's actually
a self-fulfilling prophecy about the way these systems behave but show you an example of the term
they show the hierarchical
if i don't do that now the the next in the next example
so the conclusion is that the sort of the first the first
as theoretical overview
what we said what i said is biological systems agents resist the second law
well strictly there's is the fluctuation theorem because we're not talking about equilibrium systems
they must minimize their average surprise all although surprisingly entropy
and they can minimize surprise by suppressing prediction error will formally free energy
well prediction error can be reduced by changing predictions that perception
or it can be reduced by changing sensations namely action
perception entails recurrent message passing in the brain to optimise predictions while action makes its predictions come true
and thereby minimizes surprise
so in the time that i have left i just try and give u
the sort of
an example from from sort action and perception and the perception and action and then
finally turned to the key question is how and why do we explore what research
had we build models and optimizes models
the first example is meant to illustrate this sort of
just a simple
use of
dynamical models as generative models that environment hand
perception as categorisation recovering the underlying causes
and what i've done here is just
consider the problem of categorizing
the bird might have in categorizing a song emitted upwards which permitted by conspecific about that
i'm trying to categorize it in the same way that we might try to categorize
a word or or the meaning of a sentence
so i have to generate data and then i have to specify
birds generative model
and then run the
predictive coding scheme
in order to see whether i can recover the underlying causes of
the sensory input
do that
just basically boring to state lorenz attractor here
to modulate the frequency and the amplitude is some synthetic ship the bird might make
in terms of the hidden causes i'm gonna change
we control parameters that the ants attracted to change the flow
the change the tempo and the amplitude of the actual chips cells so that i can actually
think of these two control parameters
that are basically coefficients of these in these equations emotional attractor as defining
eight nature
eight song in a two-dimensional perceptual space
and the job of the burden i was trying not from the sort of continuous time-dependent import
which is just an opportune frequency
back to
you've time-invariant central
categorizations are going from fast time scale to a slow timescale so gently model goes from some time invariant
category just some fast dynamics and the main versions taking first dynamics mapping back
seven slow categorisation