last lecture my throat is about so i
and just a little bit tired so let's see how we get on
so let's just re cup we started off with
trying to define a linear models
and look at ways of identifying these linear models
arbitrary functions and then yesterday we looked at using again a linear model to define
a function which was basically the log odds ratio
i mean we looked at how logistics regression
and we started off with what appeared to be an arbitrary loss function are an
i mean squared error
and that led to
least squares solution
and we then moved on to look at the likelihood framework can be lifted probabilistic
representation of these linear models
and then we could start to characterize are levels of certainty or uncertainty
in our estimates of the parameters
and our levels of certainty and uncertainty in subsequent productions that we were making
and then moved on to adopt a bayesian framework
and we were able to see that
again for linear model linear regression model
posterior distribution over the parameters that came out and they closed form
and likewise with the predictive distributions
they all came out in the very nice closed form but when we were attacked
logistic regression when trying to do classification
over two classes then we had a problem
and that the
marginalisation they required to do was no longer analytic
and we therefore had to resort to
numerical methods such as monte carlo markov chain monte carlo or
use some sort of approximations
the approximation that we were tired
i was using
a lot plus approximation where we would find the
the point in parameter space which was most likely a posterior on a and b
then place the goes in at that point and the covariance about ghosts in adopted
the carpet shark
of the joint likelihood surface
and we played with that yesterday in the lab we don't clue today in love
but yesterday in the laboratory we looked at
function approximation
using camera functions
OK so we're doing probabilistic candle based regression
in essence
if you remember
we are trying to model some function
over attributes x
the linear form that we been adopting
is a linear expansion
some basis functions
applied to
what we used yesterday
and florence was was getting are very a
description of what is happening with this
cannot function
which we used
which was the
additionally myself
which is the radial basis
can not
what you found
and what we did in the laboratory was that
if you remember we place the priors
all in all of our
this is the coefficients of the basis functions
and so we had
the prior variance too to think about
and then in addition to that
we introduced this additional
it's associated with the the camera function or the basis said that we were using
and what we found
and some of you produce some really beautiful surfaces showing that the predictive performance as
a function of values of alpha and beta
what's that
we know that the
prior variance
give us a way of controlling the capacity of the complexity of the model by
shrinking some of these here
OK so in essence we would be using a reduced set to a small number
of basis functions to describe the function that we are trying to model
but then we also saw that we had this
this is because the parameters in the define the basis set and if we made
that quite wide and then we found that the class of functions that we were
able to
to devise was very smooth
and likewise if made this value very small then we found that they were very
expressive highly nonlinear
a set of functions that we can define so if you remember we were trying
to model the set the same function
and depending on the values of alpha and beta we could have
i representations which was either
overly smoothed
on one which was
but nick the excitable sort of
OK so
we we eventually had to use things like leave one out cross validation to identify
with these alpha and beta parameters where
but of course
for those of you who want to adopt a bayesian framework
you know that really all that you want to do is just
a team
this distribution
and then average over all possible offers and all possible betas
but this of course is not straightforward
well that's great we can model really quite arbitrarily complex functions
and today in the laboratory will be working with logistic regression and we'll be looking
what you do is you go you try to show to ask a database events
about two if
will then so is these artists performing where in one
and you have information and then move to the next one is performing when OK
so this is what we want to the application to do
given the music style we wanted to explore the web and get events out
if i do it manually
what i do is going to things like music mods
which is something like this
it's nice what publications
basically it stores information about the movie sense
you can always do something like these so you will hear you say
i interesting for music
the band announced this
as you can see there are many so you have lots of these
we to enter
the a b
OK you got to you before
artists that performs folk music
under b and the mean of others and that letters OK
if you like one of these
whether this guy is OK you can move here and you have information about it
in and if you like you can also see
support it in a different archive like musicbrainz
there should be somewhere you a link to musicbrainz
i don't know if
what they did the which is very cool
is a sharing their identifiers
so these two websites are really sharing the identifier of the artists so you can
move from one database to another using the same identifier actually what what was done
was musicmoz
using the musicbrainz identifier
integrating with the music style is the information so you have the description and you
might learn about good now what would you do that
here so you have all the information of all these people from are you choose
one because it's too difficult to exploit it for me
you go on database like upcomming or event the database
and there you ask for these artists to
what you do is basically you go here
you have another very web two o style interface that allows you to query for
then you can
just right here somebody
and you go with
all the event actually
i guess
you should go here
so you have all the events OK
so the next step is of course
look through
find one
let's say in germany
maybe somebody somewhere close to hear and understand where wearing and say i can i
go there are not so in the last step is really to use google maps
or any other maps application and to find a path to the final point so
i put in the slides these are two
this is a music model
catalogue of their
of this style
and then he you have page
the next video detail about
the events of one of these performance and here i was looking in june four
in event close to my house i live in italy actually live the north so
i support these events here which is in the government
so i mean i look up in a google map cell fires it from my
home so it's one hour in something which is not true because these traffic but
this is different
right so
what we want really is a mashup
and measure like you've seen before web two o technologies
and we want it done using semantic web technology and of course we also want
to show that this this war so is f send doesn't bring some more computational
problems seen and is also way to solve the problem
which is just different from web two o technology but still a good way to
solve the problem OK so the rest of the to is about our using semantic
web technology to solve this problem
so going back to evan hammonds lights which are
introduction to the topic
what we have here is the standard semantic problem we have data available
they are available for machine because actually all the series but i i d showing
also at the machine interface musicmoz
gives you a dump of the data in XML you can
downloads them and whatever you like with musicbrainz you've done for the databases in and
was four months so you can
lot them in a positive that obeys and put all the layers on top until
you have the data out in their semantic web way
and the events that obeys at rest API so you can put to rest request
on on a
browser there
and what i got out of the response in XML
OK so the first point is data are out there and it's available so this
is fine now the the problem is we want to combine and and what we
found that web scale and the problem but i'm sure it's almost at web scale
i mean it's about three different website
but still in his website that outside our control we can not really
change OK they are outside then we have to cope with venezuela and so
what we're going to do is this we bring in these data
and try to collaborate so
most of the examples that were done in the early days of semantic web we
always thought could about meta data so we have a page and make description of
any major limited description
so is a couple of years these idea web of data came which is more
moving exactly in the direction of sharing data and not the data about fifty to
not make it but in many in any case i believe that what i'm showing
works also for metadata is not that
water seems like it could react with water
and your reaction
this up here
so if you had water acting as an acid in water acting as the base
you could be forming a conjugate acid thrown in my own and also the conjugate
base hydroxide
so this raises the question then
if you have a glass of water
how much h two o
are you going to happen that glass of water
and how much i hate roney and iron and how much hydroxide ion
it would be
in in water
so we can consider that
how much water is and what
OK so so here's our equation again
and what we're really asking
is what is k
so for at equilibrium conditions
we want to know
how do the ratios ratio of products
two reactor
so how much of these ionized species do you have how much product
over the liquid water
that's OK
so how do we figure this out how do we find how do we find
for this particular reaction
well here's some of our are all familiar ways of relating
terms rather involving k
so we have delta g not because minus are t times the natural log of
so if we know
delta g not then we can find k
at a particular temperature
knowing the gas constant
so we can rearrange this expression here
two all for k
in terms of delta g not
and we're going to do this at room temperature
and this reminder that the gas constant
so first we need
delta g not
so there's a couple of different ways one can calculate delta g
and you might want to just sort of thinking ahead per minute what are those
because that's an important useful thing to know on wednesday
so this is one of the possible ways if you know something
about the delta g not of formation of products minus reacted
what is the other equation that you might use to find
delta g
i heard it
so this one that one should look familiar to you as well
this will be on on wednesdays or this is material on wednesdays example i've seen
example that's certainly something you should to look familiar to you for for that exam
and it also shows the connection between the material that was covered on exam two
and material that we're doing now
so everything they
learning for example two
it will be useful in the future
all right so just calculate this one way
so all i have done the math out here for you
so if we look up all of these values
and we plug them in
we find that this delta g nine
it is plausible
seventy nine point eight nine killer tools per mole
so it's fairly large positive numbers
so if we have a fairly large positive number for delta g nine
what do we predict about the size
they're going to be a big number small numbers
it'll be a small number
and so
you could actually calculate that from this equation or just sort of remember the relationship
if you're just ask qualitatively if it should be large
four small
we can actually go through
and calculate what they would be
at room temperature
and the answer is one point zero times ten to the minus fourteen at room
temperature and this number of you'll see a lot in
the next
for quite a quite well next on so many many lectures that will become
a familiar number two you
all right so that means this is a fairly small number
so that means that
most of the water is actually aged two
a very small percentage of water is ionized at room temperature so there isn't that
much in terms of hydro near minus hydroxide ions
in your water
a small percentage of the water molecules are ionized sorin in this charge four
so not much of this at equilibrium
compared to this
lots of water in a glass of water
all right so this the equilibrium constant has a special name which is why it's
going to become very familiar to us as lectures go on
and this name is kate w
w for water
so the equilibrium constant for water
and pretty much all of the at the base
the things that we will be doing or room temperature to make your life easier
so that's why don't you come particularly familiar
right so w
can be expressed in terms of the concentration
of hydrogen ions
times hydroxide
and i just wanted to
make appointing you we talked a little about this more perhaps
we're not including this autumn term so
we don't have the water down here
it's just equal to
these two not over
the other two water molecules in liquid and that's because if you have the material
that's nearly pure
you don't include in your equilibrium expressions so if it's something solvent the concentration
water is the solvent is just not changing very much
this is where
this is not
OK it's hard to see
OK so
you which you would choose the bandwidth in this case as follows
you would go
so i mean what you want is that basically you're
he lost
the expected value of loss is well approximated
so you need to make a certain smoothness assumption on loss induced function class
and so it's a good idea to choose
a similar
kernel width
for getting the weights as it what you will be choosing afterwards we estimator
so in other words if you choose the kernel of with five
for regression and classification afterwards
it's probably a good idea to pick something like that
for getting the weights right
just because a lot of function class often is rather similar to
the original function class
in terms of scale
i mean that's precisely what we did
now doing cross validation here
these are not always easy i mean what you would have to but what you
do is i mean you have to take a subset of
i think doing proper model selection with cross for cross validation or you can do
it anymore
that's really hard
but at least you can still use cross validation to assess the performance and then
you would just take subsets and then
check the performance on the test set
what's it
well i would
go and take it as the
the medium
pairwise distances
that that will be the quantity
i mean it actually turns out that you can define an interesting band space by
optimizing the the the bandwidth of the kernel itself
at the moment we are working on this and
it might be possible to get slightly better sources in this way directly
but we don't completely understand the problem yet
i can show you some notes and then afterwards
any question
it is
how to use
OK well
this is what you do is you just replace those expectations by currently averages
so that means if you
i don't have too much data
this is about the for loop so it could at a time
OK now there's a simple way how you can get something that's almost as good
as this in linear time
so basically what you do is you just essentially block pairs
of well
well block two pairs of variables together and just average of that
you can interpolate between those two
you will get similar
statement i mean that is actually for the asymptotic normality you just need a lot
lot large numbers
so it's
bit easier
and we've actually written this up the the problem is
you really have a rather severe trade of
computational complexity versus quality of it taste
there people
we do
they they don't have to subsample it's just double full of you trust
this so for instance i mean for this i mean you're just pick some
x i y i
and then i will take
the average overall
xj y j
not being
x i y i and take the average
and then you just where this
and what this requires that you can compute
once and for all
well actually what you do is you just square this out directly and then you
can dig to both things in the same falling
so i can show you the pseudocode for that in our paper
any further questions
OK how much time do actually have left half an hour
fifteen minutes
while OK good
will be OK
we just give some parts
now this is we're trying to work with arthur gretton
le song
but it took off and olivier bousquet contribute to the sum of their parts
so what we've been doing so far was looked at
min operators
and now we're going to look at the covariance operator
we're going to use the very same tools that we use the the mean operator
for covariance operator
now why would that be interesting
because you can do
independent component analysis with it
you can do feature selection
and for independent component analysis you want the covariance operator between two sets of
right to vanish
for feature selection
you want the current operator very large
we use the same criteria
this gives you the best i see i was in this gives you the best
features of later
problem is welcome some set of observations x and y has now
and you want to find out whether distribution factorizes
and more specifically what to have some
measure of dependence
you can use it for ICA
you could differences
this estimate
then check whether this factorizes we can just go for it directly
and in that of doing the latter is
it work much better
he is very very simple
linear case in all we do is we just make that non-linear
so we take some linear function say
and what i get
is this
so i've done a legitimate
s primal simplex
on the primal problem and improve my objective function from zero to three has
i did corresponding pivot on the dual
which was not motivated by anything other than being
analogous to what i was doing the primal and look what the beautiful thing that just happened here
i still have the negative transpose property
minus three has minus three force minus three s three has three reversed through force
every role here is the negative rhetoric corresponding column here
the negative transpose property
is preserved
doing he analogous pivots
this is a very important fact
and even on not running down a proof
trivial proof
just have a look at those few lines by matlab code understand exactly what's happening
in the pivot and show that you have this property so we do the second
period here
obsession said this we the second that so x three lander
o after a few iterations here this is three going three going around one
and i so w one must be believing variable i guess i said that down here
so what
the nine force as they number that a key
so i look for the ninety fourth the negative nine force down here so i click on this button
and click on the button and i compare are and the prison and i still have the negative transpose property
so now this dictionary here
is optimal
i've solved the problem
i also solve the dual problem
so by clearing all the purple entries here
and the primal
i've managed a clear all the purple entries here
on the dole
so i've solve the dual problem
so we apply the simplex methods in the primal problem
which i just to illustrate in this particular example
and we can do both the two phases with that's not very well we can
do the whole thing we can apply the primal we apply the simplex methods
to the primal problem in two phases if you can sort of feasible
and do the analogous pivots on the dual side
we are done
you'll have some both the primal
in the dual problem
both the primal and the dual problem
and furthermore you have this negative transpose property so that if i o five thirds
here i have minus five thirty here
but don't forget all but i should point out this minus five third is ignoring one important thing
it's ignoring the minus sign right there
so the actual dual has this extra minus sign that might pivotal doesn't show
i suppose power
next year
probably put a minus sign right there are
so that
the pivot tool shows that the dual is the minus
so anyway we all we have this negative transpose properties or whatever they are negative
would be fair but this is the negative of the dual objective
so what does this tell us
o and get to that later i forgot my order here
think about what that tells you
we'll get back to work
so this suggests another
simplex methods
the dual
the dual simplex method is exactly what i just illustrated here
we are doing this on a problem that had purple
only here and not there
and we ended up going
and finding an optimal solution
to this problem
so what are primal problem had
purple only here
end no purple affair
in my mind i could think about the dual that's
think about applying the simplex methods to it
that's what we want to do here
so the dual simplex methods as
applies when the dual problem is feasible
then the wavelength follows immediately
so you see here are a few examples that i've calculated for you
if you start out with a
low frequency of thousand hertz you get the wavelength
of three hundred kilometres
radio waves
megahertz still
talk about radio waves when you go up in frequency
wavelengths of course gets shorter and shorter
we call these
if you go to ten
fourteen to two to fifteen words
you get into the domain of infrared
visible light and ultraviolet
and if you go even higher
then you end up with x-rays and ultimately all of these are members of the
electromagnetic waves this a with a non-zero there stands for angstroms
that means ten to the minus ten years
so the whole family of electromagnetic waves
and we give the name so that
we can talk about them
without ever mentioning the specific frequency already what wavelengths
so given the fact that
electromagnetic waves and travel
with three hundred thousand kilometres per second
one food
you take one nano-second
twenty six one hundred thirty metres deep
the light
from me to professor pathology all the way at the end
it would take about o point one microsecond
one second
radio waves to the all
eight minutes takes the light from the sun
to reach us
the light from the nearest stars will take five years
and the nearest large galaxy studios
we take two million years for that light
richard so when you look at that galaxy
and you see the galaxy the way it was two million years ago
in astronomy we
users are
a light here which is the distance that light travels
in one year which is about ten to sixteen meters
if you study galaxy which is at a distance of ten billion light years
you're looking at the universe
the way it was ten
years ago
in astronomy
you can look back
yes you can look back millions of years
you can also look back in time
billions of years
forms of electromagnetic radiation certainly light and radio waves from radar
can reflect off surfaces at least to some degree it depends on the surface
and this is the basis behind the distance determination
you send a reader pulse
two an airplane or two were rainstorm some of the radiation comes back at you
you know the speed
and so that allows you to calculate
the distance
if the distance
to the plane is the
you send a brief pulse
and it comes back
quality echo
it takes a certain amount of time to come back which you can measure
and that
signal has to travel twice the distance
that is the speed of light
times t this is what you measure
the distance in
time from the moment you send the signal to you
get the reflection back and so you can calculate the distance
the distance
two demos can be measured this way
five corner reflectors
on the moon three were left by the americans into
so we're left by the soviets they said was still the soviet union
and optical telescopes from earth
can send a very brief
laser pulse
police corner reflectors
all the time
length of time of these polls is only one quarter
over nano-second
imagine light only travels
seven centimetres in one quarter
of a nine seconds
because of the
the that are
that's all
and i want to throw it
in fact
the are called
the fact that are
what you
but in fact
of course one
OK call
so that
the best
the one
we are talking about the
but that
that's the one
one of the
we are now
i don't want my account for
the following content is provided under creative commons license
your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
this MIT opencourseware
OCW MIT
that u
thermodynamics alright let's start
the more dynamic
the flow of heat
for more
dynamics of emotion
thermodynamics was developed
beginning in the eighteen hundreds
at the time of the industrial revolution
the taming of this of steel
the beginning of
power by burning fossil fuels
the beginning of the problems with
sio two
global warming in fact
it's interesting to note that the first articulation
the impact of sio two
on climate
it was done in the late nineteen hundreds by reading
beginning of the
generation of power moving it for
fossil fuel generating energy
o locomotives etcetera
three calculated what happen
burning of fossil fuels and
he decided in has speculation basically got the calculation right
he came out in two thousand years from the time to do the calculations humans
would be in trouble
well since cystatin mission we had an exponential growth in the amount of CO two
and if you go through calculations of people have done this populations through
since arrhenius
the time they were in trouble two thousand years and the population
has gone like our
now really in trouble
so four different lecture
so anyway thermodynamics dates from the same period
as as well as getting fossil fuels out of the ground
it's universal
turns out
everything around us energy around one or the other for biological system you're burning calories
bring eighty two
there are warm-blooded animals need energy to move your arms around move around
mechanical systems obviously cars built
even in astrophysics when you talk about stars black holes that you're moving energy around
you moving around
new changing matter through
and the concepts of thermodynamics have even been applied to
systems out of equilibrium like
the companies like enron
completely out of equilibrium
crash and burn
the more dynamic or nonequilibrium thermodynamics two
two economics
it was developed before people knew about
atoms and molecules so to science based on macroscopic properties of matter
since the
since we know about and molecules now
we can rationalize the concepts of thermodynamics
using microscopic
and if you are
five sixty two that's what you want about learn about statistical mechanics and how the
mister concepts
what makes it doesn't prove it
but it helps to gain more intuition about
the consequences of thermodynamics
so it applies to macroscopic systems that are in equilibrium
how to go from one equilibrium state
one of the sequences
and it's entirely empirical science foundation
people have done experiments three ages and the accumulated the knowledge from these experiments
it synthesizes experiments were a few
empirical rules empirical laws
which other laws of thermodynamics
and then they taking these laws added a
structure math upon it
to build the edifice which is
very solid
because of the dynamics is the science
equilibrium systems
so these empirical observations and
summarizing for law
OK so
these laws are
really deep colours
not proven
not wrong there are very unlikely to be wrong
let's just go through these laws
very quickly is the zeroth law
the zeroth law
every one of these laws basically defines the quantity of thermodynamics and then define the
the zeroth law defines temperature
that's fairly
common sense
but it's important to define
and i call that the common sense law
this is the common sense
the first lord
hands up defining energy
what we're going to call you
the concept of energy conservation energy can be lost or gained
and i'm going to call this you can read
and the brain
they don't lose energy
and then
the second law
is going to define entropy
and it's going to tell us about the direction of time something that conceptually
fairly understand
it is going to put a mathematical foundation on
which way this time
clearly if i
chocolate this one here
four on the ground in britain the pieces
if i run the movie backwards
it doesn't make sense right we have a concept of time going forward in a
particular way
that is and should be play into that concept
and i'm going to call this the
you can break
zero degrees kelvin more
can only do it is zero risk
the third law
is going to give a numerical value
two billion entropy
the third law is gonna be the depressing one
the high energy phosphate from ATP ATP and transfers it
two tyrosine amino acids
that are present on substrates
so here's an amino acid sequence
in the single
letter code and if we admit that why is that is the code for piracy
if is the protein that functions as the substrate
tyrosine kind is a terracing kind eyes will add a phosphate group
to the side chains of the terracing which i'm not crying here but had terracing
has a hydroxyl group on its side chain and therefore it will phosphorylates tyrosine
that is to say at phosphate groups to it
it will phosphorylates this c
so these two rectangles here are fat tire seen kind aces and what happens after
the two subunits of the receptor have been brought together is thereafter what one finds
each of these receptor subunits becomes multiple phosphorylated
in each of these lollipops indicating here are sites where there is a tyrosine residue
has become phosphorylated
in fact there's a tale of the pdf receptor that extends even further to the
cytoplasm which also acquires a number of different phosphates on it
and again i remind us this phosphoryl ation really is what often called coltrane's phosphorylation
because each receptor molecule
phosphorylates tyrosine residues on the other
obviously when these two receptor molecules are far apart in the plane of plasma membrane
this trends phosphorylation can not occur but once the two tyrosine kind is residence at
the time wanted to terracing kind is have been brought together
pulled together by the dimerisation of the receptor now this cross phosphoryl ation one each
phosphorylated other can occur
and soon the receptors are more highly phosphorylated all these phosphate groups
to repeat myself being attached to tyrosine residues in their cytoplasmic domains
and this in turn creates interesting docking sites for a variety of other cytoplasmic signalling
proteins and we'll talk about some today and next time but what i want to
leave you with is the following impression that after this phosphoryl ation actually occurs there
are a number of of molecules in the cytoplasm signaling molecules that have affinity for
when i say phosphotyrosine obviously i'm referring to the
phosphorylated form of tyres
it's been created by a higher sekine kind is an enzyme
so here's one molecule that can bind
this molecule a combined one of these phosphates another one combined to this phosphate
and each of these molecules once they are attracted to this phosphorylated receptor can then
emit downstream signals
so the the variety of signals into the cell
but ultimately end up in persuading the cell to proliferate
and so
these effects year of growth factors in the g one phase of the cell cycle
are mediated by this transmembrane signaling
by the activation of these of this receptor for example and by the resulting
the release of downstream signals into the cell
which persuaded the cell to proliferate or not to proliferate
to be sure
the c one platelets clot platelet aggregation and they released ptgs they also release other
kinds of growth factors inference there's is another growth factor that's called IGF one insulin
like growth factor and that has its own receptor on the surface of cells and
there are on the cell hundreds to thousands of these pgf receptors
they're IGF receptors their EGF receptors
a cell often will require several distinct kinds of growth factor activations in order to
so this is only a minor part of the entire exposure the cell experiences in
the g one phase of the cell cycle
to elaborate on the point that i made last time
an important biological distinction between normal cells and cancer cells is the fact that cancer
cells require relatively little growth factors in the medium in order to proliferate
normal cells have very strong requirement for growth factors in the media and therefore what
we can already imagine is the following kind of scenario
the cancer cells have somehow
deregulated this signaling pathway
somehow they become independent
all the stimulation that is normally required usually required for cells to proliferate
and in fact we know of several different ways
by which cancer cells can acquire this independence
one of the most important ways it's it's and really interesting on here's a cancer
which we'll talk about very shortly and what you find in certain kinds of cancer
is it the cancer cells
themselves release growth factors in the media
so there are certain kinds of cancer cells that will release
let's say a growth factor this like EGF into the medium around around them so
well you say that's kind of amusing but so what
the important part here
is it the same cancer cells
receptors for TG four EGF
on the surface they producing growth factor and they can also respond to the same
growth factor and therefore this EGF once it's released
can swim over here
activate receptor
and persuade the cell to start proliferating
this is
in if you will positive feedback loop but no here importantly that the growth of
the cell is not being controlled by growth factors coming from cells elsewhere in the
tissue of the body
here we're not talking about different cells talking to one another here we're talking about
a monologue where this cell is talking to itself this is sometimes called on to
try and save and refers to the fact
certain kinds of cancer cells are able to make growth factors to which they can
in fact in normal tissues
it's rare
for a single cell type in normal tissue
to be able to make a growth factor
and two recent be able to respond to the same growth factor why can normally
not respond to the growth factor because it will make the receptor for the growth
for example
epithelial cells like the cells in your skin the cells lining the gut
they can release pdg f
but they don't have pdf receptor on the surface and therefore even though they release
copious amounts of PDF that will not result in this order the military proliferation and
therefore you don't have this d control cell proliferation that you see often in cancer
cells this awful crime loop
in many kinds of cancer cells you have another alteration of this growth factor signaling
and here what we see is the following
they followed synonym antonym links
and then they judge the opinions strength
with respect to
the reference set
so they follow the links but then they had this other so that they could
use to say well how close to to judge how good it is so they
don't just indiscriminately follow links they have a leash on that
two to four there and then they expanded further with the naive bayes classifier
too much information can have e
yes o
another thing that they did
i still think this is a good idea we started doing this
i guess
in two thousand one or something and i mean
different people use to wear
it's going to be noisy but
editorials for example
are more likely to have are more likely to be associated with subjectivity than for
example hard news and the wall street journal and other documents come with without metadata
so that if you go to the treebank it has many different reviews letters to
the editor
news and so on and so you can score word and say
if the word occurs more often
then you'd expect from chance in reviews
then in use then that could be evidence that its objective
so that it's it's kind of noisy we found we so we found boost the
performance from doing that but it some information and the good thing is that you
have lots of things out there that are labeled as reviews and letters that editor
other categories
anyway so they used they use that to build up
a lexicon for their purpose
and then they combine those and they also combine them together with
hatzivassiloglou and q and attitudes and then they use that to classify sentences as objective
or subjective
OK so it's still in service the army
this is their first paper on this
i believe and they use scene sets
they want to find the semantic orientation of turns and there they were the first
ones to do class classification to use the gloss of the wordnet sense is to
so you see sets and they start with positive and negative seeds sets and then
they follow
the pads the lexical relations that are in wordnet like synonymy
so for example
going from brilliant to brainy to intelligent smart
this is me brilliant following antonym linked to unintelligent and then you can get stupid
brainless and all that
and then extended the sets iteratively
they use the final sets the gold standard to train the classifier
and then as long as
as long as
and then she has sentiment words then you can use the classifier to train
then they moved on
and in two thousand six they had a couple papers they use the best systems
of the two thousand five paper
and they had we thought this is interesting because they had the additional goal of
distinguishing mutual from positive negative in our terminology finding subjective versus objective and then breaking
down the subjective into positive and negative and they found they found that the subjective
objective parties harder this several groups actually who report back in in different levels of
analysis that doing the subjective objective phase
is hard
and it's important and if you can do that can make your life easier in
then subsequently annotating things as positive and negative
i think there's also they have later we're too there's a new paper from two
thousand seven with a they moved on to a new approach
this is the key at all application in semi supervised learning to evaluate expression classifiers
now she learning can actually do more for and the best way to think about
this is just learning discriminative features what features actually carry more information
so let's look at that
so i'm trying to find some categories here so this is a panda bear this
is the
rules what that is more informative
and the goal of the algorithm would be to not with all the features equally
but wait
the radio indicates there's a matlab kind of a sort of visualization thing that more
important feature blue means less important feature
so what we're going to do is illustrated here
going to try
to find these distance functions
but the distance function will be
will be learned
and the goal is is to tweak the distance function such that the distance is
within one category
you know from airplanes to airplanes are small
but from airplanes to giraffes large
so we'll take the machine learning paradigm between june the distance function
so how do we do that so simple setting this up this is an image
i the images jnk we know that
the distance i i and j are in the same category and get into different
categories so my goal is to make the subject
greater than the subject
and note that we have tried we'll always have to work in this paradigm that
an image or any object can never be characterized by using a fixed link
parts of images can be
but they made it to the one image may have
and it featured entertainment and seventy features
we always have to work with that problem
so then this is kind of more of the details
so we have various features and for each feature will try to find the best
matching feature another view
and so on using big d
that's fall distance function but that distance function is made up of weights
and elementary distance function which facing features
and so we have
so we have a whole bunch of features here and then we had the distances
of each of those features by some the little these
and here is another image and then the distance of the idea
for each other
and so these features are all
focused on the distances and in the the future image i
so that defines the dimensionality of the space
is that which i equal because there are defined with respect to the local image
and now
what we want to do is to make sure that the key
which is a different category is
and the larger distance than
same category
the distance between images and so essentially this becomes the question the weights
dot product should be larger than these
i can see the difference vector this guy must be greater than zero
so far so good
and now we just throwing the usual SVM mumbo-jumbo
so we want to get this guy greater than zero but we want to have
some regularisation so
i apologise for that
leaving behind through this thing so this turns out to be
it's really i can do
some mediation on that the u
you get a minimisation problem with their weight vector and then this is kind of
the penalty term
we want to not too many of these guys
the machine he goes through OK
so let's see the results of this so what this enables us to do is
i learned distance function
when you put more weight on list weights
on features which are more distinct they are less distinct they were category that's what
you learn then
so here is the talented dataset which
it was developed about
you know for so that some four years ago
and when it does it came out in two thousand four
people thought that this is this is horribly challenging problems
because that recall that in two thousand three or two thousand four the problem that
we thought we solve was digits
i mean i could be also solve the problem of face detection
that's where we went out
we could do it you could do faces and all this group of
their own opinions on what they did was they collected images of hundred different categories
the web
so these are images of pianos and media's anime then
i think this stop so the pianos
a sort of a flower
the cell phones etc cetera so that quite natural categories for each category they collected
maybe fifty or sixty examples
by doing so search based on text queries and then having a graduate student go
ah so we'll see what else you go that i will however short i will
not answer the world email
right i will answer emails from the class
but i will not answer and i i think i speak for the asia TI
is neither will answer the world email on how we're going to keep the world
out of our inboxes i'm unsure exactly where this going to be a problem or
not at any rate that's what's happening
all right any questions about any questions about the mechanics of the course or what
your expectations should be what my expectations of you are
right now i would like to take an informal poll
actually when we started this class of the number of times now and it's always
been a mixed crowd and i think that's one of things that track about this
class let me ask with these in this class or lecture engineering undergraduate graduate
are so it's pretty strong show of hands but let me also as for the
non he's in this class
i that's also pretty strong show of hands these are as is typical the majority
of the students in the class but there's also a pretty strong group of students
in this class who are not allowed to engineers by training by desire by anything
are and they usually come from all over the place i was looking at the
web was one of the classes before the classification people from chemistry to something from
chemist there's somebody on the back there are i and others and people from earth
somebody from somebody was talking actually for science this morning before science OK
well so i think it was an amicable and these may be
all right now
it's important to know
i think the cause is very rich in material alright region applications rich in content
and appeals
many people from many different reasons OK
for these and they were taking the class you have probably seen
a certain amount of this material i want to say most of the material that
you probably seen a fair amount of this material scattered over many different classes
but it's been my experience that one of the advantages of this class for electrical
engineering students either undergraduate or graduate students is to see it all in one
right to put it all in your head at one time at least once right
because the subject does have a great amount of coherence it really does hang together
beautifully for all the different and varied applications there are core ideas and core methods
of the class that it is very helpful to see all ones are so if
you've seen the material before
that's fine i mean is i mean that you can you can draw on that
and draw in your experience but don't deny yourself the pleasure
trying to synthesize the ideas as we go along and there's nothing so pleasurable was
thinking about something you already know
try to think about from a new perspective think about it from a new point
of view trying to try to folded into some of the newer things you you'll
be learning so i've i've heard this from electrical engineering students many times in the
past that it's it's a pleasure for them to see the material altogether once it
may seem like a fair amount of review in in some cases it will be
but not in all cases and even if it is a review there are often
slightly different twists are slightly new takes on things that you may not have seen
before may not have thought of quite in quite that way so so so that
is my advice to the to engineering students for the students who
i have not seen this material before the other coming out from different fields
and maybe only heard you know
secret tales of the fourier transform and its use is well i hope you enjoy
the ride because it's gonna be alright or right
as we go along all right now
for every one i sort of feel like at the issue and call this of
warning or just sort of statement of principle or whatever this is a very mathematical
this is one of the sort of holy trinity of classes in the information systems
lab electrical engineering molecular genetics very broad department is split up into a number laboratories
or research lines i am in information systems lab which is sort of the mathematical
part of the subject of signal processing coding theory imaging and so on and this
has been for a number of years taught by faculty sort of thought of as
a cornerstone in the signal processing although has a lot of different applications a lot
of different areas the other courses in the holy trinity or two sixty three dynamical
linear dynamical systems and two seventy eight statistical signal processing centers is actually master so
because is also very common thing sixty three
the class also a strong majority anything to seventy eight
OK so there's available little if you have a little bit less but still number
of people
OK maybe
we start right on time and i have a tight schedule today because my flight
back to munich is
tonight today
eight PM
i am sorry with a little bit so welcome to the auditorium outlier detection techniques
my name is a clue that
i present this chart for you on behalf of has been my boss and
in order to make it was also around here
but she is involved in workshop this afternoon so that he will stay
the other day so if you have any questions come to your mind afterwards not
today than just
i hope you
i will show up
these shortly
the coffee break so
you see his face
talk to him
i don't have what so
someone has to watch clock because i think it three we should make all right
maybe one of you could
of course i have an eye on this
OK so some generations before we start please feel free to
ask any questions at any time i want to
little bit casual so you can
you can discuss issues here if you have questions just
interrupt me
and the general aim of this tutorial is you to get
more or less the big picture of the detection which is brought
area of research so
cover all
details all methods of islands here but we try to give you a kind of
big picture of works
and the big picture is not in terms of
listing some methods and algorithms
you will get a list of methods and algorithms
the main point here is in terms of getting the picture in terms of basic
approaches to modeling
the approaches followed by detection
and as i said some some will also be provided
but so
this selection is quite arbitrary so if you favourite algorithm is not on the list
please don't
and well usually these slides should be
made available for the KDD website but i heard about some problem so i just
visit our website maybe a skip to the first page here
the website
for these systems is to define the semantics the
and then you will see
so we're pages
the later slides hopefully at the end of this week or
being an expert
so let's start
just navigate to up two of my personal website you will find personal website on
this on the side
and then
four artists to homepage and then
i will try to make it
very clearly
OK so let's start with a short discussion on what is an outlier what's what's
all about you
and mostly any paper that these about section
the site the definition of hawkins
most simply says that out there is an observation which deviates so much from the
other observations as to arouse suspicions
that it was generated by
a different mechanism so hawkins statistics
so we had
in statistics based traditional on this
task and
if we take a closer look on this
this definition we see that he or
colleagues also assume that the normal data
not the outliers usually follow
special mechanisms to generates these normal data points
for example some given statistical process and the outliers of those objects that deviate from
generating mechanism
maybe are generated by
tracer methodology because he
no it's not computers working budget six hundred dollars
three days later
trillions of dollars in information technology investments we have resources to the
ten the plot was
and you can see some examples
just distribution of microsoft i am thinking about this
it's on under right
which to me just say this
what is the question because it forced
the tracer methodology usually people to perform much more intense in the first round to
how is it that way
no global social or people can less tunnel
five shortly after the start sitting somewhere in
and please to
try some kind
mathematical models
so the first thing
thank you so very much information no a little the target
trying to reach you can construct visual thousand sets a distributed
and it's not time as
there was a revival of interest in the small problems separation thanks to about colleagues
colonel duncan watts and steven strogatz who essentially suppose we think social networks using random
graphs right in particular structure in this which we have some kind of reference for
you know some of the
random restaurant to make small
they have to think about following very simple model
in which we mention know
three and again training
the simplest model we can see the
before the GRR
we have an to
right so the reason you you know
one explanation is that very small world if we only knew people the next as
well based on this
she and when ships that we have the ones to reach across the country half
way around the world a story or so
world spam links social ties to make
make the world smaller and
so think that to
random access the screen which in turn
probably indicating the strength of the
exponent of the the k
travel experiences physical space
in which you probably something do something like myself one thirty square
thank you
this be actually
next model for thinking about not just a small world for the experiment so because
you want to model the something you already know something about the world but not
you try to use what you know
green actually later start
actually the model is simple and yields surprise so in particular has to decide
so very small
completely world you're looking be independent of the distance
recent report
one of
thirty nine to clandestine very short
that is the nature your different people who are very close to
so what
these two ran and on the other hand will not be the
four times in fact
the actually
one for search
the simplest where
it's very quick essentially social network reaches itself in not to support very very to
distant targets essentially following the best way possible
the system which was to let
because the roads
and we need to remain in office buildings finding if you simply want this work
to be the irishman area
but maybe i'm five
some of those
the fundamental issue here about building
really this two-dimensional grid
was deleted pretty
it was released
to see how the structure constrains friendships are based on principles of the collection
connections to phase transition
phenomenon physics and actually think that is
there is one of the basic questions of course is well so what is the
real exponent in
human social networks and for
say well of course we want to create a random trying to come that with
first there was something to that person
after all
the question is the standard this is a approximation to the world
does the approximate x y
square and again something even in two thousand they couldn't to me
much traction i mean
well nineteen sixty seven
but as
six seven years
you see these sites were
twenty two
measuring this it's it's sort of tree namely u two million people to to
systems with friends are really
so we can measure
sex and actually some supplies money
most are now
a couple years ago delivered now ravikumar just
provide right into tokens
ten want
an online learning community that has featured so
it has be so time
he was the systems by the
we're looking
that's exactly what happened
probably decrease distance
girls actually
novel because the the random variable is not seen you see something as which depends
on the heating
so what do we have basically in in hidden markov models where you first decide
on hominid values the random variable can take at any time step and this is
in the terminology of the
hmm it's called the number of states so you decide that your HMM is going
to have to and state so at each time step it could be in one
of the n possible state is discrete to qt can only be
say want to tree up to n and that's all that's the only values it
can take that you're u we'll never know which value it was you just decide
how many values it could
then you have to define
what we call a transition probability
which says that if i was in the state j
at time t minus one
the protein to be in state i at time t is equal to that
so this is this defines basically how you can move in the random variable but
without seeing it this is something that you need to estimate without never having seen
qt for true it's something happening behind
the c
and then you have the emission probability so this is really what you see
and you're going to decide that there going to be a distribution over what you
observe that is going to depend on which take your that's why because interesting so
let's suppose that you have and state in your
a random variable
for each of the state there is what we call an emission distributions
which could have emitted your data so now you have your data
and it has been emitted by one of the state you don't know which one
if you knew which one it was then
its distribution would be this one
so the pretty to image given that you are in that state
and the the thing you need to to to connect all that is to have
an initial state probabilities which says basically where do we start this this process how
how does it start
this is how you start the process first decide that there was an initial probably
due to start in that random
or hidden state are another one another one from there you can now
the goal
with the initial and transition probabilities
for all these three
probability models have parameters
that defines the parameter space that defines a family of functions
and we're going to need to estimate the
to maximize some
some like you don't have nice some cost
there are several things that you are interested in doing when you have in nature
in your hand
and the basic three problems that were defined
ten fifteen years ago
are the following
let's suppose i give you an HMM with some parameter
and that i give you a sequence of data and i ask you
what is the probability that the sequence was generated by this HMM so what is
the protein sequence p of x one could be given
this HMM which is parametrized by a set of
peter parameters
this is very useful it's like computing the probability of the goshen or a mixture
of gaussians you need that
that's the first problem
the second problem is
you decide that you have an HMM with these sets of parameters
lots of transition probabilities emission priorities and his initial probabilities
now i give you a training set of several sequences
and i ask you what are the best value of the the
the parliamentarian
suggesting it we maximize the likelihood of your training set this is training if you
remember this is very similar to a training set process caution mixture model because you
are searching for the parameters that maximize the likelihood of the product over all the
sequences you may have
probability of that sequence given the model of course to do that you first need
to be able to do this
this is the first then you can do that
this training
and then in some cases
you may even want to know
OK i assume that this sequence has been generated by these hmm but we all
know that this HMM is in fact
the combination of a random hidden process and some of the process not what i
would like to know is what
i assuming that each observation was only generated by one of the state
i would like to know the path we followed into the state space so at
each time step i would like to know in which state i was at that
time for some problems it might be useful in fact in speech recognition is very
in some cases you don't care about that in some cases you do care and
this is the third problem you
you would like to know whether what is the
the best
past so q being the best true it in space
that that would maximize the one that maximizes the joint probability of your data
the is
the bible
so what can we do it with HMM if we are able to
to solve these three problems the first one is that in fact it's the generative
it's distribution and as such you can generate new sequences using it so how do
you generate the sequence using an HMM
we use three blocks that we have the initial probabilities emission probabilities the transition probabilities
so first we have our initialisation initial probability state we select one of the state
as being the initial state
this set of
models the initial pretty well and then
we're going to to
two loop
and basically using the transition probabilities
two to decide
what's the next day
and when we in the next eight we're going to
it according to the distribution of the emission distribution of that state and then we're
going to
the transition to the next
the image transition in and eventually we are going to reach estate which would have
labelled as the file state state of which if you get into that one you
and in that case you stop and you have your sequence you have generated the
sequence according
two your model
in order to be able to train an HMM so to try to solve the
values three tasks that we have neither even computing the likelihood computing the
the best set of parameters of finding the best path
the very nature agent that has already been trained we are only going to be
able to do that if we make a lot of assumptions and they're all based
on the on these markovian assumptions like first-order things saying that for instance it basically
the first one says that the brain is deprived to have emitted a single
at time t
in theory should depend on everything that passes before so all the input
previous values and even the current one of the state variable and even of what
was observed that the true probability of what could happen if it all depends on
building my my application and finally to engineer some of these resources then this step
is to plan the ontology developers development as we do with that we should be
doing in any civil engineering projects
so in that case in in
you already know there are several ontology seminar life cycle models in the engineering so
what we did inside the project is to about these life cycle models to the
ontology development and for that we can say that we can use the water for
life cycle more the incremental motherly iterative model despite one and after that because i
know the requirements and i did this preliminary study i can say
OK the
for my ontology i i will instantiate one of these more than they will create
by ontology life cycle model and it is important to say that there is no
you unique life cycle more than four
four for all the the ontology development projects i mean in some cases you could
use incremental motherlode tentative or water
so so in that case
because we
we found in the
when we search
four sources we found several sources in HTML and the internet of the organisations also
forced the
the ontology development process was scheduled as follows so so first we have the requirements
information then we consider the reuse and reengineering of resources after that we do this
item on monday and then they implementation and what we did was to create a
kind of like this one in which you can see here in the middle that
ontologies or ontology reuse and and an ontological
so the use and reengineering comes before the competition the ontology concept but it should
be possible for foreigners to create this kind of gantt charts you know the two
two two two two
to visualise graphically the order in which we plan to do the activities when
and how
is the relationship between the different
so big because we
five so because we
we have selected we did this specification with the planet and we already know the
resources we plan to reduce at this point i'm going to explain very quickly some
guidelines for non ontological resource reuse and reengineering so the idea is that at this
point we can use information
about that appears in glossary dictionary lexicon classification schema the saudis son and folksonomies and
then in the case of classification scheme we can find the
the the classification scheme i'm in different in different formats i mean someone could use
about the nomination that essentially is the snowflake the
the flat and it a more than a set of four representing the taxonomy so
maybe the idea is that if you have one i could have several data models
for this does not mean so you can see here two of them for one
of the neck could have that astronomy implemented in different languages in that case i
have a spreadsheet and also
in in XML
so the idea is that
probably for when we have engineering all these resources we need to integrate we need
to we need some kind of rappers went to transform does not this information into
the ontology is we could stand some part of the ontology we could integrate other
part we could we could cut off part of the parts of the of the
of the model that we we we already transform and then we need to integrate
into a coherent model so in our case this is an example of how
we have an engineer one i is always stand about that provides information about countries
and then that of a that also provide information about the different regions in this
space so based on that what we did was to create the ontology more than
what would we talk about country subclassof location years so class of location and then
the relationship between the country and so based on that we can transform the content
from these two resources in two instances of the ontology and then to generate the
the RDF
so for for ontologies are used in that case there are several possibilities and they
appear invisible in the in the neon project so you can reuse general common ontologies
as they are
you can reuse domain ontologies
or you could have the situation in which you only want to use the model
of the
ontologies i mean because you don't need let's say one hundred thousand concerts in one
and this will be
so the joint talk
i hundreds and after the talk tears will take over
the task we will consider this talk is
we want to measure natural images
natural images
he noted by u
think of them as the long vectors
normally the matrix structure but they are not long vector having an components
and we want
to reconstruct them from noisy linear measurements
y contains the noisy linear measurements x
the design matrix
every row of x
corresponds to
too little food applied to the image
and then there is some noise to edit
this talk their applications in digital photography
and also in
magnetic resonance imaging
it's an interesting problem two
from given a fixed measurement architecture x to reconstruct the image what you
the problem are going to take over here is how to choose the
the measurement designs
if you look at the linear and if you inform them in some way you
at this
before you see that there some some structures and sparsity structure
and the theory of of compressed sensing suggests that
if you
do a reconstruction
with the sparseness and forcing penalty then
you should
use randomized measurement architecture
if you look closer to the image then you see that
most of the energy is concentrated at some some some point and if you have
the PCT than
the concentration of energy is also very striking
researchers from computer vision and low level television vision their argument
random x maybe it's not
not so good
no contributions here
we from study
on several natural images
and we propose
fully bayesian methods
for optimizing
the measurement design namely we want to tackle the problem of learning compress and really
want to investigate
how the design affects the reconstruction
OK what what properties of the going to exploit
you know the image is sparse what does it mean if you look at the
pics of this is the this is the gradient of the image means you take
the neighbouring differences and
at this whereas
you see that many of them is zero the means in the histogram it's
center zero and it's really a sharp peak and many of them are zero but
there edges then they can also
and they are allowed to take bigger value that means the black histogram has heavier
then say
since a goes
and all model we are concentrating on
well plus
potential which
is a reasonable fit to
the histogram
i would whole the optimisation go we were applied greedy strategy
optimize one
of these measurements
matrix after the other means we the
we could compute bayesian posterior over over the image and then we'll select
the rule which maximizes the uncertainty that means the direction of maximum variance and the
idea is to really shrink
the entropy of the distribution
and the algorithm we only uses expectation propagation
i mean give many details which i suppose that if you really interested in the
algorithm and how we
we make it fast and so
then i invite you to come to the poster session
to get an intuition on how this
this procedure is sequential procedure works we've got a video
you have three three different panels
on the upper left you see
o expectation propagation algorithm
at work
this means that the reconstruction is done by by expectation propagation
and the design of the measurement architectures from expectation operation in the middle
you see random measurements on by the way the measurement for those of in those
windows here
this is like the standard way of compressed sensing through your sparsity enforcing penalty
and it's like the like the last so
and on the right you see this heuristic
in the
the wavelet decomposition of the image and we just measure
wavelet coefficients top-down from from course
two to find scale
and when fourteen years
the reconstruction error over
the number of measurements the images are
sixty four by sixty four pixels
and what can you see
first of all you see like the top down localised nature of these benefits measurement
that means
they have also scaling behaviour
you see
these are the optimized
measurement for this and they also change their scaling and in the beginning there really
course scale and then they go to to find scale and these
these random measurement they don't
i don't really change OK looking at the reconstruction error we have
in the
random measurement architecture has the quite high reconstruction
the simple baseline heuristic we just measuring the wavelet coefficients reflecting the
the knowledge we have of images performs better
however they come close in the end
if you really go
and designed
the measurement for us
then you can
you can get
this like
and we can only look at that
and one in which we have
database of seventy five images which you can see
you see them
the curves
average over those
of those seventy five images you see
the little shade corresponds to the
it was standard
if for a given the blue curve is the bayesian learning
as proposed by jean-pierre last year i see no
it's difficult to attain
so in that case where we need to do is reduced to binary problem
so that we can use the kind of tricks they around talked about yesterday for
reducing to binary in fact joint work with one
and so the idea is really simple maybe don't even look at the slide the
really ideas really simple what we can do is we can come up with so
when you're trying to predict the class of a particular example
where you have let's say five classes as we do here we can do is
we can come up with by binary questions which say
is this example in class a or not is in class b or not
and so on
so that's the most straightforward way
of taking a multi class problem and reducing it to a binary problem
leads to a person of adaboost called adaboost on MH
and we can generalize the air bound that we had before like the training year
is upper bounded by the same product of that we had before
but now multiplied by
this number k which is the number of classes which
not so happy about
OK there are other techniques for more interesting ways of multi
reducing multiclass two
so one of them is to use output coding this is the technique
you should say up their detrick and they carry this is the technique that was
developed by detrick trick and they carry
and the idea here
is to take each one of your labels
a b c d e in this case
and associated codeword with a sequence of pluses and minuses in the matrix like this
and then what you do is you train
on each one of these in this case for binary problems
so in binary problem one
all of these examples which were labeled c or d get labeled as positive examples
and all of the examples which were labeled a b here he get labeled as
negative examples in this alternate binary
OK new trained separately for each one of these four problems
OK so we for binary problems
and then classify a new example what we do is we evaluate
each of the classifiers which a train for each of these four binary problems get
sequence predictions sequence of pluses and minuses
we choose the core the label the row of this matrix
which is closest
to the predictions
which we've got four
each of the four binary classifiers
and this is a nice technique because it's more robust
to mistakes that are made by the individual binary classifiers
so what we do is we can show that we can also prove training error
bounds but those bounds and being independent
of the number of classes
which seems like a great thing
but the catch is that the binary problems they are constructing
here might be much more complicated and much more difficult to get good air raids
OK so what i want to talk about next
our confidence rated predictions which are way
a practical way of dramatically speeding up adaboost
and practical problems
so so far
we have assumed that the weak classifiers are giving us hard predictions
in other words for every example
predict either positive or negative
so what's wrong with doing that
the problem
comes up an example in in an example like this one
so here we've got a bunch of positive and negative points
and suppose that are weak learning algorithm has identified a rectangle like this rectangle are
where nearly all the points inside the rectangle are positive
which seems like an important pattern
but all these points outside the rectangle
are roughly equally positive and negative things practically random outside of the rectangle
how is this weak classifier going to predict
in a case like this
well with the weak classifier would really like to do is i would like to
positive inside the rectangle
but i would really like to abstain it would really like to say
i just don't know what the answer is if i'm outside of the rectangle
so the problem is that if you require hard predictions plus one minus one predictions
you have no way of expressing this idea of not knowing what the answer is
you have no way of abstaining on particular predictions
and in fact if you need to predict
plus one or minus one outside of this rectangle
then you clearly going to be making a whole lot of mistakes
on these points outside here
so if you predict positive outside the rectangle then you'll be wrong and all the
if you predict
negative outside here you'll be wrong in all the positive
so in either case you're going to be introducing a lot of areas outside of
this rectangle
and the problem is that means that you end up with a lot of examples
a lot of mistakes which need to be cleaned up on later rounds would later
rounds of boosting you need to correct
those mistakes
you've made on these earlier rounds
in practice this dramatically increases the time to convergence
so instead what we can do is we can allow our weak learning algorithm to
use confidence rated predictions
predictions which have been rated with the confidence
so on your own talk about this a little bit last time as well
so before we clas sifier always at output predictions which were either plus one minus
so now we're allowing are weak classifiers
output predictions which are just arbitrary real numbers
and the intuition is that the sign of that prediction positive or negative
is our prediction are actual prediction as to whether the positive and negative examples
and the magnitude of prediction
is a measure of confidence
so now you just want to abstain as we did this last example
the weak classifier to with zero
in this case indicate that doesn't know the answer
OK and so
these confidence rated predictions it turns out that you can use the exact same update
but the question remains of how to choose the alpert's in each design on each
and here we can go back to the that training aircrew for the that notion
of minimizing exponential loss
and so
we want to do on every round is you want to choose
alpha teenage their product which always appears together in such a way as to minimize
in the case that the
nonlinearities in the
it is in the observation model sorry as i just described then the
the prediction process looks
it consists of the diffusion just as it did with the gas process the gas
in filter
so the whole distribution drifts bodily according to the deterministic part of the aggressive filter
and then the random part of the autoregressive field sort of smears it out by
literally blowing it is literally a guassian is what happens to the probability
distribution and then finally the reactor effective
of measurements superimposed at the end of the cycle
so let's see what happens when we actually run this striking against clutter
here is an
certain girl dancing around my laboratory
two strains violin music we just off the right
she would dance until violence
was played
funnily enough
the best kalman filter that we could designed to do this with the same dynamical
model lasted only a second before
there was a momentary confusion i'm not sure how picture this between the outline of
the head and the outline of the screen it was
you know just a momentary aberration at that point it look like i the hypothesis
had reasonable support and randomly the kalman filter with its validation gate and so on
when for the wrong type of having once made the mistake it can never recover
in the particle filter is not the same mistake wasn't made these ambiguity arose at
the same moment the distribution spread out to reflect ambiguity but and also later supporting
evidence comes in for the main hypothesis and the ephemeral hypothesis vanishes and everything is
back on track so the robustness of being able to consider multiple hypotheses under these
multimodal likelihoods is a huge advantage
and here's even more extreme example where
we're tracking the motion of the leaf
where the cluster now is as vicious as can be in that every element of
clutter looks like a foreground object
here's the tracking it's thing lying around and we're zooming leaf is going to pass
in front of the PC really fast in front of the leaf and you know
there's of momentary aberration if i were to show you the distribution of particles in
there you see it spread out instantaneously to represent that ambiguity so but then the
ambiguity gets resolved that that's what these things are really
and of course as i have already said with reference to juggling
having the particle filter being able to deal with non guassian distributions also gives you
more freedom to be creative without the dynamical model so in the particle filter this
was done by
in the juggling
the problem was done by switching between states the different phases of juggling is an
even more extreme paul
we're tracking the ball to bounce off hard surface and
the way the ball behaves at the instant of bouncing is is unlike as possible
its behavior when it's in freefall also be ridiculous to try to
press those two kinds of dynamics to cover them with one model model that you
learn to view insisted on doing that would be very weak
sure enough his a picture of what happens when the ball bounces on the on
the hard surface which is here
and we with a model this is supposed to encompass all kinds of behavior that
the ball just drops through the table
in the case where we model explicitly the bounce and this can be done with
a sequence of a sequence of random variables even including such details as exactly when
the bounce occurred because there's a video frame time elapses here and the actual instant
about could be anywhere in the video frame time actually allowing uniformly random variable that
within the bounds turns out really makes a difference and you see what happens here
the instant of the balance is that some particles
carry on with the old behavior
extrapolating the dynamics and falling through the table and other particles
generated by the other branches this dynamic model which has in which there is a
finite probability bounds and the coefficient of restitution and all that are included in the
and finally of course the evidence
gets resolved on
on this
the alternative hypothesis which happens to be the correct one
and we tried also
using this kind of technique for
an interactive
process for cutting up objects from images where we replace time with space so
now we're filtering along the curve as it were
and i got to
so now
i'm going to try and
cut out this chap
and so i'm going to i'm going to fourth time forwards and backwards by spinning
the wheel on my mouse
so here it is time is going forward
you see it
there's observation likelihood
which knows about high contrast and the likelihood of the desired edge following aligned by
contrast but there's also
dynamical priors
which prefers smooth curves
but the action is a bit like a regularizer if you like and then finally
there's an observation likelihood associated with the user whatever the user chooses to do so
the user can act as an oracle and supply extra information like i just did
to correct behavior i didn't like and what you also here see here
it is a kind of trace of all of the hypothesis that were entertained along
the way so this martian blood been spilt here
across the tuna of this guy
it's kind of track
you don't have the explicit track because that would be too confusing for a user
but you see this area all of the areas to be considered so now
actually as a user
i can pick up
any point in the the spill area and say no continue from one of those
and now i'm just spinning the mouse wheel i i can even look at you
guys while i do it doesn't take much cognitive effort
every now and again i have to go in and
right now it's done
it's completed and
you know i could
another one somewhere here
get rid him
one of problem when recursive problem size and number two was constant time to do
the the dividing work here is divided by two
and the combination work is doing one or possibly two multiplications
this is the logo
and allowed to do is multiply numbers logan is the best you can do
a simple but powerful way
and every one computer power number you know what to do
is anyone not know the definition of nineteen numbers
and is willing to admit it
OK so this is a good old friends lower than the definition of
reminder in particular the base cases
september nineteen numbers i will claim
are very important because
here's throughout nature you look at certain fruits you see the actually sequence you count
the number of little bumps around each ring if you look at this this and
in the beach and how the waves hits have been actually sequence
i'm told you look all over the place actually sequences there so how does nature
computer maybe not just sequence
different classes and how we can compute seven actually sequence as fast as possible
you've probably seen two algorithms are called them
so the
the most naive algorithm is a recursive algorithm
three say OK
f of and say well if ten is zero returns are venice one return one
otherwise return
recursively compute f of ten minus one and f of n minus two and them
how much
time does this algorithm to
those who have seen it before
it's not obvious to guess
not to be exact
how many people have seen something before
and analyse it
also running time
really really long ago get any more precise answers just one
was sent
exponential yes
also correct and more precise
even more precise
maybe you've seen this analysis before
its feeder and
where is the golden ratio
again the golden ratio appears throughout
the world in mathematics but this is probably the only time in this class very
very very minute cameo
we're happy
OK this is called exponential time this is bigger than one that's all you need
to know
this is exponential time
meaning it exponential time means basically some constants the power and
exponential time is a very long time
OK polynomial time is good
it's so
this is what we want are polynomial time algorithms this class basically entirely about polynomial
time the question
say what the algorithm does again so it just f then so define function the
actually n
i checked for the base cases and otherwise i recursively calls actually and minus one
i request look often actually be nice to add these two numbers together to you
get this branching tree something to some problems of almost the same size additively smaller
by one or two so you have i mean you almost not reducing the problem
size at all so that's intuitively white
exponentially you can
draw to recursion tree you see how big it gets
how quickly i mean by over two levels
you've only reduced on one branch the problem
from and to and over two
the other one maybe you've gotten from and down to one but none of the
branches have stopped after an over two levels have the least to the power and
over two
which is like square root of two to the power and which is
getting close to