are attached to something like a box
on the part of the
o which is called the soundboard
we analyse the some four
the soundboard is a must
for you to here
the tone
if you have a strange
and you would also late that string
added resonance frequency with rocket and go into those
you wouldn't here
the reason is that the
the amount of and this place is solenoidal because the string is so small
that is just not enough
disturbance in the air you can hear it
so what you do
you monthly strings
on the box
on the surface
in the case of the piano
the piece of wood
and that is what starts to oscillate because the string oscillates in the strings mounted
on it
and so
the whole board starts to oscillate
now the amount of energy this this place is much higher
you can hear it
this is easy to demonstrate
i have here
during four
four four
it's not modelled on anything i think you can you can hardly rules
i can now you can hear
the portal box on the table
you will be able to hear it
one or
even today
so that's the function
all of these
some boards
and that's the reason why these
tuning forks
all mounted on boxes which is the soundboard
and so that
make sound
loud enough for you to years
i have yet to win a little music box
there are problems
and i rotate this
drum around these little prongs do this
he also late different frequencies
i don't think you can he it
not impressive right
i put the table
that's the reason why you need a large surface
two oscillate
in the old days i remember
that in wine cellars
the all of the wine cellars could tell
what the level of the wine walls in the barrel
and he will do that by knocking on it
and in the beginning of his at the level where there is liquid
very little sound when he reaches the whole part
very large
and that upper part can easily oscillate the liquid cannot
that's one way of telling
which of these barrels filled with some substance in which is hollow
if i had known brains at all
and if i would bring this tooling for
i put on my head and open my mouth you'd allowed told
i can demonstrate this
more impressive right you don't hear much
that's maybe why i'm at MIT
yes my expertise certain john miller not just stay there until
just as they really were
john very my fellow
we can also test whether
he has a brain
getting nervous i can tell
what is truly for going ahead you open your mouth and we will hear nothing
from the right
but you get the right to
what are
sixty four
so string and wind instruments they resonate
very unique
you experts now we called harmonic
natural frequencies
but all objects
have resonant frequencies and not just one but a whole zoo
of resonant frequencies which sometimes
a very mysterious and not so easy
as an example
i have here a wine glass
and this is a very complicated
piece of glass
i can make
this glass itself not talking about and i was about
the glass itself also lay
in a zillion different
so what i was really referring to is i finally got her to use macintosh
thank you very much for thank you want just briefly thank donnelly elliot the people
don't really mostly work for making this meeting happened the management will yield a chance
to see all the cell in the front row here
so and more than that i also want to thank all of you guys for
coming today
from all these different fields among its think
everyone in the audience and the
particularly if course invited speakers i feel really good line-up of top people from different
fields to come talk to everyone thank them all
for taking the time to come
o two meeting that they don't usually come to
and in two
a strange country within a country called back might not normally get to so that
i really appreciate that and what i want to try to use that you know
as well as doing so we don't always get together so let's let's communicate let's
share ideas and celebrate
this this this field
and this group of fields
and i've i when i invited to speak the speakers to cameras where each one
of them to to share their view what's going on to take some of their
time to give a little history and a personal perspective how they came the field
as as
ask and answer the questions like
now why are people in your area not just you but why why there just
in your area in the ideas of reinforcement learning
so if we look
and what's going on
the premise of this meaning the premises meanings that reinforcement learning ideas are having an
impact on on many different areas so we can list machine learning and AI
control theory operations research neuroscience psychology and economics
and if then you can find places where
these ideas are used and in particular even the particular algorithms are used so let's
raise the bar a little bit and and we can group these things into lists
four different areas that are really really different they have different criteria for success different
reasons for being interested so
machine learning and AI maybe
we started begun there
but and and and now control operations research these are little bit have some similar
goals many i think if you ask you know like dimitri bertsekas and why he
is interested in if you just like my stuart russell director interested in reinforcement is
not they're not just the same they have some different great interest different kinds of
rigour different degrees of exploratory possibilities
so those are very different in practice obviously neuroscience and psychology those have totally different
ways of measuring utility
and so like psychology in the first place temple difference learning i algorithm to the
td lambda
like alkanes were published was in psychology and it was
it was published on its own merits wasn't like this system call machine learning stuff
maybe it has implications for psychology was just psychology
and we feel can science today there's a little bit of carry-over but really it's
evaluated the temple distance-learning learning ideas and reinforcing ideas more generally are evaluated by their
success in predicting data in explaining data and so that's i think really special effect
and say
so four at least four different
very different research communities with different criteria
independent validation i think i'm i'm going to say that that's the first time
perhaps the first time that has ever happened
you can see kind different kinds of crossovers but independent validation forty iterations communities is
very special thing that's that's what i like to to think we want to celebrate
and talk about so what is happening why is it happening why are
a few ideas what can we see the same algorithms in the same idea being
user validated in is totally different ways
OK so what are these ideas
so let's just start superficially right we just want to relax today we've been doing
a lot of conferencing in many of us already and was a kind of kind
enjoy ourselves and let me urge you guys too
two it interact i don't have so much material today that it's going to be
there it's going to be tight and you know the point is to talk so
he question just bring your question right now everything comes misrepresenting something if you want
to refine it right that's what we want to do to find our sense of
what is happening that brings these fields together and you get a better sense of
what is sort of these ideas we just superficially talk about learning through trial and
error the ideas of reward and value the markov decision process framework and the specific
algorithms that we can see being used in these different fields
the goal of this talk then begin asking what are these ideas will be a
little less superficial let's look more deeply these ideas and which ones are actually critical
as opposed to just being incidental
care what too and then we got the final axiom that saves
everything that's mississippi can't have enough success
it's one level
so and then there's other reasons as to why
these regular justifications that might contain items that contain superfluous parts formatics are still parts
of axioms but we might get some kind of external max masking going on
and this is why we have our regular justifications
and this is the only justification that we have computed that we're looking at
and then what could happen is that we get parts of an axiom are in
fact here from one of the justifications inside this
and this combined with some other actions that may be still inside the justification
and they also combined with an axiom that's external to the justification
so what we actually end up with are
fine grained justifications was so previously but was talking about parts of axioms we also
end up with a further fine grained justifications and the regular justification here
mask these other justifications
these fine grained justifications so
really actual fact although we've got enough to understand entailment paleontology from regular justifications we
may not get the full picture there may be other reasons as to why didn't
entailment holds
and these are just the same as by
because the justifications of fine grained enough
axioms and justification
consider many parts
so we first this condition of external masking because it into the past inside the
justification in fact with axioms are outside the justifications produce new fine grained justifications
so in some sense
with the termite part that is what we want to think about are fine grained
and we defined
i did some theoretical work on this we produced definitions for this problem definitions
and we've come up with two new types justifications the first one the fourth one
is called the conic so we have the conic justifications
and these are justification that don't contain any superfluous parts
and all parts as weak as possible and this definition makes it clear
it is clear to exactly what part of axiom is before
this is is a very dedicated and some work on this but
their work was characterized by kind of an operational death
operationally defined definition for size justification so they just produced out twenty four computed these
computed the just produce algorithms that compute what if all fine grained justifications but
it wasn't clear when looking at it if they really were fine grained justifications they
may be difficult to compare one system to another
so we've got a well defined notion of passing this definition of what we and
then we got precise justifications and these are also the conic justifications
but these things here again is primarily geared towards repair
and the precise justifications
each axiom in the justification is a minimal repair small
flood the class descriptions don't contain any nesting i'm not going to go into too
many details on this now but if you want to talk to you about it
after you can do and there's also talk in the main conference on wednesday which
are going definition of ways of computing these things
so just to show you an example that
if we have an ontology here
consisting of three axioms a so close of the and exactly one r c and
this is nested these well condoms and seminal by the way
and then we also have these subclassof role c
and s
and he is equivalent exists RC
and flawlessly this entails that a is a subclass of the
hopefully you can see that but we don't require
everyone see that
we have
it across the that kind of pass through here if you like so we know
that it's only got a long-established sunglasses successes and here was that we know it's
going to have one
and here we require that for any can be
we've got the necessary and sufficient condition here so and i call this one as
and don't have access to services across the
so the part of the justification that are superfluous to this in this particular entailment
so in the first case we've got axiom here
and i see this across the
and i mean one are
this is taken from
the first section here so we remove this country be that superfluous
and also here
we don't actually require all of this cardinality restrictions we don't require the utmost part
of the exact cardinality restrictions unit acquired in part so we know
from what we've got here are a d and we know it's got this one
as successor
and then on the second was offered also chops off another contingent here
so we all we need is the fact that this falacy do cluster c
and then on third axiom we've got this superfluous part of this comes in the
OK so the equivalent
axiom here so we don't actually need the implications go one way
and this happens to be
here going right to left but here which on it
and that's why he had this RC and forces classify e
so we moved another part of the axon here
and as i say the definition of provided us what is coming justifications are
it makes it clear to me what parts of axioms are so there's no dispute
as to whether something is laconic or not
and also whether thing contains the weakest possible parts
so we can take a look at some of this imprecision a
so for the purposes of showing you examples of
the kind justifications i'd like to go back to the computer science
the ontology
and just a slight power gain to classify it
we noticed we've got some unsatisfiable classes
and by the way we can get an overview of some of the entailment selection
of instruments and this for axioms panel
which is on the ontology
we noticed some things satisfiable here
what is an entailment shown with this kind of
now cluster one slide by dashboard on a yellowish background can click the question mark
this is a shortcut that brings up the
actually just want to add all unsatisfiable classes here
i want to compute
i was just like book is added you can i want to compute justifications for
he is unsatisfiable classes so
you notice that there two ways in which we can
come look at laconic justifications in this explanation workbench
the first one is that we can compute one laconic justifications for regular justifications
so this is really a lot of things so that was really
there is a lot of XSLT
just for
four laps so good at all in hopes of extracting
information from our collection not to be here
the is
examples right so we have to try to
well not just in the earth
it is possible to write an XML schema
note that one
but you can
you have to know what you are actually so one schemas more generally
so what is semantic web languages and all
we reach actually pointed different out
after this
one thing is very important
this is what we are looking for the
so what can
a lot
four is the fourth book
that is the
are different kinds of services and some of
for me on
so there are
these being harvested
where they can
we have a very strong are called
one of the
thing but i will be destroyed
i mean the whole area that
being able to describe classes and a series of of the shows what is this
is this is the same
nobody has any
people who usually most
something something of the system that is always going to be doing entirely
the fish like rule system
but that's not the same as we have
april of
that's a very important role in the reason for my
or try
these is really for
then he
or one or more
this is
this is the
the key is one of the system does it contain contradiction or
so some due to
the station
all rights reserved
so it is
he's the core
you should search for all the time
coming up there because you can do quite a bit analysis out
i so for
you create
questions quite
pressure and you feel
of all time
so we have things that is most
i one hundred
what is actually meant
however they really useful
you can say oh no
schema to start
you seem to be consis right now
and all really know this actually huge
all these two areas
text for this
seems to be much easier
so the
is trial
where that we need more than that
a lot of north
i mean there are
this representing real world money on
are really
the other thing
what you want to get more
the scission configurations then you can deter mined
all the different observable
and then i will show you some dynamical results
what we obtained concerning the mass distribution
so static results so we have done this
hartree fock calculation we have
put some constraints these elongation asymmetry constraints any clues
if you only look at q three equals zero
you have this fission barrier that prevented before
spherical shape high energy than the ground state which deform for centre point other point
corresponding to either mirrors
and then you have second story saying well because corresponding to either
the second set and then you have the valley going to
what we call symmetric valley was to fragment having the same as
but you see here that if you impose
the formation here
you can have another valley here which is the asymmetry valley and then at the
end you have a small fragment one
here you see that you can reproduce the
seriously fragmentation and all the different asymmetric fermentation
so from semantic two very asymmetric fermentation
so if you do that for different systems so you can find many different features
of the features of these neutral landscape really depends on the nucleus you are looking
so if you look at the toyota under twenty six iranian of family
you see that you can find different feature the first one concern the superlative from
minimum here
because you see i don't see anything here
so that's was
what did surprise we thought that all the actinides would have scouted for minimum so
fission isomers but in fact no
if you add too many neutrons support system having more than one hundred fifty six
neutrons you don't have disappeared one
so that's why in the cross section you don't see all the structure
you can do so that schools and the single minimum but you see here you
can have a family from shape here
four car you so
extensive calculations are now performed to really
pin down what is the difference between the
all the different nuclei
see also competition between the different values and different modes
in blue you you had the lowest energy
so you see here
that is for symmetric fission
asymmetric fission but competition between two values and here
it's only
non symmetric fission and overly here
so really you can not use that mean that you cannot use for dynamical calculations
one landscape which is calculated for one you applied to the other one you really
have to
to do the right calculation for the right new you're interested
now you have a question is how do we determine the scission configurations because you
know how to impose global deformations to the fissioning system
then you have to say OK then it's fission OK you have two fragments
but you are gaining not ways
classical object having density one and zero outside
you have to diffuse necessary phase
and you this interaction with a given range so you don't know you don't have
any topological definition
one of them
of the of decision points of what we call also the exit point
so that's why
you need some prescription so there are a lot of different prescriptions
i just mentioned here a few
the first one is that you say that you have to be separated fragments
when you have as nuclear
interaction between the fragment which is very small compared to the coulomb repulsion
so i mean that
you you
i have only two fragments interacting through coulomb so you put then
number and say OK
decision when
the energy is less than one person
the other criteria that can be used is the densities in a
even if you have the diffuse nice you can
calculate the density and then they can say OK these are you have two fragments
when the density in
is less than ten per cent of the nucleon density
well that create a and b news concerning the energy up when you increase the
energy or the decrease of all the shapes
so the criteria that i will use here is based on these low density in
neck so
if i blocked the for example the density of the nucleus when i'm through this
pass here
and with the two fragments having the same as
it's here so
this is the
this game the density
you have this fragmentation here
and if i increase the deformation you see that you have
gated fragment
and then you have the formation of an egg in the media
and then at the end
you have two well separated fragments so here
it was almost almost no density than a here
so this is for this image presentation and you can do that
you can do the same for
you can do the same for example another fragmentation so this is the most probable
two s dollars
to cut off here but there's two
right what the band or
they're all
there's no one here in brilliant
now again
there is a very
nine killed tools more
for all practical purposes there is no bonds between brilliant too
in this molecular orbital approach their right
four eight
four and it's got a p electron
in the atomic
so now we've got to do is going to look at the constructive in destructive
interference between these p
weight function
we've got to do that we gotta make molecular states we gotta let be
p wave functions the p atomic wavefunctions constructively and destructively interfere
to make
a new
molecular weight function
right rate here is how we do it
here's two p ex
the weight function
for the two PY weight function may look the same right one is just the
next dimension one is in the light dimension
they have no role playing right here
we're going to do is we're going to take that function over lapping
with the same way function to be at war two PY
from another atom
going to bring these two with an equilibrium bond length
gotta let this part of the wavefunction overlap with this part of the wave function
and this part of the wavefunction overlap with this
and we're going to treat constructive interference first
and the result is a weight function it kind of looks like this
in the centre right here we got a lot of weight function
his right here we have a constructive interference
in the centre here we got a lot of weight function
right along the into nuclear axis we got an little plane
well we got an all playing there because we we had no plane
in the atomic wavefunctions to begin with
so there are no role-playing is maintained here
o k
molecular weight function here
it's going to have a different name
because this is the different symmetry
right this way function is not
cylindrically symmetric around the bond axis there's wave function of the bond axis wave function
will only find xs
right but not on the side here it's not
cylindrically symmetric
so we got a new name for it that
it's pi function
we're going to call it pi two px or pi
two PY
OK it's going to be a binding weight function
and of course the binding function
if we look at energy level diagram
the pi two px and py two PY are going to be lower in energy
and the atomic wavefunctions just like this incident
the two px and two py y
in the atomic state
are the same energy
right the pi two px and py two PYP are going to be at the
same energy in the molecule
make sense
let's do more
four and so more unable get one p electron
it also has some s in s electrons right PS states are down here i
didn't draw them in and this diagram
i'm just reading right here that two px electron
what happens well what happens is we're going to fill each one of these states
with these electrons
now we're going to use
hunt's role again remember once rule
it says that when you have states that are degenerate
they have the same energy
the electrons such that one electron goes in each state
b four you can put a second electron in either one of those states
the way this algorithm works with you again begin with the nearest neighbour graph
what you do is
let x one to xn be the neighbours effects
you project next to the span of x one through x
and that projection you're calling x bar OK
so i have all my data
i made my nearest neighbour graph
for every data point i can look at its nearest neighbours and project the data
pointed to the span of the nearest neighbours
and then once i got the standard the nearest neighbours
and i've got x but i simply find barycentric coordinates of expire
which is basically finding a set of numbers that sum to one such that expires
the centre of mass
and i represent bar in terms of this by centric coordinates
what i do is i construct sparse matrix w
but the i it through all of this
matrix is the battery centric four minutes of x i
in the basis of its nearest neighbour
OK and then they use the lowest eigenvectors of this
matrix to embed
so if you have already seen this probably but many of you may not have
an unjust
during these to give you a sense of what it is that people are trying
to do
at the turn of the century OK this is
from two thousand
and this is the intuition they had and they came up with these procedures and
for the most part you can't
prove things correct about these particular algorithms but you could ask are there other algorithms
that would do do meaningful things for the same general kind of a question
so is an argument for why the LLE is somehow computing in some sense the
last year
i don't want to go through this it's a little technical
but there is an argument in the parish
he showed that can i wrote actually shortly after this algorithm was published
in science which is giving some kind of a heuristic argument for whole LLE was
somehow calculating
the trace of the hessian which actually is the glacier
of maybe risk in the square of the laplacian
so then let me discuss the next algorithm which is the algorithm which is called
the plus in nineteen
and about le plus i can maps you can actually prove a few things
and it's related to a few other algorithms that have also been discussed later
so let me develop plus i maps algorithm
and the last in the map maps algorithm looks like this
you again build a nearest neighbour graph
so this is a graph
with every data point is identified with the vertex
and you put an edge between two data points
x is close to xj in some sense so you measure the euclidean distance between
x i and x j which is the only distance you can measure
and if it is less than epsilon you connect them
and as you build your nearest neighbour graph
you make this graph a weighted graph
so now i have a graph with n vertices i have ended up points have
a graph with n vertices each vertex is identified with the data point and w
i j the weight between
the i eight and the g eight vertex is given by that exponential functions
another general function is actually quite important because the correctness
of this algorithm will depend on actually the
functional form not
precisely in that function but on the decay of that function
so there is one parameter t here
that you see
if t is very small
it penalizes heavily if
the point six i annexed you far apart
and if t is very large it doesn't do that so it actually is in
forcing locality
so now what i've got is i've got n data points
i've built a graph with n vertices
and it's a weighted graph
where between the i th vertex and the g eight vertex i put the weight
w i j
it's symmetric
w w is a symmetric matrix
and notice
that actually in this setting that we are in its around matrix
because the way this matrix is generated is the following
i get a bunch of points randomly sampled from this manifold
x one x two x three x four x five and so on so i
get a random number of points each point on the manifold
got in points and now have generated an n by n matrix
which is a matrix
which looks like this
it's random matrix
so this particular matrix will have i can vectors and i can values
OK and then there the manifold and the central result which we will talk about
later after we just
intuitively understand this algorithm a little better
is that by looking at the spectrum of this matrix
and i can values and i can vectors
of this matrix essentially or something very closely related to this matrix
we can recover
dikin values and i can functions of the lab class beltrami operator of the manifold
from which the data was sampled
we make sense of that statement
the algorithm looks like this
you look at
matrix called the laplacian matrix
and that laplacian matrix is equal to the minus w
w is as i just defined it is symmetric matrix w i j is
what it is
with those exponentially weighted decay
is the diagonal matrix
we're DII is simply the rule sums of w i j overall j
so now i have this matrix l
it's actually immediate
that it is symmetric because d is a diagonal matrix and w is a symmetric
it also turns out to be positive semidefinite
which is not immediately obvious but it turns out to be true
and i can values and i eigenvectors of this matrix gives us
it is used for embedding
that's in the plaster nineteen maps
there's another
the distance metric
that was also proposed this is due to
the final form and rafi coifman
the diffusion distance and it's very closely related to this essentially
very very similar
so what you do
it is you think of
the heat diffusion operator on the manifold HD and we look at that a little
bit because the two main objects that's really we will need to
Omega matter of pointthree and I mentioned the power spectrum if we
look at the power spectrum of flow of fluctuations as a function of wave number
or momentum so this is large wave number or large momentum over here small distance
scales small wave numbersmall momentum the infrared large distance scales here then what
we would expect is a theoretical power spectrum that depends upon the value of Omega matter
times age because the peak in this power spectrum is sat by the wave number
associated with the equality of matter in radiation in the early universe and that depends
upon the something that's knownasthe shape parameter gamma which is very well approximated
by omega matter times age so just by looking at the power spectrum in fitting it
to a cold dark matter spectrum it gives us information about omega matter again
suggesting that Omega matter is point threeor so so the observations of the total matter
density of the universe is about pointthreeand we don't believe that baryons
can give that larger of a value there are two main reasons for
doing thisfor believing thisactually three one reason comes from the calculations primordial or big
bang nucleosynthesis but of beforeadmit it so after the bang the universe
was too hot for nuclei to exist and thanaboutthreeminutes after the bang
the primordialprotons and neutronscame together in form the light elements most of
the protons and neutrons formed helium forwellmost of the protons remained as hydrogen
the nuclei that will form will mostly helium for due to deuterium and helium three and
in order to make it through the first day the universe needed just a little bit
of lithium the abundance of lithium produced in the Big Bang is very small about
one part in ten of the ten to so the abundance of lithium produced in the Big Bang
is comparable to the abundance of benzene in Perrier ok so it's not a very
large fraction but justa little staste to improve it now the exact values of
hydrogen and heliumandlithium depends upon the ratio the specific entropy of the universe
during nucleosynthesis which depends uponeither either the ratio of baryons to the
photons since we know how many photophoton density is we can convert this
into omega bomega baryons times h squared and the observations are
consistent with Omega baryonH squared up about point zero two maybe a little
bit larger the best indication of the baryon density comes from
measurements of deuterium deuterium is the most sensitive element to the baryon density and
there is not so easy today to make a measurement of deuterium abundance and deduce
its primordial abundance because the binding energy of deuterium is rather smalltwo point two
emv it's easily destroyed are eaten by heavier elements so we want to know the
primordial abundances abundance of deuterium and thatis best determined by looking at Lyman
alpha absorption systems at high redshift so a typical astronomer will look at a quasar
and on the line of sight of the quasars will be clouds that had not
yet formed galaxies and these clouds will absorb the radiation from the quasar a
very much in the Lyman alpha region so this would be the spectrum of look
this particular quasarand there is an absorption feature here at a redshift of
three point five seven two so there's a Lyman alpha cloud at a distance corresponding to
a very large redshift looking back to the primordial universe and if you measure look
at a high dispersion spectrum of this a lot of this light from this quasar
what you see is that a Lyman alpha absorption due to the hydrogen and
you also see a feature here that's due to deuterium so here you can model
this and deducethe deuterium the hydrogen ratio and this is what corresponds to a
omegabaryon h squared a point zero two since we determine that H squared
is one-half this is omega baryon a point zero four but the total Omega
in matter is pointthree so it's about ten per cent it`s not large enough
there's another reason to believe thatbaryonscannot be all of the matter
in the universe oh let mealso mention that W map determines omega B H squared
from looking at the height of the acoustic oscillations peaks and their determination again is
consistent with a with a big bang nucleosynthesis value and it`s measured to very high accuracy so
omega baryon H squared is about point zero two if we look at what happens
to how you would form structure in the universe that only has baryons
baryonssuffer in the early universe around the time of recombination a dissipation
known as collisional dampingor silk dampingso in this interesting region that happens between
the tightly coupled region for thefirst threehundred thousand years and decoupling
the photon mean free paths starts to become large and photons will start to drag baryons
around and will dampany baryonperturbations on small scales so the baryon photon fluid
suppers damped oscillations and let me show you a movie that I tried to show
the first lecture but I think is working now so what this is is a movie
that was made by DeanEisenstein showing what would happen in the universe
if you starta hundred and tenyears after the bang at a redshift of eighty two thousand five hundred and seven
this is when the universe becomes matter dominated so you start with a club a
finish this discussion by including the antibonding bonding orbital and this is the set free
when you're drawing your molecular orbital diagrams any time you draw bonding orbital there is
also an antibonding orbital that exist
it might not have any electrons in it but it still exists so you need
to draw the interior molecular orbital diagram so i wanted to make sure you have
a complete that for hydrogen your notes so let's take a look at this hydrogen
we can first draw in our atomic electrons
so there's one electron in each hydrogen atom
and and this means will have a total of two electrons in hydrogen molecule
so we can fill both of those into the signal one s orbital the bonding
orbital we don't have to put anything into the antibonding orbital
so that's great what we've seen as we have in that lowering of energy of
the molecule versus the individual atoms
so let's try the electron configuration of hydrogen the molecules molecular hydrogen
what you saw
what we've done a lot of his drawing the electron configuration for different atoms we
can do the same thing for molecules so if we take h two
we want to draw the electron configuration it's very short
on is is think about
one has
and now we have two electrons in it so it sigma one square
so this is our electron configuration let's take a look at another example let's try
the molecular orbital diagram for h e to now
so again we can fill in our time
orbital here is going to be two electrons in each of our atomic orbitals
so now let's go ahead and fill molecular orbitals me to fill in a total
of four electrons
so we have two electrons in bonding orbital
but because we're we're using the same rules to follow up
molecular orbitals as we do atomic orbitals so
the poll exclusion principle tells us we can have more than two electrons per orbital
so we have to go up to our inside bonding orbital here
so this means that we have two electrons are lower in energy
but two are raised in energy
so with this BS stabilised molecule then
no so compared to the atoms it should be somewhat the same energy we shouldn't
get any extra stabilisation from forming the molecule
i select
go ahead and write with the electron configuration would be h e two
and again we're just filling in the different orbitals so we have to think about
one has
that's going to be square
and then we have sigma one as star where
so we can compare the two electron configuration and we can actually think about what
we figure out from the and we see that you are lower in energy to
electrons are raising energy so we have no net gain or no net loss of
energy for each e two
and there's actually way
that we can make predictions here and what use molecular orbital theory predicts that h
e two does not exist because it's not stabilised in terms of forming the molecule
the way that we can figure this out using something called bond order
bond order is the equal to one half times the number of bonding electrons minus
the number of antibonding electrons and the bond or you get out will either be
for example zero which would mean that you have no bond or you can have
one single bond one point five one-and-a-half bonds two
o double bond and so on so let's figure out the bond order for two
o two molecules here that we figured out the electron configuration for
so i guess we'll start with helium two
so the bond order
it's going to be equal to one half
and then it will be two minus two
so our bond order for eighty two is going to be equal to zero
so it has zero bond there's no bonding hg two
let's look for hydrogen
four hydrogen
bond order
it's going to be equal to one half
two minus zero
so we would predict bond order of one what kind of bond is a bond
order of one
i would expect to see a single bonded hydrogen
so what it actually turns out the reality is that eighty two does exist
but exist as the weakest chemical bond known and it wasn't in fact even found
to exist until nineteen ninety three so i can assure you this is not a
bond that you see very often in nature and it is the very very weak
bond it only had the dissociation energy of zero point one killer joules per mole
it means that if all these
our food
in order to
go here you have to spend a lot of energy
that's why you have something very stable
but now imagine that you have a lot of neutron excess neutron excess
how can you be sure that we have a similar scheme
so how can you be sure that these numbers will not change
disappear or change
or not
state so this is really a very important question now nowadays
are these magic number still valid for exotic nuclei
so this is an example that i give is concerning the ten equals twenty eight
magic number
so this is the magic and which is due to be not be care so
this in this line here so this is the number of neutrons
twenty eight is here
so is that the case is closed can
and then
you go down with the with the product number so you go to also for
thing him to reply here
so you see that experiment and we are far from the truth and that's the
decreasing here
so a proton number so this in the landscape
so neutrons here always the same
and protons here you see that
so i'm going to eight important so you have some problems on these articles
foster for sixteen so this is
and for some reason was in
so the question is how
occupancy of proto levels change
the schemes for neutron you had this problem neutron interaction so how the modification neutral
in and in practice on sorry in advance
when measurement is to calculate this energy difference
and then to see if you have the decrease of these gaps if you find
decreases means is no more magic numbers
so this is what has been done
two different approaches mean field engine with
and they both agree on the reduction of the shell gap anywhere twenty eight in
exotic nuclei
so for example here you have the energy so far calcium here
you have this difference which is equal to four
o point seven and
and here is reducing to three point five
the same year
position with between ten cm and since swing
but this is not an experimental fact
so this is only from very
and the difference between fragmentary figments
how big is it how do you know that it's no more magic numbers
so you need some observables
one possibility there are other spin on for example one possibility
it all looking
even even nuclei of the two process state
or what is the blue one
because as i told you in magic nuclei if you want to excite the nucleus
you have to spend a lot of energy
so it means
the the two personalities will be very high in these two play so we will
be very high energy
and it will be of
a single particle citations so so
not very collective so that's why we have very low transition probability to go from
the states of the ground state for to detail so that's why you are looking
at and is on the beach
you're expecting
the two president
deep into transition probabilities
so there are measurement that has been done
this is an example so you have the energy as the pentagon's the neutron
so first look at the density of ice at the picture
you it to from twenty twenty eight
so you have to magic numbers you
if you go from suffer so two separate unless you see that the peak is
let's here for twenty two
and for cities you don't see anything at all
so this is one proof
the other ones are we to sort transition probabilities of ground state depends on depending
on the neutron number
four clancy you have here decreases
and the idea is this
is that
more variables give more freedom more causes given more constraints
it had very few classes per variable the problem is it to satisfy properties many
solutions because it's underconstrained
if i have a large number of cores variable the problem is hard it's underconstrained
and the chances that can very quickly
discovering the problem is unsolvable
the hard region is one of these
have a particular racial where you really can tell if you're going to be able
to solve the problem and not and then you have to keep putting one more
work into it
and you know exactly what this ratio is depends on the number of problems but
for random three SAT problems
it's in around four points
and people are you know it trying to learn exactly what the number is
so the important thing for this is that most problems are easy
and that's actually going to be a great boon for us
OK so
how do we solve societal problems let's look at the back tracking approaches first
the basic idea in the backtracking approach is very simple as we're just going to
assign truth values by depth first search
so i start out with no interest was signed and the necessary you know one
rote one variable and then to another then to another until i have to backtrack
and then you know i keep on doing this exploring the whole tree until i
find the solution
notice that when i assign a value sell to variable this has one of two
the false literals
i e the literals that become false by virtue of saying that variable i e
i that rewards
the negation depending on what signing
those essentially disappear
i like to think of a class in which the variable appears right if if
i have made the literal truth other clauses true
it had a five-minute rule false the little disappears
if i little through the clusters appears
so every time there is some about the variable i went up to the simpler
problem and so as i progress in my search the problem becomes simply to one
of two things happens
i i the wind up with an empty set of clauses which means that i
believe all of them so i succeeded
i went up with an empty clause
i mean that i made all the little and some clause false
therefore the cause false and i failed
and so what happens when i feel is that backtrack
i do some assignment that i just made and i might try again
and i keep on doing this until i succeed or to have exhausted the tree
and returned
so this is the basic idea there's a couple of additional improvements that we can
do that actually make a big difference
one of those is what's called unit propagation
and the propagation is that if you have have a unit clause meaning the just
one literal you know
what has to happen if i had the clause not a i know that has
to be false otherwise immediately the problem is not satisfied
OK so i think that i can before i search is active military unit clauses
and replace them by the artist
now you might think well gee how many units was are they going to be
my problem maybe not in
maybe not many but but the
the key thing is that as you replace
because there were links three become linked to
and then they become length one
so unit clauses crop up as as the search progresses so this one's up you
giving enormous time savings
given that we can use is what's called pure literals which is little just have
the same truth value everywhere
if they always appears nonnegative and i know that you know i was nothing by
sending it really true and certainly an organism that also again pure literals will appear
as the search progresses in the the CNF gets amplified in this will buy me
a lot of time savings
so here's the famous DPLL algorithm DPLL is short for the names of the people
who developed there this pattern and motion and loveland
and the way it works is just as follows it's a because procedure
if you seeing is empty
that means we delete all the causes of return true
else if CNF contains an empty clause then i feel they return false
else if it contains the true that i call DPLL again with the liberal replaced
by the necessary value else if it contains a unit clause i can just call
DPLL with the unit clauses you know the value of the two
they were replaced by the by the necessary about otherwise
i was saying there will
there is the CNF and you know choosing which variable is the heuristic process the
one that you know this is quite important and here's what do is
i call DPLL recursively with that are close to true
and if that succeeds then i'm done
otherwise i call it with the value of of the variables set false
OK so this is where things branch
and this is the killer that it can solve a lot of set aside problems
very fast
not nearly as fast as stochastic local search for a lot of problems
so there's many problems like for example you know something as simple as queensland DPLL
is quite slow
and stochastic local search is just blindingly fast
so the stochastic local search words it's it's the more recent of these types of
methods but it's one that goes to the largest problems
in stochastic local search what i have in each point in the search is it
complete assignment of values to the variables
so that tracking works with partial assignments stochastic local search works with complete assignments
and then what i do is
to do years
the energy needed
dpq equals zero implies people's skills
maybe that's better
of the problems you want to solve this finding
the k nearest neighbours at some points for the epsilon nearest neighbours at some point
or something like
these are the places where kind of technology can be useful
first of all the k nearest neighbours sort of the
most current learning
it often works
surprisingly well in practice
i wish
should be or if you have two metric
to the problem
it's useful simulation if you a set of particles which are running around
if you want to think about the metric is being the euclidean distance divided by
the sum of the velocities
that actually this magic
and then you that gives you a lot of time to find the nearest neighbour
search means first things could
and then you can do the interaction and you can just keep on
finding the next year's neighbours
it's also useful in
the networks were
want to design a network which will find some files with a latency so the
notion of a neighborhood in terms of
this the thing latency
so this is the basic problem
some bad news
can do better and brute force
in force
maybe you need to
elements into RAM
in the context of in space into
and then querying you can just for every single point
you can get distance to the query
and finding
it turns out can do any better norsk case
just because you can get
so there are
most people who don't problems and i'm somewhat unfair
comparing them
but i think it's illustrative so is this
the rule and stop in two thousand two
the algorithm which was took over m squared times november twenty space
and integration of
and then there was this navigating that which is it that two thousand four
which is essentially the same
there are ball trees which are
what you can the
the thing which people use alot right now
and then they actually work very well in practice
but the worst case
there are m squared time and in space
and then cover tree talk about here which can have the same
o worst-case asymptotic testable tree
the things she
that's right so
these are algorithms just rely on just having a metric kd trees rely upon the
euclidean space so are some some sort of
axis aligned space
OK to pretty well when you have this low dimensional euclidean space in high dimensional
euclidean space
often these techniques in the parking lot better
and you know these things are not too much solar thank motorists
the cover trees is will not be too much so kd trees all those experiments
have not been done yet
what do we need to constrain the URL
exactly so that you
i always find the
the closest neighbors the
the first thing is
all of these
it is artificial
the support approximate queries reasoning
there are some other approaches for doing approximate
my question in general is that you should go for exact
and then if you discover that too computationally burdensome if you go for approximate
OK so
why is it so so
this for
well know there
now it it's
what was going to happen fundamentally thrown extra assumptions
four and say i did so in the worst case we can do better than
brute force
but to be one of the worst case
and it has some structure
and given that structure we can do better
so we define the structure is and how you can do better next
OK so
what structure so this is actually find the current rule
if you have
a ball of radius r one the point
the set of points in the set
which is
these services are
there's p
these are
if you double the radius
company new set of points
and the divide the set of points in a small ball
call that
take the worst case over all points and all races
thank all the worst case the expansion constant
so this expansion constant is sort of like to do it dimension
so if you had kind of a regular grid of points
would be about four che
period points in three-dimensional space to be about a dish
now there's a few things in notice about this notion of structure
one is that
it doesn't obey which you might think of dimensionality sometimes so for example if you
have the set of points
you can list
you can have this can be p
this can be are
and then we double it
include all of these points here
between the expected cost can be very large
it is
some other way
different dimensionality
maybe even closer to fractal dimension
which is
you have a larger radius
yes so how many balls of the small radius and you necessarily cover all the
elements of large areas
but we're not going to use that one because
we can prove very much respected
there's to be here and to thank the organisers for for inviting me
particularly since
and that for so being kind of very close to the competition learning theory community
although had so connections are
i know that the stuff i'm going to talk about today
is things were learning theory
is a difficult to apply to and
i'd like to present this as a challenge for for the community
to to study it
so that was about learning representations or a deep learning as a come to be
known you can think of deep learning is one particular way of learning representations
so we know that at in the history of pattern recognition and machine learning we've
or you could good job that are coming up with algorithms to learn classifiers predictors of various kinds
always assuming that either the feature set or the
kernel was given to us
that the kind of questions i'd been interested in for very long time before
you know
before you from the first act a
set of working on machine learning which was in the early eighties
was learning representations because i think it was
some from the start that it was kind of the secret to words more powerful learning machines
so that's why i have never had a huge interest with things like kernel methods stuff
like that because they just were not solving problems
i was interested in
that doesn't mean that i think useful
but i think
my my interest just elsewhere so here is where the interest is it's
learning learning representations and
learning representations
i think is is probably the next step for for ai machine learning
as well as for things like nor science cognitive science
neuroscientists have no idea how the brain learns representations
and i think machine learning to help them with that
so how do we learn representations of the of the of the world say the visual or
perceptual world
and by by merely looking at the world maybe acting on it as well
neuroscientists as themselves a similar question how does the visual cortex organized itself to perceive
you know to
turn itself into a visual cortex f
the the sort of connected question or for machine learning would be how do we
know feature hierarchies
reason for hierarchy is is going to conclusion of interest to a couple minutes
so deep learning problem really is the one of
is one of
you know learning
representations of the world just looking at data
as we'll know
a pattern recognition system have been built by either building handcrafted feature extractors followed
by you know classifiers
although the more modern approach to things like object recognition speech recognition
actually has another stage in
in the middle here the little features effects
in the case of speech are things like this disease in the case of vision of things like sift hard
and the second level
i'm actually uses learning
it it's based on some sort of unsupervised learning
very simple one k-means sparse coding
to sort of turn the low level representations into sort of mid level representations could call it this way
and that is followed by some sort pooling and and then classifier supervised classifier
so you know one more stage fixed unsupervised learning supervised training
that's kind of the mainstream approach to speech and and image recognition
until the recently
but really that model hasn't changed much since the early days of pattern recognition when
you look at the perceptron that's pretty much what it is you know feature extraction
globalized sort of classifier
you know maybe it's time after fifty years fifty five years so to
move away from the model
if we look at f
how are the brain performs vision
and another huge advocates advocates for you know
inspired by biology but
but sometimes useful to give intuitions from it
is much more hierarchical we have kind of a
for the sort of fast recognition process
that people performance and you know animals as well
this sort of a feedforward path that we can trace the eventual pathway the cortex
the cortex
that goes into several stages each of which has
you know very highly non-linear operations
and goes through you know very areas of the brain v1 due to the for fiji each of which
has several layers processing if you want
so you might have to a single had to go through maybe ten synapses something like this or ten
or neurons if you want
to go to the
an area of the brain where object categories are encoded
so it's not just
it's not shadow in the sand in the usual sense
it doesn't look very much like kind of architecture review so far
ok so it's sometimes useful to get a little bit inspiration from biology but is also very generous
because we don't know what's important where we look at a piece of brain i don't know what matters in it
and so here is an example of what not to do this guy called down from the
nineteenth century
who builds are airplanes model to bats and
you know you know much aerodynamics he was very good at building or steam engines
but powerful like steam engines but not very good at like you know stability and things like this
and to build a second full size thing actually took off
you know through fifty meters one meter
was completely uncontrollable which is why you probably never heard
a function of course was about a but yeah but but not on
the other on some points the wright brothers this thirty years before the wright brothers
so you know he got
used to close biology you really know important about it
he had to figure out you know a lot of a dynamic instability
we might as the question you know not phase there are people in the world we
got lots of money from
a very governments who claimed that we can put use the
functions of the human brain by basically simulating giant brain on a computer
and i think it's completely nuts i think it's just you know it can't possibly
work if we don't understand the underlying principles are
so what are the underlying principles intelligence
what is the equivalent their dynamics of their dynamics intelligence right that's that's what are
we might want to go after
in terms of some conceptual
ok so
architecture we might want to go after something of this type where you know if the raw input
and we have to go through a whole bunch of transformations each of which is kind of
train all machine oil
and and as as a
as a side effect of this whole system training
itself to perform the task world can have
drive each of representations of the problem
so the first if you're theorists
at some theory i know first question to ask is why we need many layers of wind energy can we just
do this just to layers like say this
ok have a kernel function compare your input with earlier
training examples or a subset of them are
computer linear combination of this new dot
now also of course you know someone has to give you this kind of function which is just
as complicated is coming up with a feature vector
the you know if you limit the complexity of this function here
it's pretty clear that there is a whole bunch of functions that require very very large number
the following content is provided under a Creative Commons license your support will help MIT
OpenCourseWare continue to offer high-quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
visit MIT OpenCourseWare at ocw . MIT . EDU
this the weekend is over for now and 3 0 9 1 so the announcement
this Wednesday that we know lecture instead celebration of learning
test number 2
these are the
room assignments we had moved them just a little bit
I move the dividing lines rather than the same rules that we wanted to make
a little more room in here
and in the locker genome so there's of more people are being asked to go
to 1 dash 190
and this is the group to go to the Walker Jimmy 3rd floor of the
Walker Memorial Building and then the front half of the alphabet group reported here
and if you take the test at 1 o'clock don't go 6 120 because we
will be there were putting everybody 26 100 that where there are plenty of vacancies
so it's good so I'm just gonna go quickly over the the
the comments that I give before every test is to put everybody in the right
frame of mind but the coverage is lecture 7 317 possible start with ionic go
through the generation of x-rays but not rags or anything like that long
so remember you better bring 5 things with you periodic table table constant something to
write with a calculator and you're AG
you know unmakeable suggestions for some of you want to write your recitation instructors name
on your AG because I want to tell you what I wanna do if I
don't have a recitation instructors name on the exam I'm not gonna greater
you know why I guess 630 these if you don't put the recitation instructors name
on the exam that means you're no hurry to get it back and that'll save
me time we'll just take all just putting aside greater the ones for the people
who really want to get back the next day and I'll get around to the
other ones
so well
I think after the after 2 months it's not unreasonable for us to expect you
put the recitation structures name only an example on the purpose of the test is
to provide you with feedback so we want to just tell you are you mastering
the material you
is your study habits are your study habits effective enough so we're trying to do
so this is not an aptitude tests on emissions tests I just wanna see if
your mastering the material if you are going to say congratulations keep up the good
work and if you're not going to send a message saying you keep up at
this level you fail the class you need to get that information on a timely
1 of this test taking strategies read the paper 1st identified easy questions work on
your schedule don't do number 1 because I made a number 1 number 1 only
because it's the easiest 1 for you to be confidence-building the nerves
and so on show your work show your work
all right cryptic answers because as you get wrong
we can give you part
if you give us lots of
binomial volumes of information to give us a few ideas as to how you are
approaching the problem that we can give you partial credit for parametrically try not to
immediately start going through your calculator
and then please bring something to compute with I was astonished in the 1st half
the number of people that had no calculator a
the course was
any line because like that will do
i think that's easy case where we can
can divide this too
can a linear function approximator
or contain a line
the classes from years
obviously it's for questions
the answer is no
but could change the feature space so the answer would be yes
you could change the feature space two
x squared
what's where x one night six y
not just w one times x plus w two times y
but instead
w one times x squared plus w two times x y
plus w three times y squared again you know these are still linear in the
the weights price there are sort of item here
still linear in the weights
but with these equations highway these equations i can build
a linear function
linear function of these
draw the circle
in the x y space
so the point is that people are an impression that live buccaneers are are are
extremely limited
that's not true
it is only the latest of expanded feature space knots x and y but any
any features that you could use that would still give you and your partner
and this is why the function approximation so popular that it is quite powerful
but it was so here's the deal most time
opposition with linear function approximation is convex being is one global optima and you can
with many fascination there are often local optima
OK so
you can find a decent solution maybe but you want you don't get to unify
the globally best solution
so so
neural nets used for take this sort of form
this slide slight slightly modified and know that do have the problem of running into
local optima however there are many tricks that you can use neural nets to avoid
local optima
so just go that look look what mothers that mean that you can use them
work in practice
but it is one kind you
carry out an unknown knowledge method everywhere
well you easily the that's that's the problem it's just that the if you do
gradient descent
or right
radio said
and for space
you know
you end up
OK you're saying you're saying this non-linear case is actually convex
OK i would disagree
the thing in general and non linear function approximation OK that's that's example
but we got some white function posterior you can always take the gradient with respect
to the parameters
of that function
OK and all need to do
it up with the previous methods two
are defunct approximation is to be able to great is to be able to do
gradient descent
OK if you forget get fish around gravesend or it's very simple you about the
about function that you want to minimize maximize
in this case we assume that we want to
i actually suspect that
other points
so this is very functions back to every parameter individually
you get a vector gradients
this area
back to partial derivatives which is the gradient
OK so it in two d problem you might have this sort of ball
and you you want to find the minimum of this poll
actually i guess
i guess this will persist for the maximum
this here the gradient shows that
yeah have character right
so no need to the gradient is interactive increase
looks like and if you it's the minimum here then you go in the opposite
direction negative
the fraction of the gradient
so if you want to minimize a function take its gradient take some small step
in the negative direction of the gradient and the problem is convex
say like ball
you will always be able to find the minimum
so now let's look green green separate for reverse learning we're going use the mean
squared error as our error measure we will take if we want to minimize their
function we want to follow the gradient of error function with respect to the parameters
so the air itself are called the airtime t our them the teeth episode update
as delta t
so let's look at
i i i i don't care what the is here vt some sample could be
the sample
one step back up it can be the simple monte carlo back all i care
is that it is some estimates
of the value in trying to predict disimsample that's what i'm trying to predict
so i
second style not that no no it's not on the slide
so the
could be a linear right from approximation in which case
again this some sample it's all i care to be multicolour the care i got
OK now let's take a linear approximation summer of i
one to k
they die times
agonizing up here so he
love let's see the approximation
OK if you want to the actions exist
at this as well
so this is my
levi approximations by kernel parameters state i is is the estimate the guy
this is the area between like by sample estimate
my current
i was under the population
now let's take the derivative
the error square
with respect to
some parameter theta i
let's try to square
the idea is to
OK a little bit about distances
because they will keep beekeeping top again and again and discuss the structure information and
across america background so let me remind you that you can find the lectures on
that website
so you remember where we left off last classes with the slight like this
where where we went back to the freeman equation and we did some manipulation two
variety in this form
where this is now generally not for our universe that there's only a single component
but with the universe has got several different components radiation
mark this court about two and cosmological constant
and so
there are two things that one can learn from this equation
which is nothing about this simple thing that we derive the friedmann equations but just
recreated in different form
it's one thing is that we've introduced these my god here
and these omega are cosmological parameters
so these describe the density of radiation today in terms of the critical density remember
the critical density is the amount of stuff that makes the geometry of the universe
is flat this is the same parameter format so in here you can have
called our mother and you can have very ionic matter for what these kind of
equation is concerned there's not much difference because on very large scales by audience will
behave like martyr small-scale of things have different
cosmological constant curvature so we've introduced cosmological parameters and for the past fifteen years the
name of the game in cosmology was actually to determine the cosmological parameters
we can already have a clue of where some of the information may be coming
from if you measure this function is that you can get some handle on the
component of the universe
and the other thing that you can learn from this equation is that if you
have a mix of components radiation marked the curvature of cosmological constant in some of
them you can put them zero depending on your choice of more chances are that
at different times in the life of the universe you know the scale factor changes
a different components dominic
because the scale different is a function of the scale factors
so for example if you normalizing because it's a it's customary to normalise so that
the scale factor is unity today
and it becomes smaller and smaller and smaller in the past
you can already see that if you go back enough in time the asian will
and then at some point master will dominate
but then you can see that as you go in the future then what will
dominate eventually if you have some cosmological constant the cosmological constant that
so that was my motivation for going first of the exercise of let's see what
happens for a single component universe because at different time in the life of the
universe different component dominates the so for that period you can describe the evolution of
the universe like if he was if there was only one component
if you have
for some simple cases if you ever muttering curvature only
then what happen is that the density
is that death a destiny
in other words it is possible evolution of the universe from the big bang down
to the the future and so
depending on the geometry you choose remember the geometry if you have no cosmological constant
is just given by the content then if you have something that is more than
critical then it's includes universe and eventually stop expanding eventually turns around collapses on itself
big bang and big crunch
not much fun to see that if you have a universe that is less than
critical then you have an open geometry and if it's less than critical means that
you don't have enough money to actually stop this initial this function so it will
continue to expand forever and there is the limiting case in between these two
it is a case where you know
you never collapses in another keep expanding so eventually at infinity will stop it is
that infinity will not stop so this is the limiting case between the two and
this is the flat jam
OK so this is some nice and clear if
you have much include but because density
you know
rhapsody or the whole the whole distribution sums up let's say seven hundred thousand different
songs a typical walmart store can get carry about thirty thousand of them
and and this you know this this part here gives you twenty two percent of
the whole distribution
similarly you can ask for books so for example you can take lot of noble
like big story
which gets around one hundred fifty thousand books
you know on amazon you can you can be selling in the millions of books
and so amazon is about selling about two point three million books book book titles
and now we can ask okay how and you can assume that you know what
is nobody selling hundred thirty thousand most popular books and you can ask how many
how much sales that these popular books and it turns out that they give you
less than half of the same so all this sort of you know
popular titles they idea and you have a lot of
the sense what
and similarly for movies basically so
this is just the idea to show that
in this tale even though these things are very rare but because there's a lot
of them
there is also a significant portion of the of the probability mass in the tail
of the distribution
sort of much more
and what we user to from like experience with gaussian distributions
so the question
when i was talking about degree exponents
the question is what is the degree exponent and it turns out that
very different networks
all have this heavy tailed degree distributions and here are the estimates for the degree
exponent usually it's somewhere between two and three so for example for the web graph
the graph is that that so we have the degree and out degree exponents there
are between two point one and two point four
autonomous systems this is internet just like to point four
actor collaborations this is basically a data from IMDB is about to point three
citation networks have the exponent around three
online social networks have it around two
and this this graph here shows you the degree distribution for
i think like one billion web page sample from the beastie in
nineteen in two thousand or something like that and you can see some of these
heavy tails
some funny funny things going on
so what i want to ask now is if i if i see a heavy
tailed distribution like that how the estimate the slope
and before i do this
let me sort of show another little example why these
power law distributions of the solutions that have this particular form of fun it turns
out that for example if if you're exponent is less than two then your expectation
i won't exist so you're you're mean will increase with the number of samples from
the distribution rights so the more samples you get the higher the average which is
kind of funny right so we have a distribution of has infinitely similarly if you
ask for many years
distributions power law distributions with exponent less than three we have infinite variance
so these are very different from
normal girls institutions or whatever but to to go and ask how how can i
estimate the power law exponent from the data so that are like few different ways
so what should people have have done is to feed the line sort of using
least squares plot the data on log log scales and fit the line
right so
just you know do not least squares least squares regression on log log axis
this is a really bad
and i'll show you why
what works better is to you know you can feed line but instead of on
the pdf you do it on a ccdf so are complementary cumulative distribution function so
you're plotting probability
that or the number of the number of or fraction of observations that have developed
that have value greater than some x
and then what you can show is that if this
on log log axis this has some slope
then if you would be plotting pdf the slope is one plus the slope of
the CCD
and then the last thing is you can use MLE
right you can you can plug
plug in your data points in cake greater value of this formulae and you get
the exponent what is sort of the key here is that you have to decide
where does your distribution start to follow a power law right so in a sense
you have to decide from which acts on
there is this
heavy tailed of power law
and that's a very good papers
basically people at santa fe CMU and michigan about how to work with it and
how to estimate probability distribution
so let so let me just show you how things can happen so i showed
you this picture before the degree distribution for flickr non-linear scale
now i'm putting the same data but now a logarithmic scale right here sort of
see that you know at usually this follows line OK so everything seems to be
so what i'm blocking you here is the core of the city so complementary cumulative
distribution function right so instead of blocking the fraction of
of nodes have degree
x plotting the fraction of nodes have degree more and more than equal to x
and what you can see is if this would be consistent with the view of
power law
distribution hypothesis then it should be aligned with because you get this like
OK here
right so
even though he things here it seems things fall on line actually they don't know
that there is not affected
so i can then go and feet something as right so if i fit the
power law i would get the line
but if i'm feeding
has said get it
it that writing style much like CVS
so you could then use these tools
at the change log
built around three when you're happy with it
it integrates patch files to stand off
you can all people pull your change if you publish your get three
other people are able to pull your kids three
pregnant again
so what i complain let's get ready
you can close to somebody else three
or you can pull changes
trees all over the the place develop
i knew push these off the tree maintain eventually the size of the
one of the great things about this is that we change log entry
but added everything you have patched into the territory
you get changed again
when somebody calls for military
they get your change log entry with each that the said changes
when i was pushed the tree all the way to change logs data
so every change you know what happened who made when
this also means you know
who broke
so get out the wonderful command called get play
which can blame tells you who last changed its line co
so you're trying to get right change
article used
it's only given what changed will give you a list of all of the things
that change between two point
so it's history file
every changes back to wild
what the change was who made it when it was made in what order
it doesn't solve every problem
be nice
we now have multiple get three lots of
PC game trees remained friends very
video three
all these different reasons
within these trees you can accumulate except changes
often this is not a problem because most of the time for example nobody else
cares about how PC change the people
change there are all these changes due in the system
everybody is happy
sometimes you get a big sensor changes which was play
so memory management changes are good examples
if you change part of the
kernel memory management
it's very likely that you will change
recall memory management is shared between all the system in the NN direct
and you will change every single architect
so you change the i sixty four tree three sixty three
you changed PC tree the tree and so on
and somehow you have to coordinate all of these changes
so they go in the same time
and they all fit together and you don't get completely unbelievable when you when you
try to merge all this together
so can be very hard to coordinate all these things
what's very recently happened there is now actually called learning
which is basically combination of all of the trail of the game trees mango trees
which going to new releases
so let's next is a particularly exciting when kernels arise
that's the one that nobody nobody but
simply from all the pieces together it's hard to see what happened
but it does mean the point you see
where the problem is why don't do what machines were broken
and those can be fixed before
all of these changes thing pushed on linux
so hopefully only the people who intends to run the next three like it really
actually experience the the pain that goes with it
debugging is a very different situation these days
it used to be a long time ago
there were a small number of people around the new then state
some the romantics
other than that munich was the
it's fair to say nearly the eight minutes everybody here and
pretty much hardcore
unix user develop
and this
it means that all the when you could buy
you could say for supporting the bug
i think i
can you stick if you debug statements in see what's happening
his some ideas about how to drive around the city of any of these
most of the users we have today
response to suggestions like
fiddle the driver and see what happens with questions like what drive
and attitudes and actions
this task is to choose actions so as to
maximizing more or get in the future
by that sort of the reinforcement learning problem
it seems like an interesting thing that come back over and over two is that
you can think of a unit of experience the agent has a unit of experience
in the world which is get an observation takes an action get toward and observe
the next observation
and that
you can think of reinforcement learning is the problem of learning how to act from
these units of experience and this will become
more meaningful is because the reinforcement learning problem
again they choose actions to maximize the expected cumulative reward or some time horizon we'll
talk about how they cause very precise as we
i define a markov decision process frame just
make sure you understand the larger problem the reinforcement learning about
now observe course that this looks very simple but of course these observations could be
vectors order structures arbitrarily which
sensory observations the actions can be multi-dimensional white
simultaneously moving my
my my on my legs my walker card and so on by digg all kinds
of motive motor effecting all kinds of motor actuators
and they one
the one
aspect reinforcement learning assumes that is less general if you like then the
extreme generality so far is that the we subscribe to what's called the reinforcement learning
hypothesis what's reinforcement learning hypothesis is the hypothesis that an agent acts so as to
maximize scalar measure reward
so assume the reward some scalar signal
whatever it this examples the where the reward might come from but there is some
scalar reward and instead ask is to maximize some cumulative measure of this scalar reward
of course the reward can be arbitrarily uninformative and we'll see examples of that for
the more this is very important because may not be apparent what i've been saying
so far is of course the agent has some partial knowledge about environment
the agent might have some ability to predict what will happen as it takes actions
in the world so there is
no commitment to the amount of knowledge it has about twelve
so you'll see me if you've heard reinforcement learning toxin often hear talks in which
no knowledge is assumed to be the extreme where a lot of information about the
environment is already known to the agent so we'll we'll talk about this distinction is
we go to as well
so here is a listing of some of the key ideas in reinforcement learning that
i want to present today
except the last one two to one
so the the first serve key contribution of the area of modern reinforcement is what's
called temporal difference or temporal differences idea i will talk in quite a bit of
detail about that a higher level summary of what temporal differences is that it's really
the idea of updating i guess
on the basis of another guess makes it very different from supervised learning where you're
updating i guess on the basis of teacher provide information so there's sort of circularity
reinforcement learning to talk about the idea of temporal difference in the key idea reinforcement
learning reinforcement learning has it is the idea of djibouti traces talk about that idea
what policy learning to this is an outline function approximation for reinforcement learning and then
hierarchical reinforcement learning
so they begin by giving you a quick demo of reinforcement learning problem here is
a reinforcement learning problem it's simulated robot soccer
this is the work of storing something
this particular soccer problem is called people way in which
four red players
we are trying to keep the ball away from the three blue players while staying
within this square that surrounds the white squares sounds and these are
these robots have sensors
they can sense objects that are within the field of view the field of view
is denoted by the white straight line on these on these circular robots and actions
like kicking the ball and dribbling the ball and so on and the task again
as you can imagine to just keep the ball away from the
the blue planet and what you're saying that he learned behaviour i show you minute
random behavior so here's the random behavior with this acting randomly and
hopefully you'll see a difference and as to how fast the lose the ball this
is the the ball much faster here than they did in the learning yes
the rect in this but specific into the red team was learning the blue team
was not
so neither the
the defensive players if you like the learning
and i'll talk a little bit more about one interesting aspect of this of course
is that this is a multi agent problem i think michael littman talk about multiagent
systems i want spend much time multi learning ability to focus on a single latent
learning but just to give you an example of a cluster bombs so here is
the drive the point what might be a good reward function reward is basically you
can imagine they get one unit of reward for every time step to be able
to keep the ball away
so maximizing reward would be maximise the amount of time can keep the ball to
themselves and the sensors are again
the ability to detect objects
within a certain field of view
sensors and the activities of things like traveling kicking ball
so just to complete this little demo they showed that in this forward three keepaway
pass the learning players to keep the ball we for ten point two seconds of
the random people with six point c
by the way of covering the idea algorithms and the functionapproximator today so you'll see
the algorithms and the architecture used to one
place be making possibly more concrete by showing you a specific examples and the random
all for you to write a computer program that does that if you just sit
down and try and write a computer program by hand
the solution is to automatically write these computer programs and when we say automatically write
the computer programs so we actually need is you write a computer program the main
structure of it but has hundreds or thousands or millions of unknown constants and it
and then you have another computer program which takes as we'll see in a second
database and figures out how to tune the constants in the first program that you
wrote based on the database to optimise performance on the task in one so we
should have in your mind is that very complicated task too complicated to program by
hand and you write a general computer programming has roughly the structure you think will
solve the problem so in this case it might be except the face as input
to compute some sort of general features about the geometry of the image and what
those features using some unknown weights and add up all those weighted features and give
an answer as to win
whether or not it's a particular person something like that these constants are going to
be set automatically for you buy another computer programs and the main focus of everything
that people study machine learning is that second computer program how can we use it
to set the constant so that's called learning machine learning that the learning approach to
to i
OK so i just want to quickly go over the sort of difference between core
artificial intelligence which all of you are too young to remember but you might occasionally
encounter in some dusty book and probabilistic AI which is you know what most people
in machine learning work on so some of the core areas of a i like
knowledge representation work with facts and assertions and they develop rules of logical inference you
know if the glasses on top of this box in the boxes on top of
the table then the glasses on top of the table
there's a whole area of planning in constraint satisfaction in which people work with
the applicability or the effects of different actions and ask what sequence of actions should
i choose to get some results how should i schedule my UPF struck so that
every package gets delivered within the allotted time
and the expert systems are sort of the predecessor maybe to a lot of machine
learning systems these were set systems that had various rules that were designed by hand
and then those rules would act together to help the system recommend a course of
action or flag an alarm or
alert the user about something that might be happening
so in probabilistic AI the emphasis is on trying to make these systems more robust
more applicable to real world scenarios so the emphasis is on noisy measurements how we
can approximate getting it we want even though the exact answer might be really hard
and instead of logical assertions we tend to work with probability distributions
in ten instead of logical inference we tend to manipulate those distributions by producing conditional
probability distributions and i'll show you that in the second and set of logical operations
we tend to work with these things called probabilistic generative models and the thing that
i'll talk about in these lectures are really a general sense of these of these
models so before i go on i want to give you sort of motivating example
to try and
get you to think about why there's even some issues in machine learning so let's
say that i told you that there was some input here
but i measured and some output
which i wanted you to predict
and i'm going to give you some examples here are some examples of this input
output function
OK so you go into the world and you measure the input and this is
the input and for the input you recorded that this was the output and i'm
ask you to make a prediction so i'm going to tell you the new input
is here
what do you think the output is
OK so
most of you would have some sense of this is the function may be in
your mind or in some more formal way you're going to draw a line through
these things and you're going to make a prediction somewhere around here right
now what i hope to convince you is that this simple thing that you do
in your head because your visual system is so good connecting lines and making smooth
curves actually involves a whole lot of assumptions that we have to think very hard
about and to motivate that i'm going to give you just one example use the
the input is now
a binary vector
and here's the output
and then i'm going to ask you to make predictions
on this new input which you've never seen before what do you think the output
not so easy right
why is it not so easy
it's not so easy because it's obvious to anyone that this could either zero or
there's no possible way you could predict this having only seen these inputs right