index will be on the fifteenth of august
the limits of
it's a more theoretical questions and more the questions but quite easy once i mean
you know
to process without the computer
that's all
that's that's later
so i hope this gave you first let's say ten plates was ideas about what
the cause is about
this is about
and i suggest to use the next ten minutes
four open questions or further
things you want to know about his see neuron is you
so what is the difference between i'm saying because of the recording what's the difference
or the advantage
added value of
q cv zv something such as cluster analysis or even just
well actually there is
there are also that's it
there are some similar similarity right
that you're able in both cases
to cluster y cases in groups right
or in types
two main differences and it's not like an advantage or the density difference in nature
the two main differences is first because you got to keep all the cases
and in those cases which you mention you're going to have some some cases will
be left out
or less
it was it not taken into account realistic and you can't some waiting for the
doesn't have to be most often right
so in the case that you have to in cases because he was in any
case keep them all
that's the first difference
the other thing is that
the two zero mentioning kind of more powerful
as you gain a larger as you into larger and situations right
and quite the contrary because you would be stronger when you go to smaller and
so i would say that there is a kind of a continuum
the first thing the difference is about the assumptions behind analysis
in order to engage into their personalities
you will have to take on board some basic assumptions
the main statistical assumptions
such as you know are
i suppose
you wouldn't in that case
which is
which is essentially taking processes
so actually is in both cases the it is pacification to speak
and you can use them
also as say in dialogue we can see what you can get pretty we get
processes and seen so much of his done using this done in the future
crossing the two
this analysis and
this year
i think we should discuss class cast in the second week you might have some
so very dramatically my my basic would be
tribal from the data and see what you get out of it in the morning
that the way to
yes there is
there's a pretty good reason please
by marks
not to count
that's the marks
a eight x x o marks
it's working paper on combat it's also
recently published an article just came out i think we can come up very soon
on this
question of
the connection between number of cases
and the role of
articles called conditions
there are some sort of some i will admit that may be the time to
elaborates on the exact rules of thumb
but the idea is that
i was going to say because i don't think that's the appropriate common to make
something that particular noise so we have basically k log k sort of thing so
it's it's a polynomial in k as opposed to a naive method which would say
take all possible input patterns to keep statistics on each one separately now about is
going to be dependent on to the k
so you really can sort of teasing apart in this case and
i get something like a like a plant however long it takes to learn whatever
the sub pieces are which in this case was quite trivial but in some of
the harrier cases
more so
in particular the way we use this idea this hidden bit idea to learn structures
is well if we have constant down on the on the the number of parents
that node can have then we can actually enumerate essentially for each node what's possible
parents would be
and those end up being
corresponding to the bit positions an example that i had there before you have to
learn in the example that i showed you have to learn which bit to listen
in the dynamic bayes net stuff you have to learn which parents to listen to
of all the different possible parent sets of size three say
which one is actually doing a good job of
giving me the thing actually condition on to be able to predict so that's what
ends up being and then we had this you know this lovely thing i copied
just because it has lots of plants indulges in it
but is primarily
you know it's it is about as long as the the size of the parent
sets is relatively small that's big then this all goes away you don't know what
your conditioning on and you don't have a good quick about
and eight for that matter and d i think the this is just cut out
of the paper this is he
these k
he was k moment ago
so that's good
and this is why oh no no that's not true
so so these the now is this is the bound on the number of parents
that you have right so this is why if it's unbounded you get something that's
very very big n is the number of state variables so the number of nodes
in your net
a is we're going to say oh actions
i think
we're going actions or something else but i think pretty sure actions it's not playing
a big role in this band anyway the thing that looks scary here's and the
end of the day right that's the number of nodes raced to the size of
parent sets
which is
roughly how many parents possible parents you
so possible
set possible identities of the parents what they could be it's not good when you
have like eleven parents right because i don't even know that means in real life
it seems like two
maybe one remarries you get three of eleven
anyway so we've we've looked at doing this in some artificial examples where this is
an artificial stock-based example we did actually start off with some real stock data to
hard to predict with real stock
so so we have to put that aside and we made up our own articles
much easier to predict
had some very nice structure to where there was never more than i think to
parents like that we don't have an enough could turn to make it a little
bit harder but each node has at most two apparent in the base that the
actual bayesnet underneath but i don't know what to write access to learn which ones
to listen to
and we compared a number of different algorithms in this you know how how well
can you make money in this artificial stock domain and then what can you buy
well we have and one
this is
well there
fraction of
you can do
i also agree
it's all i there
the problem here is that earth
here for
all of these approaches to
o over here it's like twenty one
and we all only
are you on
it was
when you use
early on
there there are
what the label
one of the world
even if you have a
what does
o one of
these are also
two well or four
all the
in was
but they do
so o
well i always wondered why one
i'm going to be
this is the best
on the face
these are all the one
what you
all right
able to
i of these
and again
types of fuzzy norms for for disjunction functions you have s norms and the complement
of s norms that t norms and used the right thing using de morgan's law
but i don't think that's worth doing i've done that you don't you just for
them in
let me skip that just so you know there's things like t norms and s
norms that are used if you want to formalise this idea of different base of
combining fuzzy sets
yes maybe interesting graph that shows you that some of these norms are sort of
more extreme than others at the mean maximum again i have sort of plotted the
degrees of membership for my sets a and b here on the x and y
axis on the z axis we'll plot the the t norm
the minimum norm in this case
using using the minimum
and the maximum norm over here is kind of see this sort of kind of
a cutout piece of apparent apparently sort of the opposite piece and if you go
from the product norm you can already see how the product norm squeezes this edge
but little bit but of course it will need to observe the borderline cases it
will need to observe the fact that this needs to be one and along this
line definitely want an output of zero so those cases fixed but you can do
something with the area in between so it's already got gotten squeezed down a little
bit by using the product norm and this one pulled up a little bit by
but but but some you know the further we go to country it's enormously into
the book you'll find more about this just so this is just another definition of
fuzzy norms you see how it's actually flattened out or they about here to gets
pushed down even more the t norm the s norm gets pulled up even more
appealing to apply to all of these one hundred per platform is zero and then
we have very extreme norms that all they do is essentially follow the the constraints
that defined at the beginning they're all that so the sort of the conjunction the
drastic version of the convention is going to say for everything that i can but
and not constrained otherwise by sort of the extreme of this up with europe and
the same is true for the drastic sum is all is the one i in
the case where we have no other choice so you have sort of very extreme
versions of these norms that are very very critical new very soft versions of these
well get
and you can if you wanted you could sort of operator spectra is in the
drastic product all the in the left drastic sum is all the way over here
and then you can go bounded sum next meaning some in the middle so the
mean not so very soft versions of these norms and the drastic product existence itself
OK so i think the message is just there are many many many different ways
of defining these fuzzy norms and it depends really what you want to do with
the i'll get back to that later for the for the fuzzy rules for two
different ways of using norms result in very different ways of interpreting what will this
OK you have interesting effects you start thinking about that you you start doing things
that you would expect results because you have seen that in on what we for
example if you were conjunction a and the negation of a on
that's tautology in
williams stuff
what be false right or down here a or not they ought to be true
but if you think about the the base defined
the negation you actually don't get that i you for example in this case i'm
using the product norm for
for the for the conjunction and i use one minus the degree of membership of
a for the negation so we have the blue one is something of a the
degree of membership of a the red one is the degree of membership a and
then i just straightforward apply my conjunction operator actually get something that's not always are
it is moderately odd
so have some bizarre little effects like this one and the same is true for
i you don't get all this challenge in this case i'm using the the maximum
norm again the red line that you can hardly see is negation the blue line
here is the original set a and the green line is a or not a
degree of membership to the set of a or not going to get something that
depends of course on the norm exceptions are different norm here they defining disjunction i
would get a different result may not be able to
that's something you should be aware of that leads to interesting little side effects for
example if you arrange fuzzy points and i dimensional space you can actually not show
the the triangular inequality holds but you can show is that it's not violent
there's the great land in between
OK fuzzy implication we go one step further i'm not interested only in
sort of an or writers who also won two
derive sort of an implication it can do that too involved many different ways the
two different two interesting they are deriving it using r one tautology that comes from
logic a implies b is not a or a b
using for example in remarks normal results in something like this
yeah essentially here we have the and operator in here
and if there's one minus that's the not a in the months operators or operator
and there's a very different way
you start to think about challenge implication which is defined by using this is an
application and then from there to derive disjunction and conjunction operators using these two tautologies
why AM i even wondering about OK this is the results that i think we
machine that missed the bit so it's obvious transmitting and then the fire and what
you find the devices that are built into the the biometric passports which are basically
cryptographic smart cards technology that has been used in like a pay-tv
four four
payment systems and so on are all kinds of applications for every smart smartcard always
existed with context based interfaces
and now they
got basically the the
i have received an additional radio frequency interface
so in that case speaking about RFID ashura i mean it's still the same kind
of our protocol some other systems use but the underlying i mean beside the communication
channel devices actually complex
to give you an idea what's inside these passports basically they contain usually something like
an eighteen fifty one microcontroller some some derivative of that running up to
we're somewhere between eight and twenty megahertz they have a higher very large numbers of
water in in order to implement or accelerate hours a day five triple this implemented
and so on so it's a fairly complex system on a chip
it just has an interface that speaks a are probably and therefore you can you
can put into the RFID category
so let's let's have a little bit of a look at the readers which in
in the standard documents always called coupling device which
doesn't make the mistake of calling day even though they can write
usually you connect them using some standard whatever interface might be serial port might be
used be might be in some cases even ethernet and so on
unfortunately there is not a single standard for any kind of RFID reader there is
no standardisation of the harvard no standardisation of the protocol called that these devices talk
and there is no standardization of any software API on on the computer is not
even in the windows
if you want to deploy system then you have a complete vendor lock-in situation to
whoever provides assistance
because the API is used the hardware interfaces and everything uses is completely different from
one product to another product in the market
this is just completely different from from most other it's a simple computer peripherals these
days i mean imagine a world where every keyboards we could probably
ridiculous even even smart card readers foucault contactless smart cards
basically ninety nine percent of what you can buy in the market today conforms to
one specification which is called the CCI g use PCC eighty and that's the standard
interface and you have one single driver worked with almost any hardware but for RFID
the way
then if you look at the actual RF interfaces the number of different parameters that
defined as i have been is obviously you have to low level parameters such as
operating frequency
modulation scheme and what's called operational principle
frequency there are systems in all kinds of different frequency bands are systems operating at
one hundred twenty five hundred thirty five kilohertz
ten megahertz thirteen point five six megahertz
in this UHF stuff hundred sixteen megahertz there's two point four gigahertz stuff and so
on so any any possible our band that people can
use of unlicensed people have invented RFID systems for
modulation obviously is an important parameter and then there's what has gone variational principles
because that's really something that is very different between these systems
what's very common is called magnetic coupling
magnetic coupling basically means you build something like a transformer between the reader and the
over the years and it's basically to magnetic coils and the reader is inducing electric
into the
coil of the transformer and thereby powering transplant
and that system is used for the one hundred twenty five thirty five kilohertz and
thirteen point five six megawatts systems
the one hundred twenty five kilowatts stuff is not really used that much anymore i
think the only really popular application these days is for animal identification
so i'm in many countries you can you can have your chip injected into the
neck of your
that dog or something if that that talk i think some countries even have mandatory
save the targets lost and somebody finds him you can identify with dogs was the
they're interesting even other things there are specific animal identification transponders that
coles ingest and which i shape physically in a way that they stay in the
stomach and not like it's really weird stuff now in any case what's very popular
these days is the third one five six megahertz systems they are used for all
kinds of contactless payment systems for access control for the biometric passports and so on
so this an extremely popular as system or the frequency at the moment
what's upcoming
is basically what's called backscatter
and in that case you're not using magnetic coupling and and some kind of magnetic
transmission but use the electrical field and use very
fairly high frequencies in the UHF range where
actually send the poles and then some energy is reflected in electrical poles and then
some some of that energy is reflected by by changing the amount of reflected energy
some information can be called that
this is really starts to get much more scary than the magnetic coupling systems because
here you can easily arrange something like ten meters some systems probably up to one
hundred meters of distance as long as you have line of sight
and no not too many metal or other objects interviewing
and what's what's even more scary is that this surface acoustic wave stuff which we
use extremely low-power microwave signals to point four gigahertz or even beyond
but those two systems you don't see that much yet the UHF backscatter stuff is
mostly used for
things like container identification in
in any case is not telling us anything about the vertical localization of the of
the person because we had only two microphones and not only informs you about the
bearing from which the sound is coming but now fusing the sound proposals with sound
likelihood and colour likelihood and you see you get a much tighter distribution this is
the estimate of the mean of the posterior distribution computed from that from the particle
and lastly
a variation on
particle filtering that uses kneeling
introduced for monte carlo sampling by radford neal
just before
deutsches paper and then he put it into
temporal form particle filtering and now what you see is
the results of tracking in three views of the camera
the outline of a living person with quite complex model sort of robotic
animated model with joints and angles and all this kind of thing
you can even step over this box
and you see the
motion is effectively track
i've only got about
and now the stuff left now
and lunches in ten minutes so
i'm just going to
sort of
it's on a few highlights of this
this last section which is which you have in your notes at least part of
it and by the way
since i fiddled with the talks whole lot
you know since i reconnect
a month and a half ago
output the new version of the talks on the on my website in this location
when i get back
to cambridge
so you know we very thoroughly with console models the different kinds of state space
the kalman filter for that approximate filters that work in more general settings
you know capturing the contour of an object is not everything what about the appearance
of the object seems we've rather neglected that
and even before we get to modeling appearance of the
and objects this parameter parametric consul thing itself is rather limited
form of model because its topology is fixed so i mean
you know if i e
take a couple something and show it to you sideways and then turned to forward
so the cup is facing you and you see the circular rim and so on
the topology the outline of this this object changes and it's a a bit hard
to see how we make that happen nicely with active contour models actually people try
to do this using
rather in the way that we did the juggling families of models with the discrete
indicator variables associated with them in the markov chain to tell you about how how
how you can move from one model to another but you know it gets very
messy and actually building those models is a lot of work
and somehow it seems messy way to go is there a more automatic way somehow
of building those kinds of models
because the topology
actually it turns out that
daimler daimler chrysler lab working very hard on this for pedestrian detection
and they have these
rather cute
and that's in
magazines like the economist
making scary promises about what they going to be able to do by two thousand
five and the the guy running allowed our value gavrila is someone that i know
feeling sorry for him as two thousand five approaches he must be actually was going
to take a sabbatical in cambridge and then mysteriously didn't come then it has anything
to do the two thousand five deadline but anyway he's going to make
protesters recognise on cars that will turn all of our streets into
zebra crossings
people separate crossings of meaning
so it's going to be as safe as it as if there was ever crossings
everywhere all the streets and
sure enough you know the
traffic incident statistics in the u are pretty horrific and a hundred and fifty five
thousand per year of injuries to pedestrians many other kinds of injuries to more than
a million but perhaps we could do something about
these kinds of
of accident if only we can detect pedestrians
more accurate so that going to mount stereo vision systems on the front of the
cars not expensive ones like these but highly engineered ones can be fitted perhaps into
then when the driver is moving along the pedestrian walks out in front
the system will detect it and bring
the vehicle to a grinding halt
yeah just missed it
OK so the idea is to
the parameterized contour model
so families of templates
and rather like
and to match those templates too
data and images so the idea is that you take in coming image and you
do some low-level signal processing on it to get the edges the edges don't have
to have total topological integrity
they can have breaks in and missing bits and extra bits which is good because
that's how real edge detectors work they can't really give you logical integrity however now
when you take a template which i depicted here just as an outline but it
can have internal
lines as well one slide over that data
there will be
places where degrees in places where it doesn't and
the whole business of actually making an observation likelihood for such objects is difficult
and i'm not going to be able to go into that but suffice it to
say you can make and model
which is a whole family of such templates in the beauty is that you can
training data and pick up all of these families of templates and you simply
make a for
gather ten thousand frames let's say and get the and do it in reasonably good
condition so we perhaps in the in an area where you know the colour of
the background so that for this training phase you can simplify the data removing the
background and just get the
templates that belong to the moving object and now you can do some statistics on
these templates to form clusters and even distributions around the over the clusters well that's
more difficult
why is it difficult because these templates are not vector objects they don't live in
a vector space you can't there's no obvious meaning to having two templates together so
you rather limited in the algebra you can do the templates and that makes
modeling difficult
what does this
all right
right here
i was
all of
we are
and if you were
i think they
you know
so my
on the other
that's all
they are
so the whole
right on
you know
if you have a rule
the world
we want
we already are
one monroe
share of employment in the country
that is in
low-wage jobs private consumer services is
all kinds of services that
we regularly
consume from shoe polishing
two here cutting
and this kind of services typically jobs that are
very badly paid
except if you have presented some relief for
when building work
and the idea here
and this is taken from an article by
lincoln would be in comparative political studies two thousand three
ideas that
the higher the replacement rate
the lower we expect
employment in private consumer services to be
why should it be the case
you get
a lot
so let's say one hundred percent of the previous job
please for a while you're not going to bother about taking on the job
that's less well paid
which is to job in this area
so the high replacement rate
the lower will be demand for employment in this sector
the lower jaw
will be filled
as a consequence
the less chance will be offered
i will dig into the substantive relationship a bit
when we talk about functional forms and conditional effects for the moment i would just
to highlight the straight line
which tells us
if we move at
a certain distance on our independent variable being the replacement rate
we expect
employment in the private consumer services to go down by a certain number of steps
here we are right in the middle
the core issue not regression analysis
because what i've done is
made a causal claims
until during a nice little story wide is called plane might be
i've made a connection between two variables
i said
the country
shifts let's say from point to point four
and the replacement rate
then we expect employment good down by
it would be
something like
four percentage points
which is why the bot
so it's
in standard terms this is a quite substantive
we draw a straight line
through data cloud
that represents
two dimensional
great of
combinations of
values for variables
here we have case that has
o point fifteen something like that for replacement rate and ten percent for employment
and with many other such
and we want to get this straight line representing summarizing
the art of summarizing relationships so which summarizes the relationship
between horizontal and the vertical axis order variables represented by the
the horizontal and the vertical axis
as good as we can
you got the criteria as good as we can
was been quite a lot of time
figuring out what it means
to be as good as can
now look at this one is this good
well it got published hence it must be good
however there are few things that are annoying as we would expect
the line represents the data out
what does it mean that we expect
points to be close to the regression line
we can count those points that are close to the regression line and without going
into details
here we got the ninety five percent confidence intervals i will talk about and tomorrow
that's a that's we argue that's close enough
if it's within the ninety five percent confidence intervals
it's not the majority of points here
and there are other things that are going as it
if four point three
we got lots and lots of points
on the two dimensional grid
the cover quite a wide range
the same year
so apparently their values for our independent variables
and t applied to we have k
that's the areas
and so is enough
mean specifying your favourite procedure to do
they tradition in approximately a
we can just spotted is just a creation
genetic recursion
then we are looking at the edit data process
and what you
is that
in this approximate procedures
you will be able to
control the errors
and what you're looking for is that if you're controlling the atmosphere controlling the absolutes
user powerful functionapproximator regression procedure by the
are many many samples
so you're controlling the errors
what you hope is that eventually you will be able to control the
the and or
approximating the star
in the long run so you this many many times that's
and the question is if you are getting close in a small vicinity at least
i don't know
and so
the next attempt to seize that so
if you can control the supremum at r
after all the error terms in all the variations use large function for so what
i don't know
we talk about that but what you should you should do and then you can
hope to control those editors
imagine that there is controlled so
in other words the maximum of all these editors just bonded by a single value
perhaps that's maybe a small that
then you can conclude
if you take the distance between the k and signed the limit
this distance is not going to be large and three times the government steps along
divided by one minus
so that's good news strength
then if you're making a similar smaller
then the difference between
yeah it rates in the long run
and we start
i'm going to
be smaller space
this is what we are looking for
should be given because
so at the end OK what you
you will have this just you pick some of these traits and you compute the
greedy policy with respect to the tree and and
well if you have this guarantee
you can plug in this grant he was our previous state and said that the
banner of some
guy is small enough
then the value of the policy is close enough to restart close enough to be
we had the previous result
and then there is this other property that in the small vicinity of the optimal
value function the banner to always
this is against just some continuity property
so i'm not going to get into groups the proof is very easy so it's
so that's one way out of
thinking about what if extending the arrogance too large state spaces large action spaces
one problem is that we don't really have a good idea about how to control
the supremum federer's in chennai
so you'd better control after hours and not simply on all matters so when lauren
harris could be very sensitive to lack of samples
at some part of the state space if you don't go to some part of
the state space you don't have a very good way of estimating anything that i
so the supreme power could be really bad
and maybe you have a good reason to avoid some parts of the state space
because those parts are important but you're supporting matter is going to be large there
but why why should go to those unimportant part so it's not clear that
controlling the supply on an is a good idea so
people one and we consider and the is
that builds on the on expansion operators so another way of thinking about this approximate
is that
let's let's sing that we have a really huge
state space
if you really hit state space you cannot hope to represent all values you cannot
you don't you don't you're value functions really functions of infinite space
i know vectors anymore unfortunately
so how do we represent functions so infinite spaces
using your network for what can i regression procedures
or whatever
right so you use that function approximator
so when you are using the function approximator
and i reiterate that you will have to leave sierra functions so what happens
if you want is that you're trying to compute this band of that you apply
the operator
and they project on hold back
two the function space
so one
but the colors
instantiation of this dismantled
so how much time there
so one particular sensation of this matter
is let's imagine that this is the state space is a one into riots began
you compute tf vk
some magical way
but of course you can ask for these functions
actually you can actually come to this function what you can typically culture is
its values at certain policies take a few points
and you can't use
the values of after the k and those spots
and then what you do is that you use your function approximator
to come up
this function
may be go through this line so maybe you consider this that is visible that
are so you just use and interpolate
so this is the function
that you will come up
if you think about what i'm was doing that
i do still feel bad about having been unable to
o that is
illustrating how
drawing a tighter control rather than just the rectangle
some kind of compromise
get a lot more right now the only thing wrong is the blue line the
transparent either because in
now the user has done is you know how to draw curves
which is annoying
well you know
but perhaps slightly you could draw visitors staying outside rather than having to travel
inside and outside
one compromise
and as i said i do still feel bad about the
about having done the binary alpha zero
here is a kind of hybrid idea i hybrid methods i know but you know
better than the
so here's the hard segmentation we have in the
from what
image and our reasonable thing to do for limited transparency the kind of transparency might
friend in the middle suggesting that
associated with the program aliasing in graphics
you know it's the reason we want transparency is really to implement and you see
that kind of thing because
construct automatically try
is simply an expansion of the boundary has been found automatically by doing inference and
so segmentation using alpha
you calling it out
most i called x graphics they call this thing out depending you know where i
snapped the slide from the time have occasionally got out that we have important because
later on in the talk about something called alpha expansion and the opening of the
mine has nothing whatsoever to do with how everybody wants to use out for everything
is very popular
so anyway this this try map is automatically constructed
now we we can afford to do
inference of but with transparency restricted to this
three the extra constraints on keeping that we can narrow is enough
two inhibitor of the artifacts so now
using actually the same
prior as before
allowing the output very
between zero and one
is really quite possible result crazy things are and the is and that both his
realistic looking soft is good when you do
matching one thing on another you expect sort of it the wrong it is hard
and also deals with some extent with the
remaining aliasing artifacts
and the way it's done actually is
by running a dynamic programming
on a an energy function that is now restricted to this report
and the
parameters of the energy function
our parameterisation of this profile
the transition from
total acid the trip transparency
which is running along the normal to the
the river
so now
each you know this but up into many many
segments each segment gets the pair parameters
for the for the width of this profile and the position of the fans transition
now you dynamic programming
along the contour on those two very your not then
programming is
everybody programming get here
you know very sophisticated educated but
the fitted profile that
thank you
and you see even works to some extent these kind of all
every situation providing the with of this region hair is not more than was that
the present the you with the right
OK so that's that's it for
the this problem of inference of foreground and background so you probably want to talk
about before
we get on two algorithms which will probably be my next time
is stereo matching
you know why is stereo matching the problem the right kind to be treated
in this framework
so in summary you
quite i you will
prior how many actually from this institute
the government if actually from the max planck
otherwise i
this is like family hold back the visitors visit to get this through
i see
alright OK go guys
so you know you lost none of you from the fact you're
and i mean you from
max plank
cybernetics like environment or you know you do cybernetics
i thought i was making rope
you do
do you do
human psychology
one does
do you do physiology
do you do
you all do
should have asked this beginning to make of
OK all
have you seen one of these or perhaps about ten years ago everybody was sending
them around in a christmas card
and the one person in the audience who does psychology visual psychology
if so here we have to do this i think which is
we can what you do
cross view exactly yes so you have to cross your eyes
you know with a natural way
in order to see the stereo pair there are actually two images in in this
image is what they
and school wallpaper that if you've woken up in a bedroom with highly patterned wallpaper
after a hard night out
actually never mind the pattern will like that
and you see the pattern kind of you know comes before you leave for the
kind of hovering in the ghostly plain way in front of the wall because actually
your eyes not looking at the same thing in this i am looking at this
and this besides looking at this flower
and so i was gonna be
now we just need to do it without the help of any alcohol to do
to do this deliberately
what if you've never had any does anybody know how to do you not remember
christmas card but also stereograms what the centre and christmas cards and you deliberately cross
your eyes like this when you look at the christmas card in this three-dimensional leaps
out you know i promise you there is a three-dimensional things
times y minus p
i guess here
well we would do is
compute p
we get the training example
we compute the probability p according to the current model
and then
four parameter beta zero to parameter beta d
we update the parameter
and we update the parameters by
adding by adding something to it
which is the step size
and then
partial derivatives
and more than now
and after a done this loop of the baby jays' we've finished learning from this
example x
and we can move on and learn from the next example x
OK so
the reason it's called
so the x question so the algorithm itself
most implementations they are the
itself and not stochastic in any way
it's called stochastic gradient descent because
if you
think of this example axes being a random sample
from the whole training set
and then this is the derivative
with respect to the single examples of the same example a random sample
then this is sort of a randomized approximation to the true derivative
the average
the average right-hand side here with equal to true derivative
but each individual right-hand side here
is just a random approximation of the true derivative and that's why it's called mister
is called stochastic gradient ascent so
it's as and according to a stochastic approximation to the gradient instead of as and
according to the
exact gradient
the room
he fell
yes yes and no
among the the application of this personal experience with
among all involved training sets that are in fact finite and fixed
and then the thing that you always wanted to heuristically is sort those into a
random order
so that
so so so that each prefix of the stream is representative of the whole stream
and if
and you want to be able to throw away each x after you've trained from
then i think
to get some probabilistic guarantees you do need to have some assumptions about how your
training data coming in
in random order
but that's a thing just a special case of the assumption
so normally we make the assumption that training data representative of test data
and i was talking about how here
you don't need to say you seem the axes are representative of the training ex
is represented the need to assume that dx two y mapping stays fixed
if your training data stream
the first part of the stream and are represented in the later part of the
i'm not sure that any learning method can be
successful because
every learning method is just going to use the first part of the stream somehow
and come up with some model that seems to work in the first part of
the stream but that is not going to work on the second part of the
and there are a
stochastic gradient descent is closely related to other algorithms including the perceptron algorithm which are
non probabilistic
and which directly designed for stream data in which give you
guarantees that are called regret guarantees
which is that
so with an online algorithm
it was also here the situation is that we're using stochastic gradient as a training
and we still think we're going to train and then at some point gonna stop
training going to have a classifier we're gonna use it
but the online situation is that you get examples one the time you have to
make a prediction for this specific example
and then you can learn from this specific example and then you move on to
the next example
and then i regret guarantee is a bound for the annual using is not going
to do
more than a certain factor worse
then the best possible algorithm
and stochastic stochastic gradient algorithms can have regret guarantees
but i'm certainly not going to get into
that now
but the the algorithm in practice the algorithm is very useful
much for a lot of reasons and one reason being that it's so easy to
we're going to take a break in a few minutes i think
just one
so this is the algorithm now i just mentioned some heuristics
that make it much more useful in practice
so maybe the most important
there is a scale
each feature
to have
i mean zero
i just a same mean and variance
so it's not going to work while it has some features may be like age
which range between zero and one hundred
and and then among other features range between zero and one
because the dynamic range of the first feature will be a hundred times the dynamic
range of the second feature and this land is the step size and typically only
have one lambda you don't have different lambda three j and so too much
first single and to be a good choice
all the xj is have to be in the same ballpark
since the feature x zero is constant equal to one
september twenty five is open i said that's fine
i was an idiot
i have electricity electricity and magnetism for decades at MIT
and i know
i should know
that the demonstrations that we like to do require very dry air
no humidity
because the humidity makes the charge to leak off the object
and that's the time when you should give this
it's not the time
and i something else to do
i've had sleepless nights for the past week
absolutely sleepless nights following the weather or by our
had arranged this morning
and if you would walk in you with wet clothes
it would have been all of
if you think it is a little chilly here
sixty seven degrees fahrenheit
why do you think that is
i have asked for the air conditioning to be on for forty eight hours in
a row
because and air-conditioning takes the water out of the air and i can't have you
sorry that you pay the price
a low temperature
so now we will do these them we have to do it fast
in february i can do it very slowly to they have to do it very
fast because if i put positive charge only here if i wait one minute it
we're going to run
the glass with silk
and then the glass will become positively charged that's the way we define positive charge
i will try to put positive charge on this balloon
i'll try to put as much fun as i can
put a little bit more all
now it should be
having some charge the positive charge let it
calm down a little
and now i have here it is rolled which is positively charged positive charge
expels positive charge
very good
but now i'm fast while the charge is still there if i take gruber which
becomes negatively charged
and i wrote
robert we were but always with cat fur so if i wrote this was kept
for i should be able to attract that but really that the is positive and
the rubber is negative let's see whether that works
there comes
see now you have positive charge density negative you're seen the positive charge repel positive
charge using the positive charge
negative charge
the idea of conservation
of charge
that means
if i run this
glass wrote
and if the glass rope becomes positive
it means that
this must become negative
benjamin franklin idea
was elected flow with is positive
this becomes negative
so let's see what i can prove that you by now a lot of charge
may already have reached off because it's september
but i put a little bit more on it
well a little bit more positive on it
and then i'll try to make
role again negative very positive overall very positive and so the
silk now
should become negative
conservation of charge
the same attractor
so that
so now you seem to if the world becomes positive that in the still becomes
call my hair
then i really couldn't predict
whether the called becomes positive or negative
but we can bring that to test
because we know now of the balloon is positively charged
and so if i call my hair if the column became positively charged it will
repair the balloon but if michael was negatively charged
it would attract tractable the
make it attracts the blue from was negative
now you may think
that this business of positive
and negative charges
this idea of
and attraction
you may think that that is very similar to magnets
since magnets
can also repel each other and they can attract each other
but there is a complete misconception
there is a very fundamental
between plus and minus electric charges on the one hand
the poles of magnets which we call north
and which we call
south pole
i show you a bar magnet
and we have one here we have actually two year
is one
number one here
this site is red
and this
happens to be what we call the north pole of the
magnet and this is the south pole
i have another one
also colored
this site is the north pole
and the sizes assoc
the north pole attracts the south pole
i can easily show that
this is the north pole this is the south pole
and they attracted to
the this south pole attractors north
if i rotate
the north called will repel each other
the south pole to repel each other
look at it
there was almost all
what we're
they repel each other cells both south pole
everyone many missing you empire max planck institute for informatics strongly
and this is a joint work with me gentle kind then sheila
the video here shows that typical street crossings in with many people occluded
so the goal of our work is to detect and track all the people in such a crowded street scenes
he has a example images from the crisis in quick sequence
it is a very challenging to detect and track of the people in such scenes maybe because of occlusions
on the single image the pedestrian detection becomes very difficult because of significant partial occlusions
and for tracking across the sequence
a certain number of people the long-term occlusions even and the intact even farther into
a sequence which makes the tracking fails such cases
and our approach based on the observations in such scenes for example when people walk
side by side across a pedestrian crossing
a large number of people are going depend on the person so we say the
dominant occlusion occlusion cases other person person occlusions which actually resulted in a very characteristic
patterns and can be explicitly train and used to detect the presence of two person
recent approach about
michael people tracking in crowded street scenes
based on tracking by detection approach
so basically that implies that
the pedestrian detector on single image
even though they don't have
they don't have some detections whether people is occluded
and what they did is they include some elaborate strategies to link between
across the occlusion events
and so this should strategy requires sufficient with abilities for a certain frame before and after the occlusions
and this doesn't work for other people always under the occlusion the intersequence
so all so it is so we see that the successful occluded
person detection is key solution to
for for addressing the problem of multiple people tracking in crowded street scenes
state-of-the-art pedestrian detector is able to robustly detect the people and the different imaging conditions pose and viewpoint variations
but fails at strong occlusion levels
and there are already several approach has been proposed to detect occluded people
with explicit occlusions occlusion reasoning
basically occlusions as distractions or nuisance
and the implies individual evidence from the individual person which becomes higher highly unreliable with the person
and here in our approach we explore alternative strategies so it implies joint efforts of two people
and use the characteristic patterns of people people occlusion between detector and detected the presence of two people
any our work we use deformable part model is our this baseline and the next
question is what's the performance followed peon for occluded people
how can we quantized
any other data that's we propose anti i two people datasets
so there about an underage person person occlusion images in our dataset has said he has examples
and we categorize other images by ten different occlusion levels
and now is this data set became explicitly evaluate the detection performance for of every occlusion levels
and this is the debut performance our two people did here we show that you
collaborate at its different at each occlusion levels
and you can see with our employees about five percent
the optimal good performance
and when the occlusion level is increased the deeply and performance drops dramatically
ends when the occlusion level is about seventy five percent a mall
the achieved score is honest actually about fifty percent which shows that at most cases
the only one of the two people is detected by the deep
so it is clear that the deep in is
he is severely challenged spend occlusions
any other to solve this problem
for the first iteration young quote should propose occlusion bad apple person detector
which would be based on the deeply approach
and we detected the presence of two people
and the same can we predict the bounding box for individual person
and for the second iteration we propose a drunk person detector which is trying to
between single model to detect michael person
the double person has been a single person
first at talk about our double person detector
so that you can use a mix of components
ends and initialize it by different about the bounding boxes but shows
and further training the use latent actually ends up reasons and they also do mining what happen active
exact examples
and in the end the linear regression functions for each component
to get more precise
and in full analogy to and our detector also use a mixture of components
and each component consists sit up consist of the feature
which defines the cost location of two people and also deformable part
do we use Chinese reastaurant processes in model based clustering basically if you think about clustering the
the natural object that you should be working with is partitions because the partitions tell
you how you cluster your your your data set right so given a
data set S we'd like to partition it into a certain number of clusters of similar
items and so we can describe themodel as follows so for every cluster C
in our partition we can define we can describe the data items under that cluster
as coming from a distribution parameterized by theta C okay and a Bayesian approach would
be of course to introduce a prior over the partitions and then a prior over
the parameters of the clusters and then compute the posterior distribution over both it's
nice to use a Chinese restaurant process for our prior over partitions because it
doesn't limit us it doesn't limit us to using only a small number of clusters
it just a allows it actually allows us to also infer the number of
the number of clusters in our data set right because basically the Chinese restaurant
process tells us not just the the number of clusters but also how the
data set is clustered together but of course I'll come back to the finite mixture model because
that also is a model for clustering okay and which we're familiar with
and the interest we we can actually derive the Chinese restaurant process from this
finite mixture model as follows basically if you look at the this quantity here zet
the zet vector it tells us for every data item which cluster which of the
K clusters that data item belongs to alright and we have already seen that the marginal
probability of zet with phi integrated out is looks like this form okay now this
zet actually describes a partition of the data set but not jsut a petition but
it also tells us for every cluster in our partition a label between one to
K okay so it des so this zet describes a partition of the data set into
clusters and a labelling of each cluster with a mixture component index alright so I'll recall
that the way we define the partition doesn't have index indices for the clusters so
we can get rid of the indices by basically looking at the induced distribution
of partitions under this process and we can work out that that basically equals to
this quantity here where this thing is exactly the same as that and this term
here takes into account the fact that of the K clusters in the in the
the K clusters in our partition we have a we could have
lots of different ways in which we could label the clusters in the partition okay
and now if we take this quantity here and take big K to go to
infinity we'll get a proper distribution of a partitions where we don't limit ourselves
to at most K number of clusters okay and yes you take K go to infinity here
this probability of a function over partitions converges to the EPP F of Chinese restaurant
process so so that's it for the Chinese restaurant process we see that
it's actually important representation of the Dirichlet process and it turns out that of course is
also an important object of study in its own right mainly because it's such a
natural object for a clustering interestingly historically it actually predates the Dirichlet process and
it actually originated in genetics basically is related to a formula called Ewen's sampling
formula that came out in species sampling so imagine that you have a biologist which
who goes into a forest and then collects samples you know the first sample could
be a particular ant the next sample could be leaf or from a tree the
example could be an ant again an example could be a polar bear or
something alright so the idea is that this Chinese restaurant process is idealized process for
describing how the samples that the biologist collects are like clustered into the into
the different species there are lots on MCMC samplers using this Chinese restaurant process that's
a nice survey by Redford Neil that talks about this and of course the random partitions
that the Chinese restaurant process describes are again very useful concepts for clustering problems and
also some clustering problems in machine learning alright so we can have model based clustering we could
have clustering nodes of in graphs into different communities we can look at building others also
commutual structures from this partitions so if we have time we'll get to
look at hierarchical clusterings using concepts of fragmentation and computation of partitions okay so the
other representation that I'll talk about is the stick breaking construction and this also relates back
to the clustering property right so we know that when we have such a generative
process where G is DP distributed and each of the theta Is are IID G then the
same values can be repeated among the variables of theta one to theta N okay and this is only
possible if this G a random distribution is atomic okay atomic in the sense
that it's infinite possibly infinite sum of of atoms each atom being located at
some point part of the space and phi K is the probability that one of
the theta Is takes on that particular value and we already saw that our G distribution has to be
atomic when we looked at how we might draw from this from our Dirichlet process
okay so the question now is we know that draws from the Dirichlet process will
always be of this form where the phis are nonnegative and they have to sum
to one and the thetas are basically points in our probability space theta the question
in particular
we've got to compute the
the score of an alignment
in each position
again the linear function
instead of just having a number of here and summing over all the positions
we are allowing out have linear function that takes input sequence
and the alignment operations that position
we can tune the weight vectors to give us alignment score for each position
that includes also
insertion and deletion
and i know that there is no doing agenda estimation setting would be really really
hard because we would have to model dependencies between the feature vector which was
it seem to model
but it's not a problem in data set
so we fix the representation and we figured out to be argmax just and
the last thing that we have to
do specify loss function
and so
first guess might have
just count the number of incorrect
alignment operations for example the correct alignment like it would be
it was a year you the
this is the predicted alignment a is actually of here
and in the correct position
you would get a lot of what we
the possible one one
but actually the
bioinformatics collaborators told us that this is too hard
it doesn't really matter if you get it exactly right
together within window four that's good enough
from they can be local search probably pi
that's because q four loss function so if you just get you know
two amino acids you into the
to the correct when no one
and then again if you think about this a little bit then
separation oracle that you need to the cutting plane training
again you can do get
program exactly the same alignment
this again
so now we specify everything
we can just like that the cold and
look at a couple of weeks
this is the standard datasets
we train on
roughly five thousand non-aligned
validation of the five live to parameters
and then we block tests
we use
these features here i mean that the secondary structure of surface area
that's known for the structures and we use the predicted values used to stable
for the the new sequences
these are the results went through
representation and
the point that i want to make is
kind of unconventional gender training you would probably build models that have maybe thousand features
and we try to push it
actually come up with
you know
features that describe here triplets
describe window around the current location
putting it all the way to model that have around half a million
and if you look at the test performance higher is better
you actually benefit from building
the best
the best results we actually go
the most complex models
this allows us to
to build these models that
you just wouldn't be able to really train easy way with them
it's a comparison against existing methods
if you just do
the blast alignment that's not
what kind of these all sequences that are hard have no that
this is the
best results that we got picked on the validation
in this case is given by this equation here
so this is just like you can't matrix something to the main diagonal
in work that
multiply by observations
then you multiply by the
so this is just like kernel expansion is a computer plantations
so this part you can do
and this is what you have to do when your training new test point comes
if you do that
you get the green curve
depending on the value of x
like at different values he
now for the variance of this because i'm not always equally shore
for example for instance here have much darker there
we get different values for the variance
this is really integrating out parts of my prior
so this is the only deviation from what i told you so far
will usually have to the markov chain monte carlo whatever to really find out what
your posterior looks like
if everything is gaussians
you can actually integrate out things
the this is what your degree of uncertainty looks like
again it's the standard deviation
and what it means is here we're not seeing much darker
i'm becoming less errors
you have seen a lot of stuff
not much more certain
so the red line is the amount of uncertainty
and the green line is just the mean plus minus the uncertainty
we also see something interesting happening here
this is the boundary of the data
the uncertainty increases
so i'm not seeing anything over here
does anybody have an idea what this is really big problem for high dimensional data
used for high dimensional data it was things at the boundary
if you take an hour to number of points
very high dimensional spaces
depending on how you scale things they will all be almost equal distance from each
other and they will be all
on the surface of football
this particularly bad news
this means
you know we really uncertain pretty much everywhere
number this
these are fairly small scratch that in practice usually will be OK
just bear in mind that there is skeleton in the closet namely a very high
dimensional data you want to estimation
things like
turn really ugly
this put everything together the lookup is with actually generated by
and custom semantic noise and you can see my system it wasn't too bad
OK it wasn't really exact here but
given take it is actually very nice
try something else
so here instance have observed in it out and uncertainty just blows up
heteroskedastic relation
tongue twister
the idea is we make both the linear and quadratic term in y given x
so i think FA status in life
to be white and fluffy chicks
and y squared times y two fix
my fix cx is just look at the inappropriate between politics and y theta
the function of y
and we'll get the quadratic term
so that's my kernel
i mean that is make mean and variance simultaneously
now i'm going to use the representer theorem but there's a time interval problem was
that the remember in a state of santa theorem i said well this is all
really great
if y has finite cardinality
now obviously are
the finite cardinality
if you look at the spam
of this for all possible lies
just look at the first time here
six ix
so that they have only one x and all possible wise
what's the dimensionality of the space
if applied in all possible ways here
is infinite dimensional
the step three
one dimension
the world for infinity
who world full three dimensions
what's the two dimension
OK five people
well one dimension
was asleep
it must be the complement so it's
i think overall had like five percent of the hands raised some
if six
then look at all possible values of y remember this scale the number
take that
convex hull of all these
what's the dimensionality of the space
so who thinks it's one-dimensional
and one person
who thinks it's two dimensional
i have zero covariance and so we say that they are uncorrelated
and yet they are not independent so it doesn't it doesn't work both ways but
if two variables are independent they are necessarily uncorrelated
OK we can discuss later maybe some special cases where
the inverse of the converse is not true
OK so here is another thing to somehow give you a more intuitive picture of
what this concept of correlation is is all about here
are some scatterplots of two random variables x versus y
so this could make x can represent them the weight of a person and why
could represent the height of a persons and so what you see is that if
if x comes out higher than average in this plot here
then y also has a tendency to come out higher than average
and that's exactly what you mean by positive correlation
and for this particular plot the correlation coefficient was o point seven five
and you can see that if you if you stare back at this equivalence formula
for the covariance
you see them here
the covariance is the expectation value of x minus mu x
times y minus mu y i
so if x is bigger than its average in y also has a tendency to
be bigger than this average then this is going to be positive and similarly if
x is less than this average and that comes along with having y less than
its average in both terms would be negative and again the covariance would be positive
so that gives you some sort of intuitive explanation of what correlations are supposed to
be about
so here would be a case where the covariance is negative
next comes out higher-than-average why has the tendency to come out less than its average
as the correlation coefficient approaches one then the
the band here becomes narrower and similarly you can imagine that if rho was close
to minus one the band would be like that
whereas if rho is zero then you get to no
no tilt
it also here is a fairly low
value for the correlation coefficient
OK so one more point emphasizing that is that correlations are very complicated things to
deal with when you're talking about an error analysis and sometimes people will be doing
a big complicated analysis you're you're trying to to to defend and some guy in
the back of the room will say did you take into account correlations
and the way to answer this person's question is correlations between what and what sort
of correlation is always defined between
a pair of quantities
so so please keep that in mind says correlations it makes no sense to talk
about this global correlations between
large quantities many quantities unless you consider the pairwise correlations are always dealt with pairwise
OK now what i also have in the
overheads from yesterday are number of slides on error propagation and what i want to
do now is just to say what the problem is to show you the answer
and then to leave it to you to go look at these overheads
the basic idea is the following suppose you have some set of values that you
x one through x and so symbolically let me call that some vector x
and suppose you have the covariances for each pair
of those quantities and i can i can write that is the matrix right i
can see the i j
is the covariance of
x i and x j
and i would need to specify that for each each pair
OK now having done that now consider some function
of these quantities
y that i specify and the question is then what is the variance of this
and so
what you need to do the covariances of the individual x i
they were they can represent the the errors that the uncertainties if you will on
the exi and i've been from this function i want to know how do those
errors propagate into that function
so this is the kind of thing that i think you've probably seen at some level in
year undergraduate courses in some undergraduate lab practical
and so they probably give you several recipes for how to do that and so
what i would ask you to do in your own time is to look through
the way have done it here
and then to finally wind up the answer
so what the answer tells you is that you have to to construct derivatives of
the function and you you multiply those derivatives with elements of this
covariance matrix
OK so i believe that that and that's really where i wanted to get yesterday
it's already or were ten minutes into today so let me wrap up lecture one
and move on to lecture two
this works
so what i propose to do now for the next thirty five minutes
forty is to give you a brief catalogue of probability densities and
i will go through a number of them
very quickly and skipping several things that i've written on these overheads so you can
go back on your own time and read a number of the additional details but
these include binomial multinomial poisson uniform exponential lcmk squared co she learned are some of
the example uses in particle physics and we only look at maybe half of these
will only look at some of the information on each of them
so let me start with the binomial distribution in this one will discuss a little
more carefully
consider first
capital and large independent experiments called bernoulli trials now what bernoulli trial is is an
observation that has only two possible outcomes
so i could label those outcomes to say
success or failure
suppose that i have then an independent
bernoulli trials
and that the probability of success on any given one is some specified
constant p
so that will be a parameter that characterizes this probability law
and what i'm interested in finding is the probability to find small n successes
given a large n
independent bernoulli trials
so let's think about how you would work that out so
i've said
the bernoulli trials are independent and so therefore
if i consider some
number if i consider a specific outcome in a particular order for example success success
failure success failure
remember what we had from the definition of independent events it means that the probability
for the whole thing to happen is simply the product of the probabilities for the
individual events
that's what independence meant so therefore the probability to find the specific outcomes success success
failure success failure would simply be
p times p
so the the two probabilities for success times one minus p that's the probability for
times p times one minus p
and so if you just reordered the terms you see this is key
to the end power the small and which were that's the number of successes
times one minus p
raised to the power of the number of failures
OK so that's almost the answer but it's not quite the answer because what i
ask for is simply the total
number of successes being an idea i don't want to insist on what order they
come in i don't care on what were they become in so i simply have
are drawn here for n equals two it's something that we've seen before
namely if you want to send a zero
you send a one in the first compound the first degree of freedom is zero
and the second and if you want to send
they warn you send the opposite
we've all seen
but this is a very sensible thing to do when we look the binary detection
because when you use scheme like this
of course the thing that happens
yes we now
no that we should look at this in terms of
just looking at this line along here
because what we're really transmitting is a is a pilot tone so to speak which
is half in the middle here which sticks right here
plus something something that varies from that
so that when we
when we take out the pilot what we wind up with one-dimensional system instead of
a two dimensional system
which we used to call antipodal communication
and which
everybody with any sense cause centripetal communication even now
but in terms of this is the simplest case of the simplex code
so the simplex code is simply an orthogonal codes where you've taken the mean and
moved out and as soon as you remove the main from an orthogonal codes you
get with the rate of one degree of freedom because one of the signal becomes
dependent on the others which is exactly what's happened here you just
four you're signals are in one degree of freedom here when you do the same
thing down here
well you get this talk about that later
so one thing you can do from orthogonal code is good with simplex code the
other thing you can do
if you want to transmit one more bit
this signal said
just to go to by orthogonal code which says along with transmitting zero one then
one zero you look this news they say what i like what i also put
in zero minus one
n minus one zero
and zero minus one down here which is exactly what the buyer orthogonal code is
the prior orthogonal code simply said take your plugin all code and every time you
have one change one minus one and get an extra codeword out of it
what to do between the set of codewords in the signal set
anybody have any idea
absolutely not both exactly the same thing
and you
you think of it as being code usually if what you're doing is thinking of
generating an error correcting code and then from that error correcting code you think of
using QAM are PAMI something else out beyond that you call it signal said if
you're just doing the whole thing
as one unit what what a lot of systems now do
is they start out with the code then they turn this into an orthogonal signal
said OK
OK OK in other words the code produces bits
from the bits you group them together into sets of bits from the sets of
bits you go into a signal which is
which is for example something from one of these three possibilities here
the important thing to notice here that is particularly important to think about it for
a few minutes
it's because you do so many exercises
and you've done a number of them already and you will do a few more
in this course where you deal with the EMI equals two case
and you can deal with this by orthogonal set here
you can shift by orthogonal set around by forty five degrees
in which case it looks like this
OK so that looks like two PAAM says it looks like a standard QAM
it looks like standard for two way and
this is exactly the same as this of course
when you do detection on this
you do detection by first saying when you transmit this does the noise carry you
across that boundary
and then there's the noise carry across this boundary the noise in this direction is
orthogonal from noise in this direction
and therefore finding the probability of error is very very simple
because because you look at two
two separate orthogonal kinds of noise and you can just multiply these probabilities together
in the appropriate way to find out what's happening
the important thing that have stick in your memory now is it as soon as
you go there and make all three
life gets hard
in fact if you look at this orthogonal set here
and you try to find the heir probability for you try to find out exactly
you can't do it like this you can just multiply three terms you look at
these regions in three dimensional space
if you want to visualize what they are what do you do
what picture deal look at
you look at this picture
OK because this picture is just this with the mean taken away
so the air probability here is the same as the air probability here when i
send this point
the regions that i'm looking at
look like
and they're not orthogonal to each other
so to find the probability that this point gets outside of this region
let's just a little bit messy
and that happens for all and bigger than two
i never knew this because
well i think this is this is probably a disaster that happened more teachers and
the people working in the field
because so often i have explained to people
how these two-dimensional pictures work
but i just get used to thinking that this is an easy problem and in
fact when you start looking at the problem for equals three
and the problem gets much more interesting and much more useful and much more practical
when n becomes three or four five or six or seven or eight beyond data
becomes a little too hard to do
but up until their it's it's very easy
OK so we make use of that a little bit
so we said orthogonal codes and simplex because if you scale the simplex code from
the orthogonal code have exactly the same error probability
OK in other words
this code here where i made the distances between the points square root of two
over two which corresponds to the distance between the point here
this and this have exactly the same error probability
so you can in fact find their probability for this or for this whatever you
find easier
you know i think it's easier to find the their probability for this
i've let you down the primrose path because in fact this one it's easier to
find their probability for
this one again you can find their probability if you want
but the energy difference between this
and this
it's simply
is simply the added energy that you have to use here to send the mean
of these
the mother of all batteries
it was invented
by robert
from the graph
robert on the graph
he was a professor
prince princeton in nineteen twenty nine
when he designed
what we now call the van de graaf generator which generated
i think something like four five hundred thousand volts
and then he came to MIT in nineteen thirty one was professor here
he built here
then the graph generator
which can generate one and a half million
we have the super one year
it's not in the room
it generates six hundred thousand volts
we use it in february
but not in c
it's sick
two high
we have another one which is not bad
you see that here
and this one in the winter would easily generate three hundred thousand four hundred thousand
more like hundred fifty thousand four
very respectable number nevertheless
could this machine kills me
frankly speaking i am not sure
i have never tried
but of course we can bring that to test today
the first thing i want to do with this then the graph
it is to see whether we can draw any spark there we could only draw
over half a centimeter
here we have a much higher voltage
we can probably do
much better
so i'm going to first run this machine
and then i'm going to turn off
the lights
and then we'll see
it's always nice
spotlights don't want to go off this is not unusual at MIT
of oil you can look fantastic
i don't have to do much myself
so that's the thing so i'll actually left the tensile there
note stop
let's see
you see we can draw sports
even though we could only draw them there over a distance of about half a
this is more like
four five and so to stand suspension behind
so that's one thing
you can do
with the
then the graph
i wonder if i could some confetti on
public goods
what do you think what happens
you good alex what do you think anyone things that it will get
that may be like on the call
o would all go boom
think it will go boom o things it but also
immediately if they don't raise your hand
and all things that it may actually some of them may go off but some
may actually stick to it
just like in the mysterious way the balloons
well let's bring this to attest that shouldn't be too hard
so we going to put
some on it
whatever happens it will go fast
you ready
so really gone
other one word
we understand that no right because whatever the charges on the dome
negative or positive i don't know
whatever the charges
course these
pieces of
the air
the racial
thank you
he was
the three hundred
all right
what he heard
four of
o thing
and he
you get
and and
the whole world series that
and all
i the mean