it could be a collection of
you know i don't know batting averages of somebody rather it could be arbitrary collections
that you've come up with another ways before is again going to let you walk
through them so it doesn't have to be something that could be described
such as and wanted to to the previous element it could be any arbitrary collection
you have already use that again i just put it on your hand i could
go back and rewrite the thing that i had previously for finding the the the
the square root of the perfect squares just using the for loop
and i want to do that was go on to tertiary go back to
my advisor examples
conservative could try again i got to number one find the devices right now what
my code is doing is is printing for me
which is useful
but imagine i actually wanted to gather them together
i wanted to collect so i could do something with
one out of my mind multiplying together might want to do that know something else
with find common divisors of things by looking at them
i need in fact a way to make explicit what i can do that with
ranges i need a way to collect things together
and that's going to be the first of our more compound data structures and we
have exactly such a structure
it's called a tuple
this is an ordered sequence
now i'm going to actually add something to it it's gonna make sense in a
little while or couple lectures
which is it is immutable
meaning i cannot change it will see why that's important later on but for now
to pull
this ordered sequence of structures
and how do i create them
well the representation is
square brackets
followed by a sequence of elements separated by commas followed by close square brackets
that's really what i said it is an ordered sequence of elements
you can see where they are
OK so let me do a little example of this i go back over here
let's define
a type type
we can look at the value of test
in the ordered sequence
i need to get elements out of it
so again i have a way of doing that in particular
i can ask for
the zero element of test notice and putting square brackets around it
it gives me
i know this sounds confusing but this is a long tradition it gives me yes
so i
i created list here and thank you
and you guys are on top of your saying i want
OK so i
you can see why this was mistaken little well i did not want to make
a list i wanted to create a tuple thank you for catching and i want
my friends not square brackets there
also see well why both of these things work this way but is not what
i wanted
so i guess i should go back and let me do this correctly this way
you can look at test
i guess test now if only get the element notes
angle bracket are
we're broadcaster one square brackets what i thought OK
now can go back to where i was which is a strange piece of history
which is we start counting at zero
so the
hate sits with the first element of this to pull his position zero or index
zero OK so i can get the zero one out i can get
i do to get the third thing out because it was zero one two
notice however if i do
something that tries to go outside
the length of the two but complaints
two balls also have another nice structure which is i can go the other direction
which is if i want to get the last element
of the two people
i give it a negative index imagine you think about as starting right just before
the beginning of the thing
i give it to zero is going to take the first one of the other
one is going to take the next one but go the other direction if i
give it a minus one
except the last element of the two form
again i can go minus two
so this is what we would call selection
we can do things like ooh
get out
i can also pick up pieces
of the two people
you know i want to show you the format here if i
give it this strange expression
this is saying i want to get the pieces the tuple starting at index one
the the second element and going up to but not including index three
gives me back
that piece
actually copied that piece
the two people
this is called slicing
and just to complete this to other nice things you can do with slices
or you can get the beginning of the end
the two people
so for example if i say test and i don't give it to start to
give it
and then it gives me all the elements
up to
o point
and i can obviously do the other direction which is
i can say skip two
then the compound under these things
the idea is of course you can translate all the implications and things into the
the conjunction and disjunction and then you can drive negation inside everything else
so if you take you have
something of the form not a and b you can transform it into not a
or not be where the negation has been driven down inside
and you can keep doing that until the negations if if any
are of atoms
and that's
a useful
normal form
we can do more
we can insist for example
that's in this
formula in this form
the so-called and all graphs
for example all the
all the conjunctions are inside the disjunctions of experts the disjunction is inside the conjunctions
and that gives it a couple of other normal forms conjunctive normal form
disjunctive normal form
of which can
the most important for now
on form
a formula in conjunctive normal form
is a conjunction
possibly with several conjunction conjunction is associative commutative and so on so this is all
the to conjunction and each of the formula here
is the disjunction
and each of the formula here
an atom
or a negated atoms
OK and that's
useful normal form this is stated for propositional logic but it works for first order
logic as well you can have variables and things
in there
and in some ways you can get rid of the quantifiers are not going to
talk about that today i think peter baumgartner is going to talk about it later
in the week
this is
formula in this
can really be thought of as
equivalent to a set of
formulae can you can take these conjuncts here
and the only thing that matters about them is set
it doesn't matter what order they come in something like that
so you can think of the formulas having an equivalent
consisting of a set of these
primitive disjunctions
sort of conjoined clear certain
and so you can do the same again this set of primitive
this is this this is the disjunction here
because disjunction is also associative commutative idempotent all those things
this also you can think of it just as i said the only thing that
matters about it is the set of atoms and the set of negated atoms
so a convenient way to think about it in fact has two sets the positive
stuff and the negative stuff
and that's me two sets of atoms
ignoring the apparatus of quantifiers and variables for the moment just just thinking about propositional
we can represent
all formulae therefore
in that kind of form
i'm going to say
but this is this is
this is
quest quite important for
especially for automated reasoning
i'm going to say that the clause
a pair of sets
of app of atoms in atomic formulae
it's the pair
the college
positive and negative
of sets
of atomic formulae
so no no connectives in here at all just atoms
and we really thinking of it is the disjunction
OK with a with these things
negated in these things not negate
all right
we can think of any formula is equivalent to a set of clauses
OK the this one this one this one this one
and that's important for automated deduction because there's some
machine oriented reasoning that you can do unpleasant
what i mentioned that say i was talking about proof theory
well because i want to think about algorithm
an algorithm for taking any formula
or a set of formulae
and reducing it to close form
this is going to go through an ocean
the generalized clause
which is just going to be a pair
of sets
of formulae
not necessarily atoms
the idea is that this is the disjunction of some of the negated some of
them not negated
and we're going to reduce our
a formula we start with
well we can think of it as set of general general clauses generalized clauses and
we're going to reduce it to simpler and simpler ones until they eventually we have
so how does the algorithm goal
we've got the original formula a which has got all sorts of
connected and stuff in it
might have any arrows
corners and
other stuff in it
we think of that
as g clause
in which the positive set
just consists i
and the negative set
is empty
all right
and that's our first
so first state were well it's just that set
it consists of exactly one
this function is very curved
it's like this
then so that's high curvature
then you want to take a small step
and even low curvature then you want to take a big step and
you would
but it
you put the second derivative into this formula also
but computationally
second derivative methods very tricky
the second derivative can be
it can be difficult to compute it can be numerically unstable and it's got another
disadvantage that i'll mention in
a few minutes
look almost whatever method we want to use to
maximize conditional likelihood on training just to go question we need to compute this derivative
divide the data of the log conditional likelihood so
my now that's what i'm going to
evaluate and it turns out to have
it comes out to be a very elegant expressions which it comes out to be
something very similar for the general case of log linear models
OK so
i have my parameters
and they don't want
debated d
so now
first in the simplify
trying to
alpha equals
later zero
let x zero
equals one
for every
x far
the expression that i had was
alpha plus
some from i corps one
to die
jake was one the debated jxj
and so now this simplification that is going to be
some from j equals zero
to d
of beta jxj
i can
i don't have to tweak our first separately from the vedas i can just read
all the data is the same
so now
i want to evaluate
so dividing data
of the log conditional likelihood
for all j
like conditional likelihood
this the sum
i equals
one to n
the probability of why i given
x y
the they parameters
really clear why this is the log conditional likelihood
i'm going to separate these out into two parts
so the
such that y equals one
they are such that y i
equals zero
every training example
has a particular value for y i
and that particular value is going to be either zero or one
so i can just group the training examples according to the value of the y
and so
this will probably be one given x i
and then the probability is zero
x y
data OK
and the reason i'm doing this separation is that you know the formula for probably
is different from the formula for public of zero
so i'm going to treat these separately
by debated j
a lot conditional likelihood
so remember that the derivative of the some
it is the sum of the derivatives
this is
so some from my such that y equals one
by david j
so what i forgot to log in here
the likely the likelihood would be the product of the probabilities
and the log likelihood is the sum of the log probability
i need
to put in these locks
she formation
not sure what we
the company
to solve the problem
it's is
so this is the last twenty years not
the first is that the child child
so the notion of this
this is a
these are just
o control
could say
this is so
this small
interesting is also
can be elliptical
can you say
she which variety of
and most of this two
short scale so to
these are some of the system
so this
so that's the of the
it's one
the first is that the first
and also
the complexity
for instance
she was the first on
so far we consider for instance for it was
this is just to
two meetings of
precision which so you can't sell three three
when one thousand five
we use this information in is the first
even is that
in fact results from places such actually special
the solution is
three hundred of thousands of
this is
the this is because
this a
for some reason
and this is florida which is both
and the ricci as above plus the just pull it
the extent
so i guess
it was
this is the reason is that system
this is all
of course such
a lot of people
four thousand
this should be done
this is just
is a small just
we see some
he he
six months
obviously so any this image that is not the first to
in the previous
so you don't have to make it is
structure dawkins the construction which
that's what i want to write
this is one of the
the most complex structure in
although both sides of of the best business schools in my
she should shown
we see
so this part
the final decision function
this is in contrast to
and this is the
this is
at each
he was
so many of his friends
this is just one
and in order in which should
i wasn't sure what is the user right as
but some of this
six thousand range
four seconds or so for the
there no standard deviation the tree
and here is the username and things they
this is summary
so we allow these two
and will
on the
people who were in the image systems to make
he was
the tail
o two two one
average called precision
recall and precision
which is the calculated
call among first in the images and this is the first
if you want to
with the same
the measure
and another way to
this is called
and this
well call me
you have
the surrounding country
there and back to make
one of the major
as a user you've made some of the system and you
this is main
and they were correctly
so they try to
weight training
so this would be nation
and use it as a measure of
but in this system
it is how many times to
before you get the image
so many
the collection
there was a and you have to get the image so you provide some sketches
in which
and it turns some results which are in this case
just chat
what is one
we are looking for
this is the only it into where they might
you model
and the you use
this is the right to
you find the killer
so this is because when you have such that much
well know which one to use a so
before you find your image
and i
no natural images which divided by the images and this
so this
she also used for
should actually is
the name
precision and recall depending on the amount of retrieved images
graph where
is the classical precision
precision recall
so what's the point that you recall
and that it was
and all of them
it also
he examples
precision recall so
there are several layers
just a name
like the way
you can do it
you what
i was you
the reason recall so it should have the mop
the graph
the first is the more higher
and for this flow
we have
one of course where
and the second one
so called
number of image so
four this
the graph shows
and if you go to specific interests usually such
to measure the of
it's so about
OK so far too quickly
and to use this image actually has a query and they
see the position of
which is a
of course there was no we assume that this image is the first
if we had one
problem is this
well known
i want to be
the define measures
actually correspond to each
i could be seen
using different measures
so the first one
performance measure
percentage similar similar in
it was about
comparing with the brain
the fact
you can see according to what i want
you have a higher percentage of users
and this is one model the right answer for this
who makes it
the because this time
but the first
but the precision
for the same
what have actually
so you were because we can measure
the measure
during this is
for example
we have
all right
this is
the second one
two of
it is the first because all his right is the second one
in cancer already may not be in the right in the right class you are
still in six three three minutes you wondering what happened to the indian guy normally
lectures is sitting there
we're trading off lectures for the next director of the class do about the next
lectures up until spring break and hurried back to my sam and feel free to
address question of like me
so we're going to keep today we're going to be talking about this concept of
enforcing modularity we started talking about last time
so last time we saw how we can use this notion of the client service
model in order to separate two in order to separate i
that is separate to modules from each other so
the idea was that we could have we could by running the client service on
separate machines we can isolate these two things from each other so we can make
it so that the for example one the client wants to invoke some operation on
the server the server is can verify can verify the request that the claims made
to make sure that the client is asking to do something malicious
similarly we can
this is what we saw last time with client service model
and this has been the it's the other benefit the client service model was meant
that we can decouple the client from this from the surface so it meant that
when the client issued a request against the service it was possible for the it
didn't necessarily mean that the client service failed when the client issued the request it
wasn't necessarily the case the client would also fail so the server could my my
tracks excluding request and the client would get a timeout and would be able to
retry and similarly if the server fail if if the client failed the server could
continue handling requests on behalf of our clients that was and i separation the ability
to split the client from the the
so far apart from each other that there was that's a good thing
but the problem with this approach is that we had to have two separate machines
right away we presented this was the the client was running on one computer and
the server was running on another computer and this is a little bit if you
think about this this is this is exactly what we want right because i mean
suppose we want to build up a big complicated computer system is composed of multiple
at multiple different modules if we have to run each one of those modules on
a separate computer that's not really very ideal right it's going to mean if we
to build up a big service going a whole lot of computers and clearly that's
not the way the computer systems that we actually interact with work
so what we've seen so far is this notion we have a module
per computer
OK and we're going to do today is going to see how we can generalize
this instead of having one module per computer we can instead have multiple models running
with within a single computer but when we do that we still want to maintain
these nice spend these nice sort of protection benefits that we had between the client
service when these two things are running on separate computers
so the way they going to do that is by
do creating something we call it virtual computer so
we're we're going to do is we're going to create this notion of virtual multiple
virtual computers they're all running on one single computer and then we're going to run
each one of these models within a virtual computer
and i'll talk about more about what i mean by a virtual computer throughout the
next couple lectures but the idea is that virtual computer has this sort of see
exactly the same to to the two programs running on a virtual computer looks just
like one of these kind of server computers might have worked and in particular virtual
computer has the same sort of abstractions that we studied in the previous lectures available
to the real computer has so virtual computer has a virtual memory
and virtual processor
today we're talking about is this notion of virtual memory
and this virtual so you've already you guys have already probably seen the term virtual
memory and sixty four so the word should be familiar to you and we're gonna
use exactly the same abstraction
we used in sixty four so we're just going to show how this attraction can
be used to provide this protection between the client server that we want to things
we're also can introduce today this notion of something called the kernel
and the kernel is something that's in charge basically of managing all of these different
virtual computers they're running on our one physical computer so the kernel is going to
be the sort of system that knows about is going to be a piece of
the system that actually knows that there are multiple virtual computers running on the system
i want to start out by first just talk about why we wanna virtualized memory
why visualizing memory is a good thing so
abbreviate virtual memory SVM so
why would we want to virtual memory well so let's see what let's let's see
what might happen if we built a computer system with multiple models running on at
the same time that they didn't have a virtualized memory
so suppose we have some
and we have some memory
and within this memory
we have
the data for a a couple of the
code and data for a couple of different modules is stored the same model a
and model b
and this is the data that this is the things like the code
and the data that these models are using the currently executing so
in this environment suppose module a execute some instructions
so so so let's revisit this if you think this is memory let's say that
module a begins at to address a year and model b begins at address b
b here
suppose that model a execute some instruction like
and some value are one
in memory address be OK
so the model a rights into memory address b here so
and they're going to want this
i want them to know that if they get this it's going to be hard
and i want them when they finish negotiated with me and they squeezed out of
me i wanted to feel like they got this
i want them to feel like they work for it and was worth getting and
they can go back to the people say i couldn't have gotten
any more and that he that's how i start to get them angry so how
do you do that always services
these easy easy everyone
response exactly the same way so that don't listen to it
to go into the first meeting is an asset not shuffle some papers look around
make few notes taken by blackberry while the talk and send few smss you said
and maybe time alas now look back at celje i'm sorry
what we're saying
it to round three rounds about thank you said they just explode they leave the
room mission accomplished phase one phase two was started and and you know regardless of
what you subscribed to another here's the bottom line the
a single best way
to sap to suck out somebody self-esteem
to really get them angry is to deny them your attention
and on the other side of things our research said
that three of the most powerful things that you can do what you've been told
since day one in every book you ever read about leadership and that was for
god sakes list
and i don't mean
fake listening
i've done the courses you've done the courses i can fake listening better than anybody
i can turn on autopilot and say so what you mean is and that's what
her you know in fact the research says if you're if you if you want
to listen is different for a woman and the man but if you want to
convince the manual listening all you have to do
johann eugen make monkey sounds
so is that
the other technique where they talk about feeding back and also what you mean is
is more effective with females for reason i don't know but but is the point
the night people
nine people your full attention and they go not give them your full attention but
more importantly then be seen to act upon what they feed to you
we seem to do something about it take to feed back and do something about
it and you will raise their self-esteem and you raise your charisma with
forty six of the the behaviors are in there were in around the whole area
of simply listening to people actively soliciting their input
and then doing something about it is the least expensive motivation will ever get
thing is common courtesy who's who is one of the things we found in our
search dreadfully dreadfully missing in people when they became managers
when they became leaders they started to feel
that saying sorry saying please and say thank you should certain weakness
you know i wonder what your mind doing that for me please
and you get people say
we should i say please to get paid
to do it it's their job
you know why should i say thank you to get the thank you at the
end of each month OK to get thirty percent of the thank you at the
end of each month thirty five percent of why should i say sorry you should
say it because simple simple courses like
saying sorry saying please saying thank you
this is one of the critical one just being responsive
you get these emails from people
you don't have time to respond on one line that says i'm just up to
my neck right now
i will get back on this thanks
make some major major difference can
please and thank you
hold your tongue
this is just this is nothing this incomparable research this is a good old-fashioned dale
and it's just classic other side of listening stuff
it's just when you get into one of those heated situations where things get really
really bad and you just want to let them have full barrel of oil barrels
and you the boss so you can do even better than anybody else you stop
button just hold back
and that strength of character just hold back and currently used to say
right all down on a piece of paper put it in a drawer and go
back to the following day and see if you still want to say it one
on one communications the most important thing listening to the second one just showing some
positive regard for the people
public speaking did figure in this and we do that there are different there were
some of the behaviors were associated with that and i'm going to just touch really
really quickly on some of the things that you can do to improve your public
speaking when you stand in front of people this is not speaking course the first
one is look like a ten
now you know i have a mirror in my house
so i know i don't look like a ten i j jim sirbasku is called
himself short fat ugly little man i call myself medium height tall guy what kind
of beaky nose and thinning hair and and i know that i know that i'm
not of brad pitt or any those are the guys but when you go to
absolutely stunning electricity California in this problem all i so I'm not claiming that's most
general that this problem would fit every need no other actors have multiple sources and
sinks and make the problem more general but more difficult
true true true and had
yeah so could be phone calls it will but if that if you're calling 1
person in California then you're sending a packet here which can get split up in
different ways and gets in fact network
what contain he's doing that's taking your phone message splitting up in the packets sending
and cheap way
and of course it's and the other packets at the same time so there there's
another generalization we've got a bunch of different sourcing appears simultaneously trying to get there
a message through
and then there's was
and right yeah that's my network
yes right put together it whatever it is that network why isn't perfect because somebody
paid extra for this paper extra capacity that can be used at all yeah that's
right but actually in reality that happens all the time right of menu pipeline is
built from from Morocco to through Turkey wherever it adds more capacity will then it
turns out that that maybe you know they got excess capacity but the
minimal cut is what's determining how much slow gets you know from the oil fields
to the refinery here and I could add a cost per node to 2 2
goes through that node 0 you can imagine that I as long as stage linear
and I can make these things for general here so I mean this is a
really good discussion and this is the model problem but
but if we think about natural ways to make it closer and closer to reality
we still stay with
we still stay with this linear programming framework
we can we can get a lot as well in a way that I have
decided that multipurpose
you know so optimizing from multiple users there that's that is really a different problem
you know however if I'm optimizing if I'm choosing the axes that optimizes some function
for several purposes of optimize several functions at once in some way so that that
there are
caring and you know that a by the way game series
it is another example of linear programming and 1 and discovered that slightly before
of linear programming we discovered that almost the same time and people in the 1st
years even when alignment didn't instantly know and he is willing to every other that
it was the same
and you have to do you remember the name of the fundamentals what I could
talk about game theory I mean excitement you wanted among other problems but the fundamental
duality there is called the minimax theorem there's a minimax equals the maximum
in the in the world of game theory proved by 1 on the minimax theorem
the minimum of the maximum of something is the maximum of the minimum of some
and the end to end the two-person game theory that 1 alignment was
that would match linear so that would match a linear program I could think
this is probably not means
yeah well yeah like well
the answer is yes there's a duality and nonlinear programs
there is but to tell you what that if you tell me 1 of the
functions to tell you what the other is
it's going to take next week to do it but it's not just like UCI
I I came up with the dual problem out of the blue really and but
it wasn't totally out of the blue there was a there was a method there
that could apply a nonlinear cases but not obvious
anyway Game Theory two-person game theory would fit this
set up and so the minimax theorem is that is the duality theory 3 per
cent gain
you know that's what John Nash won the Nobel Prize for
the wrote a thesis so I didn't mention the other key names that this optimality
condition is associated with Conan talk and now written down the Greek names in this
and then at John Nash who were
rodents PhD thesis at Princeton under Tucker to everybody's surprise Nash was real character of
you you know this book the beautiful a beautiful mind about John match through its
it may become a movie also movies movie rights have been bought purchase of its
by Sylvia Nasar are and it was on the best seller systems a biography of
john nash called a Beautiful Mind along
so he won the Nobel Prize in a few years ago
but his life was a track tragic story so well he was brilliant and actually
for most mathematicians for all mathematicians that this is what you get that his PhD
thesis that he got the nobel prize for was not in any way that most
deepened difficult work he did he went on
effects in a high dimensional analysis
and then schizophrenia but took over so we had many many years when he was
1st around the MIT math department in and around the longest time around the Princeton
math department but really out of that
communication with people and was difficult and then incredibly and recovered so he gave a
lecture at MIT a few weeks ago in fact which worry had a standing-room-only audience
so far we have not seen any ground
later we will see the connection of these graph
so the key message
the key messages that
when we introduce conditional independencies
we generate factorizations of the
think you've learned is met
the question is is this useful for
remember of tasks for four questions for complex
joint distribution
the to have conditioning as well if they have condition independence they will be able
to be factorized in some way
is useful for
well let's investigate
let's see an example
so we want to compute the marginalisation for p of x you we need to
sum over x one x three of these
so that
now if we don't have a position what's the complexity of
it's just exponential the
the basis of every one of them because they need to search through all possible
entries on this table
if i assume that i'm assuming just for simplicity have
a discrete state space forever by
so that that's the order of the size of the first that space second that
all of them equal clinical equal to us
we have something SQL
now let's assume that we have a position
the same expression here
but instead we have the fact position as mentioned previously
these functionalities factorize into three pieces
we have following
this is key operation that we're going to
learning the first part of course
the session is the distributive law
i have some of to violence
and here i have some fun
all i
these factors
x two x three
the next three
these problems
o is constant with respect
to this summation in x y
if i'm something of x one these entire that musicals
so what i am
if i have a
the quality
only black
i have
plus a c that's exactly what happens i have a form factor
in the summer
the fact
p of x given xt you fixed it is common to all the elements of
the sum over x y
so how can i write this one
i can write this quantity as a
multiplying the policy
this is called the distributive law
he had three operations these operations
and these two problems have three free
you have only two or three
his brother and this up
so by going from here to here again
so let's do do the same
let's put in evidence these facts
let's put it outside
of these sums
that's what i pull this factor outside of the some x
then i saw this on how much is this
o thing in
because you want
how much is here
which is summing over all the values of x y
the probability function is the function
if the probability function fx
six x two
how much it is
this is just one right because this is
pretty close estimation
when we use the estimation of initial way
you need less iterations
if are using
presentation of which run as i said this is again vector of all matrix
you can
look at this metrics i don't know how like this
sheet of paper
and this is our
of course this again vector will be some normal vector to the sheet of paper
so our
metric in this space
because we did some small number of changes to update
usually change not a lot so we don't need to move this vector significantly
and because of this we can assume that our previous israeli of this vector is
very good estimation
actually using previous israeli of pagerank one exposure to reduce number of collisions significant
another thing that we can do
try to apply some fertilization
so we can try to distribute calculation of our plagiarized
or a number of boxes
in OWL class
so how can we do this
and we can do this using this
first of all we decided that
our source while our compressed segmentation of matrix is pretty small
so we can
fits it's
in two
we can see that in tour
every box
also we can
will the things that these results
result of previous iteration
is always not so the and we have enough
the capacity of our network
i mean this exchange
to call the results of previous iterations all boxes
the simplest approach again but what we are doing here
do some iteration
every box now
has some part of pagerank some new results in part of measuring
then the doing some exchange between boxes so not all boxes again
i have the full presentation of metrics and the whole of the whole data the
previous iteration now they everybody in calculating some part
for some some part of this
o this page i'm can be doing this is changing again
there are a number of much more sophisticated algorithms how to implement this but this
very simple and naive approach usually works well
and of course we can we can do a lot of different
much more sophisticated algorithms that are based on this
idea that our matrix is not only very far
but actually the density of this matrix is not uniform
usually they have some
lots of internet graph where they have a lot of links
and some
well they have
or don't have anything activity between them
so what we can do
we can divide our metrics into this part
calculate separate radius
you understand that if you have a lot of links to have a lot of
exchange between all of them
what if we don't have links sexually one way
so we can all we can do this calculation
and then provide to the rest of the matrix metrics only one way to
that's it
but it's much more complex approach there are a number of articles people try to
optimize you trying to find this this
blocks of
a lot of internal links in the graph
actually they can increase speed of this calculation significantly
but as ordinary
when the main aim of those was that they would act as a very good
classifier when we want to distinguish between the classes like
that's the person read
evening news yes or no
and we should provide such a classification as accurate as possible also we decision trees
that's say that somebody read and then yes or no so then we want to
optimize the classification accuracy of such an induced models
here we are not optimizing accuracy because actually our data can be such that we
don't even
this thing is that our goal is not even distinguishing between the classes but just
find some interesting associations are between the items
so here we evaluate ruled by its support and confidence measure it is the conditional
probability that
x and y called jointly and the confidence is the
the conditional
the probability of y
given x
and we evaluated by the number of samples for which
x and y is true at the same time and well if we compute this
probability by the relative frequency computed from the data set it is the number of
instances for which x called the black holes divided by the number of items it
by the number by the popular the entire population
whereas here the confidence would be the conditional probability of y given x which would
be the support of x y divided by the support of x itself so let's
see some this association rules let's and
discovered association rule would be if somebody reads love stories magazine then
the first slovenian use surprising slovenian scan of it
support would be a comma five
which means we come of five of the whole percent of the code
the population reason both
a love story magazine and can lead and confidence is
sixty one percent which means sixty one percent of those reading love stories magazine thirty
it's also slow things can be to which is an interesting piece of information
let's look at another association rules here we are simplifying the form of association rules
in such a way that we have just one item in the condition
and one item in the conclusion because we have decided so
but in general we could have a conjunction of items in the condition and the
conjunction of items in the conclusion
so well known example of
which i don't have here well-known example of association rules would be let's say somebody
buys beer and coke in the magazine then he also buys
so this was funny finding and then people who analyse
people buying habits would then put all these things in the store together so that
let's say whenever you go in liberia also grab peanuts and then that's how people
organised the magazines having fun such association rules
trying to analyse the buying habits of people
so for instance this was interesting we were trying to find the readers of the
based on the pro or other eating habits and we could find that people do
law if they also read marketing magazine if they read financial news
so prof in
if they read the views money and VIP
and all these rules have quite strong support and confidence so what we could interpreted
this set of rules like most readers of marketing magazine financial news
he was money and the power also readers of the
and that's that was pretty interesting for the media not
is doing this is to this
information when
you can always transform the decision tree into a set of classification rules
vice versa is a bit more tricky
with fantastic precision
experimenters hoped to get nobel prizes for finding deviations from this and they try to
do it for decades now
but really haven't
well maybe there's an exception here one
so we should do so the nature has spoken this is a large part of
the truth about fundamental action interactions in nature
so we should take this very seriously
and in particular take its aesthetic flaws remain very seriously
and if we by the highest aesthetic standards clearly something is missing here
we have
partial symmetry
things fall apart into unrelated groups here five different unrelated groups are also three families
that's another story
three different symmetries that are unconnected
in recent years we've learned that the standard model also gives a rather lame account
of neutrino masses that have been discovered
so we want to do something better
this a great idea for doing something better that is
all these theories of QCD
QED which of which is the vast generalisation and the weak interactions are based on
cemeteries among color charge is called gauge symmetry
what's suggested is to consider
just making a bigger symmetry of want all those images would be
and if you do that you for find things really click into place very beautifully
there are a number of ways to do it but probably the most beautiful is
based on the group so ten
you to know anything about ten and it's been representation you have to know anything
about that either
but what i want to convey here
and i'm not kidding
is that if you
look at that extended symmetry now among five different colours
you can find all the particles that used to be in scattered multiplets
come together all of them can be transformed into one another by the symmetries of
by larger cemeteries so their one indivisible unit like the different sides of the dye
four of an icosahedron
and for all the different possibilities occur
according to the group theory
this charge assignments that are plus or minus the half you
of these different five different color
all all possible combinations of
charges occur subject just to the limitation of the number of positive charges is even
so this gives a much more coherent account of why the standard model is the
way it is
why the particles we see are what they are
if we didn't know
the properties are names of these particles over here
in advance
just from knowing
mathematical characterizations
we would be able to reconstruct most of what we know in fact from
hundreds of years of experiments about these particles and the foundations of physics
furthermore those funny numbers those charges also come out
not unrelated
not independent of the strong and weak charges but a certain function of them
which again
arbitrary but dictated by the overall symmetry in the theory
so it seems to be a very good idea
take the standard model seriously and if you do it cries out for
a large amount of symmetry
like this
but there's a big flying the alignment apparently
that is this the reason that the weak interactions are called weak compared to the
strong interactions
and y atoms are much bigger than nuclei
it's because the different interactions have different powers the strong interaction really is much stronger
than electromagnetism that's why pulls quarks together whereas atoms can nuclei whereas atoms can be
much bigger
because they don't feel strong interaction electromagnetism and the weak interaction is turns out fundamentally
kind of in between
whereas complete symmetry
would require that all these interactions have exactly the same strength
as a matter of fact
from experiment
our dreams of symmetry seem to be disappointed
in the first
but we remind you
one of the main
lessons we learned from the standard model
from QCD in particular
is that the strength of interaction you see depends on where you look at in
particular what distance you look
so by taking that very same kind of calculation
which as we see is
was brilliantly
validated by experiment
and extrapolating it
to higher energies
we can see
if the primary interactions which is supposed to be at smaller distances
are you could be equal even though the interactions we measure small and large distances
because of the distorting effects of these clouds the build up might be unequal
and again with the stroke of the pen we can extend those calculations the so-called
renormalisation group calculation to see if you see what happens smaller distance
and if we do that using just the particles that are actually in the standard
we find that it almost works but not quite
this calculation of
how the
strong coupling there is this is actually the same graph is what i showed
just now
in different in different format is the inverse coupling that's plotted so actually increases with
and it's a logarithmic scale so the running becomes approximately logarithmic of the inverse coupling
if that's but it's the same calculation
and the same results
then we can also do this a similar thing for the weak interactions and the
basically electromagnetism
and we find that
with the uncertainties that we have from experiment which are indicated by the width of
these lines
down low energies
the extrapolation almost but not work quite work we don't quite find unification
due to
so what you get
all only other
document as one of the carbon chain
and then you count the occurrence of
so in that large
that large objects that you have
well actually you don't
of feature will take into account
this is to compute its conditional probability you counts the number of occurrences of that
normalized by the number of occurrences of the term
the class
you might want you would like to to
because of two
my occur in an object
class labels
and when you
so you can actually if you if it's not very clear there
you have not been made
if you want
and then
that that which you have to classify
you expect
the features of the tokens from that that i think that
and then for each class
you compute the probability that your that example belongs to class
so your computer core which is composed of a lot of the prior
but you have computed the
like a lot of this problem for each you also have the score
i look it from the conditional probability of that
and then
the core that maximize
the probability of class
three days
he with told quality that compared
the two models
here we take the multinomial model
we take into account multiple occurrences of the features which we do not individually
you want you have life completed
if you
do not remove stop words
and you
classified documents can be bought
the work that might talk
probably occurs
every document
so you have a probability of one the
close to one
the multinomial model
and i said to find the key probably let's use case one
classic my
that you have seen
or you could go on
some threshold
although this is made more difficult because the disadvantage of this method
that actually have to me
are not very accurate they
if you have many many pages with
two of
probability become very small you come close
and if you
the winning comes close to one of the probability
when expressed in the field robert e
let i call it we can go
otherwise may
classification which quite well
in natural language processing is much the maximum entropy
one might models
and i going to talk about the maximum entropy really
so we tried to
so we have to
because of the two
you choose the one with maximum like and
and this is used
logical implication is logical consequence
a couple of lemmas that's a
look at the relationship had a world between implication
and logical consequence
so what this is saying is that
a world makes
five true
and the world makes five splice site
in the world has to make site through
that's exactly the reasoning that we used here
if the world makes
an implication true and it makes the antecedent true
and it has to make the consequent true we got a contradiction here because of
the the set up
so what it's saying is that
something like
you know
phi and phi life cycle gives you cited works at world
you can use your classical stable it's all the same
then for any model
all of the members of phi and phi implies sire true everywhere
in size true everywhere
now i'm shifting all i'm doing on keeping these guys say
but i'm replacing the world the model
why is that well
what this says he's five string everywhere
five splice sites straight away
if that's the case then go to a particular well and you will be able
to do this step and you will be able to get the size throughout the
and this guy just this side through everywhere
beginning world you like and you can do that recently
part of the deduction
one half of the deduction theorem says
five implies
site so whenever
gamma is true everywhere
find size true everywhere
that holds
they in
size the logical consequence of these guys
so what's the same is you've got to model
and suppose gamma is true everywhere
and whenever you have that phi implies size to everywhere
that's your model that
now you say
suppose that you go to a model whereby bias gamma and phi is true everywhere
to you pick
sub model here
and you say well five true everywhere as well
well then size going to be true in a small part one
what this is is that the implication
is true everywhere so at this at all of these points in fact everywhere we
know that the implication holds
and then at this point the implication gets fired
and concise i becomes true
so one half deduction theorem says you can move
the phi across the our across this
it turns out to the left
i can't do it the other way
that's the point of this slide
in normal classical logic what you can do is you can also
go that way
but the modal logic fails
we know that
box p nor is a logical consequence of p
i wrote that i can remember one of the first examples i showed you was
box p nor is a logical consequence of p no
box p nor was the logical consequence of p know why
if the model makes p true everywhere
in any particular world the successes of the world may be not true right so
that's going to be true
but i claim that
you can't
i'm sitting here
and if i wanted to go up here i would move the phi across
so what i want to do
it is
i want to ask this question
we know that tells
does this whole you know which is true in any model
it's not the case because look take model
let's try and falsified his
how do we force flight find we make this tremendous falls
so we take a world
p is true
and box pino is false
can we do that well this is
it's not the case that every successor makes or true
all we have is the successor that makes peano false
we hope
so we were able to falsify this
there was a model
which made this falls
the claim is
if this is going to be
logical consequence if this is going to be of validity
then no model should do that and we were able to construct models
so this whole
but you can't take it across the implication
and here is a form of the deduction theorem but it's more complicated it's is
sort of this form
it says
if ci is a logical consequence of gamma com five
so in other words whenever
gamma com five true everywhere size true everywhere
if that hold
for some finite in which you can compute
the model that may gamma true make this implication true
and the implication is
five with no boxes in front of the phi with one box in front of
the phi with two box in front of up to
five million boxes in front
and that has to apply some
if you want to know how to compute in
look at the book by marcus krug in your
which is you know the
and i just don't have time to go
go into the details
well i want to say is the normal deduction theorem in which holds for classical
logic says whenever you have you whenever you have this you have this and whenever
you have this you have this
doesn't hold for modal logic one direction hold
this direction breaks down
that's the country
four to simple there are many
where am i
this is
end of lecture
the first lecture case a little bit of
started by defining formulae
i define what logical consequence was
and i showed you some properties of logical consequence
how did i do it well
the formula was just using this park is now four right this
specifies how formulaic construct
and i said that the models
logic consists of graphs which are framed
w are
and then
paid we have a valuation
so that's just w and evaluation at each world that's what the model looks like
sixty seven
was proposed by bregman
and he proposed that in order to solve this optimisation problem you would they have
this effect distance bregman divergence and you have not only one equation but you have
several equality equations
equality constraints so like one constraint for every hypothesis
then you do the following so you start off with the
initially the you project to the first half plane
OK then the project to the second half plane try to draw the somehow then
you choose another hyperplane and so on this converges to the
o point which is on the intersection of all hyperplanes
and which is closest to the to the original point in that metric
OK just go on protecting these things and then converges
that's what collaboration leveraging stream but due to me this completely equivalent to the according
to send is just a different view on
the problem the problem is just this one so this is the common properties
and he did according to sit in this function g is the convex conjugate function
to this calligraphy she
so it was
of the c
the difference
so you want
the only
less than five hundred one of the most
why is that
of those are the only
this is for
there's no no
these sites
and a
well these days
to know how
so all
the other stuff all
and also
he is
he was
i have in mind
national of
by so
o five
o thing
a that's all
little methods interior point methods
and well so we can simply apply this to this problem
so now the problem is that the number of hypotheses can be very large or
even infinite so and house boosting solving this task so how is this related to
to these methods
so i'm claiming this is very much related to very optimisation can introduce very optimisation
so the idea of very optimisation is that you
then you have to solve this optimisation problem so minimize g with respect to to
constraints and constraints in terms of peter which are greater than zero for instance
then you are minimizing so this a constrained optimization problem then the idea is to
minimize a unconstrained optimization problems they minimalist your feet plus
which depends on c
of theta
and here we have this function cup beta
that's very function k
and that has the idea that pushes away this these CNC away from zero so
it should not pass zero so essentially it might be having the shape so everything
which is on this site is not satisfying the constraint and everything on this i
said find the constraint it has maybe this shape so it could be for instance
the log function or something
and posting it's actually the exponential function so
so this is one way so there's a lot of area this leads to interior
point method
and i'm showing you the this function here so this beta
e to the minus t over beta this exponential very and this leads to boosting
OK so the idea is that you let peter go to zero
OK and for every beta you minimize this EP to
then as you let people go beta to zero this converges to the optimal parameter
in the optimal solution is one
so solving this optimisation problem with a prolific speed it's just normal gradient i mean
you can use the normal gradient method
because this is just an unconstrained optimization problem OK
and idea is that you solve this for fixed beta
then decrease peter and start the previous solution that you need to the live this
OK and the new arrive at the optimal solution
OK so
let's do this flower maxmargin margin
so we would like to just rewrite the max margin problem in that way OK
so we would like to minimize
minus role so much maestro and such that the margin of the end for example
is greater than wrote that means
rho n minus role quickly because you
OK in the
barrier function just looks like this i put in the
objective here and this is the sea and i just put this into in here
OK now let's
use the exponential barrier for the function
this is this one here
OK so i just plugged in the the barrier function
to to do this very low level correction
and then of course every experiment every biological experiments different the difficulty of comparing different
measurement for you to see measurement again you get different results and how
do you make these results
so there are few other techniques like you if you are which is a hundred
quantitative polymerase chain reaction very accurate for measuring inflation mps page we can look up
on wikipedia
OK so you can also measure the expression of proteins and metabolites points in what
you see here years to the
feel like races so where you separate proteins in two directions according to one two
properties like size and maybe
whatever sort of the property and then you see the point that i concentration of
these proteins you can then have a look at more detail either you know which
could and should be there
or even if you don't know then you can analyse with the last thing try
and put which proteins are really
so in the end we get a metric which is has size i mean you
analyse different temple you look at large number of different genes
so what you would like to see it
which points to have a certain
maybe when you're having a look at the disease sample points in the people with
the disease you would expect that certain genes are one and you will be able
to identify the here
so for example
you see that gene
are all next year when he was used some clustering techniques to find out which
are the groups in
while which genes are really charming
so this also three d structure mentioned
essentially what we have there is that what we get is the three d structure
of every atom in the protein
and if you know the protein structure then we can we can try to infer
the function of the protein
so there are two basic techniques one and on
and one in x-ray crystallography this one is better for small molecules and this one
much more difficult only works for those proteins which in this life
but you can also do what i i
so then you been that protein interactions
and there are several ways of measuring these interactions i want to go into detail
i some people being already so
the main idea is that you consider one protein and then you try to find
out where the protein which parts of the protein in that case i mean to
either DNA or you can fish out of water
that's fine too
this is good for transcriptional regulation and four on a processing regulation of the full
OK so so there are many other data types available protein DNA actually subsidies localization
protein sequence itself we can sequences but but but but
protein modifications by mass spectrometry
mass spectrometry military
and also i who was winning which is usually used in some statistics
many more data exist and they actually the
mean the techniques for generating new data
constantly being invented
so why should we have a look at the data set
first of all most these techniques are not
o three i mean because money right so and if you can find prediction to
replace measurement
then i mean based on other
then of course there's a lot of money
so this is to a quite so if the
the second if people
model because able to model data said well then we can based on these models
also try to understand biology
i mean so you can point since try to reconstruct the whole underlying the biological
OK so based on
eight analysis as you can also try to reconstruct the past twenty
what when you analyse genome you can try to infer how have these genomes evolve
so we construct like evolution
and of course we would like to predict the future so for instance we would
like to to predict whether a certain compound which is used for treatment of the
disease but this is going to be
useful for treating this disease or whether it's interfering with other
proteins which it shouldn't interfere with and so on
and of course
maybe also try to improve organism point and this is what people
with the only thing that appear
so there are lots of different specialized problems
so for instance find structure which is stored somehow nineteen eighty four predict properties of
proteins or relate molecular with microscopic they that what be data and i mentioned that
one of the problems by image analysis measurement normalisation sequence processing and so on
i just give you a few more examples here for instance fact finding structure and
DNA that could be we have just the sequence
and now compare
several people
we can see that the evolutionary history
we find rearrangement and application between several of the whole population
you can also try to reconstruct the phylogeny of species we can try to find
out how one species is related to another of how close are the
we can both trees and so on
on the other hand you can try to find genes and i'm going to talk
about what the result is the gene structure
one part of what
trying to then transcriptional regulation
when certain genes which on the edge of the measurement data with the expression measurements
and give the conditions very much of the data and then you can try to
relate the sequence
the UK
the expression pattern and try to predict the expression than just
and the same you can identify life-sized identify coding sequences
you can identify items despising what i mentioned so when this intron spliced out winners
by in one there's a lot of the machinery of
you can also predict protein properties
pencil the direction of the current
so now
he put around the solenoid
a look
let's call this the number two
it was around the solenoid
and that's called this number one
o which the solenoid is part
when i was the current number one
he never managed to see the current number two
if there is a current going number one that is the magnetic fields
and the metrics needed field is seen of course by
the conductor number two by that look
never any
so he concluded that a steady magnetic fields
as produced by
the solenoid
circuit one does not produce
the steady current
in number two
but then one day
you notice
but as he
close to switch
these are current number two
open to switch
again he saw current number two
and therefore he now concluded
changing magnetic fields
is causing
the current not a steady magnetic field but the changing magnetic field
and this was the profound discovery
which changed our world
and it contributed largely
two technological
of the late nineteenth and early twentieth century
the current
therefore an electric field can be produced by changing
the magnetic field
and that phenomenon is called
electromagnetic induction
and and that phenomenon
runs our economy as you will see
in the next
few lectures
i have here a conducting wire
i could have chosen any other shape
try to make you see three-dimensional
and i approached this
conducting wire
was obama by magnets
as a magnetic field
running like so
as i approach that
that conducting wire
moving the bar magnet that's essential i can hold it still have to move it
if i come down from above and i moved it down
we're going to see your current going
this look
and that current
go into such direction
that it opposes
the change of the magnetic fields
the magnetic field is in down direction and it is increasing as i move the
bar magnet in then this current loop
it will produce a magnetic field
which is in this direction and when you look from below
currently go clockwise
producing a
magnetic field in this direction
if you move the bar magnet out
then the magnetic
field is
going down here
then the current will reverse
the current
he wants to oppose the change
in the magnetic field
and that's called lens law
it is the most human law in physics
because this inertia in all of us
o fight change at some level
lenses law
is extremely powerful in always determining in which direction
these induced currents
i will
it is not a quantitative law
you cannot calculate
how strong the current will be
but it's very useful as you will see today
the direction
of that current
get you out of all kinds of problems
with minus signs
i now want to do demonstration
which is very much like
what you see here
i have here
a look
that is discredit you see there except
that's not one loop
but as many of them
hundreds doesn't matter
and what we're going to show you
and and near
that is connected sort is somewhere in the circuit in and here
however by making it
and i'm going to approach
this conducting look
to bring together actually
very interesting work has been going on in more probability pascal probabilities into learning theory
so there's been
a lot of study of the behavior of distributions
and in particular when they are so-called concentrated
this has become seen as and very shown to be very relevant in
trying to analyse learning systems in this statistical learning framework so i want to give
you a flavor that and in particular the
the main sort of gold today is to be true to rademacher complexity
which i think has
once you get the hang of it is actually law
easier to work with
and potentially i think something that people might pick up and use in particular
applications in and analysis is so i'm hoping to give you a sort of if
you like user's guide to how to apply the rademacher complexity in the hope that
you might find this useful
but i think also
i believe you know some of the things we saw yesterday i think you'll enjoy
some of the ideas and techniques that have been developed to you to apply these
ideas in learning so hopefully you know will be there will be some fun to
be had on the way
maybe some applications that you might make this stuff later
and of course you know you you get a few more words into your vocabulary
that can
use this cocktail party so OK so
if we're looking at statistical learning is concerned with reliability and stability of inferences made
from a random sample that's sort of where we started yesterday and if you remember
those this
distribution functions like plotted when looking at the size of the sample for learning parzen
windows and how they sort of started very very concentrated very tight and then as
i took a smaller and smaller sample a sort of got more and more sloppy
in the way they behaved and eventually you know became very unreliable to infer anything
concentration is precisely that property of having a distribution that is concentrated in the sense
focused around the mean
of distribution
and this is said to have been the subject of study for
as you know very classical result actually is of her thing is exactly of this
type so i wanted to just briefly remind you of that if all you know
show you it if you're not familiar with it and it leads very nicely into
into the sort of
next perhaps slightly more advanced concentration inequality that i'd like to show you but his
her things results it relates to
the mean of
a set of random variables x one it
up two x and which are assumed to be independent which i failed to put
on this slide but
if you go to pan right independent down there
basically the assumption about the variables is really quite we call we assume is that
they are are bounded within range AI two by each independent i mean the different
it does not seem to be the same identical in that sense of the independent
but not necessarily identical
and the inequality bounds the
the probability that the particular
instantiation of this random variable as a
so in order to compute and we pick a random x one
random x two to random access we add them up and we die by and
we get about so imagine
you know one possibility would be you've got a sort of
a one-dimensional input and you just computing its mean so you've taken and dimensional sample
and compute the mean and
that's that's sn for you OK and what this is trying to do is compute
the probability
that means in particular
is significantly different from its expected value
so in those
plots i showed you if you remember i had the mean is a little circle
and then the distribution so this is precisely computing the probability
but you can have samples significantly deviated from that circle
and what this is saying is that the probability of being greater than or equal
to epsilon is less than or equal to some
exponentially decaying function
and notice that the exponential decay
depends on epsilon so
as epsilon goes away were going to get
it's more and smaller values
m squared now that m squared actually is a bit deceptive because there's some two
and on the bottom here
so if you imagine these all being the same when you get this some equal
to m time some constants
one of the ends will cancel but they still being among the top here so
as the sample size increases it's going to shrink the the range of that display
in the in the distribution and it's coming gonna become concentrated around that the
so that that's the sort of flavor that we're looking for
exponential decay away from the mean of the distribution
OK so
with that flavour let's move to
how concentration can help
statistical learning theory
and the results come from what are known as concentration inequalities again as a really
good phrase to use i thought about the concentration inequality
conjugate gradients are completely hopeless
with stochastic approximation never tried to do that it's just
can't work
the other algorithms typically what happens is that too expensive so they mark court for
instance order in q
you don't want to run an audi q algorithms
on so little evidence you just have sort of a little patch of current data
and you don't really want to do this
brings heavy machinery to bear on this data because the minimum that you'll find will
be a different one
every time depending on which data you happen to have
and it's very costly
it's very expensive
so those algorithms pretty much out of the question
and now
what we're left with is basically no simple methods and then things like common field
use it as a generic term for these sort of second order
online maximum likelihood methods from signal processing
those work they explicitly incorporate a model of the stochastic nature of the data
but they typically make strong assumptions about what the nature of the data is
so if you actual data violates these assumptions they don't work anymore
so if you if you have a good knowledge of how you data looks like
this may be the way to go
however these things are ordained square
and so if you and gets big if you parameter space gets gets very large
then you can't use it either
and so then you just left with those two
and now finally
i explained why i do the research and doing
if you set it up just right if you set up your problem just right
then this is the best thing on earth
and what i'm working on is trying to make this
converge faster
so one key problem that you have
with first order
gradient descent
is that it can be very very slow
it can take many iterations to converge
actually i think i have that picture later so
i'll show you later why exactly so what i'm working on is is methods to
to speed that up
OK here this is actually the same thing in words
particular conjugate directions break down so this is the reason there's no technical reason why
conjugate gradient methods don't work
with stochastic approximation
the other ones are just simply too expensive
this leaves evolutionary algorithm is very inefficient and simple gradient descent slightly less inefficient
i would say
OK now let's go into
techniques for speeding up
gradient descent
all rights on this one
this this you can copy already
so here's a just set up the notation out of
o called the gradient at time t
and what i mean by that is
it's the gradient of the loss
on the current parameter values and the current data
so this is a stochastic quantity even at the same point in parameter space if
i pick some fresh data i would get a different answer came
think of it as a stochastic function
nondeterministic functions it gives me a different answer every time
but somehow over time these answers all average out because if you average all these
and you keep the parameters fixed
in the limit
so when a is a subset of b
can be decomposed as a plus
the complement of a in b
so you can write appeal be as p of a plus b of
the b-minus in the set notation
and because of the nonnegativity again you get this one
well this is just a matter of rewriting things so usually it's convenient
when you have a deviation inequality
well know that
the probability that x is larger than some quantity is less than some function of
this quantity
it's convenient to see
the confidence value
so given us this treshold that town
how how large can be
this one this from the bible
i could
OK so you want to guarantee that there is a large probability
x is less than some quantity and to obtain this you just inverts this function
yes yes yes
yes sorry
well this of course is one of
the problem may not be
OK this one
the trick is to use integration by parts to write what the expectation is expectation
is the integral
the value thank the probability
p of x
and then you integration by parts
so this is OK you assume that x is larger than zero
so this is sufficient from zero to infinity of x of XTX
so you
differentiate these integrate that
integration of p of x gives you
distribution function
and when you differentiate x
gives you one
gives you this country
another set of
interesting results
again i choose five seconds at five minutes to think about it
the first one is more or less the definition
there is some sort of keywords
for the second one i can give you
you have to use
the simple fact that expect the story
of an event
is equal to the expected value
the indicator function of that event
that's full markov seen equality
convexity anyone
OK so
actually it's it's
it's a bit tricky too
actually prove this statement because it requires some additional assumption that they not
but here
it's this statement would be true
for finite spaces
remember the the convexity of a function means that the function is always smaller
OK so you have it means that the function looks like this essentially and if
you take two points on
the graph of the function
draw the line between those two points
the function being convex means that
the function is always smaller than this one
you can write it as
and that's the definition of convex functions
f of
x plus one minus five
is less than alpha
f of x
this one minus alpha f of y
and this for any alpha
between zero and one
actually when you see that you notice that this is already an expectation
this is the expectation
of a random variable with that would take value x with probability alpha and value
y with probability one minus alpha
and by
repeating this argument you can show that
the same is true for any
a number of possible values so if you have f of some
of p i x i
which would be the expected value of the function of a random variable that takes
the value x i with probability p i whether by sum to one
by repeating this inequality
you get that this is less
the summer
of the i f of x i
which is exactly the same as saying
function applied to the expectation is less than the expectation of the function
now the
the trick is that
for this to be true for arbitrary continuous spaces
you need
some notion of continuity of this function
actually it's called lower semicontinuous so the function has to be such that that's to
be equal to the maximum
of all the functions that are linear and below this function so if you draw
all the lines
that are below the function
and at each point sorry
this should not cross
and at each point you take the maximum value obtained by any such line then
it has to be equal to the value of the function