i use my lecture notes
same thing
it's up to you
you want me to hold it up for you
that's what i sometimes do in the middle lecture across the world OK go ahead
a show in which you do
is moving string by
we know
by changing school in
so the
i would like to thank you
very kind of you
we have some other surprises for you
my graduate student extract original miller you now working at the
at harvard
he has the didgeridoo
in fact there was a story behind the data
it's original research
it's not so different from this
it is open here
it's open
can look through it and see
it is therefore
also next benefits
and they had better get the bot is i don't know where probably in australia
and never finished first ever going to be the first
got is that you don't walked away was
now the price is in good faith
i wanna see you for forty years john
look at that
that is close to forty
in his right close
so is fundamental respondents sixty eight together for forty gotta to get up
by roughly two and a three times then good luck john
that was good for the
the in
no way for
well i don't believe
why not try again
i just want to spend up to
i i think you get two hundred sixty eight so
how can you say something very exciting
we have only
it is to my knowledge
the physics of wave oscillations vibrations
which he brought
if you think this is problem
so you see what you
it's real from all
and not too close to the
they get the four forty roughly
full OWL on
are not
no closely
two twenty
strong than four four
so when she tries to get four forty six e
there's still
among lower than the four four you can change in practice that already before you
i i lower lawns
you may
four forty
you don't get to twenty four
the way it's not your fault but trombone
play something
four were
two more installments before will have to make
right we have smith with friends for
in space not
so this french or you have to break earlier
and then will have
just six years old
a guy named for keyboard which we have here
i think you get something close to midway on piano which was for forty hertz
three minutes
go it
well had
go ahead
nine or forty
this is something you
and we
we were
and senior producer for four
anyone wants to volunteer singing
yes try
c help you can make it on out
we have competition already
what's your name
because of
the song can you try to sing for forty four close to that
i think you listen with one support
going to once again
what you see in the future
this is your time
see something interesting anything you want
beautiful overtones in your voice
you want to try it
you have competition
get the four forty
very now systems
OK you back
and it so you can just walk around the island structure like
so you see the violin
you seem to violate
you may have noticed
that the strings
welcome to the final session of the conference portion of ICML thank you for coming
so as the group had
about one hundred and seventy rounds of play is about ten boat rides
approximately three thousand cups of coffee
and have a lot of inspiring and productive conversations
so when you program chair of the conference you want to pick an event for
the last session that really encourages everyone to stay to the very end of the
conference something that nobody wants to mess
and hence we come to an during
it's my pleasure to introduce the last invited speaker
i first met and in nineteen ninety seven when we were both trying to email
into was working with andrew more and had just finished publishing three papers that year
in model selection and cross validation and clustering i i believe and the two of
us talk about collaboration in text classification and hierarchies of classes classes using shrinkage and
andreas inside
and scientific sensory delight throughout this
and the next year and told me that he was leaving CMU and going to
MIT and i was really surprised i was asked and said well graduating anybody to
move on and see different part of the world and this is what you finished
your phd already i know you don't agree with but i think he really quite
finished so quickly
and he said no i finished my undergrad i he was a phd student center
went on to MIT to work with michael jordan and then moved with mike to
and finished there is is now an assistant professor at stanford is published almost a
hundred papers yes for best paper awards are spread across natural language processing computer vision
information retrieval and machine learning which uses deep and incisive knowledge of machine learning
but but among this is actually the thing that i admire and you for the
most is that he has his eye on the big picture
you know what i was talking venture copiers NIPS he told me that i didn't
get into a i just to do statistics
the time and i think much of the community has lost some of its big
AI dreams
andrews is focused on finding the common architecture for intelligence in the brain and building
general purpose robots for the home and today we can hear more about the latter
please try to be welcoming unless invited speaker and doing
because on
what it is today is
tell you about
so what does it say about sphere or the stanford AI robot knowledge
and so on
the theme of this talk will actually be application machine learning for robotics and describing
this work too
you can make use of my own excitement about the impact the machine learning is
having robotics as well as some
you should be well i think it's the most exciting open problems robotics
the project was started about two-and-a-half hours for years ago
motivated by the observation that in the in the last few decades has fragmented into
many different
and today
each of these boxes is an almost entirely separately such community you've also entirely separate
conferences and so on
and so we want to define unified challenge problems require tied together these disparate threads
of a back together again
i'm glad to be stationary i
see familiar with the history of a i i think of this as
very much a project in the tradition sharing here they keep doing this with two
thousand eight AI technology rather than say nineteen sixty six AI technology as was in
the case of shaking the EU because the project this girls
so long term challenge problems several cells onto a single robot able to do things
like tidy room is the dishwasher
fact of items assemble furniture prepare meals is thought that
many others already actually have robots that holds today
we call them the dishwasher washing machine and dryer and i think of evolutionary robotics
become only when we can start to build a single robot they can do many
different things rather than the highly specialized single purpose robots probably have a dishwasher
short go and stop this talk was two
because on the second of those challenge problems the robot able to fashion item office
and so concretely arm was about they can understand the verbal commands like
there is that the state from my office and be able to carry out that
and so when talk about the five elements on just repeat on the slide
we developed in order to build applications
so creepy
on the left after recognition system so the robot can say recognise this paper the
oscar to fetch
on mobile manipulation so that they can navigate into spaces open doors get inside your
office because they
for perception to give the robot the sensitive FET space around
as being also they can pick up this paper that so you want to search
and the is spoken dialogue systems to tie the whole thing together
let's start by talking about
opt recognition
you image today is
superior to that of any evaluation vision system and there are many reasons for this
some people talk about context about commons and so on
i think one of the reasons that human after recognition p of human object recognition
is so it appears that
humans use using here
to the directly in object and does it in a very high resolution images
and recognizing objects much easier from high resolution images low resolution ones
so for example
on the as you know what is an object
two a vision people
you to show a high-resolution image becomes it's easier to recognise what is on
and the page and that that's where the coffee mug will like by the this
this is the robot so it's no wonder that object recognition on the robot system
work very well
right so
just be clear on this as i'm facing is looking directly at you i actually
do not have enough pixels in my i
to recognise it as the projector over there
great recognises this project over all my rights i need to turn my eyes
and look directly at it
the high resolution version in michigan recognizes the project
and i can tell the way
as long as you are exploring all states and actions indefinitely
and as long as the obvious smaller conditions are satisfied for the learning rate
then these organisms converging is
and bicycle master and you know what is going to fight
and so
this works with any policies so that's why it's called of matter
on the other hand sources on policy methods and any method that avoids the policy
on police and by following the policy
then on policy matters
so this section be will become
important later
so there very very and expect to start start to think of them have time
to read
so this figure is is the positive and maybe you want to think about it
being the beach
you see the battlements of q learning and sarsa over time
and this is the work that is so then this is that the problem so
there is likely an otherwise this is just amazing read
you want to get to the goal state this is the problem and you start
from this date and if you fall over the cliff then in one thousand five
you get back to the start state and it's a very one of one hundred
at every time step you receive reward of minus for maybe i should have mentioned
have changed this to something more along
but anyways
so the positive like you learning is performing worse in this case
that's herself
i will give you the answer
to think about it
because this is the two learning is going matching to try to optimize
why is that finding errors
OK so one thing that i didn't specify about but but it's on the slide
is then
we are using by running these experiments epsilon greedy
these are the size
i don't know
OK so i don't know if it's
back to say it doesn't really matter
OK so the next idea
is that we
the conclude previously that sometimes monte carlo is better sometimes better
the next question is can we interpolate between these two target and so that we
could change in the smallest way from monte carlo two
two TV and vice versa
and the idea is that
you can do the bootstrapping after one time step or two thousand seven four
many more time steps
if you do
if you
in the limit
you do bootstrapping after if it number of times that that corresponds to model that
you're not doing bootstrapping at all
so what bootstrapping is that you're replacing
trot out this concert
rewards from some sidestep
is the value function estimate so this was run
you could do and after one step two step mother
it doesn't really change the computation
what are the properties of the target and
but this way at least you can interpolate between
it all
this basically the method i want to cuddle
and then you could
maybe you optimize these two are part of the problem tissue somebody powerful
faster convergence based
so this is just formalizing this idea so he
compute everything up to
the end of the episode
into the zero you just the step after
one thousand seven
but you could do that after t time steps for many more
and so then you could have this learning target and and with control how much
she would strap
so i sort of explained already that
in some examples
monte carlo can perform better than TV and then you can imagine that could be
intermediate cases found it makes sense to bootstrap the debate but it doesn't make sense
to which are too much
and so this example is about that if you are interested i can spend later
or this is sometimes just keep or that
so this shows that
if you
this bootstrapping changing and
so this is the root mean square and are
approximating value function and so small that user better than you see that in this
particular example but the reality is
you actually have the best performance feature learning methods than any clues three or five
so that's good
so the next five years that may be
if this works so well
you could
many children step preacher so instead of
just using a single and maybe you want to
some makes this different returns you do that
it's called a complex backup
and so the next idea that
makes this
is that well was university occur to you that you could have reach of these
different bootstrapping models
you could use an exponential
you can use exponential ways that
so basically you
you define some long the value
and the weight off
the TV zero of this is going to be from iceland
the weight of the second that there is one minus lambda times longer though
the third one minus lambda times long the square and so on
if the HDD and of the episode then you just use this
the remaining
value there
and so the good thing about this is that these sums to one
so this is the proper way of doing ratings
uses weighted
so use a little bit of this and that so
and then changing the landau
it gives you control over
if you really want to concentrate
when you're not doing something close to monte carlo but you're doing something close to
in particle if lambda equals zero then have seen here it is in all
and the probability of sunrise rising tomorrow how can i read
so there are some limitations
so these objective vists interpretation
it's kind of
you know
it's kind of people things you say
i can measure i mean i can try to measure this probability is but i'm
assuming that they exist and this is some kind of intrinsic property of the word
that there is
like the ride this story the sun as actually two in
actually it some probability of writing tomorrow and
this is kind of a property
of the many of nature
and i i can only
observe it's like the the mass sun some last but it also has some probability
of writing
and i just want to measure the
so these probabilities pre exist
and the last interpretation
so for the subjectivist interpretation these probabilities they are just numbers that people
a given person would assign to some evidence and that correspond to
how likely or
i mean how strong is belief is that this event will occur
there is
i mean you can naturally defined mean naturally assign
i mean the same numbers these beliefs real numbers to these beliefs and then you
know you can come up with the natural or input
natural rules for combining is when you when you believe in one event in to
be one event and or another even how you
combine it and so on and
you can show that if you
use these natural rules then it will lead you to
something that has the same properties as probabilities
probabilities are the right way
to formalise
the natural notion of of belief in something
then once you can of choose in one of these interpretations i mean you don't
have to choose basically you can just run your calculation without even
thinking about how to interpret these numbers
and one way in which you can
combining these numbers these being decisive action i mean you can derive that actions
what is called the bayes rule and
what is is just the way too
abate your probabilities when you make observations so you have
prior beliefs
in some what
your h
you have
in some way to measure how
what is the conditional probability of observing some data given here but it is that's
against the need to define so of some numbers
and the natural way to
derived from that's how much i believe in your i after you have seen the
is two
apply this rule and this is kind of
if you want to be consistent with the axioms
that's the only way you
you should do it
but again you can't really measure all these numbers but you know what you have
agreed that this is the right thing to do you can just work but work
of the details
my point here
what can we gain using probabilities is is this the right way
you know
doing inference or
well i mean it's natural way to do it or it is a convenient way
to do it you get this nice formula you get this nice
number that you can combine but
we don't gain anything right we we still cannot prove that
what we are saying is true because
we don't get any guarantee
the probability is that just help us resulting but
if we did not sit these numbers right in the first place
but even if we set the right i mean because there are so many ways
to interpret that you can't really prove that
the probability of something is something because
you know you can come up with all sorts of interpretations you can hear frequencies
objectivist or subjectivist and none of these people with three
so again it's kind of disappointing but even though you are using probability it doesn't
mean that you're doing the right thing or that you justifying
so we know that the problem is that we we need these assumptions there is
no way we can escape this assumption
so what can we do
what we can do is
you know
implicitly assume something like the future looks like the that
this is kind of reasonable and you know everyone would agree with that some degree
or what we have not seen it looks like what we have seen
and it's clear that if we don't make such assumptions
then there is no point in doing in the
you know in working learning theory or even working measuring at all because if you
don't assume that there is some regularity in the world
there is no hope that you can cooperate with these algorithms
but still we want to make these assumptions you know as limited as possible we
don't want to assume too much
and we want to keep the minimum which means that
if we can even completely get rid of this assumption actually you can a certain
sense if you
i don't aim at proving that
some reason is optimal that if you want to compare algorithms like if you will
i want to predict but
two i mean to predict well but you want to predict as well as some
of the and if you want to imitate the behavior of an organism
independent of how good the reason is that you can
you know somehow get rid of these assumptions
so it's a matter of you know
can we match some of the first
like in when we
i'm willing to go with assumptions in the question is
and the question that the series would answer is
given these assumptions
what can we do
at best threats what is the
optimal algorithm with respect to this assumption that something we can
now i want to have slowly go towards more
one thing
how it's not too slow for you
i fixed myself put o five percent of people that should be easily by the
end of the lecture
so far it seems to be OK
eighty three percent
OK so
maybe you need to it faster
so let me introduce now
and try to dissuade picture of
the things
it's a
you know how to distinguish between different assumptions of frameworks because you probably have heard
about you know online learning or
semi supervised learning or bayesian inference and all these things you know i want to
kind of
chart where you can
place these things and related to each other and understand what is an assumption and
what is just
matter of sitting the problem and so on and trying not to confuse all these
and that have weights w i
at time t minus one
we then will propagate so we cannot say that xt
it's going to be whatever the dynamics
some function f x d minus one
cases and you
new sample
xt i
and then we got no way to get a new weights
it's more or less how
the algorithm is going to do it that's the picture
quite often these distributions are moving with certain the hockey playing case with
what you want to maintain is the distribution of the with the mode
the player location
but then the player moves and distribution system
because the distribution is estimating the location of the play
location and speed and so on
so if the distribution is moving too quickly then what happens is you know a
lot of these particles
and that was very low weight
and algorithmically what happens is you end up with only one part of a lot
of time
so what we're going to do is we're going to this about computation here but
i forgot to say that
with all the serial machine
but instead of drawing samples from one to two three four
what we're going to do is going to maintain and samples
it just keep propagating and samples what
so to eliminate this problem
we introduce resampling
we propagate things through the dynamical system
we select the brightest samples
and and
propagate some again
weight to
so if the so in the distribution is moving
you have to stay with the samples in order to be able to track
without this algorithm would not work
but this
according to the importance weight
i importance weights
the story is about
there's more to the story
in terms of analysis of bias and variance in one is it good to example
we're not
but i'm going to leave it at this stage that suffices
suffice it to say that if you implement the first part of the just missionaries
because otherwise it will not work
so this is how the algorithm works
at the beginning to draw samples from the initial distribution
we you have an initial model state
if that model is not very good ones and worried because the idea of the
dynamical system is that
you start far off but soon you catch up with with
players so the robot spoke about estimate but as it moves on along the world
the estimate improves
and then algorithm is as follows
you draw a sample from the transition prior
so you move forward just like we did with that right
move forward one step
and then evaluate importance weights in this case if you propose from the prior distribution
importance weighted simply the likelihood
these stationary point
i mean so there there's a theorem for BP that that the goods stationary point
a minimum
four EP and know that they are not necessarily holds
exactly so for belief propagation of people have done is they've developed alternative ways of
minimizing the energy
for example one they go directly downhill on the energy
o or one to try to find the lowest minimum of the energy and so
on and people have done similar things three but in my experience what i found
is that finding the lowest EP model evidence
or even the highest one is necessarily the most accurate one
because it is in the bound in in any sort
finding the the one that has the highest instances making sense
o king
that's right
this is essentially a rewriting of the free energy
if if all the factors in your model
are already
in the right exponential family for example if all of the as artigas in but
they just coupled
and your after all there are fully factorized right venue in BP situation the definition
of BP
from my point of view
if you're in that particular situation then this would reduce to
the bit free energy essentially
on the
on the web page where you can get my thesis i have a paper which
which shows exactly corresponds to bit free energy
it's called the EP energy function
but actually i should point out though that the
the way i wrote the energy function that paper wasn't clean is this this is
not my new favourite way of writing the energy function is and that if you
look if you look in the literature you'll find various people who give different energy
function three p and i think that this so this is like a million ways
of writing this energy function
i just find this to be the nicest way
reverting it
mainly because it's a function only of the message is the message you don't have
to be normalized
and indirectly gives to the model that was the nice properties that i like
and in fact if you if you just take this
take his energy and you differentiate the spectre the priors of the phi tells you
really get DP update
as you just have to green to zero and you have do so
so it's a really nice wearing
yes question
that's right
it's it's something that i don't really use except to compute the model evidence
i mean some people
people who study BP use the BP free energy
two to understand the article properties of so this might be useful for that as
well the there's been very limited work in that context
i myself i always adjust to compute the moments once ironically
the use of reveals
future work by
for the look at the paper
so in the paper i i give intuition for why this is why is good
so so by by giving the generalized view of what he in terms of minimising
divergences we can all change it to be to become different algorithms particular i can
the difference i minimize some of the divergence in different message passing
and the paper said earlier divergence measures and message passing shows how you can get
a variety of different message passing by changing the divergence is today i'm just going
to give a little taste of that by showing one difference measured you can pick
in particular
you can
you can choose the KL divergence where q and p are swapped
that's one thing you can do you can say
i don't want to minimize the killer peter q i want to minimize the KL
of q
and we can use you can take the recipe i just gave and just change
all of the KL divergence is in there too one cycle from p
run the exact same algorithm
but but change the project operator essentially
and what you get you get mean field approximation
which i think is is an interesting relationship to others
and i'll show you that works more generally
you can use an alpha divergence rather than kill them as well for the into
sort of a big family of divergences which killed one and you can get other
you may have heard of for example you can get reweighted belief propagation
by using bayes in the same recipe i just gave up with alpha divergence and
you can get power EP is well that's all described in the paper i cited
let's let's stick to KLQ to be OK so we interchange the arguments of
to kill is not symmetric functions we do actually change
we are measuring we swap two arguments
and what do we gain by doing that right
in my mind
the sort of main the main good property of going from KLQP to p
is this one is that when you minimize these local divergences
you're you're equivalently minimising the global divergence
so in particular
that that approximation gap that was present in the because our context was wrong
doesn't exist if you scale of q to p
and i'll show you
i give you a brief sketch of why that's the case
all right on the global divergence right on the local divergence and show that there
very equivalent
this isn't a complete proof that the algorithm is the same you can find the
proof in my different measures paper give sketch
OK so what's the global divergence the goal divergences
the KL fifteen q of xn pnx
and just to reiterate what that is
that is this
and recall that
q of x is the product of all of the approximate factors
it one formula on the left in the formula on the right
is this the form below yes i just past that to be a formula is
a formula such as positive
the right to draw formation tree work through
a bracketed sic of the brecon in this way
right rather than
this way
the box grabs onto its arguments
more tightly
i'm then implication does
you will slowly pick up these things as the
this lecture progresses anyway so what i'd like you to do is to convince yourself
that some of these other things are a formula is the the
in modal logic we really deal with actual formula we deal with shapes
sometimes they call schemas
and what i wanna do their say
when you have the shape then you start using formula variables like five
phi implies phi is the shape
because i can substitute any formula i like so if i wanted to i could
take this whole thing and put it in there as long as i put the
same thing in getting
the formula
so what we're going to do is we can instantiate
and the word is uniformly
OK so the example box p flies p two
so the box
p nor implies p two
i claim this is not an instance of that
sorry i
OK so uniformly the phi has to be the same thing
but this is p not but now it's saying well actually we change their minds
when we went from
so the area to the
that's all just wherever you see five has to be the same wherever you see
side it can be different from five it can be the same as five you
want as well
so and convince yourself that this scheme of things work and sometimes all one two
calculate the formula such is going to be that the number of symbols in assuming
that these guys
p not p two are all of length one
so i want this to be to get right it's one two
it's this is of length one this is of length one
this is lovely to then
this is of length four
big party
no it's not graph theory it's just
traditionally called sky
whereas if you have no background whatsoever in logic which is what sometimes happens here
then what's the schema sounds very it all and by shape what i'm trying to
get across is this idea of the uniformity right
shape is something that's the same everywhere shape and if you see the same shape
in the places he's got to instantiated in the same way
it's just something that i think about which other people
other people use it as well but you still see it more and more recently
in introductory textbooks
OK because not everyone has a background in say philosophy anymore so all of the
old terms of schemas in
substitution instances and things like that
they just don't have the background
OK any other question
i find
and now this lecture is all about the kripke semantics for modal logic stand after
guy called so keep
made major contributions to basically showed
that modal logic has semantics in terms of graphs
from nineteen twenty remember was more logic was healthy disciplines using only syntax
is and
i'm sure you guys as you goes no principal component analysis can essentially be interpreted
as getting distribution
of objects and you essentially if you ignore
some of the similar low-energy organ components you essentially going some generalizations so like essentially
what we do with PCA is we essentially get you can think of it this
as a generative model we have the generative model of how
a bunch of faces here
given that the are already listed same way so given that a lot of weight
on the eyes and nose of every subject
and make sure that i made sure that you find so i've removed the final
from each of them that they all go back to the same template
and all of here
is a measure of how that appearance changes as a function of these identities
so really simple idea
can i can go into it a little bit more detail
the training examples for instance the way that we do that is said probably have
always nice coordinates that define the box here and so
this is where we get people at the university of pittsburgh or myself in this
and clicking clicking points
and we get these these what what values
what we do then if we keep them with notation here is that of the
magical does so what my source image
and the magical w ensures that the size of all these images have the same
to just say it's in by and another in square by one convex and square
one called the on-screen one column vector
and just for
completeness i shall refer to my training data summer training examples given that the normalized
for these for these grant reports is t one t two all the way through
and this is what they look like one to normalise
these are in happen that this column vectors of pixel intensity
and essentially all then
is but for
put it into a big matrix of t one through t m
and you see here so to say this is an squares
in terms of
we should be using the same thing that this is the site m squared them
in terms of pixels and i've got in
and images this one then of gordon and m squared by in
what can do then typically is an assisted living in PCA remain so to say
that you want to make sure things of the same origin
and this is kind of like the ghostly
i mean face things like being made in we actually we actually did a series
for the discovery channel recently on like facebook stuff and things of that was being
made in the media likely this idea of an average facts selectively like registering and
registering face across many many many images an interesting thing is that a lot of
people can claim that the average price is it's all it's it's much more beautiful
which statically beautiful anyway then an individual because it has little symmetry
and humans tend to like symmetry interface and also become smooth out lot the irregularities
and things like that
i i've heard of that affair that as well but from my money they look
kind of quite closely things but the depending on the
but there is and it's it's an interesting it's an interesting artifact the kind of
but again that's perhaps some sort of redundancy in a human visual system perhaps so
that we like we like people with with really small faces and symmetrical faces so
there's not much i mean but the but you know they got the average faces
and then we apply
principal component analysis which i hope you're all familiar with
you can either do
classic organic decomposition or this to an SVD
and essentially what we've got here
is that
i is essentially concatenation of these i can vectors
up after up to the an organ vectors and if i look at these i
vectors in as an image you can to get these ghostly looking images become the
kind of thing like that's the kind of place like but they
there there are some parts that so like parts it should be so positive values
that are negative values and vice versa
and and obviously we've got inside that we've got a diagonal matrix that's got the
organ values that kind of gives me it's essentially the amount of energy in my
training sample sets associated with each of these i are parts
and so this is all quite rudimentary i mean this is classical stuff
and have a point is essentially this they can go OK well
we found the image matching the
SST works quite well so let's use stay but instead of trying to solve for
just p
just trying to solve the wall let's try and solve
for the appearance variation at the same time
that's essentially what they do so it's kind of we can go get to the
only whatever
so this is
this is my source image and i'm trying to match for
this is my p i don't know MIP map is there some kind of searching
life much likely and that the mining industry exhaustive search on this kind of light
how to get the labelled data and how do we actually know something like politics
at the moment i guess negative sentiment
it's a hard problem
we kind of cheated a little bit by using the emotive comes
so the molecules smileys
it's something people very often attached to
personal messages or tweets what
so we took the assumption that they uh smiley face happy face
represents the positive sentiment and the
south place negative sentiment
so what the data
and is the
deep deep semantic analysis of
what keywords are likely to be sentiment-bearing and so on and so forth
well actually
just extracted all foreground
from the street
by i mean character-based foreground not word level foreground
and we build eh
logistic regression model
or a collection of such
and the
these are the results
what it shows is about
which trains a single logistic regression model over such a presentation
using more data
definitely improved the performance
i mean clearly
now interestingly given a small sample
three classifiers
vastly outperforms a single model
using fewer data so this is trained with a hundred million
hand although the trained with just ten million examples
and this is the number of ensemble elements in the collection
so clearly
one element with
one hundred million examples this is not as good as three
trained with is ten million
so some win
and it's interesting that those ensembles of linear classifiers
weights often find people which often people find to be not as effective as the linear classifiers
in this case they work very well
and there's a lot of diminishing returns by going into
more than eight hours for
with the ensembles sorry the user was samples was more important in this case the news of more data
but more than just a helps
some people may ask
okay so proposing this
the category this an online algorithm
which streams the data about what they are
what if there really is something which requires iterations
so what do i do now
so there's a few options and is not impossible
so the number of iterations really small just like my we unroll them
now we can just
a look
we can do is to pay
well the problem is like we very often don't know
the number of iterations ahead of time
and even if we did you'd probably be fairly large
it was like this too
actually implement this thing in
in something like a cascading framework in python sketch
it's extra work it doesn't really fit well with what are we to
recently that some options of having
custom control flow
to pick
but i mean is very sensitive actually not fully baked yet
so the only option is to
right customer mapreduce job
o use something like an external framework like mahout
which can do it for us
really phase one particular problem word this is interesting
those topic modeling
so the topic modeling is something a lot of people study for a variety of reasons
we also find it useful
for applications
so what you see here is like what big one particular topic
so now the question is what i'm trying to prove to you is that e
e two is more negative than the one so ultimately what one is
what's the relative magnitude of the two over one
what is it is greater than one that's the question right i can prove that
is greater than one
that means that the line stable then
the set of ion pairs and if you
if you look at the series
this series
you know the series logo one
with series expansion log of one class act
is what is it's x minus x squared over two plus executed over three etcetera
etcetera few plug in x equals one that's our series
one minus the hapless the third
it's all there so if you if if you're going work that out log two
n two log two pi matthew can show that for the line are series
and is equal to two
the natural logarithm of two which is one point three eight six which is greater
than one
so what have i shown i've shown that by taking a big and number of
individual ion pairs and putting them all together and align the system's energy
became more negative
so that's to say that
it's favour so we could say
and energy level diagram is to the energy
here's zero if this is
the energy of the pair let's make this he over the of the ion pair
he over the for the pair
so this is one
we just showing
that for the line so this is pairs ever get number of pairs this is
as big as the number of
i pairs in line
that's one point three eight six and then if you go to the real sodium
chloride crystal and you do the same calculation one in three dimensions so that you
take every sodium
and you count all of its
nearest neighbours next nearest neighbours next next nearest neighbors not only online but in the
plane and above and below in all three dimensions and go through that calculation it's
even more negative it's one point seven four seven five
if i start to react sodium with chlorine
the result is the crystal a three-dimensional array
because at every point first thing happens electron transfer y
to get a stable octet the result i got ion pairs
plus attract to minus minus is attractor pluses they start climbing together but they don't
stop with one plus one
one plus one and then the ion pair grabs another one another one and before
you know it you have a crystal so this is simply the energetics of crystal
formation so this is a three-dimensional crystal you can consider this line of one dimensional
crystal because it's ordered
it's ordered psychology one-dimensional crystal so this says that when it comes to iron
what comes to ions
comes to ions
line dancing
trump's ballroom dancing that's what it's a
they they rather be in line then dance two by two
that doesn't apply to all things but it does in this case
now let's look at properties let's talk about properties in we've got a long way
we started with this
hypothesis of octet stability and talking about properties of crystals there is solid at room
temperature why
what's the what's these are huge energy
these are huge energy
coulombic forces
high melting points and boiling points like to have a high melting point boiling point
because when you ask yourself the question you should consider what is the thermal energy
first the bonding energy if the binding energy is very strongly negative thermal energy
isn't great enough to disrupt those bonds and allow those wants to be broken and
half fluidity
strong bonds means high melting points and boiling point transparent to visible light
transferred to visible light
crystals of the sodium chloride crystal is transparent to visible light table solved is white
but that's because you've got powder and you've got multiple surface scattering large crystal of
sodium chloride is
clear and colorless
and it's faceted you can see that it has it has the shape if you
take it
one of those individual
grains of sodium chloride look at it carefully you'll see the edges look like this
why is transferred to visible light here i ask that question when you want to
know something transparent to visible light or not
here's the ministry material
and here's is visible light
and what is going to allow for absorption or some interaction with visible light inside
here you've got electronic states and you gotta ask yourself is the energy difference here
the delta e in the electronic states how does that compare with the
visible light
what's the invisible like you know it's about two to three
electron volts
o two to three electron volts this has what
sodium plastics isoelectronic with neon chloride minus isoelectronic with our got what do we know
about the average valence electron energies
which is sort the the first slide it's up around thirteen
fourteen fifteen
electron volts
this thing is going to touch only global
so what happens it goes through
all that glitters is not gold but it must have free electrons
this has no free electrons
they're all bound
so that's how you determine if something's transparent
it's going to be electrically insulated is not for to move around all bound hard
and brittle y
because of its strong bond strong bonds means the material will resist
an applied force
you apply force to the material will resist until you have the force great enough
to break the bonds so you don't have ductility which is what you have in
metal that makes metal so fascinating because metallic bonding allows the atoms to glide over
one another without resulting in catastrophic failure
whereas ceramics ionic crystals
i will resist
until they shatter there's only two categories it's either elastic with full resistance or
the bonds soluble in water and other polar solvents will have to come back to
that later they melt to form ionic liquids ionic solids from liquids so that's
that's i showed you last a what happens when they
and we were able to electrolytes and make
fantastic novels like like magnesium
OK what we find what we find is ionic crystals where we look well you
electron transfer senior the donor and union acceptors so we're the good donors donors are
over here the on the left and the the periodic table
and where the except on the right side of the periodic table
so if you take some from column one or two when you mix it with
some from column even nine bingo you've got
reactions so here's an example that shows here's here's some very very metallic elements groups
we're going to discuss today
resistive forces and drag forces
when you move an object
through a medium whether to guess web the liquid experiences drag force
this drag force depends on the shape of the object the size of the object
the medium through which you remove it
the speed of the object
the medium is immediately obvious
it's area you move through air you feel the wind for you here that the
drag force
if you swim in water you feel this drag force
in oriel the drag force will be even larger
direct force
this resistive force is very very different from the fraction that we've discussed earlier
when two surfaces
move relative to each other there
the kinetic friction coefficient remains constant
independent of the speed
the drag forces and the resistive forces
they are not all independent of the speed
in very general terms
the resistive force
can be written
k one
times the velocity
was k two
times the velocities created
and always in the opposite direction
of the velocity vector this view is being made
so all the signs k one pnk two
and obviously the the squared
they all are
positive values and the k values depend on the shape
on the side
of the object and on the kind of media and that i have
today i will restrict myself exclusively
two spheres
and when we deal with years
we're going to get that the
the force
the magnitude of the force this part
equals c one
times are
time to speed policy two
times are spread
times the square
and again it's always opposing
velocity vector
c one
in our
units kilograms
four meters per second
and c two
as the dimension of density
kilogram per cubic metres
we call this
the viscous term
and we call this
pressure to
viscous term
has to do is the stickiness of the medium
if you take for instance
liquid water
and all antara is a huge difference in stickiness physicist also refer to that as
if you have a high viscosity is very sticky
then this
number c one will be very high
so this we call the viscous term
and this we call
the pressure to
c one is a strong function of temperature
we know that if you take part in you it
the viscosity goes down is way more sticky when it is cold
c two is not very dependent on
the temperature
it's not so easy to sing
why this pressure term
he has to be square later in the course when we deal with transfer of
we will understand why there is the squared term there
but they are square is very easy to see
because if you have a sphere
there is some fluids
gas or liquid streaming onto to it
this has a cross sectional area
which is proportional to are squared and so it's easy to see that the force
that is object experience we call it
the pressure term is proportional
two are square to that's easy to see two liquids
have factorizations
if you
read conditional independence you can read conditional independence by the concept of graph separation
but i i d separation
and likewise the opposite also holds and is especially important
because remember that use their actions
is the one that's most interesting to us
because usually the set of conditional independence statements is what you are listed from the
domain expert
the main expert knows nothing about factorizations of probability distribution
so these actions particularly for
so if you have a probability distribution that satisfies the conditional
independence statements implied by d separation
then it to factorize what they were
so in other words you should
from now on we we should think of
the separated
from b
by c
you should
now i know that this is basically means a
conditional independence
these are purely
graph theory
we define the most of the prediction
it is based on the definition of that unblock that
it's a purely probabilistic on
so here you have
two universities in the meat
it is very important
so again
if you see x two
x five and x six
so again
x five has head tail with respect to these
its head tail with respect to this but
so it is with respect all that cities head tail
yes these he is blocked
is but he is blocked
and any path that
goes through
x five
in this case
o particular this bad block this blocked
you see that there is more than one pattern there's more than two pass
that involve x five so this is one
which has had failed is another which had failed
but these but here in the those
involve the sewage is here
he x five
he's a head-to-head nodes with regard these
so again
so OK so you want to ask if in addition to x one
and x five
i also had x two
but also
is that the question
no it's not walk because when a as i said this is blocked
no this is wrong this is not a blog
there's not a lot because when they observe these here
i i created connection between extreme x six
so that's exactly what we have here
in this exercise
all i see that was one
this is OK so so basically
i mean well
well this
it's not the separate
because these that is what this but is blocked in this but it's not book
if this best for any reason i was blocked then it would be separate for
example the is viable what was observed
then it would be separate
because the first condition with be met
because this is the tail to tail node is that it doesn't matter if the
second condition is not met
as long as the first one
so again
just remembering
in this particular example
if i want to ask the question whether x three and x six o be
they are not be separated if we observe x one and x five only
because the spent here is not blocked
they are separate fields
x one x five and x
because including this that will also be one because of these which is observer in
its tail to tail node in the
it's not clear now
OK in your other question
OK let's keep going
so remember this two theorems which basically tell you that well
if you
if you have a bayesian network
the factorisation of that vision
willing to align precisely
which conditional independence is not only the conditional independences that we saw yesterday
because yesterday we saw that we constructed the bayesian networks
starting from very simple conditional independence so let's just
ignore some of the conditioning viable so because that's what we did right
so basically we started with the entire factorisation of the joint probability distribution in terms
conditional probability distributions
and then the forces some particular conditional independence statements that were kind of of string
handling that
and then there's obviously a lot of interesting challenges in deciding given
the results from each of these purposes what which ones are most relevant to show
for that particular query and what you should use to show them and so on
i think one of the things one of we have in the past had approach
this problem as we said g we don't have much capacity let's see if we
can find some queries that we'd like to send to
some of the other corpora that we believe will have good results but that so
much harder problem because you're actually trying to decide based on three words in the
is this going to be interesting
will the you know google groups corpus have interesting results that three query
and that's actually much harder problem and if you actually send the query down get
the scores back from that corpus and the relevant documents and then you can make
a decision saying oh yeah well the score from groups is twelve in the score
from printing five so i'm going to assume that one of them is more relevant
other of the scores may not be directly comparable you
over time over a set of queries understand
you know what when one corpus is going to be more relevant
the other big change
that's happened relatively recently is that
we now have the ability to
update our index in a matter of minutes here
for for given
page as opposed to waiting fairly long periods and during very large batch updates
and a lot of things that have to change your system in order to really
do right
first of all how do you know what pages you want update it's good to
have a system that can identify
are there interesting new pages on the web that just showing up in the last
minute or two
or are there important pages that have been updated that you ideally like to have
any page as soon as it changes be updated in your inject that's a very
difficult thing not of crawled into the world to really do that and some pages
change every time you crop because they have like the timestamp at the bottom so
you sort of have to pick and choose your battles and decide for given budget
of pages it adopted one of the most important one that you want updated so
the two indexes
fresh and useful users
so the crawling system needs to be able to accommodate these very fast update requests
like i want to update this page and i want now not here's a whole
bunch of urals and i want to
you know in an hour
the indexing system
it is challenging because it depends on global information
every structured for example where you depend on things like pagerank you depend on the
anchor text of pages that point to the to that page you need actually index
data with
the other with the target document
so you must have some way of getting this information or some approximation of it
in order to index the page within a minute or so
and serving system has to be re thought of it so that it can be
except updates four different documents while you're actually serving requests and accept updates fairly frequent
and the data structures you actually one user fairly different in that case they know
something we update things in batches of ten hours of
the other thing that i think is important in
and we've
i realized over time is that
it's really important when you're trying to make progress in improving ranking and and search
quality and so on is that you want to make it easy to do experiments
the faster you can make around africa experiment from when you have an idea to
when you actually can
demonstrate prototype that idea the better it's going to be
so we spent a lot of effort building tools that allow it
the make it fairly easy to do some kind of experiments in that they're not
hugely beneficial
some experiments you don't actually need to sort of do very much you just want
weight different ranking parameters and those you can actually do without really rolling out
anything in terms of new binaries or anything you can
just do them online are the ones that are more difficult to the ones that
need information that you didn't
i had the foresight to build a new production index
you need some way of computing and information generating it
after involves pass making a pass over all the documents are over some
derive information from from all the documents and be able to build that structure the
side that you can then use
to do your experiment
and not really talk very much about these various systems but p several of pieces
of infrastructure we built
are useful for doing some of these countries parents i already talk about a bit
idea fails which is just a big file system spread across thousands of machines
mapreduce is a abstraction that makes it easy to write and run large scale kind
of batch computations
i deals with like nasty things that happened like machine failures it automatically paralyzes things
across parts machines
basically it enables you to write
simple fairly simple programs that can extract information which is of interest to you for
your experiments and perform those ad-hoc experiments market
bigtable is a sort of semi structured storage system think of it as a very
large row and column oriented store
so for example one thing that gives us is online
efficient access to per document information any time you can say what is the current
information i know about
CNN dot com
and i will tell you OK pagerank is this will have profit this time here's
the current contents that we know about so on
and this is very useful for being able to update documents in a matter of
minutes as opposed to days
OK so the experimental cycle
you want to start with a new ranking idea you obviously use these tools to
generate interesting data and then you want to be able to
at first run off line experiment users are involved in this is actually just want
your say ranking change and look at what effect it has on how quickly how
results are ranked for
different results and some human rate increase that's another one maybe you'll do a random
selection of korean just look at what changes compared to the production ranking
so important thing to note here is that the latency or the throughput of this
prototype don't really matter
you know you can run ten thousand queries and it can take hours
not ideal but it's OK
and then you can iterate based on the results of this maybe you find that
she works well in this case but not this case i change occurred about
maurice pollen
and you have the size expected cost
more than that
well no really
i mean heuristic because the have two objectives
so the real problem is really by criterion probably two objective to minimize the expected
return expected mean
i mean
and the very
but you can minimize the same
but at the same time
so you really have
you have to define what we mean by the solution
and this is one possible definition of
so really
later converted by criterion problem into single about
or maybe it's only a partial
the real answer would be to look at the complete rail car between two objects
compete for me for doing this fixed come on it if you want point
but this is not quite as a function of four come as you know it
just LP with european bites means
but now we at quite experiments
another example is again very familiar and support vector machines
suppose now can we go back to this problem linearly separating two sets of points
we suppose we assume that there exactly separable
and we try to pick hyperplane that actually
it's better and more robust and more robust separation than other feasible hyperplane
well the most common way of defining that minimizes to maximize the margin between the
and that turns out to be one over the not relate to one of the
normal to get the maximum margin separating hyperplane minimize the norm of a lot of
that's qp p
or in the support vector classifier can combine the two
and look at the most general information and very have that's not separable
we tries to object if you want to maximize the margin and minimize the error
of the classification
expressed using this piecewise linear penalty
and again you can look at a weighted sum of the two
give support vector
so that's all the QP but it can be expressed as a QB you
convert back piecewise linear term in all office
and so this linear programming quadratic programming last a class of problems that been discussed
in this part geometric programming
i'm not sure that really want to use in machine learning but other applications
so it's again on the problem like this the minimize
the cost function and the constraint functions this specific form
it looks like a polynomial in x
except that the
exponent can be any
the positive or negative
and i don't have to be integers
but restrict x to be positive domain of the function of
and this coefficient from the also
that's called the posynomial
in this context
polynomial in n
the people
it cannot describe these
it looks like a polynomial but the core components that can be any
and your specific x to be
and then minimize that function subject to
posynomial function subject wasn't on the constraints ax it
it's called the genetic programming
now that's not a convex function of x
of what can be any number
in general functions of this form are not convex
but there is a simple trick that allows you to convert this into a convex
and the trick is that instead of using x positive components access variables use their
blogger variables
and then the problem transforms into one complex problem if you buy this function
function i make a change of variables x x with the exponent
financial of some
other the variable y make this change of variables
then you get this
because the problem
and you've seen these are convex functions of y
so log of a sum of exponentials of y
and then in this form you get a convex problem and can easily minimized this
this is genetic programming problem solved
the it's called him i mean there are several theories about how what's called genetic
programming which means
one of the theories is that it's
it comes up often in geometric optimization problems variables which of only in height
here are examples of loss functions for each of the problem
really of regression you take the
least square
measure which measure how far is my estimate
of this target from the true target
in the classification problem
i i i will have a
since last not telling me
it's not to me
zero if i had the good targets and
one of the way so i will have
penality for i didn't find that could be a good target
in in density estimation
usually what we do you think is the likelihood
but since we are in machine learning framework
and it's not a positive measure we have what we have is the negative measure
usually we take the negative log likelihood
because it's easier to compute than likelihood to
so that
instead of you you don't want to maximize the
the likelihood what you want to minimize the
look like likelihood which is the same person
so now let's put together finding searching for a good function in a in a
function space f
we take the
the risk of harm
of our function of a given function is the expected value if over the whole
domain the whole possible values of my name
of my my sample
of my examples
that will be the expected risk
and what want is we want to minimize so you have this because it's the
expected value of the loss function
over the entire domain
what i want to minimize this
so if a could had the
the function which minimize my laws
what does that mean over the entire pacific values of my domain
i will be happy the problem is that i don't know this density probability distribution
is similar
so we cannot compute that we can minimize it
so what we
do instead is we choose
to minimize the empirical risk
so we which is the risk is computed
only over our training set
and to take the
function which minimize
the risk of on this train set
OK but how good is the approximation
it's not exactly the same
over the whole domain only on a sample of system
we know
that is for any function so without being the what you know
without the need the one that we chosen choose on the training set we know
the empirical risk
is there is an unbiased estimate of the expected risk
sure i told you what that means that the index the
the expectation of the empirical risk is equal to the risk
and we know also that
it's quite consistent estimate that is if if my
then there it's it's in need goes it's big enough
i will take the risk would be a good estimate of the empirical risk would
be a good estimate of the
expected risk
the more samples the smaller
rolls walking
so was less
yeah i think you're not taking the integral over to
you know you're taking it over to you're in fact
for example the
this the source of
we saw the number
this list is
in fact this is this is the only related
two two these factors think again it says something about the
the fact that
are our instant factor mean
and the mean it's it's an unbiased and consistent estimate even i don't need to
know in fact that p
he said
something related to to the rule
i don't know the proof that can have it in mind but
even if we
it's a it's a it's related to the weak law of probabilities
so but
in fact we're not interested by this
this value what we were interested in city
this value so the value of the empirical risk for the
the optimum function
i cannot do that anymore because this time i have two dependencies on
so i i
it's not that easy
we want to know relationship between
the empirical risk of my optimum function on my
training set
what will be the expected risk of this particular function
if if i could take the whole the in
and it is it
close to the to the optimum risk or not
OK so that's out the question we tried to answer
so for example we want to know if
taking this particular functions
cold cold is still
eight times less likely than hot cold
so have a lot of cold cold then actually still be unlikely
so let's see
what the correct
with the model actually believes i'm going to show you another graph that we have
looked at before unfortunately the lines are kind of on top of each other here
but there are four kinds of lines and every day starting with a two
we have about the previous day and that day
so this pink here says it's pretty likely
that you know
a little less than half probability to be a hot day that was preceded by
a hot day
it's also pretty likely to be a cold day that was preceded by cold if
you look very carefully
at this you can see the this problem star behind
these two things are unlikely
a cold day followed by a hot day
try a hot day pursued by called a recall pursued by heart those are unlikely
these are like
and that's what you would expect from this picture
the higher parts are still more likely according to this model so even though we
can't tell what the weather is we still think of
it is more likely than hot called
and i'll show you how we reconstruct this minute
so let's go now to
two an alternative
which is what if we have an inertia
OK well it's still the case that this is totally flat because
this is the ice cream probabilities are still correlated we still have that exactly the
same on cold isn't
so i this is this of working
the same and called isn't this but if we look at the second order probabilities
the by gram probabilities will see now that now because the model start out by
assuming and inertia
these have switched
the yellow and light blue
are the problem ones hot to cold and cold heart because that's where the model
things the model things that should put more probability
on the patterns that alternate instead of the patterns that keeps the same way
the point is that this graph is exactly the same both times
but this gradually changed
therefore we can't get this second order probabilities just by looking at the first order
we're going to have to do something a little bit different
so let's go back to this picture
well we're interested in
what we're interested in is the person if we look at
all of the two to the thirty third has a quarter go through this article
about through that article to go through that article to go through that i
most if most of the probability goes on has to go through that are
then the day three is probably called a pursued by called
so if we look at the
probability paths going through particular are not just a particular state then we can see
we can see which transitions are likely
so how do we do that
well it's going to be similar to what we had before
so we've got a lot of paths coming into this called stay here a lot
of paths coming out of that called state here we have one are here which
has some costs
so what's the total probability i let's let's call that cost
can number x no we already have x we already have p
which is a
well actually we
so what's the total probability of all paths going through this art
well we have x times a times speed plus six times a times q
plus x times a times are
right lots of pads coming in lots paths going out
if we multiply these individually and some of them are going have to do thirty
one schumann's because there's two to thirty one paths going through this article a quarter
of all of them
but fortunately we have are often probability
so we can say it's just alpha of the state
times a times span of that state
the total probability of everything coming in
times this are times total probability of everything going out
so we actually do this on the spreadsheet
so here
here we have probability of
o site
go back here and change these back to original numbers
OK that's our original reconstructions so now you see the probability of a colder call
hot to cold cold heart and heart to heart the particular day
some to one so this is how the two to the
these four cells are how the two to the thirty third have got divided up
among the four arcs that could happen
twelve and thirteen
that's those numbers and that's what we're what planning in the graph
and i will click around the computation but it's basically just doing this with the
office embeds that we've already computed
so this is just acute dynamic programming track
being able to avoid summing over a trillion pounds
can we still do it for infinitely many functions and that's what this sometimes ideas
about the time we make is that made this problem solvable
the called symmetrisation
and is the introduction of capacity concepts the basic idea is that even if there
are infinitely many
if the capacity is
small in some sense then
on the finite sample of observations they will effectively behave as if there are only
finitely many or are they
actually a sub exponentially many but you see a little more about this later
so let's look at two functions
we have a function class containing two functions
we will provide right this thing here so remember this is what we are interested
the maximum of these two functions
this deviation
so when you
when is this
this equality here true
we could say we write s two events one is the
the event that the risks so the test around the training error for functions f
differ by one than epsilon
so i mean it's a i'm interested in whether
one of the two functions has the risk of the east side of the the
worst function has the risk of at least two or more than epsilon
and this will
with this will take place if
the first function has the risk more than epsilon all the second one has risk
more than epsilon this is not an excuse for the close to both the
the that
so c one is the event
the first function
we draw such training set such that the risk is the former site c two
is implicit functions
so that we can rewrite this quantity as the probability of the union of these
two events
we can rewrite this again some of these two probabilities minus the probability that both
take place
probabilities on the negative so if we drop this we get upper bound
which looks like this
so maybe you haven't personally i don't know how much mathematics computer scientists typically studies
maybe i can i can quickly ask how many of you are the cognitive scientists
all psychologists
OK so that's
i would say twenty five percent
how many of you are
mathematicians and physicists or mathematically minded computer scientists
so that's that's more so i think it's probably for you it would be easy
for the other ones i'm trying to also give some intuition so
so roughly speaking the short version is that we're interested in with
one of the two functions misleads us about the difference between training and test error
minimisation credited this will happen is upper bounded by
the probability that the first one is misleading
second one misleading us and is just about because you could be that both are
misleading as so i could be doing some double counting here
OK so if we have this
now we at this point these quantities now
so i can use the channel of these both these we get
the identical to the both of them so i will get the same results before
which was this one only with a factor of two here
the factor of two i don't i don't know if i have to because this
thing goes down exponentially with the number of salvation so this goes down so fast
it is about two
it doesn't cost us anything
now let's look at functions and i think you can imagine what's going to happen
even if i don't go the details
what we will get if we get an an extra factor n
so we came up with this
it's going to be like before this time some of n
quantities each to them
we can do with china we get an extra factor n
so again to make this a little bit intuitive
suppose you're you trained learning machine with your favourite method which is by said
suppose you're doing something that none of us would ever do
training several learning machines very all in the test set after was to take the
one that does based on the test set
you may be right in this paper about it so all how can that be
well actually if you take any functions and you do that
then again this plant sorry
it's not written down here but
so if you take two functions and choose the one that does that
then this volunteer
tells you how far you can be
of course you estimate of the test error
function that you're reporting units papers can be from the true test error
so it can be can be a waiver factor of two more
actually it's not that bad we have the largest set
again this factor of two is really pretty insignificant compared to pass this goes to
the first step that you do computing the CSP projection is to make the whitening
of this over all
covariance OK
it means that you
the data like that
in this case
the core covariance
this is
the uniform
OK so
so you
use of this problem
the projection matrix
OK so so the interesting thing is that here the
the class axis of semantic perpendicular now
OK and now
this is just one further rotation that because is required
and so
which is to take on
so we
intuitively speaking we would like to
a number of projections where
along one projection the one class has a very large variance whereas the other one
has small variance
and next projection has
this class have large variance this one small very
and if you use all these these type of projections they called the CSP projection
use them together and you can discriminate very well
use them as input for the fire
and so
the rotation matrix basically is
you know
by computing are fulfilled
this was the two class idea so how do we do this for multi for
many classes and one obvious way to do it which is the SVM way
one against the rest
but of course also known as we ends i think we learned that there's that
smarter ways to do
and one against the rest
and so
what we
he did on proposed this is that we
we bayes we compute the multiclass CSP based on the simultaneous diagonalisation
of covariance matrices
so after whitening he would
simultaneous diagonalisation
many corporate
and in fact
so here's
so you would have
i like to find these are matrix
such that all these covariance matrices class covariance matrices
you know we would get this
to be the and the sum of all these is is unity
and in the last slide just
so in fact
here i if i put index d i here
and if i
right this is DJ
then the i plus the days equal to one
and the first is that often like these are extremely but much bigger than a
single model for
one approach to solving libraries would be to apply the same approach here so when
you have something that is defined standard c library like live or the math library
likely then you just include the entire text of the library inside the building program
but that just makes things extremely bloated i mean
think about if you just want to use print of program like we had in
this example and you have to include the entire c library which is megabytes long
that seems like not a good way of of
doing the linking
so what do with resolution libraries is
it's actually the idea is to only include
on the door to all files in the library in which undefined symbols that were
previously encountered
i define
if you think a little bit about what i said that's one reason why it's
usually good idea
when you
you know do GCC
on and use the linker use the to specify the libraries at the end
because what we're going to do is
we're take all the waterfalls and then they are going to be things like das
lm mean the standard c libraries usually by default already included on
on this on this
command line
but if you have functions like square root and so on here what we're going
to do is we're going to build up what the link is going to do
is going to build up a set of undefined symbols until it gets to the
and this going to be undefined symbols remain many if use the square root program
a square root function and you can write your own square root function
it's in the math library then
you might ask for the math library to be included and you want to pull
the definition of square from the math library
the way in which the linker knows to pull the right down five is
the math library is going to have information that says we five contains all what
any time we see an undefined symbol at this stage regardless candice archives looking for
the symbol that's been fire in particular looking in this example for the square root
and when we find the square root symbol somewhere inside in some doubt o five
we're going to take that dodo file and not the rest of the library and
use this algorithm that we did so take that don't phylogeny alone and push that
as input to
and that's the way in which we're going to build up
so that's why
least in this particular implementation of out of images of the lincoln which is very
if you put the LM will confront you're problem because if s and otto's the
father actually use quite
in the math library was included well in front then ignore
square would not yet have been part of the undefined set of symbols on until
and you know there are other ways to deal with that you could have because
they're going more passes presumably can deal with this problem but this is just an
example of how the next does this and this just work
OK so this idea of linking and on you know some resolution and relocation has
been you know people worked on this
for a very long time in almost every software system used in fact if you
use latex to build you're of you know design papers and so on on it
doesn't version of simple as it does similar solutions well because there's all sorts of
cross references that later and uses essentially the same kinds of algorithms go over the
files on and all the documents in multiple passes the results pretty general algorithm
that we describe here of building these different sets to ultimately figure out there answer
find references remaining
so one step back for a minute and generalize on
the different approaches that we've seen so far for doing on simple resolution
and so no regret algorithms can potentially do actually my if you view this as
a game and we'll talk about you know this is a zero sum game no
relevance can potentially do much better than playing minimax optimal strategy which in this case
be fifty fifty depending on how the world is
OK but they'll never do much worse so well defined minimax optimal
minimax optimality later we get to it
in fact the existence of these algorithms gives an immediate proof of the minimax theorem
will see why don't talk about that later
i just one thing to mention is that our view of the world of life
they call it is it's some unknown sequence it's in the future you know there's
going to be some sort of traffic patterns the future we just don't know what
it is
and our goal is to do well no matter what their sequences
in expectation over
internal randomisation our algorithm can use
so in particular in this view
our algorithms are going to have to be randomized
so what do i mean by that what i mean is if you the deterministic
then there always exists a sequence in which every day
you're playing the bad guy you see that that's true to fewer terms it's ready
to go what you can do the first day of them what about the world
this way and then if given that the next thing you would have done is
go up with them whether the world the next is like this if you give
me a deterministic strategy i can always reverse engineer a world in which it paying
one every single time
and in hindsight one of the two choices must have been
you know paid only half
or refer about
the only hope we have against
they can of be an adversarial view of life is have to be random
OK so kind of you in the game is of our algorithm against the
now in practice you know of the world not really out to get you your
for analysis
OK so it's a little bit an abridged history and developments of this kind of
stuff goes back quite a ways so hunan in nineteen fifty seven building on the
work of blackwell the earlier in nineteen fifty six gave an algorithm with actually actually
solves this problem
and it has attracted
o and was the number of choices we had he was amount of time
it's where over t so as time goes
because of this is dropping down to zero
exactly what want
if we just kind of re
order this in a way which i i like if you have
you know how long do we have to play
to get our average regret down to some epsilon so down to
o point
one hour
so there you are then just setting that that's on
solving forty you get
and over at once
so that's how many times you have to play in order to get your average
regret bound
the time number time to take how how quickly or converge
and this actually is optimal in terms of its dependence on to europe
you can't be scored one of security and game theory view the number of rows
number choices constant not so important number of times that so pretty much the case
ninety seven people can stop thinking
o before i get to that has been worked since then so let me get
the white how came back in machine learning let me just kind of this a
little bit about why
this is the optimal
dependence you could hope to get in terms of the
in terms dependence on t
so so think about the following setting let's go back to this picture we had
two out and two possible worlds and imagine that the way life is his life
flips a coin
that every day a fifty fifty chance this is the expensive one is the chief
one four fifty fifty chance this is the key point is expensive
so life at court then it doesn't matter what the algorithm does
to see the world for a fair coin each day to determine which type of
the it's going to be
well whenever year algorithm does there's a fifty fifty chance you have to pay
what do we do something world record so whatever your algorithm in expectation pays one-half
everyday whatever you choose to do so in a few days you're expected cost
nothing you can do that
on the other hand in hindsight
the best trout in hindsight is
if i were to flip a coin t times because had this entails is that
if the expected value of the minimum of the number of heads number tails because
i for the pointy time you know i expect over two had expected which details
but the expected minimum because it's going to be this variation expected minimum ends up
being killed over two minus
requisitioned for twenty times you know it's going to be this binomial like this in
binomial kind of first order approximation it's like
here two plus and minus square kind of sort
right so you can be
if you if you flip a coin
he target year two had customized as per the and expected that the minimum is
going to be
that's gritty
after puberty
and so you divide by t per day
if the world axis way there's no way you can help her data is going
to be one of the things we can get that
so OK so that's just explain why