property as soon as the number of measurements is bigger than this as slogan over
as factors and that's what explains the kind of the
the non-recourse results you've seen before just by taking the matrix is idea entry they
naturally have sparse nearly
nearly orthogonal columns
and that's what i call the blessing of i dimensionality when we think about high
dimensions we we think that it occurs
because you know the space is empty and so on and so forth it's precisely
because the space is empty because precisely this year is empty that i can pack
lots of columns maintaining approximate orthogonality
which is something that people go in quantum information theory all the time
so renormalisation makes life is not going to go back to your comments about how
this this play was incoherent
and so there is another way of finding matrices which is practically much more relevant
than then matrices because the problem is when we do
maybe as if you were the genesis tutorial when we try to do
real x real devices based on compressed sensing there's no way i'm going to store
and i'd just images text suppose we doing imaging where ten megapixel the five hundred
thousand measurements on the sample by twenty there's no way i'm going to store five
hundred thousand by ten mega
by ten in matrix and its
it takes thousands of DVD stephen wright the matrix so to apply it's impossible
and that's what is very important in the field to be able to have structured
matrices databases is restricted isometry property is that i don't need to store and for
which i have fast algorithms
and one way of doing this is very simple
it is to start with the unitary matrix u
like the fourier matrix that you've seen before and just to select rows around
so i could take a unitary matrix select rows at random
and that will bayes are restricted isometry property is very deep
theorem that goes back to well that was proved by myself and terence tao
also by which is an inversion but the goes back to ideas from burgas
so this result would say something like this take an orthonormal transform let's say for
look at its maximum entry squared multiplied by ten
so in the case of the fourier matrix is one
and then if you select rows at random
ips from this matrix it will be the restricted isometry property as long as the
number of measurement is essentially the coherence time the sparsity times along fact
and one versioning tells me
but if you can laws exponent from five to one
then apparently you are in the fields medal because he proved along the one conjecture
which is a big thing in numbers here
our focus now in the last ten minutes of part two and part three and
make it very short
in the last ten minutes of part two i would like to discuss applications and
opportunities so there's a lot of people working in this field as i mentioned earlier
and maybe i need to switch to
right so we can discuss
several efforts are underway to kind of leverages
techniques in hardware and and so the first stop is the discussion of new analog
to digital converters that happen to be very involved
OK so
roughly speaking when we think about how to do a conversion everything goes back to
and shannon says well suppose you want to digitize bandlimited signal that is you want
to kind of digital signal living in a certain bandwidth so for example all signals
between zero and two gigahertz say
then shannon says of course you need to sample at twice the rate so we
need to sample twice the highest frequency
and so we need two points per cycle so if i want to digitize signal
in about two gigahertz bandwidths i need to sample four billion times per second
and that's a bit of a problem because today signals to get wider and wider
band and so for example this is the united states frequency allocations map the united
states has already located about three hundred gigahertz worse than weights and so this is
reflecting the fact that signals
very wide in the frequency domain
OK for example if you go and you care about military application people can make
radar pulses that span several years at the moment because it just a short
so signals are wider and wider band and if we look at what the industry
is doing there's more flying in
in computing of course but it is also more law in analog to digital conversion
that says something like this that
if you have it in analog to digital converters that sample signals at two hundred
megahertz how long they have to wait
with a given accuracy let's say twelve bits of accuracy on the on the data
how long they have to wait until you see
the same accuracy but at twice that speed
at four hundred megahertz
and when you look at
the tripoli literature what people put out on the market it see that you have
to wait about eight years
so to double the speed i need to wait about a years is now when
i say well how long have to wait until i see your ship is actually
sampling the radio frequency band in the two point five gigahertz bandwidth with twelve bits
of accuracy
well i have to wait seventy years
a big problem because lots of people are interested in since signals are wondering wider
than lots of people interested in digitizing signals
you know why you know what
now the thing is
heavy elements of got lots of protons or positively charged packed together
feeling electrical repulsion the nucleus would apparently want to blow apart clearly doesn't otherwise you
wouldn't be here
so from that
they deduce there must be a very powerful attractive force to work inside the nucleus
to hold it together that was called the strong force
the third force called weak by comparison with strong is what caused radioactivity assert that
radioactivity beta decay
which changes one element into another is very important in the centre of the sun
fusing hydrogen into helium and start building up heavier elements which eventually
and up inside us
so those the three
forces known in nineteen fifty five
there were however
weird things happening experiment the theorist i have to confess to his actually experiment which
tells us how things work
i know
we theories like to tell you that we've got it all sorted out and the
will of the people here claim claiming string theory
explain saying this then introduced me wakes up at this point
the experiment will tell us whether that's right or wrong and experiment has a habit
of showing things that we had anticipated
and in the nineteen forties
the way the experiment was going was
looking cosmic rays sending balloons high up in the atmosphere
because out there in space nature
is providing us with naturally produced high-energy particles exploding stars
phenomena that we don't totally understand even now
particles in the space
the magnetic field in space move around and some of them hit the upper atmosphere
and in doing so
the atomic nuclei
in the
as into the atmosphere into pieces and showers of particles come
falling down and in fact passing through is right now
so by sending detectors in blue into the high atmosphere you could
these primary cosmic rays
and in doing so
they found not just the ordinary particles that went like electrons protons and photons
particles are very strange properties which became known as strange particles
and nobody anticipated these what they were nobody knew
and it was in part a desire to understand what
nature revealing from out there
there's more going on that we have previously known down here
that was the birth of particle physics and the way it was
in the nineteen fifties
the desire to be able to replicate the cosmic rays in the experiments
so the top picture shows
a picture coming from the left probably an atom
of an iron nucleus is coming the cosmic rays detected
in some emulsions hitting
and at the atom and shattering into pieces which are sharing along at the bottom
you have a picture
from many years later an experiment where beam atomic nuclei smashing to target and produce
secondary particles the point being that the observation of cosmic rays the observation discovery of
unusual particles in them
led to the desired to replicator
cosmic ray collisions in the laboratory
under controlled conditions to see if we can understand what was going on and that
was the beginnings of modern high energy physics
the result fifty years later
is that the basic structure of matter
as far electron concerns we know nothing deeper than it
as far as the proton and neutron in the central nucleus we certainly do know
something deeper than it
we know
the protons and neutrons are actually it'll clouds of quarks
and that
these many different varieties of particle that were discovered in cosmic rays and
when they started in the accelerator experiments they found hundreds of varieties of such things
different combinations of the quarks linked together just like
different combinations of
electrons make different types of elements with
excited levels
so different combination of quarks make different
collective particles
with excited levels
so these hundreds of varieties of particles that have been discovered in cosmic rays and
particle physics during the nineteen fifties and sixties we now know
are all due to a deeper layer of reality namely the quarks
and today
to the best experiment we can do
electrons and quarks appear to be the basic
letters of nature's alphabet
no i stress when i say to the best experiment we can do
we've seen this morning how
energy scales of TV
which is the highest that we can produce in the laboratory
correspond to distance scales of ten to the minus eighteen metres
so what we really saying is that on the distance scales
ten to the minus eighty meters electrons and quarks appear to have
no structure
but if we do experiments a hundred TV
and pro-business is a thousand times smaller
we might discover that in fact electrons and quarks have an internal structure
just a repeat of what we've seen over the last century when atoms were thought
to be elementary
and then you discover the structure of the atomic nucleus is thought to be elementary
and you discover the structure why not the same thing again so fair question
i will discuss it as we go along and you here
reasons why we think it isn't that simple or maybe it is we don't know
but experimentally
all we know today is that at this distance scale electrons and quarks appear to
be the basic seats
there are many profound similarities between electrons and quarks will meet
this suggests that
if they are not fundamental there's something very special this time around
nature is conspiring as if there
and this is one of the conundrums science to try to build a theory that
unifies electrons
hi everyone my name is ready and working with doctor richard green he's my supervisor
and away from the university of canterbury in new zealand let me tell you a
new zealand has an eleven hour time difference so it's about eleven PM right now
so frivolously it's not your fault okay let's get it going
boundary detection boundary detection is sometimes used as an essential first step to image interpretation
in fact there are many computer vision algorithms which rely on the boundary detection
now this here
the global probability of boundary detector is one of the best boundary detectors right now
and so that's what boundary detector looks like
so what is the boundary i'm sure it's common sense to all of you and
this here that's what humans think is where the boundaries that it had boundary
separates different areas of an image
it's that simple
the way computer the way of boundary detector works as it tries to find five
boundaries by finding significant differences between neighbouring areas areas of the same image
so what that would look like
as we look at one particular region then it would look at region next to
it would say oh these are significantly different there must be a boundary between and
so that is how the boundary detector works
but it's not
that simple because in the real world
saying these two areas are significantly different
is not simple
why not well
fixtures most images in the real world contain texture
is made up of repeating variations
and these variations are what make boundary detection quite difficult
so this here this is a little example of why
how that might look like the canny edge detector does not consider texture information and
so are one it's done
is it's looked at the end
and the barebones face
and decided all those little variations are significant
and so a naive boundary detector like this
can easily confuse these repeating variations for significant differences
so that's the problem
that has been quite
pretty much solved most images contain texture
four boundary two
the boundary detector to be good on my images therefore
that must utilise texture information
so this is very important and right here this is a boundary detector which does
not consider texture and so you can see how it's
improve the results greatly now this actually happens to be
our particular
algorithms i'll go along and i'll tell you about today
although texture people have found ways of handling the main problem right now is is
the texture is slow
most texture boundary detectors are too slow to be any use in real time
so generally they take
more than ten seconds and sometimes even three minutes per image
so it's not even an option for a real-time algorithm a lot of the time
to use the texture boundary detectors
there are a few texture boundary detectors which to work in real time but they're
they're quite low quality this is too you may have heard i consider this to
be the
state of the art the second moment matrix and surround suppression
real time texture boundary detectors like this
the like quality they can be improved a lot
and so what we need
so we need it takes the boundary detector which can work in real time
and so our preferred solution is the standard deviation ridge detector
so this detector
is capable of three things that can detect boundaries
it can ignore variations in texture
and most importantly it can do all of this in real time
so how we manage to do this well this algorithm works by finding ridges in
the standard deviation space
so there are four steps the algorithm
and i'm going to go through the right after the slide but keep in mind
the biggest difficulty is
how can you ignore these variations in texture in real time
it's quite difficult so let's see how it's done
OK so one
quite simple the standard deviation transport
for each pixel
calculate the standard deviation of the local area
and then repeat for all pixels
so you can follow that much
OK but
you probably wondering why
do we do this
well the reason one there are two reasons only reason one right now standard deviation
is approximately equal for different areas of the same texture
if we look at the standard deviation transform for this
there have been many
you'll see if this is quite true in this case the for has
approximately the same standard deviation throughout
and so
if we can design an algorithm which can detect this
then we can find a way to suppress the variations in texture
how do we do that well that is the next step
so far
but still too
the gradient transform
looks at each pixel individually
so let's say we're looking at this particular pixels
o call it the point of interest
so what happens is the surrounding pixels pull the point of interest in their direction
now we sit up the system so that pixels with a higher standard deviation have
a stronger pull
so if all these pixels on the left have greater standard deviation
and they all have more full
now of course you can probably see what we do next we take the sum
of all forces
and so that's the gradient so the overall gradient is calculated for each pixel
so naturally the gradient will point to the area of strongest standard deviation
now let's look at
but the real magic of the algorithm
this is a continuation of the task
workshop and very
about something that
future and if there is
graph g
and what about
i think it's going
OK so so this and going to talk about some more sort of been doing
this for the last
for a while now and this
so most of what i'm going to talk about it
joint work with our new engine parts of the input space consequently inria willow expert
and so basically i would like to to start with the sort of the geometric
the notion of the sort of underlying geometric notions notion of manifold and the less
sort of thing was going were interested in
and what does the data is generated by an open source you know maybe ten
written digits
which are generated by what we don't know exactly what generated by the some process
to generate an
c perfectly well
OK well in some way to get an example those very explicitly it's clear that
they have some parameters trequenu parameter representation in other domains well maybe
slightly less clear but pretty much i would say for all sorts of high dimensional
we can say that the true dimensionality is far far
lower than their sort baron dimensionality of the data and in fact one may argue
that you know if
you know
one hundred and just tried to number of pixels
hundreds of thousands and basically if the two dimensional to the is really a hundred
we will never be able to that
it's impossible
so it's really is the number of true
i mean by that is following the dimensionality of the data
another situation is much of the data is quite meaning and give a couple of
so i mean linear methods are nice but they work well in many applications but
they don't necessarily reflect the structure of the data
a simple example to think about it just a mixture of two gaussians very simple
parametric distributions you probably can do so using a linear map
well maybe you can separate them
now manifold forward to manifolds and manifolds in the fall so it slightly more general
motion so
suppose we have some sort of manifold which is a first class with probability distribution
on the surface
so the probability density may be different in different parts of the surface plus you
may think there is some maybe some noise of some so you know maybe it's
not there is not exactly on the manifold but little bit off
and this is probably one of the most general model for data that you can
so you probably to check
so for example to give example of mixture of gaussians satisfies the definition manifold is
just essentially thousands
plus you have noise which is
this is quite quite general for zero dimensional manifold wasn't as mixture
OK so let me give you a couple of examples so speech for example we
can model speech by a sequence of data elements in models which is followed by
a sequence of tubes
and while the conservatives so with bunch of two well actually citizen
you know exactly what the issue was and that's
that is clearly parameter model the speech itself is an infinite dimensional space right of
high dimensional have use this
but the students
fixed parameter something like
for example what you
i think about this for example and you just have a little by this moving
around the space here if you think of the visual field and you're just moving
this little about the number of pixels here arbitrarily large but there are just two
degrees of freedom
two-dimensional manifolds and finally something like robotics you may have something new manipulate for example
many many degrees of freedom
and we would like to study so this is not an example of an embedded
manifold we may want to study what how the location of the
also of robotics
relates to the degrees of freedom and more generally in the house great
relates to all these degrees of freedom for example the quality of the group in
england configuration of robotics on the interesting function it's linear manifold to function on the
so finally so so how do we sort of what is the connection graphs and
what sort of
what they did
we believe that they can't list in many machine learning problems we believe they come
from a probability distribution so that is probability distribution and there is a discrete version
of of this probability distribution which
the probability distribution if
i think it's meant so
then what is the point in structure or debates itself
and one may argue that
graph based representation of the data actually provides a nice model for the underlying many
so one may think graph is being discrete meaningful in the sense is that it's
sort of discretizations is a representation of the probability distribution
so kind of like
this is the samples from the manifold and a construct some graphs
and this is a graph of the presentation for
so in a sense it's sort of constructs underlying structure OK
now i think about actually problems in machine learning
how this applies to the problems of russia
of classical problems of machine learning one is that of course ification regression well we
know that this a bunch
examples and we
based on this example is going to build the classifier to classify data
classify speech
something like that of the regression you info
you know what the stock market is going
to be tomorrow from
you know what to do
yesterday could rich
then there is the representation dimensionality reduction
which has several purposes one purposes of visualization the
i like to look at the data understand what it's doing
another the purpose is sort of data quantization clustering
the same
we have to
she she
time t
when t
it was
you should
he said rules
seventy two
the term
the result was
you also
and this
we used to
it's the
can use the
all men
the way the
so that all these
it also
so there are all the same reasons
you reach the
i don't know
it all
you want to do
one of the most
all these things
it to be
the first thing to say
so what you get is this
so we get
this is the only two
i used
i love you in
he here
so there is the
you need to
for the
is huge
he he is
two years
we see
we are
it's a
and for all
one is that the
need to
this is
the whole was
magnetic flux that is created
when the current was running happily here was better in place
the current was let's say
all the time
i max
very close to the values v over are
so all the time there was he produced in the resist
i squared r joules per second
or providing that's energy well of course the battery
but now
when i take the battery out
there still current running
and that means
while the current is dying
there still he produced in that was this
that he slowly comes out until the current ultimately
become zero
so where does that energy come from
well the energy must come from the magnetic field that is present in
the solenoid
this idea here
that we have
that comes out in the form of heat
which really was there earlier in the form of the magnetic field
it allows us to evaluate
what we call
the magnetic energy
field density
let me first calculate
how much
he is produced
as the current
goes from the maximum value down to zero
and have to raise something
i raise this part
so at any moment in time
the current
is producing
heat in the resistor
and so
if i
my voltage becomes zero at time t equals zero
this is the amount
of heat
those straight here
i swear i integrated from zero to infinity is the total heat
that is produced as the current guys out
but i know what is current was just to raise it to remember it
so i can bring i max outside
and i can bring the resistance outside
and then i get the
the integral from zero to infinity
two minus are
over l times the
and this is the trivial integral
this integral is well defined by
two are
o by the way it is i squared to over two here
very important
don't forget the two
so that the integral is l divided by two are
and so if now
look at the product of ice cream maximum are l divided by two are i
get one half
i maximum
great so this comes out in the form of heat
and i'm axis and the maximum current that we had
when the current was
flowing after a long time
i can now by manipulating numbers
i can now
calculate how much
and this there was in that field per cubic meter because the magnetic field
i was exclusively inside that solenoidal
and if i know that the energy that is ultimately coming out is one have
allies claimed
that he i
so i can replace that either by b
divided by new zero
james l divided by n
and you have l
and so if i substitute in here
the value for l that we have on the blackboard there
and we substitute for either value that we have that you can drop the maximum
simply tell you them at any moment in time that have the current i running
through is solenoid
that the
and energy it is available in this order forms of magnetic energy is one of
our square
so when you do that
we substitute capital l
and capital
i you'll find
that one half
ellis created
then becomes
the squared
over two new zero
and my little are cleared
times l
checked that at home
simply substitution
but this
is the volume of the solenoid
where the magnetic field exists then we have assumed that the magnetic field is zero
everywhere outside
and if you accept that
then you see
that we now have a
results for
the magnetic
energy density
that is how much energy it is a cubic metre
that is of course this value
because this is the total energy of the magnetic field
if we know the current
and this is the volume of the magnetic field
so the magnetic field energy density
is then be grid
divided by two new zero
this is in joules per cubic metre
so in principle
if you're not to magnetic field everywhere in space
you can integrate over all space
you can calculate how much energy
present in the magnetic field
and earlier in this course we did something similar for electric field
we calculated electric field energy density
if you remember what it was it was one half
actually non-zero kappa
time is credited with also in jules
a cubic metre
now in the case of an electric field
it represents the work that i have to do to arrange the charges in a
this very simple information can be enough
to detect attacks
and think about this
this is the kind of that is that
once you have the points in the data and
metric space
there are many ways to connect similarity between those points
and this is something about that
hasn't been very wide
used in machine learning
most people have used corals
that correspond to the sensors
the euclidean distance
this is basically a simple expression for kind of
like the product of the
two very large but sparse vector
but there are also other ways too
measure similarity
that turned out
to be not so difficult to implement from the technical point of view
you can use various metric distances
i in
so this is there are having taken
there are also some interesting on similar cases that have been known from the fifties
sixties and various other fields
of data analysis and it turns out that some of them very interesting characteristics of
some very
shows the performance on the net
in order to deal with it
similarity measures efficiently we have come out
compute the
similarity measures
in a unified fashion
so basically think about it
computing all fun
all down to some
how does that runs over some operations all on a single word
because of that one show that
you have a general
performs an operation on elementary
o operations and you can define the operations
in the final operation
in a meaningful way that very simple
so this is basically what you have to do one single currency in order to
add at the top end the abstract
abstract framework
what almost until his death
essentially we like to to design efficient algorithms for
now algorithms that run in
linear time
that have efficient indexing of all the dimensions
the the space from that data into extremely high demand for thank
in all possible combinations of and random high dimensional space can be very large numbers
but you only have a small number of possible and ground in the final data
if you are able to index this
the subset of features and efficient way
we can
efficient around the best
and the many
data structures that can be used for that we have what we have developed for
the particular hash tables tries suffix trees and some more advanced features
recently there are four
tells you how it works in one case so you can try this
some of them may know
it's actually
very classical data back to the sixties and seventies
and it basically boils down to
storing the dictionaries of words
in the compact representation
you can see here for example
i think by high card
can be stored basically no
where you share
the car card
same representation
and you can store some additional information
that allows the can
tell you
the frequency
individual time
so you can
store the number of assertions
this is an example
what card
has been studied
let's see has four times three times on one card
and one from the work of
and so on
you also count the number of leaves
which are the node
that correspond to single words in the
in this case
this branch has one only
which part of by
and this branch
two leaves
in all nodes on the path to car because this was one word
and then one the corresponding to work on
so by using information you can essentially compact have of trees
in some sort of parallel traversal algorithm
basically works for
for free from top down
each time taken for the similarity of nodes
individual no labels not correspond
we find in this mismatch
so you find that
keep going
and you also have something called local mismatches
which is the local node that you have matching symbols
but i have course on the difference in the corresponding labels
this one does have a leaf labels and this one does not
there is also counted as in this match
finally we propose
further down the line that
turns out linear runtime complexity is linear and this is what what we need
OK so you can
we have in this case
dependent on the k is
number of cases
you can think of
the decay constant not interested in
extremely large round
the following content is provided under creative commons license your support will help MIT opencourseware
continue to offer high quality educational resources for free to make a donation or view
additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses visit MIT opencourseware at OCW MIT
that u
i want to pick up
exactly where i left off last time
when i was talking about various scenes one can commit with statistics
and i have been talking about this in the data enhancement
where the basic idea there is you take a piece of data
and you really much more into it that it implies in particular
a very common thing people do with data
is a extrapolate
i given you a couple of examples
in the real world
it's often not
desirable to say
i have a point here
and the point here there for the next point will surely be here
and we can just extrapolating a straight line
we before soft some examples where i had an algorithm to generate points and we
fit the curve to it use the curve to predict future points and discovered it
was nowhere close
unfortunately we often see people do this sort of thing one of my sister favorite
stories william ruggles house
who was
head of the environmental protection agency in the early nineteen seventies
and he had a
press conference spoke about the increased use of cars
and the decreased amount of carpooling
he was trying to give in people the carpool the time carpooling was on the
way down
and i now quote
each car entering the central city
started in nineteen sixty he said
each car entering central city had one point seven people in it
by nineteen seventy this had dropped to less than one point two
if present trends continue
by nineteen eighty
more than one out of every ten cars entering the city will have no driver
amazingly enough the press reported this is a straight story
and talked about how we would be dramatically dropping
i have course
as it happened it didn't happen didn't occur
but it's just an example of
how much trouble you can get into my extrapolating
the final scene i want to talk about is is probably
the most common
and it's called the texas sharpshooter
now for a given session is are immediate from texas
our right is going to be offended
i mean things can anybody here from oklahoma
you like it dump on oklahoma would be much better than i will talk about
the oklahoma sharpshooter fallacy
we will talk about the BCS rankings
so the idea here is pretty simple one
this is a famous marksman
who fires his gun randomly at the side of the bond
has a bunch of holes in it then goes and takes a piece of of
can of paint
and beauxis
around all the places but what's happened here
and people walk by the bonnet say god he is good
so obviously
not a good thing
amazingly easy to fall into this trap
so here's another example in
august two thousand one
a paper
which people took seriously
appeared in moderately serious journal called the new scientist
and announced that researchers in scotland
had proven
the anorexics
are likely to have been born in june
i'm sure you all knew that
how did he had they proved this or demonstrate this
they study four hundred forty six women
each of whom had been diagnosed is anorexic
and they observed
about thirty percent
more than average
born in june
now since the monthly average of births
divide this by twelve is about thirty seven
that tells us
that forty eight
we're born in june
so i first sight this seems significant and in fact if you run tests
and ask what's the likelihood
of that many more being born in one month
you'll find it it's quite unlikely
in fact you'll find the probability of this happening
is only about three percent
which generates mappings between these
different representations and basically are present
information in sort of modality neutral way
well let's see deal with images and text then we are able to such a
representation tool transition from images into text and back getting good work we will get
back images
so quite efficient technique
last three hear presentations which have just briefly mentions of first one would be this
collaborative tagging which appeared
so the relevant representation on the recently with this appearance of web two point zero
and physically collaborative tagging is a process of adding metadata to annotate some kind of
content and this content can be documents web sites photos and so on are most
often we have these annotations in the form of
actually keywords and what's important is that this is being done in a collaborative way
by many users from larger community so here we discuss about this long tail and
so on which of these big community has collectively a lot of knowledge and somehow
we would try to align all the participants of the community is situated they express
their knowledge much less in the same language and this language would be this keyword
most of us are designed to get this annotated data small for the low relatively
low cost and then
we can all this operate with this that here we have two examples so from
if you're gonna flickr so here i have photos which certainly it's hard to do
images our
everybody who uploads
photos at this tax a
in the form of keywords solely this key these photos are getting comparable because we
can just compare just the keywords and this person quite well actually
in the same way this would work for
the so-called delicious so here we annotating photos on flickr delicious is is this folksonomy
other people
at are annotated websites so this is the
search for text mining can hear more less you get all kind of text mining
websites and since they share this text mining keywords and then we get these results
i think we would have a little bit more problems by getting such relatively clean
clean list of websites
the idea behind this collaborative work is basically
still a lot of people around the world which have enough free time to add
this information to explore exploiting this good in three times p
templates frames so this would be a little bit more sophisticated techniques o
and the idea here is to extract
information from text by using some kind of domain specific linguistic better here i will
show some of these batteries
let's say
this would be
from this system called know it all
this will be set of better of the show basically how this works
let's see if it if we put in a will
better like this
cities such such as
now we get a list of documents in most likely
whenever this cities such as appears
will be behind behind it will be the name of the city
and so we recognise
one is the type of the word just by
applying this linguistic better
on the
of but by using this linguistic pattern to for the search
or the two cities such as glasgow
and so on so in the same way we can we can develop or even
linguistic patterns for which are domain specific and we can capture a lot of information
about the this is
an interesting technique which is
recently used guess in semantic web a lot because with this kind of veterans we
can model different relationships and concepts and so on
and the last one hundred thousand is smallest at the end of the the borel
ontologies so here's the idea is really to represents the
the content of the text in the first logic for first order logic and ontologies
more less vocabulary which carries this information and the relationships between pieces of information
so i'll skip the details here because we'll touch semantic that the DNC maybe just
to show you an example of how text can be translated in the first order
logic let's this is an example from cyc system which was afterwards so if we
have a sentence like this there is groups are capable of directing because this nation
so this can be translated to first order logic so that
if something which
variable groups if something is terrorist group then this implies that this group is also
behavioural so in the relationship here kappa capable weights
as estimating something so these are concepts from the ontology and so i don't know
about this so this is also sort of relationship and here's a little bit longer
sentence which is translated in the first order theory so this is
this is
something which we would like to out myself a lot but it is still difficult
to the moment
at the end of the show how these kind of representations can be used for
a very complex question answering
OK so this so much about the representations about text now
once we have text presented in such a way
what can we do with it
so here i will show just the most typical tasks which we can perform many
more tasks but
but it's just a couple of
the main one
for document summarisation this is
so summarisation is quite on text is quite hard problem
nobody really succeeded
to do it properly
so what the task was given the task is very simple just to produce shorter
summary version of an original document nothing more than this
and they have two main approaches to this one of the so-called selection based on
over the summer just a selection of sentences from an original document and this is
something which you can get in microsoft word or in some of these
commercial products
tuesday is market day before yesterday
here you have examples of vector f u v w c
and what can i say about that so
so those are victorious
the spaces are two
and for instance if you do the difference between
u and v
this vector
which is w
and if you remember what you did when you were in high school
it doesn't matter whether these w w is here or here or here
this is exactly the same victory
you don't care about the precise location where it is
if you do the sum of u and v
you have these long vector here
which is just obtained by
i think you just moved to along this vector and then you had this victory
to the end of this vector so you do this path and then you end
up with
these these long vectors
and if you divided by two
in the middle of these two points
and the the last thing i don't even know if it's necessary to talk to
you about that but
let's talk to you about that if you have a scholar here and which is
between zero and one
then the resulting vector the multiplication of land by
he is
this vector
so it's a vector which is between which is which is based on these on
this line
and depending of the value of mandates closer to here or here
in a product so in products if you if you if you if you missed
the slide if you don't understand the slide
it's done for you
what i'm going to talk to you about for the remaining of this talk is
just how you deal with his
inner product or dot products maybe a little bit more elaborate it into an elaborate
dot products but
i'm just going to talk about
dot products so
so again this is something that you learn in high school
so this is something that is symmetric which means that you you take the argument
against swedes then you still have the same value its billionaire
meaning that if you take one victory taking the inner product by by himself you
have a value that is non negative
and define it meaning that if
it's kind of a product of a vector brain cells is equal to zero then
it means that you is zero itself
and so what
an inner product or dot product tells tell tell us about the the space
it provides the structure of the space where you leaving actually t provides structure because
if you do a little bit of topology the main tool is distance and
scalar product
induces the distance
so there's is a here you can see the norm
and from this normally can you can derive a distance which is already related
so if you don't like the
mathematical parts of of
of things just think of an inner product as the similarity of similarity functions and
you happy so
this is one of the first message that you have to take home today
so it's it's the beginning of the talk but still it's very important message message
if you have a similarity function between the object you you're the objects that you're
going to work on the new happy
you can do a lot of things
there's a slight thing that i don't say when i say that because there's some
heritage details on the similarities but OK just just say that you have a similarity
you're almost happen
and the last thing that is very important is that if you want to compute
the norm that the length of
vector he just taking the inner product of you
and you
and if take the square root and give you the distance the norm of the
so let's stay at the high school level
in our two you have one victory with the two coordinates
and another one and the prior to the
the natural inner product is just the sum of the product between of the corresponding
now we are back with a little sketch here so what is important well what
i want you to show is how
the inner product is core correlated to the fact that two vectors
o point
to the same direction or not
here if you look at these vector
you minus the this this vector or detector
and you look at each
then you see that they
o point
to the same direction
two the upper left corner core of these what
and when it is the case then you have the inner product on the of
those those two guys which is positive
on the other hand hand if you take the if you look at
your mind is v and g
they're pointing towards
opposing opposite directions
and in this situation the dot product is is negative
otherwise if the two vectors are perpendicular or or to low then the the dot
product is equal to zero
so that's it
you know
develop new operations because thanks completely forgot to verify that the information could be maintained
so you want to make sure that you've done all those so usually you have
to play
with the actions
in between step
it's not just a
do this to this to this
they were going to do now a more complicated data structure
not that much more complicated but its correctness is actually kind of challenges
answer is actually very
practically useful data structure
o amazed at how many people
i'm aware that there are
these structures of this nature they are useful for them
when i see people writing a really slow code
OK and so the example random interval trees
and the idea this is that we want to maintain
for example time intervals
so the whole database of time intervals that i'm trying to maintain
so let's just do an example here
that's it
this is going from seven to ten
five to two eleven
four eight
from fifteen eighteen
seventeen nineteen
twenty one to twenty three
OK so is the set of intervals
OK and
if we have in our life
since this interval i
which is seven karma
and we're going to call
this endpoint we're going to call the low
and point by i
and this we're going to call the high
o point of i resign is low and high rather than left to right
is because
never tree and ran what the left subtree in the right subtree
if i start saying
left and right free intervals and left and right for trees were really really confused
this is also attempt let me say when you're coding
you really have to think hard sometimes about the words that you're using for things
especially things like left and right because they get so over used throughout
so you
you know it's a good idea to come up with the whole wealth of synonyms
for different situations so it's clear in any piece of code
when you're talking for example about the intervals versus the trees is around both going
on here
OK and what we do is we want to have a we want to support
insertion and deletion of
the intervals here
and i would have a query which is going to be the new operation developed
which is going to be defined
an interval any interval
in the set
the overlaps
the query interval
OK so i give you a query interval like say
a let's say
you know six
and you can return
you know
this guy is this guy
this guy
could return any of these
because these are all less than fourteen
so whatever
i can return any one of those i only to return one
this to find one guy that overlaps
any question about
what we're going to be
setting up here
so our methodology
is we're going
first of all step one
here's our methodology
OK so step one is we're going to pick a
two underlying data structures
anybody ever suggestions to what the structure we only use here
the support interval tree
but this structure should try start with
this support interval tree is
interval tree is
have an idea
a red black tree binary search tree a red black tree really is a red
black tree
so i got to say what is he doing
so what's going to be the key for my red black trees so for each
interval which lay uses the he
this is this is where this is
because the lunch options here right
are some ideas i always better to branch than it is to prove
i crime later but if you don't
branch and never get a chance to
so the generation of ideas you need that when you're doing the design phase in
doing the the take-home exams
so we're kind of low
blackboard can i raised
create a little bit to do it
just to give you an idea of what is the simplest complex many of you
know what it is but maybe some of you don't so i just just like
to draw a few pictures
so what it is i don't think
i think
the simplest complexes typically a geometric object which is formed from
from simple geometric components for example two dimensional simplicial complex would be formed from triangles
and of course the edges of the triangles belong to the vertices and these geometric
objects are nicely put together so that the and the boundaries of these triangles are
glued in nice way maybe we had that we can have a triangle sticking out
like this but it can stick out like this because the vertex has degree two
vertex for simplest complexes are geometric objects consist of which consists of simple geometric shapes
triangle in the two dimensional case that he in the three dimensional case
and the more generally what is that regular within group together along the the
for surfaces and more generally if implicit in high dimensions a simplex is just a
higher dimensional analogue of these things that we have over here in dimensions and three
well general general set of compromises something a little bit more general so it's official
complex really has these local triangular shapes while so complex can also have for example
hexagonal shape polygonal shapes in general and it can also maybe have curved shapes like
this this would be awful of complex for this kind of geometric structures are used
to model this data to to achieve this solve this problem
i would like to five to give general clouds of points structure so this idea
of using objects that this of this structure data both very far back it goes
back to the clear which lived in the nineteenth century and the voronoi in the
beginning of the twentieth century the linear in the thirties so these are people who
are already used this idea of what to come up with the basic models and
then there are a lot of people who work in this nowadays and i just
put here down to names because they were sort of made especially impression to me
but there's a lot of people who work in the field of computational topology who
well who designed algorithms for solving problems like this for constructive simplicial complexes on a
finite set of points this is typically computer science called triangulation so we're talking about
three years here
so as i said there's a number of algorithms number of implementations libraries and so
on for a lot of people work in this field and this is quite well
represented in most of these
for example algorithms and so on in most of these models that exist the prevailing
model which is used as the simplest complex for triangulation or maybe already are so
complex and there's a little problem with this model and the problem is that it's
a huge thing because we are talking about different simplest of complex we want to
list all the elements of the triangulation want to list for example in this case
the trial this part of it should be re-set the triangles as well as the
edges as well vertices so there's a lot of data to list of when talking
about simplicial complexes so the problem is that these models are sometimes not as effective
as they won what was deemed to be
but on the other hand using these kind of models on the other hand we
we have policy into practice policy which is what it's not very old field but
there's a whole arsenal of various topological invariants which we can use point to stand
this object to come up with so we have this
cloud point of data we construct for example a simplicial complex on it and now
use all these topological invariants like for example homology groups homotopy groups and so on
to understand what kind of an object this this this model of the reconstructed is
understand its shape and its properties better
so as i mentioned already one of the problems with this approach is that the
plot to commence mothers which we come up with are often very very big so
here's an example of this is a simplicial complex was constructed in our lab maybe
a year or two ago
so this is the triangulation of
the parts of space where the set of
the art of sailing boat is taken out and the reason for this triangulation was
that we're doing some modelling on fluid flow around the shape of the on around
the whole of the sailing boat well in order to do that you have to
have a very very very big triangulation so this one for example i think has
more than a million triangles so it's really huge well of course for our experiments
we need a lot of triangles so in this case it wouldn't make sense to
make a smaller object but in the sense of understanding the shape of this year
of the how well a million triangles is obviously or to to hear stories obviously
too much so we could simplify the strangulation a lot for that purpose well anyway
as we see the fact that we have very very large model scores for implementation
are efficient that have implementations of things which are simpler than simplicial complexes for example
typically see the CW complexes are a nicer way to describe the logical spaces and
we would like to have a few thousand possible to still grasp the metadata that
we need of course and on the other hand we need efficient algorithms to do
with things like this
OK so these are two major problems which are addressed in computational topology now here's
another problem the problem the other problem is that well we have this
the first
will actually see that a lot of the mechanism is very similar to what we
had before
it's just
you know reapplying the same tricks again
the first thing that we had all the exponential family
model so p of x
parameterized by theta
given by
e two
five with theta
minus gl later
and this is why is called the sufficient statistics
this was called the natural parameter
and this was the
cumulant generating function
and we
then concluded after a bit of the derivation that if we want to
right the negative log posterior
so minus
of p of
given the doctor solvent of observations
this would be
in general given by
m tom's
g of data
one m
some i going from one
five of x i
inner product with data
one of the two sigma squared
norm over theta squared plus some constant which is independent data
and so this was basically
trying to estimate with their parameter from the exponential family with corresponding
critical organisation of data we saw that there are connections to agustin process
and i'm not going to go into that very much more detailed and that there
are connections to extremes
so that's what we did not find
read if we looked at something like a like iteration and we derive the margin
and their connections to novelty detection
the next six makes that we do is we said well actually rather than building
a generative model
we might want to look at the discriminative models
in other words i might want to look at or conditional models we have p
of y
and parameterized by theta
would be given in the very same form as above by the two them
in approach between forth ics and why
and theta
and now the normalisation will depend on the location so minus two data given x
and again this will be
government generating function but not for conditional models
this to be sufficient statistics in x and y natural parameters
and just incomplete similarity to about here
we have the corresponding map problem
of minus log
p of
given x and y
being given y
and now we had
well some over
are you going from one m
g of data
given x y somebody actually reminded me that i had forgotten to break their minus
inner product between
five of x i y i
and theta
one of the
two sigma squared
norm of
o thing to win
plus the concert
and what we saw is that depending on what model you pick for y
like which domain which type of sufficient statistics you could actually recover a couple of
estimation procedures for discussing process classification will come up with a special case
now what we're going to do today is
we're going to exploit the connection between this and the exponential and the graphical model
a bit further
the third ingredient that we had was if we have some graphical model
then there's the difficult theorem
which tells us
p of x
has to be written
well that's just some normalisation the product
overseeing the set of maximal cliques
of so c
of six
and basically what it means is that for any distribution with certain conditional independence structure
which can be nice to represented by a graph
density the joint density in or distribution over all the random variables
assuming that doesn't vanishingly where
i can be written as a product of functions on the maximal cliques
again this has the consequence if we combine it with our exponential families notation
well of function
why of fakes
had to be written
as some form some functions phi c
of c
the ice is the example of variances is of the axis of the sample variances
which is what these things are then
you get
the some of these and these
there are the sample variances of the principal components of the ones
so that's
that's why one
so if you take the vector y one of the y two also always one
and then you get the same total
as if you take x one so sec it's variance in order additive
so let's say you can think of this as
in some ways
decomposing these variances into an nice form
so we end up with
what we're doing this procedure
two the iris data
you can see that
y three y for the third and fourth principal components
was no
because pounds
involving one three are constantly evolving one four
the second one one
got one one one one seems to give me too
so some sort of this is second
but focus
well this depends on
and how much is going to some people would argue that sort of bounded and
the weights of people argue that with me
also feel
people who basically
well before
the information in the two clusters spread all over the diagram
well to this all
the picture tells you about sampling cells are two
what's the problem
length tells the
two really
which tells us to
and i think you see some of the problems with
but combinations of who said what you can see
so what does anyone basic structure that the two groups
so what we have actually managed to achieve
the basic structure is now confined to just one variable
a lot not for the labels it was before so we will concentrate the solution
to this although here might argue the
i want to white so basically all the basic variational bayes
structure that information is not one one so we could discuss y two y three
y four because they're just one fluctuations
that's the thought behind it
so you do that way by looking at the pictures i will want to be
but it also
trying decide how many
dimensions you have otherwise effective dimensionality various sort of ad hoc methods of doing this
is the formal
correct one but this is what people do
so the first one is
remember is that this is quantity for example on this but if the same as
the whole of the variance for the axes
you can say well what proportion of variance
picked so if i just take the first are composed of photographers two is what
proportions that mix of looking at the situation five lambda one lambda two divided by
the sum of all the wonders can say ninety four seventy percent but i would
tend to think that was a good representation of the data
if i was looking at a picture of what if we also so that's one
do people use
one is this
the no
falsifications just this is what people think works
so it's important variance
if you take the average of the wonders
that the
if you see
so there is less than the average and variation
if you find lot less than the average number but that's really saying that if
you can actually read this beta which had swept you two one which is where
the vision
there you can rewrite is something nice
and prime
is the proportion of positive that so he might be present and what you get
if you rewrite like this is
a difference where where
s trying now takes the role the true probability this is the proportion of positives
second that you're talking about
the second here but it is it is referred to as the
he had the story
it's in your best gnx but only talks about the slope of process
for a long story short you can do this decomposition
exactly which is different from for fear of the
two with approximately
dividing this quantity will be
using the wrong
you could have two debates inside the boundaries you can examine close these two things
this not something very useful but because
if this decomposition gives you much more information than the previous four games with itself
is you
to show that
i have a problem here also some actual models that we
basically this is doubtful cross validation so
this is a performance
each of the ten fold so i wanted to look at is
these points here i left
which is
clearly can
calculate probability just go right
binary numbers so it is not not surprised that this is not going to
but by doing the ROC convex hull penetrations
we can get the calibration loss
close to zero
but if we in
have a little bit refinement loss because are creating the convex hull
many previously we've only horizontal and vertical segments which means that we find a lot
of zero
by introducing times
we will not get segments so we
the calibration of close to zero at the expense of a slight increase of of
the refined and is another example here we have the calibration with the same as
the naive bayes
and you could argue that may be in three four
in this celebration doesn't make an awful
so it's really interesting because these are important in machine learning the first ones i
haven't seen with BPP any results related to machine learning i was just showing this
because that's the idea of one of the national ideas of randomness is to do
that idea is to say
take it totally
asymmetric view
which is the same well we want some
nondeterministic of course machines but this time either no computation accepts
OK no computation is you can't accept that we know or half of them do
now what's the difference between the thing before
and come to say it's not sure we'll come back to that later
so for the following with this so this is really the number of computations are
not taking the different steps
which i'm doing it i really want half of the computations being able to say
that half the computations work or at least some fraction
larger than zero is going to is going to work
what people believe is in our opinion believe is not
and the is sorry yes i believe it is in our
it is in our people without being now what i'm saying is to not be
but not p OK policy product polynomial in equivalence
so in equivalence
so the idea is you've got some polynomials
kx one plus three x say it right next to the squared plus three multiplied
by often
another one will be explored seven and here's some more polynomials and the question is
if i do
the product of these polynomials and here the product of these polynomials
do we obtain something different
so i suppose we've got this polynomial this
this part of
i know about this one this one this one this one this one so don't
have to be the same length
the question is
do if i by all this together and i'm going play all this together as
far as polynomials go
are they are they different
so how would you solve that problem
the basic way of solving the problem is just to develop
this into a some
of monomials this into a sum of monomials and see if you do the same
if you think that clearly gives us nazis you obtain the same that you're done
you say yes sorry say no
they are not different and if you think something different than you say yes there
are different what's the problem with that approach
problem with that approach is that it is too long
because if you start taking all these products thinking about the big problems here you're
going to be in size not polynomial so the algorithm itself that you could be
thinking about of developing all this is not
so that doesn't work nevertheless why is this problem in our p
because you can prove quite easily that if you take
some number
right and you just apply this part of the of each one of these polynomials
with this number
and then building the product
of what you obtain
do the same here
well case number one is they are they are equal meaning by that the answer
should be no when you're always going to obtain the same answer so just answer
no that's no problem
case number two is that these polynomials
the result
is sort of the the product of these polynomials is different to product this polynomials
apart from in a finite number of cases you should be updating something different
OK if i give you a fuzzy calculator
the value zero well
for value zero might be OK but i mean i would be OK for a
certain number of possible routes and here press officer
a number of possible but in most cases i would be different
so so in fact in that case i will be obtaining yes
very often so i've got a nice
randomized algorithm that solves in polynomial time this this problem whereas i do not have
it is not approved of course the problem is not p
if we could prove the problem is not in p then we would have typical
prove that p is
different from NP but you can see why people believe that is not in PC
and believe that it is in our p
OK so there's a special class called zpzp p is zero error probabilistic polynomial time
that is just to the intersection of four and co RP is saying well perhaps
i can
so make mistakes on one side small and on the other side small run both
algorithms and parallel
and notice that if i you know if i repeat experiments various times we taking
random numbers i'm i'm pretty sure
that's pretty sure means i can get the probability of making an error down to
rule something very very very small
so this sort of algorithms which basically i just keep on repeating a certain number
of times the
the experiment until i'm happy about things or usually called las vegas
they the
they are always right because of the end of the day i'm really going to
be able to to reach short conclusion but what's going to happen is that there
might be worse case where really got keep on going until i get this conclusion
i need those words case absolutely horrible what happens in the worst case because i
mean the randomized situation are going to be so false so
so unusual that it's only in average i'm going to be college
so let's have a guess in quite the same as the monte carlo
OK let's see
quickly yes
two examples some examples of stochastic algorithms just for the sake of it
monte carlo algorithms
really folks for
the response
he that's sent ten percent of
you are
suppose now twenty one three
for the one that really wish
so this is more
the rest
have to just
or you were
i think one
so that's all
or the area
this is
so the important
threshold so it's an
he was
that's right
so well
probability metrics
and one one
so that that's where
there is a small
or one five to three
things like this one
so that means that he
what i want to track
harry potter
so for have
it's you know it was
we're going to see things
based on
so you see this for a year or any sort of g
just like in the
the one
i think it's wrong
the brain does not work so
she three
use it to model selection
the second half still
and he
she that it would
based on that
three were
you know
twenty years
while you were problems
all the problems in the world
i don't
at last
are one problem
on the day when the
but problem
for his work
i don't know
i don't want to be
you did
it's really a sufficient condition for a long
and then it
one is
there also
what is it
and so
cells so the
he was
what is self
but the average all
eighty nine problems so
to your benefit and use
well i turn out solutions
only on an individual basis in the fashion that i just described i found that
if i write down the solution to each of these problems you don't do them
and you say ah so that's how you do that throat and if i not
look at it until the night before the quiz
there were not solutions handed out others and corrections on an individual basis on your
so said all i i wanted to say
i think that's about all
for the formalities
actually i should
had one postscript they say the the causes don't
how they excuse me the problem sets don't count anything put your final grade
they do in one minor sense when you have a large class in new plotted
the grades and there are no obvious with gaps in between the comes a point
where you have to separate one group from another
and if you'd done well on the quizzes and you've done well on the problem
sets and there's just one quiz it's a little bit though it's OK here she
had a bad day that afternoon and i'll give you the benefit of the doubt
and even though i'm not a vindictive sort if you're right on the fence you
haven't done any other problems
then without malice i say
gotcha you about how whole and those side of the barricade and i think that's
only a natural indication because there are some cases where with solomon judgement you have
to decide who
it's what green
OK let me say have a little bit about two
there are
a number of books that deal with crystallography
for the most part though they
it consists of an introductory chapter every single book on the solid state feels compelled
to write some sort of half-baked chapter crystal structure or crystallography
usually these chapters consist of big tables
and they say there are
fourteen of these there are seventeen of these there were thirty two of these there
were two hundred thirty of these in one thousand one hundred seventy of these
and then
that has all the excitement and stimulation of reading the telephone directory
you know it's the crazy cats the characters but it's awfully hard to to see
the plot
so what we will do
all the way through is derived everything so you can not only see how it
turns out why it has to be that way
and that's the way in my opinion one really wants this material
a couple of other very pedantic comments about the material
in the early part of the term in the first half in fact we're gonna
use plain old geometry
geometry really doesn't cut much mustard around the institute they if you can integrated or
take its fourier transform that's the mathematics you don't have to take seriously
geometry is a perfectly valid branch of mathematics and one can do what we're going
to do
in more complex terms using the language of group theory and we will in fact
use a little bit that later on but for the most part just diagrams with
simple geometry are they going to be one of the principal tools in the initial
part of the class
about halfway through will switch over to something that is much more mathematical in the
traditional sense here a little bit of linear algebra and matrix algebra will help you
if you have had better have a look at for a while will build up
from ground zero so that you will be able to fully understand it
will hit if you igon value problems towards the end of the term is that
it doesn't to get your adrenaline pumping that will be developed in the physical context
so that you're doing this sort of problem before you even know what it's called
so it's going to be user-friendly cause that doesn't rely on something that you may
have had two or three years ago
OK but
the other thing that i wanted to say was that this
it is not like many classes and that you talk about something for one week
and then you could decide to talk about something completely different the next week or
first half of the course will be one of long process of synthesis
we're going to start out very very simply with the mapping transformations this is picked
up and rotated over to here and you say all on let's get on with
it come and go faster but
will build on this and then build on what we've just done to what comes
next and unlike most of the classes in science that you take
where you start with general terms and you zero in on some little nugget like
f equals m a equals
mc squared
lambda equal to decide
a little nugget like the billion cubic can drop in your pocket and then when
you need it later on you pull it out and add
hot water and then you have the tool that you can use
we will do something that's completely
different and its structure will start out simple it will grow it will blossom like
an elegant villa agreed structure that gets more and more complicated and diverges rather than
converging to an nice title market
it's going to get very very complicated
and the reason for doing this gradually and thoroughly is so that you can understand
the complexity and we're comes from
OK so my moral here is keep up it may seem easy when you start
but we can assume that you've got that down cold before we go on to
the next step
OK texts
how apart from these have big treatments which i just keeps going on one of
apply as human see what's happening
and starting from that
we often read in the literature that has been was presented as the leading classification
however in some situations
in my experiment but also in other experiments in the literature we observed naive bayes
can also classifiers to
twenty outperform as you
so why in which settings
how can we avoid this situation of
if so
how can we take discovered is
to answer this question we must develop better understanding and that fits quite well in
in the work which was done initiated in
in both together
because courses are working with the learning so they want to get a lot of
of knowledge from
what working on and then to try to apply given his knowledge
try to play successfully some techniques
so that remains
in the initial target
a quick recall to frame a bit everything
introduction to text classification what kind of data set by using
what is after datasets publicly available
and austin all about fifty thousand medical abstracts
of cardiovascular disease
data set i'm using
twenty news groups about twenty thousand images of varying things
this spread into twenty categories twenty newsgroups writers i also using twenty newsgroup it was
initially does it actually
writers to couple plus all this this is the rate descent try to school this
published two years ago
data transformation
and you can perform stemming you can
compute and round TFIDF and actually i don't do anything on the dataset just use
it as it is
then binary classification task because we could consider multiclass categorisation
i won't discuss now
why but it is motivated
we can discuss it after discussion that interest you
i'm going to get a by using as sources where
used in the previous previous work and we especially focus
i mean i support vector machines
we can study
and the different viewpoints those classification techniques we can either reduce the number of columns
of your data metrics also number flies
so to reduce the number of columns you perform some feature selection construction
in our case today
it is not topic two
comprises techniques we just select information gain which was demonstrated at
good in the first one
but when performing
in terms of resampling
on the other hand we reduce the number of documents of the train set but
then we systematically calibrate so which means we have systematically as many positive and negative
documents the train set
like if i have
transit of sixty four
in the following figures then it means thirty two city two
and so on five hundred twelve and so on
for evaluating a user classical f one measure which is the harmonic mean between precision
and recall
i give formula to give you some idea and that's what's used use information retrieval
and text classification so it's not
fancy machine
what we also
because the train at this time but i don't speak about it today
given our focus which was really two to compare widely on a wide range of
experiments settings
we draw
many learning curves and then we try to see OK what's happening
so it was quite
heavy work because we had spent hundreds of classification task which we then
where we will
we major
o cos
a lot of work
and in the beautiful world what you would expect is to have really nicely look
she was
the wireless
i don't know whether this makes any difference OK
so the wireless network works again also the wiki
works again in case you don't know this this some kind of online collaboration tools
and in particular if you don't have the
slides of two myself months talk in the
i think he will hand the model he has and the amount then you can
find them on the wiki
so this is the
what can i was just pointing out that the IP number so there is no
name for it if you type this into your browser if you connected to the
wireless network you should be able to access it and you find a lot of
stuff on that you can find some pictures of people have taken during the summer
anything else
OK so i think i want to do more time from thomas and i look
forward to his tutorial
OK thank you that introduction
right actually i just noticed that there is no clock and i have no
wristwatch so maybe someone could give me a sign you know after forty minutes or
so i can you know five minutes to
one break in
OK so
i just arrived an and an overnight flight from the from these coast so i'm
not a hundred percent clear maybe it's because of that but i will talk about
machine learning information retrieval
and you know there will be some technical content but also try to provide some
you know what problems in information retrieval when machine learning can be useful and you
know that should give the motivation to learn more about machine learning but also talk
about specific machine learning methods here
OK so let me begin with part zero
you know
we can look back in the history of mankind you know and ask ourselves in
the issue of dealing with knowledge and text right and we would see that you
know the very early stage of the of the culture all civilizations
it was important basically to preserve the knowledge and the way it is typically happened
was in libraries right and so you know there are some famous ones on here
library of alexandria
and then in more modern times british museum and library of congress of course you
can see that the number of documents number whatever books or scrolls in the early
days you know increases dramatically in particular over the last couple of years now
this of course is mainly due to the fact the very recent increase in information
that space available in
the repositories due to
the fact that a lot of documents are now in digital format right and the
kind of the all-encompassing repository of course the world wide web which today has seen
several ten billion documents but you know and their digital libraries we have special purpose
content providers like lexisnexis to provide almost as much content as there is on the
web so there a huge content repositories you know companies have their own intranets and
what's called digital assets basically right documents in chile that that somehow encoded the knowledge
in a company
and we have scientific literature databases medical information portals and so on and so forth
so there's a lot of that stuff out there a lot of digital content
of course it's not enough to just store the information right so over the last
decade a lot was invested into
creating these content repositories and so now the content is available
but it doesn't mean that it's useful right just because it's it's there in some
say database or in the digital library so there is the question of
you know how can we actually support two
get access to the relevant information given these repositories and this is actually dates back
quite some time so here
actually in the early days of the computers vannevar bush
i thought about this machine which was which he called mimics which was is basically
like you know personal computers so basically the idea that you would have access to
all the information from your desk
right and and you know and he is kind of
you know a picture and there was also a prototype i think that was still
there was not never really successful
but the idea
you know of course now this is trivial he also set
you know this is quotation here
you know there's a problem because
you know the publication as he says has been extended far beyond our present ability
to make real use of the record
and you know that the techniques that we are using are still
you know from the days of square rigged ships so basically there is a mismatch
you know in in that time between
the all the publication of the contents that's out there
and the technology that's available to make use of that content right to efficiently access
you know what he called make use of the record and he calls the major
civilization a challenge to deal with that's actually after the second world war where he
was looking for new challenges are scientists right he thought that was one of the
main challenges people should look into so somewhat later in the sixties also pioneers in
information retrieval more includes define information retrieval known as adequately identifying the in asian content
of documentary data right so
whatever adequately means but you know we have to get some to the information content
rights not just enough to store and to preserve
all the documentary data now there are many facets that we see today of information
retrieval and i want give you
like a complete overview of information retrieval you know this is not the one one
one tory information retrieval but still let me mention you know most of these should
familiar to you so there's no query based search
we'll talk about this in the first part of categorising and annotating documents
organising and managing information repositories of things like assessing the quality
of information sources which is very important context of things like the web understanding users
information need
techniques like collaborative filtering recommender systems and then of course also this nowadays we also
things like you know multimedia retrieval distributed retrieval and many other aspects
so what i will talk about in this tutorial then is you know how can
machine learning helps
and the general idea is that
the information content so what moroni includes called you know the information content with you
know is what we want to get at is not directly observable right to give
you a text you know you don't know exactly what is the information content in
was the relevant information in there