in in a bayesian manner
so the difference really is important philosophically a point estimate tells you nothing about the
you have in the parameters and it and it's not useful for computing marginal likelihoods
whereas this variational bayesian PM gives you something that tells you how certain or uncertain
u are in each of your parameters and wants to give you a lower bound
on the marginal likelihood which you can use for model comparison
this has been applied to
a lot of different models including discrete graphical models but also other things like mixture
models hidden markov models state space models et cetera
in the main advantage compared to traditional you and is that it can be used
to automatically do model selection
in those models so for example
in a mixture model you can get to automatically try to figure out how many
mixture components it should have
and so it doesn't it also doesn't suffer from the overfitting problems the maximum likelihood
methods have and it's about the same computational complexity as the EM algorithm so that
you know in my opinion
over time
apart from the fact this may be a little more complicated to implement i don't
see any reason why one would run just the classical rather than this algorithm
let me try to show you a demo
here is this algorithm
not on graphical models but trying to fit a mixture of gaussians
this is small
OK so imagine you have data
which of these little blue dots
and you try to fit a mixture of gaussians we all know kind of the
standard GM for mixture of gaussians hopefully a lot of you have seen it but
here we're going to do is we're also simultaneously going to try to learn the
structure of this model which in this case is the number of gaussians to use
we start with two
let's say and this is the initial conditions
as we run the algorithm the gaussians move around
and at some point the
lower bound on the log marginal likelihood converges
and then what the algorithm is going to do is is going to split
one of the components so it's going to split this red components along with blue
direction here
so keep in mind that red components
it's like that
so it becomes two gaussians here in this lower bound on the marginal likelihood when
every time it split
and so now splitting this one
now it's got one two three four five six components
this part shows the proportion of the data assigned to each component
and now
it found six components now it's going to try to do is is going to
try and try to find seven
and what you see is every time it tries to split something like you're trying
to split this into two
the lower bound on the log marginal likelihood is a little worse than it was
when he was six
because the
the model prefers simpler explanation with six gaussians and seven gaussians what happens is this
components going here and the number of data points that accounts for get smaller and
smaller and eventually the component is going to basically starve to death and disappear
but what the algorithm is doing in general is comparing models
with seven components at this point to the best model was six that i found
and none of the models with seven has
the value of this
which is the lower bound on the marginal likelihood
so users as a surrogate for the marginal likelihood we're doing model comparison
so any questions about this
let me point something out the picture that i drawn
it is representation of the probability distribution of the parameters of the gaussians
because this is doing this variational bayesian you algorithm it has
the distribution over the mean of this CNN has the distribution over the covariance matrix
of this guassian sort of shown is the mean of the mean and the mean
of the covariance
OK but if we want to find error bars on these we can also find
them from the model
right so this is the key assumption in the method we cannot compute the question
was we're just playing the lower bound we're not putting the actual marginal likelihood
the key assumption is that we can use this lower bound as a surrogate for
the marginal likelihood we can use this instead of the marginal likelihood to do our
and that's obviously an assumption
i started
the next step is temporal difference methods and this is the class of metal that
has to be used
in quite a few practical applications for some great success so
you want to pay
special attention to the
so we that this is the
it is a monte carlo method and and
the incremental they have
computing the value function for policy
for that
so how do you do that so
basically what you want to do that once you will the state
you want to
update your estimate so that's what every visit my the opposite the multicolored right
we visited states it's not here anymore
you come to the poster
this contd
reward from that state on
and you do it is obvious
and if you remember we had this rule that if you want to compute an
you can do that in an incremental manner
copulating the difference between the target value to the target value is the value that
you want the average man
and the actual estimate at times that use that
size learning rate
and then just update using this equation
this constitutes averages in an incremental manner
you could
so all four so what this off policy so why i'm using such an argument
acts of the you know possibly be you want to
know that so i just said that we want to use learning it
but actually when you're visiting st you want to be that state only
so the learning great for all the other states is turned off
right so to zero
so i wanted to write is activation
four pretty much every state so i could write it for every statement and i
would say that
well for any state this acquisition should hold but learning great
four states which are not visited currently either zero right from one to do that
i could do that
OK so that's why you have this argument here
so basically what ofwat teacher all that seconds you call the number of visits to
the state
and it is inversely proportional this learning rate which is inversely proportional to the
or maybe
if you
if you saying that the environment is nonstationary so you are getting out of that
you are not a nice man i things here
the you should use smaller in
if you use a small learning great is about that decaying learning rate
what's the ratings that size
and then what happens is that your estimates are sort so-called matching to the true
but they
stop wondering about the true value
so you're estimates
you know you remember these are all random variables are estimates that on the variables
so they have a distribution so about the distribution
so what you can prove
if you have a small learning rate
is that this distribution is going to be concentrated around the true values
and the variance
is proportional to the learning learning rate
but the problem is this method so one problem with this matter is that this
doesn't generalize at all
two problems
which are not a piece of
so in episodic MDP
you have a goal state and once you because it to compute this photo
people don't buy discounted sum of rewards the returns
and we use that
if you don't have both stated they will
but the computer sings
what you want to do here is that
well you realize that
the way you could compute these values is that
you just use the military returns
that so at the end of the day no one ever uses node elimination really
but it's a good way to understand what quantities need to be computed for you
to understand the final algorithm which almost everyone uses which is belief propagation is essentially
dynamic programming so that the
during the elimination if you know something about inference and you wonder why we're learning
this use algorithm node elimination and just think of it as sort of didactic sugar
and and soon we'll get to the real business of belief propagation so here is
that we want to compute the posterior over single
note any algorithm is an algorithm in which you will are these random variables you
rascal model you do a particular calculation on each one allows you to eliminate it
from the graph from the model
and you can only work for each of the variables in the many
each of the last fifty and is the final note that you wanted the posterior
and that's the
in so you can think your nodes in which the query node that you want
the poster over appears last any you go through the nodes pushing them out of
the equations and and i'll show you how that
how that works
before we get into
the details of the elimination algorithm i want to tell you just about a bookkeeping
trick which allows us to
get rid of the distinction between
evidence for conditioning
so what i did you know there are known we observed that they value
and i nodes that was just something over because we don't care about their values
are decision variables that we want to sum over you can
make those two things the same by introducing what called evidence potentials so imagine that
you just introduce the potential function in other words you multiply the joint distribution by
an additional factor
which is zero
on all the observed when they don't have the value observed them to have
and that's what
when they do have the value that you observe them death right
so a slightly complicated concept but imagine that there is no here
xj which we actually observed
and only XB could take on a lot of different values but what we're going
to do is we're multiply
the distribution of attacks
by delta function
which just takes on the values you
except that the actual value we observed were takes on the value one
after having done this is the case that the sum over xj
whatever distribution we have xj times this potential here which oncology
it is exactly just the observed value right so
this trend
allows you to treat marginalisation and evidence in the same way
so first we can multiply these evidence potentials in which will force the that we
actually observe to take on the correct values and now i'm just going to some
of everything except the clearing out so just keep it simple now our main goal
in life is to some at every node in the world except the query and
we have to work find what kind of something over the evidence nodes also because
we put in these potentials
OK so this trick just allows you to treat conditioning and marginalisation in the same
and then everything just boils down to to marginalization
what's the basic idea basic idea is just pick an ordering and go for
right so if you go back to the simple example that i showed you here
this is exactly the elimination algorithm except for the fact that i somehow picked an
ordering of the nodes here implicitly and i didn't tell you about that and you
can see it by choosing to sum over the nodes which are at the bottom
of the graphical model first i can do i can save myself some work so
i want to know is how should we think this ordering in in doing things
that this is just a piece of c code which you have your notes which
tells you about the algorithm we're not going to go through the details of it
here but but all have
slide on it now to show you what it does
the idea is that each trying to remove whatever the current variable in water is
from the distributions are trying to somehow one variable at a time
and because of this book keeping should we use for marginalisation notes this just sums
them and for evidence nodes this just conditions on their observations
in everything that's why
so each step in the elimination algorithm performs a song to get rid of one
and that is usually over the product of some potential functions that's how the structure
of the graphical model looks and so these potentials can be the original functions that
we had in our graphical model or they can be
these evidence potentials that we introduced as a bookkeeping trick or they can be some
intermediate quantities to remember in the
big six note example there was an intermediate quantities it appeared that we ended up
carrying around
in the algorithm is just some down the node except the query nodes and then
we just really normalize
what we have at the end
so this is a this description is really for directed models for undirected models everything
is really the same except that in the initialisation phase instead of using these parent
conditional distributions use the clique potentials so don't don't worry too much about the difference
the elimination algorithm can be used to do both marginalisation and conditions and he
so it's slightly larger class then all distributions but you still pretty good and it
turns out here is the same so we have if we have an opening that's
fine i was not zero it has nonempty interior and if our objects have compact
so they are not infinitely large then we can see that the
in principle at least we can invert the optical procedure we're not using information in
that case
OK so
i want to move on a a little bit i want to in detail for
a dimension before one application of this mean map
is to construct tests for where the distribution of the same or different
so i told you
whether distributions of the same or different the information is contained in this quantity here
it's trivial to write down
estimators of this quantity in terms of kernel functions they turn out to be very
simple formula as you just have to compute pairwise differences and some overall sets of
points you get empirical estimate as you can prove to converge
to the true quantities and you can prove fast you can give bonds and construct
test and stuff like that and if you're interested in that just look at the
papers you can get slides maybe you have to worry so that shouldn't be a
a second application that i want to mention is dependence measures
which is also
kind of interesting and it's interesting that if fits in the same framework
and let me spend five minutes and is so assume that
we have two random variables drawn from some joint distribution
px y
with with two marginal px and y so now what we interested in in independence
testing or in dependence measures is does this distribution factorizes into its marginals
it was beautiful paper some time ago by by john
define something called the generalized variance
there has been a number of
papers by arthur gretton and others who have extended this work to construct various of
our dependence measures and the main idea in all these you know this work is
again built on something which is
classical in probability theory
in which is similar to the classic result i told you about before
so in that thing tells us that two random variables are
well first of all if if two random variables are independent and also all functions
of these random variables are independent
and if something is independent of the covariance is zero covariance is just like the
first order of dependence so if we have to run which are independent then also
the covariance will be independent and even the covariance of any transformations of these random
variables are independent you can make random variables by applying some a priory chosen functions
OK so we know that if two random errors are independent
the covariance of
any transformation and numerous with many independent but it turns out the opposite is also
the case if we use is officially a large class of functions and again turns
on the continuous functions do the job
so i guess you can already imagine we're going to do we will replace these
the set of bounded continuous functions
by the unit ball in reproducing kernel hilbert space
and if we do that
we get a dependence measure for random variables
and it turns out we can also re-write this dependence measure just as a again
the distance between two means in the reproducing kernel hilbert space and the means will
one is the mean of the joint distribution and mapped into the reproducing kernel hilbert
space the other one is the mean expectation asch is a product of the marginals
so we're going to test whether the joint distribution is equal
to the product of marginals in the reproducing kernel hilbert space
and if we do that quite nice it turns out in this quantity with square
it we get something which is called the hilbert schmidt norm of cross covariance operator
between two purposes coming into spaces and again we can write down a nice empirical
estimate is the trivial to compute based on data so that's another application and a
lot of work has been done in this direction people have extended this tool
conditional independence testing and it's also maybe is one of the main areas where we
also using kernel methods
because we quite interested in causal inference and conditional independence testing plays a central role
for causal inference
the question
so the question is how about mutual information so it's it is related to me
of course in principle one can use mutual information to test something like this but
some you if you want to compute much information then i have to do is
density estimation for all you have to come up with some of clever way of
estimating mutual information which is trivial
so i would say this is pretty elegant way of of directly getting independence measure
which is a nice geometric quantity in reproducing kernel hilbert space and it's no
i wouldn't want to say this is this is better than x y z but
i can say is that a lot of people from the causality community
what need
independence testing and conditional independence testing now use this as a standard so it seems
to be seems to be good method for that
OK so let's there's a number of other applications that i won't go into detail
i want to
tell you just so that you have a broadband bonding methods after this two lectures
i want to tell you the representer theorem
and then just very briefly support vector machines
will be equipped to
a walk through the NIPS poster session and more let's get an idea of what
positions to handle
and then uses mobile manipulation code to the sheltered to grasp the door handle in
the way to go inside the office
on the navigation inside the office two
well know is what this desk
and then use the phone to computer vision to try to find this steeper on
the right is prepared to camera looking at different parts of the scene something different
areas in high resolution
well that is the camera view on
so the tango show where things as almost a pair which is
and the old and tried to paper
select across point
and become steeper
last switches back to the standard in the mobile robot navigation
on to navigate back to the conference
going back to the conference room
due to this paper
so you know
on the one hand was sequence demo
on on the other hand we had the robot should couple different items for a
couple of different places and the kind of works
this was the demo i hope this is also the beginnings of robot to
on you still use special items for around the office
so having some of these components for object recognition navigation opening doors and so on
on one i thing is that you actually start to put together these components to
try to build new applications relatively quickly
and so on so you about is very briefly is some did on on
trying to build on the tory taking application
secretary treaty on
the building of this that the computer science building and just means to that that's
the offices in a building
and what to do with the robot can go into these offices and figure out
what the coffee mugs and as a matter of on going around the united in
the world
well because he will be like because robotic can wander around my house at night
and way that the things the next morning you can tell i left my keys
i before the finality coffee mugs he's
so we started his application on
you know you about to office and so on with the because linkedin
so the pipeline was some to recognition
and in particular using vision is actually caused by the reckless court
you not atypical result on whether rectangle show with things is
i wouldn't claim by any means that we have the best vision after recognition system
in the world not by a long shot
you know i'm sure there are many ways to improve this
on the other hand i think pretty reasonable machine learning people who actually highly motivated
to build the best vision after recognition system we could end
this is about the soviet invasion of the soviet gets better but was never able
to get to work on
well enough to the article self-centered convince
so going on this theme that when you do things on the physical robot called
the domain
to become natural to do differently
in the addition i most of computer vision not all that
a large fraction of computer vision
it's based on RGB color the green colour on grayscale on it is natural because
most famous pictures are taken for human consumption
completely makes sense to take pictures using RGB vision because that's what he realize
it is about form in perception in the natural world often extends well beyond the
human visible spectrum
for example
that's the dolphins used so long
to perceive the world in three d directly to measure distances directly
and on the talk about the animals of the instance pieces states can see outside
the human visible light spectrum
are actually right that's a very boring you know that colour is not going to
converge to the presidency in ultraviolet and
actually appear very colourful each other ABC about
this is a
scholar of course so we can see it
so do better work on depth perception someone hyperspectral on our perception of actually talk
about only the perception of what you do with robots to measure distances to read
you know
the posterior vision a bunch of you are still visible you have two cameras
if i corresponding points in two stages and compute that by triangulation
it turns out in the literature to something this variation on this that does actually
standing now
cox's theorem
in which you was one tower of the laser pointer
two is on
to shine a laser pointer
and after the concert nightspot that
the camera can see where this place waters
and you can depend on
triangular using exactly the same triangulation calculation as you have with two cameras except now
is really one emitting from the top of the tower in one way of the
laser pointer
and because both senses can agree on this one bright spot on the environment correspondents
especially this is called this there are many people use it
it turns out they can even on turns out welcome so why on actually cost
not just a single point the environment the entire vertical lines and really does speak
the vertical line across c
and then get the DFS mister disappointments
to say well take
this is what the robot looks like is this in scene from left to right
and right
on the
the robot was getting
the position of all the points that laser beams following
and so
all these examples of on on the left is image taken using normal power
and on the right is a three d point called constructed using one of these
places so there's brand from the slightly higher point of view the original image
had this is very rich data on the other hand is also may be less
in this initial writing them
you might expect because you're human visual system so there's a particular you still do
not see geocoded all the parts of the is that no idea what they of
different coffee most likely because there
you have a point cloud into a lot of things one two
and so on
compute surface normal so in this part of the right
of course different pixels different colours depending on the surface normal
and so on you know science that corresponds to points with the surface normal
pointing roughly towards us a vertical surfaces facing us
the only the magenta response to points with the surface and all the points up
to five horizontal surfaces
so the green down here as well responding to sort through the focal direction
and then i to think about this is on
can now represent pixels like now for example you know have this color
on this position
and the surface normal
i think about this is that some
the probabilistic approach has a lot of other advantages and it's really
allows you to do automatic system building in a way that experts
you just don't like it
just to complete the three-minute sales pitch beginning here is just a laundry list of
applications where machine learning and in particular
use so speech recognition
this doesn't seem to be
so speech recognition
speaker verification if you've ever interacted with help of system where you
number you asked two
those using probabilistic models
in fact hidden markov models until about these lectures same things for
text handwritten text or as you are
face location tracking in video
search and recommendation
financial protection fraud all these things here medical diagnosis API
in games is now becoming big deal some modern video games have adaptive
computer but use machine learning
scientific analysis
and all kinds of other things so i can see this is not just you
know the problem of detecting faces whether you know these systems are deployed
much more widely than the
almost all big companies have huge datasets some kind of learning
if only just to detect outliers problems or make decisions which
transition from
OK so
in machine learning in general there is some canonical problems
so over all labels groups for general tasks
my attack
and actually this morning john lamb
talk about the equivalence between different problems in this set but
the this is getting started you can think of these as
different kinds of problems my
so all each of which has its own servers
single input and output desired goals so the most common
approach or set problem is right
in supervised learning given some examples of the inputs that correspond to
what you are going to see the real world desired output and here's your goal
is to predict the output on feature
so for example
this is my from working properly
so coming in order to do that for any
OK good test my own and the people
so in supervised learning problem has some input on how the desired output to the
input might be some description of your email
and the desired output might be
label spam or not
really important might be free from video camera and the desired output might be
the location any phase
well desired input might be some history of currency in the desired output might be
so these all supervised learning problems and and the names that you're probably familiar with
things like classification regression in time series prediction is also provided
unsupervised learning is in some ways more exciting and in some ways less well defined
unsupervised learning is kind of like the radical because to write everyone thinks it's kind
of cool and interesting but not really sure exactly what it's all about
so unsupervised learning
you're given only the inputs
and the goal is to automatically discover some kind of structure representation are features so
clustering outlier detection compression or code these are unsupervised problems and the problem is for
example for clustering it's not really clear what how do you measure the question if
i tell you about all this input
the clusters of these hundred got together and these are guys together these guys
together and then i say what you get a good job we have some quantity
with culture
a couple of other problems one is rule learning which is really
subsequent supervised learning for finding very very common joint settings of
the main dataset reinforcement learning in which in addition to inputs and outputs
you had the idea of actions and state of the world to reinforcement learning is
really a scenario where not only can use things in the world but your region
your computer can take specific actions that affect the the world is not just a
few queries using it for you
this processing and neural network can actually take an action which will affect the world
particularly about the future
distribution of the sizes
these last two are not going to talk about it
because we don't have very much time but a lot of people here who know
much more about four hundred ninety
something from him
OK so i just wanted time press forward here and keep focusing on this image
example and actually try and say how we actually start solving this problem so one
key issue here is how do we represent information about the world
the computer can actually see anything
so you want your USB camera into your computer
what actually comes use the camera is just some
stream pixels which
so that would represent the right so we need some way to call this image
into a computer program that i was talking about the structure is defined but concepts
are defined in order for us to start working on this unfortunately is probably the
most important part of machine learning problems in the car which we formerly known released
in terms of how i can recommend to do
it's crucial value numerically represent the input your problem in program it's also hard to
decide if further and the best representations for example
example here imagine you just listed pixel we just with this
excellent mistakes on this comes on every row and that would turn this image into
a huge vector numbers that would be a representation
so no matter what we have to think away numerically representing if it's spam we
might decide on a fixed set of words and we might represented as a binary
vector whether workers in you know
zero one zero one zero
that would be one representation in the first remember this image representation is a a
lot of information loses information about
beside each other
the spam representation of the information about the order of the words if you just
use binary word there are some problems whenever meet
once you've done this
we're going to think of these numerical values as random variables
so for those of you who are at rest your probability and statistics a random
variable you can think of is just like a variable in a computer program represents
a certain quantity like the intensity of a pixel
here but its value changes depending on which they are programs looking at or depending
on where uncertainty
so what we do is that we use probabilities to represent distribution
now one of the output
what well
the outputs will be with the outputs always are
the use
the estimate and in the
new estimate
and the
p c the covariance of that estimate the error in that case
so we've got two stages here
so it looks to me like we're going to have for output
we're going to have an output at the end of this
page is predictions state so this is like
correct all and i have to tell you more
what i'm saying now is going to apply to the forward port
the outputs from the prediction stage will be
and do you had
at stage k
but it comes it
at the prediction step has used to be
so there are frequent notation is with
make some messy
combination subscript
that's the predictions
based on the old data
up to k minus one not yet using k
whereas an output after this one is going to be you have
kk that's the
that's the best we know
at the end of stage k
and that's like the
the thing we're after
and then we are also interested in p or whatever letter i'm using
that is the
one is the
the covariance matrix for the error in
everybody is running this what he is the is the covariance
for the error
errors in
you KK modes one and then we'll update that
and by the way what should happen in this in now in all our matrix
formalism which is a PKK is here like eric this request
you expect this to be bigger than this are small
he guys are smart
yes this should be smaller y
because we've got more information
so the variance should be
all right so our formula for this
so so we're going to have
two levels of formula we're going have the prediction formulas
and then we're going to have the
correction for
and actually there some of the formulas are not as bad but another quite to
messy so do you see like what's happening at every stage where
we're we're adding this role
right reading that wrote to them so this is where we were at the end
stage one
now we can move to move on to the next time
so we have the prediction
so it's like we're doing exactly do it all these calculations but our matrix stops
if we're interested in this state
it's just turned out better separated into two pieces rather than swallow the whole thing
at once
and then now we've got to this point we've got those answers
so we know those and now we are ready to add a new road to
the matrix
that gives us a correction
exactly the correction that we figured in recursive least squares
i mean that that
we we don't lose
what was done there
and that will take us
from these answers to these editors
in fact there probably be some formula like
PKK is p
well whatever the update one would have been here
so we got
we've got four formulas to write down
formulas for each of those
depending on the inputs and the previous one
and then there's this
kalman gain matrix this k that we saw
that's built out of the other matrices so it's not like something entirely new
but it's convenient little bit of algebra to isolate that matrix
as and have a formula for that so will also have we also have
the kalman
make the game matrix that that's stage
now i'm
when we one we finish introducing this role we will have the best possible
estimate based on the measurements and the and the state equations of the of the
last guy of u two
well that's what will happen that's usually what we want
suppose we wanted
the best estimate of you zero
based on
all in all this information that i've written down
what's what's with that
i suppose i i proceed forward this is all four were all that everything i've
written on the borders forward
and forward stuff takes me
to u two and the best estimate for you this is that this is the
winner this is the best over here
this is our best
based on all
basically the best for
the last few for the last UK
based on all data
and this is its
it's it's sorry it's cover covariance matrix
it's covariance matrix
but let me finish that thought what about you not
do i have anything new to learn about you not from what happened later
the answer is yes absolutely
so that if i'm serious about you know what i should do back substitution
i said that i hadn't put anything on the board that went backwards in time
but the one thing i did put on the board that goes backwards in time
is the back substitution for triangular matrix
so what's what's the word for that
you know the word for
what we get when we
good exactly smooth
so there's there's there's the process of going backward
two small the earlier information if we want to do it
you know if that information is important
that then would be a further set of formulas
for example to understand how this
function works
so what
in this case
number of slots will be eight
two three
these are size
seven bits
anybody in only seven the computers at the
here's one
a fixed value that's used for astronaut or keys
in this case let's say one
one one
o o one so that's a
i take in some value for k that i'm going to
one multiply
so it is going to be one one
o one one that's my k
multiply to each of these is the foreword with
i view it as foreword with of
the machine has k seven
in general this would be like thirty two bit number and mikey
i'd be doing to thirty two normal multiplying two thirty two bit numbers
so what find that out i get a two w bit answer
w bit numbers you get a two w
the answer
in this case happens be
so that's the part i part
then we take me to the w one my to the w says is
i'm just taking
ignoring the higher bits
this problem product
all these are nor
if i take something more
power two
it's just the low order bits
so i just get these lower bits of being lot
and then
right shift operator in that's good also by the way because a lot of machines
when they multiply two thirty two bit numbers instructions
that gives you just
thirty two orbits
usually industry construction is faster than the instructions to give you the full
sixty four bit
thank you
so that's very convenient
and the second thing is there and i want
just the
in this case three
the higher order bits of this work
this ends up being my age
and he's and getting removed by
right shifting
these all this right should be and
zero come higher bit and you end up getting value for each OK
so to understand what's going on here
why this is a pretty good method
what's happening with them
that one way to think about it is to think of a
as being a are binary fraction
so imagine the decimal point is here
the binary point
the radix point is here
when i multiply things
i'm just taking
the binary point and something there
just imagine that concept we don't have to
actually put this into the hardware because we just do with hardware does but i
can imagine
it's there
and this here and so we're really taking is the fractional part of this problem
by treating is a fraction of the number
control that sort of modular wheel
so here i have
this is going to be
i'm invited to eight parts
this point is zero
and i go around and this point is that one
i go around and this one is too
and so forth
so that all the villagers by wrap around this unit we'll
all the integers
line up at the zero point
and then we can divide this into the fractional pieces so that's essentially the zero
point is the one
we divided into eight
five six seven
so if i am
if i one times a in this case i'm basically saying well
one times a final slide is basically going around
five and a half
right because one times in a
is about
and have
notation and try to be careful as we go through and make sure that there's
no confusion about what that means in context
there are a couple of them though
which are are fairly well defined one is based on this one is t one
t one is the running time on one processor
so if i were to execute this on one processor
you can imagine is just as if i had just gotten rid of despondent sinks
and everything just executed it
that'll give me
a particular running time
we call that running time
on one processor to work
this actually serial time
OK so when we talk about the work of the computation we're just mean essentially
a serial running time
the other measure the ends up being interesting
it is what we call t infinity
and this is the critical path like
OK which is essentially the longest path
in the
in the dark
so for example
if we look at
this example
it has to be one equal to so let's let's assume we have unit time
threads i know they're not you time let's just imagine the purposes of understanding that
every thread cost me
you know
one unit of time to execute what would be the
work of this particular
seventeen right
OK because all we do is just add up
o three six nine
thirteen fourteen fifteen sixteen seventeen
so work is seventeen in this case where you time for general you add up
how much
how many instructions or whatever were in there
and then t infinity
is the longest path so this is the longest sequence
so i can be an infinite number of processors
you still can't just do everything at once because some things have to come before
other things
be an infinite number of processors many process what was the fastest you could possibly
execute this
little trickier
so what's your seven
so one
is the longest pattern
so the work on the critical path length is we'll see here
attributes of any computation
OK and then abstractly there the and this is it if there was a very
long time
so we can use
these two measures
to derive
lower bounds
on TP for are for p that fall between one
so the first floor around we can derive is the TP it's got to be
at least
t one over here
OK so why
is that lower
o five p processors
OK why would i have this lower bound
OK i got the right idea
OK so
so but can we be a little bit more articulate about so that's right so
it's you're using all the prior you want to use all the processors if you
could use all the processors
why is it why couldn't i use all the processors though don't have be less
why does have to be at least as big as t one
asking for a little more
precision and in the answer you've got exactly the right idea but
a little more
four precision for persuade the rest of the class this is the
this is the
lower bound
yeah that's another way of looking at if you were to serialize the computations
OK so whatever
things you execute on each step you do p of them and so serialised it
then it would take p steps to execute one step of the p way
you know of
the machine with p processors so then
OK i can be a little more precise
yeah good so so let me just let me just state this a little bit
so p processors or we rely on p processors can do
most p work
how do we get there
well before you came to doing mathematics philosophy computer science which think infinity one
talk about infinity some is infinite means one
there's nothing bigger
it has been
classical notation infinity
just use
this notion an infinite set it got complete collection infinitely complete function that i think
about it back to the completeness theorem for first-order logic you learn about the lindenbaum
m around
and then when obama
you take an infinite union you say well after we do all this after we
do all state after we do all these infinite stages we union them up right
you can do that for intuitionist
because they're going to reject this notion of a complete infinite set
it's like there is an infinite sequence ended in lying on the infinity mean that
have in
brower goes looks back into the history of mathematics and the history
and says well you know people
didn't have this notion of a complete insanity until late nineteenth century
it seemed to him to be dodgy notion
when just didn't make any sense and
he said well look
while we do everything with
the notion of infinity is just as a something that doesn't end
OK now
think about
ways of representing things that down and
do you have any
ideas of things that you deal with
the down and some of you deal with
but there
well sure
if the functions are just keep on now
non terminating programs
you can teacher program
right to counteract this to keep on doing putting lines on paper and more and
more lines after william run paper but
you can teach program to do that
came after the invention
he came after touring
and after the
invention of the
he started thinking about this says
well let's think about
mathematics says what a computer could do
this is intuitionist mathematics modern intuitionist mathematics is effectively this
not necessarily with deterministic program might have nondeterministic might your programs to the coins and
world i see no use
non deterministic methods at certain points and that's actually necessary in the treatment of the
real numbers likely we don't have to go through that is extremely complicated and kind
of annoying and went to a course of mathematics for doing course on logic
not intuitions fast do intuitionist logic
OK so
what we get is this idea that
get rid of this idea that there is mathematical truth out there
but rather what's mathematically true is what can be proven
effectively prove
using something like a computer programme right or something that we would do that could
be managed by computer program
so now we move away from a very mystical notion to a very sort of
commonsense notions
of mathematics mathematics is just
what we can implement
not a silly idea at all
well not the priors idea was silly said but
it's much more down to earth much more common sense
sort of
my notion of mathematics unfortunately
has some problems
back in about nineteen thirty twenty nine
our in haiti
what's now known as intuitionist logic
and it's been given what is known as the brower
nineteen come over all
OK what's that
well for hours that guy hiding is going to the logic more of does anybody
know moreover commodore of
this year
OK algorithmic into
yeah complexity come overall complexity
anybody know from anywhere else
in the kolmogorov axioms for probability
it's maguire
he also came up with this interpretation of
browsing writings work
intuitionist logic
how's it going to interpret these things well
we interpret the connectives in terms of a will go into that well go into
some detail so
conjunctions always easy
in b means there is proof of a and there is a proof of b
or sometimes we have the proof of a and we have a proof of b
now a or b
will mean that we have a proof of one or the other
are there is a proof of one of the other now
sometimes added to this is and we know which was which which proof which once
one has to prove
is no free lunch that if you have no constraints on your hypothesis space you
can learn anything interesting that goes beyond and the bigger the the principal hypothesis space
and the less data you have the more constraints the stronger the inductive bias need
but of course that really satisfying because that's all there was to it then we
already have human-like
machine learning systems which we don't for the most part so really this is just
the opening up of the number of questions which we want to ask exactly how
is it that abstract background knowledge inductive bias guides learning from sparse examples in that
case is that talked about
what form does knowledge take
what is its content and representational form across different task domains this is a hard
problem and one the lot of cognitive science is devoted to try to study because
people most that kinds of inductive biases implicit knowledge people have their constraining the generalizations
a lot of it is quite implicit unconscious you can just ask somebody so what's
your inductive bias exactly
right but that's often what we're most interested in this as explaining how they can
do these tasks so we need techniques that can elicit and formerly represent the kinds
of prior knowledge people bring to these tasks
maybe the most the most interesting kinds of learning questions are how is this abstract
prior knowledge itself
the learner requires now course inductive bias
it doesn't have to be learned
in principle it doesn't have to be and if you look kind of classically in
machine learning
as well as in cognitive science i think the sort of default assumption is that
it's not like inductive biases are these hardwired constraints we designed by hand into our
learning algorithm in machine learning or the people who most forcefully advocated for inductive biases
in cognitive science of people like chomsky in this penalty and others in the neediest
camp saying that they're just the mind comes into the world through genetic specification to
have very strong constraints on what they can learn what they can expect and that's
why were able to learn so much from so little
but i think it's clear that in many cases inductive biases in human learning have
to be learned there are many reasons for this one is that will show you
in a minute there are some very compelling examples of cases where human children at
a certain age maybe age to have some very important inductive bias but but slightly
before they don't
and there is evidence that they can actually be taught these inductive biases another
reason the to focus on learning is that we can learn about new domains that
we didn't have access to in our evolutionary time where we can we can learn
chemistry and then acquire new inductive biases for jam making inductive inferences about new chemical
compounds or to take a more intuitive example you know we live in a very
complex social
system and there are different societies follow different kinds of rules many of which didn't
have any precursor in in our evolution existence we didn't have the same kind of
population density and size of cultures and complexity of cultures yet when you grow up
in this culture are able to learn lot of implicit knowledge of how your culture
works and then you use that to make very rapid and for the most part
reasonable inferences from very sparse data about new people you meet in new situations that
you find yourself
and this brings us to the last question which i think is particularly interesting to
from machine learning point of view as well as human one which is it seems
like there is a tension between these two aspects of human learning on the one
hand and these are just distinctive aspects of human which you don't see necessarily so
much in other natural animal learning systems on the one hand we have these very
abstract constraints inductive biases that allow us to learn so much from so little on
the other hand it seems like we can learn new ones
we're very flexible and inductive biases can we can come up with when you go
to a new culture you can pick up how that culture works you can actually
learn things in school and it it seems like might be in conflict right if
we have strong constraints which limit the hypothesis we can entertain then how is it
that we can
then not only entertain these which are part aren't covered by those constraints but actually
sort of throughout those constraints in and come up with a new set of constraints
for a new situation we find ourselves
the goal in this work is to come up with a computational framework for addressing
these questions and these are hard questions where you know we're we're just beginning to
make progress but i think we are starting to make some progress on these questions
and hopefully will be useful
insights machine learning now the the approach that we're working with builds on a bunch
of ideas which are probably not get familiar to the community that we might be
using them some slightly different ways because we're working on a slightly different more human
motivated problems
the most basic technical ideas bayesian inference as you can guess from the title of
the talk
mean in the sense these technical ideas are each can address these four bequest i
had here so how does background knowledge guide learning from sparse data well
if you are bayesian priors are some sense derive from this abstract background experience so
it's better
clear powerful and totally general purpose way the background knowledge can guide learning
but of course that doesn't really tell you very much in in any more than
just pointing to inductive bias and we need more but more powerful richer kind techniques
one is to address the question of the form of knowledge right
if you just look at a very simple bayesian analysis what is the prior to
the set of numbers or a simple parametric statistical distribution but that isn't knowledge right
and we want to understand how rich knowledge representations can generate priors for bayesian inference
so that requires us to look at more structured probabilistic models for example probabilities defined
over graphs or richer things like grammars relational schemas and so on
if we want to address the question of how as background knowledge and inductive bias
itself learned well from that we where we've been using hierarchical bayesian models where you
have multiple levels of probabilistic representation with say above the level of the conventional prior
you have some kind of hyperparameters the prior on the price
and by looking at learning in those hierarchical models we might be able to explain
where people's inductive biases come from
by combining these techniques right we can we can learn inductive biases which are not
just numbers are parameters but actual
structured knowledge
and lastly we want to understand this this trade off in may be seen in
parallax between constraints and flexibility for that we've been working with nonparametric bayesian techniques where
the complexity of the model is determined in advance but is able to grow as
licensed as new data come in so new data come in and when the when
it when appropriate model can make itself sent to make itself more complex as needed
but but maintains the ability to have strong constraints for data that respect previously learned
so the line for the talk
it is will will be to go through three case studies in modeling human inductive
and we'll see how much exactly
time there's for all three of us the last one will be somewhat abbreviated
the first case studies on we're learning and the model i'm going to talk about
is in some sense very very simple hierarchical bayesian model
it's it's probably trivial to to many of you with one sort of little twist
at the end which is so trivial but it's worth going through is just to
warm up for the basic ideas and also because it allows us to
address really to talk about one of the most interesting phenomena of how humans learn
inductive biases in child
and the phenomenon is what's called the shape bias in word learning
this is a
the phenomenon that that was studied by a number of developmental psychologist starting in the
mid to late eighties and here's an example of it
you take a two-year-old child whose learning to speak english
and you show them something like this and you say this is the backs and
then you show them three other things here and you say can you show me
the other backs
which one you think they're going to choose
that's that use the first one the one that has the same shape as opposed
mapping between inputs and outputs franchise units
but you can apply this sort of reasoning to all sorts of other models that
so what we tend to apply this organism stochastic processes
and you know that might confuse you but essentially you can create these alpha parameters
to determine the relevance of each of your input dimensions in the gassing process and
you're learning the kernel from the data
and the curl is telling you which ones of your inputs are relevant and which
ones are relevant
machines are based on this idea
and they
essentially assign relevance to each input
to each input has some basis function around it and there's the relevance variable to
each one of your inputs
input data points if you have n points and relevance is here you have
n points in d dimensions you have the relevance
OK and now what that does is it gives us our sensory it allows you
say that this input is not relevant
so it's always sparsifying things it's i think of it as a way of doing
so far stochastic processes
but has some disadvantages the error bars get can be catastrophically wrong and relevance vector
and there's a nice paper recently that that shows how to fix that
this was based
in terms of algorithms that i know
there are a whole bunch of ways of making gaussianprocess is sparse
and the relevance vector machine is one of them and ends up with very sparse
now why do we want them to disperse
i know it it sounds nice
you know maybe it's for computational reasons may be computationally are often smaller and faster
and that's the motivation for the relevance vector machine but we have to ask ourselves
these questions we can just blindly you know say
i just want to sparse solutions
you know because
possibly but it's not in
in the argument that i had before
it's slightly tricky because you can get good generalisation even if you have infinitely many
but it's true i mean you may you may get better transition but there's no
hard proof that you'll get better generalisation it could be
the by sparsifying you've overfit the data in some strange way
that's also possible
so any time you do optimisation so this thing in the center
optimizing this thing that could lead to problems
in fact i have a paper where i talk about
overfitting some
it's not as bad as other things but sometimes even are close to termination can
lead to overfitting
so there are some ways of trying to fix that
you know just to spare people i'm not going to continue unless people asking specific
and then you know
i'm happy to talk about anything specific
so what
i think you know all techniques are vulnerable to their assumptions
well it's interesting right so
most estimation methods
make far more assumptions than bayesian methods let me try to explain why
i get the data set
i learned
some parameters theta
had from the dataset
by minimizing whatever
i minimize some penalized loss function let's say
i learned that had
OK now
when i do prediction
my assumptions
are very very strong
by assumption is that the data really came from a hat
whenever i'm making predictions
so i've completely ignored
the fact that i picked one particular thing have consistent with the data
rather than considering all the possible status that could have been consistent with the data
it's like here right
any one boundary
is making very strong assumptions
all of these boundaries are actually consistent with the data that i have said
this is what i'm saying so
optimisation methods are most traditional machine learning methods
peak particular
it is some sort of selection of the parameters
and ignore the fact that the data could have been explained in many possible ways
OK even when i'm doing
automatic relevance determination i might find some
some subset of my genes that are relevant right
by optimizing this thing
but that could be the wrong subset
you know if i were to run
you know sampling algorithm
then sometimes it might that subset sometimes might affect another subset of genes
so there's uncertainty there is like you know in any modelling that we have a
lot of uncertainty and so
you know the
one of the kind of premises of bayesian learning is to try to be
as honest about your uncertainty as possible
you know i don't
set of notes here
it it
it has been introduced as a sub concept of a
what i wanted to show that didn't work really was that it is a synonym
to student nice to effect
there's something wrong with the prefixes as you can see now i have two names
are little
i'm a bit puzzled about this
why is it so
but you can forgive me a try
what if i put away these thing here
i'm puzzled by the all namespaces
and if that means
and this was
the thing now i have
now i did it correctly
so you see that
now the system has found that
our new notion person taking lectures
it's the same thing that was there before
before we call this
as you can see
reasoning services health
to identify
so called sin so the actually as you see there is no need to introduce
a new
name for the concept description that i have typed in
the point here is that the this ontology is not a large one really it
contains about one hundred concept names and quite a number of associated axioms for practical
purposes you might end up having
two hundred thousand concept
names and then this is
quite the challenge for reasoning engines
probably won't be able to display this on on on the
on the screen here
but i mean the research problem that that we deal with is how to make
classification possible at all if you have two hundred thousand concept names and associated
have you ever tried to
define two hundred thousand classes in
you are programming languages java say c plus plus ever
try to compile around the
comparison program with the number of classes i didn't dare to do but i would
things will also be harder for standard modelling techniques if we deal with examples of
this size
now i think you've got an overview about the
about the
the main ideas
subsumption satisfiability you've seen that one can interactively explore
the taxonomy
one can
developed the model type in some x in
the system then
compute the taxonomy you see that
the system can find out that oh well this new name is not really required
we already have a name
student it might be OK if we want to have a person taking pictures
but then we are at least we are aware of that this is something that
is the same as is denoted by student so it makes sense to have synonyms
in some cases but in others this might just be a modelling depends on the
domain and on the model of
i mean
subsumption relationships that system finds models might also be intended all i didn't see i
didn't know that there is a subsumption relation but it's fine with me
you might even exploit
a facility that these tools then insert
some axiom or modify axiom such that it becomes apparent that there exists is a
subsumption relationship
but this is another story machines
are provide sound and complete inference services as you might know and so you can
rely on the
services to dig out all
today i'm going to tell you
about some work that we've been doing quite recently in my group and some kind
of understanding is we've come to based on that work under the general topic of
computational social science
but we least
by telling you about something i did twenty years ago
almost twenty years ago i attended a small workshops
in anaheim california
as part of that year
and i was a graduate student at the time and
was a little bit frustrated because i wasn't finding the community that i wanted to
to to do my technical work in and then this workshop came along this how
this looks like exactly the same and it was in fact
kdd nineteen ninety one
it was a workshop at the time actually
but it had some just fantastic work in those places that accepted by my papers
what's interesting is that in the intervening twenty years we've had remarkable growth
we've got two journals
that are every tissue filled with with release quality technical work
we've got a long history of this conference and other conferences
in the field
we've got special interest group in ACM
we've got a steadily increasing number of papers every year talking about knowledge discovery and
data mining
this is some data that gregory nicely sent me last night about papers mentioning those
words in the title
we might ask why this success
what is it that led to this tactical field actually taking off and doing what
it's done over the intervening twenty years maybe why have we done more or less
or different things
and unfortunately the answer is we don't really know
we don't know why scientific fields succeed or fail we don't know much about what
it is that makes that community grow and prosper as the kind of organic thing
that it is because we don't know much about how those kinds of organizations actually
and that's going to be part of what i talk about today but we can
hang out waiting for us to figure out how it is that these organisations work
some to give you some conjectures about what it is that makes this field work
the first thing is that we are
relentlessly exploratory i think when we're doing our best work we identify and formulate clearly
new research problems on a yearly basis and new applications new things that we can
do with with the kinds of of tasks were interested in
so the ecumenical
that is we're not fixated on a single class of techniques or a single
type problem we say as long as it has something to do with knowledge discovery
and data we'll do it
and finally i think when we're doing our best work often externally focused that is
we're looking to other fields two of relevance to other fields as an indicator of
what kind of quality we're we're doing
well i'm going to be talking about today with computational social sciences i think an
opportunity to
realize many of these things many of the the things that have made or field
work really well
i mean when i say computational social science world run definition is that it's an
interdisciplinary study of complex social systems
notice there's nothing about human social systems as this early in their and their investigation
through computational modeling and related techniques
so how is it that we can understand model and and get deeper
comprehension of social systems
not surprisingly this doesn't just involve computer science involves a whole series of different fields
in the social sciences but also statistics and you mass actually over the past eighteen
months we put together an initiative in computational social science and we actually hired former
new faculty
one each
in computer science statistics sociology and political science
and the reason that we did was we said this can be done within an
individual department and on each of those hiring committees were faculty from all the other
departments it was really remarkable learning experience for all of us and a really good
way to make sure that we hired faculty that were going to fulfill that kind
of vision that we had about computational social science
now the field is
convergence of a variety of things happening externally and internally first of we got new
data collection methods and new kinds of data sets that are available about how it
is that societies actually function for the first time we've got access to a very
low level data often have people move in society how people relate to each other
how they communicate those kinds of things
the result we've also got a whole new classes of methods that have been developed
within KDD in other areas that are making it possible to analyse this data sets
and understand them in a way that was we couldn't before
and finally we've got new questions and theory at least new to us computer science
that i think computer scientists and statisticians are finding deeply fascinated we're finding out that
social scientists actually know an incredible amount about alternative ways of interpreting what is societies
and that working with those theories and trying to understand them and trying to realize
them in some kind of computational model is fascinating and invigorating
now some of you may be looking at this and saying that social science OK
fine you guys can go off into the social science and we'll do some other
stuff because it's not really relevant to what i do and have been finding out
is that social sciences relevant to a lot of things certainly there are deep scientific
ifif twodifferent prior believes that are both reasonable give you grossly different conclusions then the
any possible interpretation is that the likelihood isn't terribly informative that there isn't a nervousthere's
not as much information in the data or about the parameter as you would like it
to be so why you Mr. frequentist why areyou so happy with your inference that
is only using that likelihoodsosensitivity to a prior to the prior is is nature's
way of telling you thatthe likelihood isn't terriblyinformativeit's
always important to carry out a sensitivity calculations if you if you
want to promoteyour analysis then you should show your clientthat the that the
inferencesas are pretty robust to to assumptions youbrought to the analysisand oneway
to do that is to examine is tovary those assumptions to to to try different
prior distributionsfor certain certain domains ofapplication peoplehave triedtryingthis idea of
having a rangeofa sort of portfolioof priors this isparticularlyappropriate in in areas of
public healthfor examplemedical statisticstypeinferenceswhere you knowthere's a
hypotheses about the into the connection betweenI don't knowsome environmental factor and and and and
diseaseone oneparticular parameters of real focus andquite a nice approach then is to
take a range of priors corresponding to the skeptic theyou know different stages
ofprior conviction that this particular effect is important and justto to examine
the the effect ofacross thatportfolio on the resulting inferencesthe a I'll show you
when I'll talk some about some examplesI'll show youso the effect of some some sensitivity
calculations nowin in big modelsof coursethis could potentially be quite generous you have
a lot of different parameters you have you probably have a lot of different prior assumptions
and now are we really supposed to to to vary all of themare you gonnaare you going
to rerunyour MCMC computation for everyone of these different combinations of
prime modelsor you probably aren't there's a there's a few tricks you can use
to alleviate the problem andwhat this isone rather niceone based on
important sampling which I'm I'm sure you've heard aboutso this this is the
way it goes we want to examine the expectationposterior expectation of some quantity under
a new model where the new model is the old model with a prior modified
from P to P Nuso we just go through the calculation it's aimportant sampling calculation we can
write that expectation as an expectation with respected original unmodified posterior with the
there issome waitfunctions W whichare simply the ratio of the new to the old
prior so the likelihood does not change we just change the priorspecification and so
there we got thesewait functions which are the the ratio of thetwo prior distributions so what
this is saying is that we can compute this posterior expectation under the new prior
by taking a sample from the original prior and rewaiting it appropriately so
that's quite a nicecheap way of examining sensitivity to variations in priors
where youcan reuse theoriginal sampleand don'thaveto to to to repeatyour calculations
okay well the larger part of this questioning the model section is going to be about something
we call model criticism and I'm gonna I'm gonna talkaround this areaa bit andalso then
introduce a particular idea thatI've beenivolved with a year ortwo ago in a
particular proposalfor doing this so what is model criticism is not the same as
model comparison this is about a checkingassumptions using observed datawithout explicit
reference to any particular alternative model so it's it's a sort of goodof
fit type calculation so it'ssomething you do atquite an open-minded stage or perhaps you're in
the position of really only havingone model you could possibly think ofso
youyou know you implement that and the question is now you've done soyou
should perhaps look at theawell is thereanyevidence that the datadoesn't
follow the model you've you've got so in ain anideal situation you'vebeen ina sort
distribution for for botha log normal distribution so that's has the correct range but
what I'm saying here is issome conflict these are both scatter plots where the
points are overwhelmingly concentrated up in the left end corner so so far as thosehyper parameters is concerned
what's happening is that the the information from the data and theinformation from my
priorare are conflicting now maybe I maybe they are really what I want in which case
I'm content with the analysis but maybe I willnow say well perhapsI wasn't so sure let's
examine inthe effect of changing those prior assumptions and that high-level to something much
more diffuse indeed this is much more likely what you'd actually do in practice I
thinkokay a gamma distribution with with a high variance when you do that
then you you you're less concerned about the resulting critique plotsfor there two
hyper parameter variables okay they they're well spread out among the top access
yes so we probably say is not such a strong conflict anymore and the effect
of that is now that thethe spacial interaction among the random
effects can now be much greaterandin factthe datapull usin that
direction and you know there are substantial spacial trends where we now see patternsofspacial dependence
and some degree of conflict in the region specific random effectsokay so these these technic
thesetechnics don't tell you one answer isright and one iswrong I mean you're just drawing
attention to the way that the different assumptionsin the model are interacting to perform your
posterior inference and I hope these are helping you make a choice about which is the
better modeling set upokay I think I will move on the thethese
work was recently written up and you can find it alsoon my website
you'll find more detailsthereif you don't do itthan ask yourself
well how do I know my models are not in internal conflict to someway okay I wanna saya few other
internal other issues in less detail other issues about questioning models model
criticism is underyou do itquite at anearly stage where you're saying well you know am I happy
is this this model fitrather more formally we might want to get
into a situation of choosing between models selecting a modelthere'sa whole interesting philosophical
debate we don't have timefor now aboutwhat youknowis there a true model etcetera etcetera
as afamous aphorism much quoted thatall models are wrongbut that some of the are useful
you've all heard that phrase you've all heard thatyeah well take your timewaitingyou know in inreality there's pretty
well always some doubt in your mind as to how to modeldata and that
doubtmight beinformed by the data you are actuallymodeling so there's aquestion of using data
to to help choose the model you'regonnaanalyse the data with and this is a
huge huge area it'svery very important research areaat the moment and it'sa lot of work
going onbutI'm some just gonna give you avery slittle bit of a glimpse to thisthe
standard set up is that you have a discrete set of variables so sorry
modelsindexpopulate K andwe have a prior distribution over those
models so Pkis your prior probability thatit wasmodelK that generated the data and these
modelscould be quite different in character so theyeach ofthem has a parameter vector
and I call that parameter vectortheta K for thecase modeland possibly those parameters are of
different lengthyou know might be preparing quite hatchery genius range of modelsso what's our set up our
set up will beas well astheprior for models we have a parameter
prior within each model and then within eachmodel wealsohave alikelihood for the data
which will dependon dataY and samedatain all cases of course but the it will depend on
both the both the modelof choicethe model indicator and
the parameterand then by the ordinary look rulesof probability the joint
the the joint distribution of everything known and unknown is just obtained by multiplying these
three model factors together that's the that's the vanilla situation model choice is just a
hier hierarchical modeland then we're interested in typically making joint inference about
K and theta K some people like to that it would juice K and then proceed
conditionalon that choice but it's more in the spirit of Bayesian a paradigm to
regardK and theta K asthingsthatare jointly unknown and you want to make
posterior inference about thetwo togetheryou're simultaneously telling deciding what is the data telling
you about your choice of model not and also what it's saying about the parameters
in the modeland of coursejust by the usual usual thing this this is just the
this this posterior distribution of the two things is just proportional to the joint so
from this view I meana modelindicator iaa completelyis just another parameter it's nothingspecial about it
at allit's just treated as another level and model choice just becomes you
you have your building buildings
against this linear combination
the function h
of a m
remember that for us
we do this in the feature space
link with the output space
but we're going to do this in way of freedom and he's doing this sort
of fremantle
in nineteen ninety
almost at the same time
peter bartlett medicine
don't that also
there's an but it also propose something which is called in english
which is a very principled way to see it that way
in the case of freedom and you really devoted his is gradient boosting two regulation
for it
it's quite
direct chose this
for the second phase output was
so the idea is the following in fact
you are doing
to start from some function as
and you're going to have
also function
and the way you are going to at all the functions so here
you have some
at the current point as current time
because state n minus one us some
current linear combination and you're going to have some function and so you're going to
some function
you are going to be the loss function
that express
you are
your prediction functions
yes and it can be you
to gain funds for regression it can be square loss
and you're going
to see the function throughout as a vector so you have to find ice at
some point
so you are
in fact in the space of
community linear combination of
function basis functions you have some vector which is f
and man is one
and you want to you here and you want to one another function
and this function h
you what you have to edits in such
in such a way that you will still as the UH is the direction given
by the gradient OK
so what you are going to do
OK so we all get you it's called g with
so you're going to say i'm going to derive business function
at some point
OK this use
the value of the function that exchange straight and at this point and you are
going to find a good direction
and the idea
is to find
the parameters of the basis functions so the next one to n one and
i'm going to find as the primate of this function
which is which are the closest
which is the closest to the right direction
so in fact when you use the loss function
there is a you can do this directly
you can
you can solve the problem
quite nicely
so the idea is the following
you start from this one
you for this you can just
or you can
he is the average and then what you going to do
you're going to find
the output that we have to consider
in order to next regression
so here is the way we're doing this relation so
you've been something at the moment it's at the moment the step n minus one
you want
do something better so the way to do something better is to do
we use the
o point where you have made some errors
so in fact throughout the regression problem
you are know you have now
newer version problem and what you are going to do you are going to change
the output
in order to deal with the residuals so the error
you cannot do with
so you find these points
why i am
which is in fact a modification
your output
with his new
you start your problem for instance
so again is as well as
as well as for its generic it swells
you find h which is to close this
he's predictions are close as to this point so it's usual regression problem but change
the output
OK and once you have you parameter of the but function you just
and you go on
OK so let's look
what we are
if we take n
as the square loss
because this is usually the case for which takes its windows
the most
basic law
if you've been analysed to organize its another matter but just want to take see
because you take square
two things the square loss this derivative suggests equal
two the residuals so did the difference between the output and the
previous predictions
so in fact
it gives you
what you have not predicted yes
and what you have to
to predict
you do the job of doing your equation
on these new data
you find new parameter
and you
and you are the new function
with your parameters
because this is the idea
so the idea is how can i change
in relation how how can i can i change my output
in order
two and the next step
be able to have better is
remember that in the first edition is not exactly that
the classification
should look closer at
gradient approach for adaboost what you're doing
you say
i am going
folk use on the data
i am not able to predict that approaches that
so i'm going to wait
to weight with a great conventional lightweight
i'm going to wait strongly
the data
that i have not twenty predicts as the previous day
remember say why do you could some weight
new data and the other distribution of
so in one iteration
you act
on your output
so far as
the idea is not to act directly the but
velocity his data is cleverly plotted without an arrow bar and are you
really convinced that this is a straight line fit looking at this data well Hubble was so Hubble
determined that the velocity is proportional to the distance and that with some constant that he called K
which I like K but in fact is now known as
H naught Hubble's constant and Hubble's constant is usually written if you measure the velocity
the recessional velocity in kilometers per second and the distance say in megaparsec
Hubble's constant can be written in terms of a dimensionless little number H
a hundred kilometers per second per megaparsec
Hubble's determination of the Hubble constant in nineteen twenty-nine was that it was five hundred kilometers per second
per megaparsec roughly a factor of seven
to large
well in case you doubt Hubble's results of a linear at least for small velocity small redshift the linear
relationship this is a good determination from nine nineteen ninety-four
of the Hubble
program of measuring velocity versus distance
you know nobody bothers to plot Hubble's data anymore which would have been in that little
box there
and you see that it is very well described by a linear relationship
and the determination of the Hubble constant today
Is that the Hubble constant is about point seven
point seven two
With a
statistical and systematic uncertainty
From the Hubble key project
and point seven one with an uncertainty of about point-o-four or point-o-three
From W MAP
so the way to remember the value of H
it is the anthropic result that H squared is one-half
so when you if you see little H squared around
just imagine that it is one-half
so let me say a word about the Hubbel's determination
Of the distance and redshift relationship
Hubble measured a redshift of a galaxy and related it to its distance
but exactly what is the distance is it the distance when the light was emitted
the distance today and in fact it is something known as a luminosity distance
this is is the definition of the luminosity distance that goes in the Hubble's law
so astronomers can measure the flux
of an object and if one knows the luminosity of an object then the luminosity distance is the
equivalent inverse square law distance to the object
and this
just comes from conservation of energy is the area of a two sphere centered on the
at some time of detection
T zero
and you could find the area of the two sphere from the metric so if you
look at the spatial metric the area of the two sphere is the area of
constant R
so the area is four pi
D omega
times A zero squared R squared
so the area of the two sphere is four pi A zero squared R squared
in terms of the cosmological
inverse square law fourth
there is also a redshift
of the energy of the photon
so the flux is the energy per time per area
there is a redshift of the photons and also a redshift of the time
there is a a streching of time intervals due to the expansion of the universe
so the flux is redshifted by a factor of one plus Z squared so the luminosity
how work for the systems i simply don't happen very very reliable information
therefore sorry guys but i will talk a bit radical i also
in some the search engines implemented this way something like that
what is information retrieval task
for example
we talk about the number of information in real time
in my opinion what is
what it is common for all four of these
for all this stuff
first of all
the and for me the most important one that in all this task we have
a user reason information need
you have some huge amount of information
and you have some information need
we you want to select some information from the bigger set
and this information can be taxed that is the most common one
so i found it can be speech and for speech easily converted into text
like can be music
music search engines is not popular but there exist
it can be images the had this lecture about images information trail
on the other hand in the real life we always have to mix
morning search engine they charge for video news which are mix of images
and text
an updated sound something like this
what that that's what i want to actual information retrieval
it can be much political judgement have some query
our information need what we
i was thinking in our brain what what we need to find we can convert
some questions to the system
usually two
not useful to anybody but but it helps us to find something
it can be
classification of clustering here in wiki when we say OK let's divide our view which
a set of information to some pieces
and that's find the piece that is more suitable for what i'm looking for
or it can be extraction summarisation i have
war and peace from leo tolstoy
please give me all
fragments that i'm talking about war
this example of
summarisation some power extraction how we look at this
and talking about my
personal understanding of all the staff fifteen years ago
when i
i started doing this when i started working in this area
everything was very very different from me
i was thinking architecture
one approach sound is another i'm not doing sound i don't understand how to process
images completely separate
OK for actually creating indexing for classification summarisation creating my
and some some west coast occasion algorithms
for extraction summarisation again another
maybe because i became warden stupid but i think that's all the all this
task and all this type of
all of them are actually
the same
if you're looking at all morning approach to information retrieval from all types of information
and using all types of stuff what they're doing
the structure features
from your data
then you're using
and now it is currently we are usually using some
much learning approach
to combine these features
and simplex try some probability that actually result of this system
if x if they estimated probability that this particular document is relevant to the query
regarding search
if estimating probabilities this particular document
belongs to this particular
topic or class
it means that we had
if we don't know this place is this class its unsupervised classification of course there
is a
and extraction is now the same but we are working on phrases of our from
from from the document
and sorry i was thinking that you
would have some white or but we don't have it so
therefore sometimes take more than ten i should
so when i was thinking about this
this current i at first i started to think about world picture that i give
you the previous slide
and then i understood that it's not the votes not it's not possible to cover
all this stuff all data structure
therefore what i decided one friend of mine he gave me this advice section
said that let
why i trying cover everything you feel saying that everything in the same way
don't you look into
some particular example
let's consider this example toy search engine
we have
the set of documents
that somehow are going to port into our search engine
and a user
do a query and get results from the search engine
and all framework for this lecture is actually development of
the search engine development
during so it's not really development
they're going to write in any called but
every lecture slides
beginning to then but in different parts of it and different levels utilization
and verizon
each information retrieval structures
that somewhere inside the search engine
there are no
what sort of put such all of
what are going to do well
OK so
let's start our
our development
what our course outline
first of all introduction what i'm doing right now what about what they are going
to talk about
the next lecture
should i think will be today
after this one
it's some basic because i want i want to give a short overview about
because structure in computer science
it's a huge area and
for the car so we will
simply because some small
useful structure
four after all the usage
and in what environment are going to develop policies to what is our hardware what
then start to build index
usually we need to index such test
and we'll talk about the search in this index
and then i'm going to present to topics that
they're ridiculous are
so somewhere
between these because they
should be used in in
what steps in inverted index and in search
i decided to to put them apart at the last lecture there's about language models
and the link graph
how to present them and how to process them
when a
when you don't hear me anymore somebody in the first row can tell me i
hold up my point OK
OK so
OK i said this is from the features laboratory max planck society achieving his mother
page and also you slides on my website on my home page
OK so this real has three parts
today i'm going to talk about the basics of postings the idea some interaction
and and also about adaboost behaviour on the training set
tomorrow morning i'm going to talk about some theory in particular some translations error bounds
and then some
results related to convex optimisation something related to much like a much larger margins and
also two greedy optimisation
in the second session tomorrow i'm going to talk about extensions patients of boosting strong
talking about relational posting two hundred machines and also improving postings robustness and also extensions
to regression and other problems
and i'm going really talk about applications
OK so in this
so you can download the slides it's also
the she also thinking
OK so today is going to be quite easy so tomorrow this i guess that's
quite that it's a bit more difficult is good to morning and once you understand
that that's all you
good stuff
OK so
there there are some sources of information that you might want to know so that's
in particular that page posting along it's been told so this some all i mean
currently there is a lot of information on the but it's not very current some
kind of a better term for that position so this new version which i just
started like two days ago for that and that
play supporting to talk later
OK so this a page five options theory that contains also some publications on boosting
but may made his publications
OK so the main conference hosting
things are published book series published as the conference on computational learning theory colt but
also on the information new information processing systems conference NIPS two-thousand ICML
i guess the main general is machine learning machine in general but also the journal
of machine learning research but other people have also been published in information from in
computation and and statistics
using the log there's also a list of people who slightly out of date
list of people working on boasting and also there are few implementations of boosting algorithms
available but essentially
there are many algorithms because these are usually quite simple i mean you just need
a few lines of code so you can just to the left
there are a few regular papers and this one written by what they actually several
similar ones written by roger pierre particularly the mention one here and HP ninety nine
and also in two thousand three i
cause that every paper astronomy
is also called an introduction to boosting
and really when you have questions ask at any time OK time
so what problem so
we would like i mean you probably all the introduction stuff several times i just
make it short
OK so we consider points two classification problem so we have a natural because i
give examples so the natural world through the plastic apples so that you to have
the class label and the plastic apples have minus
and we are considering of classifying these somehow
so all the instances of the data comes in