i'm going to turn only then the graph here
and the then graph created electric field
so we have the vendor graph here
let's suppose that this vendor graphs
creates positive charge sometimes and graph creates positive charge on the dome others can be
designed to create negative charge on the
remember from now lies on the positive
what will happen
electrons want to go in this election
so this becomes negative
the positive charge stays behind
but that becomes through induction the dipole
because i have connected
i have been connected with these metal bars
so these electrons can flow through his bar
and up here
i removed the bar
so when i removed the bar
i have created now
i have here
insulating thread then the fishing rod
and at the end of my fishing rod
i have no permanent dipole
with a permanent dipole
i'm not going to probe the electric field around this then the graph
i could have chosen the same then the graph but there's a reason why i
think this one
and as i walk around this when the graph
you will see
that this fishing rod at the end is this dipole that the dipole always wanted
to go radially inwards or outwards depending on how you look at it on this
field i can probe this field and make you see for the first time that
there is indeed
somewhere here a strong radio field
going in or out of the
then the graph
and now comes something very interesting which i found out this morning for the first
time when i did this experiment
if the other than the graph
it is also positive when i run it
how do you think this dipole is going to align them
if i walk into it
will the negative pole
the closer to the then graph although the positive one go closer to defend ground
so i give you thirty seconds to think about it so i make the dipole
as it is here let's assume this one is positive this pentagram
so this site becomes
call it a this site becomes
positive that's been i now walk which is
type libraries in this field
let's assume that one is also positive we don't know that yet
however the dipole line now will go
in words or will they go out for
o things a goes in words
very good who says a goes outwards
OK able going work
the two when the grass
have the same polarity
so if that doesn't happen
that doesn't mean that physics doesn't work it means the two then the ground have
different polarities we'll see what happens
so let me first then create
a dipole
so here is the
the dipole
it's sorted out now
i turn on the
this been the graph
two induction takes place remember that the yellow
is pointing towards the then the graph
and that the audience is away from the van graph
so i induces dipole
i really should we do that
i don't know what happens when it
after we moved field first
yellow was inside right was that the weight was
yellow inside
there we go
about creating dipole through these metal boy
and i break contacts
and this should now be that
now i turn on the
field of the
so if the polarity is the same
yellow going
i will try to swing in little
i noticed two things going to line up beautifully radially
but the yellow
it's not in yellow without
there two hundred about have different polarities
you see they rotate nicely
and they and the beautiful radio
when i go all the way around here
i may swing a little they may also made a little bit through them think
they will come to all
look the field is indeed
beautiful radio
and the and always
so to speak on the wrong side
two when the graph
have different polarities
so you see how we can create dipole
and you've also seen
how we often
can make statements about
the specific polarity
i can probably electric field
using grass seeds in all
grass seeds
and when i photographed scenes in an electric field
it will become polarized there's nothing you can do about it using grassy
and the electric field is like so
and so the electrons one goes far away in this direction is they can induction
and so this site remains positive and so what is this grassy going to do
going to rotate
it's going to line up with the electric field
is an object that is floating in the liquid in water
and if if i pushed a little further in
let it go
and there is a very unique frequency that you will be able to calculate
eight o three
there unique period of one complete oscillation
as this object
goes up and down
even when steady winds
can generate
periodic almost periodic motions which all of you have experience you walk outside
the wind in your hair
goes like this
that doesn't go about like this always has this tendency just like a flag does
the same thing
if i generally do in here
and i have used similar
you'll see
that this went
doesn't make the aluminum just go
well there's a certain period to that
after work
if you want to have some fun
what is more fun
writing your own
that's the periodic motion
falling in love can be periodic events
now i don't do it too often
because most of you know
quite exhausting
the motion of electrons
out of this
periodic an oscillatory
the motion of the moon
the planets and the stars
all symmetry
is a beautiful example
i produce sound
i produce sound by oscillating my vocal cords
i use thereby pressure waves my vocal cords whose only air circle the air push
on the air
which produces a pressure wave and the pressure wave propagates out
in the lecture hall
reaches UEFA euro start to
move back and forth
and you
your brains tell you
that you here
a sound
i have you tuning fork
which is designed so that if i give it a bit
at the problems move two hundred fifty six times per second
recall that two hundred fifty six hertz
works is one oscillations per second
on the or you can hear them russia where you generate and we will deal
with them and they don't three
forty air reaches you draw your own starts to shape this is a high frequency
four hundred forty words
most human beings
can you hear
in the range from twenty words
twenty kilometres
animals who can go beyond
and to be nice
you for the first time this first lecture
i would like to test your hearing and that will be free of charge
i'm not so much interested in knowing what your lowest frequency is but what your
highest frequencies
i'm going to generate here sound i'll start with hundred
they will go up higher and higher and then we'll see
where you ewing stops
so let's start with hundred hertz
i'm not going to ask you can hear it because clearly all of you can
now go
a bit of a thousand or so like my that not
changed my
four thousand
you know
there little less
six thousand
one of my own
while i i was
agent using the heuristic really first of all
more the case as
forty thousand dollars a year hands you can your
you can not here
forty thousand
don't be ashamed of it's not your fault
all right this photo about fifty thousand coconut you raise your hands first of all
you're getting all
sixty thousand
we cannot sixty is of course the ones we already raised and you don't have
to raise your hand
o canal sixty thousand coconuts
seventeen thousand
eighteen thousand
OK so now we're going to change and i want you to raise your hands
if you can hear it
so i first go
twenty thousand
ninety thousand hundred ninety thousand or so
i was only on by factor of ten
ninety thousand will can
but that's the
twenty thousand
twenty one
the outcome of
very short
twenty two
very good
twenty three
twenty five
twenty seven
so of you have an amazing
because i really talking about twenty one thousand
all right
absolutely key in this course will be simple
harmonic oscillations
because they are extremely common
in nature
the simple harmonic oscillation
our dictionary and forcing things at least up to huge
what we decided to do
we decided to be as much as possible in memory
creating a dump on all these
all this temporary part of inverted index
and then merge
this temporary index
and this is exactly what we are doing
created all modelling memory something like this
fourteen two
imagine that we are building viagra more
or OK let's start this unigram model building unigram model and the
i have
the whole memory filled with our dictionary
what are doing
this simply setting this
this information file
started by
it will be
a a then count how many times so first more than worthy this etcetera etcetera
after the
the whole
the whole collection
we can merge this file using of the way in which all there is a
and create all the models
so far so rules so
wait using this approach
we can process
and any number of documents for building of our models
how why and say why and talking not about probabilities but about content
why we need to save only
abduction festival
if it's safe probabilities during the
we kent updated
it's not so we need also to know the whole number of documents
you can
try to do this simple math
if you
one hundred documents
and you have
five documents really that with this work
you are added
one hundred one document and you see this word sokol can calculate probability if you
o point zero five
i don't know what to do it you need to multiply it again to the
whole counter this number so you need to you need to say i can't
and finally merging indexes
also it's much simpler to keep
can't because it's simply and one column to another gratings inside
and you don't need to do any other irishmen
when we have result probabilistic model in memory when we already created it in good
one to use
and want to use this probability
it's always
better to use not real probabilities but lottery
because of these probabilities in real life
are extremely small numbers
and if you combine the small number especially when you multiply these numbers
you can easily get
on the floor you can easily get zero
in my experience it is extremely
common situation
when people are creating some probabilistic algorithms
they calculated probabilities for small model
everything works fine
then this this stuff
the government
at this moment suddenly the model became very strange and they don't understand what's going
and usually because of underfloor
if you are working with
the most common operation is multiplication
because usually have assumptions about independence
and look there is a presentation is extremely
good for this type of operation
what we need to do any single image
need to some our probability
sometimes we need to some probability
when we again have
independence assumptions have assumption that this event network
i care together and we want to calculate the probability
in this case
senior programmers doing
he taken
some blue
unlike the rest
and his writing some form like this
again during
are usually during the and it some presentations
capital and which is the number of molecules divided by the volume is also
the divided by katie
so this is a
five by katie
times and
i take this
creation and i say i
equals minus
divided by katie
i'm going to be on the here and i think to divide there
so we get the
divided by p
equals minus
defined by kt
some kind of constant
and the y
first talk about that constant
constant must have the dimensions
one divided by meteors
because this is the mention this pressure divided by pressure no mention
the y has dimension of length
but this must have that i mentioned one of length
in fact i can calculate
what katy
over g
but you don't have the dimension of length
i know OK
i know t i take zero degrees centigrade so these two seventy three
i know which is
what i take for the molecule
a molecule of air was an animal well
we have
twenty percent oxygen
we have eighty percent nitrogen
the atomic mass number of
up to thirty two
nitrogen twenty eight
but really there is more nitrogen than
so take twenty nine
as a reasonable atomic mass number four mean mass of a molecule and show you
get them that is roughly twenty nine
times the one point six six
i'm standing minus twenty seven kilogram
he stayed in that equation you can be too far off
and what you find
this is a thousand metres
has unit length
or it is a two kilometres
and we call this
eight zero
so i will rewrite so little
what always was done with the integration
i rewrite
created and introduced for that constant
one of the eight zero
hmm i turned upside down there to get links
so we have the p
over the
one minus one of eight zero
i integrate
two zero which is sea level
and he at some altitude h
so the y
these are all the sea level
altitude h
that's an easy integral
so i get
l m
altitude h
divided by p zero
he calls
minus eight
five by zero because the integral of the y from zero to eighty simply age
so i find no
the pressure at
altitude h
because two because he zero
i'm the mines h
divided by eight
this is the altitude in the atmosphere
and if you take this page then this is the altitude kilometres h zero down
so if you use this equation
you can calculate what the pressure is at various altitudes general atmosphere and that's not
a bad
approximation error is a point nine kilometres high
uses equation you will find that the atmospheric pressure is there only one-third
of what we have here
none of oxygen to live
i did quite a bit of observing and
observatory in chile which was at an altitude of twenty four hundred metres
so you can feel that so this is the same as the probability of observing
infinitely many more given finite limit one
if you compute the probability in the baseline plus models
you get identically zero
you may argue that that there because i mean
it's pretty unlikely that the road will exist forever
that would mean that on the contrary the probability that a lot
infinity given one b is one
so you will be absolutely sure that the world exists whatever
and this seems like a ridiculous statement
so the baseline plus model
cannot cope with the situation
and this is yet
phrase terms of raven paradox you observed in black ravens you ask whether all ravens
are black
and the basic plus one you get identically zero
which is
to most people
why if you choose uniform is universal prior
you can show that rapidly converges to one
with the rate which seems reasonable
well solved the black ravens paradox
the main reason is
in the baseline plus model prior density
so the probability
of ten to equal one is
and you start with zero prior going here this in discrete models having non-zero prior
for all
compute the hypothesis
then parameterisation environment is very important which i mentioned before you go from ten the
ten square you would not like you know to get different answers
jeffreys prior
but this problem in small spaces
and you can show
that the universe proprietary power station in four
is large space
then there the so-called problem of all evidence
you have your data before you start modelling
and then you could cheat mean either consciousness lead or unconsciously so you you bias
everything to what your data
and then things go wrong
but if you take is universal prior
even if you know your data
before you start i mean you know the price of two to the ninth the
commonwealth complexity of hypothesis
whatever you are now try to cheat although by assume all my model you sort
of to the data you can do that but then i mean you get a
complex model and you get paid for
there is no way of treating anymore
another problem which is formally solved often when you start with the patient
you start them on the class and then you make some observations then you see
OK this multiclass class was small micro outside and then you make some adaptation
if you start with the big class of new
you never fall outside except the discovers and computer was
so you argument this class may be unnecessarily large so
what things
but OK
it is what does it mean the last and maybe there's not computable physics but
as long as it's computer but it's in the class but
so there is no evidence of course i mean you know we can never be
sure so
what if we detect uncomputable physics then you know many things break down i mean
all the concept i mean of of universal turing machines
the true church doing and all these things
i guess
the main things can be rescued i mean at least i mean if this extend
the class which includes uncomputable physics i mean that you just don't do the same
thing with this larger class
of course then you can say OK i mean look here extending model i mean
like everybody else does it gets bigger and bigger
i mean at least for you know a couple of hundred years now
this computational hypothesis is
i mean of course you can never be
sure and in any case is the largest multiclass anybody uses
except for a few exotic doing things you there might be some uncomputable physics and
so on
these are mainly to criticism in one way the biological system popular physical over there
something else so i don't believe that
and the other question is the problem of separating the observer from the system which
is quite interesting because if you say the universe you know you can simulate you
know any computable way
well now you have to carve out somehow this AI system from the environment and
and that gets really tricky especially in the maximum which explain later because they assume
that the rows computable but the model itself is not computable i mean that should
not be the case it's in our universe and yet the issues
but it's
but nevertheless i compared to what people assume normally this is really i mean
enormously we
and i can't see it or any
reason at the moment you to make it more week
and what we can also show finally so
in the case of of of continuous model
i said you only assign non-zero probability two
a discrete subset
and from the physics perspective is good enough i mean maybe you think of this
calling independent and why should know the bias b computable
but if you think about it if everything is computable then also the bias computer
but many statisticians don't like to say OK i mean you know even if it
may be philosophically true i mean it's you know
any more observations
can proceed
OK so let's proceed to the
the second part which is really
when we start looking in more detail above
into a graphical model
in order to make some
progress here we will need to
to define a few
a little bit of notation OK
very straightforward
i will be talking
most of the time about some random variables x and is run viable is basically
a random field is a set of
individual run via k
like for example
potential image is around five
can be seen as the prior has a running yield where the random variables comic
violence because for
and the lower case x will just north of particular realisation of that run randomized
so for example an image
generic image genetic one megabyte image for example can here and the environment
in the particular one mega image of
you've taken by me with a given cameras particularly is one possible element of the
huge space of possible image
well that
particular element is
lowercase x
if the set of all possible realizations
which is huge of course in this example i just gave
capitol access to create a
random field cont
restricted to only the subset of articles
indexed by the indexer
OK this is only a subset of the random
next a killed
is basically
the random vector composed of all the other virus
other than
this is important
because we all the time be talking about
on par set of variable
subset of the entire set of articles
the completion of that
so basically have here is basically the set of all possible station
and p of x is the probability that reliable ax assumes particular realisation lower case
just notation i mean we need to support for while this
flood because all the rest
of of the
four course will be
basically using this and the venetians and
of course you have some basic properties of probabilities
the first fact is any probability between zero and one for any event in your
and the sum of all possible realizations
in the set of all the
i will give you one
all familiar concepts
i'm sure there are no
major problems here but i mean if you have any questions
you can
welcome to us
but are two
in fact that you will
all the time
when you talk about graphical model
the probabilities all that OK
you can just think of them as rules but i mean
what you really doing here is basically defined kind of defining conditional probabilities
we have a joint probability distribution on two sets of reliable
the probability of
these are the bible conditioned on these
and here we have the probability
of only one
i should say that these are lower case axis is of particular instantiations of the
not a reliable really
it is defined for p of x being greater than c
yes question
that's true i mean it's just that in general you defined
this thing by dividing this thing but that
so this thing only be well defined at least in the simple formalism i mean
you can both more complex probability formalisms
i don't really requires things
but that's far beyond what
so marginalisation well
now these calls his very critical moment before
extremely familiar with this
what surprised many people were not so i mean we need to make sure that
everyone understands the marginalisation
so basically we already given example before
we had the probability distribution any viable and we want to compute the marginal probability
for x y
in order to achieve that we need to compute
when you have some
the probabilities of all
realizations where the critical value of x one
we do that
if we need to sum over all realizations of that particular value hold
it doesn't matter the value of the order so we need to sum over all
the value of
this is exactly what this is saying if we want to compute the
probability that a given set of random variables has a particular realization will need to
sum over all
realizations with that the whole
nothing holds the semantic web the rest
what happens with the other five to sum over the entire list
all the time variation of the rest of the lives
that's exactly what is here is a
i mean
i'm just being picky here because of all this calls is
scanning the simple
i mean
it's also
the basis of
almost everything doing so
we need to
the photos
on this concept
the funny thing is that we do this all the time
compute marginals in our minds and
even without noticing that we can do that for example if
if i if i if i troll
two point
OK let's assume that the
two events are independent i thought point
and then i what's the probability that after
growing according
the first outcome
that's the question
i have a quite improbable plots
what's the probability that in the first part
the outcome was there
so obviously fifty percent
this was a member of the french the gear had invented halide photography so someone
in france offered to x-ray
the human soul
this is very good
i'm ashamed to say what happened in the united states the new york city college
of physicians and surgeons
o announced that they would use
x-rays to project
anatomical diagrams from textbooks on to the brains of medical students thereby creating and i
quote an enduring impression
and i want somebody offered to extract copper pennies and thereby turning them into gold
so that's that's
but seriously what would really did happen very quickly was the use of x-rays is
the diagnostic tool
already in february of
eighty ninety six there was a scottish physician
who used x-rays and look it's simple it's just that you could do this in
high school
i mean what is it you know it's just a gas discharge tube
a pair of electrodes feed through
he's got thirty five thousand volts and that's kind of stuff that comes after chelsea
of your
a television set
this is trivial stuff
so people off
with these things everywhere there's offices and an open view
nobody knew
so this position
had seamstress come to him she was involved in an industrial accident in mill
a needle broke off in her hand now how would you find the needle in
x-ray they identified the location of the new
perform the surgery for dental applications it was
immediately adopted were already using in eighteen ninety nine is the form of treatment for
very interesting article
so what's the relative physics what's going on here
where do we have to go i say we have to look at the animal
because that's where the electrons are crashing into that's the site of the collision isn't
something's happening about arnold
so let's look inside the anode
suppose it's copper what can we say about it
an old
this is where the
electron collisions
that's the maximum
impact isn't it
let's just see what might be going on and through the power of estimation
how far
how far down i've shown you that
with nitrogen at six hundred sixty eight
electron volts to get to the initial electrons what about in the case of the
an old well what's going on there like and say what's the energy of the
one as electron in copper twenty eight plus that's one electron system
and you know that in real copper with all of its electrons this value is
going to be
and overestimate because the presence of all the other electrons is going to set up
some of the proton nick
coulombic force of this will be an upper bound on what that you could be
we know that simply equal to the energy of the one as in hydrogen
z squared
so if i take thirteen point six electron volts
times twenty nine
squared i get
eleven point four
thousand electron volts which is still less than the thirty five thousand electron volts the
ranking has around can is running
huge bowling alley here he's able to knock out one as electrons from copper
and what happens when you knock out electrons into shell electrons
what's the next thing that happens
now let's look at an energy level diagram
let's let's suppose this is
the anode so this is
the anode in the gas two
energy level diagram so this is going to be and
equals infinity
and i to do a few of them so this is an equals four
equals three
n equals two
and equals one not to scale and try to show that there are a little
bit farther apart as you go lower and lower and so this is ground state
energy e one this is
n equals two shell any equals three shell
he calls for shellingout here is zero isn't
and so what i have got some
the incident electron comes zooming in here
zooming in here this is
this is the one that's been accelerated writes the energy of the electrons all kinetic
and that's the product of the charge
on the electron which is
elemental e
time supply voltage which is thirty five thousand volts that i get thirty five thousand
electron volts is the energy
and it can come in and we just showing that it's got enough energy that
it can even knock out an inner shell electron
it can even dislodging english shell electron
so let's see what would happen if that were the case
it is large is an inner shell electron what's the next thing
this was the sort of a long story in what follows
looking at some
rather nontrivial minutes so
this is actually useful for anything
it is useful for something
because it tells you
tell you doesn't just give you
the the
function that the line would give you enough to tells you something about what the
of these predictions
i think the whole distribution over functions
so we have also shown you two random functions from distribution
interestingly the random functions
from the distribution
i'm not actually will not
actually some of these little red
o o o if you don't like these functions then maybe you shouldn't be using
the nice thing here is to get
you get out of the three
this is something you don't get
think of lines being lines but i think about being a prof
when you get them for free
and actually get the other thing you get free is you can automatically
find out what the noise that would the data
but the most likely
the level of the noise because you can optimize the much like
this is something that also in the traditional find framework but there isn't really a
particularly good answers
in one dimension it's pretty easy to see
despite expecting OK
OK so the kernel
looks like this
this is just a function of x and x right
and you have to you have to use it in the limit where
so i go infinity
it has one free parameter
which is
which is the
which it would tell us something about the magnitude
and then you will typically have also
another contribution to the grounds which which would be taking care of
the the question is how does this blind kernel compared to the gulf kernel well
that depends
that depends on on what data looks like could data actually
looks like that with that these kind of functions then
the plain kernel would seem to be a better idea i presumably would give you
a higher value of much like if it if the data really come from very
very smooth functions then this doesn't seem to be the appropriate right OK if have
ten data points spaced far apart
the data does not to tell you have a lot of that but the marginal
likelihood probably extremely close to each other
so the question is how robust the half approaches do if you just specify you
know one kind of one kind of kernel you get away with that just one
people have been wondering about this and i think this is certain degree of
robustness in this in this kind of approach is so
for example that showed before we wish we had this periodic components etc et cetera
of course
you know i'm really injecting some valuable information that case vital so so presumably i
wouldn't do
as well and that kind of stuff like but if you look at
the problem is that of typical in the machine learning literature that it turns out
that actually
the squared exponential kernel
often does a pretty good job
and this is the same experience people have been work and support vector machine they
almost exclusively use the kernel and they typically only have a single
with parameter that they worry about they don't even use the notion of a rt
of having one with parameter for dimension
and the reason why they don't do that because they don't have a nice way
of choosing the from the truth
for the next four years
they had to
thank you
and the good morning everybody
i come from the department of intelligent systems of this institute and has already announced
talk about stochastic search methods but before we start some organizational issues handouts for this
presentation were distributed around so if there is still some of them using this material
is that
for several additional copies here
anybody still needs these
the second
o thing is
if you agree about twelve o'clock i would make a short break of of five
to to seven minutes they told me this would be a good idea
and the last announcement
during my talk
if there are questions if there is something unclear
as you can ask your question
so we
make it clear once not to wait until the end or wherever so
you are encouraged to us
during the presentation
if we start
our presentation will
consists of consists of three parts the first make a short introduction or an overview
of this field of the stochastic search methodology
and if you
go into detail
regarding two methodologies that fit into this call this is simulated annealing which is
right now
traditional rather popular stochastic search methods and then into the field of evolutionary computation
we will discuss evolution and is
first about the motivation for this technique
summer school is on knowledge discovery so we have to relate to the field of
stochastic search it
knowledge discovery
we should first say that in knowledge discovery we are often faced with problems of
performing search in high dimensional and multi modal search spaces
how to make this clear
what means high dimensional i think everybody knows
if you have a problem that depends on the certain
parameters of variables because there are many many say this problem is high dimensional
so what is multimodal problems
if you imagine
function surface
a lot of certain functions
it is multimodal if it has
multiple local optima
one can of course imagine that searching
in uniform all the
so space is easier than in multi mode
finding the global optimum
in such
is computationally expensive it is
demanding so we of course need effective and efficient search methods
catagory of these methods that will fit into the scope is also stochastic search methods
regarding the search techniques there are
many of them
four different purposes over time in different periods but just to mention few groups we
of course
we don't have time to go into details
so the traditional approaches calculus based like gradient methods i think we are all aware
then there's enumerate you search techniques like exhaustive search for dynamic programming
and finally the whole group of methods that are discussed today
this is stochastic
search methods examples are want to colour search taboo search evolution witness has already said
thatcher illusion area which was not discussed the other things but
just for those more interested in stochastic search there's a number of good sources of
and in the literature there is a
there are some references like the book new ideas in optimisation but i really recommend
to all of those really interested in these techniques
there are also other
sources only refer to later
of course if we discuss search techniques they have different properties one thing is degree
of specialization
some techniques are very specialized which means they are dedicated that they were developed to
solve certain types of problems
and the right here in the error function
newsprint everything air which is like c and it's just designed for error handling
and call exit minus one which says what this program
reports are the operating system and we're done
this is it this is all that is contained in germany and the only two
important to this one right here including the string for class and using the standard
name space and if you do that and you get right down
european for leadership
now german is probably one easier want but what about some of these other heterogeneous
well i could go into some detail about all these but i just don't have
time and i really wish i could show you how this works shows how this
works but i just kind of give you a quick overview today
just to show you what you need to know if you want to get off
these libraries
the first one historian tells that h
this is the one that gives you strength integer integer string string to real madrid
uppercase lowercase et cetera
behind the scenes most of this stuff is back to this classical the strings string
you've seen it streams fifteen streams you've seen c after all streams into less and
less than you great and greater than
the point of the string streamer does the same thing it said that rights to
a string buffer so you can take some integer dump into a string that's here
integer string function right there
there's a couple other things you can do with that we use for doing i
conversion between strings and other data types like integers
so you might want to look into that if you play around
as for convert application converts to lower case
there's a function to upper and two lower the take individual characters and convert them
to uppercase and converted to lower case
just for the of string call that function every time presto your string is an
upper case that was pretty straightforward
in case you're interested in politics that we actually read some of these functions if
you want to have a working implementation of street that if you go to the
sea as one of the website under the code section there is a working implementation
are so if you want to keep using these things just go down the that
file take a look at it play around the world
so we want to set
the next machine
it doesn't have any understanding the see story
you know it's some users only possible to compile everywhere
and it works pretty well i mean i think we only to find a few
of them but you can see how they work and you can define for we
give you string integer you can do bring up or string to real parties by
changing contacts
this is the big winner miss empire that age have you've ever played around with
the ross sea possible simple functions before
they're kind of nasty i've always thought that this thing called in which is the
counterpart of the at the input is kind of like a rose which is it's
very sweet it's very delicate but the second you break it down to the foreign
and it hurts a lot
really you have to think of this as probably one of the most powerful one
of the hardest user input libraries and have any programming language see
so we give you this entire library just to take care of all these things
for you don't have to worry about it
it turns out that the way it works every member get one you can use
it really one of the file
we can use line on the sea stream to do incorporating reading
real as text strings can be converted to an integer
plus or minus a couple of things that get injured again if you go to
see as one six website there's a working plantation of this if you do want
to consider doing people must be and this is actually pretty good input functions you'd
be surprised how many people don't actually know how to write these things so got
around the have some find see what they do and that way you can continue
using the coding conventions you've seen by using only standard c plus plus
the random functions in c plus plus are pretty simple others two functions random strand
random and see the randomizer again
consonants are expensive dolls are expensive and
randy gives you a random integers in the range zero
to round max so if you want to get around w one to get around
integer random boolean just take the number in that range scale it down to zero
one feels back translated etcetera
it turns out this is probably the easiest one to rewrite from scratch is just
have to be able to careful how you do your bounds checking but it's not
so bad the header file for that c standard library but you can find all
the one of is simply
what you actually are going to be missing is this one
graphics dilation extended graphics
unfortunately c plus plus does not have a standard graphics library this doesn't exist and
there's a couple reasons one it's very hard to standardize traffic you have to make
sure something it works on every single platform which is very hard to do
no so if you're writing c plus plus good from microprocessor where you know that
you know have traffic to kind of be difficult to support the library
so there's no standard c plus plus equivalent but i'm back to this program that
i'm using right now is written in c plus plus very got some kind of
so what i mean by that is rather than a lot of situations
you don't just want to predict whether an example is positive or negative
you have reason to believe that the outcome the actual labels probabilistic so instead what
you want to do is one to predict
the probability
of an example being
positive and negative
so it turns out that there's a principled way
taking the output
a boosting
and converting it into a probability estimate the conditional probability estimates
OK so these are all the good things about viewing boosting as loss minimisation algorithm
but now i want to add a very important caveat
there's a temptation to say
now i understand adaboost all it's doing is minimizing exponential loss
and so exponential loss must be a great loss to use
but i've got this toolbox that tells me
you know ten different ways of minimising any function certainly any convex function and a
lot of them are a lot faster than adaboost
so i'm just going to use one of these other algorithms which is going to
be much faster than adaboost and minimizing exponential loss
so let me say that i think that it's a mistake to work can be
in this might be a big win possible that that would be the way
but it's possible that that's not going to work at all
and a because i think it's wrong to view adaboost as just an algorithm for
minimizing exponential loss
and the reason is that you can construct other algorithms
we're minimizing the same exponential loss
which will provably give very poor performance
so you will construct examples it's really not that hard
in which you have some other algorithm that minimizes exponential loss
but the performance is much much worse than adaboost arbitrarily bad
what this means is that this
explanation of adaboost as an algorithm for minimizing exponential loss
is useful it's a useful way of thinking about the algorithm and has its benefits
but it's not
it's not a complete explanation about adaboost
and it's not
necessarily going to guide us to better algorithms
OK so
i'll skip the
OK so there are other ways of thinking about adaboost so which i'm not talking
even the ones i'm talking about are not talking about i guess
so one of these ways is more recently thinking about adaboost which is to view
adaboost as a dynamical system
and here let me give applied for cynthia rudin talk tomorrow at two
so where she's going to describe how you can you adaboost as a dynamical system
and she promises that the talk will be accessible to everybody certainly the students seen
talk so
you can believe her when she promises that
there's also been working on the statistics literature
showing that adaboost is consistent algorithm in the statistical sense of consistency
and so statisticians are very sad people like leo prime are extremely satisfied with this
particular explanation of adaboost which are not going to talk about
and there are also some very interesting connections between adaboost and maximum entropy so
one way of thinking about adaboost is
as a special case back from entropy or other modification of maximum entropy
where you remove some of the
normalisation requirements the normalisation constraint
and so again i can't we talk about this here but i can certainly give
you pointers
OK so let me move on to the last part of this tutorial
which is on experiments applications and extensions
i'm going to talk about some basic experiments that were done on adaboost just to
see if it works at all
then i'll talk about
multi class
the multiclass version of boosting
and i'll talk about confidence rated predictions which give the big win in practice
using boosting
i'll talk about some applications to text categorisation and spoken dialog systems
and by time i'll talk about how to incorporate prior knowledge human knowledge into boosting
using boosting with active learning and then finally an application to face detection
OK so
the parking lot about the theory of boosting and i want to switch gears and
talk about the practical side
so let's start with the good stuff so
why is that was the good algorithm
well first of all it
fairly fast
it's a very simple algorithm in any case it's very easy to program
there are no parameters to tune the only parameter is
the number of rounds of boosting but because boosting tends not to overfit
i never said that it never can overfit but it tends not to overfit
because of that the
the number of rounds of boosting often is not so critical
let's see boosting is very flexible algorithm is flexible in the sense they can combine
with any learning algorithm any weak learning algorithm
you don't need to have any prior knowledge about the weak learner it just like
in whatever weak learning algorithm you want
adaboost is provably effective
comes with these provable guarantees that we talked about provided that
the weak learning assumption are roughly holds so provided you can consistently find these rough
rules apply
and so this might lead to a kind of shift in mindset the way you
think about designing algorithms
because usually think about designing an algorithm which is going to do really well over
the entire space of examples
now instead we can just think about
designing a learning algorithm the weak learning algorithm which is just a little bit better
than random guessing so maybe that's easier to think about
on adaboost is personal algorithm you can use that
with data that's textual numeric discrete whatever it's been extended to
learning problems
he on binary classification things like regression
all kinds of stuff
so that's the positive side with the negative side whatever caveats
well you know like any learning algorithm adaboost depends on the data that you're actually
and you will see that this force now you must be in the direction of
i one cross with b two
and that's exactly what i predicted to wires go towards each other
if i leave everything to say but i reverse the direction of i two
now to two current sign opposite direction
then the forces will flip over
so now the two wires
and i will demonstrate that to you
i have a
those two y is here
you will see them there on the screen
i will
explain what you're looking at in some detail
the two wires run vertically
this is one y
this is the outline
and when i run the current
in the same direction
they will attract each other
you will see that shortly
three two one zero
they go to at each other
i'll do it again
i run the currents in opposite directions
they will
repel each other
and i run them in opposite directions
everybody can do it again
one zero
the reason why i showed you this demonstration is the different one
well i want you to appreciate
if i
i have this conducting
played of alumina
and i put that in between the two wires and i repeat the experiment exactly
the same thing will happen
and that tells you that magnetic field
really very different from electric fields
because the electric field will be heavily affected by conducting
she would like to
very few of them up
so what i'm going to do now is i'm going to put this played in
and then
i'm going to again put the current in opposite directions so as know why is
repel each other
as if the played one of their
one zero
there you go
the magnetic fields
very interesting
story to tell
and magnetism
how do we define the strength of the magnetic field
his electricity
we define the strength of electric field
in the following way
measure the force
electric force
on the charge on electric charge
and then electric force
if the charge the electric field that determines the strength of the electric field
be nice
if we could now
the magnetic force
the magnetic charge
so that would then define the magnitude of the field
it would be nice
but we haven't found a magnetic monopole
we can do it
if you come with the magnetic monopole tomorrow i can do it
but we have no magnetic monopole
and so it cannot be done this way
how is magnetic field then defines
well is defined in the following way
i take
an electric charge
and the electric charge
and if the electric charge
moves with the velocity v
and that is the magnetic field where
electric charge is moving
that is an experimental facts
that's the forces
is always perpendicular
if you want to call that
the magnetic indication that's fine
it is the magnetic field of the charge is moving with velocity and is the
force on that charge which is always perpendicular
two feet
the magnitude of that force
is proportional
due to speed of the particle
and it is also proportional
due to charge itself if i don't know the charge
the force doubles
if i double the speed
then the force doubles
so the way that we define out
field strength
this way
force and i give it to be to remind you
magnetic is a few electric charge
he was the velocity of the electric charge
cross product
we've been
you see that the force is always perpendicular to the
and that is linearly proportional to be linearly proportional
because the charge q and is often called
lawrence four
the dutch
this equation is completely signed sensitive
if you change from the positive charge to negative charge
then the force flips over
on the degrees change direction of the e force slips over the interaction of b
four completely signed sensitive
four magnetic field frank
it follows from this equation
this is not and
q is cool
and these meters per second
so this would be the unit for magnetic field strength no one would ever say
this one this one and this one
and the message
that i accelerated discharge
i could not possibly have reached
this location in space because that message can only travel with the speed of light
sorry electric field here
it's exactly the same as it was
but it was
still here so when the object is here the electric field must still be like
this year and it must be like this year and it must be like this
the message hasn't
reach that point
but now look at this charge which is now here at time t delta t
now the electric field
like so
and it's like so
so this field lines
must somehow meet up with this one is one and the same field line
and what does that mean that somewhere there there must be a kink in the
electric field
and there must be a king here
notice there's no king here which is interesting
and so
it is the collection of these kinks
the propagate outwards with the speed of light
and they produce an electromagnetic
disturbance a change
if you're out in space here
and if for instance i would also laid this charge back and forth
you see these games go by all the time
he breaks in the electric field
you would experience that
as an electromagnetic wave
if there is a changing electric fields
according to maxwell's equations has to be also changing
magnetic fields
but the interesting thing is
even though it is an extremely simple picture
that in this direction if you were here
you will not see any kinks
so it is no electromagnetic radiation going in this direction nor is there any going
in this direction
and the maximum is going in this direction and something in between is going in
that direction it's not much of a plane wave for that matter
i mean anything it's more like a spherical wave
but it's a very special spherical is not the same strength in all directions
so even though it is a rather classical picture
it helps me at least c
how these
electric fields and therefore so should be fields are formed by charges
that we accelerate
and i have a two minutes
that shows that also
in a slightly more detailed weight and i was able to do
so let's look at that movie
marcus you're ready for that
OK then you can start that
so this is a computer-generated movie whereby we
accelerate charges
this is a constant speed now we're going to stop it stopping means is an
acceleration right you may call it the deceleration but stopping is an acceleration
it's going to be stopped using all these things
and they propagate outwards the speed of light and
this was electromagnetic radiation
you can see several times you get another chance
charges now to stop using magnetic electric field lines coming out and being accelerated
you see these here
moving out with the speed of light
going to see more
there is
to accelerate during acceleration
only during acceleration do you see the formation of the king's when gold was constant
no longer
only do it notes stopped
stop means an acceleration there you see
this will be from moving out
the bit more you can
the oscillating effect
you have already have seen this
here is the
stop the mean deceleration
you see
we from
and when it's sitting still
or when is going with constant speed and is no electromagnetic wave
now we're going to see some oscillating charges
which is more realistic when you have an antenna you have currents going up and
down with frequency omega
you obviously have
stops and starts to oscillate back and forth and that's what you see now i
look at beautiful
weights going out always going out only during acceleration there's one going out
there's one going out so you accelerated
backwards forwards backwards forwards
i think that's fine
thank you marcos
so the classic picture
even though it has lots of limitations it's not the quantum mechanical treatment
it's still very useful
as for instance if we
think of a
an antenna straight wire with current
up and down the high frequency
could be seventy megahertz could be gigahertz
you produce electromagnetic radiation
and you are
accelerating charges up and down by having current going like this
that from this classical picture
we know that no radiation will go on in this direction
but we also know that in that direction
during acceleration
that is in this direction wt acceleration was like so
and in the direction of the acceleration
no electromagnetic waves go out so nothing goes out here nothing goes out there but
in the plane perpendicular to a which in this case the blackboard
is the whole plane like this
and in this case of the internet is the horizontal plane you we have maximum
radiation going out
everywhere in this place and in between somewhere
you don't have observable but you have had
to have no
but immediately when you
when you make these observations
because this person
so basically what
what's happening here is that you need to
remember that
whenever u
the tricky thing here is about the head to head nodes
if you
the not observed
the head to head nodes
the parents are independent but this one is you observe the head head nodes
have that connection
let's proceed
the separation
it's the critical concepts to define
this is the critical calls to the foreign
conditional independence
on bayesian networks OK
so that's
three important calls
so basically
this separation uses the definitions of
look at that
a set of nodes a is said to be d separated from another set of
nodes b
not from again
given a set of nodes c
the second from to given
if every path from a to b is blocked when c is in is in
the conditioning set
this probably best by by
by steps
from may just do this by by
sorry for this
so the pens is said to be d separated from a set of
the set of old
this separated from a set of rules be
set of nodes c
if every pair
from a to b
when c
is in the conditioning set when seasonal
so let's look at this sort of the OK
we assume that c is in the conditioning set
this is a subset of the conditions that may be the entire conditions
king particularly to subsets OK
if every possible path from these between these two sets
is block
when the condition c
then we say that
a is d separated
but from b by c
so why is the separate this is just the notion of what we call graph
separation for directed graphs
and it's tricky
because exactly have directed graphs when we see that for markov random fields
undirected graph to want to take all of the very
very intuitive
but in this case
it's a little bit tricky but you need to keep in mind that this is
the definition
in other words
you need to check
every single
from set a to set b
given the conditions set c and ask whether that that is what
if every he's blocked
then you have
d separation
then the sets of be separated
by c
so now
here's an exercise
you have these bayesian networks
and the question is
whether x three is the separated
x six
when the conditions set is x one
and x five
this is basically
the question
we observe x one x five
we have this observation
and we want to
no whether
these viable
and these viable supported
if we observe x one x five
so any guesses
why not
thing and
it is separated or not for that question
so you need to check every path from here
so here every number of bands
from here to here
for every band
you need to
assume that these
and the the also
that any
and so i
i think that's the question you want to sort of be asking yourself in my
practical i'm going to try and
get you to sort of look at the problem where do monte carlo actually makes
some sense this other practical sort of will be looking at other methods in NLP
looking problems appropriate so the question is really it's monte carlo the right approach feed
for you and maybe the way to find out have to implement it and compare
you do sanity cheque whether the numbers in the right ballpark and then you go
fast method or you go to this because it's the only thing
this actually in another motivation for during samples we concentrate alot on sort of numerical
computation because the concrete thing today but i just examples are pretty say this is
a figure from
david mackay's textbook and this isn't machine learning applications there are people who interested in
tiling shapes in this the whole sort of feel the geometrical combinatorics and this is
the problem we packed lozenges inside a hexagon you randomly sort of create you can
think of this as the whole the whole breaks the sort of the pile telling
out if you can see that optical illusion and this is the random sort of
way of stacking bricks into hard
and when you just glance at this you can see that sort of the circle
and the whole literature on describing the properties of the circle the minor notice it
was there unless you just looked at samples e
you could have found this article exists and describe properties of it just by doing
mathematics but you know is something you should go and look for by just one
single the sample
and for r
i think if you can visualize what you probabilistic model is doing and you can
draw samples and might give you hints the sort of things that should go away
you should do so his his really simple example it's sort of it by now
that the toy problem in machine learning but
here are some
very low resolution binary images of digits
and these are samples drawn from probabilistic models that have been fitted to the dutch
so the
these here are sixteen samples drawn from the model which the mixture model suburban areas
say this to the probabilistic model that basically says
the way i am going to generate an image is i'm going to pick
some templated for example are image and i can add a bit of noise to
and then that's going to be able to out the way you explain any the
image you see you say this is a bit like one of my templates and
it's a bit different so i'll explain why not
and then you draw samples
you see the really noisy and so that immediately tells you that the sort of
model and if it's you can't explain all the variations by just a hundred templates
which is what was fitted here you need to have some more flexible model that
can capture all of the invariances is that you get in an image
this is actually a long history of this sort of just eyeballing things and seeing
how things turn out so is monte carlo methods really took off in the fifties
one of the first computers but before that for me who was the physicist was
standing his colleagues because he
would come in and he would say oh i think that this neutron experiment will
come out like and he was often write and he is answers in the right
ball park and it's because he was up at night with the hand adding machine
running monte carlo simulations on his desk without computer and now we've got the computing
power we can just do these things trivially so you know we really should
so for us if we written down our model is a directed graph rather than
the sort of through the dynamical equations for new neutrons we should know how to
sample from a model and if we've gone the rate writing down directed graphical model
or bayes net some people call and then
the algorithm is really simple and i'm sorry i missed even lectures i don't know
if you want to say
the way that you would sample from this base that which was in
we've been applied the running example if the first just sample all of the parents
right at the top and we know what the distribution is because when
this graph is giving up the joint distribution which tells us what these distributions
and then we sample all the children once we know what the parents are just
from the conditional distributions that we've written out
so this graph to give this natural generative structure and that's one of the reasons
the great modeling the once gone the effort we never and then see what it
does and it captured the things we wanted to
so how do we actually
implement that how do we do this ancestral pass and rule these variables and the
short answer is that you know we just is not what we we use whatever
computing environment provides because it's going to have implemented in it already
a lot of the standard distributions that we used to drink from the prior is
going to be simple and if
you're likely to provide these functions and the
good book which i understand that explains how a lot of these algorithms work under
the hood so this is sort of old established stuff
we can have to understand how a couple of these library routines actually work because
that's going to sort of
tell us how we can improve on them and that's unless you really know what's
going on in coming forward from that
so here's a really standard way of drawing samples from a distribution
you have some probability density
you just sampled uniformly point underneath the area from this curve just
the area here and you just choose something randomly from inside and then if you
read off the location in the input space you're interested in that's your sample
so the reason this works is just that
if the coherence twice as high than here then like much area and efficiency are
twice as likely to sample it's respect the distribution
and the way you implement that is you notice that
so this point here
has about
half of the probability mass to its left
and this point here has a
six of the probability mass was left to this amount of mass is to the
left hand side of the point is actually
a uniform random variable
the implemented by drawing uniform random variable and working out
how far through the cave should be
so mathematically what you do is you work out the cumulative distribution of the curve
you draw a uniform random variable and the new shops that through the inverse cumulative
so i say in my grandkids point seven i read across to this cumulative curve
i read down on sample
and that's great as long as we can actually
compute the blue curve and inverted which we can do for gaussians and exponential some
simple one d
distributions that we can't always do
so if you look inside the source code for something like again random number generator
depending on which label or you're looking at it might do a series of horrendously
complicated things depending on which parameter regime you're
and one of the things that might do for some of the promontory genes is
rejection sampling
we want to sample point underneath the blue curve for distribution
and we don't know how to do that because we don't have to compute this
cumulative and that's it
but we do know how to sample from a bunch of other distributions like gaussians
uniform distributions piece wise uniform distributions so we get some of the distribution
that we do not have some of from like get in and we scale
the function such that it always above the blue curve
then we sample
the green distribution the q distribution
and so writers of options
hoping that they expire
on exercise
and that's when they make money
write an option
and the buyer of the option
pays the money up front and then you never hear from the buyer again
and here
that's that's the way you like it
so you make money by writing options
and hoping that they don't get exercise
and of course you can write a put option
and that means
if you write a put option you are signing a contract that says that whenever
this other guy on the other side of the virus
decides to
the guy will
i will sell you a hundred shares
at the specified price
again you're laying yourself open to whatever this guy wants to you've got to receive
a hundred years
and pay the money
these kinds of
context our
very old
and in fact
we had a conference
over the weekend at the yale school of management
it was very interesting never
experience is anything quite like it
they i should put the website
it's called the
seventeen twenty
about the stock market
and the by nicky rare book library
he has a copy of it
they are very rare
about the stock market crash of seventeen twenty
did you know that there was a big stock market crash in the years seventeen
what was happening in new haven in seventeen twenty
well i know one thing that was happening in seventeen twenty
you you've in new haven
i'm guessing pretty pretty sure you has some pretty angry investors
who lost everything in the stock market
but it could have been the US stock market which wasn't created yet
the crash of seventeen twenty
was primarily in paris
in london
those with the financial centres of the world's i'm speculating there must have been someone
here in new haven
probably yale university he lost in this crash i don't know
busman's someone here who lost it was a huge and devastating stock market and this
is the first one actually
the first stock market crash
and so we have a lot of fun at this conference and this relates to
after the taiwan relates options because people writing options
galore in seventeen twenty and
the book the great
so does it work if you search on great mirror of quality
on the web
it come up with our conference
and you see and says this book
you know copyrights expire after
but complicated formula but in less than a century so
this is all public domain so has it up on the web you can read
the whole book
unfortunately it's written in dutch
which might deter some of you
but lots of pictures and we had great fun so at this conference the
it was the most interdisciplinary conference ever seen
because we had
professors from
we are history
comparative literature
finance economics psychology and we had scholars from all over the world who knew
about the year seventeen twenty
including a lot of that the dutchman who are here
but anyway that the highlight of it was they were a highlight for me
was it had to
we saw a picture of an option
from this time
an option contract to buy stocks
from amsterdam
and it showed it was a printed form
they had printed forms back now this in holland it's open to open it up
with blanks to fill in as a place to fill in the exercise price
and they exercised a i don't know whether it was american or european
at the time but i'm sure if it was american they didn't call it an
american option in seventeen twenty they don't even call them options because it's on dutch
so i don't know
it was some other word not options
but i'm just saying this because the ability to think about seventeen twenty is that
they didn't make the same distinction between investing in gambling that we do now
right now
anyone on wall street is very close to be
any suggestions
connection with gambling
and so
back then
they didn't care
so lots of socks would have lotteries attached to
there would be all kinds of something called the time team
a group of investors would invest in something and
one hypothesis one make a large error in estimating the generalisation error
all the hypothesis to make large error has been generalization error and so on
and so by the union bound with the left foot to
which is therefore less than equal to
subsequent to that
and so on
then just take one minus both sides
the creation of the previous one then we take one minus both sides
the probability that does not exist
such that
on the property that does not exist a hypothesis i which i make a large
error in this estimate of this is equal to the probability that for all hypotheses
i mean
camera unless the generalisation error
on and taking one minus the right hand side again
he two
gamma describe them
and so
on the side of the inequality flat because i took one minus both the minus
sign the sign of quality
so what we've shown is that
with probability
abbreviated to WP with probability
one minus the two chemistry
we have that
on left one half of each
will be
moving camera moves on
simultaneously for all
hypotheses in r
and so on
just to get this name was just to get this result the name this is
on this is one instance of what's called uniform convergence results on and
that the term uniform convergence this so these the fact that all the shows as
n becomes large
o then these eps long hats what all simultaneously converge to absolute pitch that
training error will become very close to generalisation error simultaneously for all hypotheses h that's
what does the term uniform
refers to the fact that this converges for all hypotheses h and not just one
so what shown is one example of uniform convergence
so let me clean a couple more ports to come back and ask questions you
have about this was taken look at this initial unmixed
what questions you have about this
i value of
right so let's see
chris has gamma how the value of gamma computed so for this purpose for the
purposes of this of gamma is a constant imagine the gamma some constant we chose
in advance and this is the bound holds true for
any fixed value of gamma
on later on as we
take this bound and develop this result further on which is specific values of gamma
support this analysis imagine that prove this holds true for any value
have the hypothesis spaces and so this this simple result will work in its present
form the which generalizes on very won't get to today but will generalize this at
the beginning of the next letter to the hypothesis
his theory practice linear
i might get a little more of that later today i will talk critically about
our problems
that's the consequences of a
the understanding these things to you in the next lectures well
his raise your hand if things are true so far make sense
cool great
all right then just take this uniform convergence bound and
we write it in a couple of other forms
it's sort of the bound on probability this is saying suppose pacific training set and
typically transit fixed by my threshold by air pressure gamma
of what is the probability that uniform convergence holds and well that's that's formula gives
the answer is the probability of something happening
so they actually three parameters of interest one is one of the pub what probability
the other parameters was the training set size and and the third parameter as the
value of this error threshold gamma
on on on the ground
that very painful for these purposes
this suggests two other because forms the bounds on which is so you can ask
and this is what we propose giving gamma given and what is the probability of
uniform convergence
on the other because forms are
so given camera
the probability delta of making a large error
how large training set size you need in order to give
a bound on on
uh how much harder publish a society need
to give a uniform convergence bound with apprentice cameron delta
and so
so he said delta to be able to to cater to demonstrate that this that
all i had on the left
and strong
four and what you find is that on there an equivalent form of this result
says that
so long as you training size and weight
and this is the formula that get by solving for n
so long emissary to do this
then the graph would break into two or more pieces
so it's a if you cut those out then the graph breaks apart
so we're going to see is that these two things these two notion cliques
and cutsets these play an important role in how we describe undirected graphical models
the way these graphical models work is that what you're doing is you're using the
describe what you believe about the dependencies that you see in your random variables
right in many applications is again the notion of locality if if you have a
collection of sensors your intuition is that censorship interact local in the spatial sense the
censor here should interact with one here but it shouldn't interact directly with something on
the other side of the room which interact with its neighbours
and so the graph here is is specifying this neighborhood structure
in a more precise sense use the graph to impose constraints on the random vector
and there's two different ways to do this they seem different first but they turn
out to be equivalent
in the first is by the notion of markov properties
so you say that
the random vector x all the random variables its markov if
the subsets of variables x a and x b become conditionally independent whenever you have
a vertex cut set
so what this means is that
if you observe the the values of the random variables here
right your conditioning on then when you observe them
then it says that
this subset of variables x eighty a becomes conditionally independent of the subset
so it's sort of capturing the fact that when you condition that's breaking the graph
and in terms of the random variables it's breaking them apart because they become independent
see all
you will have heard last time from sam about the simple example when you have
an HMM
this is the simplest example of the markov property if you think about the present
and this is the future and this is the past
so if you condition on the present that the cuts that that will break the
graph into two then as m told us the past and the future become conditionally
some kind of mystical but that's just a special case of of the markov property
that i just stated
so this is something past and future and present that's a special case of this
poor interested in this actually for more general graphs and you get much richer markov
properties in more general graphs
so that's the markov property that's one way that you can use the graph to
constrain the form of the distribution
the other way constrain the form of the distribution is
is in terms of how the distribution might factorize so let's get back to this
example let's imagine that you had
binary variables so variables that took value zero and one zero one one zero and
one that every one of these nodes
right so
in general how many numbers would you need to represent the distribution over that set
of random variables
right so to do the seven minus one
right because you've got to do seven possible configurations in your whole graph
but then probability distributions have to some to once you lose one degree of freedom
right so to do the seven this is a toy problem again this this is
not something practical it's already getting big if you thought about something that for instance
modelling in images to binary image that was a four hundred by four hundred you'd
be looking at two to four hundred square
that's a very big number that's an understatement that's
that's more than the number of atoms in the entire universe the entire visible universe
so it saying is that unless you start exporting structure there's no way you could
ever even store you can store vector that has two to four hundred square elements
if you can then i'd like a version of your computer please
so the point here is that we're going to use the graph to constrain the
form of the distribution we going to impose the to be local
so it's going to drop the number of degrees of freedom
so we're losing something in doing that we're losing we can express all distributions anymore
but we're getting a lot because we can actually do things with this model we
can store it we can apply it and we can do inference and the way
we constrain is by saying things have to
decompose into local functions these are called compatibility functions are potential functions and these functions
are local in the sense that they depend only on the random variables in the
cliques of be function for one two three
a function for three four five et cetera local product of functions
so just look at a simple example lets go back to this image model that
we had before now i'm trying to model about boone
and again i'm using this the simple lattice model and thinking about these being grayscale
values might be zero one or they might be zero one to two hundred fifty
so what you want to think about is the cliques here the maximal cliques are
just edges just pairs of nodes
so what it means is that you're sort of allow function of pairwise interaction term
that's going to sit on every one of these edges and that term is going
to tell you how is this pixel value related to this pixel value
so simple case if i just had three grey scales
number three by three matrix
i might look at an interaction of this form i could have one number a
along the diagonal
and then be on the off diagonal
and so this would be two parameters here and if i said a larger than
what they would tell you is that you're more likely to have their values on
the diagonal values are equal
the values on the off diagonal so this would start imposing kind of smoothness constraint
would say
pixels that are nearby like pixels on this knows
are likely to have close grayscale values
so it's a very simple kind of thing that imposing but it let's start
so that's how compatibility functions work they sort to tell you about local interactions between
OK so let me say something briefly about directed graphical models again this recapping what
sam did
for directed models you have now arrows on the edges and the semantics are somewhat
you really think about the parents for instance by focus on the blue note here
its parents are these red nodes and you think about the factorisation is taking place
over conditional distributions of the child's given its parents
so in some ways it's it's a kind of parent to child it's generational factorizations
the child conditioned on its parents
so these models are useful for
they can express certain kinds of causal relations sam mentions something called explaining away phenomenon
so the certain kinds of things that directed graphical models can express the undirected ones
can not
but vice versa there are some things that undirected models can express the directed ones
one model is not better than the other
it really depends on what kind of application you're looking at
and it takes experience and intuition to sort of figure out what's most appropriate for
what you're trying to model
for the purposes of this talk
i'm going to focus mainly on undirected models as i mentioned before
and the reason being that when it comes time to doing inference
the first step
when you're given a directed graphical models actually to convert it to an undirected model
so from the computational point of view
if you're given a directed model you typically converted first to an undirected model
and since all be talking primarily about computation in the later part of the talk
all sort of assume that you've converted this directed model
if you remember sam mentioned this it has a quirky name the procedure is called
because what you do is you marry all the parents the parents have had an
illegitimate child
modern convex it's fine
and it's not just every line segment defined by two points but the entire line
defined by only two points in the set is included in that find mindset
the set of linear inequalities
the finds are convex sets
one point here in
and i use this notation with this inequality to denote componentwise inequality between vector
this is a component inequality between vector x in effective b
norm balls the set of vectors x with normal is then given there are is
always convex
as for any norm that's follows from the definition of norms
and there is a related set known as normal college
then we look at factors xt is some vector in r and t is the
and the norm cone is defined as this point xt
the norm of x is necessary to fifty
so that's the con because every positive multiple of xt that lies in this set
is also in the set
and you can also show it's convex if this is the norm
and that's true for any type of norms
and i will also encounter the set of positive semidefinite matrices and that some notation
so in
n denotes the order of the
press stands for positive semi definite
and then i'll use again this generalized inequality
in the case of the matrix of the node positive semidefiniteness so this means that
the symmetric matrix is positive semidefinite
and it's also
convex sets
and then there are some simple properties that you can use to show that to
drive convex sets from simple convex sets
so if you take the image of a convex set under a linear transformation you
obtain a convex set
and that's easy to see because line segments are mapped to line segments by a
linear transformation
so for the inverse image under a linear transformation
and also the intersection of any number of convex sets is convex
that's follows directly from the definition if you
think about the definition
and that's
a very useful property
allows you for example to immediately see that this set is convex without even applying
the definition
so here i define a set c of vectors in rn
and the vectors the components of x are the coefficients of course a polynomial of
order n
x one course antiques to call center t and so on so every set of
every vector x defines a course in polynomial
and this shows three is very visible but this shows three
of course some apologise for
choice of x
then define set c as the polynomial coefficients of a polynomial
for which this polynomial is between one and negative one
on the interval
of t between zero and pi over three
so these three example satisfy this property so the columns corresponding coefficient vectors or in
well this set c is always convex and that follows from the
is easily seen from the intersection property
because if you
look at this condition for a fixed e
then the condition that p of t is between
one negative one defines two linear inequalities in the coefficients x
if t is fixed
so it defines two
half spaces
and the solution set for fixed is actually a slab between two parallel has spaces
and then in this definition be
define x the set c is intersection of infinitely and infinitely many of those convex
so this is convex because it's intersection of in this case infinitely many convex sets
and so in an example for hours two it looks like the intersection of all
those as spaces
and t it's convex
so that's all i say about convex sets
so then next that can define convex functions
so the function f is convex if first of all its domain is convex so
the set of points experts define convex
and on its domain it satisfies this inequality is jensen's inequality
so this is that if you take two points x o y
then on the line segment if you consider function on the lines seem defined by
x and y
the graph of the function is below the linear interpolation between the function values at
so the graph of the function lies below this
linear segments
so function satisfies is is convex
and if mine f satisfies it's the function is concave
so you can also related to the theory of convex sets
so the epigraph of the function f in in general is defined as a set
in fact xt so in dimension but dimension one higher than the
the main office
and the point xt is an epigraph if
f of x is less than or equal to t
so it's a graph of the function and everything above the ground at school because
so this is the graph of a function that's obviously not convex
but for convex functions we have the property that the
epigraph is also convex in s if and only if
marginalize integrate over the parameters and hyperparameters
that's ultimately what we want to do
and once we do that well we can be simple monte carlo approximation
right where the samples
i generated by markov chains
with the stationary distribution which is the posterior distribution of our model parameters
it's just this
general setup for
o doing inference in the directed graphical models
in our implementation we use gibbs sampling to generate samples but corsican use any other
markov chain monte carlo procedure and of course you can see the due to the
conjugate priors the conditional distributions are easy to sample from so that was our initial
one other thing to notice is that the posterior distribution of the movie and user
confusion matrices decoupled
they become as the product of individual user features so you can sterilize
in other words you can make it efficient in that for that particular graphical model
that we consider
and you can see from
this graph here is that conditional on these values in these values
the posterior distribution of the
user features decouple the same as for the movie features
so we do is standard example which is to say that conditional on
more features we can update we can get sample from a sample from the posterior
or with these latent variables
and same is for those guys and then for each feature vector
for each
we get sample for each morning feature vector by conditioning on the user feature vectors
five so that's just a standard gibbs sampling
so that was conditional on this random variable in these in the variables
we just get samples from those guys and alternate so now
this is all very standard and
i haven't told you anything you
one of the the things that we were looking at initially with sort of playing
with the netflix dataset as a huge dataset
and the main
question was that
how do we deal with this regularisation things and what we typically do is we
ran cross validation we try to figure out what the appropriate hyperparameters should be
in just to give you the player the netflix dataset is very large it contains
hundred million ratings contains half a million users and a about eighteen thousand movies
there's a validation set
and there is a test set for which must be predicting
user movie ratings
in the dataset itself is very imbalanced so
you know other users could give only one rating in the users would be fifteen
hundred ratings
and the performance is also says by
you know you make predictions you submit it
to the netflix and then give you the results so
it's one of those things that's hard to cheat on who accidentally you
now one of the things that
you know the question is
the nice thing about probabilistic matrix factorisation doing map version of forensic medical situations that
very efficient and you can do it fast and
initially we were thinking well actually take a fully bayesian approach you have hundred million
ratings big data
and typically if you look at
attitudes of all the people that you know MCMC methods are
really really for small problems
and what really work in this particular context
and we actually with surprise that
indeed it does work
so here the results that showing you
this is the SVD one
which is basically probabilistic matrix factorisation model but without any regularisation
this is probabilistic matrix factorisation model this is a slightly different version of probabilistic matrix
factorisation model
and here's what bayesian PMF gives you
it gives you much better
root mean squared error so it gives much better predictions compared to the MAP estimate
and to us that was a little bit surprising and the surprising thing is that
you know you can actually run these models
with third dimensional feature vectors of sixty dimensional feature vectors
which are quite big models in
you know
these are the times about eleven hours maybe forty seven hours
a couple of days
and you can see that the gap between those models is actually quite large
what's going on
right so here the results by showing that
is you increase the feature dimensionality which is to say that as you make your
model bigger
what happens with the bayesian PMF
the error
the performance improves which is was
you know sort of a good result for us because it basically says that you
know the the bayesian approach doesn't really require you limiting the complexity of the model
based on the training data
which is not the case for the map based models we we actually trying to
learn the parameters of the model
and you know for the three hundred dimensional feature vectors and half a million users
thank you have about seventy five million parameters in your model so if you had
so many parameters in your model and you don't have nearly enough data
fitting those models becomes really challenging or regularizing the model becomes
a very challenging task
so again the the the i guess the
the main idea here is that as you make your model bigger
for this real task
the bayesian methods actually give you a better performance of the performance improves
one of the other good things about
you know finding or getting samples from the posterior distribution is that you can take
uncertainty into account