OK so this would be
slightly less in summer of but but still very elementary in many of you know
it but
nevertheless i hope you don't really get
and here OK i'll try to put the idea that the things
that speak out OK so i will talk about learning with
it's particular area of machine learning that bothered around and you know a little bit
more in there
other than the toolkit of machine learning that if you are working you should really
know about this kind of thing that you can use
various contexts
the ability
to override this morning sharing this is what we have six of lecture one was
that even though alex i will not give a three RR
actually i think i'll use the point on the screen because it may be the
people next door
to build a lot and
can we turn up the volume
i could just to be clear this
OK so i will give three electors now this one is about the concept of
similarity and the formalisation of this concept in terms of kernels and also i will
talk a bit about feature space is associated with columns then we have a short
coffee break after with about a small mathematically about the notion of kernel
the associated reproducing kernel hilbert spaces i'll show you how knowing it doesn't cost much
time and finally i will talk to you about one
application of this feature spaces which is already know this is touching some fairly recent
research connected to the notion of kernel means so maybe not everybody knows about this
tomorrow alex will continue with support vector machines and structure estimation
OK let's start informally so suppose we have inputs and outputs
taken from some sets x y
and they were given a training set of scales x i y i have taken
from the product of these two sets
and we assume that some regularity except that something about why
if we talk about learning the notion of generalizations so we want to find rules
from observations which generalize well in the sense that if we are given a new
point x that we haven't seen before
we somehow should be able to find a suitable why that fits together with this
x well in a certain sense and in which sense it fit together well one
sense would be to say somehow this new pair x y should be similar to
the ones that we have seen before
and then of course immediately the question comes up how do we measure similarity and
for outputs this is
usually fairly straightforward although it is also a topic of research and it can be
arbitrarily complex but for simplicity let's say for outputs this problem is trivial and we
just use the loss function so suppose we interested in binary classification our output are
just past minus one in which case we could use the so-called zero one loss
function is just the loss function that checks are the two y value is the
same or the different
science the loss of that's a plus one when values of different in size loss
of zero whenever they have the same but for the inputs it's less trivial problem
to come up with a similarity function and that leads to the notion of kernel
so let's say we use a symmetric function that takes inputs and assigns a real
as the similarity value the for instance if our input space where the euclidean vector
space after the end we could use just the canonical dot product between these inputs
of this notation i denote the i th entry of the vector x
that could be used as similarity measure in a way to the simplest similarity measure
that we considering machine learning but of course if all
space x or false x
beginning only called sexy is that if it's not a dot product space we cannot
use the dot product and in this case what can we do well we could
for instance assume that are similarity function k has these the representation of the product
in some
space that has a product so about this i mean we could assume there exists
a map takes our inputs mapped them into the product space
and then our similarity measure is equal to the dot product in that space
so in that case we can think of are inputs sometimes i will use the
term patterns for the inputs in this case we can think of them
as the points are represented in the vector space
and then we can carry on whatever metric organs we want to carry out in
that vector displays in this vector space is sometimes called the feature space
let's look at an example of such and such an algorithm that we can carry
out in this representation
this may be the simplest possible classification algorithm and in fact so when we first
describe this all it was just for the introduction of the book that we wrote
about kernel machines just as the tutorial introduction but recently we noticed this is actually
much more useful and i'll come back to this in my lectures in the context
of kernel means
so this classification algorithm what it does is just given two sets of points plus
pluses here and the circles here we try to find a classifier that separates one
from the other and that even the new point x which is down here
for instance continue point assigned to one of the two classes how do we assign
a new test point x to one of the classes where we could just compute
the means of the positive class
notice plus the mean of the negative class minus also written about here implies is
the number of positive points these all the positive points of something or positive points
that was the point i mean ones with labels that plus one is the mean
it we have same for the negative class and given a test point x we'll
just check whether the closer to the negative to the positive me it's trivial way
of classifying these data points in
one way to do this
different ways you could just compute the distances directly
but another way to do this would be i mean we are working in the
product space so we can compute distances another way in which we can use the
dot product directly rather than the distances would be to compute this point c which
is halfway in between the positive and the negative class means
then compute the vector connecting c to artist point
this is this vector x minus c
and now we just have to check whether this vector what kind of angle of
this vector close
which is the vector w which is another connecting the class means
so in this angle is smaller than ninety degrees
in this point test when x is on
this side of the hyperplane that noted here and if the angle is larger than
nine degrees it would be on this site
obviously the set of all points that are closer to the miners then to see
plus forms half space
over here which is separate from the other half space but these hyperplanes in the
it's going to say
you can get it right
OK these laws are universally valid
it cannot be circumvented
so many people have tried to do that
every year there is
newspaper story
wall street journal new york times about somebody
has invented a device
somehow goes around the second law
it makes more energy than it creates
this is going to be
well first offered investors going to be very very rich
and for the the rest of us it's wonderful
and they go through these arguments and they find venture money to fund
company began very famous people to endorse and etcetera
you guys know because you have MIT degrees in your
later it in fact sixty that because you're not going to get for the investing
it's amazing
every year find
somebody coming up with a way of going around the second law
and somehow convincing people who are very smart
this will
there are more than is also big cities
as you can see from
my descriptions of these last year
it makes you believe initially
and the feasibility of perfect efficiency
this is the first law
the first was very upbeat
it talks about
the conservation of energy energy is
and served in all its forms can into take heat energy is converted to work
energy and vice versa
it doesn't say anything about
we have to waste heat if you're going to transform it into work just says
its energy it's all the same thing
right so you could break even if you were very clever about it
that's that's
pretty neat
so in a sense it says if you want to build a boat
it took energy out of the air the one of the air
sail around the world
you can do that
and then the second law comes in and says well
that's not quite right
the second losses
pretty much the same in all its forms
but if you want to convert one form of energy into another
you're looking for
very work
and i wanted him to work with one hundred percent efficiency
we've got to go down to zero degrees kelvin to absolute zero if you want
to do that otherwise you get away some
some of the heat
somewhere along the way so that
OK so all right so you can get perfect efficiency but at least if you
were able to zero degrees kelvin
then you'll be all set just gotta find the refrigerator under your vote and then
you can still go around the world
and the third light comes in
that's the best part well
it's true if you could get a zero degrees kelvin
you get perfect efficiency
you can can't get to zero
even if you have it
infinite amount of resources
you can get
and questions
so far
so thermodynamics based on the four laws now requires an edifice
and it's very since very mature science and it requires that we define things carefully
so we're going to spend a little bit of time making sure we define our
are concepts
and our words
and what you find that when you do
problem sets especially at the beginning
understanding the words
and the conditions of the problem is
most of the way into solving the problem
so we're going to talk about
things like this that this is ten
is that part of the universe
there were study
these are going to be fairly common sense definitions but they are important and when
you get to problem set
really nailing down what the system is
no more no less in terms of the amount of stuff that's part of the
it's going to be often very crucial
so that the system for instance to be
person i'm the system could be system could be
hot coffee
so the coffee and milk and whatever else you like in your coffee would be
the system
across the water ice
o point system
the volume of air in part of the rule maker forty years on this corner
of the room
that's my system
after you do find the system is
whatever is left over
of universe the surroundings
to find the system and everything else is the surroundings you are my surroundings saturn
my surround for universe that's part of the surroundings
and then between the system and surroundings is the boundary
the boundary is a surface
like the outside my skin or
the inner wall of the thermostat has that
coffee it
or could be an imaginary boundary
for instance i can imagine that there is
the boundary that surrounds the four leaders of air that sitting in the corner doesn't
have to be real
container to continue this just an imaginary boundary there
and where you place the boundary becomes important
so for instance for the
good rational scheme which seem to be based on a probability distributions that you could
actually observe i mean i don't have to invent these probabilities distribution so i want
to know the likelihood model for sensor i can just run that centre on ground
truth many times and make a histogram of its errors and model the distribution so
you know that distribution is something good that there really is taken from data it
doesn't have to be an arbitrary thing and now
it looks like i'm going to have to bring in an arbitrary discounting factor
it's a bit upsetting do anything
anybody upset
right so that i think that's good
yes that's a good suggestion so we do know
we ought to know something about about this column it's been moving at thirty miles
an hour in a southerly direction for the last few seconds the chances are that
in the next instant that's fifty the second for european video frame
it's still going to be going very similar species
that's not exactly the same speed
what you suggest should we what assumptions we make about speed
anyone can make a suggestion
i don't want to so you know one x one assumption one extremist make no
assumption about the speed is what we seem to be doing here the assumption is
to assume that the speed now is the same as the speed what was
i think it's a great idea
yes we could model the speed so in other words we could have some random
how precisely we expect this speed to continue the same or how much variation we
from time to time so the missing thing is a dynamical model and we need
a stochastic dynamical model one with some variability in because of the dynamical model is
too precise
then it'll it'll be
the observations of vision will lose out against it because you know excessive belief in
the continuation of the dynamics so then it clearly needs to be some noise in
the dynamics for example i could take this piece of data here using tracking system
in the camera to write the word andrew and i my computer has picked up
so that trajectories series of dots
and learned
what's called an autoregressive model which is one of these identical linear dynamical models with
noise on it and now just to see if if i've learned anything like what
actually happened out there
i can simulate random from this model that was a good way of testing out
with the models that you've learned make sense sort of sanity cheque so now
i've run this model around
it didn't learn the word andrew clearly every time i simulation this model i don't
get the word andrew
i guess if i did perhaps supplied the training data many andrews written absolutely identically
then maybe with the right kind of model maybe i could have learned exactly the
word andrew but in any case
i suppose what i'm trying to do is to build the track of the fingertips
i don't really well maybe even think attributed the doing handwriting i don't come completely
want to
i don't overlook i don't want to train specifically what andrew i just want to
pick up what scribbling is like
and encompass the variability that occurs in a typical scribble to use as a dynamical
model for tracking so seen in that light reproducing the model like this and asking
it doesn't look like a representative scribble it seems more reasonable and actually you can
analyse the autoregressive process that you learned here
to see what it's all these modes up and sure enough when you look at
the dynamical mode you see the dominant one is slow
drift down into the right which is the kind of average movement of the handwriting
and then the next most significant modes ones that explain the next great portion of
the data are
circularly polarized modes with time constants of about the second decay times about the second
and so on and
you know that's all
quite plausible that actually you can learn
predictive model which is not a completely precise deterministic predictor but nonetheless encompasses some classes
some class of dynamical
so very simple
example of such a thing
would be
a random walk
i mean i can you know drunkards walk without any preference for direction will be
something like this
so here is this is a this is adrift so we have an average velocity
zero in the downward direction
and initially we
i have some state of knowledge about the position of this
this drunken with purpose and now
the drunken with purposes
a staggering perhaps towards the door of bar
and with the loss average velocity v but also with this randomness superimposed on the
wall so this is a very simple example of the kind of model that we
might put in here and by manipulating the magnitude of the magnitude of p
we can get the effects of different kinds of dynamics is very drunken dynamics and
his only this might this level of noise might be
more plausibly what you want for
the degrees ps provides them with some data about berlin
maybe the population of the island and that
belongs to the group of german cities
if the client wants to know more about german cities he just the references this
URI i and gets information that hamburg mansion also drums it
this approach however
navigators information space by dereferencing
you can also use some tools for doing this
that is really simple semantic web browser with
at the top
you you and a URI identifying sing identifying
this debate the referents there's some information coming back and information is split
when you now and click on
this bell and
the brothers the back chant you references the URI referring to poland and
my to retrieve this information from TV PDE about but
so this basically is the main principle build global information space
building on RDF
using just the reference to the
the inferencing mechanism
and yet published data
so this principle have been applied to various projects
and quickly given overview about
the different project that currently publishing linked data
that's the first one of the first project was w three c linking open data
the community effort to publish open licence datasets on the web and intending
then this page
the effort started in two thousand seven the
there is a small set of data sets and was about five hundred million
RDF triples
and it's growing
really fast since then
kind of the
motivation we are facing now is that this effort has
published all this set
we look at the upper economy see lot of data set about music music musicbrainz
myspace is last of down here we see a lot of information about geographic locations
you name statistical he's the world fact book
down here we see more literature
publication related information that's dbp this this book mashup that gives information about books
as the dbp
up here there more
information that relates to people's online activities like
foaf profile shocked data flickr photos view that gives you a quick review was
so a lot of kudos which cooperates your online presence
so lots of information
altogether this network of data sources is
guess two
they contain about
three of form
a billion RDF triples in telling by a couple
ten also million RDF links but feel kind of
we're keeping track of the grows but
since having here
he kind of lost overview because the network is growing so fast
six but like true data sources because they are used a lot
for linking to other data sources GU names and
names in RDF because of the geonames database giving you
information that coordinates about eight million geographical location
so many people use this data source if itself geographic information the data sets and
saplings to data to due
also gives you feature hierarchies or can move up
part of town go to the tower go to the state things like
now the data source widely used is
contains information that has been x extracted from wikipedia
and this kind of everything is in wikipedia also kind of everything is indeed PD
it gives you information about two point
two billion concept described pressing hundred million RDF triples
which i'm going to draw up here so let's just call it box p in
let's use the same terminology
that's that gx
and the condition is that
you're on candid your reachability relation must be transitive
so if you ever have
three points in row with this guy i can see that kind that i can
see that guy
then that guy must be able to see that guy in one step
it can't be any infinite chains
and by that i mean
an infinite sequence of distinct points
right so if you keep going eventually
there has to be a point which is
i did it
that's not first order definable
because in first order logic you can't say something like this is
finite sequence
we try to write that in first order logic you capture approximations but you'll get
so what to what it turns out
something like this
if we look at
say classical propositional logic
let's call this
classical propositional logic
right that's truth tables
then you have already seen
classical first-order logic
right but so this is conjunction disjunction implication negation
now you have for all x
dot p of x saying there exist six p of x
what about second order logic well second order logic that's
classical second order logic says not only can quantify the variables
but i put can qualify of the atoms as well right so i can write
for all p
for all x
here this might sound crazy but it does
so what's going on is that
propositional modal logic
OK without any quantifiers
somewhere like this
we have all the classical stuff of course because we put it in there
but we also have some of the first order stuff
so was formula for example capture only first order conditions on primes
but we also have some second-oldest for example these two
OK so
this is
and this is quantified second order logic
this is why
more logic has proven so useful because you get greater expressive power
but must many of these logic not most
the interesting ones i decidable
the ones that have been used i decided
you can give algorithms to decide which by
deducible from gamma and which of course then flies
logical consequence is that you can't do that in first order logic but we've got
resolution which peter
i'm going to talk about
but there are formulae for which it just never returns an answer it just sits
there runs forever and you'll never get an answer
so that's what we're logic has being
of such
interest in computer science in particular
what about
so what we so now is that we've got second order logic
we've got a first order defined ability but it breaks down
what about
they don't have any kripke frames at all
and that's one there
OK so what
it's called h just makes this a double-headed arrow
and what this paper shows is that
none class frames
contestants logic
so that means that he would calculate a are in some sense more powerful
we have the notion of five deducible from gamma
but there is no analogue
five is a logical consequence of gamma because there's no could keyframes that determines
so what people do well people hunted around
and they
i said OK fine
we're looking for semantics will complicate the semantics of it all
and they came up with the notion of general frames
which unlike the frames to have an extra component which has aspects of topology from
i don't want to go into the details
then you get a general completeness result
OK whatever you can capture with you would calculate you can capture with
general frames
in most of the stuff that you see in computer science we always talk about
cricket semantics because
the use in computer sciences
modal logic is the logic of graphs
you want to reason about graphs right secret key frames of the
things it usually c
if you want to see how to compute sulcus formulae
from first order formulae and vice versa on paper
very good
paper by marcus cracked you can see the reference in the at the end
there's even an online algorithm called scanned you typing scanned and say
gabi into google and you should be able to find the which all
give you the
analog secret automatically so you type in the shape
it gives you back the first order quantifiers first order formulae
up to now what i've been talking about
everything that i've been talking about are called normal modal logics
i have looked at what happens if you all to some of the peripherals
OK so you have this hilbert calculus and i said there was modus ponens necessitation
what else was there and certain axioms right
so in philosophy that the
now we can notion so what i've done is i've we can this rule
right necessitation sit
you just discover up these and you go from side box i
so you throw that one out and you say
if you can deduce five
implies site from gamma
then you're allowed to deduce box phi implies bauxite from again
so we can nation
and again you can talk about
o five deducible from
as a set gamma and ask is there a class of kripke frames
thank you thanks very much for the opportunity to introduce this challenge here and so
are i challenge is in astrophysics
it's to do with measuring the shapes of galaxies and images
so i'm sarah bridle and i'm very grateful to you
john for suggesting that we make this into a pascal challenge that clinic that he
held at university college london and
this is this these are the people who have been working on this problem within
cosmology the last
ten years and we're unanimously delighted that this has been accepted as a pascal challenge
i really hope to start a dialogue with you and to learn from you and
how to solve this problem
so let's see
i need to know more about you and so our universe seems to be about
twenty five percent dark matter and so
i i i don't for you i don't know how many people have heard of
dark matter before have the headed out untested OK well that's great OK so any
more bizarrely seventy five seventy percent of the universe we don't know exactly how the
that whole point seventy percent of the universe seems to be
something else
and we don't understand which we're calling dark energy for the time being how many
people have heard of dark energy before today
OK few a few people OK great well so we were trying to learn about
the dark energy and we're trying to learn about the dark matter and really i
would say the majority of experiments in cosmology
and that it planned at the moment are to learn more about the dark energy
often using the dark matter
today about it and the bottom line is we don't know what nineteen ninety five
percent of the universe is made of
it's quite embarrassing to stand here and say this to you but it's true OK
possibly the most promising way to learn about the dark energy
and the dark matter is to use what's called gravitational lens
and so gravitational lens things is where you have a lot of dark matter and
a distant galaxy appears
it's been different place because the light
comes from the distant galaxy two as they bent by this blob of dark matter
how many people have decided gravitational lens things
fantastic growth because do so what you need is the bottom line really is that
if if you're gonna bend the light then just as if you look through your
bathroom window you see street lamps appear distorted well we're going to see galaxies appear
distorted because of the intervening dark matter
so for example this galaxy here will appear distorted to this galaxy here
and it's measuring this distortion which is the entire basis of this challenge and our
challenge in cosmology
and i would say that within cosmology community gravitational lens thing is seen as the
method with the most potential
tell us about the dark matter and dark energy
i think potential
because although
statistically it has the most promise there are many potential risks
involved with it and one of the biggest risks
whether or not we can solve this challenge
i say we i mean you can OK so this is the the most beautiful
picture of a gravitational lens and this is really extremely so
i just show this because it's pretty this is the most extreme that it ever
gets and this is not a typical system
but i don't know if you can see any the gravitational lens in this picture
we're looking for really distorted galaxies and really stretched out to be much longer than
they they really would be and they get distorted around the clump of dark matter
anybody see anything that
they might this is this is the clump of dark matter which you can tell
when we guess anyway because there's the big yellow galaxy in the middle
and that they're generally tend we think to be place dark matter clumps then you
might get serious sort of reddish galaxy here which has been stretched out maybe another
galaxy here here
here the more you look at this picture the more you say so it's very
very beautiful effect and looks looks even better on the screen in fact so so
we are actually looking at a much smaller effect here
and so more typically
we assume that the distortion is the same across the entire galaxy
and you can write it as this distortion matrix now everything i said about the
dark energy you don't really need to know that to do this challenge
you need to know anything more about gravitational lens things on this one equation
and i think that the rest of what i'm going to say
is was possibly quite familiar to you already
this one equation one slide is the bridge which is is basically what you need
to know about astronomy to do this challenge
OK so this is one matrix distortion equation and it has two unknowns
we call them shears
and in this picture here this year is about point two
in this equation
and a more typical
more typical value for that is about point oh three so we're looking for a
much smaller effect so if you had a galaxy which was originally a circle
and it would be distorted to be
with the major to minor axis ratio of one point oh three
so it's quite a small distortion we're looking for
many graphs that have what are known as bounded treewidth
so they might have tree with stays one that would be a tree an ordinary
tree you might have things with the tree which is always two that would be
a bunch of triangles glued together
but there are also other graphs arise in practice that don't have bounded treewidth
so let's just get back actually let's think about the bigger version of
so let's let's think about this graph
this is just a bigger version of the same graph
i mean this is still toy idea three by three version that's completely toy this
what seven by some risks basics
the about seven
still toy you want to think more like four hundred by four hundred
you want to sort of start to think about triangulating this thing
you have a lot of edges
do you think the tree which is going to stay like nice it three or
anyone have any intuition about how the tree with the this graph behaves
it's certainly not true with one is not a tree
we sort of know it's at least tree with three because there are other smaller
examples that
i guess one way to think about this is you could sort of make
supernodes if you want to buy
taking an entire row in collapsing down to one point
if you did that you would actually make a whole chain
but in general you can't really do much better than that it turns out that
the tree with the this grows
essentially like the side of the length of one of these sites
so if you have four hundred by four hundred model like for an image it
would tell you the tree with this four hundred roughly
even though used in the junction tree algorithm it's giving you savings it's dropping you
for instance to to the four hundred square
which is
ridiculously big down to two to four hundred
is a lot smaller but is still
completely impractical
so it's it's giving you a huge game but it for practical purposes it's not
at all helpful
so this this sort of tell you all models like this with the tree with
gets very big it doesn't stay fixed like two three or four
and so on
it sort of puts a bit of a damper on our party
because it says that
you know the junction tree algorithm is is very elegant it's very nice it seems
like it's an all-purpose solution but it's saying in many cases it's computationally intractable
and it's because of this issue of exponential growth of industry which
that you pay this price
but that's not to say that
i mean if if you are given a graphical model the first thing you should
do is it's not always easy
as as we discussed before actually finding the best triangulation and hence finding the tree
with this is actually hard to do
but certainly if you're given the model in practice the first thing you should do
is is trying to a sense of what the tree with this
it has low treewidth you would be very foolish not to triangulated and apply the
junction tree algorithm i mean that would be just very silly
but if you sort of work out that it doesn't seem to have bounded treewidth
then you sort of understand the junction tree algorithm
isn't going to be applicable you probably won't be able to do things exactly and
you need to move to approximate methods
that's sort of the summary of a junction tree that
it tells you essentially what the inherent complexity of
solving these problems exactly is it
its exponential in this notion of tree with that tree with comes out of this
constructive junction tree algorithm
OK so any questions about junction tree exeter
we just figure out what i'll talk about
so the last part of the slides in part one
sam sort of been very helpful in covering some of these things so i'll just
move quite quickly this is just going recap of things it's that sam said but
also perhaps highlight some slightly different issues
part of it to be an hourly for follow tree
this lead is four
what we are doing this in simply port these not this
to some
two or
to plant not for this
so this is not reporting data and this is
flaws in this knowledge when they have bought part of course please
and this is happening now
this is
while computing of the tree
and it's used in all that basis can be used the used here
and it's pretty fast
is as fast as building inverted index at the same time create
the tree so that
now if you are going to do
everything is very simple to
so they have some set of changes
we try to see these
the trees
and the replacing and updating slope so we can remove slots and that's what
and because of the tree's very good structure for keeping indexes and very good enough
we can we can
keep our indexing plates using the tree
and as far as all implementation that i've seen you doing my life of indexes
that can be updated in place
usually the field based on the tree
we had experiment
based on static collection creating in this one
if they are have a small number of changes for using marriage and
update processing the
if for example
can change the whole index using up date and place and our index based on
the tree
OK so
from this point of the things that we we've done in the so we have
all the algorithms and approaches to implement it in
all structure
so the next question is
imagine that we have such a collection
that it's not possible to index it on one computer
and in this case we need to
implement the same indexing scheme
set of computers
we need to distribute this process of our set of computers
at the same time we need to effectively use of this computer
the problem is that as i said when you have a lot of computers
all these heart failure there simply unavoidable
we always have some
some percentage of computer that for unknown reason broken
i don't know why
believe me to you you can always see it in their own cluster compute
the simplest approach and what we can do is we can create something like
it's the same channels as a
are used to use in your in in any in suppression systems so but there
from one box to another
and the idea is
when we describe describe when i described in different to you
creating some temporary file and then out
for this files not on this box but in another both of
OWL classes that process all the data
the only one problem that
doesn't work for
order that is not a problem for the training of
that this is distributed channel
so i'll
should be divided into a number of generators and consumers
and because of are clustering need some central controller that knowledge
core generator for consumer and consumer can
very so you can ask
controller of our consumers for my data
and controllers smart enough that it can handle all these failings and what's going on
generator produces produces data
this data
those two
and consumer then reports and on this date
OK you can you can send next ball data
and so on
for example consumer can
in this case
generate doesn't get any results but engineering has a copy of the data that was
already sense
and in this case asked
controller again
do they have another house to compute computer that can process what what i generate
and controller of
supply new
consumer and this consider process to date
this is description of the algorithm
and for indexing
how would look like our system
we are taking all classes a OK
these boxes are
all the information boxes that are processing our documents in some form
and extracting this
features of this
i e
and they put them into index and index
created this temporary
in texas in them
and supporting them into imagine great results
our index
and of
is it was motivated from statistical learning theory OK
and indeed statistical learning theory just little digression about learning theory this very different approaches
to learning theory one is sort of like a base in top approach
another one is not so well known
but is a physics you top approach so sort of decayed away in the literature
but the physics also some mechanics type approach
you have to you can establish learning curves and
it involves complex calculations correct calculations
a third approach is to school learning theory where you devise bounds upper and lower
bounds on the generalization error
and i won't go into the subject in great detail
but also you can drive these theoretical bounds on the generalization error
and i'm just i'm not going to state the bound mathematically i'm just going to
have a look and its implications
so if i'm doing some so the learning task
from handling real life data
i would evaluate on test data a given the test error
and the corresponding theoretical
test error i call the generalisation error OK
so that generalization error
from statistical learning theory i can drive bounds on it
and the bound i'm interested in
it has
properties OK
the upper bound on the generalisation error does not depend on the dimensionality of the
that's one observation and gonna make
the bound is independent
the actual size of the input space i'm considering
observation number two
is that the bound is minimized by maximizing an object called the margin
which are the notice gamma
which is the minimal distance between the hyperplane separating the two classes and two
and the closest datapoints belonging to each class all that's best illustrated with a picture
OK and here it is
so here i've just got classification
two types of labelled points plus and minus one
and in this case everything quite nice because the two types of data well separated
here they are OK
and my classifier
is a line in two dimensions or in n dimensions and dimensional input space is
a hyperplane OK
out of one and the second but
the how the classifier is a hyperplane
is it directed hyperplane
in which anything lying on the side of the hyperplane given in brown here
will be labeled as past one positive
everything on this side of the hyperplane will be labeled as negative cases are directed
now what the
so ok all the classifiers well we we can be viewed as such
what the serum therefore says
it's my best classifier
is a hyperplane
all classifiers
which is maximally distant from the closest points on both sides well actually intuitively that
seems pretty clear
because the suppose my hyperplane was like some of
OK it separates the data correctly
but is actually quite close to some points
doesn't seem to be intuitively
quite nice is the same then again if i came along with the classifiers
like so
well this is going to get some points wrong OK
so the belong to classifiers can devise some just simply be wrong to give me
an error on my training data
there will be a number which will come correctly separate the data
and it seems intuitive that in fact the best hyperplane i could
five is this hyperplane
which is maximally distant from the closest points on both sides
from very nicely separated data
indeed closest points here
the support vectors
they of course support vectors while the vector of course because really i mean and
dimensional input space so the vector
they are called support vectors because if you like they support
where the hyperplane should be
because if i started removing these guys here
then my optimally separating hyperplane which shifts
whereas if i remove these ones
none support vectors
well they will make no difference
i can remove them my maximally separating hyperplane which is set where it is OK
come on to that command
so my story at the moment is quite simple nicely separated data
i'm gonna mess so the picture up shortly
right so
this is support vectors remove them mice separating hyperplane would shift
these doesn't so that's what i call the support vectors
and finally i call a support vector machine because it's learning machine case that
so all logical
so this is the joint geometric picture
now i actually want to formally drive
the story of the support vector machine
first of all we note that that separating hyperplane
is represented lights so if you go back to your
first mathematics which did universe tour of school
then you know the hyperplane can be written light so generally
you have in textbooks and all x equal c
the equation one equation
for a hyperplane all playing OK
i've taken the see of the side but this is an equation of the plane
and x is my data
as written so called the bias
OK could be familiar some threshold
if i normalise it will actually be the normal to the hyperplane OK
so i'm going to paint here but
i'm just using the formal definition of a hyperplane and
x equal c
where n is the normal to the plane
call this the bias
o call these the weights
and this thing here
goes into my decision function like so
looks just like any sort of this argument of something like a new network decision
and hence i put my data points in here
perhaps a new data point we're missing out if positive negative plus one out it
was negative again minus one my decision function like sir
right so i
i know one thing about this this of this decision function here
this site function
you know even if a people speaker would have been likely to generate this text
you probably didn't help one to start so it was probably still generating
certainly trading
this probability
with the current probability
that you were generated from p and q and if you know this there then
you can see all of those things together
i want to i don't think this one
OK so our question now is what's the probability that we would have generated this
particular sequence of letters
the english well
we've already talked about one mile forgetting which is like trying to
so let's see how we can get it right
let's apply the same techniques we looked at before
so we've got a lot of things on the left-hand side of the bar in
fact we have nothing on the right-hand side of the bar unless you want to
on the right-hand side of the bars english
so what's the probability would have generated these if we were speaking english
we can write it like this the probability that the first letter is h
and then if the first letters h that the next letters
and then if the first two letters reach o
the next letters are so again we're subdividing the probability space
first it's all the sentences that start with h
then in terms of the ones that start with h continue with and so forth
so let's see what happens if we estimate the probabilities from part of the corpus
juris balanced corpus a little better than the one i showed you before it's called
the brown corpus was collected in the nineteen seventies it from university back
we see the of fifty two thousand sentences about a million words in the brown
corpus from all kinds of different genres of text news text fiction narrative and so
for fifty two thousand sentences forty four hundred started with the letter h
so if you just take the naive estimate from data
we're going to say
the fraction of of the time when you think of those forty four seventy sentences
let's start with a three hundred ninety five continue with
of those that start with h show
five continue with are and so on
two address these estimates up you're probably pretty good because they are based on a
lot of data
this one down here
i do think it's really impossible in english that hrst is followed by another s
zero over three must be impossible right we've never seen before
there are three sentences that start with course in the brown corpus
but there are no sentences that start courses
OK so what are we going to do
look relates better
OK so
if we back
where every letter we can we ignore everything for the previous two letters
now these numbers start to go up
and we see that our probability is a little less than one of
so this is like trying to
for every letter conditioning on the two previous this is saying if the third of
all the sentences in the brown corpus and there are a hundred twenty six of
them were the three batteries or four letters as
in what fraction of those
about ten
is the
fifth letter you
OK is this quite right
not quite literally
it's bias for the start of the sensory which might be good right because that's
less by after or question was
does the sentence start with horses
so what
on the other hand these numbers are still a little bit like
so how does this is what i tried model two different
hundred twenty five thousand which is a pretty stable estimate right
for this particular advertiser i'm getting something like two five l five is pretty small
number so i'm going to give away maybe ten percent four five and ninety percent
two hundred or five thousand weighted average and you get that's the main idea
and it works because of the clustering
but it was because of cluster the advertisers so that they are kind of similar
to each other to these editors are cluster because they always tend to be done
the same keywords
so this clustering is really important if features randomly cluster didn't start doing this it's
going to be miserable
so the main idea is when you're bring the
the new borrowing strength
to estimate something i final resolution there should be correlation
among things from which borrowing information otherwise it's not going to work and it is
believed in general like if you look at advertiser graph right that i are organised
into campaigns and then there a bunch of campers belonging to give given advertiser so
that its correlation among adwords ads that of that belong to the same campaign and
there is correlation among campaigns that belong to the same advertising and that's the thing
that you need to exploit to come up with good estimates that fine resolution
recommender system have not used to
the hierarchical information so much they have been
doing more of the projection style algorithm will you take a user new project aiming
to a lower dimensional subspace taken out project them into a low dimensional subspace and
then you kind of believe the inner product of these two captures so that's a
different style of regularisation there's no one regularizing things in the whole industry and so
on but this is something which people have done in the home
founded to work
there were clustering the advertisers based on commonality
based on the common commonality of keywords so save two advertisers bid always tend to
be on the same keywords then they will be put into the same cluster so
they did that first using a bipartite matching algorithm
and then use the cluster to get
ctr estimates are very fine resolutions by borrowing strength from coarser resolution that that was
the main idea
it has been done in a court lasting also so this is yes so
this is one way of doing
regularisation so here actually the hierarchical clustering was
more database structure you derive the hierarchical clustering of advertisers using semantic information you did
not use any click information in deriving the clustered you just use the keyword information
to derive semantic clusters and then use that to regularize the estimated finer resolution in
some instances that will be some natural hierarchies given to you like you can add
nested within campaigns campaign the advertisers can also exploit that whether it is going to
work or not depends on the quality of the clustering that can be used and
that is in all the whole
thank you
yes so that
i believe is that there is there are some external factors are captured by this
clustering which will help you estimate the CTR of an ad by knowing the city
of related acts so that's the whole
in some cases the natural hierarchies work much better than they to induce hierarchy in
other cases they don't
maybe the date of this hierarchy were actually work better so
in one needs to try this approach is out and see which one works so
the other thing which we did was the kind of refining
the work that recalls an infinite has done the estimating
so we did the same thing but we kind of did it in a more
principled framework i think
so so what we had in our case was so we we were again solving
the content match problem
and every page was classified into a hierarchy and the ad was classified at the
same hierarchy and we use this natural hierarchy information to get estimates of CT at
find resolution by using data at coarse resolution so i won't go through again the
o thing
but let me show you
how we did that
OK so
so this was the main model itself
i is the i j is the
so we had some data for every page that there
and our goal is to estimate the CTR i j and so the main idea
here is
the CTR finer resolution is nested within a it is related to see during the
course of resolution
CD fine resolution is centered around the city at coarser resolution with some variation
so that's kind of like a state space model so you know if the victim
of this distribution is very small that means there is very high correlation with the
city out of the parent entity out of the show
the fact is very large that is a very good correlation
and the good thing was the
the appropriate which was estimated from the data itself so assume the city of the
child node is centered on the city the parent node with some distribution
and the weight of the distribution controls the amount of correlation that is there in
the data that's all estimated automatically from the data twenty miles
so the end of the day
at the end of the day this procedure also
gives you a weighted average
of CTR is an estimate but the weights are estimated automatically from the data you
don't have to cook up weights they don't have to say OK i think this
is point nine this is point one
all that is automatically through the through the amount of course you know that's good
then you don't have to worry about how much information that is in the hierarchy
in which there is no if there is no information
it will give very little weight to
apparently there is a lot of information including a lot of it parents
if that if you have enough data
had the desired level
then it will not want to anything at all from the so there is an
ad which have been shown ten thousand times on the given query it will not
required anything from the it will automatically do it for you you don't have to
tell it not to use data from the that is going to happen automatically belong
go to the parents and grandparents and there isn't enough data that particular solution
and the waiting which is done is decided based on the amount of correlations you
so that's the main idea of this model
so the idea the computation is very fast and you can use the multi resolution
kalman filter to do one pass algorithm so so it all works
things like
this is the spatial kalman filter is not
so in this paper we don't do them put here
so this is like
so again these results showing that the method works in this dataset so few
that's just fine satisfy one constraint at the time
OK so
so let's look at the constrained by i which is which is this linear subspace
if you just had one constraint to be one-dimensional problem because it just looking for
one parameter eta
that's much easier you know if it's just the one dimensional problem you can use
line search or something like that
so here's the algorithm
the initial value of p
it's going to be an iterative algorithm you start with the equal to your prior
and i keep adjusting
OK until you finally get to the i projection
here's what you do is very simple
you just take whatever you currently have
and i projected onto the next subspace
OK so you just get cycling through all the subspaces
you have to a constraint to have these key
you now have these case separate hyperplanes and you want to satisfy all of them
in other words you want to be the intersection of all those hyperplanes
but he was one project to that intersection
so what you do is you just project onto one of them the project onto
the next thing project on to the next and just keep cycling through these constraints
and somehow this should work to see why this
so let's look at these problems so
so for instance that say that two
that's just to subspaces
OK so then we want to get we want to get somewhere in the intersection
we want to get there
OK to the intersection point
we start with any o by
and now instead of projecting onto
the intersection of the two subspaces which would be out
we just project onto one of them
given as far away from the other
now we project onto the next
now we project onto the next one and so on
we keep going back and forth until we get intersection
so how complicated of these projection operations
well projected onto just one of these constraints is really easy
we just have to
projecting onto one constraint when we just had one constraint it means that we are
looking for an exponential family that just has one parameter
OK this just some data i
so we want to project the current distribution is obtained
and we want to project it so that it satisfies the i th constraint
so in other words the thing we're looking for something of this form weighta is
just one real numbers
so that's quite easy we just looking for something of this form that has the
right to expectations
we can just do a search for this
and so on
OK so we get a simple one dimensional problems
the question is why does this thing converge
and we you can see that is
well we have to do is to prove that they are actually making progress on
each iteration
and if you look at the iteration that sam the city
and the next one and you know what i'm doing some cycling between these constraints
right let's say the thing i'm currently doing
this projecting onto the i th constraint
projecting onto l survive
so i think the city
project onto the city plus one
and this is my ultimate goal start
i know based on lies on this thing because he starts satisfies all the constraints
for peacetime must lie on and survive
OK so now i'm claiming
that i've actually moved closer to the star
so just by the pythagorean theorem
that's the hypothenuse and this is one of the legs of the triangle
so in each step
even though you know so this seems to you know so see how this get
constraints and what think you know just projecting onto one constraint you might totally mess
yourself up with respect to the other constraints
but you don't have to worry
because of the way this pythagorean theorem works
you can be sure that even if you just one constraint at the time
you always moving closer to the
the final decision
this is an example of the kind of
sort of kind of arguments that come out information geometry
some almost let me sort of part
what some of the methods by projection with the one i told you about well
it's very nice method
i don't think it's the one that actually gets used
is the situation
because remember
within the same texture
standard deviation tends to be equal
so we have a situation like this
all the forces will be approximately equal
so therefore they will cancel out and so the same texture is eliminated from the
so that's that's where the real magic of this algorithm is
a second reason why we use standard deviation
and standard deviation peaks on boundaries
so if you just look at this
and all the areas between the different
textured regions
the standard deviation has paid
so one is that happen well
if you think about it
within a texture
the standard deviation are only has to encapsulate the intra class variation
of the texture
whenever the standard deviation
cross sister texted areas
it has to also include the inter class variation
so naturally adding into class variation to this will increase the standard deviation and there
are exceptions to this of course
in general standard deviation does take between on boundaries with textures me
and sorry if we can design an algorithm
but can detect when standard deviation peaks
then we can have the boundary detectors
so that is what we do in the next step
so our best here this is what the gradient transform of the image looks like
in this image that hugh represents the orientation of the gradient you'll probably notice something
very interesting to read it
just like for a moment if you have a one-dimensional functions
in the peak
take will have a positive gradient on one side
and will have a negative gradient on the other
so that's basically exactly what's happening here
one gradient pointing towards
that way and the other great pointing in the opposite direction
so we have this pattern where the standard deviation peaks
the gradient
and so what we need is we need to detect this pattern
to be able to detect boundaries
how we do that
well OK that's the standard deviation image if you want to say that so we
don't stick very
so first of all
you can probably imagine the best way to figure out to
victors of pointing towards each other is to use the dot product
so we use the dot product
the question is what do we product
the way we to draw here we
if we want to find
how how strong is the ridge at this point
then we will compare
points at particular offsets
from that point of interest so will to find the response here
take the dot product of this and this
so naturally these the opposite saying will get a strong response here
so we repeat this
at different orientations
so that there would be the horizontal orientation and then we take the maximum
so if i just summarize we do this with
four orientations there are forty five ninety and one hundred thirty five degrees
and then we take the strongest response from all of the offices
and the result of this is the ridge transform
so this is what it looks like we have an image here
and this is the ridge transform
you'll notice all the text and cross has not appeared
and the boundary detection and so that's what we want we want to ignore texture
so that's quite good
but there's one thing we can do to improve this
that's what it was about
so what if we take the ridge transform
and we subtract the gradient from which was to
we can get a nice
final result trying to being there
and so why does this work
actually why do we do this for a start
in the previous step we are only compared to points at the time so we
only take a very small sample
and so are often well
miss locate the boundaries
so this is basically cleans it up and it does it very fast and so
it works because a peak must have a negative gradient on one side and a
positive gradient on the other
so always basically work are very fast learning algorithm
so that is our final final result looks like that
so our results one
i have objectively missions were about two main
conclusions for you
the first one is
this algorithm found is able to execute at forty three point two nine frames per
and so this is orders of magnitude faster than most non real-time texture boundary detectors
which take ten seconds per image so it's about five hundred times faster so it's
a lot more useful for real-time
if you're willing to accept the trade-off in quality
it can run at up to three hundred twenty five frames per second
and this supports our claim but this is a real time algorithm
so also are i've tested this algorithm on the berkeley segmentation benchmark so that is
a publicly available system which objectively ranks the world's best boundary detectors
and so on this
objective benchmark our algorithm scores zero points x two
and the important point about that is that fits the current state of the art
which is the second moment matrix which gets zero point five seven
so this supports our claim that the algorithm is a texture boundary detector
so we do have an algorithm which can
suppress the texture variations and it can do all in real time
so in conclusion
so that players
for aristotle
the realities were reversed
much like modern scientists here that
the primary reality was not conceptual was here
and so
in order to understand the nature of reality
like a scientist played those very warm start here
there's no felt was very important intention around study to try to learn from
from there
to build knowledge reality you can
see here
this debate about
was expressed
what fails
school of athens this is not a great reproduction very fuzzy but i i can
conclusions here by gestures when so
the page has
different intellectuals centuries
anachronistic because
the people depicted in the painting did not
live is contemporary
right whales big point here which is the
that is what tools through the ages scholars
o in t
o great debt
two figures
in the middle
the school that which are later played
and here they are
here is a plate of the old man teacher
and his student aristotle in
point and here is their gestures were played
is pointing upward
this is the last children
the forms of those during
and aristotle has is paul
extending to the ground in a few ports of particulars
the world of materials
here only by their gestures to indicate a
really to produce the knowledge different ways of
coming to understand
the nature of knowledge
school that's
there's got
so there are different views about the nature ultimately
and the
the question of what is reality what is ontology and how to get there
in two
more than a thousand years
until through the the middle ages
until the time of the enlightenment philosophers
i began to
really take on this question again with
renewed bigger
two groups of lost first disagreed
about how knowledge is
initially acquired and
those are called the called
the in the rationals
the in appearances argue that knowledge begins with experience
you'll find this argument
pretty stable are which is it goes like this
the way we learn about our world is through our senses
our eyes
our years
our sense of touch
in fact
the first one never be
except the second make sense to
in sort of intuitively
classical theory
and so that was that was one view
the rationalists
i believe that that's not the way
that we acquire information they
say what we learn it usually begins not to information key passes but through are
the reason why
so what was twenty
we don't need to see that in the world we we
no that is our minds etc it's it's rational built
from inside
empiricist and rationalist are associated with your
primarily with the british isles with
england and scotland and the rationalists
can't to the most famous names associated with
those are
locke hume berkeley
in the british isles
and descartes in
the on the continent
the basic answer here
is used seventy which one is right
you would say
the correct answer would be that
both points of view had inadequacy to neither side won the debate for example on
the rational side
it very quickly became evident particularly later on
when hugh
and or
CQ politics
they would say
that it's not enough simply to
perceive something with our senses if you want to make sense of any
we can't have an idea of of what it is before
if i say
i'm pushes object in my hand is moving object making it possible to
how do we know that
human so the only way that i could understand causation because i previously
an idea of causation market where the idea of causation comes not from the senses
began to hear that information gained only senses was not
by itself
now on the
on the
on the russian side the art
how had interesting
and he thought
there's nothing i can trust about information gain from my sins
i would be i i d be completely to see
about so
he said
five to be a good philosopher i've got down everything
i don't believe anymore
and that approach it is called radical that we sweep away all of our preconceptions
we start from a very young as far as i know no one has ever
tried to set
but it's pretty pretty crazy stuff
but the car
tried to build up work
and you may have heard this phrase
cogito ergo soon
i can be certain one
can one thing which is what
i think therefore
i must exist
you can have a finger
we define the right hand side of our of our in terms
right so but that's the same as to say
that either point one four point two or point three and so on are less
than x
right the the minimum must be less than x then either the points can be
less than x and that's the same thing
so now we can apply basic logic put two negations in front of this
not not doesn't change anything here we pull in one of the negations
and have to flip this from or to and
and this expression we can now quite easily evaluate it's the probability of the negative
of negated statement so we do one minus
so now we only have to deal with this we know that these were IID
drawn samples so we can pull out the product because the probability of these i
have sampled the product and now we have another negation here one minus and what
remains is the probability for a single data point of being less than six
and we recognise here the probability of something being less than x
it is again a cumulative distribution function but this time just of our data distribution
it is clear this farm or
any trouble
too fast to slow or
OK so now the next thing we need to evaluate is this thing here
will we see that in the interwar from theta to theta plus one
this distribution function simply be given by x minus the
that's quite
what's this
this is true suspect so
if our density
is given by this
can you
then our distribution function is given by
well this is the time and this is
theta plus one
right and this is nothing but what i wrote down their x minus the in
this in this particular in triple
so that's easy we've come to the point where we can actually
calculate this thing
and then we have we just plug in this
this was the previous equation we derive for the distribution function for the estimator we
plug in this value x minus the to
and now in order to evaluate the probability that the true as the true parameter
is in the inter vol
we just need to evaluate this thing here
at the points the theta plus
epsilon and theta
now if you if a value of this thing at x equals the to find
the this thing vanishes so i can forget about this term and this is the
only interesting remaining term
and here i just pluck plug this into the equation so it's only this term
that remains i plug in four x theta plus of cylons
the theta goes and this is all that remains the probability
the true
parameter is in the travel of is given by one minus
one minus epsilon to the power of n
and you see this quantity involves only one aspect of the sample because we haven't
seen the sample yet we can't do more it's just the number of points in
the sample this involves
and this is the quantity that we would like to be ninety five percent so
this this one minus delta where delta with only five percent
here i'm flattered that for you so you can now also for epsilon
as a function of the number of samples and of delta
and that gives one minus delta to the power of one over and
and here's the plot of this quantity that we just focus on on one line
which so you know this is the confidence plot to this is the length of
the confidence interval so we have this fixed point which is the minimum of the
data and the question is how far do we have to go to the right
in order for this interpret to include the true parameter and quite plausibly it
the more
confidence you require into your statement
the the bigger you have to make your confidence interval if you want one hundred
percent confidence of the speak then you have to take your confidence interval to be
after equals one
and you also see the more points you have
the the smaller your confidence interval becomes this for n equals five and you could
stand good for and so forth
so that's the kind of statement that frequentist can make for giving a confidence interval
and it can be very useful statement indeed actually this is not so much like
PAC learning theory which make similar statements but wouldn't assume that the density comes from
this particular family work but would wouldn't make any assumptions about the distribution
here's what bayesian what do not
so one
another example the space of
so if you think it was like maybe it was
let me see you
i mean that's true you otherwise you may end up with an implicit equation that
would have to solve it this is just it's just the fact that this can
be calculated analytically otherwise
that have to solve some fixed point equation or something like that
how does the bayesian go about it i would like to emphasise the bayesian is
predict something like a binary contact matrix OK so i think of this training each
position here corresponds to a particular column and also role
and what the binary contact matrix with actually
tell us is whether two amino acids are within a certain radius of each other
after the folding process of the protein right so that it would capture some of
the three d structure of the protein and
i'm not an an expert in computational biology but from what i know is if
if one could accurately predict the binary contact matrix that would actually take take as
a very long way and actually making a prediction of protein structure right so it's
interesting to think about how can machine learning methods be used to start from let's
say the primary sequence and then start to predict actually this contact matrix writing clearly
binary entries in this country metrics will not be independent right that will be there
there will be very strong dependencies between these things right because there is only a
small number of contact matrices for instance they really make sense
because you know not everything can be in contact with everything else at the same
OK so these are the types of problems that
i would like to present the solution to here in the generic sense i'm not
going to solve all these problems
you know a serious
application but i want to show you how with a few ideas for machine learning
you can actually have a nice tool kit of things that that you can that
you can then use for many of these things that
so other any questions before wasn't much
content motivation but
they give you a sense of
of problems OK so the first thing i'd like to do then is to talk
about multiclass classification OK because that's a natural way to get started towards more complicated
things right because
on one hand right if you
if you think about like predicting large label sequences and things like that right you
can think of at least in the naive way as
as a problem over a very large output space of different you know just a
very large number of possible outputs right namely all possible label sequences let's say of
certain length now you can think of that is just being you know a gigantic
multiclass problems so obviously you need some more ideas to
transforming back into some something tractable in something that can be learned but so it's
good to start with
with multi class and introduce appearing OK so
so let's see
what we can do on the output side if we have a case where we
have k classes so basically present of one particular approach here of setting this up
as a problem that then you can solve by a variant of the perceptron algorithm
or a support vector machine there are a number of different formulations just use one
here because i'm not primarily interested in the modern clusters of aspect but it's only
two as motivation to to go beyond OK
so here's the
the general setting and also for notation values later so i assume there is an
input space x usually that can be
as a subspace of r you know a certain set of subset of our art
our to the deal it's a finite dimensional representation or it can be something more
complicated and we have an output space y and in this office space really consists
of k labels where this number k is just the number of classes of categories
that we have and the simple the model that we can look at if we
look at linear classifiers is to take
the binary case and generalized in the way that we actually get no of weight
vector for each of the classes so that the particular class y
i associate a weight vector of the same dimension as our inputs with that specific
class and then i can define a discriminant function that assigns a score of two
in particular
input that can plug in here and the particular class this function is indexed by
the class label y it by just you know the inner product between the weight
vector and some representation that might choose from my
so this is just the generalisation of of binary classification where binary classification usually you
wouldn't even have to
weight vectors but rather you will look at the sign of this right and make
a decision based on that
so for convenience i will also think of that function as a function of two
arguments x and y components and you know how would be then predict a target
class y star
well we were just define white star for given x to be the argmax over
all possible
class of all possible output of the function f of x come y and if
we just plug it in it just means we we just get that right so
we just pick the score
sorry the class which gets the highest score
and the score is defined by weight vector that we have associated with this class
right so is relatively simple if we look at this geometrically what we do is
we partition
the input space
with hyperplanes and if we look at the the boundary between two classes right we
can ask ourselves well
ignoring all the other classes for a minute right when be favourite class y class
y prime well we would do this
this inner product between w y
with whatever input representation we have exceeds the same inner product with the different weight
vector namely the wonderful life crime and we can just subtract this bring it to
the left side use the linearity inner product and that's what we get namely that
we should look at the difference of the weight vector
right and check the sign basically the inner product that and that's one is positive
and we favor y
if the assigns negative we favor by prime minister zero it's basically the boundary between
the two
OK now the region
that is the region where we label inputs by a particular label y
right we'll just be the intersection
regime of things that there although not it idiosyncratic if actually really want arrogate collective
intelligence if I type in the name of the hotel wrote a camera or anything
a consulting firm you know person and I wanna know whether and how I can
aggravate the ratings see based on is the person doing the red invalidated not was
source was clearly differ from how many were there and so on there's initial standard
way of doing that right now and finally announced that you know how companies people
find my side real trouble if they find your search for Google that I guess
our own plans everything into your mouth ran Braman there's something fishy about this because
Google without love grew on a bus where firms work there but but it's really
a hegemony
based on flight pattern matching as we're find things nowhere and if you want if
we can think of the most fundamental thing expanded welcome needed to change the damage
to the Web is to to give an alternative to build most of also called
the funny things by long strings of words is just 1 way to find things
and the reason is waste it's got a lock in their destiny and is a
destructive technology to overcome a lot and lock actually limits they literally don't actually display
slide all the pages in every site despite the Mets there's a real or cream
skimming that happens only a tiny fraction the website available to us to search and
the rules of the game are very adversarial aunt and not very far like a
constant were August's perhaps so that holds the whole paradigms Conakry here just now it's
now time for us to do something
so finally I wanted to acknowledge act because I don't know what I'm talking about
from sniper research these days but did notice a couple of highlights its authority happening
in this area supporting collected not systems only knowledge that and when we only QAI
wanna make sure we give people who some more or some more points
and I disclose couple with a sort of your brain drugs kind of picture so
this this was that this is this is a course I got this opens and
area collected intelligence insights color I start on this is a picture what tagging is
to me now it's like graffiti character on its it's farmland and to look at
you should sometimes but Nassos Jackson Pollock and give up old after a while I
found but this is all I think it should look like pair of engineer is
really cool graphic neural 3rd them by collaborative taggers said the word comes from people
who would spray paint the walls that's what that's what traditional think can when they
work together they make you a lot so I hope we can pilaff experiments on
behalf of of them the Bankstown for release you they talk we have microphones in
we about 10 minutes for questions so those would like to to make the peace
and please do speak microphone because we're being and state cellulite that places the it
to be taped as well said that there is to ask that
yes it is passed Idaho August
With Disney of so so don't be I did here you had talked about the
movie pocket 1 of those workshops and you talk about on the phone little knots
and my full of political pledges would be that by ABB like conditions that of
you that you and you can tell the more about that these these shared right
next to me the best was once a my ontology what was happening but basically
had to work with even with workers structured data we floor sources say I think
there's all structure that when I was a step right August far down like going
to the formalisms on dimension and tried accident licenses claiming is possible and even there
in the realm of mathematics and engineering mathematics but it did but not primitives that
had to be explained in human terms like it turns out that we were not
the fundamental choice of Masson length and so on being from primitive dimensions is a
treaty is not science it's a choice by convention so all these things um all
ontologies eventually becomes unstructured some point the definitions and so if we think with if
some fundamentally it's that is the case that way then we should we can look
at that continuing banned all the way back to the other side of the the
structure of the weapon is based on ontology of Lincoln Kennedy radiological right the neural
that is of fundamental thing it says basically things evidently and you know if you
have two strings that had the same euro that it is the same thing and
so on his of all smaller there and all the other stuff in between is
levels of formality so it was the desert passes the big the biggest point I
think that's what they stand for me is that I realized that he like in
all analysis designed built and so on that have lots of options blogs and text
and video lost and they're just just attaching themselves to structure there's always structure but
but ended machines only reason about the structure part but dollars not course think you
can get all out that all unstructured pieces out is that there's no point that's
what need is that in Vietnam matches
Mr. so that my from the site real travel is this sort of fits a
pattern that we see a lot of places where there's a side were authors provide
content the into stored and other people to that I'm interested in on Monday as
a user and want to offer my content I wanted store by some of agency
or agencies browser will by some other large that interfaces so my data that is
not owned by rail travel I don't wanna give my days of travel do you
see a future for that reason there's economic problems with and some technological problems and
redressing technological problems the social and financial issues are what I'm interested in a surrogate
point is not the only reason that things are stored on real by the weather
right so
so we should really think of you know we have a large number of constraints
and the question is on a small number of those be active right whether or
not every index i kinda shows up with one or more constraints is really secondary
to illustrate because if i have constraints for data point one
and zero point o point two or with fifty fifty in the end
is not that important right maybe
if you have to store all these things maybe you can save a little bit
rate if you get passes over i but i'm not so much concerned about this
but i'm concerned about the sparseness of the overall solution just in terms of number
of constraints right but you can see already in this expansion right if this expansion
is sparse then
you know there are two ways of accomplishing this idea just having a certain number
of lives being active here or
a certain number of of wise but but we really talking about is a combination
of both
so this is the type of person to get so so in an ideal if
things would go well right what we would find this that hey if we solve
this right actually most of the of wise will be zero which corresponds to
right by the conductor conditions we know that basically that corresponds to inactive constraints right
or the other way round if we have an inductive constraint is guaranteed that the
variable here will
the zero at the optimum but the problem is you know all those kind of
intuitively we might feel that
could be the case it's not clear that actually is and so one of the
analysis that would show is what we can actually say about the sparseness of canada
bit more complicated
but but this general form if you do some pattern matching with what you know
what kind machines
right i mean
you you're happy with
with what you see
let's just move on to have this slide here which for some reason
as funny transparency effect but
i hope you can still see it OK so here's here's the algorithm k and
i would i would argue that it's very and do this again and again that
it's very simple
very appealing algorithm that really decomposes the overall problem nicely into subproblems that can be
tackled in various ways so what people do is the following we will work with
relaxations of the original quadratic program and we start with taking no constraints into account
and talking about the margin constraint OK the constraint on the size that's fine so
none of the margin margin constraints we initially take into account and all the idea
will be that we pick one more constraints iteratively can we build up so-called working
set of constraints every time we pick up the constraint we get stronger relaxation of
the problem right so there is the total number of constraints you know we only
have a subset of constraints to relaxation right and if we find the solution it
will be
better in terms of the of the function the the value of the objective function
right but it would potentially violate some constraints and as we add more constraint the
relaxation will become you know tighter and tighter will become better and better and of
course the objective function value will typically go i can stay the same if we
had something that has no effect on the solution but typically it was right
and the hope is that somehow we only need to add a few constraints can
the main result will be
the figure out by considering that says yes you know we only need to add
that many constraints and that's what we see later but first talking about the algorithm
so there's basically this working set is initialized to zero the weight vector zero
slack variables zero
now i cycle through all training examples x i y i i compute the best
possibly the best output
which is unequal to why i'm OK so this can be the best or the
second best so usually
you know this i think of as a black box here that is application dependent
dependent on what phi is and what it encodes
you know who knows how i'm going to get it but i think of it
more in software engineering terms
OK you pluck this in as a black box the black box device right something
that gives you the next constraint mainly for this particular x y
i should consider know this
why had
and what i do know is i check whether i meet the margin
the margin minus the current value of ci i i have already lowered my modern
this delta here is just a shortcut so i considered it
of the difference between
the compatibility of the feature functions between the correct output and the output that we're
kind of proving here and we also have a parameter alpha epsilon i didn't specify
that so that is the design parameter i'll talk about more
on the next slides OK so just think about is being some small tolerance
value of that we say we don't care if i have constraints are violated by
this than epsilon saying here is
you know for given training point find
the most
you know the y had that has the largest value of the compatibility functions different
from while i check whether that
constraint that corresponds to that is violated and the weather is violated by more than
epsilon k and if that's the case then we saying well that's that right because
now we have an example like we have for the
example x i y we have found the y had that really
you know it's the margin more than it should be
so now what we do is we had this to all working set
and we can also keep it basically working set for each training example separately all
we can do one global
OK and then once we've done that we optimize all quadratic programs
w signer with respect to all parameters either over the whole set if we do
and unless we do not region
so you see
one of them claiming here that the brain doesn't realize
is being run
in the larger debate
there's only one thing
that i have
eleven to match
some of you might realise
but you see the update is the same
you have to do the same because the argument is only caring about the first
component of the factors that led to the either the margin is the same
because of this trick here
and city with
so there is only one point in this construction where the transformation of the stream
affects the way the ongoing work
i didn't see the first
yeah exactly exactly so i changed the wine
i DX
and changing the x
so if you remember
so i divided here by the number
but if i'm adding one non-zero component which is not going to change
and because if if i want my professional growth rules
i have to
change the nonzero here elements
so this is so the i don't know that is being run on and on
and on and on and on
modified stream because it's not using his up there is using these up
plus the extra component that had at the movie
x will become prime
what is the contribution of these extra component
so it
one of our group of squared
so now
i think if the prime
it is
exactly the same i had before
number of and
this guy here square which is the next thing i added
so in other words
if i were and i really like these
i'm running the algorithm on a dependable
i understand that that i mean analysis
that they had hold only for separable streams
but if i think they were sees any constant because the wrong
then my
will hold also for nonseparable stream
we the same exactly the same but
with exactly the same bound them
not exactly the same bound because
i know that you know where it is that because in the about the also
the normal vector p
also the probability for
so now let's look at
but the nice thing about it is that i mean i don't have to know
anything about
the other thing the boys choosing this concept
and then the always will as the
now this will go through
so let's recap now
if you come to that in a minute that was of course i mean
i want to try all the fact that the
OK so
what about bounds bound
in nonseparable case
so what we had
so we think that is that is it is
and then
the bound that would be like this
so we found that
the requires investment that tends to actually
increase the deviations from time to time
in addition to that and next thing actually the behaviour make it is dominating in
case of war
you have basically the so one item which is imitation imitation hurt
herding imitation is something that
the an really nice when you think of you in the stomach
economic model of homo economicus
a rational person so trying to optimize
having or information an infinite computational abilities
it turns out that imitation
is very irrational when you take the concept of herbert simon of bounded rationality we
know that we are bound we are not irrational in the
simple minded sense of journalists we
those job when we want to invest our money we look things we i think
but we know that we are not full information
so indeed if i don't have full information on
different types of industry makes sense that i call the friends were looking more carefully
this industry of it is makes and that i should see what are the different
positions of the
network of connections interacting with
and the consequent there was being this so early
and a mediation process hurting process like that can feed on itself and give rise
to these extreme is see that these not showing again this curve
the super exponential growth that you see that many different time-scale you can see it
even the largest timescale log linear are straight line exponential growth of of things that
is overall exponential this is a very nice data base made by
some of the top american financial economists showing again log linear
the cities of all acceleration i want to stress that because we are in the
transdisciplinary set up you try to develop these interaction
that this concept of positive leading to
these catastrophes in finite is great
singularity find time can be found in many different systems that some some not something
that we tend to appreciate enough because we are interested in stationary solution something that
exists for a long time actually
from the theory of information solar system
the equation of turbulence in some limits general relativity
for the formation of black holes in finite time
two blondes in in plasma eruption failure certainly
earthquake dynamics
some models of mike and experimental situations involving biology some chemical processes even though
trivial example when you let coin
four on the
you know that actually the number of collisions of the car
is infinite
before we settled in finite time
there are a dish so this is called united scheme has been recently she was
in nature paper and stock market crashed my position
one reason that was one idea why it's so difficult to identify them due to
the need of developing broad picture emphasizing i think is positive feedback which is not
something so much use
and some of the kind i mean i stomach and eventually come in some fashion
economics we much more
trying to think of what is called mean reversion
we tend to think that these are fundamental value
and that the market forces due to some arbitrage we tend to actually bring back
the price back to find the right stressing the opposite and stressing that there are
well actually the opposite forces
that's so that requires
a different way of thinking the problem i want to briefly mentioned
the reason for that we be with my students which also
maybe help understand and why so difficult to do
crashes which is the fact that when you develop models
in which
that are common knowledge
comm between is ijaws and critic information that the any given trader can develop
which also compete with
so the mediation process
which are rational they basis when the street type of information compete in the decision
making of it agent and the agent's try in the bayesian way to learn from
their past mistakes to improve the ability of importance of the three types of information
they somehow over interpret
the random news that come in
and this gives rise actually to global herding by this misinterpretation of the news
and this amplification news which are more-or-less random of course make it very difficult for
the prediction
so we have i don't have time to go into specifics
but this kind of model can be agent based model can be
put in
produced by the science facts and here you see
a string of random so we put in the model you know