at all you know
well that's one
o flat
and what is
o thing point
and then
matter of fact
he was
is a
that would have stopped work
in fact
it's all
or they black sea
and i recall this is the
there a very comprehensive
all right
far from it with
you make
the main
are man
and that would be
then the average
from next and and more
are going to when not
so there is no
trying to measure
how one
i think are very revealing for
because the
on the main point is that only he would on to which out fans
i learned a lot
so what you are not always develop
which is kind of
they are
thing that i want to more
there were about one
is this a for
the visual and
so there's a lot more
it is
this rule
that have been known for all role
course there
so there
right now the economy
it was the
if you
one two
do this as long as we
and on the
a pretty well known
it was a
will show
in this
but the problem is that the
so i
what the
we didn't worry just go
of work
so anyway role
nine years
he is
according to the results roles
you know
that would be validated according to
big rule should
he was
not to be
if you don't
we need to realize
that means
there is a
the good the bad
is going to be like
one day
we want
bound we want
delta x
less than some
of stealth
lessons that will sort tell us how hard the problem is to solve
right now a couple of points to make
you could say
where are we might also not know a very well
somebody's made that comment after an earlier lecture
we might
there are we ought maybe taking into account delta and the answer is true so
it so i could do what i'm doing now
allowing delta a that's absolutely belongs there is when we do these elimination steps where
we're making little mistakes in
and on the right-hand side are making mistakes in b
let me
make my life easier to think about the right hand side but left behind
that's one point
the second point is
really relative error is
the right thing
if i'm just estimate is really what i would like to know
the size of delta x compared to the size of x
i could change if i just wanted all text to be small or large i
could multiply by zillions
would multiply expires and then it would
nonsense out of my errors
but if i
look at the relative error
on line b by millions will change the relative
so i would like this to be less than so
and again on the right hand side so so this is less than some some
multiple and that's the question of the error in
the relative error in b
is that i'm sorry that that's written solo down because that's the that's the question
what's the constant how large could the relative error in x b if i know
something about the relative error in the cases like what i controlled by
by keeping more digits
and this is
what comes out
no we can if we made errors in the process of solving it we can
say OK that's that's part of the b
so so we're assuming that we solve this guy exact
but it was the wrong problem
so i want to know
if i solve the wrong problem
how different is that relatively speaking from solving the right problem
and you see that
somehow our little bit the business of norms or help
because what do we know about
norm here and
so on let's see if we can get some
you see that this is this tells me how hard the problem is to solve
that's the size of that that so that's going to be the condition number
and i want to know
what is it
a typical problem and actually matlab will
estimated if you if you given that the linear system given that given this problem
it will estimate the condition number will give you a signal the this and if
it's a wildly i condition number
mallet will tell you
OK so now
let's just get figure out what that c should be
OK so what can we say
so the true solution as a sequel
inverse peak
that's the true solution so their souls
the norm of x
is less than one
the norm of a inverse
times the normal b
so we're using norms here for
a inverse
that's that's OK that's the definition of the norm somehow
what will i mean when the norm of a and version b
the inverse is the big matrix that sort of is telling us what
it's telling us that the matrix is nearly singular it's inverses giant
i want to do things relatively
because so if i have multiplied by a million are divided by a million i
can make the inverse million bigger million smaller without changing reality here
so it's
so it's relative that's reality OK now i got this equation how can i can
well of
in press
this right
and it
and that very
at the time he
used to be
you're wrong
that's it
it means that
get gold
so not
you know all
these are
that is
and long
this year
and i
the area
it might be
you know
one of the
these are the
he's your brain
xe for so we have n times the times k
as the size of the data structure the question is does that actually show up
in the bound as well
i don't know
we've had a wicket remind me out of follow and that's actually that's that's very
cool idea
and in particular a lot of a lot of problems actually had that structure certainly
the gridworld that the important people get fixated on have local conductivity right so given
state can only reach a small number of neighbours not the full state space
so i will i i'll just so that's a good question i don't know
what you
i don't know how i feel about that but i like the question
but i ask it again when i get to the part where i say oh
and this is going to show that you're not actually optimal after any given
when i get others context that set up shortly that make it easier to i
know but i'm going to get it will be easier for me to explain later
so it is it seems silly to repeat now anyway
not itself
OK so the question was
i've been shamed into it so the question was
the mist mistake bound and which the PAC MDP framework for sets
it's basically one says the total number of mistakes in an infinite run is bounded
by certain numbers
but what doesn't say is that
after this amount of learning from here on forward your optimal
OK so those are two kinds of things that you might think about learning rate
one says that you're going to do all your training and learning in some fixed
period and then from then on you've got it and the other one says you
can make a mistake could happen today could happen next week but each time you
make a mistake getting closer and closer to perfection
now if you look at any fixed block of time
if it's a big enough block the fraction of mistakes that you make block has
to be going to zero right but the fact that matter is in the bounds
of talking about there is no last moment which you can make a mistake and
part of the reason for this sort of inevitable in the for MDP cases because
imagine if there's a transition that really really low probability so most of your life
you kind of live which at home which started watching the movie the matrix which
i assume most people see my kids and being the minds are being banned but
let's say you live your life you live life and then when they discovered that's
not reality there's this other reality over here suddenly you can not getting near optimal
reward anymore even though you were in the old space and so
the moment which that transition happens you can't put it down on is so low
probability event can happen anytime in the future so it's really it's really i think
it's impossible to get the kind of and you're hoping for
but i have come to grips with this one i think it's OK alright so
what i'd like to do is to draw
to to
kind of extend this idea
so we can talk about continuous basis we can talk about space we have more
structure we can talk about
lots of things like that by i
expanding this idea
after focusing on the following problem model learning is a supervised learning problem
given examples of the form state action and inputs state action in your post output
next or probability of next
it's not specific this idea is not specific to table lookup like this building a
big literal explicit graph
what we'd like to do is expand these kinds of efficient learning results
the generalizing the notion of the transition function to be just some function approximator something
that maps states and actions to next to
but the problem is that the existing first to kind of standard machine learning theory
doesn't give us quite the right guarantees for us to build the reinforcement learning to
the amount of ice so this is sort of
the context i thought i'd be able to use a moment ago
so so here's the deal so we talked a little bit about paxo in in
the supervised setting
park is set up like this input to drawn for some fixed distribution we get
to observe labels for the first set of them say m of them
and then future inputs are drawn from the distribution o so once we've done that
of functions that take values in some bounded range
then with probability rapidly approaches one
uniformly over the class we have expectations close to sample averages where
closes in terms of these rademacher
rademacher averages
so not not to be considered fused with the risk of of fire escape right
this is the rademacher averages about that class
these are real valued functions
so now we're going to consider
the class
class of functions
that the federal losses right as oregon
convex loss OK these functions map from the domain x cross y
right so we'll call function g so that evaluated ex-wives file flight times f of
OK and this is the guy that we want to have
you know his expectation
uniformly close to sample average right so the
by risk this this expectation malindi the fire
right and this is the sample average then uniformly close over
over some some costs
g the class g is the
class of gx where it comes from some complex the classification
OK so
for this class we we we can worry about
the rademacher averages
right of these of these viruses
OK so it turns out there are some easy
two let's evaluate the
these rademacher averages
so i go through
a few of those
so i have twenty minutes
so the first one is
is is true just to remind you the rademacher averages
but it's the
it's the supremum over a class of
this inner product between random
plus minus one vector and the values of f evaluated at
in data points x one to xn so in place in our case of functions
are defined not just an expert on on these x on x because one right
so we have x i y appears without considering you know we will be replacing
if there by
five y times ethics
brain but
OK so the
the from the definition of rademacher averages we're doing our optimisation over this class obviously
if we do the optimisation over smaller set we
we were get bigger value so so for some subset the rademacher averages and bigger
six percent
we took
actually this is OK so if we if we include class and all negations of
functions in class
taking the convex hull of that
doesn't change the rademacher averages at all
right and that's because we're taking a supremum over this class
OK of
something it's already linear criterion in f
OK so you take the convex hull is the extreme points there are always going
to achieve that that linear
the achieve the optimality criterion
OK so we don't change anything by by introducing the but by including all convex
combinations of these functions
if we multiply functions by constant
then we multiplying the rademacher averages by by constant
OK since we're maximizing which we take the absolute value of the constant
so you know this is this is also straightforward from the definition
this one is the only one that's not
immediate from the definition and and you know there's an element
but not so short argument
so this this is called the telegraph
contraction inequality that
that if you have a lipschitz function you compose your functions with a lipschitz function
right then
the rademacher averages and no bigger than the lipschitz constant times these functions right so
so i think if you think about it if we have an upper bound on
to the element
one of the hash function is going to give us is going to give us
no particular slot
there's one might go up here
i have another one here and there
we get to distribute the elements for over the
over the
so what's the
and that's going to occur
as we do this
so far i have been a little bit lucky
what's the problem potentially going to be
one two
things are in s
more specifically
assigned to the same values a big ideas and he gets mapped to the same
what somebody else has already been mapped
when this happens we call that a collision
so we're trying to make these things down
into a small set
what we could get unlucky and our mapping
particularly if we map enough these guys
not going to fit
so my record
being inserted
and already
occupied slot
the collision occurred
it looks like this method
but now there's there's a pretty simple thing we can do
what should we do when
two things matter since like
one represents the whole set
you can use any data
tree like
ash cash what you do is use hashing scheme
can actually just kick it out
you don't care about representing a set precisely
but in a hash table you
programming you often want to make sure that the values you've never exactly
evaluation sets you can tell whether something belongs to the set
what's a good strategy
he created a list
for each slot
just put all the elements that hash to the same slot into the list
and that's called resolving
by chain
the idea
o records
in the same slot
for example
imagine this is my
and this for example is slot right
have several things
they are
sort of you are you
several things that may have been inserted
into this
table of the elements of s
and what of this was just
link them together
so no point here
this is the satellite data
they are all linked together in slot right
then the hash function
applied to forty nine
got be the hash function
is equal the hash function of fifty two
which equals one
ratings because they're pretty much arbitrary
so we to used to point five
o point seven and zero so it's not clear what how to map a single
numeric scale
so what is here is just a
the in every output based on the greatest humans provide into one of the three
groups so for example if all four rate this sentence when it comes to this
if all surfaces ungrammatical sentences systems here if three of two thousand seven hundred ninety
five and two thousand seven
well was just one missing
can also consider it comes into this
this is also the idea of the average
for every sentence order have well exactly
four generations and this the judgement we assign to the
what has just one mistake or
and she
so what you notice right away the baseline will only every sentence
the climate so compared to the other two
configurations see that the number
changes the of two-thirds of all the sentences produced by
complex integration system two thirds were immigrants
and that's
what is the sum to one
which i just
you solutions someone
doesn't work well if you do this
if you wanted to
so she is the dimension d with less than one percent but you can use
this one
that's a
he five and they were fifty by these words
well i mean it's
so it's not just so you can imagine that every changes close
if you get a full would some try to think of these tend to the
lines so that
the final qualities about the average length of the impressionists of the members of the
sentence and the cost
it was twenty to thirty five finished and compression are generated at the average length
of eight ten or twelve
so the spanish so i will talk much stable so he can
notice right away a simple enough and
the more the better more medical center but again you should take this number separated
from the second iteration
works so have a cluster twenty sentences so that means that they
well i was for example but this was somewhere between ten and fifteen
so just
the difference between one last chance to ten articles
which means that i get just ten sentences if i have a question forty five
minutes that have passed
four different
so you must what i did was give me give me forty five percent and
now i'm talking about it
the average length is computed for each feature
those clusters
those are now being it's
yes i suppose i haven't but a necessary one
the reason for that is that the system is designed to work out any syntactic
in most systems that exist today
that information so here one of the main ones so also
it's not only cards to some practical because it's not good enough to
is it practical results the
from the original site was
interesting to show that although so most people almost surely all systems use syntactic trees
here we show that actually you can do about that so that
this means and then in this case it would be interesting to compare this system
chooses that information on the other hand we also need to go to camp in
number system which is much more information
with the system which is very simple like this
he all but it's what i so there are two sets on one hand you
want to show you some that you can go and use it on the other
hand there
so what he she was also
this very traditional to make use it to show it's not
all this is we need to see that sometimes
so i is an open and p
part of speech tagging
it's available in general many languages
it's this this was just this method is very very very straightforward if you see
so this what you see here seem to these is the same as saying is
for this which was just this is very
but this OK go
is is to
OK so here's right so just all conveys so
i split just the sentences into words right face it to
you want to see the answer is no
all right so now let's return back to simple mixture models we now have a
goal which is to be small selection problems and then discuss a solution to the
mixture model how do you pick a problem for mixture models and see where it
breaks down we try to understand it
OK so the chinese restaurant process so forget what kinds so far and now focus
on probability theory
that's the process which customers arrive restaurant roundtables
and therein customers coming in and the first customer always at the first table
the subsequent customer sits at a table
drawn from the following vision you sit at table proportional to the number of people
already in that table that's what am i
a start of new table proportional to some prime parameter make that you have
for now
so i sit here
with probability the first customer comes in sets here
with probability one
and the next this sources there are probably happens the new table probably have
right so that in this make out but not the one that the correct thing
to do right is proportional to that
so after and people come in this in a random partition of n customers in
some of here some here some here somewhere
it's random however the number of occupied tables is random
and it scales of log
kind of long tail as more and more customers come more more tables get occupied
all right and the really fantastic thing about this is that this defines an exchangeable
distribution of partition the customers exchangeable here
the nice ride this is an integer order came in first order
the actual in the end result is in the water
the exchangeable
right so if you want to easy to prove that is right down the probability
measure this induces i this all later slide take the product of those into the
common in apparent order
so because exchangeable by d that is there must exist an underlying data in some
generalized sensible behind
and this
probability distribution must be enabled over data
and that the is not a vector
i don't think it turns out to be the dirichlet process is the international objects
you'll see that little bit later but what are you doing
so i learned about this about six first with the birth theta randomized algorithms kind
of like story how i learned about this in the whole field
i gave a problem to my randomized algorithms which was the following
take a random partition permutations of the numbers one through n
so i have no interest whatsoever in factorial permutations like a random permutation of the
one of the problem the probability that an i j on the same site
permutations are something like right what was probably the who the idea in the same
so most listened can solve this problem is about three pages of combinatorics and probability
fundamental problem try it out on
and in the most of it will be converted to have
so that seems to simple the means i my colleague jim pitman is an expert
coming from the probability
you know and has come one come out like this and he says you have
to learn about five
five restaurant process here is the proof of a little problem
what's the problem i and j are together in the same cycle
well by exchangeability this is probably the same probably the number one and number two
on the same talk
and everyone always sits at table number one and number two sets are probably happen
with some other people probably have
and he said there's about thirty other things you can improve really simply by writing
so i this in bold up and learned all about
this field and get some of you have heard about this field as well
OK so now that in probability theory the saboteur statistics
machine learning
what's happening with mixture models
well i really very simple now the tables are clusters
in the end customers that are stable are the data points in that cluster and
we are random number of clusters
we don't to fix the number of clusters
it comes out of the probability
and today now let's get the likelihood is that kind of the prior on the
number of clusters likely to follow whatever the first customer sits at table
they draw from a problems with some parameters for that table so i said that
first stable i think they are from some prior on on data
mean covariance
and everybody says that table here is that mean covariance
and if you start a new table you take your own meaning covering for that
i get a cluster i mean covariance for every cable from imagine pictorially a much
faster pace
OK so the likelihood of the usual mixture likelihood now that kind of data at
a table the data points are just the galaxy or whatever probability of x given
OK and i have a fully specified probability models
well the table problem parameters problem data
because what you've pierced us now is internal logistics they come into company right up
here with the headquarters and take over your entire
internal logistics cycle in sourcing
so you have yet to sheep laptop
and it breaks and you go to the warranties is called one hundred help you
call one hundred help and they tell you take it sheep laptop to the upstart
and senators my head back to seventy two hours here's what you don't know
tutorship laptop
goes from the up store to the ups hub at louisville airport in kentucky where
an airline hangar at louisville airport in the clean room your toshiba laptop is repaired
by u be yes employed
it never touches so she hands to she basically unsourced entirely to you yes
maybe the outcome you wanna get the kids who personally sneakers you go online naked
outcome what you don't know is on the other side that's screen someone in finally
brown shorts
who's taking down your order
on picking and packing the shoes from the
ninety warehouse the ups managers
and shipping them to you and collecting the money and be happy view yes see
the poppa johns pizza tracker by
i guess who's driving
say it with me now someone in funny brown shorts okay
because you upstairs in source sorry but the chances in source the delivery of the dough
from the bakeries to their outlets
the up yes so this is a whole new form of collaboration it requires more
micro you get a huge amount of standardization
and as a result it's going to be a huge flat here
over time there are hundreds probably thousands of companies today that no longer touch any of their products
there are nothing but marketing shells in source
basically the
to pierce
the sixth the last new form of collaboration i i call informing
informing and that's my name for google
that's my name for search because i can now inform myself i can collaborate with data
all by
tivo is a former informing for entertainment
and informing is a powerful new form of collaboration
so just review in the first three it created this platform for multiple forms of
collaboration then we have the next six new forms of collaboration outsourcing offshoring open-sourcing supply
chain in sourcing and informing
that's nine
what's the ten there are ten
i argue in the book that tent
i simply call the steroids
steroids are wireless
voice over the internet
in file sharing
and what these steroids are doing
is now turbocharging all six so these new forms of collaboration
so i can now do anyone
from anywhere
with any device
that's the second chapter and that's the argument about what i consider to be the
ten forces that flat the world
the third chapter and stop after this tries tied together at least the base argument
the third chapter is called the triple convergence and basically what i argue is that
sometime around the year two thousand
there were three huge convergences
which all came together to really shape the brief history the twenty first century
the first convergence i would argue is all tended these flatteners
right around the year two thousand converted into a tipping point with the complementarities between
them all started to work together
so they
informing helped outsourcing outsourcing healthy offshore in the open sourcing drove in sourcing all the
complementarities between these ten flatness started to work together
and when they did
they created
the flat world
what i mean by the flat world
they created a global
web-enabled platform
from multiple forms of sharing knowledge and work
irrespective of time
distance geography
or even increasingly language
that's what i mean when i say the world is flat i mean we've created a global web enabled platform
from multiple forms of sharing knowledge and work
irrespective of time distance geography
and increasingly even
i believe that's platform
if you if you think about the platform
you can explain more things
about what's happening in the world today
and with any other r
you can explain the rise in energy
and you can explain the rise in outsourcing
you can explain
and might ease
open course
end you can explain
nine eleven in arcadia
so there
first convergence is what flat in the world
by producing this new platform
that more people than ever can plug and play
the second convergence
is that we are just at the beginning of this
is that we're all having to learn the horizontal lines ourselves says we're all having to learn to adapt are
business processes are study habits
are innovative
approaches to this new platform
as are going from world where value is created in vertical silos largely i've command and control
during world war value will be created increasingly horizontally by u connect and collaborate with
which is that the beginning and making all the changes from going from vertical to horizontal
now the best way to understand this is i think the whole david the stanford
economist at a remarkable essay that i'm sure many of you've had a rate electrification
and yes the question why was it when electricity first appeared
we didn't get a productivity books
and the answer is we looked into it was because get the actual productivity boost
from electric motors replacing steam engines
we had first redesign buildings from tall multi-story buildings that could accommodate big steam engines with their police
two smaller laws long buildings that's where the factory could operate with small electric motors
and the managers had to adapt their management practices and
after architects adapted the way buildings look then shop-floor stewart had to adapt how they
manage the shop floor so there were a million
different habits and structures that had change
and once they changed the tipping point
then we really got
the productivity boost from electrification
well i would argue that we are just at the beginning and doing the same thing
with this horizontal platform are just the beginning
changing our habits supports underlies ourselves
actually discovered this in a very personal way
when i was working on the book
on the other hand the says the maryland my daughter my oldest daughter's a sophmore
courses school in new haven connecticut
i was going to visit her last march
it is a complete pain in the behind
to go from the there's the maryland to new haven connecticut
you've to drive from the says that
be w i airport in baltimore
take southwest airlines from baltimore to hertford and then drive from hartford for an hour to know
the problem is going up less print
taking into bags been closed for my daughter
hand on
on and i
the central and southwestern the southwestern and flown southwest but as you may know itself
you you don't get a reserve see
you just get a ticket that says it
at very low temperatures
there is very little thermal agitation
and so on
you can then
he zero line
and so the value for
half of them will then be
ferromagnetic materials
if you call it
you expect the
kappa of them going up
so you get stronger field inside
so its temperature dependence
if you
make material very heart
then it can lose completely its ferromagnetic properties
what happens at a certain temperature that these those range domain fall apart
sort of domains themselves no longer exist
and that happens at the very precise temperature is very strange
that's also something that is very difficult to understand the unique
quantum mechanics for that
but at a certain temperature which we call the curie temperature
with four ironies thousand forty three degrees kelvin
which is seven hundred seventy degrees centigrade all of a sudden the domains disappear and
the material becomes paramagnetic
in other words if
ferromagnetic material will be hanging on the magnet
and you would need up above the curie point it will fall off
it will become paramagnetic but paramagnetic material in general doesn't hang on the mac
because the forces involved
quite small
and the change is very abrupt
and i'm going to show that to you
was the demonstration i have a
right there you will see very shortly
this is not a washer
honest you
and there is here
a magnet
i don't know what it is north of thousand doesn't matter
and here we have a thermal shield
so this washer
it's against the thermal shield because it being attracted want to go to a strong
magnetic field is ferromagnetic
so it will be sitting here
and i'm going to read it up above the curie point seven hundred seventy degrees
you will see it full of
what it calls again goes back on again
so i can make you see
properties disappear
let me make sure i have a
proper settings
i see nothing
there is
so here is this
here is shield
and the magnet behind it you can see it is right there
so it goes against the right goes to
towards the
goes into the strong magnetic field magnetic field is not uniform outside the magnet
and it goes towards so now
i'm going to hit
it will take awhile
because the seven hundred seventy degrees centigrade
it's not so easy to achieve
the three most
common ferrimagnetic materials
cobalt nickel and iron
nicole has a
curie point
of only three hundred fifty eight degrees centigrade
so if this were nickel all
this when they call
you like that
i think i strong hand
from and the conning
i think i fixed
i'm a big boy did it myself today
i lost my temper that's the detail
OK let's try again
so somebody it up i was mentioning that
nicole has a curie point
of the three hundred fifty eight degrees centigrade
but it is quite low
this is seven hundred seventy
cobalt is fourteen hundred degrees
curie point
very special material
god already was ferromagnetic in the winter
when the temperature is below sixteen degrees centigrade
but it is paramagnetic in the summer
when the temperature is above sixty degrees centigrade
beginning to be wrap up now
seven hundred seventy degrees centigrade
you expect
some visible light
in the form of red light then goes
and i will keep repeating
pp thoughts on it that you can see
that indeed
it's no longer attracted by
the magnets
and the moment that i stopped eating it
it will very quickly call
we've become ferromagnetic again
it will go
back just watch it
out again ferromagnetic
so the transition is extremely short
all right
so paramagnetic materials
as i mentioned several times in general cannot hang on the mac
the attractive force is there's not enough
to handle the magnetic force
has to be larger than
its own weight
and dynamic minute materials is of course completely out
because diamagnetic materials always post
the weak part of the field
it's only paramagnetic materials and ferromagnetic materials that experience force
the strong part of the field if the field itself is not uniform
now there is one
very interesting
i want to draw your attention to
this transparency here
look here at
oxygen at one atmosphere
oxygen one atmosphere and three hundred degrees kelvin
as the value for
i of and which is two times ten to the minus six
now look at liquid oxygen
the you that is that
you by
so it's going to
so of course
so i or
something like that
i was not always like
the that species
not of
later on these
but in
what i like to say that
one the best
you are you
so the the
for the last ten years
so the
one of
one i one
wouldn't what
it is
so is
one is
so way
that's why we
one gene expression
this is
so last
rule one
that was long
one of
long as
so one
he played
it's not
one of the prime but my analysis and its involved
no reason
so what we look like
one class
has it
was the first
well sometimes you know
one is i saddle after the
let me just give you the the level message the high-level messages that belief propagation
is working on this problem when all of these rows are equal to one
and with that setting that's not a convex problem in general it's very easy to
make me multiple fixed points you can make belief propagation oscillate
it turns out that if you do something quite simple if you choose these rose
in a somewhat different way you can always guarantee that you get a convex problem
and you can always therefore unique optimum of message passing
and the way in which you do it some theory behind this but just to
give you the flavor
you're essentially just and you want to think about this experiment
let's imagine that have a giant had
you have a graph
in general has cycles and i take all the trees that you can extract from
the graph the many of them
so here if you look at that graph showing three trees
if you take all of these trees and
put them in a had you can imagine sort of drawing the tree out at
and then you can ask
if i look at some edge how likely is that edge to appear in that
tree that i just
took at random out of the a hat
it's going to be happy
take up the tree
how often does an edge appear
so in this case this at for instance that has to be in every tree
you can remove this and still have the spanning tree
this edge here
only appears inferences two out of three of the trees that would have a weight
of two thirds
and this edge here would appear in one third of the trees
so it turns out if you use
numbers that are generated in this way they belong to what is called the spanning
tree polytope
then in fact you get a convex problem you can prove convergence guarantees together a
reweighted form of belief propagation to improve convergence guarantees and
various things for some advantage here is that you now have convexified the problem is
not much different than belief propagation but in general this algorithm tends to have a
much more stable it's provably stable and has much better convergence properties
another thing that you can do again just give you a high-level flavor because you
know have this perspective that things like belief propagation are based on the two ingredients
entropy approximation and approximating the constraints that there's nothing to stop you from using quite
different kinds of constraints
right i don't have to stick with linear constraints like i had here
and one kind of constraint is actually very useful to use semi definite constraints to
further restricting the form of the moments
so the idea here is that whenever you have a moment matrix it looks like
this just looks like a galaxy in case but i'm not we're not thinking about
gaussians writing about discrete cases
discrete cases have to satisfy semi definite constraints as well
and if you impose constraints are actually putting you're using an infinite number of
hyperplanes cutting it many many times
and just to show you the sort of power of this
let's go back to this example that i had before
where we had these things that belief propagation is perfectly happy with right this example
the setting
but if i take these guys i extract for instance mu one mu mu two
mu three that point five point five point five
these are the cross terms point four point four point one so i put that
in this matrix if you put that amount you find it's not positive semi definite
so what this says is that right away this
using a semidefinite constraints ruling out something that belief propagation will be fine with
so sort of thing here tightening you sharpening your relaxation with extra constraints and in
general there's many such constraints you can add and it's not yet really well understood
what's best is obviously trade-offs in terms of computation time and accuracy except but this
is a whole sort of active area that people are exploring
in the last few minutes
actually so any questions about those two particular examples before i discovered the last thing
just to recap the high-level message here is that you can convexified basically any
basically any variational method not mean field style but any one of these outer styles
beta kikuchi its expectation propagation they all can be convexified and in my personal opinion
they all should be convexified i don't think you really have an excuse for solving
a non convex problem when there's something that's close by and convex it will be
much more stable
i give a strong vote personally for convexification
any questions and about
this particular segment
probably people are fairly tired
and sentenced to military conditions that phenomenon called long term potentiation LTP
in fact there will a few more eyes
he discovered all the phenomenon called rock on the question can also manipulate
on synapse in such a way that you can get reduced
if you see
of synaptic transmission but in any case
this right shows
that is
it's not the strings the y axis in the case
it is indeed because all
the strength of the set of steps
the x axis is the kind of recording
and this is the basal level of
and then you do something to this that this is not five
and they need
if to go to the top of the simple down but it does go back
to the this horrible state the higher level
four of the sixty minutes in this fix this can last for many many weeks
the probably many months later maybe
i think the synapse available
was substantiated by by this pp discovery
but as i said earlier
memory processes
very likely to be not the same thing but it's the phenomenon of ensemble
neurons forming a network in which it
but it was in the city the synapses
if this is all
how do you
how do demonstrate
this ensemble
synapse phenomenon of memory traces
here comes
my colleague mike woodson
we're not going to give you but i think he is listed for the
the two are this afternoon i do
look at his facility with one and you can see here
it's actually the mouse
and in the electrodes
in countries such
and it's not the same electoral onto the road microelectrodes
in proc the deep inside the brain
and the tip if in the hippocampus
and in this specific area we can call this year one area from which we
were going to be
as free the animals recover from surgery
an animal
now if we allow the rules in the mind that they have this going on
this is connected to computer
and in the computer will spit out a moment moment the activity of
a set of CA one hippocampal neurons
and animal allowed to
acquired the memory of specific space this a you coming here this morning we will
hear that yesterday
and you have my wrong wrong before
you have already acquired the feature all this particular rule this space
spatial memory so the simulator to that allows
road can do that in fact this is something very important for them you have
to know that the southern india is very dangerous because the possible cats
and the idea is important because it for some time ago and the song so
what that
with this idea
explore a specific and in space
and the former memory therefore memory of the space and as these memory form
simultaneously in real time
for all change
of the bunch of neurons in the hippocampus
and they come up with a very very intriguing
and on
i would say i i will try to explain which ones right
eighty boxes each box
if the present one neuron in this
pyramidal cells of CA models
o thing right
and also
it's square
pop number over space which is about one point five metre
in one edge
and then the activity of neurons
it to how it indicated by red
and activity rule one and it is indicated by blue
right and at the same time of animal
explore the space
he has had a video camera on top
and the new money to the actual location of the animal
he commanded without any good
this kind of diagram
so if you look at this cell
active since cell is active when animal
it in the middle of the space
when i go to provide this way what that way or that way it doesn't
matter that he comes to decide which is the specific location in the environment
the this five
if you take the identify in the middle of the space but it by a
o upon in this time
and the song some cell by doing this fifty minute recording
OK internet cafes is as i've already said this this is a quote from one
of the ideal observer alqaida into a very effective tool use it to disseminate information
people in afghanistan go across the border and send email
and now they consent
they can post
the videos have been lauded
all the tax though what could be a lot of people worry about
terrorists actually attacking the internet
so this goes under name of electronic warfare warfare so
the idea would be that the
terrorist group would sabotage the internet bring down
with the mass effect on the world economy
and then the cycle of these for psychological warfare
ideology et cetera
so a lot
there's a lot of people extremely worried and tried to protect themselves against attack
so how would they do that
you need to disrupt communication unit to damage by two hardware
one thing about the incident is designed to is exactly what it's designed to with
would withstand the internet was this was going to adopt program
so it was designed so that you could take out some links to the internet
it will root itself around
and these are some of the methods that you could do this
you can
electromagnetic pulses these
that is to find out how to get lower or you could attack
you can send worms are hacked hacking into the
into information systems and so on
this is really
right now
i don't think of myself as the it y with the y would terrorist that
the internet it's useful to them
it doesn't
i think a lot of the worries about
specific attacks on the internet infrastructure are present
what they do definitely
behaving this it's may that a with a
they they
they before that is in the propaganda and information exchange that they really work
this is just an illustration of how
recruitment what happens on this is there is actually examples of this
in in
there is a genus for this this exp terrorists for the jihadi forum
where you have an armchair
it's not active terrorists is is basically going to form is is picking up posting
and responding
he he is
he's talking to some sort of ideal of for the whatever it is and
the ideal put him in touch with the local
o operations guy
who brings him together with other armchair
she had his first fully connected to the context
and he brings about maybe sense of honour award rafting trip in the
the lake district if you the english one
and then you have your
it's a terrorist cells
and then they blow up some building
but the the
psychological warfare
well what this is really an outbreak
how terrorists manipulate public opinion pieces
in the western democracies democracies very
what what does it mean it means you're trying to disrupt or damage what the
target population knows or thinks it knows about itself make it uncertain makes
get it
the models are particularly vulnerable to that
because we we allow opinions on on different subjects
the true censorship she is almost impossible on the internet we
governments can't control what their citizens use the chinese i got this
this great firewall of china
they have been hundreds of people who are basically adding neurons which are blocked from
entering the chinese internet
but it of course they can't really control what is published inside china so the
this is the primal
wish strive the dual
i take the saddle point equations which detailed by DB equals zero
and that you want to be on this
would give me
this requirement here
what i'm actually doing with duality here
i don't know whether a lot of how many people whose
familiarity with optimization that briefly the the primal problem OK
which perhaps my
primal problem is a quadratic
and the dual problem this is i'm in time problems the john problems i max
time problems and the solution of to the primal and the dual i have exactly
the same solution you can drive one from the other OK that's what i'm trying
to do i do a dual version of this
which gives me
when solving committees that the same solution
so there might be OK is me this
dl by w actually do a deal by the w that's going to give me
IW here
could have done the square
it can be done but here is distracted term
and indeed detail by the w
it gives me
this expression here
which must be satisfied solution of my primal problem
when daylight w the solution this must be the case
now could take w
substitute back in in here
here here and here get the dual solution
OK i'll just do it and then explain this sort of philosophy of this proof
so w goes in there
and if i place w in their naturally the BMW now gone
i get this dual formulation here
so this is my argument therefore
is from statistical learning theory and must maximize the margin
but i had to strain it so that the primal branch department of the college
it looks roughly sort of like this
there's always the dual formulation of any problem in optimisation theory
and actually when this but i all the primal problem the solution of the dual
problem is also does indeed the solution of the problem the problem is still widely
because zero deal by the w zero
they gave me this requirements so if i'm able to actually go
minimize this expression here then i will arrive at exactly the same solution now
i say here
so maximizing function maximise the jewel
it's actually called the wolf tool
which is this expression here
this actually is the main equation for support vector machines our just cause and have
a look at it before one to do other things
first of all what you notice is the data is coming in here
OK that's the data
xis and the corresponding labels which otherwise
and indeed max task is in terms of the alpha across multipliers
it is actually constrained optimisation because those alpha first must be positive
and indeed is the second constraint which you don't overlook which is constrained here
so it is constrained optimisation
well you'll notice that the important point is my next task alpha
it involves a quadratic programming time across tasks alpha
and alpha square time special
so it's a quadratic
just like here
actually here
and the max is going to have some unique solution
indeed it was sort of ties together because if we consider that max maximally separating
hyperplane i started with you can probably see the only sort of one solution really
and hence i get only one solution to this problem here
so and that is my essential
problem nexus object subject to constraints given
and was for alpha
and it's called is convex
only one solution OK
and my data just simply probably data in here
the quadratic programming get my solution because another feature is very efficient algorithms for quadratic
programming so i can handle very large data sets
right so what i do
it is i would solve quadratic programming problem
having got the alphas
i put the office in here
now initially
but it's not quite true
because typically what they actually do that is they say
it's adjusted for risk
it's clear that some stocks are more vulnerable than others
if you buy stock in electrical utility
which has guaranteed revenue stream because no matter how bad the economy get
a lot of people still use electricity
you don't expect it to fluctuate alive
if you buy
a high-tech company
it sells things on the internet
you might expect it to fluctuate normal it's enormously
or if you buy stock in
a retailer
you might expect it to go up or down more dramatically with the economy
and so
in fact
is an notion of risk and i'm not going to do this in the simulation
but usually people have to be paid to take risk
so it's usually the case
but you can get a higher return if you're willing to take more risk
we might or might not have time to come back to that
more generally the point is
the each stock actually behaves of a little bit differently
there's the distribution of how it would move
so even if on average
the stock
it is expected to not move at all from where it starts
some stocks
you will be expected to just trundle along without much change
not very valuable
another stocks
my jump up and down the line
because they're very vulnerable even if the expected value is
the same
it move around a lot
so how can we model this kind of thing what we've already looked at the
basic notion
last time we looked at the notion of last lecture we looked at the idea
of the distribution
and we
do is simulation were pulling the samples
from some distribution
it could be
that would be a gaussians
we're if you recall there was i mean
and the standard deviation
most values we're going to be close to the mean
especially if there is a small standard deviation if there's a large standard deviation would
be spread
or it could be uniform where every value was equally probable we also look at
so we're going to
assigned to each stock when we created
eight distribution
some way of
visualizing are thinking about
where we draw the price changes from
this gets us into
a new linguistic concept
which will see
down here you don't have this particular code on your handouts
you do the code that uses the same concept
so here's my unit test procedure
and here's what i'm going to create distributions and i'm going to look at two
a random
are uniform in the gaussians
what landed does
is it creates
on the fly
a function
as the program runs
that i can then pass around
so here
i'm going to look at the thing random that uniform for example
between minus volatility in plus volatility
so ignoring the land
what do we expect random but uniform to do
it has
equally likely in the range from minus volatility to plus volatility
it will return any value in here
but notice the previous slide
where i am computing volatility
that this phase velocity even goes to infinity
now you know
that there is no problem
there is no energy flowing
was that speed is no different from the water
in fact the energy flow
it was the group velocity
which is
the group velocity
is the omega
the case
and that was always less than c should perhaps remember
not zero again getting
my enthusiasm get carried away is less than c
and remember at the cutoff frequency were no longer radiation would go through
this phase velocity went to infinity and the group velocity went to zero
i have fulfilled the promise to those of you who couldn't sleep
i tell you that the meaning
of phase velocity is larger than c
and that's all
there's nothing wrong with it you have it was what are you have to make
you have admitted electromagnetic radiation you cannot transport any mass was that space
you cannot transport any
energy with that's speech
so there's nothing
obscene about
very straight
and i want to do a demonstration
show you that
waves can be linearly polarized
next lecture
we will discuss how we
generate electromagnetic waves
we do not by accelerating charges
in this case the electron
and i have your transmitter
this is an antenna
through which we are going to oscillate current
the frequency of eighty
so f
so the wavelength lambda
it is about three point seven five meters
the wavelength
it is the speed of light
divided by the frequency
out to be about three point seven five meters
and as we oscillate eighty million times per second back and forth electrons in
isn't enough
that means the current going back and forth
electromagnetic radiation is produced the next lecture you what exactly see how much
and why
and that electromagnetic radiation
is polarized in this direction linearly that should not surprise you
if the intent is like this and the electrons move like this should not surprise
you but you will see
next to say why it is linearly polarized is correct
and here i have a receiving antenna
this is the copper wire
which is cut in half
and where the two
roads connect
there's a light bulb
any current that flows in you must go through the libel
when i turn on this transmitter
i want to show you
that as long as i hold this
receiving antenna like this
i will see these lights go out
but when i do this
i want
because electromagnetic radiation if you goes like this is going to slosh current in year
with the frequency in megahertz
and the life goal
but when i do it like this the electric field is like this so
there is no current flowing in this direction
so this is a dramatic way of demonstrating
there is such a thing as linearly polarized
what we decided on the lights we going to to right
made target we possibly could
so here's the transmitter and
and here is the receiver
and i'm holding it like this and you see that i'm receiving a signal
so does the current sloshing back and forth
and the light is on
and now it's all very field comes in like this
the lights stuff like i don't see current going through
it does
but this is sensitive to the polarization
o of the incoming signal
when i go a little bit
to this site
as we just saw electromagnetic radiation if you must be always perpendicular to the direction
of propagation so direction of propagation always in this direction so that's why i hold
it like this for maximum effect
because now he feels is like this
whereas in the field is like this
how do you feel is like this
and the light is not bright
you will see to say why
but clearly when i do this
first nothing and because of the linear polarisation
of the electromagnetic radiation
so what
come to close it will actually if i come to close to this you my
love that
the light will go
will burn alive
you want to see that
OK so i'm going to call the hierarchical clustering today it's
be quite kind level view i think that's probably like you can probably have
whole conferences on high hierarchical clustering because
that's all sorts of hierarchical clustering algorithms out there and this is really kind of
like a little idiosyncratic journey through hierarchical clustering landscape
so i have to tell you about a few
of the more popular ones in the field hierarchical clustering algorithms which i think is
neil has said that i'm kind of bayesian so
in the going to start with the traditional hierarchical clustering algorithms and then slowly move
towards more and more bees things as we as the public
so let's start with hierarchical representation i think this morning neil has told you about
representing data with like nonlinear
manifold right so dimensionality reduction linear and nonlinear manifolds
so another very popular way representing data is using hierarchies so representing data using trees
so and basically there's many different types of data that has a hierarchical nature so
for example in
natural language processing you might want to
represent sentences english sentences using its posture
so each of the interior nodes of dissenters corresponds to a little phrase
which describes that part of the centre
and the what's come the the leaves of the tree basically
so another example of hierarchical representations is in
so here count showing you a little
drawing i got from the internet of
the language tree of the wall so
languages at the leaves of the tree
and then
the tree itself health describes
the evolutionary history of languages how languages develop and change and spin off from each
so it's kind of
also hierarchical representation of what i believe
actually happened
in the past
so another example of hierarchical representations is in
phylogenetic trees so
i hope that i think all of us believe in evolution
and if you do believe in evolution that you do believe that you know all
of life on earth came
count evolved
from one single source and that
if you look at race trudy hands
evolutionary history of these species then you you basically get the evolutionary tree
which describes
the relationships among all the living organisms on earth
still more examples so here
we don't necessarily believe that
out of the data we see actually has
and the underlying hierarchical structure but will still like two
somehow represent data in hierarchical manner to visualize it better
so here i a little
dataset in which you have
micro array data in which you have patients cancer patients and they you genes
and each little
square here tells you how much that gene was expressed in the patient
you might want to
cluster the patients
in social way that it might be informative about for example which stage
of cancer the patient has
so this might be the stage one cancers patients and this are the stage treatment
cancer patients who wants
you see that this counts so relationships
that's being extracted that's being
extracted by the tree
and on the side of the genes you might want to have some
hierarchical representation of the genes such that genes which are more similar to each other
in terms of the expression levels
put in the same part of the tree
do more examples
so in in image processing and signal processing you might
the images the signals using
things like what reason with decompositions so here
we have an image like this and if we
we can model this image as
it follows we start off with the whole picture
we split it into four quarters
and then within each quarter
if the
image within that quarter is not
is not uniform
then we we keep on spitting it can recursively splitting until
within each little region here
image is basically of a uniform
colour of
gray scale
distribution i this
in this talk october high hierarchical clustering so the idea
is that if you have some data which comes in in this form
and you believe that they
is cluster
so you it comes from
it comes
they that can be described as a whole bunch of clusters so you might want
ask the here and the clusters that another cost that
but within each class you might still you might believe that the cluster also has
some sort of internal structure in which you could
model with sub clusters
so now if you
OK you
at the data is split into clusters within each cluster is split into sub clusters
so that's basically hierarchical representation of your data
so that
these two the notion of hierarchical clustering
so what hierarchical so that's what i'm going to be talking about today so one
of the uses of hierarchical clustering does i think probably
a few important users
some of which i describe here
so firstly is very useful in terms of visualizing data
right so
given a set of patients we might cluster the patients into
p into