it's clear we cannot derive an upper bound of of two means converge to each
other because each of these quantities will convert the patient so that both close to
this they also have to be close to each other and we have some kind
of triangle inequality we lose a little bit over here so we get a factor
of two and we get
epsilon over two minutes of silence
basically the same thing
so if we translate this back into machine learning
does the probability of obtaining m samples
so we obtain training set where the training error and test error differ by more
than epsilon is founded by this point
now or i already mentioned at some point this refers to one fixed function f
so why is this the case
so what if we chose the function quickly interested in so we choose the function
giving us the minimum training
after all that's what we want to know is that function going well problem is
this function has looked at the training so choosing the function has a minimum training
we first have to look at the training data
so the sum of this function knows something about all the training examples
and then unfortunately
even though
even though these guys are still independent x i y i functions i mean
depends on all of them jointly
and in this case i so no longer independent
and the telephone doesn't apply
that's the whole problem so that
what we have to
deal with it now
now here's something not true
it's actually not
not a full one direction is easy the other one is highly nontrivial but i've
tried to motivate
before this picture
it turns out that
it's necessary sufficient
so the type of consistency
consistency member questions
do we get the best result in the limit of infinite dimension data points
for this is necessary and sufficient to have a type of uniform convergence
of training error
two tests are often here risk
over the whole function so in this picture from before over this whole x axis
of all functions
if we have this uniform convergence and we have consistency and vice versa
of course if you look at these things
the reason this is a little bit hard to cheque for a learning machine
and that's why actually we would like to have properties of class of functions which
tell us something about when the uniform convergence will take place not that's
capacity measures
and this will show up automatically if we try to search about
let's take a closer look at this quantity so remember this is what we were
interested in
so this is not the deviation between
training error and test error
the primitive these deviations larger time but not now is uniformly so this is the
supremum have never seen the supremum just think of it as the maximum this is
so the deviation that we get for the worst possible function and the worst i
mean function train test error are as different as possible
so in a way to function well
measuring the training error mislead us a lot about what the test
it's always function so we're interested in
what's the probability that for the world's functions
we are misled by more than epsilon
so if we can prove that even for the west function we are signing close
with high probability
then we find because then we don't care about
which one is the worst one would get just going to use the one minimising
the training error and we know we're going to find
so first of all it is probably the simplest case
function class contains only one function in that case we can just cross out the
supremum maximum
so we are left with the statement that we had on the previous slide
in the channel but does the job for
that is the telephone
it tells us
what's going to happen
just as an aside one application of this policy even if you're you're facing the
sea europe but not completely orthodox phase three o bayesian who still
evaluates things on the test set
it's a real place you should be doing is usually just putting all your prior
knowledge training the data then you don't you don't have to be anything but let's
say you're a reasonable place like lawrence
so you have a thousand test examples and you want to know no i've missed
my my around this type of the examples how likely is it that i'm close
to the true are but i would be measuring five million examples of ten million
then also this poem tells you this
because tells you
so now we have one fixed function it's now so we have chosen the function
that minimizes the training error all that maximizes the evidence or whatever criteria you want
to use you want expansion now you're looking at test set
so this function has nothing to do with test set
and then again these losses i on the test points the independent if field test
is IID test examples are drawn i i d from the some distribution
and then this tells you how far is is the empirical quantity
all my averaged over test set
from the real test error that would be measuring infinity and the test examples
and this tells you that
it's good to have more examples because
the difference would go exponentially with good on exponential
so that's nice
so that's but now let's go to the slightly more complicated case where we have
a function with
several stories function class with several functions to do it
two very slowly
we start to functions so the
plant will be
two functions and functions we can use something called the union bound
and then the nontrivial step will be from an functions to infinitely many functions so
got a couple of protons those electrons are more tightly bound the less flexible so
number of electrons and also the size for equal numbers of electrons a larger energy
will be softer and switch you're than smaller entities
so polarizabilities scales with electron number and with
so we reason that helium is going to be
so low polarizabilities words argon will be high polarizability because we have a lot of
electrons they have to buy necessity you know what the the filling sequences the more
electrons you have those last electrons the farther out so the positive charge in the
nucleus has a weaker hold on and so therefore there while they're bounded they're a
little bit more to frisky another sit near the place move around right so let's
get back to homonuclear species this is induced dipole induced dipole that's the 3rd type
of interaction induced dipole induced dipoles induced by call this a really fascinating wanted proposal
people for a long time from
and its dominant its dominant in non polar molecules
dominant in non polar molecules 100 dominant nonpolar everything's was done dominant non polar species
atoms and molecules in our here's some examples of years Oregon
the you look the periodic table argon has a melting point of 84 kelvin and
has a boiling point of the 87 kelvin
I told you whenever you see a solid you have to conclude that it's held
together by some force so let's imagine we're at liquid nitrogen temperature we take some
are gone out of argon gas cylinder and we followed through and through and that
too was immersed in liquid nitrogen liquid nitrogen 77 Calvin was below 84
so the arrogance solidified
it's going to deposit on the walls of the tube
and after while have a lot of race
some set minimum look at Argonne based what blinds are going too hard
well it's not ionic it's not primary covalent
it's not dipole-dipole
they're all the same
what could possibly blind argon
but suggest
the adhesion because it's it's it's sticking wide
all the answer was given to us by the German scientist by the name of
fritz london Fritz London
in London
he said I think I can explain this he went look back over here dipole-dipole
said you know
the we've already come to the conclusion that
electrons are emotions electrons are not stationary
so he says a managing if we could zoom in here with the themto 2nd
camera and take a snapshot instead of having a uniform distribution of electrons suppose that
at this instant in time there is a slight
in excess of electron density here at around 2 o'clock and therefore
the conservation of charge dictates that there must be a slight electron deficiency that they
this is the case what's the consequence for the adjacent are gone
what this adjacent are gone
says if this is electron deficient it's going to pull electrons in this argon and
make the bottom right here electrons
leaving the top left electron-deficient which then causes but she told her and he told
him etc etc
so what is the result here the result is we have dipoles
time-averaged it's nonpolar but it's always dipolar and there's a tiny tiny type
so he called this time fluctuating at that time fluctuating dipole
and its present in all systems in all systems even a sodium ion has electron
cloud that's in motion
and we don't see this in sodium because the action of this in sodium is
dwarfed by the coelomic force which is a thousand times stronger but this is the
only game in town
when you're at 18 77 kelvins
there's nothing left so this is dominant and the forest that comes out of this
this attractive force is being turned the London dispersion force
the London dispersion force in a London dispersion force is a is a very weak
force and it's as you would expect it's proportional to the polarizability right elements that
have being
electron clouds that weakly held are going to be more mobile than small
atoms that have small electron clouds tightly held so that London dispersion
the London dispersion energy is goes as the square of polarize ability and as you
expect it's a very weak force analogous to the repulsive force right we're talking about
electron electron repulsion wanted you see that before
we saw that in the cool the derivation of the the with the Madeleine cost
and that's the born exponent of very high number because this is very weak force
solve if this is the inter species separation this goes as part of the states
which makes sense it's sort of born like
this is actually got another name
you know
to be high
when you
this stripping of of
words but the problem is that
you might make and also a new
remove words because you build some
or perhaps another three and a system for compressed compression of your sentence because we
call this sentence compression
do make this and also this affects the classification accuracy
OK so
i had this one
so i'm going to another
part of this is cause
i think
you did
at the end of each chapter
and you can always write me something is amiss there
you these
well we use the to dynamic programming for training
that's the open source system don't
the techniques that i discovered you are that is that there
very very general so
you you have opened for
i i i don't really know speech speech group
part of speech
and so
i was speech transcription
i will compile a list of all
of URL where you can also sort
the name at this
to the dynamics
for every one is infinite
but i do this next week when i'm back in my
because i have all this information in some some files in my office
i mean that's
serious much quicker to consign that
in research
in our research
yes we do
i come back later for one
slides of our research
a typical example
well it's so hard to do this to go back and forth otherwise i'll show
you immunity it's like
if you look at the end my last slide
maria sharapova
cases that i don't know some some business associates is saved when she won the
detecting the sentence
the type
the predicates are
the for
that expresses a certain action
and you detect that active
who is doing that action
you detect also
some maybe some object manipulation here so what is the patient of that action
and you detect where it happened maybe in melbourne or
park or something and when it happens so these are difficult task so this is
semantic role labeling
in the sentence
and so the
they are difficult task a difficult task
well you could use such conditions such a linear chain
conditional random field
so that's one example
i would some other examples later
first of all that
well i don't
if some information about semantic topic models
because i think they are
for information purposes and for the winter
later you get some very simple i think very interesting research path
so the
it's for the school's football
so we currently
you can also use these models to limited amount it some amount of similar division
these models
domain is empty right
but the domain must not be empty as i said before this is some some
presupposition here so
can use an inference of this is that the whole set of axioms specified using
some editor
doesn't make sense at all if the tee box satisfiable
and also concept subsumption is an important service
if you are familiar with other logic few real very easily identify that a UCQ
is the fragment of first-order logic concepts correspond to unitary predicates roles are binary predicates
the concept descriptions can be seen as first order logic formula with one free variable
look at this one here
so for all white holes that had of x y implies department of y and
x is the free variables here
pretty much the same using in in this example
concept describes the formula with one free variable and the GCI
that i have introduced before
are a formula without free variables so-called sentences look
DCI corresponds to this formula here
no free variables any you could argue that so why should i deal with description
logics at all
the point here is that for this
specific fragment of first-order logic which has a very
intuitive and convenient syntax that allows you to grasp the set semantics very easily
decidability can be proven and also complexity results of the decision problems are available and
practical implementations for than actually solving the is
the decision problems can can be
downloaded so this is the major
considering specific fragments
and what using ontology means
coming up with a set of
i have the
i have repeated the a set of axioms here that we have discussed before and
once we have
we use the machine to check out whether they make sense
in this case it's pretty obvious that the tee box is satisfiable
then it might be interesting to find out whether there are implicit subsumption relationships
or whether there are
concepts that are not satisfiable
one is interested
in an overview about
the whole
ontology and so one is usually interested in finding the set of concept names
that are
more general than one
concept name might focus on
so the idea is that one takes every concept name that is mentioned in the
t box
or in the signature if you want and find out the most specific concept names
that subsume this
concept name that we focus on the the common subsumer is here are called parents
you might also define the children in the most general concept names which are subsumed
by the concept name and
the reason is usually supported service that
in that implements an efficient algorithms to find all the parents and children for every
concept name that is mentioned in the t box
and this is this whole process is known as classifying the tee box or is
classification process if you have a look at the tee box here so we identify
person and professor fullprofessor student
on the grid
department right and
you from from looking at the
DCI stem from considering the semantics
we find some apparent
concept subsumption relationship or apparent relationships the professor
if this up
the concept of person and even child of person full professor the child
this is pretty obvious from considering the extent to most people are just fine with
this but i would like to argue that is important to use the reasoning services
to find implicit subsumption relationships and i mean
given all the obvious stuff here
for you it's not a big problem to me
see that
are chair here is
a person might if we focus on this
relation here
we can press the button and get a print out of this
child parent relationship the graph structure is usually known as the taxonomy
it can be shown on the screen
either with
four that use or using some graph display you know this thing
we should probably and
some GCI year
it becomes apparent that
if we
and this
looks tricky i will explain in the second there there implicit subsumption relationships introduced at
of which you might not be aware of
so look what we're specifying here is that this is the set right
and this is the set of all the things of the world that are on
the left-hand side of
head off
you remember we describe this set of objects using the complex concept descriptions and we
say this is the set of objects acts
for which there exists a partner on the right-hand side as in it in a
table of the head of relations
we don't impose any severe restrictions on the right-hand side
we just say
we just
here the factorisation applied by conditional independence in these
joint probability distribution
so here we have the joint
we make no assumptions
no conditional independence
here we do make conditional independence assumption
that condition independence assumption we saw
these factorizations in particular
so now let's do the same thing let's some on x one and x three
this quantity but now this quantity is written this way
since this quantity is written that way
there is a marked tree we can use
to make computations more efficient
what's this
well the smart trick is very simple
we realize that we are some on two variables x one and x three
and we see that some of these factors
don't depend on x y
for example these two factors will depend on x one
some of these factors don't depend on next three for example the first factor does
not depend on x
so some factors are constant
with regard to some some advice
hopefully take advantage of
let's just make this summation let's open this summation x one x three into two
explicit summations and x three and x one
let's school
behind affects one here everything that does not mean does not depend on x one
because that's not constant for the summation
mathematically what i'm doing what i'm doing this
he's using what we call the stream with what
i'm taking
called factor
in the summer
pulling its outside
if i have a common factor
in the summer
the common factor is a
how can i write it
well this is equal
two eight times be policy
that's exactly what i'm doing here
in the summer over x one i have a common factor which is the use
if i keep like these
we have three
o operations
i have on multiple occasions he another multiplication you have
if i like these i have to average
and if you want to see a wonderful paper that part of all these
look at something called
the generalized distributive law
just google for
the paper to basically talk
basically describes all these operations
as simply and generalized application of the distributive law
the key idea is that
these quantities here is equal to user one here
but if you do these operations you have
cost of two
this operation have a cost of three
so when we have a course of three you just fall off
first the songs and then multiply
that's exactly what's going on
that simple fact
i will show up immediately here
what's the result of this
well first
these summation here
on which it is
just the some
some x one of p of x one given x two
well this this has to be one right
and regardless of x two
conditional probabilities approach right
these objects is one
the current index on this
and then you would switch over to
new index by tapping into the free have this
new wide field and
when you copy the new index back to be faster happiness
you do a deal
the original first copy
and then now would actually free up some disk space that you could use for
building various performance improving data structures in the middle
one of the things we built was something we call the pair cache which is
basically if you look at commonly co occurring query terms
we would offline precompute pre intersected pairs of posting lists for these commonly co occurring
i don't have to be phrase turn things have to be terms that occur frequently
increased together
so we're not building a phrase index it's just you know barcelona and restaurants occurred
in the same document
by two thousand we refined our hardware designer but we had
decided cases are OK
and we managed to get all the connectors on the front of the computers
it was quite painful to reach around the back field corporate
the ethernet cable
and we were still not only are in data centers we were leasing space in
hosting facilities and they charged by the square foot which was an excellent
the of
so we would try to pack as many computers as we possibly could use much
electricity as we possibly could into the number square-foot scruffy buried licenses
so that was good
they a
sometimes need a little extra help with their cooling
we were purchased fans for them
as a consequence we also got fairly good moving out of bankruptcy data centers
and moving into new ones
and so
the nice thing is
actually too hard to move into a new data centre have other acts all cable
operator a
and then you basically have to we'll interaction then connect together all the tracks which
is to central router and you're ready to go
so in the period of nineteen ninety two thousand one roughly
we were
simultaneously having huge traffic increases and huge increases in index size
so our index size when roughly by factor twenty and at the same time as
we were having roughly
can you know ten fifteen twenty percent growth per month increase traffic
and we are also out signing deals for example we find search
deal with yahoo to provide their search service
and that doubled traffic overnight in the same time we were actually
doubling our index size
the previous few days
it's quite exciting
and the performance of the index of system is what is really important
is it in when you're dealing with this sort of thing we're continuously buying more
more hardware and releasing more and more data center space but we basically needed ten
to thirty percent software improvements every month in order to sort of sweet by our
otherwise we would have no end up
in a bad state
so the nice thing about this basic
structure now move doctor after the side is another interesting from from the standpoint but
i think is that it's fairly easy to
had capacity new
you can grow your indexed by adding more in charge
and then you can
more replicas that capacity
and if you're very you're next slide that morning charge
and more charges
and more replicas for capacity and more dangerous and eventually end up a lot of
machines and one charge replicas
but it's a fairly
reasonable process to do that as you do you don't try to do this in
the middle of indexes sort of say OK that the next month's index we're going
to do seventeen jar instead of ten
so one of the things one of the reasons you have to keep that in
charge as you increase the index size is that you want to have query response
times the
reasonably low and if you make sure too large well it might not fit on
the local disk severe machines or
your response time we get too large and so you need to sort of increasing
numbers charts in linearly as you're increasing during exercise
it's also possible to get pretty big performance improvements which we did by
writing around disk scheduling system that was aware of what pending on that particular server
and prioritizing reads in a reasonable way
we also focused the firm on improving our index encoding which is what i mean
by now
so the original encoding
done as part of the prototype stanford was pretty simple it was actually fairly simple
byte aligned format basically you have
the document identifier plus the number of hits including thirty two bit five but for
the number of hits and twenty seven the ducati many sixteen bit for each word
for each occurrence of that particular word that encoded by the position of the word
as a sequence number within the document
and some
a few bits for attributes of
the words like was it is in the the title
was it in a big fighter little font
and so on
and for very long posting lists you eventually want skip tables into
the data structure so that if a you have the word of or something if
you have a table on the side that tells you
we docherty
a million is that of set
you know
two billion two billion in year posting list
by the line format was pretty simple decoders every compact and it actually required lots
of space so we work for fair amount of our
including data structures
and give you a brief background on
grace encoding techniques
because the be useful to understand the encoding format we used basically there's several different
bit level encodings you can imagine using which are going to be slower than by
level encodings buildings are things like you encoding re two in the number and you
have an ones followed by zero gamma you're going to encode some prefix and unitary
indicates the length of the number and that number of bits
which is a special form of golomb codes
are you you basically have a number and you have a base
during encode that number and and right because the base is always going to be
part of two
so for example
you encode
and divided by what their bases
three then you can and to encode and divided by two to the third engineering
and then and model
three that's
and preserving
before we
used for a while was basically a block based index format so
the nice property that had so we're going to have skip table and then it's
going to a sequence of blocks
welcome to
the first course happy to have chris bishop here
i flew in yesterday with his own playing
he is assistant director of microsoft research lab in cambridge UK before that he
quite a substantial academic career but now he's directing the efforts in machine learning and
computer vision
at microsoft research labs so we're very happy to have him here is one of
the world experts on graphical models and bayesian methods
before we start with this course we would like to do a little
it turns out that it would be inconvenient for him to give the last two
hours on monday afternoons so if you have your schedule handy i suggest you just
take it out briefly
because we have two options how to deal with this issue
so we propose to
cancel the lectures bishop seven to eight on monday the twenty eighth of september
and we have two possibilities where we could
catch up with this time that we're losing number one would be to have ascended
special saturday afternoon not on a saturday afternoon session
you probably mean that chris teachers hours in the morning and we would have a
two and three
in the afternoon the other so that we eat into our
precious saturday afternoon times that's why we thought of another solution to which he's into
lunchtime but not not really i guess the only it into the post-lunch nap time
and that would be to have two hours on both thursday and friday so one
on thursday one on friday both between two fifteen three
so it would still finish in time for the people taking the practical sessions and
the ones who are not a practical sessions could have been that between three and
so she we take votes who would prefer to have some extra work on saturday
this is differ everything
all these times referred to this week
so who is in favor saturday
it's not only five i would say who is in favor of the day of
looks like more
that's a about forty forty plus
OK so
well it would mean that people who
go to the practical session on
monday afternoon will skip
which lectures so is complicated optimisation problem we we tried to
if so we we put the courses bishop seven and eight in the US men
everybody can go to number one through six and only a few people would miss
seven and eight so if we put a good edits two and three in the
afternoon then those people mister in three wouldn't really profit from his fourth lecture so
i would prefer not to do that one
both in group one
it was amazing
is going on here
i mean take a quick look
OK i'll try to double check with him but
and we'll see if that works will do that otherwise would go for option number
two and
don't find out soon
OK so i don't take more time away from chris thank you
thank you very much indeed
OK so i'm going to talk about two
topic which me is represented the most interesting
developments in the field of machine learning
in the last decade or so
they are distinct topics but they actually go
rather nicely together so you'll see many links between these two topics topics being graphical
approximation schemes
which come the general heading of variational methods for lack of time i shall
focusing on one
in particular
very popular kind of variational
so i understand from the organisers that the audience is very heterogeneous and i can
see a few experts sitting in the audience but i know a lot of people
are in the first year phd
so you have an insoluble problem i can't keep everybody happy the whole time what
i'm going to do something for the first few lectures is issues things fairly basic
that is i'm going to assume that you know nothing about graphical models or variational
inference and just start from the beginning i shall assume
you understand the
the sum and product rule of probability
if you don't then you probably lasted very five you
OK let me just give you some roadmap where we're going
so i'm going to
talk about two
the two main kinds of graphical model
directed graphs
and undirected graphs
these graphs do their pectoral
that's important we really need that our algorithm can be phrased as a decision tree
and in particular we now from this transformation
that all comparison sorts can be represented as a decision tree but there are some
sorting algorithms which cannot be represented as a decision tree and we will turn to
that momentarily before we get there
i phrase this theorem as a lower bound on decision tree sorting but of course
we also get a lower bound on comparison sorting
and in particular tells us
that merge sort and heapsort
are asymptotically optimal their dependence on and in terms of asymptotic notation
so ignoring constant factors
these algorithms are often
in terms of growth of n
but this is only in the comparison model
so for among comparison sorting algorithms
which these are
asymptotically optimal use
the minimum number of comparisons up to constant factors
in fact the whole running time is
dominated by the number of comparisons sulfate and organ
so this is good news
and i should probably mention a little bit what happens with randomized algorithms what i've
described here
really only applies in some sense to deterministic algorithms
any one
so anyone seems
what would change
with randomized diagrams or wherever assume that i have deterministic comparison sort
this is a bit subtle
and i only noticed it reading the notes this morning
i give you hands is over here
the right hand side of the world
five deterministic algorithm
they are does is completely determined at each step
as long as i know all the comparisons that are made up to some points
it's determine what that algorithm will do
but if i have a randomized algorithm
it also depends on the outcomes of some quite flips
so any suggestions what breaks over here
there's more than one tree exact
so we have this assumption that we only have one tree for each and in
fact what we get is the probability distribution over trees
for each value of and if you take all the possible
executions of that out all the instruction traces one now
in addition to branching comparisons we also suppression whether coin flip came out heads or
however we're generating random numbers came up with some value between one and
so we get a probability distribution over trees this lower bound still applies though
because no matter what tree we get i i don't really care i get at
least one tree for each
and this
proof applies to every tree some at no matter what tree you get it has
to have if it's the correct tree
it has to have high
omega and log n so even this lower bound applies even for randomized algorithms can
get better and log n
because no matter what really comes up with no matter how those concepts come out
this argument still applies every tree that comes out has to be correct
so this is really
at least one tree
and that that will now work so we also get the fact that randomized quicksort
is asymptotically optimal in expectation
but in order to say the randomized quicksort is asymptotically optimal
now we've got a normal distribution
and if if the
observation that you actually see falls outside of this gate let's say plus and minus
two sigma points on the normal distribution is reasonable to
everything does so now we can see the same fine track running with this validation
gate now because the validation gate is the distributed thing because we are making many
and along normals along this curve and so we can define
the expected range of observations any point on the curve so
the whole thing could be depicted as the tube
with the mean of this
i mean that i mean prediction on the solid line and the range of observations
depicted along the student so what you see here
is that the lower part of the hand
has just fallen outside the validation gate
so now the observation process is going to fail around here
and because the observation process fails no observations made around here
the only half of the kalman filter as it were operates over those
simplifying things like because obviously
you know we're not shopping the curves up into account
bits exactly but in this region the effect of observations and felt so all that
happens is that the variance builds up from successive
predictions and the range gates for validation gate fans and fans until of course you
reach a point like this one were sufficiently fact that now
features again and everything will recover
and once we start measuring here then
that kind of punctures the validation gate you always hear the hiss there
coming out as the validation gate measurements made again validation gate collapses and actually
you know it's very well known that when all observations are present and validation gate
and switching any of them off then you will reach a steady state where the
as depicted by this validation the window
collapses to a steady state won't collapse to zero it will collapse to the point
where there's a balance between the
influence of observations and the uncertainty as a result of repeated predictions
OK so now the last thing i want to do
in this section is just revisit the idea of
learning the dynamical model was used in
and so a reasonable
let's think about this just in one dimension so i just think of point tracking
point along the line for a moment and so x x event is just
the real number
and let's say that the
process that we want to predict has this
for me it's it's as the discrete form of simple harmonic oscillator second order equation
that this wn is a series of independent random noise
yes random random noise variance in there should be b here
so that we are actually coupling this
a series of random noise variables in via some game b which want to discover
so now the the whole thing is to observe
sample training emotion and
from the training motion
to learn
the parameters a north b one and b which describe this kind of pendulum in
in the breeze
again this can all be done
pretty much conventionally if we write down the maximum likelihood principle
it actually boils down to minimizing the sum of the squares of the errors of
of the predictions
that you make over particular training data set
so in other words given the internet plus one points in the training data i
would be able to predict and plus two using this formula are neglecting from moment
the random
noise variable so now i just measure the square error in the prediction and sum
them up and the maximum likelihood estimator turns out to be equivalent to doing this
least squares computation
and when you actually boil it all down and solve these equations it turns out
you've got some simultaneous equations in we for a not in a one in which
the coefficients of these autocorrelations where you take the entire training sequence and a copy
of itself and you shift the copy and multiply them together and add up and
so those are the discrete autocorrelations and these equations are very similar to what are
called the yule walker equations which are absolutely standard in in a
learning for a operas there's a slight slight variations here to do with
dealing with the boundaries the start and the end of the training sequence problem
and similarly you can go back and reconstruct the errors
and use that to estimate the this coefficient should have been here multiplying the noise
the whole thing works very similarly in multiple dimensions so in the state space that
we have six dimensions or whatever it is for capital x we have a very
similar setup just shown
first order form of the
in other words with the history of only one time step
i could put more time steps in on the other hand with state space representations
anyway this is how you
and you win
optimized for this position
so i was actually hoping to quickly summarize what we did yesterday but it would
mean that i have to walk back there
which could be a bit of risk and we don't have any anyway some values
this thing here
so yesterday i was trying to do
introduce the basic ideas of kernels and feature spaces
it's not
too much that you have to remember from this lecture
four today but
what you should remember is slow
definitions of what is a positive definite kernel
so a positive definite kernel is a symmetric function kx x x prime is the
same scale
x y and x with the property that
whatever coefficients AI AJ used
this quantity here
and whatever point x i x j this quantity is nonnegative
when you read this
yes shoppers gets
OK so and if we have a positive definite kernels if we have a function
that satisfies
this condition fall
a i j x i x j then positive kernel and then we actually constructed
a feature space such that this kernel computes the dot product so we construct
constructing a mapping phi such that for all x x prime
this equation here holds true
and if you remember the mapping phi
but this is the mapping phi takes point x maps it into the function k
of dot com i x
so this function
again this is the function which maps the point x y
in two
k of ex-prime come x
OK so this dot is just a shorthand notation for
this function here
and then so one way to think of it was that we have some points
and they are mapped into
i'm sitting on this point
and then we we
find some way of taking the dot product
in this space of functions in the space of bumps and we define the dot
product such that actually this equation here was true in
also such that it is the product was positive definite strictly positive definite and and
so on so now we know if we have such a kernel function
it's actually the same as the dot product in another space
in other words whenever we have and i agree that can be carried out in
terms of dot products we can substitute kernel function wherever we had the product before
provided that we only need to compute the product between points from the input domain
mapped into that i dimensional space
so we we substitute the kernel for the dot product in this way we implicitly
carry out the algorithm in terms of the phi of x rather than the axis
in that feature space can be very high dimensional in the case of the polynomial
kernel that should do it was i mean in a small toy example with ten
to the power of ten already or in a small example and follicles in kernel
it's actually infinite dimensional and so it's a very high dimensional space where we normally
wouldn't want to compute the products but using kernels we do it
slightly more sophisticated algorithm that doesn't slightly more sophisticated than this house and windows-based classifier
of yesterday
so if you remember mister the this sense of class classifier
we we had two classes we compute the mean of each class and then checked
with the test points closer to the one may close to the other ones and
once we formulate this in terms of kernels
the decision function was basically an expansion in terms of kernels
in some constants
the expansion in terms of kernels was the following it was one expansion
well over one part of it was an expansion to the positive points
in one was expansion in terms of the negative points and the weights were constant
within the two classes for all the positive points and weight one over m one
all the negative points weight one over n two where n one and n two
with the sizes of these two classes
so the numbers of positive and negative points respectively
so no
we will construct another classifiers
which will also induce a separating hyperplane in the feature space it may be a
slightly smarter ones
and then it will be a hyperplane that leads to the large margin of separation
between the two classes
so again the idea is map the points into this feature space we construct a
separating hyperplane
OK so you have missed much yet but
but i had the picture i was thinking that you it
so let's see what they have the same picture in mind
when you me talking
close your eyes and imagine it
so here's are separating hyperplane
so what's the separating hyperplane
separating hyperplane is
characterized by
a normal vector w
and an offset b
so the geometric location of the hyperplane is characterized by this linear equation
previous separating the truth the property that this function here takes positive values on the
one side of the hyperplane
negative values on the other ones
let's call an optimal separating hyperplane a hyperplane with
because of these change the set
i played with the property that the distance to the closest point is maximized
subject to the constraint have
which i mean that
all the positive points and one class of the negative ones i the other so
class should be separated correctly but in addition we went the distance of the closest
point to the hyperplane to be maximized
one way to find the optimal hyperplane is to compute the convex hull
of the two datasets
the set of points can be computed as convex combinations
if you want to think of it the set of all points that sort of
like in between
roughly speaking
so we can compute the convex hull
to find the shortest connection
between these two convex hulls then this direction of the connection gives us the direction
now well treated from the outside
but essentially the process happens on inside
the dynamics of change happens on the inside
you get for example
gases which are more stable
highly disorganized states
and it takes a huge push
and this is work done by one three it takes a huge push from the
outside to get them to organize
into some sort of pattern
this is a highly unstable structure
this happens
and more easy for the system the system we can
disorganised state
this is something of interest for us virtual organizations
and i will maintain that possibly when you're talking about faster and faster
first building trust and transient very very transient organisation dealing with a system is much
like a
it is more stable and we seem to have decided disorganised state in other words
in one sense
most disconnected
the potential has the potential to
organised into particular form given the perturbation from the outside
so for example
there is the opportunity to do theoretical research
general disconnected from each other
that's for the inputs
and so organised it has
four for two days
as processes that actually merged results
and it is most likely most in this state organised in organised
that's an example
now called the architecture of course in the internal possibly in coastal states and their
interconnections that's what we mean by organizations organisation
the causal architecture of the process
internal repository causal states and their interconnections
to figure out what the cause of architecture the complicated so i'm not sure we
didn't do that for the social sciences
this into these kinds of systems and that's
where we we really need machine and
the organised system to explore exploit the two
lawrence like well it's quite easy to maintain the constraints
and you're run around and you can see here
and this is
run around inside constrained space
and does all the pattern creation knowledge production and digital
i exploit explore system it actually relax the constraints of its system and it explores
the of this constraint so actually
the notion interplay is more important here
and it able to do right
generally be able to do more computational power
national coordination is really important is that it's constantly rewiring model always
and stable
relationships of this that can be used
functional relationship where you have time to work to do in the lab
the system
tasks functions are we want to solve the coordination
three wise it's
multiple equilibria may have no regular behaviour and they require no for error in order
to generate more
so this is one of the things that his
this is a lot of us is actually does produced
it does make mistakes and errors in one of the things that we're talking about
but this is what they don't tell us anything really OK because even importance sampling
satisfied such that tries OK
so he didn't tell us specifically on many particles you would need to us so
as to approximate the joint the joint essentially target distribution properly so this is kind
of result which actually not really informative you just tell you if we have to
be able to use in a particle basically you might be able to you can
do with commercial trucks so that's not quite
what kind of positive result can we obtain
well and so i'm actually
some kind of mixing assumptions
and that the
so mixing assumption on set in the context of state space model some mixing assumption
on essentially the tall
o two more food you're trying to approximate the then what you can obtain you
can obtain results that are uniform in time convulsed with that
you that
if you look just at the coral marginal distribution
robin tries to you look at pioneer instead of looking at the approximation by electronics
works and you look at its marginal distribution
so in the context of state space model p of x and y what went
in order to compare that to small to count approximation is particle approximation then you
can show
the some basic you're you i just mentioned
that essentially the l
you obtain approximation you your day doesn't increase over time
this is essentially
some very positive about particle method you might not be indeed able to approximate properly
the joint distribution you cannot expect to be able to do that
but under regularity assumptions if you're only basically look at the approximation of the marginal
distribution then basically you what you want to calorimeter on very good properties you don't
have any accumulation of urls over the time you have like a uniform entire convergence
balls so this is why essentially all discovery techniques became popular because such was
if you know
and essentially the violence the relative alliance of normalizing constant simulate
then we have seen actually
that if you were dealing with sequential importance sampling on sampling typically you have
so the bones via that increases exponentially with time index when i'm telling you
when you do resampling under similar you right assumptions then basically the volatility violence essentially
only increases linearly with the time index this is much better we've gone from exponentially
but really not about
so you that assumption
so such that essentially
if you initialise c
i said look at the filter so these guys
so i'm going to specify what's going on
so assume you have the state space model OK
says you look at what's happened when the initial state is distributed according x not
be continue new
all o
is distributed according to of emotional new
what you all to one that basically
as j increases the different ways between these two
distribution into polarisation in the second are geometrically fast time indexed so some are you
all the assumptions as you
what happened in the past is actually going to be forgive forgot exponentially fast
so that's that's what he tells you get
you also have summaries that's essentially he's
you try to obtain
so OK we don't have a good approximation
of the joint distribution and i told you k is not very good now
let's say that two approximation of the joint distribution
o two sample from it's OK to look at the distribution of the past then
one can show
this is the result by the model was the result is that under limiting assumption
essentially the distribution of the positive sample only differ from the true
essentially distribution by a ball that increases only knowledge of the time in that what
is one small this is called it is much better than when you were doing
basically a single tree pollen something where the ball typically increasing expand exponentially fast really
positive results about particle methods
OK so like for example that i'm going to back to the example
we are describing
at the very beginning for importance sampling
so let's consider case for example when
the target distribution factorizes OK
the UN policy distribution so you have the target distribution is the product of unit
a unit normal distribution and impartial distribution is the product of the normal distribution of
violence in the square
if you look at the related violence
the importance sampling estimator it blows up exponentially fast the time index
if you look at the center to violence
in particles basically the
smc estimate sequential monte carlo estimate what you see that basically the smaller
time index which was basically the exponent is just inform it's linear increase so we
moved from essentially
two linear so
whereas two other related violence of ten minus two full sequential importance sampling you would
these are met with very little empirical support
and the claim that psychoanalysis proves itself by being by its tremendous success in curing
mental illness is also almost certainly not true
for most maybe not all the most psychological disorders there are quicker and more reliable
treatments than psychoanalysis and there is considerable controversy as to whether
the tony soprano method inside where you get this insight and this discovery all now
i know makes any real difference
in alleviating symptoms such as anxiety disorders or depression
this is why
the sort of sort of sticker shock
when people go to university psychology department what say look
hey where's so an insect how they take classes on freud
your expert on freud
and the true this freudian psychoanalysis is almost never study inside psychology departments
it's not at
the cognitive or developmental side not the clinical side there are some exceptions
but for the most part even the people who do study fried within psychology departments
do so critically
not very few of them would see themselves as psycho
and practitioner or as the freudian psychologists freud lives on
both in the clinical setting in in university but freud at yale for instance is
much more likely to be found in the history department of literature department then in
psychology department and this is typical enough
despite all of this sort of sour things i just said about
the big idea then important
of the dynamic unconscious remains intact
we'll go over and over and over again different case studies where some really interesting
aspects of mental like
to be unconscious
there's one question i'm not going to skip over this
for reasons of time
and just go
to some examples
of the unconscious in modern psychology
here's a simple example
of the unconscious
in modern psychology
so new year sentence like
john thinks the bill likes him
in a fraction of a second
you realize
this means that john things to build
likes johnny
if you are descendants groups
i don't think the bill like himself
in a fraction of a second
you would think
that means john thanks to bill expert
and as we will get to when we get the lecture language this is not
conscious you don't know how you do this you don't even know what you are
doing this
we do it quickly
and instinctively
so much of our day-to-day life
can be done unconsciously they're different activities you can do
driving chewing gum shoelace tying where if you're good enough at the expert enough fact
that you know you're doing
i was at a party a few years ago a friend of mine and we
ran out of food so is it just go pick up some food
an hour later he was gonna
still gonna be around the corner and we call them up on the cell phone
and he said oh
i got on the highway approach to work
he works like an hour when would
and and the some versions of these things happened
all the time
maybe more surprising
freud's inside that our likes and dislikes
are due to factors that
we're not necessarily conscious has a lot of empirical support a lot of empirical support
from research into social psychology for example
so here's here's one finding in social psychology
if somebody goes through a terrible
to get into a club
though like the club more
you might think they like unless the people do terrible things but actually hazing is
but are remarkably successful tool
and you see that in this subject specific also that already very high correlation between
alpha power plants and vote for heart rates the subject the
the correlation is even higher so that the hard-headed variations are traditionally generally are highly
correlated to bolt so that means that if you do and experiments where you also
modulate the the heartbeat for instance by presenting emotional saliva Protestant libraries has an influence
on the heart rituals against responses well from all the parts of the brain and
principle of these subject now that if you but what about the bits tool to
quantify the amount of of correlation defined over different subjects and different probabilities between heart
rate and Adolfo balance
but rather that see that for some subjects almost the whole brain surgery
90 % of fraction of the brain is correlated to the alpha band and in
some subjects the subjects there is hardly any coalition structure is very very large inter-subject
variations toward this kind of correlations
what's there would would now like to present some results on the data-driven analysis and
there are based on the fact that the that the model different approach that the
artificial some limitations on is that we have applied the regression model each voxel separately
instead of on the whole brain
I only have evidence all frequencies and the cost to get to clean up the
variations and we have not used any of you have not made use of the
spatial distribution of the alpha frequencies
now as far as the 1st question is who
concerned we we looked at the try to find out whether variations we find in
different subject that have to do something with the algorithms or whether it has something
to do with the original signals and for that we look at the the the
the the clustering on the on the role of bold signal so without applying any
model if we knew we removed all the nuisance effects of emotion affects all the
trends and all the heart effects and GC these projects are also applied to mobile
the bolt signals and at the defined distance measure
and this is the distance measure was used for clustering analysis and then we compare
compared different subjects have see if we if we apply this this data driven clustering
approach to durable signals and we see of if we if go to about
8 clusters and we see among subjects that you have a patrol and appraisal of
cluster foreseeable points also belongs to a cluster until seceded said that although there is
not the information in the clustering of the algorithm regarding the connectedness of these components
you used to underpin mostly connected components and if you now correlated these components to
the alphabet that all these components they appear to to quality the operator so in
this sense if you 1st clustering and
computer every topic clusters that the amount of correlation it can be demonstrated in all
the subjects and if you look at the sort of clusters and they seem to
be related to the to the default network so here's the spot and this part
there are connected to at least produced assembled signals
as well
what they have done knowledge that I have not had only used acceptable parts of
the of the alpha band variation if I look at the complete pattern of the
alphabet uh and he as carriers of 10 born to 16 hertz
about this subject and I see that the that the the lot of patterns they're
they're very in time sometimes it's nothing is present sometimes volunteer Doppler happen although this
is justice power of a power sometimes as he directly due to the left and
sometimes it's more to right there's a lot of things going on and is 600
pictures and is only for 1 of the 1 part of the of the alphabet
and you should look at the frequency 1 security Tyrol origin completely different purpose and
all these deceased graphs to police the state of the brain is related to the
office of them and they could be correlated the bold enough to do that we
look at these kind of patterns and now clustering and
algorithm was applied to these different
patterns of alpha rhythm and uh moments maps of the EEG and then at the
theater that's probably get 1 group without any
this was 1 group this was a group and these groups were the same kind
of distributed here again not the average of all these groups and we can all
subjects to find this kind of patents so there was 1 nonspecific cluster there was
no overlap model
there was 1 cluster that was pretty variety of was dominating activity lower frequency
there was 1 cluster where it was dominated at the higher frequencies and it was
1 clustering gospel the middle of the frequency so once specific and low and high
called for in terms of estimable quantities which might or might not be useful for
your purposes
that's quite a the complex bit of convex analysis that goes behind the bounds quite
need the important things you can get them out exactly typically
but you can do in general is this
i have now eliminated the error from x to y and the hypotheses
what does it mean if there's anything that picture the error vector y is missing
well one thing it makes y independent of f of x
that's what is represented in the new picture
when y is independent of x means what i do two x isn't going to
change what the distribution of y so basically that so there's no causal effect
so the hypothesis of no causal effect which is clearly very interesting hypotheses
it's kind of represented by this picture as a kind of because although this is
a sufficient condition for that it's not necessary
so there's a bit of fuzziness going on here but never mind about that and
also if i can eliminate that image
another property holds which is that in the into the observation regime
on any regime but only in the observation raising wise independent of z
and that's something i can tell
so if i test it i find y is not independent of z
and i believe my original picture on the previous page
and i find y is not independent of z observationally then i can believe that
and that our companies
that means that there is a causal effect so i can do hypothesis
and it just uses the instrument and the response
so great things we can do and although none of this theory is really new
i think just the use of the DAG models to represent the story and this
is very useful for number reason first of all
it's absolutely explicit what being assumed put those intervention indicators and then use the tag
so the bad apply very so you're telling that story translated words really and see
what it says about what you're assuming about what is reasonable
the say does not depend on the regime which marginal and conditional distributions which changed
so you tell the story very explicitly
put that in context think about your problem is that of valid story doesn't make
sense could you convince the down so that it was true
what do we can you the diagram one so the diagram you know one of
the things with you can analyse it can also some conclusions work formulae
four for understanding how to compute effects and things like that
i have a very good example
instrumental variables mendelian randomisation
so the question does lot of observations studies suggesting that low serum cholesterol increases the
risk of all kinds of cancers
you can actually easily go in and fix somebody serum cholesterol
but his is very very clever idea because there is a particular gene APOE gene
which actually an instrument
it turns out the people who are born with a particular value this gene
naturally have very low serum cholesterol
what these confounders here things like your diet smoking sort of common causes of who
knows it might affect both serum cholesterol and cancer there might be a hidden chamber
which actually having observed have been able to observe the that might and might be
reverse causation the tumour might be lower your cholesterol rather than the other way around
so all sorts of things could be problems and if we don't observe w i
don't know what's going on
but z is it reasonable to think that the conditional independencies whole well z is
your ali elements is assigned birth
and it's pretty
easy to
convince yourself that is independent of whether or not you later going to have a
hidden gem
so it's independent and is in typically it's hard to argue bit harder that is
independent of diet and smoking habits of things because part of family environment and things
like that but but but you could argue that the conditions hold quite recently so
you can use it as an instrument it's common dearly randomisation is because men those
laws for the allocation of this gene tierney what's going on
it does affect low serum serum cholesterol and so for example you could check to
the incidence of cancer varies with the value gene you have if it does
that suggests there is a causal link
it doesn't
and it's not clear but maybe there's
measuring it is very hard
but you can actually do hypothesis test set is there or not
and this is great because we have a story to tell in context
we know the story we understand the genetics and is because we understand the genetics
and we can make plausible arguments to justify that particular picture
that we can use so we can't just say oh here is picture believe me
that works i can say here's the page and this is why it works
and now i know that people to go to work for me great can manipulate
it i can do all kinds of statistical analysis and get out some causal conclusions
because i justified the picture which involves both stochastic variables and most importantly
the intervention variables question
sorry which
that's problem
vision or
in addition
OK well that is if i have these interventions will be hypothetical because i but
i'm interested in thinking about hypothetical intervention where would go in and try and set
some somebody's cholesterol see whether i would if i could raise your cholesterol or by
various means fitting wakes perhaps
then maybe i could increase you
decrease the chance of cancer so i i want to know what would happen in
such hypothetical interventions but the gene the gene is already there
so there's no way i can so it's
is completely independent of what i choose to do it here
the three d
what you
absolutely is the here
so the question was illegal about just replaces it with it because they want is
sometimes it is it is independent of w
that's not true of x
ideally would like this link to be strong stronger this link the belly of the
beast only to retain an independent spirit award
i think we'll get this
OK so we argue in some cases in which we can identify causal effect from
purely observational data if you could only make the right assumptions and this a very
theory but developed by poco do calculus so imagine software problem and it's got these
to what i call the main of stochastic
variables as well as intervention variables and we specified that the appropriate
extended conditional independence properties possibly by demented dagger pearlian DAG will possibly does by now
to write a list of algebraic formulae it doesn't matter
and again we might have some unobservable variables in which case we call you
as of variables v so we get to get off
two problems with that data first of all it's only observational
secondly it's incomplete to the good news
we just got the observation distribution over these
and we're interested in
what can we say about cause and effect which is defined in terms of intervention
it is not so much that he is using you know
infinite or nonconstructive methods but is very very aware of it ten is very sensitive
to what is almost apologetic and he brings that makes that a central topic of
OK so having
made the case that the kernel was working firmly and squarely in the hilbert but
finitary metamathematical tradition known to try to make the case that that
he was at the same time
curiously at odds with that tradition
and in some way chafed against hope influence
in order to help clarify the relationship between a girl and her but i like
to start by discussing the relationship of cooperate with one of his predecessors namely kronecker
so help us early work in algebraic geometry and algebraic number theory was strongly influenced
by that of kronecker but as is well known but was very critical of chronic
methodological prescriptions for mathematics
and in fact it was programme can be seen as an attempt to do battle
with chroniclers own terms and the situation was was was very colourfully described by violence
obituary hopper
and the copy past so you know people indulge me and let me read it
so while rates
when one inquires into the dominant influences acting upon hilbert in his formative years
one is puzzled by the peculiarly ambivalent character his relationship to kronecker
dependent on him he rebels against
chronicles work is undoubtedly of paramount importance for hilbert in his algebraic period
but the old gentleman in berlin so it seemed to help used his power and
authority to stretch mathematics upon the procrustes the embedding arbitrary philosophical principles and to suppress
such developments as the not conform
a late echo of this old feud is the polemic against prowess intuitionism with which
the sexagenarian hilbert opens his first article and nobody knew the mathematik
help would slashing blows are aimed chroniclers ghost whom he sees rising from the grave
but inescapable ambivalence even here while he fights him he follows
reasoning along strictly intuitionistic lines is found necessary by him to safeguard non intuitionistic mathematics
so it it's very very colorful i really like the image of the
albert slashing blows and and chronicles ghost
rising from the sounds like a third-rate hard or something like that
so the relationship between gilbert girl and but it's not nearly as
as dramatic
so i've characterize girls work being firmly in the tradition at albert established and much
but in fact devoted to answering questions that albert himself posed in that regard girl
gives credit where it's due in does not in any way tonight opus influence or
play down the importance of his contribution
so in fact his nineteen thirty one paper and the incompleteness theorems ends with a
remarkably charitable an optimistic assessment with regard to its effect on
o bridge program so he writes i wish to note expressly that the second incompleteness
theorem you know for the formal systems that just considered that these dams do not
contradict helpers formalise the viewpoint
for this viewpoint presupposes only the existence of a consistency proof in which nothing but
finitary means of proof is used and it's conceivable that there exist finitary proofs that
cannot be expressed in the relevant formalisms so good holding out optimism that we might
be able to
developed compelling finitary principles and the man as you go beyond for example set theoretic
within a few years however he seems to have abandoned this view so for example
the lecture and social seminar in nineteen thirty eight
he's much more critical of attempts to salvage her in herbert's original plan to establish
the consistency of mathematics so commenting on and gets since proof of the consistency of
arithmetic arithmetic using transfinite induction up to epsilon not says the following this is the
second quote there
so i would like to remark by the way the against to give a proof
of this rule of inference to note again and try to give a heuristic argument
as to why we should accept transfinite induction that's why not
and even said that this was the essential part of his consistency proof
in reality is not in the true it's not a matter of proof at all
but an appeal to evidence
i think it makes more sense to formulate an axiom precisely and to say that
is just not further reducible
but here again the drive of hope its pupils to derive something from nothing stands
so that's a much more critical assessment notices that is not criticizing hilbert is criticizing
help pupils right but he's he's he's
you directly criticizing attempts to sort of formalized health help programme as it was originally
in later years one finds him generally very critical of planets methodology for example in
a letter he wrote to how long in nineteen sixty seven
he blamed the failure of failure of school to extract the completeness theorem from his
results of nineteen twenty three he blamed the failure on the intellectual climate at that
time so did his schooling came very close to two proving the completeness theorem feed
only just thought to state essentially the pieces were all there
and his what goals as he says the blindness or prejudice whatever you may call
it logicians is indeed surprising but i think the explanation is not hard to find
it lies in a widespread lack at that time of the required epistemological attitude towards
metamathematics and toward non finitary
so addition they just missing because they don't have the right attitude
and he goes on to say non finitary reasoning in mathematics was widely considered to
be meaningful only to the extent to which can be interpreted are justified in terms
of finitary metamathematics so there is again trying to i think these faces roughly characterizing
helper tradition and then he says you know that this for the most part has
turned out to be impossible in consequence of my results and subsequent subsequent work
in his remarks we went out of his way so despite the fact that
as i have said almost all of his proofs in logic or explicitly explicitly finitary
it comments to how long good one out of his way to emphasise the
quote the objective is to conception of mathematics and metamathematics in general and of transfinite
reasoning in particular was fundamental to my other work in logic
OK so of course by representing france finding methods with an explicit formal systems you
could always able to make use of such reasoning while maintaining the planetary significance but
it's interesting that later in his career what is playing up are the transfer methods
and sought to downplay the
the importance of the finitary metamathematics stance
let's is sort of a few
yes a few months later in a follow-up letter your your repeated the claim
so this is again this is the correspondence between kernel and how why so few
months later he repeated the claim that would have been practically impossible delivers results without
and i'm just an objective this conception
going down w two starting in nineteen going down to so i go
four-and-a-half before it's zero
w four starting every starting to accelerate to so i can one
so when x to y equals one here
w formulas are owners and that's the first one day zero so w four should be my leaving variable
if x two is my entering variable
how do that just a second let's look over here i could have chosen this woman i'm not going to
if i did this one i would have only these to look at so the fore and three here
we're at five going down the radio format which is zero after one and a quarter
after x four gets up to one recorder quarter this and i'm going down every
three so x four cruelty-free befor w two because there are so i would pick
x forty by entering variable
then w one be my leaving variables was in this one or r this one scientific this one
the algebra
i think you get all the
do we just described without actually doing it
i want put x two on the left so i would just take this equation here right next to
and the last hundred to x to the side bring w four outside divided by two
rearranges that equation but then i have to eliminate x to
from all these equations up here
by doing
gaussian elimination type
steps here for example to develop next to
the first this role here
i have a plus two here in the minus to here so if i took
this role and andw w forward to it so w one plus w four r
and at all these things that will be
plus two is seven
minus three
plus minus one
this goes to zero now
which is good i want to get rid of x two in this equation
but plus w four also attracted before but then in this slide
and similarly go across here and i get i update all these coefficients which very simple
just taking
this coefficients make it the sign robert something like this coefficient gets updated by taking
this time this the divided by that's
something very simple like that
but anyway because arithmetic is very funny this little
java application that doesn't of forming so when i click this button it doesn't arithmetic
i believe that's the seven and that's the minus one that i mentioned when i added w
fore announced attracted over there's minus w four appearing there are
divided by the two and that's why we see that one-half anyway the pivot told us all the arithmetic correctly
the objective function was zero to start with and now it's too
it's going up
we're trying to maximize
end although not optimal yet because this new dictionary
the solution associated with it is not optimal because
x forums a positive coefficient and if i
increase x four from
i can make further improvements in the objective function
that's what i wanna do next so i do the same thing that i just
did i look through here i have
don't look the ones are going down so there's a minus three and minus four r and
these don't have to worry about
so seven going rate one hundred three seven going down donor fore
that's the one that will have zero first so w two is my leaving variable effects force my entering variable
so i just click on this little button here
and it doesn't have it
and i've done
you can always check
if you're right
o i
my volume is too low
if you so the bounded the biologist for making
assertions if you make an incorrect assertion like power so this is
i get bart simpson none bart simpson
calling me a loser
somebody else's play
it was me
all right
there is the simplex methods
there are some issues that we have to discuss with you yes
there are some issues we have discussed
some problems are unbounded the answer is infinity
and how
how hard to detect with the simplex methods
here's an example
that's illustrates what can go
so here's
this is a dictionary
so we could take either-or x one to be the entering variable or x three
if we
pick pickaxe
we could do it here
there's been no problem i have a look at the to the three and the
foreign figure out which we believe are wide pay the fine
i'm greedy i go with the one with the largest coefficients so i pick x
one to be my entering variable
and here in this case being really really pays off because of i look down this column here
w one going up iterative five w two is going up iterators are w three
is not changing w four going up w five is going up
there's nothing blocking x one
from going all the way to infinity
and so the problems unbounded
end and that's how the simplex methods detects unbound this
so that's one thing that can go wrong and that's why there's a little button on the tool
i'm gonna show you
different algorithms for the simplex methods over the next couple hours
i one show you the first one
so i haven't shown complete thing because
i should what i should do assume that work
feasible the start with
and i went from being feasible today after that's really only half of what we
have to do is to find a feasible solution
the star with
and so on
that's called on initialisation how do we get started with the first feasible solution
so here's a problem where i have some negative values on the right hand side
end what i'm gonna do about them so these three methods and show you'd today
various ways of addressing the initialization problem or start out with the one show now because it's the simplest
quick and easy to explain but as we
move along a so you ones i think are better
but this is a very simple thing to do modify this problem just temporarily
by subtracting a new variable which are called x zero
decided so do an experiment this year house so
what i'm going to run the panel is initially foster on i have some questions
we are
asked panelists
out that they would like to solicit questions from you
we're going to do is that
technology mediation
so if we could have the
screen on you'll see yeah the page it's going to be displayed
throughout so append own
if she goes smooth on your way but i will device
kdd thirteen panel dot back chand dot
please by the way if you have a system with three d
please use the three jiri
because there are very limited number of ip addresses available in
in this room so you can get your ip address pleased that force
when you go so the landing page for the link to set up the top there
you you'll see one veins
so you click on to the panel events
that will take future what's displayed they are
at the top most popular questions foster i have ceded the system with
a large number of questions so if internet falls of the company the clean nobody can
one problem
you i going to lead soon provides some sort of identifies asking for identify and optional
once you feel that even you'll see this you can ask a question up the top
so post questions up the top
in the non questions wrong isla top and some other get displayed yeah
if you scroll down please scroll down just say
all questions they in down the bottom
and if you click on that apple down arrows on the side
you can put a the for or against questions and the most popular ones will
wrong rise to the top
so without further ado
let's get launched and i'm going to get the first start question to asama
so some you're very successful
research for
your also very successful s microsoft in industry
what are the first night you leave all of s
in order to launch first startup
i don't know if you ask my family at that time they would have said
these crazy lost
know the real driver is
the biggest factor is probably curiosity
have you know seeing startups happened wondering what the world is about if you're just doing
research just pure data science
but then the second
and third factors which are just as important
number to
is you really want to see impact of your work
you really want to seal works spread faster
and you always get to a degree where it could only have
so much influence from a platform whatever that got from as microsoft with a wonderful huge
but it has its limitations
and of course the third one is
unlimited upside
right so
if if you really do a good job if you really have a product that
people want out there
then this guy's element and there's nothing nothing as as exciting as that
so what the biggest surprise says
well i mean now now that i've got a few startups it's no longer surprise but at the time
look nothing nothing goes like you plan
it's always going to need more money
take longer time
you go through so or i went through some very very very dark times
you know you have to
know every good company has to go through a cycle where you have to lay off employees new
you face as zero cash balance and
the world looks really dark and then
somehow things work out and everything
comes together
through sheer will power
but i think
you know the biggest surprise now that i would say having done if you start ups
still surprises me
is no matter how how many times you do it
and how many times by a lecture
about you know every month i give a lecture about sixty entrepreneurs
and one of the lectures is about
mistakes to avoid when you do start up
and i'll just share with everyone
with every startup
and up doing the same mistakes over and over so f that's surprise which is down
both that question
so i have a question for or that sort of along the same lines i
think we know that there are a lot of academics in you know in the audience in your
you had a nice cushy job as a professor and
you know doing your research know why why the world would you
go off and do this what does it add to your life as an academic
be involved in founding
it's a lot of work
so let me quickly give to answers i think one is that in academia
once we've figured out how to survive we realized that we want
or have an impact
and engines like google scholar for you to back from the size here
is one way to quantify just how little impact we're having right
some my papers are cited maybe a few times here and there but fear one maybe not
at all and then when you click on the citation actually see what they said it becomes clear
that i read the paper
yeah like put paper on exit list papers out exit through my if i was lucky
so for me i felt like
how to have an impact teaching as a research as a but but found that
creating something that people love the first thing created where i have that kind of
relationship with with customers was better crawler or search anybody physically remember better crawler
yeah i think yeah
most of your to this is you know before for the was google such
so i think one way to have an impact was was a big deal for me
and then doing it for a while i realized that
academia as kind of like playing ridges it's
it's cerebral it's it's challenging it's fun
but startups is like playing poker red
or more is satisfaction more stake
like some was saying although
i don't have ever believed in a limited upside but there is severally higher
higher stakes
side actually love the ability to to do both
and you feel like
there from the perspective academic there are
particular costs
but ought to be taken into account for somebody just jump into doing a
as you're asking is their cost to the user professor to start so
often explain how
well done some research a very in
how to make suggestions on how to do this link prediction
and back when you're in a way i we looked at a number of the
social networks that they had and we look at you know what's the probability of
friendship as a function of distance so
now it is about how we found is that most of the new edges defined
for independent friends people there are two hops away
so all of these graphs showing how many friendships were created as a function of
distance so this
x x is now these is the number of hops
the two people were part before they are connected by the set
so little to see but all these only what similar log scales
so there's something like an order of magnitude between two thousand three so
by far the majority of french going to people their friends of friends
and this
becomes even more dramatic when normalized to the fact that there are many many more
people three hops away into absolutely right you have something like a hundred thirty square
friends of friends and then another factor of one
one for that and
of course there is overlap and that approximately and so
this is good from the point of view because already under very something like seventeen
and so if you had to go any further to generate you cannot you get
into an astronomical numbers
so there's only one and all the in this book in or not too surprisingly
it follows the same
it's on work as in these other social networks by far the most of the
edges are planning two friends of friends
that brings us to this so idea problems which is here we have this source
notes and we have all that person's friends and then we have all the friends
of friends and would like to do is figure out what
his friends of friends and the actual average is something like forty thousand enough to
leave it as an exercise to think why it's so much larger than hundred thirty
it's all of those forty thousand friends of friends which ones are my most likely
become friends with the weight on the front but
and so the challenge is one of scale something out you know how to do
this for five million users times forty thousand friends of friends
and then also the machine learning challenges now you know what the right demographic in
our features are
to do this problem
so if you to do something simple so with a good thing to do would
or just to look at the number of friends in common sense
make sense since this is not the intuition that if you have many friends in
common with the person you probably know them somehow
the the first is true and so this is a graph showing the probability of
friendship as a function the mutual friend and then the
because of very quickly again it's on log log scale this time but see you
can see that going from one to ten friends going up by
in order to magnitude or so and the time you get two hundred fans your
over a thousand times more likely to
and finally make fun connection and
so that's a good start but we can actually
do much better by building more sophisticated features and doing a lot of machine learning
so just to give one example
and in the end i think there's a lot of them in this genre
so here's
this is this user's and use this to find a friend and there's some people
some in the media is
switch to make
two different and so all these edges have some annotations on the right and in
particular we think about the ages
and so
this is a serious ongoing fourteen years old this is very new it's only available
and would like to do is use the information in the new edges are somehow
they receive higher weight
so if you think about why this might be
well you have your friends from a few years ago in high school that you've
never seen sensor nets are still in your friend list but it's very unlikely that
you're going to be friend become friends with one of your old high school friends
new friends for instance use are living somewhere far away
and so it turns out that the time stamps and it is very important for
doing the job
and so we can sort of the features that take into account
by using these delta so this is one example where we sum over all the
intermediate so some of these two people
and we come up with some formulas that you know decreasing with time so in
this case we just multiply
these two times together and inverse them
and then maybe think
think some intuition from pagerank where
every node to distributes its influence equally
and if an intermediate node has five thousand friends you should be able to us
give people influenced all those five thousand people
so we'll do something like divided by
the person's degree
and it turned out in practice for whatever reason about buried degrees
i don't want to give the impression that this is
sailing all of but this is just sort of should give you a flavor of
the features that we can build with this rich
does that we have
let me give you a high-level system overview of how all the fences that things
are made based
so the first step is the you know this very user and it comes in
the system which goes in does all this from the friends figures out who does
forty thousand people are there are potential candidates
generative under features were so simple things like the number of mutual friends
what complicated things like this sort of time weighted mutual friends that talked about
but then also demographic features so things like the age of both of the other
sources are in and
the ages of all people cannot
and things like that
that goes into some machine learning system
and for this we just use sort of relatively simple off the shelf
approach to by
decision trees
and that produces some predictions for all those people so all of the friends of
friends get some support
now of course we want to show you the same two people every time you
can say
so we need to do something
you know and every impression every home page view to show you the best
pair suggestions and
the first two steps are relatively expensive so we don't do them now on every
page load i said well there is cash so the top fifty and then when
you can say well we ran all those fifty people using something much simpler machine
learning model
and that gives us the real time series prediction where we combine these stories with
for instance the impression counter so how many times you've seen to suggestions on the
last day
OK so i mean for almost the entire
the lights
is being done
that means that
i know
he sort of also if will know what you see is what you see that
there is data mining machine learning operations
elevation is one them
even distributed across all the last but we don't know yet
by by
time is running around
this is a very
after the fall of this
and the situation this is you know the and
this is almost anything stabilize
nine five in amsterdam
and this is the of of the data mining
you want to learn a lot about what belongs to what are the points race
so one of us so you can see this kind hard for me to stop
are going to
so much so that's a good times all the other things
actually this accuracy was
other easy for example the of reason you say you know this activity is going
to say
and you can look at it and you also see this
you can get a pretty high
my name's
well i want to show you here is if you are not covered by the
see a lot something red
i believe that we are producing using these messages
but a few
can we decide to it
i really enjoyed reading this blah
they are
whereas red one the
ninety three is on the third column
this is what is
and so on
OK i see you are
in ICML each time
so i go down all these concepts of
what about the
the first one is the first one he
i think the
which one that's
sigmod vldb
these are the conference you can see
as i already so high that was furious after reaching again as you can see
here it is the only way to mark that don't worry which ones when i
was young
you it which you don't
it's hard to say it i have to say it's like i conference which it
asserts that makes sense
hello everybody only going over on five
the high winds i
four followed by but there is also some data-mining something on it
it's almost everywhere estate so that's why CIKM conference is not sure which suffer loss
but it's sort of like
people need to raise
but he said
can you know which ones they found the this one day it's
b memory bank everything
we write the words we conferences we ran
what are the ones that come from the viewers so database database system they for
a system for the management of the relational