and mutual funds
and they laid
i'll after of undersea overland
fibre optic cable
i don't tell this crowd about fiber-optic cable
it's the gift that keeps on giving
because once it's in the ground
all you have to do is keep improving those which is at each end and
new like more and more capacity
and basically the goal of the massive glass fiber-optic cable
allowed suddenly more people in more places to communicate
virtually for free
never before in the history of the planet
so that's really is what the netscape flat was all about the third flatness simply called workflow
and workflow is simply my
catch off the software and all the standards
then allowed work flow
everything from microsoft word microsoft not mean told proprietary software that you're all right and
work on in your daily work
now again you go back to a mighty probably in the sometime in the eighties
you know the admissions department probably running microsoft's bookkeeping department was running novell
both departments are much more efficient because
they had computers
applications that connect applications
now a lot of applications still don't connect applications we certainly know that's
but over the nineties there was a revolution in software that's connected a lot more applications
with a lot of
more other applications
and the net result of that it revolution
from middleware right all kinds of transmission protocols
the net result is there
is that people
are able to work together with other people
on more stuff
than everbefore
when my applications
can work with your applications
virtually that we don't have to think about it
it means that we can work together like never before
and this i would argue some point in the mid nineteen nineties was what i
would call the genesis moment the flat world
because when you take the netscape revolution people able to connect with people
over a network like never before
and then you take the revolution in software more and more applications connecting to more other applications and everbefore
what we created
willy nilly
was a global platform
form multiple forms of collaboration
suddenly more people
could collaborate and connect
on more stuff
than ever
before in the history of the world
and that's to me was the genesis moment
for the flattening the world
now the next six latinas
are the new forms of collaboration that's sprung from this platform
and if come back to flatten the world even more
go through them quickly the first courses outsourcing
outsourcing is just a new form of collaboration
empowered by this platform of people the people and application the application now a mighty
if it wants to get outsource the whole bookkeeping department in north boston north dakota
or north bong galore of this platform
these one would be almost equally easy
outsourcing a new form of collaboration
the next to form of collaboration is offshoring ability to around data outsourcing is built
from white to ke offshore is built around when china joins the world trade organization
which takes offshoring to a whole new level now i take my factory from canton ohio
and they move in the canton china
and integrated into my global production system of short
there are new form of collaboration is open sourcing
open source to me
is a it's open source is actually a new form of collaboration
it's a bunch a geeks like half review sitting at home
working on the linux operating system which today is fifteen percent the global awareness market
brazil just announced a couple months ago it's converting the brazilian government
until the next
this is a whole new form of
collaboration obviously and innovation
and you know i mean how it's like to be microsoft's housing bill gates
how would you like to be the same
model is that any time anyone challenges u
to undercut them on price
and from
it's hard to be free
it's hard to beat free it's hard to beat a bunch a greek city at
home writing the next operating system are the next
microsoft word or adobe acrobat for free
some doing it because they hate microsoft's
let's be honest many doing it because they microsoft
that's a question whether it be an open source movement if they work
and many others do it for all the reasons you described understands best which is the peer reviewed science
looking this algorithm
idea about one
what is that's this is so cool you try this
but whatever reason they're are doing it is the only crowd in america who left the lot i
i don't know
he was that there was talking about
but for whatever reason they're doing it
this to me is a whole new form of collaboration firefox and firefox here's a
web browser produced by nineteen year old stanford along with a twenty four year old
and new zealand
never met yet
andy on one day in one month excuse me is downloaded ten million times takes
five percent of microsoft's explores market in month
so this is an incredibly powerful new form of collaboration
and the open university that mighty is doing in which i had the pleasure learning
all about today is just another expression this
and it's gonna be i think an incredibly powerful forward innovation
on the flatter the world against
the fourth foremost
collaboration on
i call supply chain supply chain is what walmart
and that's designed a global supply chain down to the last at some other efficiency
so you take an item off-the-shelf and walmart in brookline and others immediately made in change in china
wal-mart were a country it would be china largest trading partner the
had canada and australia
and of my friend you see sheffi use here has taught me
something about supply chains and and he is a nice saying which step
making stuff
making stuff that's easy
supply chain that's really hard
think about walmart
this is this
what's the biggest company in america
and they don't make anything
just a supply chain in counterfeit last at of efficiency
a whole new form of collaboration
the fifth new form of collaboration article in sourcing in sources with dupuy yes that's
you know the people in the funny brown trucks and the funny brown shorts
if you think all they are doing
is delivering packages
u are
not paying attention
there's a little hint what they are up to its on the side the trucks
now it simply says your world synchronized
you know we can
well it
this friendly data representation clustering kind of similar sets and we would like to have
some sort of brought in a bill to quantizer of compressed sensing
the sort of intuition here intuition is the following
we would like to
and make sure that similar or to have similar right
and that's the situation applies throughout all classification clustering and imprisoned but what the similar
in sound to this one and this one is some of the time
not necessary to look at
but this
this one and this one quite similar
so so what's the notion of similarity so he actually is arguably was the geometry
comes and one can actually say that
so just to assumptions can be made about this
and two assumptions can be made the following
one what one may call the manifold assumption
and now they've one michael in cluster assumption and other examples of what
what do you know what they make this
OK so let me start with the
now suppose
the simplest classification and that was the point
and i want to build a classifier right classifierx from blue
well i fall
we all
many of us agree
this is a good classifier
why is this a good classifier well simple classifier and somehow it seems to be
the simplest possible
the changes slightly suppose i'm doing you there are two labels points you hear about
the underlying data
like this
those artists
so i changed the problems like i tell you all the light and those are
now what's it good classifiers
again i don't know
you may agree disagree with me but
i say
most reasonable people like agree that this one is about
course it's
so why is it that all lists are somehow intuitively this is that and why
is this
well because i actually believe that somehow
this article
and that's that to separate groups and the classification foundation go
so clearly the geometry of the data on its own interest intuitive that effect on
notion of similarity quite a bit
now let's think about manifold assumption out
i want to classify this work so well how the classify this point
so if this is all i have
i would think blue i can do several arguments why this should be too
right now for example it's the closest point to the blue points well if linear
classification this is on the same side the thing and so on
however now it actually looks like this is all this
well no
it's a
actually seems to be more likely to direct why i intuitions are falling
it's not the distance which makes them much different in distance along the shore sort
of genetic distance which makes a lot of
please please ask questions and so on if you disagree with
OK so this one might want to make a manifold assumptions sort of in the
foreman usually look at the geodesic distance
not them understand and then the distance is not very important agendas distances more
in one
well atleast administration
here is another thing here is the cluster assumption again if you just have to
point probably because black and blue right side to the new cluster that well all
like this
you can think of this being a mixture of gaussians
the box here
now there
the first question is how do you choose the examples
on each of these rounds
and here we will do is what just concentrate on the hardest examples
OK you always will be focusing on the hardest examples and hardest means examples which
have most often been misclassified by the previous
rules of thumb that you've already computed and that second question is how do you
take all these rules of thumb and combine them into a single prediction rule
and there will just be something really simple which is to take a majority vote
or weighted majority vote of the rules of thumb that we computed
so that in the challenge
is how
boosting works of course and going to go into more detail
boosting is a general method of converting these rough rules of thumb into a highly
accurate prediction rule has a said it does have more technical definition which is often
overlooked in much of the literature
boosting begins with an assumption any learning algorithm any learning method needs to begin with
some kind of assumptions
of some kind and really the study of boosting starts with
kind of the difference
kind of assumptions so we start with this assumption which says that we're assuming
that we have available to us a weak learning algorithm
this procedure that i was talking about for deriving
rough rules of thumb
and that's the procedure which can consistently find classifiers what i was calling earlier rules
of thumb from now on i'll be calling them weak classifiers
which are at least slightly better than random guessing so we always do a little
bit better than random guessing
so you have a two class problem
and you guess
at random you make predictions are random you'll be right exactly half the the time
so we assume that this procedure is a little bit better than fifty percent it
can come up with classifiers which have accuracy maybe fifty five percent
OK so this is called the weak learning assumption and and it's the starting point
for the study of boosting algorithms
so given that assumption of boosting algorithm is one which given
sufficient data whatever that means can provably construct
a single classifier
with very high accuracy
maybe ninety nine percent c start with all these weak classifiers with that are close
fifty five percent saying whose sum up to accuracy ninety nine percent
OK so that's a very high level introduction to boosting
and so what i'm actually going to talk about in this tutorial
on going to start with some very brief background on boosting some very brief historical
and they're going to talk about the basic boosting algorithm that we're going to look
at which is the adaboost algorithm and the core theory surrounding adaboost
then i'll talk about some the other ways of thinking about boosting
and then finally we'll get to some experiments applications and extensions
and at some point will take a break
OK so some very brief historical background
boosting has its roots
in a learning model called the
valiant or PAC learning model
OK called the PAC learning model
so in this model
it's a very simple straightforward model of learning
you seem that the learning algorithm has access to random examples which are coming from
some unknown arbitrary distribution and one of the important things is that this distribution is
so there are at least two kinds of learning algorithms that you might be interested
in in this model the first is
strong PAC learning model
so strong PAC learning model
sorry strong PAC learning algorithm
is an algorithm such that for any
distribution of these random examples
with high probability one it's given polynomially many examples and it usually also required to
run in polynomial time
confined to a classifier with
arbitrarily small generalisation error
OK generalisation error is just you're expected test error
so you can drive the
air raids
on the test set
as small as you want in the strong PAC learning model
in the weak PAC learning model or weak PAC learning algorithm is an algorithm
that has all of these same requirements
but the generalisation error doesn't have to be
you don't have to be able to drive the
generalisation there to be an arbitrarily small number
the generalisation are only needs to be a little bit better than random guessing which
means it has to be
just a little bit better than
half and the two class
pac by the way stands for probably approximately correct
because with high probability one a classifier which is approximately correct
so current and valiant were the ones who asked
does weak learnability imply strong learnability
in other words if you have a week
pac learning algorithm
can you efficiently converted into a strong PAC learning algorithm
so the first boosting algorithm with one that i came up with that
a long long time ago
so this was kind of this complicated recursive boosting algorithm where
what do what you do is you would you've got this week learner this week
learning algorithm and you would run it three times on three multiply distributions
which would give you the small but
a significant boost in accuracy and then you just apply that procedure recursively
a year later you are trying to form up with a really nice algorithm called
the boost by majority algorithm which is provably optimal
in a very strong sense
but both of these algorithms had strong practical drawbacks there were some
early experiments with them but they were
basically limited practicality these algorithms
so the algorithm going to focus on in this talk is called the adaboost algorithm
which has which has
the boosting property but also has very strong practical advantages over the earlier algorithms
and since it was introduced there's been a whole lot of work on adaboost which
i obviously not going to talk about
and all that
so that's a little historical background so
let's get to the adaboost algorithm itself so in this talk part
going to talk about the basic algorithm which means the adaboost algorithm and
there were really core important most important theory in my view
of adaboost
o thing going to talk about for sale introduced the algorithm
and far more heated discussion
but that one example so
under the CPC setting if i had impressions
and by becomes the expected number of clicks
and this times the cost per click is the revenue
but the cost cost per click
it's been determined by some sort of option
and then the CPS
i have one extra factor and it was is this is the conversion
what this is is
what is the probability that a user was clicked on me as will actually go
on and perform the action
and this becomes
very top big and say because
this is not something that you can look because the action the user performs and
it's very different and what it is
actions that the user is doing on some other website but you have no control
so it's very hard to estimate the conversion
let's at is actually quite interesting
so optimizing for CPA or whatever you want to see it becomes very hard problem
for the have in this is why
it because be the model the revenue model that used CPM CPC
and slowly
are moving towards CPM or but is still
it states
is one slide which
essentially put of this context
suppose i wanted to maximize revenue
under CPM or cost per impression what i just want to maximize the number of
which means that i want to maximize the website traffic
on the of my access
and the CPC more
i need to maximise the number of clicks not just impressions so this means i
have many impressions
so high in the same attractor
blast actually be relevant so that
the users are induced to actually click on that
so both website traffic and that the elements
and the CPM or
we need not only to actually
but the advertiser's landing page quality on some matters it and was very messy very
quickly then the user will probably not all that and in fact the page
it's probably just leave that
and so
the network will need some estimate of not only will the user condescension
will the user actually like the landing page of that it's which becomes an even
more complicated question
but on the other hand from the advertisers for you
gentlemen increases as we move from CPM CPC
CPA and the
extreme skiing if the action if if i paid only for certain action and action
is that the user must find the problem that is just bunch of because it
guarantee that for every
o dollars that's been amazing and make some extra
by selling products
and correspondingly
the price is that is willing to be
increases as we go from CPU to CPU
but again the difficulty of picking the best at spatial also increases from CPM CPC
so the job at it becomes much harder as see
and typically CPM CPC at the smallest
so we have looked at the revenue model essentially how these places are determined
how much use and what's in it
what does this advertising
one from the users are from the
the second question of the second dimension of online advertising is
and what's it into a show my at what hope we expect users to interact
with it
and this we have to display advertising
on that
and sponsored search and essentially asking what we should do this what is the aim
of me
what they want
the simplest is that of display advertising
this is an an example of that is from new york times it's a health
and then on the other hand that netflix that says well now you can try
and fix fifty feet
so netflix doesn't really have anything to do do with health is anything that see
one of six once in this case
is for users as many users as possible
that metrics is going to promotion
tries to flee
well if you don't know about metrics i'm netflix i exist you can get movies
from me and so
so netflix simply find the
there that i existed surprise increase in random
and in this particular case one netflix wants is that the actually what should will
show that as many users as possible
we've seen the last time
that using
the islands of virus
if you have the current
going straight into the blackboard perpendicular to the blackboards
we get the magnetic fields
and the distance
the magnetic field
and you mentioned the the circle
b here
and that the strength of the magnetic fields
he calls you zero
times i
divided by two pi are
if you
walk around this circle
just walk around
and you carve up this circle
in little elements dl
calculate the closed circle integral
so the close circle
of b
adults dl
so everywhere locally
you've got to be ways
the album being yellow exactly the same direction everywhere
there you will find that is obviously is b
i could buy are
but the times two pi are
he calls also
new zero times by i
this the al here
has nothing to do with this dl you don't confuse the two
this is the l
is a small amount of length in the y goes into the blackboard which carries
the current
this is the l
is simply
you're dl when you walk around
and why
it doesn't matter what distance you walk around you always get new zero times i
you see the right in front of your eyes because b is inversely proportional
two are
and it was and here
who first to recognise
you don't have to walk around in a circle
to get the answer museo arrived
but that you could walk around
crew could pass as long as it is a closed class
something like this
and now
we have here the local b
which of course is perpendicular
this radius
and you you have your local dl
and now you go around
circle of any path doesn't have to be historical
doctor dl
that now
becomes new zero times i which is known as an MP is law
and i then is often
given index
and closed
the current which is enclosed by their past
it is actually easy to prove this using the o
and survives formalism
this is almost the third maxwell's equations we already had two out of four
it almost number three not quite going to amend it in the future
what is ill-defined a little bit in this
equation is
what we mean by and closed
i'm going to define and also uniquely
that there was never any misunderstanding
if i have a
close classifying chosen that's as i walk
i have to attached to that closed loop
the surface an open service that mandatory
you can make it flat that's why
you are free to choose it
you can also make it
one of the plastic bags open year put your hands in your
like i had any services fine you must touch
look a surface so you have some placid you could be walking
and and this would be perfectly fine open
over the surface
b flat
but it could also be open
don't like that
and now
i can define uniquely
what it means
what i mean by this i closed
because if not i have the current
go through this surface and pokes out here
then i have current
penetrating the surface and that is uniquely defined
and if i have another one coming in for the surface
four i two
this is penetrating
that surface
by convention
if you go
we follow the same notation that we had before the right-hand corkscrew notation
the connection between magnetic fields and currents
if you go around
clockwise seen from this side
so you go clockwise
then i one as i have here
new equation have to be larger than zero
i two
it is then smaller than zero
but if you decide to go counter-clockwise
which is perfectly fine
and please law
doesn't all dictating which direction you have to
march around
then i one
it would be
negative and then i two
positive so we follow the
right hand corkscrew
and so if you want to amend now
p is well to do me a favor
but you don't do books to favour because all the books use the word and
i would like to see this
replaced by
penetration the penetration of the surface of the current that is uniquely defined
the current enclosed by the loop
is ill-defined
because we possible when we apply MP's law
real try
to find easy passes around circle sometimes sometimes rectangles
and since you are free to choose any surface that you would attach
if you can get away with it use the flat surface
but you can always get away
with a flat surface
so to wrap rapid recipes as follows you
choose you closed loop
any help is allowed
around sixty people here were interviewed work shadow that are still in the surveys
which gave us a bunch of requirements for both use cases
so i'm not going to go through the use cases to the requirements but
so the climbers are mainly stay around context modelling and
process modelling and the second requirements are about how do we streamline the proposal development
process with an very the technologies that are being developed in active so i last
here was to sort of matter whether the area requirements and what is being developed
in active and to assure that there is
that's what is being developed in active is about it for the business for business
so i talked about requirements gathering
this figure shows
what activities are we doing in scope of the project so we the input to
the system is of course the requirements i just mentioned the second input is data
so we concentrated then on data collection because this is the necessary part so should
the the process modelling and mining the context modelling and mining and the children from
knowledge integration and sharing which are all part of active actually have enough data to
produce valid results a second that thing with that is that some of the requirements
actually were not from the requirements were for context analysis application which means users wanted
finer granularity content they wanted different this ways of displaying results they wanted to search
for experts so we developed this content analysis components and reinvented all of that in
our prototypes with the end goal to users and validates technologies
having delayed time between switching my slides i'm sorry
i would say
the second activity was data collection and we started off with modifying our largest develop
see bill application which is an application for search and browsing of large environments
which i'll show demonstrate a bit later we modified it cynically log lots of actions
we don't log only downloads of document but we log also what the user clicks
on what he browses through what he downloads and
we collected around seven hundred thousand records of the user activities then the second type
of information that we we provided its skills so our employees are encouraged to make
this listings of skills because this is what the company uses to find them and
to staff them projects so it's in the interest of this structured database of skills
so we had that and the third source of information that were provided was our
common our document repository and what's very interesting about this repository is that it's accompanied
by metadata this metadata is actually manually designed is based on nineteen optics on and
here on the right-hand side you can see some of the categories and the values
of the categories so pattern of information would be what industries is not document belong
to what offering is it what type of document would be business functions are trying
to accomplish so easy for learning for HR outsourcing is for accounting this is
today there are people in accenture who actually higher
i was main job is actually to upload these documents and to label them based
on the in the tsunami
so all of this was provided and then in the second year of the project
we realised out of work with context mining and michael speaking about that i believe
on monday we realize that it's not still not enough data to get useful context
so we added
some log information from our official enterprise search engine so and this is there is
around seven point two million actions over two years now these actions were not as
finely grained as we managed to do with our sable application but this means it
was lot of data to do something to to find context to do work in
the project
but the
OK constant
still out
the the first part of that we could activated sable
and it integrates a number of components it integrates those content analysis components of about
mentioned before which are basically expert graphics search and in it integrates context modelling context
mining companies discovering and miseries asian switching so
i'll go firstly through the content analysis components is is the first part of the
first of components that we have developed in the first year so some of you
who are here for the first active summer school might have heard about them but
i'll just go quickly and then i'll talk a bit about the context modelling for
the accenture case
what we found out from my requirements is that no matter what process i users
doing what tasks they're doing their daily work they rarely need whole documents what they
need is to find people
who have maybe worked on similar projects with they need sometimes in the find clients
for which we have done similar where vendors
who might be used for training or for whom we have useful similar work is
that people so all of this and this this reusable pieces of information
that this is what the islands are searching for
in order to provide some of this we have developed two components one is around
expert search and the other one is about graphic search explaining in while of it
but they are still the expert search is actually
the cosine
of omega t
and i'm going to use my same transmitter for that it's going to be a
call this wire one
and i call this y two
regarding the wave
o sinusoidal that going to propagate
in these wires and what's going to happen is not what you think
first of all
there cannot be any electric field
in the why is because it's a conductor
so the electric field
in this direction
not exist so there is no potential difference from here to there
but if there is any potential difference is going to be between here and there
if i take this wire
and i make a cross section of the wire
this is why along
and this is why i the any moment in time
as the voltage wave
this may be
that is the role of us
and this will be negative
that's the role of s
and the electric field lines that go like this
so that means if this is at this moment in time positive and negative
and the electric field in this direction between these two ideas
not along the wire between the lines
but then of course also going to be
locations with this in mind in this class
and then what this was this is minus
so on an electric field is in this direction and electric fields in this direction
so the potential difference between the EU is positive
the potential difference between you and here negative because it's integral you don't know
potential difference
minus v two
is going from one to two of
so if the electric field is in this direction this has a higher potential than
if it is in this direction this has a lot of potential so this is
how this
voltage wave propagates
so thirty field is between the y is not along the wires
is only electric
feel potential between the two wires
the oscillating surface charge densities
in order to be those boundary conditions as the voltage pulse by so it's positive
at this moment but later in time it will be negative and this will be
and all that moves with the speed of light
and then also oscillating surface current densities
i j of s
let's assume no
i call this equals zero
i'm going to short is out
so i'm simply reporting there
a wire
totally shorted out
that means there cannot be any potential difference between here and there
because i make the resistance ohmic resistance and zero
and what does that mean
going to make drawing here
otherwise i think it becomes too close
so here is the situation
the end of the
o lines
by the way is there
at the end
shorted out
if it is shorted out it acts like a conducting walls just
like which will be discussed before
there cannot be any potential difference reunion because the e field in this direction must
be zero
so you get a similar situation that the reflectivity
is minus one the the mountain comes back
as the value
in the field of inside wall
and the field of the reflected light
delete of
exactly at this location
that means you get standing waves
so that means this is now notable line
everywhere in this line the electric factor will always be here with all moments in
but since i got standing wave here incident wave
and reflected wave
right here
there is another
no one
and this distance then
it's one level
and right here
there is another node line
and the electric field here
along this line is everywhere zero but it is not potential difference between y one
and two two-year there's no potential difference here no potential difference here at all moments
in time because it's standing wave
in between
x only takes an integer allies
this is easy when you have to remember
could derail
i don't really know much about x except that it takes on integer values
any suggestions on how i should expand the expectation of x
how many people knows why are
two reasons
expedition something to probability
so i should be looking at something like the probability that
x equals some value x
it would seem like a good thing to to do
what else goes here
well x can be somewhere between minus infinity and that's certainly true
and you have some more
o thing missing here
what is this
it doesn't come out
for any random variable x takes on the value
i need to add in
something here namely
that's the definition of the expectation
the some of things where these
coefficients sum to one
looks an awful lot like
the land that we just heard
we prove that in the finite case it turns out to hold just as well
if you take all
i'm was going to assume that
so i have these alpha these
probabilities is alpha values
to one
therefore i can use this inequality
this is the most
it's right
how help some x equals minus infinity to infinity
the alphas which are probability capital x equals x
for the value for
OK so there it is
here's the lemma
raise the lemma
i cheated by using the
countable version of the lemma
only proving the
the finite case
like in the lecture
this is a lot
now what i'd like to prove some blank space here is that this is the
the summation is the most
you've effects actually people
you max
really looks kind of equal rights got some some probabilities times that almost looks like
the definition of the
thanks but it isn't
to be a little bit careful
as you may have actually we should talk about the probability that f of x
equals the particular value
we can relate these
as follows
it's hard
you can look at each
value f takes on
and then look at all the values can mapped to the
thanks to all the is where f of k equals access
the probability of x equals k
there is another way of writing
the probability that f of x
he calls x
in other words and grouping the terms in a particular way of saying well for
next takes on various values
however me
to you switch
i used to use cases and also
i'm going to call it something else is called this why
switch notation here
accent probability measure the probability that x equals x
so what i really care about is what this f of x value takes on
this just call it why look at all values why the to take on the
and then i look at all the different values of x
where f of x equals y
if i had those probabilities
because these are different values of x the problem but those are some independent events
so this
in some asian will be the probability that f of x equals y
capital tax
it's little y
and then if i multiply that by why i'm getting expectation
the next
think about this these two inequalities
maybe a bit
these are here because these sums are potentially infinite
it's true
OK this proves jensen's inequality so wasn't very hard just a couple aborts once we
have this this powerful
convexity lemma
so we just use convexity we use the definition of x we use convexity that
let's put the inside
and we do this regrouping of terms and we think that's just give facts
is it that when you minimize the l one norm we recover sparse signals and
then i'm going try to draw an analogy so what you have is when you
sort and one problem you recover sparse solution and wise's because what you say that
they have a sparse vector which is here and is sparse because these colonies zero
and this one is not zero and then you take one measurements i'd just make
one measurement is vector and so we all know
from middle school that well this gives equation of a line like this and then
you say
all right well if i were to finance his line point with minimum l two
norm well i would get this thing
which is not good
so in high and low dimensional looks close but in high dimensions the disaster
if i use the l one norm instead so this is the l two ball
as we all know
in one ball is like this as we shown
so if i use the l one norm instead and so what's the point and
is in one
on this line has minimum in one norm while well so well i'm going to
do is i'm going to grow this thing until it becomes tangent
so the point that one ball tangent is this but its tangent at this vertex
inside recovers sparse solution actually
so this i show you that anyone actually sundays example one optimisation works and why
is it it's because the and one ball is very pointy
on sparse vectors for
matrix completion something similar that occurs which is that this now we have the nuclear
ball which is picture is represented by a cylinder
so here you've got to set of two by two matrices which are symmetric because
i can only drawing sometimes membrane drawings three d so here we have three parameters
x y c we have a symmetric matrix and then this which have nuclear norm
less than one
and what happens is that the low rank matrices are extreme points of this convex
and now we have are feasible set which is used dimensional space but it actually
happens to be tangent to this very pointy nuclear ball
because the nuclear bodies pointy at low rank solutions
because this is a very quick
geometric representation of what it is worth because of the point in this fuzzy nuclear
norm or nuclear ball
at low rank solution that all of a sudden there's many where you can have
your a feasible set and maintain this tension property
OK but of course this is not proof and i don't claim that it is
OK so now of course you say well you know you can recover from the
subset of entries can you recover from all the type of information and of course
yes you can
and now by now a whole theory which is being developed to show
very precisely
now you've got information about the matrix not given by
revealing entries but by revealing coefficients so now i give you all the kind of
linear information about the matrix of interest l so i give you inner products of
before was giving you an inner product between the matrix l and e i e
which essentially reveals that i j but now you can say well this matrices don't
have to be
the matrices full of zeros and ones somewhere just pick an element
you can have anything you want
and so
now there's is this general theory of saying well you know now i have linear
information about matrix linear information about a matrix of this kind find among all those
matrices being these constraints that many with minimum l one norm and what i'm trying
to say here is that if i have incoherence between the sensing matrices and the
column space and the row space of the matrix everything should work and indeed it
works and that's we've done a piece of it was then rushed and because of
time maybe i'll skip this part
but really is a big contribution is due to david grows who who explained and
showed exactly what kind of coherence you need anyone one can you expect things to
so i'm not going to go through the detail i'm just going to tell you
that it's available and it's out there
what's interesting about the contribution of the gross is that is the physicist quantum physicist
and when he realizes that there are lots of problems in quantum mechanics that are
matrix completion problem and so i'll just mention what it is
so in quantum mechanics you have a system and quantum mechanically is if you have
a case being one one-half system
quantum mechanically is represented by a matrix which is called the density matrix the problem
is as you know matthew you may not know is dimension in grows very quickly
that the power squad quantum computing grows exponentially in the number of particles you have
and so if you have a system we keep particles you've got dimension which is
expansion of the exponential in the number of particles
so perhaps without going into too too much into details try to explain what people
try to do in this field
so people prepare quantum states
like the prepared quantum systems
and then how do they know
but what they prepare
is what they thought they prepared
how does a measure that what they the preparing the lab is actually what they
thought they prepared they have to take measurements
and what do you do when you take a measurement of a quantum system
it destroyed money modify completely
because you're going have to make a lot of measurements y because the number of
degrees of freedom
is a matrix which is an binds and quite huge and is exponential in the
number of particles
you can have to prepare a lot of quantum states
now a lot of the state that these guys prepare actually low rank or proximity
low rank
so what the theory says is that
and of course i'm here we have made a specific assumption about
how the output interact with the input
ok this kind of cartoon is typical of a discriminative models
where you have the input sort of determining the output
and some kind of sort of to close deterministic fashion
but in general all we could have variables interacting in all
kinds of ways case we could have many variables we could have
arrows going forward and backward and so on
and so you would get a lot more general polity by
drawing models ok are there any questions or comments about this
picture of a sort of this graphical models probabilistic view
but is very quite suspicious
ok so now let's talk a little bit about regular izations from this
kind of perspective ok of of graphical models
so regular decision is a weight of controlling
the bias-variance trade-off in order to obtain a good value of the
trade-off and it essentially sort of getting to the punchline
to blows down to controlling this w here through some kind of
prior ok that is going to help bias inject some bias but perhaps
model way some of the variance ok now what is regular izations usually
look like it looks like this we have initial objective which is jd
of w that's to optimize something on the data either minimize
squared error maximize likelihood or something like this
and we add to it a penalty term ok and this penalty term depends
on the weight vector and the penalty term essentially captures
some kind of intuition that we have about
priors on the hypothesis space what hypothesis are better than others
in the absence of any data and the parameter lambda over
controls the tradeoff so the make lambda the more we
attention to the penalty the loan we make the lambda
less engine to this penalty if we set on that zero then essentially
we just try to optimize performance on the data and we don't
care all about the actual prior on the hypothesis
so used to this this this is called shrinkage in machine learning
we call the regular sation and lambda here is called regulation
musician coefficients and in principle you have
criteria that can help you select as in practice very often
people do cross validation and treat this as a
as a sort of hyperparameter as well
so now let's look a little bit at regular izations for linear models
okay so here we have a linear model we have the error function
and then we have here a term w transpose w
that is what's called l to regular sation or what weight decay
ok so what this is still it basically says that we would like
our weight magnitude to be small
okay because if we emphasize this term and the weight magnitude
is high is going to make things look worse
ok so that's why weight decay ok and the nice thing about this
is that of course here the quadratic term in the front wheels
out the quadratic terms so everything is nice and quadratic
and we can take gradients and we can optimize
things work very well in fact they work very well in closed form
and we get this solution over here where the best weight vector
has basically the same form as before except fight transpose far
has a land times the data d matrix added to it ok or other words
you're adding mass on the diagonal of this five transpose phi
okay that helps to we do things ok helps you with making this a little
bit better or better condition ok and again it's sort of drives
your weights towards zero
and of course if lambda is equal to zero you get exactly the
same solution as for usual linear regression
and if lambda those to infinity then the solution is just going to
go to zero okay so this is called ridge regression there's a
more general class of regularization which actually
can tell you about really called cannot regular sation
that has all this kind of four ok and
the company to grow crops in that
cross look people
two two
factories which so the country can stop them
dependent on imported food and so on
it would be
he was
you will probably get your goals
for example the first the country's people
the bridge the country
the full independence u
o the market they
the great gas who
made more than four
we all know
the european commission for the topic
so we try
he is just as possible
they're not going to go
we know that he
you from
the first of these is x
out of the lake
large complex of let the countries
two grow full or that you don't want to predict
five months ago
south korea
it's stated by
a network of the biggest food companies ball
around fifty percent of all
on the idea
the problem is that we're not going to grow food that we must grow grow
in that land and so on and so forth
even in the countries
when they have to let me usually
they are used for example in some pretty
so i think that
o this seems going on
weak it's a good
that would be the only through
the question is
it should be remained for you say
well lead to more human here and there
or there
one is that we call
weak oppose
which can be solved within the norm for
i think there are
four such
it's not in the field
the first is that you know he's about to go
in this image
i know i know state college
proof from eastern europe countries
state regulation would even want to know the united labor market
he also you know should use the
we try to undermine
because i think it again
no from the
plus you think that if they are to be the short
not all in
i can only imagine you give it a little bit of new
new york new demand
but what
what i think is
market works
competition this
but the threats facing the
with global warming you can say OK let's see if you think that so we
we don't have a chance because if it fails
this article
we have
the problem of
intellectual property and i spoke economists were his
conservative comes in need that
maybe this should be
of those things
everybody thought of
that is not in the body mainly in the very far off
so so-called intellectual property knowledge reached this
four of private property
on the market
the market is becoming irrational
but i think it would be
a b
how can you become twenty years twenty five from the
who is hoping to get some things you all that
when estimating the one
you can also even in my you can see it a
who did what were all this
the problem is
this is the like
there's a lot of other commodities you you know you produced shows that god that
the prices belies not you
you don't know
well for example
you can help in any way
round or connect the price of
windows broken
to some market movements
a lot of economics
i think the
it was
you all
i think
one of
so considering one variable at a time it's it's two dimensional problem that we can
project in one dimension
and if we do so if we project everything onto the age variables
we see that h
reasonably well separates the two populations
if we project here on say wait minute making some arbitrary example
then we see that there is overlap between the two distribution and this variable here
alone by itself is not a good choice
to separate the two population where this variable here is a good choice
this is what would be the result of the univariate feature selection we decide to
pick this variable
throw away this one
but now if you look in two dimensions you can see that
there is about separation of the two populations if you add this variable
this variable
which alone
is irrelevant
when taken with another one
i can help you perform a better separation
now consider the second example
here it is even more dramatic
because now you have two variables that alone
do not separate the data
but when you consider them together
they give you a very good separation of the
even though it's not the linear separation in this case it's the non linear separation
because you have
class is composed of two clusters and their range during this very particular way which
is known you know and as the
chessboard problem it's one of you know the next year machine learning example that's always
quarter because when you're looking projection
you can't separate
the examples
and so
multivariate methods are going to allow us
to identify features that together are predictive but individually or not
we're now posing filters versus wrappers
the main goal is going to be ranking subsets of useful features
the filter approach consistent
considering all the features
putting them into a box called filter out putting some subset of good features and
then using them for making predictions
whereas the wrapper methods consider the features
generates some subset of candidate features
buses them to the predictor
the predictor you know training and we compute the prediction power of the feature subset
and then eventually we guide the search
for a new feature subset and we tried many times until we find an optimum
feature subset
what connects
this problem with the problem of the previous lecture is that there is a danger
if you're considering many subsets of features
it is like we had in the previous lecture one we considered many
learning machines so we considered a highly complex learning machines
the complexity of the learning problem in that case is going to be related to
the number of feature subsets that we're considering our search
so we run at risk of overfitting
in the chapters from the book there are many search strategies that are considered mentioning
here if you just to give you an or a broad overview
there are
so called forward and backward methods so forward selection methods consistent starting with an empty
a feature and progressively adding features backward elimination to start with the full set then
you personally eliminates
and then there's the search where you consider path and keeping all the time kick
and features
there is the generalized sequential forward selection
one and minus square
and landscape features are
i left sorry there's
there is no
the problem in the typesetting here
anyway that it requires
and minus k
two the g choose n minus could you think you can clearly see well training
so more trainings are done each step but fewer steps than in the simple
sequential forward selection
and then there is the PTA methods
so it's
well you you put out
and take away are so you you go for a certain number of steps l
and then you go back through certain number of of
steps and then finally there's the floating search which i think is the most popular
search methods right now for
and what you do is that you are you start going forward or start going
back your search and
you go for it until
you're not improving anymore and then you start going back heard until you not improving
anymore and so on and so forth new oscillates between going forward and backward
in your search
and of course and i didn't mention it but you could also do exhaustive search
so you could generate all possible subsets of variables and invested in them all and
you can do genetic algorithms you can do
and any
type of search you want
the problem being that if you search harder
you're going to incur some complexity penalty
in this graph i'm representing the case in which you have only four features
so these are represented by these four numbers here
and this is the state space of all possible feature subsets
so one means the future is present then zero the the future is absent
well i don't have to run meaning in a nice way and this is able
to around the parameters in
in some interactive way when you you make succession steps you can cannot parameters to
learn the parameters of q SVM so on
so i didn't talk about that i understand that i wanted to to tell you
of course
and i will talk about this tomorrow there is a big
big problem the challenge here
in some problems you have no idea of the k
i would you would like to learn
either in a nonparametric weights we build a function such that
it would be can then all you want to find some to combine different can
and learn to weight
so that there are many world
have been done by a long creating
two so then in one thousand seven for bioinformatics
so steve you are really a lot of stuff to do
we cameras
especially in the case when you want to
before talking about turning can and
we can try to define some applications you can try to define you can cannot
because you know
the data you know if object for instance you know your images
you know your documents and you have some idea what you can do
the first on easy
i would say very simple way
is just to find explicitly the feature map phi
of course if you
if you have feature map phi find sentences indicator for you can then when you
can you can use it and then you can but usually
we really want to benefit from the geometric
and we don't all we got
define very explicitly the feature map
so the second way is to use the building blocks i described yesterday
is only so the closure property so
if you combine to count as you
i have another can then if you took an exponential of again and you have
again and again and so you can of course play with it
as go
there are also
different ways to
to solve this
cameron definition
you can use graphical with that so you can take the data
you can estimate the parameters of a graphical
and then you have what we call fusion camera
it's so weighting factor defines
closing into the parameters of the graphic and that's the way to define canon between
two complex objects
and we have also
also can isolate convolution can they can bayes and syntax
you have a lot of possible
so today i'm going to work to describe
two way of defining canale and i've chosen applications
which we have
document and text mining
and the first one is closely linked to this building block and the second one
is closely to
the fisher king
can we talk a little bit about that
just to what about that if you structured data
your choices are not limited to this but
at least you can use this list
you can make this fish cannot
you can
try to use the syntax of your structure object
and you can also be found for instance if your your data are nodes in
a graph you can use
the family of diffusion can
OK just now and come back so my first example of building again
will be used it with some
implicit structure
so friends so we're going to talk about text
and index to the problem you are you one of the sequence of symbols the
world's but these
sequence is not as
and i was so it's
structure the sequence but more and more of you have an implicit structure
with the world
in fact you have the semantics of the world
okay welcome to lecture number nine
today our main topic is going to be inference inferring parameters for example to do
any science experiment and you want to infer
the parameters
that underlie
these data you've got
but before we do that i want to
o point out to a little gem
information theory that
you may not have noticed
i'd like just a start by
thinking about
the binary erasure channel
what we did in the last couple lectures was re-established shannon's noisy channel coding theorem that says any channel
you can work out its capacity by maximizing mutual information
anne then it's possible to make an encoder and the decoder that communicate reliably over the channel
reliably meaning you can get the error probability as close as you like to zero
but you can always communicated any rate up to the capacity
so what's the capacity of the binary erasure
channel please
i have a quick chat to your neighbour
is a question
all goes all the way over here and just one
there's always two ways you can solve these questions
you can see the
look at the mutual information this way around
people without this way around
and often one way it's easier than ever
so let's to be
binary erasure channel both ways around
how generalize a little bit
so that we're putting in
he zero and be one our pretend we don't know the peopple optimal input distribution
of course have to be symmetric
and i'll call these probabilities
one myself
so if we do it this way the first term
is binary and they are not
and the second term we need to think through all the different ways that could
happen that's a work we need to think about three things
figure out how probable they are then work out what the entropy of x given
why is quite a lot of work except almost all that is easy if you
get a zero you know that
input was a zero so
there's no entropy in case
similarly if there is a one
then the input doesn't have any entropy anymore
it's only a question mark comes out
which happens with probability at
one by by
you still don't know what the input was and you've got no information at all
about what input was he posterior distribution of the input is still
the same as it was when we started said
you know
which is
one minus
maximize with respect to p e naught
you end up with pino equals a half
if you want
one was there
usually doing it this way round is a bit hard because you have to think
about lots of inferences but in this case the three inferences fairly easy
this is a nice route
for solving this
alternatively we could work at the end of beer wine
means you need to work at the end of the probability of why
being zero
why being question mark
why being
one and you could laboratory work out those three
numbers the probability of getting a zero out
the probability that put in a zero multiplied
etcetera so you can work out the three numbers then you have a big
massive stuff to put into the entropy computation if qpi log on people must be
log on people about three terms
so that's looks like a terrible later work
then secondly we wanted to know why
given x
that's easier because if you condition on a particular
x going in and then they and why is just a choice between zero or
question mark or one question mark in the entropy of the distribution is the same
way around is just age
that's that's an easy thing this is looking horrendous but i want to introduce you
a little
property of the entropy which we call the decomposability over and it
this is not the jam sorry we're getting to the genome
the decomposability end he says
you can if you want to work out the entropy of a distribution over several
characters in the alphabet
imagining that u learn the character in a sequence of steps and add up how
much entropy you get on average a teacher those steps
first you can imagine finding out
the character that came out a question mark or not
and we know
fraction question that's coming out is always at
it doesn't matter what input distribution you four
we can say
was a question mark
and then
completely separately optimized reward functions
the state a separate optimisation problems after optimisation problems about the model is a learning
OK let's keep going to use more interesting one let's take the reward
just the best internal reward just before twenty five thousand
and the best award just after twenty five thousand
and if look at the behavior and then run does not learning
and show what happens to the fitness obtained by the agent with those two reward
best the reward function that that before twenty five thousand
is the rule of it basically line between one and two
just keep eating one
the agent the best reward function after twenty five thousand
last week we should take some time to learn to eat fish about twelve thousand
twenty five thousand time steps before and efficiently learning to eat fish
overcomes the disadvantage of not having eaten
that's that explains the twenty five thousand
because now here's more interesting results
look at the best internal reward functions
the best internal reward function
before you can ever learn to fix this was the need
at twelve thousand of clustering as
two thousand writers and the that even the best one hundred six about two thousand
time steps learn to eat fish so the time step it doesn't really matter what
reward function it is within the reward function as long as they don't reward functions
as good to eat bait
don't get distracted by fish but you know it's good to be experimental results between
two thousand twenty five thousand with the best internal reward function is overturning the thickness
it's saying you know what
eating bridges carols
because you have the opportunity to get distracted by fish don't like you can your
in your life
to learn to to eat fish
to learn fast enough to exploit to do to overcome
just having even ones all the time
right so so this is reversal that's the really interesting part that could explain some
of the things that are happening in in the sort of things that that the
talk about that the best adapted internal reward could be quite different from from what
the fitness might be the fitness function might
let me say one more thing i was going to be on time
i am today all my ninety minutes by the way just because
so can make get
so so the idea that lots of experiments there's lots of experiments showing cute things
about internal reward being different from fitness and advantages and so on and it turns
out there are
there are probably properties of environments that correspond to good internal reward functions we we
solve the optimisation problem but there is good reason to believe that the principles of
internal reward they can emerge
there are in the interesting and show you one
such principled in manner
so here's a strong conjecture we have
strong conjecture we have is that internal reward mitigates agent about this
four let's say that in the opposite way
if some agents were completely unbalanced
all powerful
nine to break the contract
the data and is just one powerful
so might as well just give my
as a designer i get the fitness is an award because it is all powerful
right just do the right thing
is because it is limited
in various kinds of ways either because the finite lifetime as using slow learning algorithm
as was the case before or because of limited memory
or because it is limited no
common resources any any sort right it's because of that i think internal rewards
are that you want to break contact
in fact we believe that there are probably
principles that map forms of boundedness two forms of total
OK that's
that's all
i get what i mean mitigation our internal rewards mitigate about this i mean the
bounded agent with confounded reward will do
say so
the unbounded agent
with confounded reward will will
i will do whatever do
the gap between these two
the point is
the same married agent but given the internal reward
and mitigate some of that gap that the
that's the picture
trying to do experiment so all this foraging domain in the form of boundedness is
the agent has incomplete information about the state
you can't really see where the where the world is and so
it got planned to read the warming doesn't know where it is it turns out
that a
internal rewards that
that said that encourages exploration going to places you have been to before
in andromeda
to construct physics
you need some unit of length
some unit of time and some unit of mass of three things
and playing was very excited by the idea that now
with his constant
you could join
the speed of light which appears in maxwell's equations and newton's gravitational constant g to
make one two three
quantities that appear fundamental with units that appear in fundamental laws of physics
so that by combining these with different powers you could construct
three things the length unit of length the unit of mass and unit of time
and have something you could transmit
to have something you could describe without transmitting
two how inhabitants of andromeda
since then
planks intuition has as
elevated almost into a principle
that it's the stakes have become much higher for this kind of numeral or numerology
it really
it is
probably the
the only road
two realizing
a much older vision that goes back to factories
i've tried to explain everything about the world in terms of numbers
now of course you can't really explain everything about the world in terms of numbers
because numbers don't have units
so ultimately you have to have some way of smuggling in units
and together with pure numbers
c g and h give us a beautiful way
such a beautiful way of smuggling in units
but i like to call them honorary numbers
because they are so deeply embedded in fundamental principles of
deep lies deep theories of physics that you can do without them in some form
so specifying
that they exist
it is part of specifying the theory
let me
be a little more specific
in this in the theory of relativity and special relativity
you learn that there's the symmetry between space and time
that one looks like an interval of space to you might look like an interval
of time to me from moving by
but of course space and time are measured in different units
so to make that notion incoherent there has to be some conversion factor between the
unit of length in the unit of time
and that's the role of c
the theory of special relativity
in the theory of general relativity
you learn
that spacetime curvature is caused by the local density of energy momentum
but those are measured in different units
so you have to have some conversion factor to make the local here to make
it makes sense and that's the role of newton's constant g
since in general relativity
in quantum mechanics and modern quantum mechanics
you've wave particle duality or things like
the relationship between energy and frequency of the photon
which is the embodiment of an aspect the wave particle duality
but energy and frequency are measured in different units you need conversion factor and that's
the role of playing seconds
so to make any of those theories cohen and you have to introduce these conversion
just like converting enters into yards
because there unavoidable relationships you need in the theory
and that's what i call the unary numbers
course plankton only
so it's quite remarkable that he stumbled into this nevertheless
we call them units and this core planks vision
on the other hand if you these two events
those that do not of course then the probability that the alarm is sounding is
very low and
there similarly for this that time follow entry we we can be able to specify
all these
the distribution setting and then the remaining tables
the hard the probability of our rules
here which are very very low the probability of a bimodal and we very low
up here we all know
if now
know that dalai is something we can ask what is the probability
that the bible was
in the aisles given that
alarm is sounding and we can find out that the probability is very high
if we now have
some additional evidence
that the radio broadcaster and that was warming then we can do a similar calculation
to find out that
the probability now that there wasn't bargain is very low so we started from
quite high probability and then this additional evidence enable us to
to understand the
the probability that the virus was in their houses
very very small
now i have said that a graphical models are useful because they neighbors to understand
dependencies independencies relationship by just looking at the graph in the next few slides i
will explain to you how to do that let's consider a very simple case of
which we have three noughts
three random variables a b and c
and if we create the link between all the variables that we can all see
anything about independence bowl despite so we have to draw
some link in the graph let's drop the link for example from a to b
and consider all the possible configurations all the possible really which
results from the different the orientation of the world i have listed the for all
four of them here if you look at the first three
what we can
in fact is that
the valuable and b are conditionally independent
conditionally independent given the right we see that i'm here indicate the yellow color
on the other hand if i look at this graph here
a and b are
not conditionally independent given
c was first allowed to ensure that
for the first three of should they be an independent given c well i can
simply write down for example for the first release that
distribution of a and b given c which is
great tenacity show of the joint distribution maybe c
given by
divided by the distribution of seeing i can use the full authorization
the theory about from
from the movement or see as not science also have to put it down here
p of c then
b as this apparent c
that's why i put that there appear to be c
and a fiancee so i needed there given see now we can see that these
two terms
cancel out
and therefore i o thing the
like can you can show
for the other two
i believe that or misdemeanour similar way why they are independent
and similar with
similar reasoning that we can use social that a and b are not independent
given c
in this sense that in
did this associated distributions
o four for most of the associated distribution a and b
will be independent but there might be cases in which of the particle distribution for
which a and b would be in the independent given to this is the kind
of us up the point that we have to understand the world graphical models we
can really for our independence
both random variable
but we
so we can not
fact true
two dependencies we can just say that a and b are not
independent given c
now if i consider the case we can reach i don't condition of c
this in the the first three cases a and b become
dependent in the sense this plane before
why in the forties a and b
become independent
basically what they have
in this slide is that
if c
as more than one incoming link
then a and b will be in the
but they will be independent when the conditional sitting on the other hand
if c has at most one incoming link then a and b would be
conditionally independent given c but they will be marginally dependent so in the first case
here is called collider in the second case is called and non collider so the
collider collider seem to
they behave in the kind of
wait so let them down
look at some x complicated example in which we have both collided and in all
collider in in the part between
our body will of interest so here for example we have
four variables
so we want to see if a and b and d are independent
given bscl always
indicates that i'm conditions over these five or
since there is a call there in the path
and conditioning on made the means that i i maintain dependencies and i i expressed
that by
let's look at
this next little piece of code
binding easy to be some value and then i'm going to run this
well list is run and see what it does
OK so what does look at what i'm doing a test there to say
if the string x is less than the value of the
next not appear before b is strings then i was going to do
a couple of things
because there at the same block level
given that wasn't true
did nothing
now wait a minute you say where's the else clause
and the answer is i don't need one
right if this is purely a test of this is true do this otherwise i
don't care
i don't need the else clause in to identify
the second thing i want to look at is suppose i compare that to the
one below it
ips i don't want to do
comment that out
it's uncommon this
still binding for
in the same test but notice now
but the two same commands but they have different indentation
in this case in fact i do get a different behavior
because that block identifies
a set of things i'm going to do if the test is true
the test was not true notice that last comment for print is now back at
the same level of the so what this says is the if does the test
having done the test tested decide not going to do anything in the block below
it i'm going to skip down therefore to the next instruction at the same level
as the if
which gets me to the second print statement
OK so now we're seeing some of these variations
let's see what else can we do here still image to try something a little
more interesting and then we'll get to writing some simple programs with common those out
let's go down to
this piece of code
and commented
uh yes that was brilliant let's try this again
uncommon that
one uncommon to the game
so here's a little piece of code is going to print out
the smallest value
notice what this is showing is that these can be nested
it is i look that is see x is what sorry if x is less
than y then
check to see if x is less than c
and if that's true
the x is the smallest
notice the structure the if it's not going to go to the next else
print of disease models
if the first test wasn't runescape that whole block and just go down to print
out the y was small
notice the nesting i can flow my way through how those tests are actually going
to take place
right so let's run this and see what happens
why smalls
OK the co correct
ten of hand back there
it's not doing all of the comparisons
i mean this is check this out because i want to make a point to
this let's go back and do the following
let's take y
changes to thirteen
to run
so what did i miss you
two important points
the first one when i write a piece of code especially code that has branches
in one i design test case
for that piece of code
i should try and have a specific test case for each possible path through the
by just doing that is part of the about here
the but was in my thinking i did not look for all the test so
the way i can fix that is
comment tips
overall so that does look like a rich set of vectors
for we in
look at the cardinality of the set of vectors
so the more advanced branches of learning theory did not get geometry of this set and how the
also the details with the internet
we got the cardinality of the set of vectors
and if we didn't take
expectation this
the logarithm of this county
through we were interested whether this thing grows exponentially so with the
if we take expectation in the logarithm
we get something called the we see entropy of picture when interbreed
end of determining true
a necessary and sufficient condition for uniform convergence of risk
so the uniform convergence of risk
well remembered one sided uniform convergence risk
was equivalent to a nontrivial consistency
we were saying it's difficult to check this kind of property for learning machines so we need
other properties not determining the problem equivalent
uniform convergence is
two sided
but similar
the fact that this
we see entropy
grows sublinearly
so we seem to be happening
if this zero
we have consistency
it depends
there's an expectation here
and is again over the
generation of training samples from all
unknown probability distribution so that depends on the problem that we are
dealing with
this further concepts
the the wall course a sense the first one is
if we exchange the expectation in the logarithm remember is a convex function or concave depending which way round to
define it
reduces inequality is we exchange the expectation
end lower
if we do that
we get a quantity which is
the annealed entropy
and if the annealed entropy now zero
one divided by and
it's a slightly stronger condition because this inequality
and this condition can be equivalent to exponentially fast uniform conversions
so it turns out in the former case we could have uniform conversions that's arbitrarily slow
in this case
we get the normal rate
great like in town of
if we go one step further
instead of an expectation take maximum
that again football
we get something which is called the growth function
and the growth function
is related to what i told you about before we this shattering coefficient
in the growth function
is basically the logarithm of this shattering coefficient
and the
the growth function
if the growth function divided by and goes to zero
we have an exponential convergence for all underlying probability distributions
actually i
is something well before the shattering required
someone image sharing coefficient depends on the distribution of course it doesn't
we were not written on the slides
so the growth function
going to zero
divided by and
is now
necessary and sufficient condition for exponential convergence
independent of the underlying distribution
and the growth function is something that is very close to
tell when is not mentioned that you probably all the
the growth function and
has a certain type of behavior
which is
the characterized by dimension
so we are interested in cases where the growth function
grows sublinearly in it
it turns out
the typical situation will be that the growth function at the beginning
if you have a small numbers of training examples
grows linearly so typically
will start with behavior like this
which means that all possible separations
of the two
all possible separations of training data can be realized using functions of
end suddenly some and it would typically
we no longer the case
a little bit slower
so as long as this
equality here is true
so the growth function grows linearly
this means
it no
all these and
all this can be generated
in the end points can be chosen such that
by using functions that the learning machine they can be separated in all possible ways
which we call chattering before
the slide is you
and it turns out that the
this is also something that would
turning seven fold proven
in nineteen sixty eight it was later proven also by
some of
scientists which is what is sometimes known as the cells was
approved by someone by the name of the
it was also proved by sheila
sometimes called the
ten minutes so of the last them on
combinatorial among
which says that this function
and was also once poses a question by elders to someone
and less complicated story about the history of this
but so basically the result that
the either
the function class grows linearly
four and
it is a form of
it starts like that and so much more than
the following is true
this is the end called dimension
and once we passed and
the growth function suddenly grows
only logarithmically
so that's kind of a surprising result so it staff linearly
and remember
algorithm and the definition of the growth function the growth function grows logarithmically related to the shattering coefficient
remember the shattering coefficient was reduced
most exponentially the growth function most in
so he really really grows linearly is the
massively rich one
famously wrote can stop