family of algorithms that interpolates between perception and we know are going for
those who know what we know about it
let's go back to our
let's leave optimisation
which is the relation restoring from
and then let's go back to our
all power
perceptron which we find the first class
the you know
know i love
because the simple
and i think of
o always generalized it in a different direction
OK so so we can write so let's try to the weight of the perceptron
after certain number of
observations of the brain
the weight
and the weight
we know that it can be written this
so as
one of it being
x indicator function and right in this way now
two different locations
you don't get bored with the same picture
no but i don't know what
OK this is it
it is an indicator function of the mistake
what would you do not we can be
now they really get action
and then you make a mistake i made a mistake
and imagine i have been in the way
OK we know
for some reason for doing
patient who
i want to go to art
because i want to make it a little bit
i want to
at the semantics of this expression from the perceptron with some interesting
i would like to introduce the functions
are being the are
anyone because this is the function that we conditions
on the fact that i like
later on for now just because
any function of the form
and i call it special function
for reasons that hopefully will become clearer
later on
asking what happened
if i
the weight of my degree
the gradient
of the potential functions at
the perceptron way
what is this
this is a
this is
i linear
this is the linear classifiers
i can think that are you can make it OK OK
i think the gradient
and i
i wanted this in the back
so might you can use
and defining it is this
five is any differentiable
but this is this in this case
i make it more making you and know
none of this
what about it
OK i would say that
so now that i
define a linear classifier
where the way
i define it in terms
all the gradient of the potential function
it's just that it let me write another line
you might object is defined as the
four why he
but the picture of what
so if i am using it this way
but the classification of the algorithm uses this way
but still i can compute and
and that is used to retrieval
OK now how does this matrix look like that we get
well i can show you a typical matrix here but i can show you hundreds
of millions of typical matrix here
and that's basically what it looked right so
it's a big ocean of zeros and there's some islands of nonzeros right and it's
so the assumptions i made here are basically we have million document about one hundred
thousand terms in the vocabulary
and the responses of about
ten percent which means
every document uses a hundred of the terms in the vocabulary which
if you look at news and shorter documents is reasonable assumptions
so this is how this
this matrix looks like and
you know we don't want to look at that
beast that you know
very sparse matrix but really we feel
perhaps the you know this maybe should have some interesting struck structure that we can
OK now first of all
what does it mean that this matrix has so many zeros right so so this
is the problem really is not just
it's almost everywhere and in various parts but
going back to the application that i was talking about in search
there's a problem called the vocabulary mismatch problem and that is that if we look
at the particular document and look at the actual content of the document there are
many ways to express
certain concept certain facts right by using different types of words
so but but within a document that you know we will use one particular where
you know that so there will only be a subset of the words that could
be used are actually use and that's the decision they inspire or
personal preferences are just the precision in language you know
and that leads to this vocabulary mismatch problem which means that you know very often
we might use certain terms to query for document but then the document might not
contain these exact terms but might contain other terms because the author has decided not
and of course a matrix that means you know they just so many zeros where
in principle they could be nonzeros if the author would have chosen other works but
usually it
so in here just to give you some idea right we know that
we might have a query for this document here labour immigrants germany and then we
happy because of the three terms occur and you know we can see that that
is relevant but as soon as we start varying
the query
right so to the point where something like german green card then you know none
of the terms that we use are actually in the document although
you know that might actually be good match with what about what this particular CNN
news documents talks
OK so
what we'd like to accomplish
is to get some robustness with respect to these variations in queries
OK so that we're not getting a vastly different answer every time
and in particular also that we we find relevant documents even if we don't use
specific terms
OK so one of the main challenges here
the the compactness so typical
query consists of about two point five terms right we all know that the reason
own statistics
there's there's great variability in language
there's an and semantically related terms and so on and so forth
there's a lot of ambiguity so for instance terms with multiple meanings giving example
if you query for
at the time i did this google you find information about you this is a
space probe
about james joyce's
book and then about this is frowned who you know
as a general in the
american civil war
and then there is also questionable quality and authority which is important in the web
context for something like
OK so now
i talk about the technique that can console help to address
some of these challenges and that
get back as i said to the late eighties and early nineties when people invented
this technique called latent semantic analysis of latent semantic indexing
and the idea is that we take this huge matrix and we perform a low
rank approximation of the matrix
and say reduce it down approximated by matrix perhaps of rank
somewhere between one hundred and three hundred just to give you a kind of rough
and the general idea behind this was that you know we wouldn't documents and terms
bye bye bye by computing the low rank approximation effectively mapped into some low dimensional
space one hundred to three hundred dimensional space
in which hopefully
by for instance computing inner product in that space
what is the we want to know v
eight minus six
s two meters per second
physics work
he is now plus two meters per second
all that information is in there but i want you to be able
two also
digest they don't look at the of just some don't have a parabola some done
curve try to imagine what is happening
and only then
you get some insight
then you really begin to
get it
in your brains
i know i would like to write down
in most general four
the equation
for the position
and the velocity as a function of time
for one-dimensional motion
the acceleration is constant
so it's going to be one-dimensional again
and we have a is going to be called
so the equation that i write down is the most general way that i can
write it down
so we're going to get x
some number c one
plus some c two
times t
what some see three
times square
o i already raise my example my example is gone which you would have seen
this was an eight before and here we had
what did we have minus
we had minus six t and we have plus one t squared
so you recognise these three
i can now
take the derivative
and so i get to se two
c three
times t
and then i get the acceleration
he calls
and now we get some insights
in two
what these quantities
x y
c one
it is
of x at time t equals zero which we often right next zero
is zero
that is where x is
c two
is really the velocity
at time t equal zero because when t zero
that's when
c two
it's the
and the acceleration
is not changing with time
it's too
c three
therefore c three
is half accelerate
it is give you some insight into the meaning of these quantities you can see
you can read now some some physics in there
c one c two and c three can independently be zero
larger than zero or negative
makes no different each one of these combinations is
valid possibility in physics
well we have gravity
an object
influenced by
the gravitational acceleration
and the gravitational acceleration
is a constant
and we write often for that
gravitational acceleration
the letter g
when i drop an object
or throw it vertically up
or throw it vertically downwards all one-dimensional
becomes two-dimensional when i throw it at an angle
i keep it one-dimensional
acceleration is always the same
and that g
gravitational acceleration in boston
nine point eight zero
the second square and it's very little bit for different places on earth
this gravitational acceleration
is independent
of the mass of the object
that i draw
of the speed of the object
of the chemical composition of the object of the size of the object and of
the shape of the object assuming
we have no and direct assuming that these experiments are done
in vacuum
is it obvious that the gravitational acceleration
is independent of all these quantities
by no means
is it true
we think so
i want you to appreciate that it is not obvious and it can not be
proven from first principles
i remember the last time
we dropped an apple
from three meters and we drop another one from
one and a half metres
in your second assignment
which you haven't seen yet i'm asking you to calculate
the gravitational acceleration for me
using these both
and of course
i want you to also tell me what the uncertainty is
in your final answer
and i'd like to help you a little bit
set up
and also
to get these equations
in terms of
whenever we deal with gravity
we get
g in there
so suppose
here the object
at time t equals zero
the apple
and i call that position x zero i call that zero i'm free to chose
my zero position
and i drop it zero speed i just let it go because that's the way
we did it in class
the object goes down
and it hits the floor
the general equations now
which dealing gravity if i call this the increasing value of x
you can choose it differently
this is my choice today
is the following
x zero
let's be zero t
one half
the square
and g now
o point eight
i mean it's the second square
the velocity
and if we do that we get a better model of the
so that's what we're doing this recursively
that's one way of thinking about it
OK so
if you try and do that
in a directed net
you could think about
assuming independence here
and the modelling this
and then
looking at the poster you get when you do inference which is going to be
complicated and then trying to model this
the problem is that if you do it in the directed net
when you learn these weights it tries very hard to make these
because as the assumption of the model
so it'll be willing to get weights they don't actually realise to reconstruct very well
because they're trying to get these to be independent and the posterior
and that's simply because later on you can put in most of his so these
don't actually need to be independent
you're trying to achieve something
but you don't really want to achieve in the end because in the end these
are going to be able to make these people are not independent
so you waste about trying to achieve this independence
as a result of which this doesn't work very well this respected and you've already
made a big loss here
we'll see make these two independent
it doesn't work nearly as well to sort of learn these weights and then assuming
independence here and then learn the model of this stuff
so i want to give you a practical example and then go back to the
modern theory
and we're going to take bigger images of digits the and digits and we get
a all ten different classes
and we can learn more like this five hundred binary features the mccollum like this
by features that we're going to put in the class labels with the ten way
and we can learn the model of
this feature vector with the label and its the joint density models so this is
just another restricted boltzmann machine
the lens the joint density
but this was long greedily
and then we're going be fine-tune you won't talk about much
makes it work quite a bit better but it's too complicated for
so basically think we just did this
and then we can look at what we got
so i might come back to the fine tuning of this time but i'm going
to talk about it
i want shake the model that we get
OK so this is that net
twenty by twenty eight five hundred five hundred two thousand ten
and we can give it an image like this one
and we can
it recognizes so what i'm doing now is running this way
so having trained as generative modelling now run it as a sort of just going
to model
and stochastic so these keep changing but has no doubt that is is very short
so for
run faster you can see the top ones don't change that much
rather the some the fairly stable like that one there
i can show some other digit
it's less sure about that but it's most of the times has made occasional thinks
it's a three
and so unreasonable
so i can recognise OK in fact you does quite a good job recognition
this very short that surviving woman to that
i given a tricky one
and he will express
keeping changes mind
it happens to and on the right answer which is that's just constraints actually the
fact that this isn't in the last column means that
the most frequent answer gives is made
but only just
we can deal with various kinds of noise quite well
so we think this is the one or seven most of the time
but what's most interesting about this is when you want to generate
i'm gonna run the model
as a generator
and what's going to happen is this
i'm going to
and i'm just going to go down between these units here with this fixed
so i'm just doing alternating gibbs sampling in restricted boltzmann machine that's always happening cause
that's where the action is
and what will happen is
eleven to various brain states here
and it's impossible future so what they represent because there's just activities neurons
what you would be interested in his mental state
so i'm show you both the brain state here
and the mental state which i'm sure here
you so the way mental state the language of mental states which is this if
i want to tell you one of my brain states
i could try saying you're in fifty three is on the left in the much
good it it
or i could say
this upon active neurons
which is just like the pattern of active neurons you get if i was looking
at the pink elephant
now that's a rather clumsy way of saying of this problem that was the pattern
of the brain state which is like the brain that i get if i was
looking the elephant
so we have a funny way of saying that we have shorthand for that
which is something i saying i've got the perceptron pink elephant
well there really means is some brain stated think the some brain state was like
the one i would have if i was looking the pink elephant
that's your generative model if i ask you
what brings it is this that
well because i can generate from i say the kinds of things to my reference
works like the kinds of things that would normally cause that
so i'm showing the brain states but i'm showing the mental states
by showing the kinds of things that normally cause
so as it runs that's where all the action is
just so you know what's really happening here
i'm showing you what it has in mind by going to time
because that's where the action is
again trenchant each time do it fast
you'll see that after a while
it settles into generating two was once the second generation to the just generated forever
and and all sorts of different things
once we look for the loops you generate even rather bad to use
thank you
this is really running second
but that's important that they can generate because it means you can recognise the two
label for example one
the expert level set and then it may be it passes over example two because
example two might look exactly like example one in terms of its feature vector it's
x-factor so maybe that doesn't seem to things that should be about the same as
the label for the first example and so on and so forth and so the
machine would selectively as
for labels and you could also think of this is the machine selectively asking or
per for suggesting next experiments that the scientist might might try and so on and
so forth
so this is
seventeen people have tried to do with some success there's a project called robot scientist
in the UK
and this is the little snippet from an article that appeared in wired magazine recently
so that there in this case
the human is almost fully out of the loop and there's a little bit of
by humans involved but for the most part of this machine which they call and
carries out the entire scientific process to formulate hypotheses designs and runs experiments analyzes data
decides which experiments right next and so on and so forth so this is the
machine words fully closed loop system or engine for scientific discovery is actually
for certain things are already known and made some some novel discoveries as well so
this is something people are pretty excited about
so let me
now it's a little bit about the BBC
so mathematical framework which will study these problems are introduced some the terms notation that
will be using throughout the talk so there any questions so far in
have lighter stuff and i'll just go into a little bit of the mathematical
foundation framework that will be working
OK so
the typical setup is you have some space h
of hypotheses or models
and our goal is to try to find the best
the hypothesis that set
we have a set AX which is the set of queries or questions we can
ask we can also think of these unlabelled features that we could request labels for
work experiments that we could run and so on and so forth and then the
h star
would be the true model the model that we're trying to identify and it may
or may not belong to the set h so it may have some mismatch between
our actual collection of models and hypotheses and the true model of what's actually going
and there
maybe two
distinct settings here one would be
noise was learning in noiseless learning you'd have an axe
can you request
a label for it can you get why which would just be h star affects
the true label
noisy learning
you would get that label
four response plus noise
and things get trickier more difficult when there is noise but will talk about how
that can be dealt with some of the challenges it presents
so again active learning is the idea of sequentially selecting the most informative queries are
examples to have labels for based on past queries and labels
major type t TV sense of how you might do this
algorithmically out of prison to simple algorithms that
i have been proposed for noiseless active learning in one which is quite well known
method by colin atlas ladner
and here the setting is binary classification so our hypothesis mass
the feature space to space plus one minus one have binary labelling and h stars
assumed to be a member of our collection of hypotheses
and the idea of the algorithm is you initialise
you're set of models to be the complete set
so h one is said to be the whole set of all hypotheses and then
while there's is more than one hypothesis you iterate through these three steps you
so lacked
o point
and unlabeled feature query
in the set of
four new features are queries where there's some disagreement among the hypothesis that are currently
so this is just there are some that it appeared picking an x where some
of the hypotheses are saying
plus one in summer saying minus one
there's been no value depicting a point where they are all in agreement
you query with that point you get the label
and then you simply
your current set of hypotheses to retain only those the degree
with the label you just acquired
OK so that will reduce the size of its surviving you have a new set
of viable hypotheses h survive plus one and that will be decreasing on each step
of this process because you are insisting that there's always going to be some disagreement
in every query make
so that's the the algorithm a few pieces of notation that will refer to later
this is
usually called the region of disagreement the set of hypotheses are the region of feature
space where there is disagreement among the hypotheses and this set of viable hypotheses is
called the version space
this album was actually propose more about online streaming fashion were just unlabelled examples would
come along and whenever one came along the
there was some disagreement and then you would collectively before so it's a really simple
idea and you can see how this simply pairs down the set of hypotheses intelligence
one remaining in that must be the correct one
so that's the the KL algorithm
another idea that's very similar and a bit older and perhaps even older than me
mean certainly in the late sixties is something that you might call generalized binary search
for the splitting algorithm and i'll actually be talking a little bit more about this
one and two
and some non metallic elements over here
five six and seven and so you can imagine that
if you mix these
if you take a sodium new mexico with chlorine you get sodium chloride
but there's nothing saying you can't take magnesium and mixed with oxygen and magnesium oxide
and you would expect that there would be much stable compound because instead of plus
one attracting plus one naive plus two attracting plus
excuse me attracting minus two
plus two attracting minus two so coulombic forces are much much greater
and that will be reflected in what
higher melting point higher boiling point
resistance to reactivity
so what does it strike you or they may be magnesium oxide one of its
applications would be refractory is that is to say brickwork and high temperature furnaces maybe
tiles on the shuttle
to resist high temperatures because of
the high internal bonding
you see there is the
there's there's this system here
chemistry is in the litany of facts we started with a few simple assumptions
and look at what we're doing we're designing systems building engineering systems materials choices
it's fantastic
OK so we can do this one more time was to one more time
actually something else
sure another way to to get a sense of these energies and for that i
want to look at the energy starting from real material see up until now been
talking about gas facing atoms all this stuff so let's look at this reaction sodium
solid plus
chlorine gas it's its diatomic
molecule and i want that to react to give me sodium chloride
as the solid and crystal
i one ordered solid
for this i need to invoke a couple of
bits of science first one is has this law
passes law
has has lost states that for any chemical reaction
the energy change
is path independent
path independent that is to say
but i can now
i rewrote this sodium plus chlorine reaction go different way but i still the same
change in energy
it's because the state function is the same thing as gravitational energy whether you take
the elevator to the top of the hancock tower with you walk up the stairs
the change in gravitational potential is identical you might be winded doing at the second
way but when you get to the top and you're at the sixtieth story you're
gravitational potential is independent of how you got there
that's what this is saying it's an analogy
energy change is path independent so now i'm going to break this into into elementary
steps and look at the relative contributions so what do we do so far we
talked about this reaction here we had
chloride ions in the gas phase plus sodium ions
in the gas phase right we started with geisha sodium to make geisha sodium ion
gauges atomic chlorine to make gaseous chloride ions through electron transfer all the gas phase
very idealistic but
that the with
the world works so i want to get to their starting from real sodium real
chlorine so first thing i want to do is to convert the sodium into vapor
so this is sodium goes to sodium gas
and then take sodium gas
and when
make this into sodium
gas plus electron or by the way this is called sublimation isn't it
this process of sublimation solid to vapor
sublimation this is called ionisation is an
gas phase goes gas phase species loses an electron that's the strict definition of ionisation
summary there with sodium chloride i got to do a little bit more heavy lifting
here because core starts as a diatomic molecule the first thing i got to do
with biases that have
so this is called dissociation
so i need to dissociate
the chloride
chlorine rather
and now i've got to convert atomic chlorine into iron chlorine so i'm going to
do that
adding electron
and this reaction here is the inverse of ionisation isn't it
it's ionisation be i take one of the electrons and carina away here i'm actually
throwing electron to chlorine so this reaction is called electron affinity
electron affinity
so you think of electron affinity is sort of
the ionisation reverse of the iron
it's it's the minus loses
and this one here this reaction is what we call crystallisation
so those are the five steps
let's see if we can find information
i call this one
let's say i think unlabelled this one too
this that the talk i should confess that i mean it's not so
to me to the top of the talk is going on manifolds my by manifest
the first delicious
can actually
the first half of the total
and then you can go either toronto instead
you might be running and you may be
but if you know the kind of the text that i'm talking about i'm going
to discuss about
to the riemannian manifolds and the second part of the talk is more kind of
like entertainment purposes of
they time and then
i'm not i and then
this is some interesting applications of the mythos
the is the topological space in the parameters
neighborhoods such as them amazon
thanks for instance
manifold if
i can look at the angles on the sphere is that it is that by
being no sense but the
because scale remain part of the to see it applies so the structure will be
complicated in this case a three sphere but constructor is medium so this what you
need have to remember actually but the is by
some of the right person is considered them for my interaction with the
many many some other examples of the manifold here you see brownouts and this is
the same thing actually happened or not
two and this is a notable institute and climb by the same thing topologically speaking
all right then part started to grow up to be talking about a group of
the same and also to the binary operation and by these are properties is closely
associated with an identity element and a
there are versus to each member in the set for the set of integers under
addition about the identities the group of
set of integers under multiplication is not why because the antigen is not an integer
so that and
so x is all
this talk
this it's the properties for instance it opens
racial numbers
the multiplication is the subset is closed between south of
identity right
the set of a set of negative relational numbers are not because identity is not
in the subset so it's not just
the the taliban thing about committed to see noncommutative the set of points to buy
and square meters is under my it's
application and this is called the general linear group gln
so the spatial which is the number
constraints so is out subgroup of that
topological spaces
so we are as i am moving concepts
now let's go to topological spaces topological spaces in a city is about a it's
a better inside is that is out of an empty set at an intersection of
in the city
so in
this is hard to define a topology since in this she of course consists
after the topological space
and you can see that
in which contains a point x is called in the neighborhood of the point so
we can define the neighborhood boundaries not disconnect hostile separated space is a topological space
in which this thing points in disjoint neighborhoods
so two points separated which was tend to find a small but still distinct was
there an implied important property which means that the two points on the manifold not
kind of coinciding on the same a point
this kind of a news story that i told you maybe i should be deciding
number forms is the most of
is what you see in the middle here
these are
measurements of
no lines was known
wavelengths in the laboratory this is just the calibration here and this is the calibration
this is the spectrum of the galaxy
and what you see here are two guidelines
those are absorption lines every of the stars in the galaxy
they have shifted relative to the
wavelengths in our laboratory by the way one of those lines is the same line
that are used for
pores which is the calcium k absorption lines
the other one is the calcium h two option one h has nothing to do
with hydrogen
and it's been shifted over the distance usually indicated by the small arrows
and if you
measure now the velocity you find eleven hundred fifty kilometres per second
and if you use today's value of hubble's law
this object is fifty two million light years away from us
you go to this object
which is far away
according to hubble's law it has a higher speed receding speed
and you see the spectrum here this is the spectrum and you see those two
absorption lines have shifted all the way
and out of that then follows the
radial velocity which in this case is seven percent of the speed of light twenty
thousand kilometres per second which this object at one billion light years away from us
and when i go to this one here in the corner it's hard to see
which one it is
the absorption lines have shifted even further you see the absorption lines here
and that object is going was twenty percent of the speed of light
then it would be roughly at the distance of two point eight
a billion light years
the most money
work on hubble's law was done by
the group the the
leadership of wendy freedman
when we use data from the hubble space telescope
and she measured
the doppler shift
and the distance
a few hundred object distance is always the can of worms
and she came up
presently the most reliable value
for the
the hubble's constant
let me get the
next slide if i succeed
this is when the freedman's work
forget what you see here just look at what you see here is this sense
so the foreigners objectivity was able to get a reliable distance four
is four hundred mega part six
that's the stunning distance by the way it's about one three one point three billion
light years
and she was able to measure the radial velocities up to about ten percent of
the speed of light
velocities of thirty thousand kilometres per second
so she can draw this line
which is the linear relationship between velocity and distance
and out of that line comes home law
and she concludes
that is very close to seventy two
kilometres per second mega part six plus and minus if you
i used seventy just to round it off
what is interesting
that's how small
in his entire data
the velocities rule
less than eleven hundred kilometres per second
that in scale here
this already has two thousand kilometres per second so that only data in this team
proportion here when he doesn't even have any day doesn't even use them and the
reason why he doesn't use them he says it's too close it's not really representative
forty what we call the hubble flow
so she stays away from the local stuff
but nevertheless based on that very local stuff
which is not even put in here
with his
the relationship
which was monumental
in the history of mankind because it puts the universe
at the very different
level then
what people thought before
the universe
so let's now ask yourself the question what does this all mean
the first thing that may come to mind
since all objects i'm moving away from us
you may think that you are very special we all like to think that we
have very special
so you may even think
that you are at the center of the universe
because everything moves away from you
persuasive is to think that there was a time in the past when there was
a huge explosion
which we refer to as the big bang
when all of this happened
and there were galaxies with large speeds
in the explosion they are now the ones that forest away from us so to
have the highest speed and some had a low-speed speed so that's the picture that
presents itself so little bit naive though and
partially wrong
however the idea of the big bang theory that there was such an explosion
a long time ago
that still holds
and that is considered the birth
of our universe
so now comes the question
when did this big bang walker
we could make
a simple assumption perhaps not quite accurate
that the velocity which was all these galaxies are moving
are a subset of this one GEO dataset and we're using it to make predictions
so we said okay cool we see these fifty nine samples that the ovarian ones
let's go and take a look at them so the very first thing we did
with these fifty nine samples so we said let's go back to the GEO dataset
and see if we can match them up
and when we did
here's what we found so
what if the names matched up for all the fish for all the fifty nine
samples we should see fifty nine red squares lying on this blue diagonal white squares
you see lying on the diagonal
this is not a hard counting question
forty three of the samples they got the labels wrong for sixteen they didn't get
the labels wrong or at least the problem is for the sixteen we can tell
the reason we can tells for those sixteen they scrambled the gene labels so badly
that we don't know what samples they correspond to
what this means is that for the validation data set every single sample is incorrect
for two drugs they've have been using in clinical trials for two years
we think this is disturbing
so what happened next we pointed this out at the end of january
no response
we then said can we do anything else
and it occurred to us that they said well we will show you in
but the reviewers approved about sending it to the NCI
now the NCI in the US is a federally funded institutions and what that means
is that they are subject to federal law
specifically the freedom of information act so
in april we filed a request with the NCI to get the report under the
freedom of information act and the start of a redacted version of the report was
indeed supply and we looked at we found a few things that are rather interesting
in the report or work in the report the two main things that we found
were the first review committee that went through the stuff people evaluated set by the
way we could figure out from the data been published how to do this
the only way we got because there was extra information supplied to us and we
really recommend the investigators problem
so that's one thing the other thing that we found rather disturbing was what was
there specifically this report makes no mention of those problems with cisplatin pemetrexed that i
just told you it's not there
we pointed this out in may and also in may we as the national cancer
institute what do you think about what's going on and what they said let's look
at the trials we actually don't find those three coincidental tries to find another one
to phase three actually based on that they were investigated the rationale again
that signature from the phase three clinical trial in the middle of the trial that's
been made
so we said okay is there anything further that's going to happen with these three
ongoing trials
nothing happened
nothing happened for two more months
and then in mid-july we found out something new that to be orthogonal from normal
one of the p i used to claim he was a rhodes scholar the rhodes
trust in britain says no no he wasn't
so indeed
it appears there was some CV fudging involved now
what happened was that i knew there are a few statisticians would be talking about
saying maybe you we should write letters and so i emailed a few of them
the this came out and said you know if you want to write a letter
now's about the best time
the following monday three days later there's water from thirty one thirty three by statisticians
find if you that you like and the cancer chancellor comments to do you have
accomplished something monumental be triggered a public expression of outrage from file statisticians who call
but the thing about this letter was that it went to newly appointed head of
the national cancer institute have harold varmus and to do the only and to the
so this one gets some coverage
so what happened
it suspended the trials
this has since been covered just to be in a few other outlets like NPR
science teacher and some other fly-by-night journals and a few other investigations are underway there's
actually a new google were devoted entirely to reproducible research and things like that
as we've been looking at this there's a caveat that i think we should keep
in mind and that caveat is that unfortunately some of these mistakes like the one
we've seen them before
this is not the only time we've seen some of these examples going back to
two thousand two two thousand three two thousand five
these types of errors have been around for a while this is an egregious combination
but the problem there so some observations
the most common mistake
are simple once for example statistics simple one here for genomics is complete confounding in
the experimental design others involve mixing up the sample labels team levels things that are
easy to do in excel
OK those are easy to mistake
now the funding about simple mistakes is that if you see that very easy to
but if the documentation is poor
you won't see them
so they will slip by because our intuition is no good and what that means
is that if you go out to literature we sort of suspects
the most simple mistakes are more common than we would like to know
now what would we like to have happened
well for papers we've got a little thing of saying here's some things we really
would like to see in addition to data like this stuff that you know we
really like some idea of if you're gonna supplies for the table qualifications please label
the columns
her examples are which and provide home so these are some other things and these
are recommendations for papers but we think they should be absolute requirements before start clinical
and use that structure the top-down way to find solutions
this approach
has the drawback because it doesn't have an explicit
inter level structure makes a top-down process is a little bit
four pieces at all
two thousand five hundred
maybe an explicit representation likely
horizontal and vertical edges so that the neighborhood would be a good thing and he
used to quite for them to do that
unfortunately it is known in computer vision at least
i think a paper of
forgotten mention now
there are very and
we thought what about having a minimum spanning tree based approach in which
this this this talk in which we are going to this ship as well this
should be very
i mean is if i move from the city layout
i'm going to have this is what you are going to have to
solution and it has been shown by psychologists that humans are very good and robust
to show
please time
so for a very long motivations for the rest the
so i'm going to show you because minimum spanning tree algorithm which allows me to
to build up
the bottom of wavelet pyramid
i'm going to find an trivial solution then
basically started approximative solution of TSP
in the top down weights shows some signs physical results
so as you already assumed this user graph in which every the citizen vertex and
that there is some connection between the cities
and you can use different ways you can have this graph
i decided to use the complete graph i know it's not a smart way to
as i'm going to run into some computational problems probably but for the small instances
of cities which i
i i already know values like less than fifty six it thousand
it doesn't matter what
smart way would have been to use it for neutralisation four and i not
know that in order to kind oppose the travelling salesman problem i need to have
some attitudes and edges
it's also some of these
i fully connected graph
now attributed
by weight w
i get the traveling salesman problem is simply oppose this finding the
to tell which is which has the smallest overall costs basically trying to minimize this
if the weights
and in my case always always open and distance place in this talk
this problem is sometimes called the euclidean travelling salesman problem more specifically to deal with
this the small motives and here he is p and e TSP
in general hard optimisation problem the four
may be the only way to solve this problem for moment this user some approximation
of this
well this talk is also about
approximation i know
let's try to see how
the minimum spanning tree really another connect natural way to reduce the that
telling says problem satisfied
in related
ten billion
in reality
and it has been shown that spanning trees in natural or born of length of
the optimal two as well as by it is that it is
also possible to sort of upper bound in terms of the minimum spanning tree
so now
just show you
what is the minimum spanning tree already know but
just for completion is trying to find the spanning tree unweighted graphs such that
the sum of the weights
fortunately for this problem is easy to solve and it has been shown that the
probability algorithms can solve this problem may be these
two or more prominent but the one that i'm going to use the both crossovers
somebody check scientists that
he found this algorithm in nineteen twenty six trying to optimize some
electrical networking on the all those
i'm going to say
there is one that is the sole reason discussing of
is that
it's natural to build the graph
just another loss this algorithm really does is basically start with an empty list which
i'm going to populate
and i
initialize such that all the edges as are
well to be treasonable itself
but i do is i go in each of these three this list and find
that the minimum weight
platform that's going to
i'm certain
inspire a lot more copycat and that's it
part answer to this young man's questions well you know making their knowledge
i knowledge available i think what's going on today is really exciting work connected all
the knowledge pools in the world together
that's where the flat world means
and what open universities doing is actually a key connector and all
and so it is actually going trigger huge period of innovation
because suddenly the next breakthrough science could come fifteen what morals working on a troll doll a cell phone
so i twelve dollars internet-enabled cellphone that can download google
and light is open university and well who knows where the next innovations in bioscience
will come from maybe a fifteen in romania
who downloads the human genome you know
so on
i think that's what you're doing you know is really really powerful
i guess you want things the themes are discussions today here
has been
i think countries really had wrong direction at the macro level on this subject on
end of
you know i i be cute but we have people your brain back we've movie
theaters in kansas that won't show movies and evolution you know at a time when
the world is you know going in this direction and we stand to be the
greatest beneficiaries i think we've all the secrets of sources can be great research universities
wonderful still rule of law
efficient markets
on intellectual property protection but we are not tending to the sick resource loss
last year the national science foundation cut its budget by a hundred million dollars
now that's just i mean we had its budget cut by congress five hundred million dollars his
and that's just flat out stupid you know i mean on
in in this moment in time where the flat world where was
what i really feel and what argue in the book is that we're not we're not quite crisis right now
and the quiet crisis is at and this is a term coined by surely in
jackson is a graduate of mighty she's the president rensselaer polytechnic the first african-american woman
to win a page to physics from nineteen appears
she calls it the climate crisis
and she calls it that because she was part of generation inspired to go in
science and engineering by sputnik and the and president kennedy's vision and putting
a man
end on
generation is
is retiring
and dying
and we all know we don't replace them we imported
the replacements from india and china
among other places
in the arm
since nine eleven well to things that have one is the world went flat
and when the world was flat you can innovate without having to emigrate
and when you can innovate without any emigre who needs succumbed chilly boston
you know when you can stay home in your own culture living a very high
standard of living work for cutting-edge global corporation to cutting-edge science
and and be home with your family
and second thing that happened was nine eleven and so telling all the first round
intellectual draft choices the world this tale
you want twenty really important we don't want your enemies are
and so
well actually with the theme of my conversations today with
folks i've interacted with
i'm really worried story i told nausium today just triggers the point is my daughter for national
history day which is in eighth grade
represented maryland her project was
how sputnik led to the internet
yes sputnik that da polenta darkness but in the end something happened fifty years ago
in reaction to
something totally different are reaction the sputnik
please to the internet today
well i really worry about
these are reaction to nine eleven
thousand little steps
these are rejection by
these officer
in chennai
on a grant proposal denied
to a research
you know paper blocked two funds not spent more funds spent somewhere else
we could get the total some of these things would be something that really needs at the very beginning openness
interactiveness with the world that's
american denied
and the fifty years will wake up and say we do all of them
in reaction tonight
and so
i really really worry about them so i think we're in a quiet crisis right now
that's part of the quiet crisis
the other part is simply
you know time when i think we need a new new deal to deal with
an integer this the perfect square
and i want to write a little piece of code is going to find the
square root of
some cheating levi not perfect square somebody is given to me
come back in a second journalism so what would the steps be that i used
to walk through
well if you think about these steps
here's an easy way to do it
start one scorex the thing i'm trying to find the square root of the start
started one
if it's not
greater than x
take two
it is not greater than x take three square and keep going until
the square of one of those integers is greater than or equal to
so it is greater than x
OK well my doing that when i get greater than x gone past the place
where i want to be
and obviously want to get to something whose square is equal to actually got the
answer one
kick it out
so what i don't have identified the thing i want to use to count something
some variables going to discount the editors of identified the and test
when that squares
bigger than the thing i'm looking for of identified basically what i wanna do inside
the loop
which is simply keep changing that variable
and i don't see what i wanna do and i'm done
actually print out the answer
OK so how can i call this up well and i think this is jumping
to write some code i don't quite do that because i want to show you
another tool it's valuable for thinking about how to
structure of the code
and that is something called the flowchart
people of professor good tags my age unfortunately remember flow charts back on the simpsons
back in the day
back in the sixties john reid really good programmers have these wonderful little plastic stencils
i tried to find that i couldn't find it
so little stencils little cut-out shapes on they used to draft across second in you
writing your next year pocket protector with all your hands in the answer your belt
was also about this time classes with this that you know we have
and few of those nerves left mostly keep the museum but that was what you
do with the flow chart despite making a bad joke about it we're going to
do the same thing here in chart out
a little bit of what should go into actually making this thing
so here's a simple flowchart i used to capture what i just described
again i'm actually going to do it the way they used to do it and
a rectangle with rounded corners
my starting point
and then what i say to do i said i need to identify variable a
given names this call and as for answer
and i need to initialize
so i'm going to come down
in a square box
initialize answer
is there
now want to run through the loop was the first thing i do know the
a test and test the flowchart says
tradition wants to do this in a diamond shape
i want to check if answer times answer
which we don't want to do this
less than or equal to x
now that's the test the two possibilities
the answer is yes
i'm still looking for the answer what i wanna do well i don't have to
do anything other than change the counter
one to go to
his answer plus one
due to you
eventually five done this right and that test is no
wonderfully ran out of room here in which case i'm going to go to print
statement which is always done in a trapezoid
print out answer should put a box below the system
and also i got you actually this is a useful tool for visualizing on trying
to put it together
because it lets me see
where the loop is
lets me see the and test it lets me make sure that i'm in fact
initializing the variable and checking the right things as i go along
the idea of this flowchart is if you start off little ball-bearing here is roll
down setting up an assignment statement and depending on your like is pair of flippers
and there does the test sensible this way to change it all and plus one
you may make make an attempt to
prove that
the project
the vector b on h
this is the projection
the length of this vector
and then the dot product
is the magnitude of eight
times the magnitude of b
times the cosine of the angle theta two i completely identical
now you may ask you may say g
how do i know what data is how do i know i should take theta
this angle
well maybe i should take theta this angle
what angle is a making with b makes no difference because the cosine of this
angle here is the same as the cosine of three hundred sixty degrees minus
so that makes no difference
sometimes this is faster depending how the problem is presented to you sometimes
is fast
you can immediately see by looking at this
it's easier to see than looking here
the dot product can be larger than zero
can be equal to zero and can be smaller than zero
by definition always positive there in magnitude
but so are determined by the cosine of theta the cosine of data is larger
than zero well then it larger than zero
the cosine of data can be zero
if the angle for theta
by over two not always if the two vectors are perpendicular to each other than
the dot product is zero
and if is angle theta between ninety degrees and hundred eighty degrees
cosine negative
we will see that at work
o point implied when we're going to do is work
in physics you will see that we can do positive work and we can do
negative work
and it has to do with his doctoral work and energy
dot products
i could do an extremely simple
example with you
december that i can think of
perhaps it's almost
an insult is not meant that way
we have a
and a
is the one that you really have on the blackboard there
right here that's it
would be
it's just too y
that's all it is
well what is a don't we
don't b
there is no x component
of b
so that becomes zero this becomes zero
there is only one component of the soldiers minus five
times plus two
so i get
minus ten because there was no component simple as that
was minus ten
i can give you another example
example two
suppose a itself
is the unit vector in the y direction
and b
is the unit vector
in the direction
is what
i want to hear it loud and clear
it is zero you don't even have to think about anything denoted these stewart ninety
if you want to waste your time
one is substituted in here
you will see that come down to be zero
it should work because clearly
a y means that this
this this is one
that's what it means
and b is the that means that
b of the this is one and all the others
do not exist well
i wish you luck with that
and we now go to
way way more difficult part of knot locations
and that is
vector multiplication
which is called the vector product
also called
most of the time i refer to it
as the cross product
the cross product
is written like so many crosby
equal see it's across
very clear across
i'll tell you how i remember that method number one going to teach you just
like with the dot product two methods
i'll tell you method number one which is the one that always works
time consuming always works
you're right the matrix
with three rows
the first row
why rule
zero the second one is a of x
a y
they all zinc
it's important if age is here first
that second row must be a
in the third row is then b
b of x
the y
of see these six and numbers
these are the unit vectors
i repeated this year
you'll see the minute why i need that
and i will do the same here
OK and now comes the recipe
you take
you go from the upper left-hand corner
two o to one
in this direction
you multiply them all three
that's a plus sign
so you get a y
so c which is the cross across b
a y
i'm using
and vx roof but i'm not going to put extra vignette
because i have to subtract
this one
minus sign
which has
eighty y
one minus
the y
and that
it is in the direction
the next one
is this one
eight cbx
this one
x c
in that direction
and last but not least
x p y
a y bx
the direction of the unit
so this part here
is what we call c of x x component
all this vector
and this can call seal y
and this we can call
you can also write that vector then that c
because of x
x roof
see why
why roof
c of the
cross product of a
and b
when i found
so what
so this is
this is the basis from inside and
when i do that i should get this class is now
she was
so with OK so is this one so
again this is the constraint
i don't know
no another
are there
this is again
one of the things you have to look for the foxes before we look at
female and now
we find
is that they are not defined
to be different from each other
they just instances agenda
also there
o thing
this is the this is the name that have actually said that there are different
so in order to get the contradiction i have two
make them different
and now
not unsatisfied
this is one reason why
so that
it's pretty clear
more on
and not just one
one of
using the decision
one of the people in the same year it was
so it were distinct
yes well this is why this would be the wrong for her
it's a wonderful world
in explorations was first
one thing you should be able to reason on this
so i think this is one of the things we know
so we're looking and we see that we can ask one
it is and it will give the list of which are sufficient
well known as
i o
we have
no no no no
no chance
this is
i'm missing something
yes but i don't have man
so we try this one
so these breakages one of the
think of the
so that's good
place that works so i can fix that issue enough get who's
let's not get rid of them
the changes
so as before changes are manageable if you look if you could so i have
done two things to get to the state i clicked on ball which gives me
cases where
the model is linear and calcium what we mean by that
in fact is a slightly more general version of this but that's stick with this
for them for present purposes linear gases state space model says that the state transition
is the gas in distribution where the mean is a linear function of the previous
states of matrix a times the previous state
the observation density similarly
linear and garcia
it's a gas intensity for y
with the linear function of the state xk got that
then you can apply
the kalman filter the notation is the kind of graph again
is the normal distribution for x with me
vector u and covariance matrix here
we can write that equivalently an additive noise model so we got away generating the
next data point the next state point in if we wanted to synthesize from data
from the model we would just right the next state is a times the previous
state plus the noise term
similarly why
is obtained from the from the state xt plus noise again
well these can these w can be generated independently zero mean gaussians vectors with covariance
matrices c and d respectively
i've said that they are independent over time and also independent of one another in
fact you can make and also dependent on one another
version of the carbon filter that deals with that as well but we don't need
to hear
we also require we everything must be linear gaza to the initial state
must be gas in distributed i think in the previous slide nineteen eighty that f
of x not that's the same thing the initial probability density for
the first stage of time not
so the first thing we need to do
is to get the predictions that if you remember
where we heading is to solve these
two equations are going to do it analytically in closed form for the little girls
in case
so the first one involves marginalizing out the current state from for the old state
from the joint density
it is so that's what we needed to do
carry out this integral
we suppose as before that we solve the problem at time t is recursively defined
we say that we've got the filtering distribution at time t
the normal distribution
with with me insane new t
covariance pft
and we know that to get to the next state from the previous equation we
don't need to go back to that we can generate the next state on the
previous day just by multiplying by eight and adding random noise to be
so it's really just standard transformation of variables we've taken
the random variable x is multiplied by matrix a
and noise to it so the convolution of the densities and produced t plus one
so we can get two
the density for x t plus one straightforward giving evidence before exiting the calcium
and we've got passes through that
update step
the density of x t plus one conditioned on the same data
is another normal distribution with mean is modified to mean is eight times the original
meaning beauty because we multiply by a
and we've added some noise on so it so so so we need to take
and converted into a
p p times a transpose that deals with this multiplication effect
but we also added on the noise a b had covariance matrix c so that
get started on so
the moment
and on the right side so this was the covariance matrix is bounded on zero
mean girls noise v so had three of the covariance matrix c onto the AP
so that gives you the formula for doing the update if we started with the
gas industry time
so that's the prediction step
the corrections step the updating step five days for just involves taking what we just
calculated that prediction density calcium
multiplying it by the galaxy observation density
and correctly normalizing it because for a fixed data set y
that'll be a constant
turn on the bottom line that so we just need to calculate the normalizer for
the for the multivariate density
and substituting it it well don't worry about it too much about this
arrangement but we've taken the normal distribution for the predictive density for forex
multiplied by the observation density
for y conditional upon that new
plug everything in
and re-arranged it found the correct normal
with the right normalising
this one
with this particular mean and covariance of more about the details of that you can
work through your own time afterwards and we can rearrange that using the matrix inversion
lemma to give a slightly simpler form we don't need all the details of this
right now
i just put them there for reference the whole recursion is summarized in terms of
prediction step on the means and covariances
and update state on the means and covariances which progressively from the gas in time
another galaxy in time t plus one
they get as i say that we don't need the precise details of that at
the moment just outlining the principles behind it and more importantly what the things you
can and can't do
with the kalman filter that arises from the common filter is a fundamental tool is
still substantially used in
in may
estimation and tracking tasks
you can use it to estimate the system state sequentially by taking for example the
i mean estimate for the state
you can obtain uncertainty estimate about the state using the state covariance
you can do a recursive least squares and the state doesn't evolve time is like
fixed parameter
that's basically a type of the kalman filter
you can do to fix like smoothing by augmenting the states to include not just
the current state was some previous state
will get you a bit more money you have to modify the state space model
to give you the correct update on the axis but otherwise
everything follows the same
and similarly if you want to do is fixed interval smoothing estimating the whole sequence
of x is given the whole sequence of y then the kalman smoother operates backwards
in time so one filter forwards through the data and then the equivalent equations backwards
through time to take you back to the data to estimate the posterior distribution of
particular time point t
for example
recursively backwards in time given all of the data
and you can do similar things with the particle filters so there's also particle smoother
so we can say this is very much related to calcium so why is that
the case
we believe that we have a set of
input output pairs
now the data are made of pairs he had axes implies and we assume that
the x otherwise i just real
values that money is on a multi dimensional thing so again the idea would be
so we're after
a straight line
so and now this is the generative model point of view so we get some
so x is unwise
the idea of
is to get a straight line through it so now let's we all know
one way of doing it is of course the least square method but this is
a way of justifying this from probabilistic model point of view
so now we believe that actually there is the true straight line and what we
see these data is a straight line plus noise so here's the straight lines w
not plus w one
on new
some statistically independent calcium noise to it
i believe so what you you see is the function in here
so there is always some noise added
OK so let's write down again what is the probability
of getting the data
given the parameters
now we have two parameters we got w norton w one
two values
so we just form a vector
w these two values and then right and what's the probability density for having an
x and y and we assume that everything
it sort of happens independently for
for these many data
that is first of all well there is something that generates dx is that we're
not interested at the moment in modeling this so it's just some function p of
x and we don't have to bother with this is when we are interested in
in estimating the w because it turns out that this part will be irrelevant
a maximum likelihood
so we can assume there is some function p of x
so what i'm doing here is i'm writing something well
i hope you're familiar with that i'm writing a joint distribution in terms of
conditionals and marginals so if i have
a density of two variables x and y i can write this is the p
of y
given x
times of p of x so this is done in this line
so in that condition conditioned on the value of x i say that y is
in this way so this is kind of the the way to write down the
generator if i have x
then y is computed by the simple linear relation plus
subgaussian noise is added
what is this
what is why conditioned on x
well why conditional nexus the following i know
the noise is calcium let's say
well i have the assumption
there is
it has variance sigma again we can include the variance sigma into the parameters and
so we don't know it's let's estimated from the data
so we know
this noise is
has variance sigma
and and mean zero
so the idea is the following what is then y
given x well we know
for a given x this is not random at all
but this is just a fixed number
if i six x
the parameters w one and w not
so this is a fixed number so i know that y
for fixed x
it is also calcium because i added calcium with zero mean to some number so
it's also becoming calcium with the same variance
now the mean is this
so means that p y
given x and all the parameters here
is then one over two pi sigma squared
e to the minus
why in here has to come
sigma square has to come in the mean time we put up until the what's
medium util well me tilde is the mean
for this for y
and this is
we know
why fluctuates around
w not class
w one x
so this is what i have here
this is a generative model
of course now this would open up the possibility saying well
i believe actually there's a lot of outliers or things like that so you could
come up with models for outliers you could come up with models that say
well i know you know galaxy in that falls off very fast exponentially e to
the minus something to the square so well i believe actually there's it's more factor
distribution outside so i just let's come up with something that looks like this
this will be plus noise for instance
so it's not like e to the minus lamp
absolute value for let's say let's call the noise said
and then that would be a density
you could also say well maybe noise is just additive only adds positively
like you know whatever rainfall totals
something a number that adds to something not subtract so we could come up with
noise looks only like this
so this whole
type of modelling would sort of allows for the noise process is that we think
maybe more relevant to the data
in any case this is now
the probability of of of
the data and we can write again a log likelihood
first of all writing a product
taking the log of it
and so here at the moment just written down everything
it depends only on
w one w norton w one and i can or all the other bits for
instance look p
of x
because we're not interested in modelling
the generation of these inputs
so this is all these bits to do not depend on w norton w one
i don't want to solve that because in any case we see what's happening we
the negative
likelihood is just some
of squares and this is nothing but
the least squares fitting of the curve
four gaussians
well just
derived from the calcium model
the rest are
so this
her research
or is
there's a
this is
nine here
three which
that's what you that
how do you
so of now
how to use
is one of the key
here are
there was no more
you my name
he's your
so he
each year is the current
right now it's
so what we do
three things which are not
you might be more
thank you guys this is just a really fun day for me and i'm so
appreciative to everybody so i don't know when you win an academy award how you
actually have to give thanks to so many people
and the first of all i want to thank you are personally for nominated me
for this award
and then i want to find the review committee that consisted of of this morning
about four words
and grey bill
joe coyle
larry squire
and that's all snyder
to those of you who don't know these are absolutely giants in the field of
neuroscience and in absolute giants chris barber what's won the nobel prize in physiology in
two thousand two
and to be considered and then voted to
this award by that group of people is just
still just amazes me so i am deeply appreciative
and of course i'm deeply appreciative to the government foundation for having this award and
finally to merge can course at school for being at school like and having work
have the foresight to endow this wonderful prize in his name
and i think it is very difficult for and i am sure he's very happy
about it so i had a great day i had a wonderful time of the
board and so i'm going to do is to tell you what case
a little bit about working our laboratory all of the last forty years
looking at brain systems involved in fear and anxiety and extinction
and have to work out hero i know because i can't really see the screen
so let me try this one and
can you hear in the back now
that's fine
so this course is work that has been done by a large number of students
i've only listed if you hear that are going to continue to contribute to what
i'm actually be
discussing today
and these are students postdocs colleagues that have worked on all of these projects i'm
simply presenting their data
and i also do have to give this disclosure that i have a pattern for
the use of cognitive enhancers as an adjunct to psychotherapy
and i am entitled to royalties from this company called take the should this work
be commercialized you'll understand later when i need to make that disclosure
so the take-home messages in the first part of the talk are that the amygdala
is particularly the central nucleus of the amygdala the middle has lots of different groups
of cells the central nucleus is involved in something like stimulus specific fear
another part of the so-called extended amygdala is called the bed nucleus of the street
running hours and that's involved in something i think is more like anxiety
and what we think anxiety is in more operational sense
it is is really sustain fear due to relief of release of the particular peptide
could called corticotropin releasing hormone that actually comes from the amygdala acts on receptors in
the bed nucleus to protect produced the sustains a and and try to explain what
i mean by that
so the
the paradigm that we use is called the fear potentiated startle paradigms for fear potentiated
startle test and it stems from anecdotal evidence that if you're scared you tend to
so if you're walking down a dark alley somewhere in boston tonight you'll apprehensive and
something startles issues such as a cat marking the top of the medal as can
you feel yourself jump more than you normally do and this is actually shown many
years ago by brown kalish and farber and we adopted their paradigm so basically what
we do is we make an animal afraid of some stimulus in this case the
and we do that by pairing the light with a shock so it's a very
short lives about three about three seconds and then we bring the animal back a
day later month later two months later doesn't matter they remember that as long as
we test and we put them in this cage the specially designed to measure the
amplitude of the startle reflex
and now we elicit startled with the loud sound either in the presence or absence
of the light and the phenomenon is that when the animals afraid by virtue having
pair that light with the shock they start more to the loud sound than they
do in the absence of that and we can measure that automatically
by a trans ducer here called an accelerometer
that puts out of voltage that is proportional to how much the cage moves which
in turn is proportional to how much the animals startles
and these are the kind of data that we get in this paradigm so this
is the amplitude of startling darkness
this is the amplitude of startle to the same auditory stimulus in the presence of
the light and this is our operational definition of fear and what this says is
that the animal stalls more to the loud sound in the presence versus the absence
of the light and it turns out the variety of compounds the reduce anxiety and
fear and people in this case bellingham have a reasonably selective effect that is they
don't do much the basic startle reflex but what they do is they selectively decrease
the fear potentiated component consistent with the idea that they reduce fear and anxiety in
this was the state of affairs about thirty five years ago we had discovered a
way to measure this objectively
and we were very interested in in the neural mechanisms that were involved but you
know how do you go about doing that you have a rat is very complicated
and there's also the question of why these square of all the things we could
how do we come up with this criteria for minimizing the square of the error between
the predictions of the hypothesis and and the values y predictive so why not minimize
you the absolute value of the areas arizona or the errors the power for some
what need to do now is present one set of assumptions that will serve to
quote justify
while minimizing the sum of squares error
on the tenth of the the many assumptions that are sufficient to justify why we
do these queries and this is just one of them on so so
you know there's just because they present was assumptions under which the squares regression makes
sense on but this is not the only sort of assumptions so even if the
assumptions i i described don't whole these square actually still makes sense in many circumstances
but this of the help
if one rationalization one reason for the squares regression
i don't think we we to do is on
and and out of the least squares model with probabilistic semantics
so let's see you in my example or predicting housing prices
that's the
so the price the whole system forth
it's going to be some linear function of the features plus on some term epsilon
i and epsilon i will be
no error term
you think
the error term has capturing and model effects
like that maybe there are some other features of the holes like holly fireplaces has
led us regarding the whatever
there are additional features and we just have to capture or you can think of
as long as random noise
so follows that every term that captures both these on model effects of the things
we forgot to model may be functions and quite you something
on as well as on
as well as random noise like maybe that data so it was really bad and
so you know he so they just refuse to go through surprise
and now
i assume that the errors
have on
i have had the power distribution assume that errors epsilon i are distributed just so
the nodes of sunni
is distributed according to a probability distribution that's calcium distribution with mean zero
and variance sigma square
so they use scripts n here on any sense the normal to denote the normal
distribution also known as the gauss in distribution
with mean zero covariance sigma
i think we can raise your hand if you see any cows in distribution or
the call must also one
in other words on the density for gaussians is busy scenes for the density for
and i will be very similar
two things
the density for
that's all i will be the bell-shaped curve
you know the
with one standard deviation
so cyc
on this is one of those secret
recent works
so this implies that
the probability distribution of the height of the horse
given by
and the parameters theta
obtrusions and ligatures
had enlarged the mouth cut away the lips led bare the gums distended the ears cut
the cartilages displaced the eyelids and the cheeks enlarged the zygomatic muscle
pressed the scars and cicatrices to a level turned back the skin over the lesions whilst
the face was thus stretched
from all which resulted that powerful and profound piece of sculpture
the mask
Gwynplaine the search for the interest in of the grotesque also leads us to that
image to imagine
the deformity
that drags to our the tragic destiny
those who may be mean by nature are condemned by their own bodies
like the first and happy ugly man of romanticism the monster in frankenstein
or the heroes of verdi's melodramas like rigoletto
or cyrano de bergerac
as well as women condemn to an everlasting unhappiness by their unpleasant countenance
there is a short story
by zola
le repourssoir
a certain Durandeau realizes them that
on scene
two women walking together and when one of them is visibly ugly
then by contrast everyone finds the other one pretty
so he decides to make ugliness the business
and sets up an agency were ladies can hire an ugly female partner
to stroll along the side and thus highlight their own good looks
eventhough sometimes the client is even uglier than other companion is offered to her
and then she discover her own scarce attractiveness all in that moment
it's awful to read about the recruitment process and the way which ugly women
are told about the reasons and the purpose
for them being hired
but what is even worse is the suffering of the chosen candidates
who after enjoying a day spent dressed elegantly at the theater or an
expensive restaurant in the company of a high society lady must return to their lonely
lodging of an evening faced with the mirror that reminds them of the atrocious
and it is the same mirror which is quoted by the young sartre
in which he discovered his own condition of an irremediably unattractive man
and an ugly duckling beyond redemption terrible pictures
was especially indulgent even with the most repugnant forms of physical
decomposition poems by baudelaire and and from the nineteenth century onwards
the corruption caused by lung disease is a sublimated not
only by literature but also by painting
whether the artists make
idolized portrayals of the exhaused abandoned of beauty on the verge
of death
let me quote only short passage from barbey d'aurevilly yes my lea you are
you are the most beautiful of creatures I wouldn't give up your defeated eyes your pallor your sick body
I would not give them for the beauty of the angles in the heavens
in the heavens
that dying women burnt him like the most ardent of
in the beginning of the twentieeth century the futurists fought against moonlight
museum and libraries and set themselves the task of boldly producing
and the palazzeschi
in Il controdolore called for the younger generations to receive an education in the disgusting
we have to teach our children to laugh to laugh the most unrestrained insolent laughter
we will supply them with educational toys hump humpbacked blind gangrenous crippled
consumptive syphilitic puppets that mechanical cry shout complain are afflicted with epilepsy plague cholera hemorrhoids
the clap insanity puppets that faint emit the death rattle and die
their teacher will suffer from dropsy and elephantiasis or be thin as a rail
long limbed with the neck like a giraffe one tiny little teacher a stunted hunchback and
another gigantic teacher with the prepubescent face and extremely feeble voice
who weeps tars tears like shards of glass
we futurists want to cure the latin races especially our own of
of conscious pain conformist syphillis aggrevated by the chronic romanticism and of the monstrous susceptibility
and piteous sentimentalism that depress every Italian we want to substitute the
use of perfumes with the use of stench transforming insane asylums into
finishing school for our new generations
boccioni called a sculpture also that painting antigrazzioso
and up right then German Expressionist portrayed with systematic and ruthless insistence haggard and repugnant
will located
and some of you want know that two or three on that file sequence
what i did so it was that i i'm at
ten five around here
and i'm that the difference between where where the or should be given that i've
got the the building blocks of the detector and the actual like words
you actually see that
but i actually think that are
that helps me to the search will was actually making things problematic to sense that
i there's a lot of noise in the school so if i to have a
face detector and i want to go use in based recognition or want to go
use that expression recognition all want to go
news it's a
in recognizing motorcycles or or
OK and things like i've got all this noise
president my signals
because i'm not only so i've got a lot want to separate one one person's
identity from another person's identity coupled in there
is this what noise because
the things that align properly so pixels long probably without the pixel
and so
i need to improve upon this along and just pure translation scale is not to
this is a slightly less naive approach
so instead of simply through all possible positions from the best match
that's the standard linear regression can we later as you as well the statue of
volcanology regression between the appearance displacement
and the what spice
OK i can expand upon what i mean by that
so we we no longer have to make assumptions about discrete assumptions about what this
is one thing i really like this instead of having to
kind of all we have to give you have all this give the positive and
negative object classes can actually have an object an object detector where i can precisely
recognise you object to some sort of hard parametric what sort of finds exactly have
always annoys nose-to-nose mouth-to-mouth rather kind had some game
and also away the given that are making the wall much more complex is are
in continuous now is or whether to make the computation based
and so
what we essentially trying to do
is that if one of the cover regression
between essentially what we want to do
is that if i got this image here
which is the aligned image minus
this image which is the whole people of misaligned images i want to learn a
between the the displacement of all these values and don't appear
which is which is my which is my walk noise
another and so on got a couple of properties but i need first define the
distribution what this talk he should be
so i mean how far
can i have can i take this assumption and things that how far this regression
where can i make delta p like how can i go hundred by pixels are
going to about two pixels have partial my delta patient
and actually more the question is is there a relationship and what we can being
naive here i mean the
can we actually do something that doesn't make any sense
and then when does the relationship occur by which comes back to answer these two
if you remembering from what we've shown in the previous slides you should be able
to guess that well that doesn't really relate relationship doesn't it if we look at
the pixel coherence assumption
pixels are correlated with each other least individually over small area so that does seem
to be some sort of relationship that we can leverage the same as it doesn't
seem like we can come to go
so pixel at point zero zero twenty two highly correlated with the pixel let's say
fifty fifty or sixty sixty image things so that the assumptions one you guys so
so i can quantify this what can i do
so undermining of the pixel coherence assumption
moving around and we get this kind of nice graceful the degradation the correlation
for natural image
and then might have target patches i think they just put in that that like
the fact that this is not
so pixel coherence so the pixel coherence assumption demonstrates the pixels within natural images are
heavily correlated with one another and within sight a local area this is again at
war with itself plus and minus five pixels it depends on the same scale and
also it's fine enough depends on what the content of the images but generically can
quite safely say that natural image so we can actually do a pretty good job
if we know that this is an actual image predicting even if this pixels missing
of predicting what this pixel is so i can probably take the average order all
these other values and
it comes at three princes
i think so
and i can very very the support region around the missing pixels things but generally
a local region there highly correlated likely
and so
what i can actually
i don't
it is a kind of incorporate the idea the image gradient into my idea of
and so we touched upon the image gradients already for aliasing kind deal with in
doing the by linear interpolation and things so
great it's going to come back and help us actually to do the search so