and then adding in a decision noted that leaf
so as to minimize some sort of an empirical criterion some sort of error criterion
based on the on the training data
and there
there are various heuristics i mean it's common to grow to grow tree completely until
the tree correctly classifies all the data
and then and then prune the tree
the print back according to some
it's an empirical criterion again
OK i will be considering these as examples of basis classes for instance for
methods that combine classifiers
OK so let's think about
that those voting method
so here
class of functions
these these functions that
again there
they're thresholded linear combinations but now not of the
components of the vector x but of functions defined on x functions from some
basis class g
OK so
here we're taking you can think of this is
each if t is a member of that committee
right after some
basis function maybe it's a decision tree
and when combining those FT's with some real valued weights
and then we're taking the weighted majority decision
OK so and an example
there were considered to later again this is these cheese very small decision trees decision
trees of depth one these are these are also called decision stumps
OK so the class here
these are just functions that map two
the two values depending on some
linear threshold function on a single
single component of the input vector
one class of algorithms for
working with this class of functions
other boosting algorithms that maintain
some sort of a probability distribution over the data
and choose the basis functions
in order
in some sequential order at each step
some sort of an empirical criterion
and typically this can be expressed just in terms of the
this weighting function is weighted empirical error
and the intuition
here is that they were adjusting the
the distribution of the data so as to emphasise the mistakes that
committee our previous combination has made on the door
because of the need to spell out
the particular approach
taken with with that of ship
well let me just let let me just say that
adaboost is is one approach you with the weighting is chosen such so as to
the choice of the weighting corresponds to choosing a function
from the space the linear span of our basis class
so as to minimize
the sample average of some exponential
exponentially decreasing function of y times f of x
OK so
intuitively you know if f of x is this real valued
real valued function
why is it takes values plus and minus one
you know it seems reasonable that we would be trying to
to find a small value of this
criterion which corresponds to
y times f of x being large and positive
right so that means that has the correct sign
OK and
i think that's also fine now about that boosting algorithms kernel methods
and you've seen
we've seen this here we
we've got a rather general
the main input space x on which we we define an inner product
and come up with a suitable inner product
i should say and come up with a hilbert space
is the reproducing kernel hilbert space
and the class of functions that we're considering
we can view SVM ends is working with
a bounded subset of linear functions
right so
we look at
functions that that
compute just inner products
right but there
the the the functions of bounded the RKHS norm of functions is bounded
equally we can parameterize by an element of the public space
and think of
the parameter
w is having found all
and again just as in the perceptron case
you know the the neat thing about
this kind of approach is that even with the general inner product on on complicated
space we can always represent the
the function implicitly
using this dual representation
uh by
recording just the weights associated with each just the weight associated with each
each of the excise in training data
right in the approach that's used in the typical SVM is to
consider that cluster functions and we minimize some empirical criterion
all right this is the sample average of a cost function again involving y times
f of x plus a penalty term so this is the regularisation
kind of approach we have the regularized empirical
criterion here
and the cost function that we're concerned with
right and in this case is is a piecewise linear function it's the the hinge
all right so
this was intended to give you an overview of the
kinds of approaches that i want to consider
function classes and algorithms for pattern classification
now let's get on two
performance guarantees so getting risks pounds four
algorithms of this kind
so the general approach that i want to use here is the is is rademacher
start by telling you a bit about you know the the very idea of wristbands
i guess that we want to understand how we should control the complexity of the
functions that we have so it's the best trade off the
the competing issues right the that we face these approximation a particular approximation estimation
let's recap where
well up to in the course and what relevant readings in the textbook is
we done a information theory data compression and coding when now inference and data modeling of course
relevant chapters are shown here that you know nothing about what colour methods
nine that
variational methods coming up in the next lecture at the right
like the highlight some additional reading
which covers material we were doing lectures but it's a good thing to do at the cost
i encourage you to read a very short chapter called what is meant that twenty seven
hand in order to understand this lecture and the next one
you may want to read about ising models in chapter that was not already
familiar with them
there's a whole bunch recommended exercises on
the website and
the only screen
you may enjoy
doing the same thing
you want fully understand the material then
doing exercises there
keep this course
the course website in there
the book's website is there
we're in the middle talking about what elements
in the last lecture we introduce them
basic standard want our methods
and the rules of the game are that we are interested in
i read this region called papers and it's red is a bit nasty
it's not
utterly that's we can compute it
so we can write it in minus
on z
and we have got a computer program that can
evaluate this thing before any
the value of x x being a high-dimensional thing
these properties were interested in the distribution
so the rules of the game are
so you can evaluate
but not
z we don't know z
z would be the first we'd like to know there
and we often give up on their because it's so hard know it
and the problems with
i've seen on the one hand
problem one
did make an example
there are
the company
problem that has
you know by solving a problem on or in some other way please tell me
the expected value of some functions and then
and that's red
the average value on
that is some function i'm interested in
that's the average under the he read
distribution of the body several times and i
we want
the average value of
we can use
the solution to the problem one at the problem to because we can
say well here's an estimator all
the expected value
by hand
coming up
at the random sample that you got from the distribution
looking at the empirical average
possible way of using
along to
anne sometimes today than he read distribution
will be
that he always been systems the one example i mentioned in the last lecture lectures maybe we are interested in
then we have spin system with an energy
that depends on the coupling yet
ant d
you need to robots
on the
so this sort of thing seems to be good for
think of reason
so far
should we also actually what i said was sent to what what's new sense
the very fast
notion of how this
there are all kinds of cells in the sense of the centralized computation is that
we are all centralized computation
so that that
i got the assumption
and the point is
well want to know is
the coverage region
because the things
doesn't have other
and is doesn't have gaps
it's curious on what wish
that and see what happens
that allowed
it wasn't the best coverage
with on the ship and crew
so this is this one
this is that we want
it's kind
can't you
what is it really is
so i think
for what i did i
strong reduced
three years
we're all the time
see that
very close to generate lot
the next thing is that this
you can
this was used these users
what is it
then the song has a humid
it means that is really satisfied
we aim
it's not too
one of those circumstances
there exists a surprise
the image
and can do it
he was
how is this
this week
crossing the vision and mission
you do need to be all kinds of things
and you end up with a one sided test set c
published in
your second self yes
multi s
they said yes
the tennessee college
so sitting the car you get to be a call
he says most
what not just yet
why not just
but not just
test has come
c so
you could get false negative you can say not yet you can't guarantee in my
case was
but but on other things that don't know what positives that was
surely there is should
maybe there's whole sentence
but we think not
so we use we use something
the go on precise genetic information
allmusic has become one sided tests
this type one and type two errors
and time
this is what you need to be
and this
it's true one
i just really don't match
the rules that
using the internet
the problem
but this kind of question
it is
the rules
this talk about this in terms of course
this is a generalized
so is
after rain personally
OK this will tell you how likely i to injury encounter that paid or random
given the current model of the web
and i should and
more often on popular pages then
so my webpage
OK so we want to compute the stationary distribution of a lot of markov chain
OK under sir robert certain certain
probability is guaranteed by the way it's set up this there a unique stationary distribution
exists here
so how do i find out the probability of being in each
OK well there's this property so let me set up a
is anyone familiar with the transition matrix
after it will
so a a transition matrix is gonna represent the distribution over the next fifty plus
one given the current state e
so here on the on the columns and guides
current state on the road to the next stage
in every entry in the matrix will be the same probability
of getting to that rose state given that i'm in the called state
however as prime given as
as some
however this
using transmission ixti
so do do the rows columns or someone one
so given that many current state
might just be several possible next has some to one
next a are in the
the rosettes into the one
so they want wanted see the set of
i sorry the columns just
very good
because this situation should should someone
in the course the one i get proper probability distribution
and then if i know
that some state
at some time t
so now
now we may
a vector
from s one down two as
and to use
in by
and encourages in
please just a distribution over
current state
o point one point o one point three
o point five where so that it sums to one
so far i knew that at time t
i had distribution pt
i it is wrong or that i know that my distribution p m t plus
i think is the transition matrix times p so it's either this or the reverse
but you know if it out but the point is that i can't distribution multiplied
by the transition matrix i distribution
if i compute p infinity
given random starting state
that's my stationary distribution
and again you have to certain properties to guarantee that unique
stationary distribution exists
simply because i said that random chance of changing to any page on the web
it's not some problems
the probability that to guarantee that this is the stationary distribution exists
form a markov model
OK so google pagerank simply said the popularity web pages the stationary distribution of that
web page
how often what's the probability in the web page and random surfing
so computing
OK now what away
to solve this
and this
slide here
so what if i said to stationary distribution
OK so so does called high
this is not a policy
this is a stationary distribution
so it is are different sites like
so i'm just
looking at
you have this but you you you you you have this property that p infinity
it was t
p infinity
has a single stationary distribution it back to the stationary distribution
so what you can do
with this
is you can solve a linear system
right so
i can say
tp infinity
minus p infinity
here this pipe there's people here
eagle zero
now in fact around
p infinity
i did t
minus the identity matrix
because there
and now as any constraints on p infinity
like like like like constrained p infinity do any device of this as as as
as a linear system
yes i
seven by transpose
if i additional constraints which are
that the probabilities in the columns sum to one
that's all this solve this this this this linear system
this is
just a linear system right it's linear algebra set of equations
additional constraints saying summer
i have p infinity i one
linear algebra with matrix inversion i can solve this problem is
so we try to convert a trillion dimensional matrix
i don't mind
using this information we are going to constrain the location the possible location of the
person that you can go in this particular seems to want we use it in
terms of floor fields one OK and is motivated by identification and expand the make
this big buildings they have a claimed that there is a fire then how people
are going to make these buildings and they actually fluffy idea
which you can use your so
we have to do is given the location of the person in this frame we
want to find out where it is this person to be
in the next and these are possible places and for each of these players find
the probability of finding confidence and the confidence will depend on the multiple sources of
information and of course appearing but more importantly that seems to show which would be
in terms of flow fields
so fluffy like a very simple we have three kinds of flora field what's gonna
stand floor feed and more to the regions in the scene of which are attractive
in nature like the exact location
his car in the cortex location and the dynamics lockheed martin the local interactions that
that person is going to go based on the neighbouring people and then one of
the flower field is going to look at the which are positive nature and i
was not going to get people i'm going to go there and we want to
model so so in this strange thing we have these three main assumptions one is
we have to say that person is called months ago we actually want to go
and the there is no obstacle
that persons directly going to go there and that will be modest flow
that we have seen the large and i was of quite common structures like three
games was about to various and opposing flows and that's what the flow field in
the final
the person anymore
towards the goal is the flow of the crowd around him or her and that
more the first
so the algorithm is given a sequence like that will our learning period for scene
and you learn static flow fields and the wall computer optical flow and the locations
and then finally sinks which are the places where the motion cease to exist unless
basically why distance for each pixel from that exit location the steady flow field
in the body
he was obviously the segmentation the particle flow may and after defeating and then
find the edges of the boundary fluffy the segmentation and look like a distance transfer
of that i mean
next steps are needed to get the place so given the parts and here we
will look at the appearance and then on my computer
because changing periodically and so given these three philosophies this standing by the flow field
we come of these properties can also be simple idea
but to explain so
the tracking data using these factors that influence the steady flow of
and about the flow field
of course appearance so the main point here is that if you use that appearance
which is traditionally used in the tracking and then you get a flat surface because
the crowd of people who are very similar and that you cannot distinguish them so
you don't have any unique it but if you want to study philosophy dynamic flow
field and so on you get a nice surface and that gives us a unique
place than expected by some to be
so that's the experiments so this sequence so many people here and we want and
the same actually i might
so if you look at these ships could pass
it's pretty small it's about fourteen miles twenty two and had about five hundred frames
was selected by the one
and we would have attracted one hundred forty three of those
so these are kind of typical results showing these tracks by different colours are and
there are lots of five humans it's very difficult to to
keep track of these people show you each independently
a different place one at time
and these are the tracks
and we actually cost and student two
the main trade these people for the country and then
you know we don't want to our
what this work and so these are the competitors tracks the ground truth with our
computed as you see there pretty similar which is good but of course there are
some areas in these areas
and then
so the second sequence even more complex lots of people
these are the and the typical size of what the best sixteen we have about
this is somehow more fragile and gated by context
when you think about it
much of psychotherapy really depends on this extension process if you're afraid of snakes you
don't look at pictures of snakes you touch snakes god forbid let's make no crap
around your neck
but if i can get you look at pictures of snakes make you realize that
can hurt you and that actually touches naked make you realize that they poisonous and
they get support when around your neck you get over the fear of snakes very
well it's very well used the so-called treatment of simple phobias but you actually take
people back to where they have a panic attack they had a panic attack driving
over a bridge you take them back and say you know you not can have
a panic attack again because of petrified of going over the bridge because they're afraid
to have a panic attack if you can talk to get the guy to talk
about the head and head the bamboo platter
reminder that happened forty years ago it's not going to happen to him again for
better for worse that's the best treatment for post-traumatic stress syndrome and people that are
have contamination phobias have to wash their hands continually if you can get in touch
the bottom of the toilet seat and don't let them touch to wash their hands
it's very painful but eventually they realise they don't die if they don't wash their
hands and is effective in treating these people and also cues associated with drug intake
are very powerful listeners of craving
the reason it's so hard to quit cocaine and cigarettes is all these conditions cues
that say what i really want to have a cigarette you know the old joke
is smoke after sex
never looked but the point is you have all these
jane got and she laughed at that point you have all these cues that are
associated with drug intake and they are very powerful listeners
so the idea is that if
we could
we actually say we have some data now
i threw myself off with job
so we actually have some data now
extinction is dependent on gaba and maybe coming from the medial prefrontal cortex great greg
quirk and
together that's my name for me
holland noord done some beautiful work showing that the prefrontal cortex is critically involved in
extinction we don't know what this area is we think it's exerts inhibition by gamma
and so the idea is
sorry i get something wrong with my slides rate if you could combine these cycles
with exposure based psychotherapy could you improve the effectiveness of the therapy so if psychotherapy
depends on this extinction process we know that we can facilitate extinctions with instruction with
animals with the cycle surrounding can you facilitate psychotherapy with the cyclists
so the preload for that is to show
that the NMDA receptor is critical for extinction
and let me just show you a little bit about the NMDA receptor in cartoon
form b is going to talk about two binding sites one glutamate binding site and
another called the glycine binding site
so it turns out that of glutamate binds to the NMDA receptor nothing happens
it requires the concomitant binding of glycine so so if guy senior which are divergence
amino acids bind also nothing happens but now when glutamate binds you get an activation
of the NMDA channel calcium rushes in and things happen in the cell
and so the idea was that if we could block the NMDA receptor could we
block extension
and if so
that would be evidence then that the NMDA receptor was involved in extinction
and so we have two groups of animals we train them to be afraid we
give them a pre-test and that both groups get sixty lights without sharks
after infusion of vehicle or an MBA in tag called a five directly into the
amygdala and then we test them a couple of days later
and sure enough what we find is good extinction the control animals but remarkably a
total blockade of extension in animals and had this NMDA receptor blocker
this is where we get into one of the idea of the cycle serious so
again when you have glycine binding and glutamate binding you get activation of this channel
but under certain circumstances
and so this is what we have here
the these are three different features two on the left are
all relevant features
and the third one is irrelevant feature
the top lots
basically given was unit waiting
this is the
the distribution of information games
and here we have
when we waited using the complexity measure
so the spikes going on on the right these plots
they were actually caused by the smaller nodes to being split
is purely by chance applied to the features
and we find that we actually suppress these when we
i mean on the complexity
that i can see if you take the average of these distributions classifier with the
a much more accurate measure of the feature relevance
OK so what can we do these measures feature relevance well
you could do some sort of feature selection schemes
rank them in order and select the k best output
some sort of threshold
or we could do some sort of feature weighting
well actually rely on the features to a different extent according to how relevant thing
and with random forest we can do this by altering the feature sampling distribution
a member of said that if these features are chosen randomly split with equal probability
now we can do is we can actually change the probabilities so the more relevant
features can be chosen
with greater all this
this can be done in two ways we could do a parallel skiing
we're actually
delta force and after
peachtree we could get some measure of how relevant features are
and use that to update features that distribution
the problem with this is that
in the initial stage of the algorithm
you don't have very much information about features
you have to be careful not to
overweight some features
because the album may not be able to recover from
as persons
the other way and is by using a two stage approach
well we analyse the feature elements
in the first stage
and then we use that to fix
the thing to some distribution prior to the forced construction
OK so a parallel scheme
i want to do is try to control this update right established mission we chose
confidence intervals in this case
we can use this statistic which is the basis of the average information gain here
a theoretical to me
sample size and sample standard deviation
has the
students two distribution minimise one degrees of freedom
so it can form
one conference limits
on the statistic
he went two
which gives us some level of confidence which we can set so we would use
ninety five percent the case
and organism rearranged so we get these confidence bounds
on our project management which
now the idea is that once before these
confidence intervals around it to measure feature relevance with within use that to update the
petersen distribution by maintaining the uniform distribution
but it still lies within each of these confidence intervals
so that was the algorithm proceeds these companies will become smaller
starts also the features and distribution to a greater extent
but in the initial stages
it should
ere on the side of caution
OK so i'm going to get the convergence rates
these plots
these plots showing
the average confidence interval size
averaged over all of features for the datasets
these convergence rates
basically reflects how fast we converted into of
to some distribution
they depend on the level of conferences also depend on the number of features in
the data and on the average tree size sixty percent of its
it's got slower convergence because has got the highest number of features
and this built six large trees so not generating
but many samples
the all the visible clustering functions do satisfy
this relaxed
consistency requirements
you can you can play with expansion for every pair but i want do it
when you allow
constance for every pair of clusters you can create a counterexample like this because
is if i ever had
human history clusters
now expanded such as this cluster is here this clusters is here and third class
that is here
and now what you actually do is say this is one cluster and the cluster
because with these proportions they look to get
so i want to fix constants for the between cluster in the
so we have such
relaxation of those axioms in such a way that we have pretty happy every natural
clustering function satisfies all of them
of course to show that every now and clustering function fails one of them
we have to come up with an exhaustive list of not clustering functions and
that's not something which is readily
do it but i don't know how to formulate
as a summary
come on
let me give you some examples of clusterings which do not fall into the climate
agreement so the climate is that your input is just a pair set of points
and pairwise distances
but sometimes when you do clustering
the relationship you look not just pairwise relationship that so for example in edge detection
if i just gave you pairs of distances you will not know which points on
the same page but
a relationship like this if i
if you have points like this and say
you want to cluster this picture and we naturally cluster into here is one class
here's another cluster
but not
looking at the pairwise distances but we're looking at the linear relationship which involves triples
of points rather than pairs of points on may be more than triples of points
so it doesn't fall into the framework the clustering is just the function of pairs
here the the function could be
the clustering could be a function of
triple wise
relationship which collinearity
so edge detection is a good example of clustering
which is that in practice but does not fall into this framework which is based
on just the with this is that we're
now i'm not fully contributors
no i think i if i apply to our intuitive semantics of what to do
when you do edge detection
we do have class and detection is the task is to use clustering for when
you have a big show you want to detect objects you do education is all
those points lying on the same page
if you just you just to thank you all
i'm talking about you you assume that your picture is now called it is just
binary prefixes
and now you want to detect just on by over binary mixtures saying it on
all binary pixels when you want to say those i mean an edge is more
than just the pairwise distances it is some notion of linearity of continuity of the
past or simplicity of the past the connector
you can easily do it in the petitioning i mean i'm
and that better drawing but it could be the case that your point
look like this
right now i ask you to clustering and you say here is one class and
here's another cluster and there's no point belong simultaneously to both clusters
with what is it that's what
OK so my data representation here is just a set of elements and pairwise distances
and what i'm saying is that some things which cannot be captured by this very
simple representation
if i have here on top of the distances between the points i also have
some geometrical structure i e really embedded in two
and i have some relationship which are
more complex adjust the pairwise distances
in this analysis
the input is only a set of pairwise this
why not
OK but also way so vector quantization he's
and if you center is allowed to be UK you can also formulas k means
in this way
because k means although all the information it looks at is the pairwise distances you
want to minimize
you worried about choosing the centre outside your inputs it
right but you can say this can be overcome by some technicolor addition but if
not just consider vector quantization in which you are forced to pick
but i don't want to get into this game of examples and counterexamples i enjoyed
very much but i don't think it's so instructed the use of of the time
here is another example of clustering which is not
based on just what this is and this is a texture clustering if i give
you such a picture editor class right
then you say
i mean and you can have more interesting result it just means limitation enjoying
of text they want to cluster things by the texture it's more than just the
pairwise distances it's something about more points together relationship which involve more points together
and now that nice example that i know that i really like
is the professors example because all is perfect example of clustering one of clustering task
people at NIPS especially like to test themselves on is you take the web pages
of your university that's what you have
there is an underlying function why
the generated the data by flipping bent coins with bias so why
so that's the interpolation of this so
why using a bent coin
of virus
what this means
the regularizer that's being used a penalized enormous weights because we decided we didn't like enormous waste
is interpreted as the prior belief about the weights that says if you w is
of w squared for example is saying that the prior probability of w
is a normal distribution
the main zero
hand with standard deviation
sigma squared
is equal to one overall for so this parameter alpha which a moment ago
a moment ago is a pain in the neck arbitrary regularisation constant is now interpreted as being the variance
have a prior distribution
this interpretation can be
ignored or it can be exploited
the exportation says okay let's take this literally and then we can do a whole new things
for example we can actually ask
what's the right way to turn inference into prediction
if someone asks for prediction what should do
well if you believe this model is correct
and you're asked to predict what's the probability that the next thing that we just
observed at location x plus x and plus one
is in class one what's the probability that this new point on the screen at say they'll be or wherever
what's the probability
that same potato
or cat
or raising
the data
we've seen so far and all the assumptions
will be answered that question isn't found by saying please work at the w that
minimizes this and then use to make predictions you answer is done
by marginalizing so the correct answer if you believe all these assumptions is you should marginalise
over w
posterior probability p w given data
multiplied by the prediction which is why
evaluated at
example of one
the parameters
so that's what you actually ought to do if you believe the assumptions that you've implicitly
in making
that's an example of
an average value of a simple function under nasty
hand we know freeways
the cat sat elephant
we can use monte carlo methods
we can use variational methods
we can use
the pluses methods
so let's do that
just to make clear what is read the nasty red distribution is thing posterior probability the weights given the data
and that's
is this thing here
it's a nasty red thing
but we can compute it has the form the minus and w
and we have got a formula four
so we can attack this in a variety of ways
and the first one way i will use is called multicolored
so we can take our handbook a monte carlo methods
we can say
goodness me
forward five sites and
we can say
let's give ourselves and one colour methods
use carlo
evaluate this quantity here
how different is that's well if we use
hamiltonian monte carlo during the hamiltonian encounter a few lectures ago
don't involve computing the gradient and then going downhill with momentum and randomizing the momentum from time to time
a very simple version a very hamiltonian monte carlo methods called along provide methods
which involves
going downhill a little bit and adding some noise
how does different differ from steepest descent
it differs by
having a better noise
so steepest descent just goes downhill
what we're gonna do now is to see sense with a bit of noise
under the and accept reject decision in there as well
so we can use the long bound methods hand if we go back to
this thing
what we will now see
the larger methods starting from
this place at the origin
where we use the just go downhill and here's where we ended up having gone
downhill when just the same amount of computer time all we have to do
is going downhill and add some noise is actually not a huge cost to do this
fancy bayesian inference methods you just add some noise at the right amount of noise
and it put in accepts and rejects to make sure it's all
here's what happens in a zoom in on the first elbow be optimization
so this is the first album
and during the same amount of computer time is where we get to
with a large methods are goes on around the goes are generally downhill that adding noise in an interesting way
what you can think of happening is we used go
in w space w one w two
it's actually three dimensional for this toy problem we use go downhill to an optimum
now we are being there as the minimum of the red
function which
has some
strange shaped like this
hand we're going downhill and adding noise in such a way as the sample from time red distribution
okay here's what happens after forty thousand iterations we commonly believe only and we've sampled
from the entire red
and we can take those sample points
hand add up
the predictions why
for each of those so we can approxlmate
this using the standard monte carlo idea
this is approximately one over are
are is what are
the second plus one
using weight
are where these weights
w are
come from
the miracle monte
hamiltonian in
all right that's the plan so suggested just some a are often
and i'll be there right now
so manganese forty thousand just pick
hundred also samples
here's what the weights were doing with time wandering up and down autocorrelated weight
built with what
and then you see some improving coming down
both sides see that year
nicely insulated plastic
norris regular TED for nothing special
and then he was a coffee can and here is a coffee can
open he open here
open he opened must be met
everything that you see
you can read must be metal
it's essential for
this to work
and no
you left the water running
out here in know groundwater on their so you see water running here
you can sort of just
and collected here
in two
metal rockets use one of them
and here is the
what is important now
that was some copper or some other
you can connect this
with this one
this can with this one this means that these two should not touch to other
means you have to jump over see you see them here
they are not touching
and now you bought
all of these cancers
a metal rods and then at the end of the rod
you can easily
demonstrated you get sparks
you can get sixty thousand volts and today as i said maybe
only twenty
thirty thousand falls and this is called
one drop
it was
he invented by
englishman william ponsonby lord kelvin
in the nineteenth century
so i'll started running now
and then i will change the light situation so that
you know the better
look at it
i think it's running
i we have bubbles that's not so good
is it to TV setting three
so let me change the light settings a little
all three
and one and four
then see
the opening year and if you wait and you look you you will see there
is this one
look at the you can see it but also look there
to be a little patient
there's another one
and so the gap opening is like a spark plug
is about half a centimeter
so i would say
fifteen twenty thousand holes
and this can be built on i'll tell you what this key if you want
to build it at all
it's not difficult
what is key is
that this can
and this can
supported by a very high insulating material you can see that here
is a huge collateral or plastic
and this is also plus
equally important is
that these buckets at the bottom which are made of metal
i completely insulated from the table
so you can put them for instance on a stack of a glass
plates or porcelain plates if you have
but if you put him straight on the table you will never work
and that's the mistake that most students make
that they don't have the proper
electric installation where it's needed
this has to be supported
with scintillators
and also with and then you can do it
it's not that difficult
the ultimate
as the features may be to discuss is one along the lines of what he
said was starting to say
how to move around in machine learning what kind of directions you
wonderful when you start doing research and then the other one as this
what is there and beyond phd what kind of professional perspective
don't want to have have the luck of having people who are doing right now
research in quite different context from green continuous so teaching and research to people who
are have started their own company working for other companies and i think will benefit
from seeing this
a different perspectives
of course this is just two questions have gotten to use so actually
very much
even more like if you have anything else to say that after all these experiences
in research and teaching and applications of machine learning
all experiences our personal experiences so restrictive as well as possible
one school
start maybe discussing along the lines of what is it that has said
i don't want anything else
link is not the same
that during the puberty when you begin to use you really want to thank you
have the ability of the musing so you go
directly to the court because that's what he nutrition
in part of machine tools
but it's true that
finishing on that you have to register
go back
and use you really
and you see that the really important part is the motivation really blending what is
the proper way to
they want to use the internet
graphical instead
the same is more important to be considered
calling the are telling me that some people from among us probably are more method
oriented so we see all to use this method
because that's what we know find applications for these
you may be trying to return to tell me
but l
everybody wants to ensure that if
about the
the UM and this sort of thing OK so i'm not going to take the
the two questions the two
could just trying to say
so i mean
right and i'm just looking at the field
mainly in france seeing how out there are they are not perspective with machine learning
and they are highly dispersive b
this last term
france what she for postdocs doctorates and for the positions seem to be hot
and i don't have a lot to some degree not censoring courage
nevertheless what you get when you look into this was people were really looking for
people where just capable of developing new theories machine i they want to use it
in whatever they were working with they wanted to work with machine that meant they
the road good machine probably open minded to do think
the same time
that's when got to
got during system
you can doesn't mean spread out all sorts of things which to everywhere but doesn't
mean you keep your eyes open and say it's not just truth she but there
are going editors as we were talking earlier about biology
so that you talk about about surely no more that was going to give an
example in this he
called user model
modeling is why the name indicates which is one the the model of used and
typically then use that to be able to
they will fall into different made sometimes
but the frequency with which he land into
one night compared to another may doesn't necessarily have anything to do with the probability
mass inside this means
so it doesn't guarantee that you will get the right answer might be that ninety
percent of your chains will fall into this matrix of the big basin of attraction
and algorithm
but in fact most of the matter over here
and the painful short answer is that there is no magic bullet to this algorithms
are described very simple and they have very
like technical requirements but it also means they can't guarantee against really nasty distributions i
mean you construct
a probability distribution with a really massive but type peak hidden somewhere
viscerally then
there's no way any reasonable algorithm will find it unless you put in knowledge about
the topic and the
you've got to sort of just always be slightly on your
so i'm just posting here the argument about them that you can that's just for
the record if you look into the slide slides already on the website
here's a couple of figures from a paper by cosmic which is an example of
like a typical thing people will do when they're running the chain so he's running
a markov chain on high dimensional parameter space and here are some of the parameters
and his chain and he's plotting various things about these parameters as that he he's
visited his his change so
this plot here is something called the autocovariance and the saying
what's the
covariance between a parameter in the chain and say that the same parameter six hundred
steps later so
is six hundred that long enough to forget where you come from is the autocovariance
very small
and he plotted this for a lot of different quantities because they're not experienced classes
certain plot about a scalar quantity so you could imagine the saying well i'm going
to do your current plot
for the probability you can just sort of plot what happened to the probability of
your training you would get one of these cats
the color very sensibly drew lots of these curves one for each parameter in this
model because it looked at a lot of this has very re-paint it looks as
though the chains mixing almost immediately because the autocovariance drops to close to zero almost
immediately for most of his parameters these identified one parameter where in fact
the last time is very long looks to take a very long time for the
chain to forget about
where it came from in terms of the parameter k and model
if you're going to do some sort of diagnostic
so you gnostics might tell you make some very quickly and everything is fine and
you're going to have to go away and do several diagnostics and there's no sort
of magic bullet for the different things you could try
what it identified this parameter the problem he's drawn plot of where that parameter actually
over time so
he initialize the somewhere
and after several thousand iterations it looks as though the statistics of what that parameter
doing change from this initial run this the classic sort of science then inherited you
might want to
toss out the results from these initial few thousand iterations
i've given here a couple of references and the reason i'm taking this these plots
from someone else's papers because i'm not an expert on this sort of error comparatively
diagnosing attend and i think it's safe to really
unless you're doing research in this area to just
following someone else's precise instructions because then you can blame them say rather than i
did this and i did this and i did this which would be very sensible
trial of things you like when you're writing the paper you cite someone and say
i did exactly the thing they to do that level
so a software package called code which provides the whole in diagnostic routines and you
have to use our which i don't but i just want my data out to
file what the minimal staffing catering read back in
and this paper here has been very sensible intelligent discussion about all of these issues
stemming running multiple runs and then so i highly recommend sort of looking at that
much more lengthy discussion if you're interested in doing things in practice
questions that were
the question is why am i calling this mixing and
one answer is i'm probably being incredibly useful the term because some people mean something
very specific so down
close attention to my precise vocabulary but
i mean loosely the idea is that you're just trying to
one around the whole space so are you stuck in one little river region all
has your chains to mixed with interesting regions
this is what error analysis is
you have a long complicated pipeline to combining many machine learning components so many of
these values and learning algorithms
and so
is often very useful to figure out how much of the error
can be attributed to each of these components
well one two in the air analysis procedure
is will repeatedly poking the ground truth for each component and see how we have
seen this
so what i mean by that is on
the figure on the bottom left to bottom right that city of accuracy of the
system is a five percent
the like to know
where my fifteen percent error comes from
and so what i do is of course my test set and actually code in
our service that actually implements my correct
on background vocals actually go going give it give my album what is the correct
background versus foreground
the idea that discovered that due to now that i'm giving that ground truth data
in the test set
that's accuracy increases the five point one percent
and now i'll go in and you get my out the ground truth face detection
what's going actually on my test set i just tell the our where the faces
of i do that
that same albums accuracy increases in ninety one percent and and so on and go
for each of these components
and just give it
on the ground truth label for each other components because to that no segmentation i
was trying to find figure one knows is going and tell us when knows is
that it doesn't feel and as i do this one component through the other end
up giving at the correct output label and i one hundred percent accuracy
and now you can look at this table serves color from the bottom to says
logistic regression i'm not going to the stable
and on c
you know how much getting the ground truth labels for each of these components could
help us to find the performance
in particular the stable you notice that when i added the face detection ground truth
performance jump from eighty five point one percent accuracy
o to ninety one percent accuracy
so this tells me that the only i can get better face detection
maybe i improves the accuracy by six percent
on the west in contrast when i say a in better
background removal my accuracy improves from eighty five to eighty five point one percent
so the sort of diagnostic also tells you that if goes to improve the system
it's a waste of your time to to try to improve the background subtracted because
even if you got ground truth this gives you most point one percent accuracy
well as you can do better face detection maybe much larger potential for things
so this sort of diagnostic gain
it is very useful because it goes into the system there are so many different
pieces can easily choose to spend the next few months choosing the right piece
hispanic or useful diagnostic tells you what the piece may actually work hard work
this sort of another type of analysis is sort of the opposite of what just
talked about
the analysis of twelve
try to explain the difference between the current performance in perfect performance
whereas this a plate of analysis tries to explain the difference between some baselines some
really bad performance and current performance
so for example let's suppose you build a very good anti-spam cos five but having
lots of people clever features images expression c and it features the spelling correction for
years in the host features that you had the features
in text parser features javascript parser features
he just that images and so on
so now let's europe eastern system you want to figure out how well how much
they need these components actually
on the mirror writing research papers including this was piece to make a big difference
can you have the document that can be justified
so in the data analysis
it's all we do
so in this example let's say that simple logistic regression without any clever improvements get
ninety four percent performance
if you want to figure out what accounts for your improvement from ninety four to
nineteen ninety nine percent performance
so in the data analysis on a surface having components one of the time was
remove components one of time to see how it operates
so start with the overall systems ninety nine percent accuracy
and they were removed spelling correction and see how much performance drops
the route to send host features and see how much performance drops and so on
so in this contrived example
you see that i guess the biggest drop occurs when you remove the text parser
features and so you can then make a credible case that the text parser features
what really makes the biggest difference
and also tell
for instance that all
removing the centre hosted shows on this line right before dropping ninety nine point nine
eight point two nine point nine percent so there's also means that in case you
want to get rid of the center host features to speed up computational something that
would be a good candidate for elimination
which is the same
i just want to show you what the was removed things the answer is no
there's no guarantee against the results of soap actors sometimes is fairly natural ordering of
the both ties analysis easier houses data analysis sentences a very natural ordering which happens
things on sometimes there's and quite often you to choose one ordering just go through
it all
on and they think of these analyses as of all those costs still few free
then on this one
one thing this
so there's this memory function you want talk about it saves the model
and change the case where and built a new model now these two cases where
it's and
holds on to the original model so
as the case has been
misclassified over and over its relative weight starts to grow and the ones that gets
right start to fade now
some people like this to to marriage you know the fact that you bring all
but that is taken for granted and the socks that are still on the floor
you know
one the month starts mid importance
you can imagine how hysterical some of these models again after whatsoever
the reason i read about this thing i thought using the latest model the one
that has the
you know that can actually paid the least way to the most hysterical model
and the most weight to the original model and you have a weighted sum
of these of these models the goaoc so it's very interesting clever procedure and it
took awhile to generalise to bring into the world of the models but eventually
as you add more
points that are in dispute are all along the boundaries
you end up with the decision boundary is much closer than your original base learner
which had square corners
would have allowed to do
yes thank you so i want to give the bit
solution because it was really helpful for me in understanding so
case which are one of the sources of variety
all right so now look if we focus on the tree world
a little bit again the generalized ensembles work with any kind of learners with again
trees are all relatively
easy to understand so we focus on
and we build
rule ensembles
we could we could say our model is a linear function
and our
basis functions are these served base learners
which can capture nonlinear so
we generate the models are the basis functions and then post fit to the data
with regularized regression using favorite thing now as we are a representation we lose we
lose our
interpretability but again you can take any method no matter how black box and you
can do post processing and iterative
tweaking the see which variables are getting the most important so
it's not interpretable
if you show a picture of but is interpretable
if you work with it and see which which variables are most influential smile
so i think of the tree has cut a tree is a collection of rules
the indicator functions and these constants better
and so you have these different regions
that are themselves the
the product to the indicator function so here
if x one is greater than twenty two years x two scored twenty seven inside
this boundary region region one and you have all these different regions are defined by
the sort of building block rules
so you could decompose the tree
into these
these rules and have a larger set of base learners we've been talking about based
on being a tree but you can break the tree up into its components and
let those be part of your alphabet for
two together
the if you use those
words in your model that could be more interpretable
still ways people still piecewise constant model
not linear targets can be a problem again with trees with piecewise constant but there's
nothing to hold back from throwing in more base learners that have those properties the
linear trend properties so you can think of combined
o thing where inputs are linear
or our region and you have different sets weight if it is
so use the same
use approximate optimisation
approach to software the
split definitions for rule
is one rule for each terminal node
if you if you have a shallow tree
you could also use some of the intermediate nodes regions e to to increase the
variety of things you have to work with
so now you have two sets of parameters year
in linear grammars in your tree parameters
and you might penalize both again as well as the question point earlier we could
pay attention to the regularizer normalising the data
such away so the absolute value of the parameter has some meaning
because japan was according to the end of a little trivial
enjoy it
so now what i want you to do is to look at
at the table
this table is going to show that this is not such as smart
tagline to work with again i will not expect you to commit the stable to
memory i would never ask you to tell me what the solubility of something is
by hard i would instead turn around and say
for example
copper bromide
it's aqueous solutions and then let's take it from there i tell you what the
the fact is but what i want you
notice first of all is that the table is broken into two
regimes soluble ionic compounds and insoluble ionic compounds
soluble iron compounds insoluble ionic compounds so it's not so simple
it's not so simple there's something else
going on here
and let's take a look there's one they for example the the chlorides chlorides are
generally soluble and the oxides are generally not soluble so what do we have to
think about well it's the competition really it's a competition we look at sodium chloride
it exists as a solid
and now we have to compare
whether it wants to go into aqueous solution
and what we see is that the answer here is yes
whereas the answer for
magnesium oxide which is also
an ionic crystal
it does not form
aqueous solutions so what's going on here well
what's the major difference here sodium chloride exists sodium cations and chloride anions
whereas magnesium is diving so we magnesium
cations oxide anions and in the crystal lattice we have a much much higher crystal
lattice energy for magnesium oxide if you just go through the madelon
derivation you'll have doubled
double so it's in essence four times
four times in chernoff the melting point of sodium chloride is about
eight hundred degrees melting point whereas the melting point of magnesium oxide is about twenty
eight hundred degrees
what happens when we try to make this dissolve in a solution is something that
looks like this as a cartoon showing water
dissolving sodium chloride sodium chloride is to get oriented the green
spheres represent the chloride ions and the blue spheres represents sodium ions and just
he things could you can see up here
the one two three four five the face of an FCC
gravity lattice but we've got two atoms per lattice points are basis et cetera et
cetera and here's the water molecule which looks sort of like mickey mouse here with
the the red showing the
oxygen and the white showing the hydrogen so the oxygen
and is the negative and of the dipole with the cartoon showing is that the
negative and of the dipole is presenting itself to the cations
and if the
attractive force
between the soluble in the solvent exceeds
the binding energy of the crystal binding energy will have solution
and that's borne out here
well you see that we have
the difference in coulombic force of attraction that makes it accessible for sodium chloride
four water to dissolve it but inaccessible for
magnesium oxide because the forces are too strong and the see the complement here that
the positive and of the
dipole is presenting itself to the chloride and i
i'm always amused when people draw
ions colored because i know they try to color coding but i think about it
if you could isolate the chloride ion what color do you think it would be
there's an answer to that question
what's its electronic structure he always was back what what's its electronic structure it's isoelectronic
with the
and what do you think the color of oregon is what do you think the
color very noble gases so actually these things should all be clear colorless i just
wanted to point that out i know the color-coded for your amusement but it is
i was staring at this does green i and asking myself
should i be green no no they should
OK so now let's talk about measures of solubility
measures of solubility it gets put some numbers on this
we can express solubility
in the following units
there are a variety of units but the only ones that we really
we need to worry about
o is the molar quantity which represents models of solitude
models of solitude
divided by
of solution
leaders of solution and member the solution is the sum of all solurions
also you plus the solver
also used the solvent constitute the solution
and so moles per litre when we say
sodium chloride dissolves in so many moles per litre we can abbreviate that by
upper case and upper case and which we term mole
more so if i have a one molar solution
of sodium chloride in water one molar
is equivalent to say one mole
of NAACL
in one litre
of the solution to us
was about to write water it's not this one leader of
the solution
here i think you can see that
there it's not an all-or-nothing situation
in other words
certain substances are insoluble for reasons we've
scene but other substances are soluble up to a point
you know from experience you can add sugar to water and it dissolves very rapidly
up to a certain value beyond which you can add the sugar storage shake it
do whatever you want the sugar will not dissolve beyond certain limits which we call
the solubility limit
or in aqueous systems they simply call it the solubility
the solubility
at this limit we've reached
condition term saturation
we say the solution is saturated with respect to the
to the solitude and can take no more
and there are two measures FOR saturation solubility one is
just denoted c star or some people use c seven as which means the
concentration of solitude
at saturation
you as for me to leave eric was yours
lecture course
with the cancellation that we can see it on
the tape
two two interesting well several things very interesting for me one is i knew david
has to this in graduate school
and no idea that his article
lead to
eric was or is interested in
in education
because we were unable to stay for the punchline the remedy
what do what's
what's the right thing to be doing
so i'll watch the tape to find that out
the second thing i wanted to say
there was one point there which i didn't agree with
and i don't know what you feel it he got to the top of the
pyramid the one in two hundred sixty
of the
starting students who went on to do a phd in the jewish star around them
and said i'm not
worried about them
i worry about them about that part too
i don't think i think from the first of all
the ones who are the next generation who are carrying the torch
so there's something
pretty important about them even if numerically
it's a small number
and i don't think
i mean i used to think that maybe people became mathematicians or physicists
so have you couldn't stop on
right i mean they they destroyed born in that direction they had
they had to matter gene or something
and you didn't have to take care of them what happened but i don't believe
that any more i think that
you know as write me right now we're
feel about the same if we measure success by any standard measurements then we should
probably all be
working for morgan stanley or something
now i don't think
any of us is going there tomorrow
and that's sort of a joke that about the money part of the rewards but
the the reward of
there are so many intangible but highly important rewards
that if the system doesn't offer them
people make a different choice
i mean and and some of those rewards are internal
i mean it's a great feeling to actually you know can use your mind and
understand them but
you need encouragement to so i i wouldn't
assume that the that the special ones
could be
and i'm sure i mean he's obviously a fantastic features of the special ones are
learning like mad OK now what do i do with the kalman filter
again tried to establish what's the framework
one of the inputs for the outputs
so what will the formulas be formulas for
and then maybe a little discussion of those matrix formulas
but let me get the framework straight for
the the point is as i was in the list of topics
the point is that
i'm going to end up with a very big system can i write it script
a script you
equals script b or something
and that
is a collection of equations
coming at different times
four different for for changing u
and with measurements b so that me
look this is discrete time of course
i could i could be writing differential equations things are clearer in the the discrete
so let me
so i have
say i measure some
now that's that's a vector
so as i started with some standard equation in a zero you zero equals c
static at time zero
i have a standard measurement equation five OK
goes on
the system changes
but it changes by no longer out of this is of course is garnering much
and that there were going to assume has some
very covariance matrix
thank you
o thing is zero maybe i need is a signature of e
OK fine
now that we know how to deal with
now the next step is time moves forward sean x and that this was the
measurement equation
the next equation will be a state equation this you know what is the state
at time zero
and the state at time one is connected to the state at time zero
by some linear
ah equation
so you want to call some after writing
sorry x to be you
and i
i'm going to change that well referenced second son like look up to see what
letter and
so this
the change of state the dynamics
between times are on time one
of course it's not perfect either
so there's error in the use epsilon
for the state here and now
use the index one where or another person might use zero it is not critical
OK then we're in state one
and i take a measurement state one
so a one
in some
measuring b one minus some error e one f long for the errors in the
state equation he's for the error in the
and then sure enough
u two
it is
you want
and of course and after one
and then let's say we do and measurement
time to start stop there
eight two u two with b two
i minus e
and one
further touch
well you see i didn't insist on the same
a matrix that every step of course i don't really have to insist on the
same as
matrix at everything
so this is the
this is the frame and this is the least squares problem this is the big
problem you will be
i can if i bring you all the
the use until the
one side of the equation and the bees and the errors on the other side
of the equation then i have the big system that's to be so let's do
so what is swept a
let me just copy down the
what have i got in this matrix model and what's my unknown you would see
if i can get it right
i i i ended up with five
walker equations everybody knows that
everybody is clear that these
use typically
the use will be the same size but probably we don't even have to require
but there will be vectors not scalars
known under this name
any questions regarding this simulated annealing procedure
so this is the question of randomness when actually went stochasticity comes into play in
this and with so it's actually two points
one thing is
you see
generating new solution
i didn't discuss this in detail you really generate
a solution that is somewhere in the neighborhood of the current solution but of course
there's many options to do that so we usually involves here this is one point
and the second point is comes just this probability of accepting the worst solution so
this is used as the probability were solution is sometimes accepted sometimes not
i would like to
but if you look at it from a global perspective the idea is to minimize
it but sometimes you need to
so o
yes is this is a question of
for example
how efficient is random search was as techniques like these
well empirically it can be shown that usually it's it's
random search is much worse but in those i don't know if
part of the
so called no free lunch theorem
just so you know very much into details but it was a question of this
this regards
the efficiency of the search and optimisation techniques
this says that on average
over all problems this is again
there's no
the the best the most successful technique so
this is in theory but in practice just not to be too much disappointing disappointed
you're always in certain particular problem and then it matters
check the methodologies which one is
but if we this is just the average based on average you can
you can send
now about the
second topic which is evolutionary algorithms
evolutionary algorithms
were inspired by biological evolution
this means
evolved in nature you know there's there's the darwinian theory that is the principle of
heredity and so on so the organisms
compete in a certain environment that is survival of the fittest principle that is known
from nature so
the fittest individuals survive they reproduce so their properties are then inherited by their offspring
and propagated through populations in next generations
so this is exactly the idea that is used to be the evolutionary algorithms
now we can characterize these algorithms as simplified models of these natural biological evolution
that implement these principles
it many of these techniques were actually first used
to simulate or to assist biologists in their experimental studies but very soon
the computer scientists or programmers this coward
that this methodology is ready
can be used in a very pragmatic way
as an efficient and effective search
and optimisation technique
so if we now this talk about evolutionary algorithms we must know that these are
stochastic search and optimization algorithms
so the key idea with this evidence is that
we explore
the search space
in order to find a good solution to computer simulated evolution
or in other words
problem solving is implemented in this way
it is
nice to have this and all analogy in mind when we discuss evolutionary patterns so
number further you probably just your query
number the independent so
we can drop this here
in the denominator d and then we have only two independent on the query
which of ranking
we can also try
now in the literature you will see that all of this latter to
can be dropped
assuming also that you are
are independent so
the joint probability of documents relevant to that
two random variables and also independent and we come up with
model generative model
that your document
generate your career
so this is how how
in the literature and how you come to
such a language models but now let's start with the case
this model
we still have to estimate
the probability that the document generates the query
and you very often
it is composed of that attitude
can the grand canyon unique and can be things work
so we assume
again independence
attributes of query terms
given the document
so we can actually
consider only the individuals
credit so i suppose you have credit
you could consider only individual twenty
and your
in the independent so you can estimate
quite easily from document central
with the independence assumption to make
the product
and again can
the sum of log p
when we consider all these great
and this is actually
the creation of
which stars which i start
look at the very
well i prefer to discuss this language model
so we have a committee composed of two
any computer probability that the document that generates
the quite
so we have this
of two
generated by document
which we can
by just looking at
the term frequency for instance in the document
to see how frequent
that is in proportion to all of the other terms of the document
of course the very very likely
will not occur
in document
we have a very for
representation of the document
so we need
some form of
muti action
to find
two not talked in the world
in this equation
and also yesterday well
different forms of marketing
we often moved in this model with the collection
so the two of you look at the turn of your question
OK so
we know that
she is
and those will be space induced by kernel
and the idea of the kernel is the to preprocess the data
first of all the idea of the feature space and then i'll tell you about
the data is preprocessed your data
by mapping the data into some dot product space h
so each x is preprocessed into biophysics and then rather than learning the mapping from
x to y for instance x is some pattern then y is the label plus
minus one
we now that the mapping from phi x y
so typically the dimensionality of the space is very large and much larger than the
dimensionality of the input space if the input space is a linear space at all
so this thing is a high dimensional things you know turned your data into high
dimensional objects and you want to learn with these data and classical statistics would tell
you that a bad idea because there's something called because dimensionality
if you have high dimensional data how usually need a lot more data than if
he had low dimensional data
however equipped with all our knowledge of statistical learning theory
we cannot say we're not worried about dimensionality which is worried about capacity so we
can come up with function classes to learn on this data
that have small capacity then we're not worried
moreover we would say that
people are afraid of dimensionality because in some cases dimensionality is the same as capacity
the interesting cases where it's not so for instance we've seen one case where dimensionality
are the same
and this was this case you reference to the same if we're separating hyperplanes in
RN VC dimension will be in plus one
so here the curse of dimensionality if you want
however if we consider hyperplanes with a margin we don't have this because any more
so the interesting thing we would then say is only capacity and not dimensionality
OK so
let's look at one example
suppose we have two classes of data
like this
we assume that there is some
and the decision boundary which is an ellipse in this case that separates the crosses
from the red circles
and if we want to solve this classification problem with survive to estimate is ellipse
but instead of estimating the ellipse we could also just take a detour into a
high dimensional space in this case three-dimensional computing all monomials the product or the two
one of monomials of degree two in the input variables
there are three possible such monomials don't worry about this scaling factor and once we
are in this space you think about it for a second you will see the
boundary of the ellipse
actually maps into a separating hyperplane in that space since ones written in x one
square next to square this ellipse equation becomes an find equation
in this case mapping into the high dimensional space is suddenly given us the possibility
to solve the problem using a separating hyperplane
more generally we will be interested in
patterns not of dimension two but of dimension n
so for instance we might have images mentioned sixteen times sixteen two hundred fifty six
moreover we might be interested not in productive all two but in products of all
of the where could be any natural number in this case the number of possible
products of the dimensionality of all features based on the right-hand side will grow like
into the power of the
even in this relatively low dimensional case we considered product of the five so all
feature space consists of all possible product of five different pixels in these images we
would certainly be working in a space of dimension ten to the power of ten
which is something that you want to avoid
it turns out we can actually avoided using kernel functions which turn not you can
compute dot product in that space without having to into that space
to see this take two points x and x prime
not into that space so this is the a mapping from the last slide
in take the dot product between them denoted the productivity this transpose so these two
if you do that
and you can just work out in your in your head if you like you
get three terms
and these three terms will actually be complete binomial formula that you can rewrite the
square of the the dot product taken in input space
if we don't see this now and may be surprising see the first time i
you just try this out yourself afterwards because that's one of the surprising things about
so rather than nothing these two points into that space and taking the product we
could as well have taken the dot product in the input space and then raised
to the power of two
we would have got the same result would have saved the mapping into this three-dimensional
space which would make a big difference in this case because we only talking about
two dimensions was three will turn out the same thing also works
in the general case
so this is an example of a kernel function is a function
corresponds to adopt product in another space
so here's the more general case
let's consider n dimensional patterns or inputs and product quality
and actually i
go back was i will start
with the generalized form
this come here
generalize this thing and see what happens
so this is the product between two n dimensional vectors
but can write like this canonical problem raised to the power of the this gives
me a the full from here
these indices j one through j d
and that here i then these terms have grouped them
everything that depends on x
on the left and everything that depend on ex-prime i have put on the right
so just multiplied out this big thing here
and if you look at this you notice
first of all this is a non linear function of x this is the same
linear function evaluated ex-prime
this is just a lot of some
so if you want this is just a dot product in
in a slightly transformed space
and the axis of the space are spanned by these products of features of the
inputs so these are all the possible products of the features of the input vectors
and here is the same for the second so this is just some non linear
transformation of x
here we have the same for prime and then we take the product in this
very high dimensional space so the dimensionality of the space is into the paul d
bingo so then we have a way of computing the product in this very high
dimensional space
simply by computing the partition the input space in the plane this simple and linearity
raising to the party
and the same thing works
more generally and actually i will not use this way but i will
do it differently the same thing will work more generally
a larger class of kernels called positive definite kernels and i think i will try
at age is
i considered
that said this information about parts of speech we also
going ignore all past which has a not so why is that
well because if you get just
and now which is very common to all sentences that say
president of the united states barack obama said already six months after years of sentences
but it doesn't tell you anything about what happens so to minimise chances to get
something like that
what we we do is we at
perhaps which casts has a so this gives us
it makes it more likely that we get a and is sentence tells what really
but they
and then finally the total path length is normalized so that you know
that has the lowest average in edge weights
so can be very
shaw also in terms of interest and has the
the most total weeks but there might be among to which which was not always
is higher whose average rate is still lots
rather longer but with
which maximizes work which minimize the average regret
nobody data and this was just without
so this is just an example know how to to relate to
i don't you know the page is called google news
pegasus the mail change little bit so what's
good news about
it aggregates
news from different sources does not have the right to use it does provide news
to itself but it just takes
o news available on the the web science
with respect to the
languages that aggregates news about
which are likely to be about the same thing together and also categories
so for example this is a web page correspond to the english version
think that just dotcom used good outcomes
you have some categories like sports entertainment business
top stories with right
so without categories then put to the top of the web page
so that
what you see there normally is that you see a snippet from a news article
tell you where it comes from just a few of the TED this news article
you can click on it and then you will arrive
page three times in this case it also
gives you
link is final you can really should can gives you what should was in this
almost seven hundred articles which are all
unlike many of which are likely to be about this very same event
so it's no longer just a topic is not only about the
so the problem is that
so it's not only about sports about seventy
this is what happens if you click on their
really for which
for each this related articles
so you see it's snippets those articles and you can see that what you get
so sentences that it's almost the same thing
this is what is often used for
after the concert
this is of related to use this
it says that it is not known or use cluster
the collection of news on this topic is introduced us to become from different sources
what you can expect from them is that they were published the same time
but like to be able to see that but of course it's all done automatically
so there is no human intervention what it means is that there are definitely duplicates
are and there's also voiced so nice means that you get something that doesn't belong
to the class
so for example you can have the last sentence of eighteen
two teams and
it can happen in the same cluster you suddenly get
and article about a very different game
this and this is what i mean with the noise
and so those newscasts now
to test their just presented
i need to get
so somewhere
so sentence passed again clusters of sentences which is very similar to not only
that there is sufficient to be monitored
the same position
and to obtain knows what did
i just took the first sentence is expected news articles here the idea is very
simple so if you know about summarisation petition so
for example i used to be called document distant conference dr or text analysis conference
tech what happens there you get the data gets used to work with local news
with and then you're trying to your time you have to provide a the food
system which automatically summary and then you get tested for safety or usually fifty newscasters
you process with this systems you get results for every use must be sent back
and then a couple of months later there is
the results are published so
your system is
by humans also automatically
that's a great respect different parameters how
readability assign rewards OWL
so which more and how many mistakes
grammatical mistakes him so
that's very helpful
and then the british
let's call
what happens there is they also provide space so we don't know what this these
is is
it's a system which is very simplistic
you can think of it but it should be reasonable and if your system which
is expected to be more complex is performs worse than this is system that things
we really went wrong places
or if you get the same results of this is that in the absence of
being of years
you didn't really
do you need
good job
so four
this is a petition what they used to do this
they there's an old person's baseline
during the summary of documents for documents selected randomly in the sentences are put together
and surprisingly is a very competitive so did some more
complex systems may perform worse than there are different reasons for that so one of
them is that if you try to modify it so you can get a matter
or if you get sentences from different parts of the document is likely you put
some pronouns which people geometry we cannot be interpreted out of context and the first
sentences that may have been pronounced this i good and then
usually one also for
property of just vision of news articles is that the very often be summarise the
content of the news
so it's not your fault magazine articles for example based on the very first sentence
sometimes just introduction but with uses three which was here
if we go back for example to this station