remember in the course
we measured
the average speed of the bullet which we
fired from a rifle
that was because we had
the ability of very fast time
in the old days
fast timing was not possible
and people measure the speed of bought in very delicate way
and all the tools that we have learned
we can apply now
to this
device which we call
the ballistic pendulum
where the pendulum
this is very
heavy object hanging you at the end i call it the block
you see here
and this page and has length l
ours is about one meter
i will give you the exact numbers later
and we have aborted
one of my little
and aborted
comes in with velocity v
that's completely absorbed
sticks in there
it's a completely inelastic collision
and the
real then pick up
velocity v prime was the inside
but it is somewhere here
momentum is conserved
so we clearly have
equals and plus and times
the prime
so if you could measure the prime
then you could measure the
speed of the bullet
which is the
how do we measure b prime
we wait for the kind
to come
to hold
let's see here
the speed is zero
when it was here
you had a speed
the prime
we know that there was
kinetic energy here
gravitational potential energy i can call this level
you equals zero
right here
this difference
in height is h and all the kinetic energy has been converted to
gravitational potential energy so we apply the
theorem the
work energy theorem or you could say it's equally
you could say we apply to conservation of mechanical energy
and so this
kinetic energy which is one half
plus and
and the prime squared
is now converted exclusively to gravitational potential energy
which equals and and
times g times age
and we lose our employees and
so the prime
will be described route
of two g h
so all you would have to measure h and then you know the prime and
if you know the prime
you know the speed of the bullet
but life
it's not that simple
it's very difficult to measure h and i can make you see that
suppose this angle
angle theta
when it comes to a halt
is only two degrees
then h
which is l times one minus cosine fade
is only
o point six
forty dimensions that i have chosen
falling one
that's it you can even see it it's invisible
that alone that you can measure to any degree of accuracy
so what are we going to do now
we are going to
not measure
but we are going to measure
i call this actually falls zero
and here the
and then comes to a halt
i call that
four two degrees
it is approximately
three and a half centimetres
can easily be checked by you've course
you get a huge displacement in this direction compared
two h
if you use small angle approximation you better believe it two degrees is very small
then you can prove which is purely geometrical
mathematics and i view is that proof
this is approximately
x squared
divided by two l
i want you to prove that
you take the expansion of cosine
a series of the taylor series
and you cut off somewhere and this is not too difficult to prove
in other words
the prime square and
o two g h
can now be replaced by approximately
two g
times x great divided by two l
which is g
times x
divided by l
and so the velocity of the
which is
and plays and
divided by
i bring the
down there
times b prime
b prime
is no
the square root of this
so i got next here
we map into this
as i mentioned space
we which is a pretty common
entered the party
so for instance from these pages sixty six these images sixteen sixteen if we want
to look at product of all five which turns out to be a reasonable
number that will working in attendance space
so now
we know
that we can work such a space is we control the capacity but we still have
computational problems are doing this in practice and that's is
the trick comes in
and the trick is very easy one is are used all machine learning
the first of all the simple case
dimensionality to
the products of two
so that's
he actually due to slides ago
so it take two points x and x prime
each point gets mapped to this
that's all about what to
the first point seven point
we compute the standard dot product between these three dimensional vectors
and the
in terms of this work
square root of two comes from turns out to be
well we know that
comes out this it's just the square of the original product
so we can compute this dot product in high dimensions
space by simply taking the
in the input space
recipient of two
so in this case we don't see much
but of course in the
products we can save a lot
we can see this as follows
let's just take the product the product
between two images vehicles
and raise the whole thing
so this gives us this
expression we multiply also we get these sums over here with sixty one
but here we just saw terms everything in axis here within prime here
and what you can see that this is just the product
in this representation so this is like
these are all possible products already have copied x this is simply prime
and this is just some in high dimensional space
so this is just
some or all of them so this is basically nothing but the product
after the mapping phi where phi
this is an input vector x
produces operator overloading
o course makes
in almost all products some products will appear multiple times
that's why we have this we ought to in the previous case
okay so we can compute
the product in the space spanned by all ordered products of tonality
simply by
the product in the input space and raise into the party
and there
so typically this is not generalize one can generalize this
this is the finite dimensional space
we enter the policy dimensions you want
this infinite dimensional space as well end
this was typically motivated using something called the theorem the
so far
here in functional analysis
which briefly show you because i think
it's nice to do it in terms of something
called positive definite kernels
this is this is a theorem which tells you something about
because of individual operators which has certain
positive definiteness property
if this property holds true
we can expand this kind of the posteriors are
the whole series is a series
in terms i functions and i mean
functions is
we i can values that are negative
due to this
the positivity condition
and then from this series we can construct
they mapping
into a feature space that looks like this remember these things and you can make a square root
uh and then
we can construct this mapping the mapping such that if we
take the dot product between two match points
we recover all this
i mean function here is thus the kernel
so that's one way
attitudes but i want to tell you more details about another way of doing it
because we can
for example way we can actually explicity construct
the mapping into the feature space
so that's the second main
ingredient of what
i'm trying to teach a course for the first one was
uh not be scalability dimensions
the second one is be scared of feature spaces
basically what will do tomorrow and start today is
a positive definite kernel which is called
attention but they they should both be mentioned the idea is that if you look
at the gap between
your inner product with the true label
and any alternative label y
then that gap should be proportional to the loss minus the slack
that's the margin rescaling version or proportional to one minus the flag divided by the
if we impose no constraints at all are basically say this gap should should always
be greater than or equal to zero we basically get rid of the variable and
essentially found back to the perceptron with some kind of regularisation term and just pointing
that out because sometimes it's nice to see that there's a connection the problem here
is that there are a lot of different wise
we have one constraint for every different
labeling of the sequence or partial tree and we know that there could be exponentially
many of those
so what is required here
is some way of taking care taking advantage of local factory
both the features as we've been doing all along we use that when we when
we decode but also the loss function l
so m three ends are one one formalism that use margin rescaling and try to
exploit both the factor g
vector space function and l loss function
so from the hyperplane view i think this kind of sums up the idea of
the worst an example is the more it's going to push on the hyperplane
you want the bad the bad labelings of a sequence of the bad structures to
be farther away
not slightly less bad
everybody is pushing against the
the hyperplane but the bad ones push hard
this is sort of another way of looking at the objective this is the margin
rescaling version
and what this i sort of collapse out the taxi
and what you end up with
it is inside your minimisation problem we've got this maximisation problem so this this problem
is still convex
like crfs
but the bad news is that
it's always differentiable
it's sort of
i got this piece wise
component two it because of the max
one thing that one thing that it's kind of different here is that
inside the max you've got a loss function
so it's got this it's got this sort of weird problem where you're trying to
find the best y
we're scoring y based on their actual scores like you would use in decoding here
but also with this loss terms this is called loss augmented decoding is often pointed
out standard decoding want you to find the y
that maximizes the inner products the weight vector
loss augmented decoding then again there are two versions one for each type rescaling requires
you to maximise the sum of what you would normally maximise this lost her
OK so you're trying to it's like trying to find the competitor to the correct
answer that's that's both competitive and also really bad
you know both both its loss has is lost has to be and also it's
chorus we sort of the the biggest threat so if as as i said before
in m three n is the whole point is that you can do this if
things factor locally in the same way
and you can use dynamic programming or or some other local reasoning sorry sorry combinatorial
optimization problem they uses local local independence assumptions to to manage this the other version
the slack rescaling version you actually end up may taking the product of these two
this is just generally almost always intractable
i don't actually know the case where it's not tractable
for combinatorial problems so you have to approximate some
again i told you at the beginning i'm not going to go into details about
implementation i think it's fair to say that
structural SVM models and methods for optimizing the weights according to these kinds of objectives
are very hot topic and there's a lot of work going into them there are
a whole lot of things on the table many of them require this loss augmented
decoding probably what had the most impact lately in natural language processing of these passive
aggressive online algorithms because the very easy to implement and they essentially accomplish the same
thing although the connection to the objectives is not always clear and they may not
be capturing the regularisation quite the way that we usually think about it right on
the objective functions i think there's still more work to be done on figuring out
this this connection people on the remaining more about it than i do
all right i want to keep moving here
OK so this is something of large margin classifiers what's nice about them is that
and it also minimizes sensitivity to coastal
here in some problem so in fact when compute saying what is important to is
that you have got to with this if there
which is which is this one so that is is the blue one so you
will get
following once you've got a capacitance
input impedance
after a while it is just a list the and the
the frequency welding is in this sense of what it's like
we would like to register
and the type of you don't want to get is a few modelling or something
very quite quite small
that we simply don't
and by the with is
deposit detector capacitance which
which we defined
so one something for the is extremely stable so
just to
shortly twenty the capacity to otherwise if you if you have a succession of the
input you just show the capacitance until
you a first
so this is the situation of the fail also you have to to discharge the
capacitance in general and we do that just
the only
and that's what's so here you've got this inputs counties input
yeah have
the voltage output is just going to play just like that
we have this capacitance
if we go down
two zero again and then what happens to be the value it shouldn't be too
two small that it shouldn't be too large to the people of course this is
if something happened during this discussion would have some biological and
and you know it
so the same reasons
i find that
so the question is what is called stoke in that they have that as i
said of channels general from one to two
the other you do not have so much distance issues if you take
silicon strip detectors get
eighty two on nikon between two channels which means that if you look at one
hundred the other so you will get
in between because they are close time capacitance in this course
see it
if i take this if i think this is generally of the
generated by particle causing the gender with which would be shared between the amplifier
this sparse here
so which means that you will inject
some other to go on and on and on the name
so of course as it is the capacitance you will
between basis
the signal
and then he said that it's a
it seems to have a low input input
you don't even if you don't know
the current most of the if it is you most all the current flows is
if it is most of the and flows with very little flow this way and
that's why it's better to low input impedance amplifier in terms of course if you
large domes
most of the killing to this way and then you are
north pole
so have try to find you could say well what about if just
i can simplify which is that in this case the feedback
just put all this stuff
and that's the kind of thing
which are useful in back to this
and they are which is useful const meeting
and optical fibre
so the
the relationship between the input
in the output voltage
it's just
even by this formula are hundreds of in your face if the game is really
i think it is the cost
this is again the just the value of the is also a public you get
that you know things that you want to the
so that the fact that if you compute in the same computed the input impedance
of charge amplifier operation
compute the input impedance this configurations
you will see i have a
and if you do this input impedance match on the
you could
because this deposit during growth
on the detector you have something which is very easy
and then
two two to get to done this thing is to put a resistor somewhere to
them to dump and
so in fact instead of putting the
the input of the amplifier
we just due the fact that if if we put the capacitance embodied to this
the cascade can barely see it relation to everything else so the cascade and get
some forms
and so
this is the big
the cascade made a big difference in terms of GNU object detection because you have
to do exhaustive search but rather do it in an efficient manner
and what should be the next four
yes so that's really well we go that more detail there is a dramatically reduced
basically you have the full support vector machine to start off with
and this is then there's method that you can do this kind of
i want to analogous to whatever
essentially what you have to do is a saying you're able to represent the decision
boundary with all with endless support vectors and it is basically an iterative approach that
you can employ we can talk of one about the details things but it's in
the paper if interested but essentially what i want to convey here about is essentially
that cascade is effective in that improves things in the speeds things up but this
is not
unfortunately for these guys this came out random at the same time as a volunteer
and so
the kind of work it was into
it was rejected
and they realize it was a good idea
so listen for everyone
so i mean and so essentially as as alex was talking about unfortunately in those
really neat idea in the theory behind it's really becoming marginalized again because of the
this this other approach which perhaps was an elegant but again the
practical practical speedup that gave was again much greater and so that kind of it
just became ubiquitous and so on explains the large method can combine this idea of
cascaded classifiers with this idea of using box filters
i'm going to explain what a box filter is
so a box filter is essentially let's say
i've got a sub image soft sub here
this area here
and the two adjacent regions region one
in region two
you can see that essentially what i my feature value is essentially
some nations of the pixels in region one
one is the summation of the pixels in britain to
so set to box so instead of me actually so with an SVM on actually
feeding in
so that's a twenty one twenty image four hundred pixels so with an SVM beating
all those pixels for me to for me to actually
to the classification with the box filter what i'm doing is that i'm actually instead
actually getting to measurements
this twenty by twenty image one region two one region one
and i just got a single number
region two monastery one
and i can
there are three types about is one where you actually so talked about region one
is written two
there's one where actually
at the two ears
take away
the other diagonal
this vertical and then there's the triple so we kind of got a good good
nature here
and you can essentially very size aspect ratio location orientation
in their work funded every twenty four but twenty four windows
it's got one hundred sixty thousand distinct features
it could possibly go through and it's classifier you basically do classification on every single
thanks so much as well war
why i want to come across through that the the advantage to this is twofold
the first thing is that the individual pixels for themselves
don't contain much information all the time it's when you look at the mess hall
the really useful
so essentially you can kind of think of what we're doing here
is that we can't getting different
so we can realize it so it's not good look at individual pixel so cannot
perhaps get different combinations of pixels and explore if i if i basically is almost
a greedy search can get different combinations of pixels and explore how useful that is
me recognise objects so i just look at that one individual features and obviously this
is like to quite useful for boosting so i essentially of maybe one hundred sixty
thousand different ways of representing representing the object and i can if i not enough
training data of time i can go offline and essentially
apply boosting so say OK how well does this individual individual feature works how well
does this subsequent individual feature work and then keep on adding the waiting into the
sequential learning and it is useful fold you can process a lot of data this
one thing so boosting sort myself to this and also
you can and will talk to the next part of that you can actually two
get substantial speedup by using this box filters
so so these is like SVM actually got away with SVM as you add more
and more
you define a non-linear decision boundary things using so as the sequential learning
so why why we do this so work arrived and why why would you do
the big advantage is actually how you can buy the box filters so it turns
out that when i need to
and compute approximate the value many many times and i want to do it fast
i can take advantage of an inherent redundancy in images or not an image just
in in the in the two dimensional structure
and it was always an integral image
and what i can do is essentially
but want to compute the sum of pixels in a rectangular area here
i can take what interval image so i'll go back inside the initial image between
so i've got two regions extraction x y one and what are basically
i want to do
is i want to get the summation of all values
from the origin
to expression white ash
so the summing up all those values
and then so
if only is in the context of box filters a candidate
i can get into the image of
it's essentially summations
of all the values here
to this point
with black with the black line here
is what i want my box the value to be
what i can do also is getting image b
which is this area
again with reference to the origin
then limits to see
but cool thing is is that if i actually
it goes through
one of them was
so the brain
all these is you know
you know what to do with
world war
that is
know that
when you
after all
the problem of deciding whether to
all o
well i
she she
all of the
all these
we have
so all
is less than  H if the constraint is not active then you decrease
the price unless  but you never make it negative that's the plus size so you never made the
prices negative so that's one application of the dual methods you get methods that actually are
easy to that can exploit a separable structure in optimization problems is this clear so
next question is  maybe briefly so we saw these were all applications of the sub
gradient method or a gradient method applied to the dual we've seen in the
previous section that the proximal gradient method is much faster than the subgradient method and can
handle some non-differentiable objectives so an interesting question is when can we apply
the proximal gradient method to a dual problem so when is it true that in the
dual problem that's repeated here we get this structure that's you need
in the proximal gradient method where you have a composite objective function with a differentiable term
and a simple non-differentiable term with  an inexpensive prox operator and that's very useful because
if that can have a much faster dual method than using the subgradient
method because again we've seen that a subgradient method is a very general method but it's also very slow in
practice and it's difficult to  select a step size so if you can use a
gradient method or a proximal gradient method you have a much faster way of solving a dual
and you can also extend it  to these fast proximal gradient methods and then it's even
faster yes because it's yeah it's difficult the
so the step size selection is difficult in general because we've seen that these convergence
rules proves actually the convergence the step sizes for which you have convergence results are
for example if you use a fixed step size then we didn't show convergence we
just showed that if the step size is sufficiently small you get close to the optimum
and to actually show convergence you have to use a decreasing or a diminishing step size which
also makes it slow yeah it's I'm not sure how that would
work but certainly the convergence would still be quite slow in  practice so now the
next question is just simply let's look at some  what it means for the
dual problem to have this structure we need in the primal  we see it's actually very useful
to have this proximal gradient  method so suppose we have a problem with
a separable objective a primal problem and then that's the dual function again with conjugates F star
a conjugate for H and a linear term so when is it true that we have
we can split this is in these two terms well for example if the first term
is differentiable with the Lipschitz continuous gradient then that fits the framework  for the proximal gradient method
in terms of the primal problem that means that F is strongly convex for example for
the second term  we don't need any assumptions to use a proximal gradient method if you call
that non-differentiable term in the for the proximal gradient method the only thing
we need is that we can evaluate the prox operator of H star efficiently
either by a closed form or efficient and simple method so let's look at an example suppose
this thing here cannot be written as a single but obviously it so we we
have to
complete the space under the linear combinations
and we'll just do this formally we just say OK
o space contains
elements of this form
the elements of this form where
the point x i x i x j prime here are some points from our
input domain and five beta i j some real numbers and also the
we keep we keep it open how many terms aren't just some so more prime
which could be any natural numbers so say this points also all space
next we have to say what's the dot product in all space
of course we want the dot product to satisfy this
question here
but of course we have to extend this to product also to other points
which are not of this format which are linear combinations in such
o point
so there is actually only one way of doing it
it is as follows this say that if we have functions f and g as
defined on the last slide
so these two functions with this representation
so the dot product is this double some here
if you plug in the special case where both f and g only single kernel
will see that this is consistent with with what i had before
not linearly extended to other points and
if we do something like this we have to worry about whether it's well defined
term that mathematicians like
it is well defined in other words this is
depends on how we write a function in terms of kernels
because of these problems
because it may be the case that for some kernel
some functions this representation is not unique
and then maybe the definition of the dot product will depend on how the functions
are expressed as the product to be just the property of the functions than that
off whole they are expanded in terms of the
so we need to show that this does not depend on the expansion and it's
actually simple to do this
if you briefly remember what other definitions of f and g
f was the sum of the of five and six IND was over the bhattacharyya
next a prime
you what you can see here this is actually the same as the
so half
the time the ex-prime was actually the expansion of g
so this is the same as a linear combination of expand of evaluations of g
at x i
and if you go the other way round you can also eliminate the
i fast by substituting the expression for f
so these are just two simple identities
and what they tell us is the following his first identity tells us
that the
the solution does not depend on the better days
because you as you can see it it does not explicitly depend on the better
days it just depends on what function d you really have say the function g
that has different expansions in different be different but i j edges
it doesn't matter because this this equality here shows that it doesn't depend on which
of the expansion to use it just depends on what the function g
likewise this equation here shows it does not depend on which was used to express
the function f it only depends on the function f itself
so was shown is only depends on g and if not enough as another better
so this is well defined
it it's symmetric by definition
if you have too expensive two functions f very few exchange f and g
you will get the same result here
and also it's by linear
so it will
you can take
o five times have put into the product
you can take f one plus f two
and use linearity so
i mean so the trivially built in you don't have to worry about this by
construction by linear do people know what it means by linear
so it just means that
if you have something like this
so this is a is true and the same would be true
in the second arguement if i have some
but i one one plus bit i two d two
it could also be
extracted from the product so it's by
that's nice but we still need a little bit more for it to be the
product of the products are
have to be well defined symmetric by linear and positive definite and i'm going to
show that is positive definite but that's a little bit more tricky
before we do this
let's just consider two special cases
so again i'm still here sorry
still here this definition of the dot product
and i will substitute some special cases so that's substitute a special case
where the first function is just a single kernel
and if you then take the dot product between
that single kernel the second function
you simply get function second function evaluated at x
i guess if you want you can verify this but it's just a trivial consequence
of the definition of this dot product so we have this decided here
and moreover if we choose both functions to be single clones so f is the
single sitting on x which is integral to the next prime
then all definition of the product reduces to this quote this equation here which you
might remember from before this is what we want
because this
the monster saying that the kernel is the same as the between files x i
phi xj
this suffix i five xt and this is the same as the kernel
and this equation here which is contained in a special case and the notion of
to get a deeper understanding of the formation of the rainbow behind
this of course
so you notice that the
blue light
is one percent slower in water
then the red light
and this phenomenon that you see there
that the speed of electromagnetic radiation depends on the wavelength depends on the frequency we
call that dispersion
it is a good thing that
sound in air is not this person because just imagine that high frequencies will travel
faster than low frequency is just as an example
or or so for that matter
it would mean then that if you go to a concert
you would listen to the violins on the basis that the violence would reach you
first and then the sound of the bass would which later in the forty you
away from august the worst that would be
if the effect very strong
in twenty six one hundred someone sitting in the back row could not even understand
my words because the high frequencies would reach that person at different times and the
low frequencies
so sound in air
is non dispersive
but glass and water i dispersive
four lights
and it's very noticeable
if i take
a piece of glass
and i give you this shape
the shape of the prison
and i shine some light on here
light from
these light bulbs or light from the sun for that matter
that i can apply snails were here
and angle of incidence
they one
i know the index of refraction this is for what would you can look them
up for class of course
and then you will see there is the difference of the index of refraction
four red light
that there is for
through light
and so
when you read this site
of the present
again you have to apply snails law
and when you do that you will see that the red light
it doesn't come out at the same angle
that the blue light come out
but the two diverge
that is the result of the fact that the indices of refraction i different but
also the result of the fact that we have
this particular shape body shape namely that this side of the glass is not parallel
to decide
so he put his screen here
you will see colors you can make a spectrum you can convince yourself that the
light from the light bulbs is just not white light
but that it contains many many callers
well it has to contain many callers
because of a look at the gentleman there he's wearing a red shirt
the only thing that you have colors coming from
must come from the light bulb filaments be red light in their the woman sitting
next to him is wearing a green shirt so there must also be green light
in this
lights and the same is true for sunlight
but the beauty is that making use of the dispersion
you can decompose
the white light into the individual
and the spectrum
if you take a piece of plane parallel glass
which is
window glass
you're not going to see colors
because if now i shine
light on here
white light
from the light bulbs of from the sun it is true that it will obviously
refracted here
but when you apply snails will again here
then it will come out
all the colors will come out in the same direction
the red light
comes out here and the blue light comes out in the same direction
and your brains are very special
if your brain see all colors coming from one direction
they say i see white light look at the light bulb
you say that's why i'd like to look at this gentleman using a red must
come from the light bulb
so your brains are special in the sense
the the thing
that the combination of many colours
i can show it to you in a you know rather convincing way
you see here this case
and i would assume that you see colours on the disk
if not you have a problem
and i can for your brains
what i can do
i can rotate the disk
so fast
that your brain gets so mixed up
that they're going to say to you
that's white light
so let me first give you
so my view
light on that this is going to spend couple of
so you agree with me right you still see colours
chelsea college right
still see colours right
this is why is it can be for me
not too surprising right if a situation when you look at the light bulb
the second goal
several minutes ago to be honest i'm always honest with you
the primary structure of the amino acid sequence
the secondary structure represents configurations like here's an alpha helix
here's a data
please she
so what we see in this alpha helix is we have the local structure
where the in the groove down here the NHK hydrogen bond with the residue which
is i think three three-and-a-half residues upstream one
doesn't mean that there is a with the carbon three residues
this one once again reached three residents
not all the hydrogen bonds are shown
in the background
only the ones are on our side of the lake show the front side of
the lake
you can imagine
this to perpetuate itself and each of these carbonell
they associate with the proton
many schools that either above or below
that particular residues
and this in turn can create new local structure
by the way probably
doesn't fit well in this case it's probably here proline is known in the trade
as helix breakers
why because you cannot twist itself around to form an alpha helix
so if the primary amino acid would indicate
the probably would be inserted right here for example
then the sea looks like this down below
but but but it wouldn't be continuous because the presence of protein is highly disruptive
of the formation
now alpha helix
this means that in principle you can make some predictions about the localized structural polypeptide
by knowing whether or not role the spread president for example but that still doesn't
give you the power to predict the entire three-dimensional structure of the protein itself
let's agree that this is the secondary structure of protein i e the various domains
which often form
alpha helix is within a certain segment of the protein
or a certain segment of the protein form beta pleated sheets and several are several
other less common kinds of of secondary structure
and here
we deal with
tertiary structure now we're getting really interesting or maybe you don't like it but
some people say it's really interesting because here are the tertiary structures of some arbitrarily
chosen from
the tertiary structure of this particular protein
and there are and the identities and are these are given textbook
i'm sure he spent two or three weeks to find out what they were but
here is a protein three dimensional structure of proteins
we're which is composed of four
all three losses which go
another alpha helix alpha helix alpha helix alpha helix
there different here forty four different colors
so we see that when we talk about tertiary structure we're talking about how the
how to use these are disposed with respect to one another
the primary structure as sequence is not shown here
secondary structure represents the individual
well see
and the tertiary structure represents cell alpha uses are arranged these one another
here is a protein which is structured much differently
here this is it is
one of many beta pleated sheets we saw them in in the last figure in
the last over here you quite different overall three-dimensional structure
this could be the beginning of an alpha helix down here although that's quite critical
and here we see yet another point and that is has been said before the
tertiary structure independent of these alpha and beta
all fields in the face may be stabilised by
covalent inter
grand cross formed by the city
in the end if we put all that together
then we come to the realization that the three dimensional structure of proteins
the determined by
the art of extreme
very good
i'm not actually dyslexic
i actually have cousins
i won't mention son was so dyslexic when it came to stairways you know where
the put foot up or down now that's difficult this is
it's not so bad
OK anyhow
i all within less than two minutes i really think this is what the three-dimensional
structure protein looks like
this is called the space filling models because you're one brought in
determined by x-ray crystallography what the if we could see what protein looks like maximize
look like
where each of the scene including side chains is actually affected
before we use these far more schematic
descriptions like you
we were just talking about the overall structure that formerly were really
in the case where the side chains were
and what they say would fill up
and if we give them a chance to put in all the other side chains
and we created space filling molecule model
where the
the actual animals so this is what the protein would look like
and the fact of the matter is that virtually all proteins have very specific structures
is that they can shift from one structure to another
once they leave their normal native structure they will lose
two to do what the normal jobs are
and this particular already happens to bring in yet another thing going to focus on
which is what proteins do in cells
and i a question
one of the things they do in there
hello i e as enzymes
the fact is we will discuss later
virtually all biochemical reactions require an enzyme
list in order to propel them forward
that is to say if the biochemical reaction to occur almost always
i will not occur spontaneously in the same way that the hydroxyl ion hydrogen will
going together spontaneously water
almost all biochemical reactions we require the mediation of an enzyme
which is the biological
in order to encourage this
and this while almost all
catalyst in
in our cells are protein
so if you have
four thousand three hundred twenty six
distinct biochemical
reactions occurring in the cell
that means that there's probably almost as many distinct enzymes each one of which is
the median one or another of those things
the biochemical reactions
very difficult to photograph i have not been able to get good slides
but today however
i did see some pictures on the web
and when you
log on to the web when you visit the web eight two
but you should
and i give you directions how to access
slides pictures of the
red sprites and of the blue jets
the physics of that is not very well understood being researched very heavily
it is way above the clouds
there are also other forms
of electrical breakdown
of this charge
they are different in the sense that is not an individual sport
but there is a continuous flow
of charge
it occurs always very sharp points
so there is a continuous current actually going on
some of that you may have seen that you may not remember
when we
use the carbon arc here
we had two carbon arcs
two carbon
and we had the potential difference between them
we've got this charge between them would cause the tremendous amount of light which we
use for projection purposes
so carbon
are discharged is such a form
of this charge by have continuous current is not just parts
if you take grass or trees
brushes for that matter
what is thunderstorm activity
they can go into his discharge at the sharp tips
and we call this brush discharge we call it an almost fires all the same
also called corona discharge i normally
call it corona discharge
it produces light because the ions when they neutralize produce light
it make sound pressure
so you can hear the cracking noise of the
corona discharge
an airplane that flies or car drives there is friction with the air and any
form of friction can charge things up
and so it's not uncommon at night that you can see
this corona discharge from the tip of the wings of an airplane
i've also seen it from cars
corona discharge from cars which charge themselves up simply by
driving through the area air flow charts them up
you can hear
and you can see it sometimes it dark enough you see some light general generally
blue is light
something completely on the side going back to the lightning bolts
lightning bolts
the discharge moving electrons can cause
radio waves
these are a new ways you can receive on your car radio
and all of you have experienced is driving around
lightning very far away you can hear on the radio
but that's telling you that there is likely
going on somewhere
after a thunderstorm something that
many of you may not have experience
was in the city's there's always
always examples from cars that's spoils everything but when you're out in the country
after a thunderstorm is a very special smell air i love and and that's also
oxygen two
in lightning comes up to three and oxygen three has wonderful smell
you can really smell that it's very typical
i hope that most of you
so late in life will have that experience to go to the country after the
and you can really smell
these ozone
let's now look at some slides
the first slide
but you will see
is one very classics like made by gary led
OK peak observatory in arizona
what i like about this is that these are the
observatory telescopes don't
and of course when you're an astronomer
this is the kind of whether you can do without
but nevertheless it happens
you see here
return stroke
the light is definitely due to the return strokes it's very bright
these are step
that never made it to the earth
and it is that it doesn't make studio you don't get the return stroke
so the light
as you can see here
is much less
and what you think here is only one ball
it's probably at least ten
five ten maybe fifteen
we construct
all right next slide please
you see the result of a boy camera exposure
for those of you who are sitting in front you can recognise maybe the empire
state building here
and the empire state building is hit by lightning very cheap at the sharp edge
that's where you expect it to be here
this is not
can when the camera was rotating
is just
the exposure to where you and i would see it
not moving camera and here you see the results
of the rotating boys camera
this is the same place you see
he returned from the light from the step leads to faint
you can see that
here's the return stroke
and then this
time separation maybe thirty or forty millisecond
you know stroke
you know one another one to six here like if you don't want here
so you have six or seven of these return strokes
and this is the way that you can study
and how much charge actually
exchange between these three clubs
and in this case the empire state building
the next slide shows you a corona discharge
in the laboratory is a high-voltage supply
it's a very short period and the sharp point
and you see not individuals spark you don't call this lightning
but this is what you would call the saint elmo's fire
okay goes pretty close the points ok ok and we can do an order
three effect ok or in order for fit for northern five ok six and
so on ok which of these is the best fit yeah to the data ok is
this ok is this so this ok
so that's that's part of the problem depends what we mean by fit
to the data ok so what can we mean well one thing we could mean
is what's the error on the training set that we're using
ok and we can do something really good on the training set we
can do this ok we can actually find high enough degree polynomial
that are exactly fit the training set
ok and the error on the training set is zero
okay is this a good fit to the data
well sort of our intuition says no ok why
because it's very wild ok goes to points but it seems to have no
rhyme or reason another words we're not confident that this kind
of fit actually generalizes from the training data that we have
to new data that we might see in the future
okay probably some other things you know maybe order to order three
might actually be be better ok so this points to a problem
of mismatch between what we would like to measure in the objective
of the optimization and what we can actually measure
ok what we would like to do is to measure the true rule error on
the whole distribution of the data but we don't have access to
that we only have access to find example
as a result we can only measure things on that finite sample of data
ok now if all we do is train and test on the same sample of data
then we're going to run into trouble okay we essentially get
solutions that look like this where we have
to know the training data fit perfectly but not really good hypothesis
not hypothesis that generalize well
ok so this is a really really important problem in all machine
learning called overfitting and it basically means that we find a
hypothesis that fits the training data very well but does
not generalize well once examples and
essentially the nature of this comes from have been to many parameters
for how much data we have ok we're going to make this a little
bit more formal now a lot of this that that you're going to hear
during the week is methods to get around this problem when you
do have a lot of parameters not very much training data
ok so this is another examples that picture are taken from
bishops book of different hypotheses fit through these blue
circles okay and here we have one specific function that's the
green function that's sort of the true function
the point were generated by applying a little bit of noise to
that function and then we do fits of various degrees
of polynomials and as you can see as if you're degrees to small
ok basically can't fit the data that's called underfitting ok it
means that your hypothesis spaces to simple
and you cannot represent the true function
ok doesn't allow you to represent the function
if of hypothesis space as to complicated like the degree nine
polynomials over here you have the overfitting problem that we've
just seen in other words you can represent perfectly the training
data can in fact memorize it because you have enough parameters
to to to memorize it but there's no generalization
ok and so what we would like to have is a learning method that goes
in between and finds the right complexity
of the hypothesis and so now we're going to have to talk about
how how to do that ok
so this is just to to give to the different tion of overfitting
a little bit more formally okay so in general we have
for any hypothesis a true error ok which we denote by j star
j star is the expected error when the data comes
from the true distribution ok but we don't have all the data ok
so what do we do we get a sample of data b d that's our data
set and so we estimate the true error
by a finite sample ok now the problem is that if we use this finite
sample both to find a hypothesis and to estimate the error
we might be fooling ourselves so we can be a situation where we
find a hypothesis that best error on the data set that we have
that but which is actually worse when we look at the entire
to have a different kind of of output formats
so this is a good environment for us to do this kind of such experiments
now we have the tools we have
did some experiments with the IMF staff reports the idea
is that if we wanted to follow up with
country development or even want to do country analysis and this kind of tool could
be useful
another reason is the IMF staff reports is a very well written every almost everyone
has the executive summary one page executive summary we could use it as a benchmark
for evaluation proposed
and so these are
two examples of how the
how do
staff report is written a it's very standard format always
always had three or four sections basically there is the introduction about economic background of
the country and then policies setting and a lot of local of the economic situation
of of this country and then in the main
the main concepts and you can see this report and
policy discussions
that that the second that date the meet an IMF staff scientist who were with
the country's authorities so they were wearing a little bit but not not so very
much in different reports
and then
before we evaluate the effects of different methods and we also
need to choose evaluation methods there are basically two different types
one one is the this
this package
provided in a
it's basically calculate
lexical overlapping beaten
we tend
we tend to documents so in this case we calculate the lexical overlapping the to
the executive summary and our some system generated summaries
and then we were thinking this is perhaps not the
it is definitely not perfect evaluation methods but the problem is that
it seems very difficult to find the perfect one but complimentary methods without seems latent
semantic analysis is supposed to be able to capture semantic similarities so
we also tried to use this method
and so we have and that it
several experiments in the first experiment
the proposal to test
the effect of the IDF dictionary
the regulator of the all the documents are modelled based on the vector space model
and then use the TF IDF weight
so and so obviously or or at least i would think that IDF dictionary has
will will have a big effect on the out the results
so meet system has has an IDF dictionary itself and the group said that a
should work reasonably while as a general dictionary but we thought maybe if we create
like text the specific
IDF dictionary it might help to improve the
so we have in addition to these ones from me since we have created three
three IDF dictionaries one is where small ones
sorry that was a mistake it was the old idea it was
created from only thirteen the IMF country reports
only i am kind of country reports and then there is the next one IMF
idea it is
in larger scale sixty nine the country of course
and then the larger RDF is created from
many economic
reports and papers not only that not only the
staff reports
so this is i think i'm going to
to do so
it is substantively
so it was actually very disappointing this large idea spend a lot of a lot
of time actually in
it takes a lot of efforts to create these IDF dictionaries from much document and
the performances is actually
this large RDF
performance really quite
inferior compared to other the IDF dictionaries but as you can see because this compression
rate has such influence on the summary output that ten percent of compression rate the
then the differences is quite quite small
but five percent of compression eight percent of sentences you can see
some differences in performance however the main idea of
best performing quite good compare with the others
this is based on the evaluation using latent semantic analysis
and then there's also another experiment we tested the random method because its centroid method
seems has alot of rationality is behind it but how the state functions that it
perform comparing to the random method and the result is a little bit
disappointed actually
the random method is
a little bit
they a little bit
lies and performed in terms of these overlapping metric measurements however with the latent semantic
analysis the random method should sometimes can or will perform
so brendan can do quite well
so the and then we also tested the reranking facility there are three ranking facilities
in need and
the difference is not very big
in a if we are using this evaluation metrics for lexical similarity merriment but
using here slightly different citation here vikram they have done that in a slightly different
way but they all try to extract the knowledge people
encoding in the web
so here for example in textrunner the system began new world in our and it's
only and use that
we can ask now very slight
wildcard topic asking you in which relation to paper topic standing right so you get
that things like paper discusses
o addresses
and so on and so on so what do we learn from these kinds of
systems and what do we have to achieve but managed to do if we want
to make use of this right for right now this is just a
particularly closer what we what you see when we talk about here are kind of
objects like paper in topic with some relations between different topics and maybe some form
of uncertainty the numbers here is something like the number of times you have extracted
this kind of thing
let's not have a debate about whether really uncertainty or not you can do that
in different ways for this tutorial here the best viewed as an uncertainty ninety if
you see it quite often this relation with a high number of pounds and we
are sure about it all more about it
if you just want to come
it tells us that task we are facing now we will face in the future
some are characterized by objects and these objects and and in contrast to traditional using
machine learning and AI are not just feature vectors right they are more than they
have maybe even part
they certainly have relations to other objects they might be trees graphs whatever it's an
object is not just one line in a table but much more than the more
given that there are relations we should definitely say objects not really
independent identically distributed but they're like neighborhoods right they are interconnected with other objects and
information about the neighbours are related objects of a lot about the object we are
currently facing
it might be class hierarchies and the semantic web community
i mean this is all about all the triple stores they talk about our data
are still coming from the ontology
and definitely properties of one object depends on the properties of the other ones like
if i look into the audience here i don't know anything about most of you
but i definitely know that you're attending UAI
because of that i also know that you somehow interest in computer science
announcer somehow interest in mathematics they just using my world knowledge and using the relations
between you and other entities like i i can draw much more conclusions than just
looking at you like a single person each of your independent that's all about
if we agree on that
definitely the question is how can we deal with this kind of knowledge how can
we make sense of the knowledge base of the data OK we do inference
so let's have a look at how people have commented a way
over the last ten twenty thirty years so one classical way
of dealing with the complexity and
things like we have objects and relations among them
first order logic
right so traditionally we may have an explicit enumeration we have comic representation of first
order or relational
logical representation the benefit of using logic is essentially that you get a compressed representation
of what you have included otherwise in in the long run this story narration of
all the facts so here for example where you list all the daughter of relations
for all pairs of individuals separately you just define
right so we're now when we have any information about father of female we can
conclude that someone is the daughter of someone so you get this compression
and then you can
you get a general rule
i and within then this kind of more traditional knowledge representation there was a lot
interesting going on like you can ask how to read and all the different knowledge
we talking about like trees graphs hierarchies and so on but they also
very interesting inference algorithms typically in the early days of leave
here i have not seen much UAI like satisfiability SAT solvers resolution theorem proving and
so on
right so
two even further illustrate that that's an example you're as like to give
also in his book if you want to and coach has an atomic representation where
you just list everything this would maybe take the same millions of pages
maybe an accelerating healing
if you use
propositional logic which is something like a factorized representation you can get already much more
compact but only if you use if you abstract of certain places on the board
you can get a one or two-page kind of compression representation of the theory of
the rules of chess
but of course task not just structure they are not just complex but
there's also a lot of uncertainty involved in that's why we're all here i and
we want to deal with
probability because information might be
might be incomplete
we may just be uncertain about certain things that might be typos in there if
you think of database and if you think of the task of cleaning and they
don't care big company and you have people creating and all the information about customers
very likely that there here and then a few typos in there so for example
i recently troubles financial department because they retracting my last name wrongly but only with
too little
little typos took them quite long and what faces people say oh it's in the
system so it's true
and i always try to tell them well it's in the system so it's more
likely to be true but they still don't get it to let let's try to
work on that
to then
again we can ask how do computer systems nowadays
deal with uncertainty and well that's all what you know about in the sand mixture
models hidden markov models bayesian networks
markov random fields and maximum entropy models whatever
take your favourite on the right so we have these two kind of taxis in
if you look at what classically in
AI people would have done to tackle these problems
and so
given these two axes you can ask with traditional AI or UAI scale
so given this simplified view on
i hope you agree
this will not work
let's see how you traditionally do it like with based on that
what does it mean
the traditional view we have something like table
right so you features head of labels
OK and then you do whatever you like you can do prediction you may do
variable model one
so what do is essentially to try to
have a lot of independence within you are random variables
and then try to get a compact representation of these independencies
let's say in terms of bayesian network in order to do
that's what we all know
in many cases like i was showing you already with world-wide mind project from the
we know that we are not having just a single cable or
indeed if you go for universal cable then this would be a very large table
with a lot of knowledge
it's not a good idea that already what whatever theory tells you so if you
go for any kind of normal form
then you would have not a single table but several tables with relations between
how do we deal
yet another example what was taken from daphne and here
something at least i had to learn
when i was a phd student
as everybody we're going to submit a paper to a conference and then you know
your supervisor if he has no time to tell you that have a certificate getting
but he's not talking a lot about you do about every rule like you may
say that it is sometimes get a b and so on so he's giving you
just these rules
so from that you build up your little structure in bayesian networks
like the quality of the paper difficult to certain conferences and you try to predict
the grade of your paper to see whether it's worth submitting it clearly getting
you could probably apply
the expectation propagation algorithm for this problem you can apply the variational bayesian framework this
problem this is something that we've done played around with
so all those approximate inference tools can now be used to try to solve this
and i'm not selling one versus the other they have advantages and disadvantages
so to summarize parameter learning
we had the case with complete data
in the case of incomplete or missing data are hidden variables
and then we consider maximum likelihood versus bayesian
and these two are really easy
they just involve counting frequencies are updating dirichlet distributions which are just frequencies plus some
hyperparameters added to them
those alpha is that to them both these cases were a bit harder we had
ian algorithm here MCMC the terribly or this variational bayesian sometimes called variational bayes in
yemen algorithm because this is a simple generalization of the algorithm here
these are always trying to iteratively fill in the missing data and then do
parameter estimation and inference
so any any questions about this
i was
so the question was in the case where you need to do variational bayes or
maybe one of these other
inference methods you might as well choose the non conjugate prior well
yes and no i mean because you're already doing approximate inference
you may have the flexibility of choosing larger families of priors then original analytic
answers you with the complete data
the updates for variational bayes you're going to hear about variational methods in common because
talk in more detail by the way for everybody else but the update variational bayes
are incredibly simple if the priors are conjugate
so everything becomes very computationally fast and that's the sort of situation where
the time complexity is almost the same whether you're bayesian or to a maximum likelihood
between these two
whereas if you choose arbitrarily complicated priors you're updates become very very hard
and keep in mind that
you know even if you choose the sort of complicated prior have a huge datasets
you're likely functions going to swamp out the prior anyway
you know it
you can worry about your choice of prior but if you have a a lot
of data you just need to make sure your prior puts reasonable amounts of mass
reasonable set of hypotheses basically
additionally distributions to put reasonable mass on
lots of different things
OK the questions
for non discrete data so you know there are many kinds of non discrete data
you know but but let's think of like simple
simple cases are
calcium variables a linear relationship between the parameters then
you can do this whole conjugacy trick again
and basically becomes a complicated way of doing
you know
regression of children on their parents in a big graphs but
i i would assume that i mean that's quite limiting
o thing depends really on the application for very general for very general
value data
and complicated relationships between the parents and children
one of the approximate inference methods would have to be used either something like EP
or very safe thing to try is markov chain monte carlo methods et cetera
particle filters et cetera all the things that you'll hear about
so this is a summary of parameter learning let me arms it through a
structure learning
and then i want to give you a flavor for
this sort of a really more like a research topic that actually hides a whole
bunch of things together
structure learning well structure learning is the following given a data set of observations of
a bunch of variables can we learn the structure of the graphical model from data
so what do i mean by structure well we know what the variables are is
a b c d e here
five variables the structure corresponds to
different choices of the set of edges connecting up these graphs
OK so these are four different structures for this and for these five variables and
the number of possible structures is absolutely huge it grows
you know like
two the power and squared
roughly four and variables
but let's try to learn a good structure from data and i'm not going to
assume that structure corresponds any sort of causal relationships or anything like that
we're now
thank you
so how do we do this
well broadly speaking for directed graphs there are two kind of camps for the structure
one of them is
constraint based learning
where what's done is to come up with statistical tests of marginal and conditional independence
so it's sort of as yourself alright i got the measurements of these five variables
let's do a classical test of independence between a and b
OK that has comes out saying a b are independent OK
with some confidence or something
for significance
all right well now let's do a given
a and b given c
is that conditional independence
true or not let's let's get an answer yes or no with some
you know p value or confidence of some kind
and now
he proposed some modifications to the boar model he like the boar model you wanna
throw out he liked the concept of a planetary model but then he want to
maybe look to the heavens no capitalist laws of planetary motion what's the orbits of
the planets described
it's already website
so Sommerfeld said how about this suppose just supposing this is not to scale exaggerated
sentiment suppose in addition to a spherical orbital suppose the electron might describe an elliptical
now over all this is roughly the same it's not super elliptical it's just mildly
elliptical but just enough that it's not exactly spherical so this could give users have
your cake and eat it too you could say this but this is the principle
quantum number of war it's
but within and there's a little bit of fine structure fine structure that is to
say they're details there that the 1st didn't quite catch a
so suppose we have a lot more than 1 level we have a plurality of
elliptical orbits
so we have elliptical orbits but they're roughly of the same dimension as the original
circular orbit this we have sort of a urbanity calls this a shell containing multiple
which he termed baubles to distinguish them from the circular orbits
white-collar shell model he said think about the eggs shall be eggs shall we can
describe it but the NHL itself has something so this is a sense of what
what Sommerfeld was given
so he says how am I going to capture these ideas quantitatively while the shell
could be captured by the quantity and but these orbitals some of them circular some
of elliptical under new quantum numbers you quantum numbers
In order to capture these new ideas
and so let's take a look at the quantum numbers that are Sommerfeld gave us
so the first one is on and it is as it was in the case
of the boar model so this is called the principal shall quality the principle of
quantum number or the shell quantum number principle shall quantum number and it talks about
size it talks about size the size of that is to say the distance from
the nucleus to the
it takes values 1 2 3 and so on up to infinity infinity we're talking
about a free electron
and in parallel there's another notation that used the spectroscopy
came up with their own notation they like numbers the spectroscopy stews letters but you
spectroscopy is the funny bunch don't the very suspicious so here's what happens if you
look on this chart here for a while we thought Baltimore was the bottom of
the barrel
that's equals 2 and then when the detectors got better we saw that n equals
1 so the spectroscopy said what if somebody comes along with an even better detector
and finds transitions to energy levels below
that which we're calling 1
so we're going to get ready we're going to give letters to these and they
started with the letter cake is a somewhere in the middle of the alphabet
so if we are discovered energy level lower than equals 1 we can use the
latter will be the j
so this K L M and this notation is used to this day when we
talk about X rays x-rays generated by electrons falling down to ground state called came
x rays
so this is the other notation for the values that can contain now let's get
into the contributions of
Sommerfeld he called the next quantum number lowercase L and this is the orbital quantum
number the orbital quantum number
and it describes the shape of the orbital memorize we needed some way to distinguish
purely circular from elliptical or other shape orbitals
and the orbital quantum number takes values 0 1 2 up to the value of
n minus 1
up to the value and minus 1
and the spectroscopists newsletters they they refused to use numbers they're very numeral folder so
that use lowercase letters to distinguish the orbital quantum number from the principle quantum number
and so when the
l equals 0 it's case s for shop these would be very sharp lines then
P 4 an l equals 1 which is the principal d over l equals to
which stands for diffuse
and f which stands for fundamental because by the time you get to f level
you got such compression all of the spectral lines starting look very similar to those
file over the lousy mode and flips ten percent bits we have to make a
phone call the last three times as long or we have to buy three telephone
lines that allows a
and the way we quantify this is really thing called the rate of communication the
rate was won by definition when we started with the channel with no
error correction
and we had to probability of death and what we've done is we've improved their
probably but the rate has got low we define the rate to be the ratio
of the number of source bits that are actually being sent to the number of
times we use the channel
and so for three which are rubbed off three
has the property
the number of cells called k one and two
the number of different bits which we call and which was three and the range
the rate is one
so that's the bad news
but it is promising isn't it
i'll leave homework exercise to discuss whether r two is a good idea
or not this was all one which means code
and here's another homework exercise for you
what happens when we switch to an where n is an odd number like five
o seven o thirteen o fifty one
and in particular
how big does and need to be
o thing about are and how big this and need to be
to deliver
which is my name for the probability of being error
the probability of
the error
to deliver the TV that i said we want to register my fifteen
for today's lecture
because they need to be you understand the question
OK so that's the problem and when you've done your homework problems
you will find that the answer for at this point what
is sixty one
here's the answer that book
so assuming at this point one
and is
sixty one
and this is a graph showing exactly the numbers we've just been talking about one
three but the end are sixty one and this is saying yes we can make
encoding and decoding systems have the property
that we can get the error probability down to the required level
so this is possible
we just need to put sixty one this tries to box with his your this
OK one describing there and it costs us sixty one times as much to make
as we'd really like
can we do better here is the astonishing amazing things
the amazing thing is we can do much better than repetition codes
and so anyone want to
it's just always abiding redundancy
apart from repetition
what is sphere packing me
OK so many lattice
o points
a high dimensional space
the idea
nicholas points in a high dimensional space
you want that lattice of points is going to be transmission so it's going to
be a great long list transmissions like zero zero zero zero zero zero zero could
possible transmission and
and then you could also have long
and maybe not long from OK
and you can have some systematic way of making these points such that the a
big gap between all of them right
and then you take source files
let's say for simplicity we just had
this is your set of lattice point it's a possible source of i'm going to
work with i'm going to be zero zero zero one
one zero one one this is an example of a lot to the idea is
going to block of source because at the time like one of the time and
repeating them we taken two at a time and then every pair is going to
in a more complicated way than simple repetition
like that
OK this is an example of the lattice of points in a dimensional space the
four of them and we can associate them with source strength that's school the block
four it to work well we want these to be a long way from each
other because we don't want flips to confuse them with each other
m and c are constants
the q is proportional to develop
if we divide both the time elapsed
the invented with the temperature rises when the data with heat flows into the system
if he playing at a steady rate pressure should rise and indeed it does
part of the ice
go from minus thirty
minus twenty to minus ten and so on
but once it hits zero
it gets stuck
i know he is coming in but it's not getting harder
but i notice
the ice is beginning to map
that would be a period
between here and here
when i pop in calories i don't get any increase in temperature but i get
conversion of ice into water
and that would a period when the guys
looks like some water would sometimes of ice floating on
and until all the ice
was converted to water
the whole system is stuck at that time
that's very interesting properties and a few really took a real part
and you put a chunk of ice on it you know what will happen right
the bottom of the ice will melt it may even evaporate
that's not what i'm talking about because that's not a system where there's a globally
defined but i want you to heat the i so slowly
i mean to put a little bit of calories
give it enough time for all these guys to share the heat the whole system
has one single common temperature
that's what the temperature rise and saying it gets stuck in zero
but your calories are getting something converting ice into what
and you can ask OK what penalty do have to pay
that's called the latent heat of melting
and again i know only
in calories per gram
is it calories for example one
some of you don't thank you
now goes not to raise the temperature
but to melt some more stuff
the latent heat of melting
that so much q you need to melt
that more the stuff
and the elevators from substance to substance but walkers eighty calories per gram
one melt mercury from solid making the liquid crystal have different
then once
everybody has become
then that uniform system of water start growing
and this is called a phase change this changes when
atomic arrangement from the regular race for example the form solid into a liquid
in the solid everybody has its place you can check in on where you are
liquid you can run around
the specific heat of eyes
it's not the the same as the specific you know what
because the careful even though
two made up of water molecules
the calories needed to hit one gram of ice is roughly half what it takes
to heat one grammy of water
in these problems don't make the mistake
OK then you go along and i guess you know what the next stopping point
is when it comes to one hundred degrees
again it gets stuck
well everybody
their prices and then you get the
and you can have superheated steam which is even higher than
hundred degrees
so that's the latent heat of vaporization
i don't know what you want to write something i think is five hundred something
this information i don't
katie in my head
so you can
if i tell you i took some ice minus thirty dumped in
five thousand calories
where will it end up you got first spend a few calories going from here
to here
you've got some more money left you can start melting this
if you run out of stuff there and that's what you will have
some amount of water and some ice
you don't even more calories at your disposal
you can melt the all and start eating it
you may come this way and you may be running out of calories if not
keep going here and there and then
you may end up being provided of calories
or one can ask question how many calories does it take
to convert ice minus thirty to say what a hundred
well that he
he left see delta t for that
in times the latent heat for this
mc delta the for that and claims latent heat of vaporization from
so the kind of problems you can get a fairly simple
what's the time
only kind of problem where you can really get in trouble is the following
good morning everybody
welcome to the tutorial
about reasoning for
ontology engineering and usage this tutorial
consists of four parts
the first part the introduction and related information about standard reasoning techniques and query answering
techniques will be presented by me after the break there will be
an introduction to
new ontology design technique we call this the bottom-up approach for the for ontology design
this part will be presented by any admin to learn from dresden university
modularisation issues and explanation issues will be handled in the third part
which is presented by matthew horridge from manchester university and the last topic will be
data integration through ontologies and this tutorial and them demo will be given by few
companies from both tunnel giuseppe verdi giacomo from
wrong university last cancer and
a demo will be given by mariano rodriguez from
so my name is roughness from hamburg univ
of technology
and i will introduce the
standard ideas behind ontology based modeling and we will try to develop
and methodological way for developing ontologies this is by what we call an topology engineering
and i will show several examples in which ontologies are actually used
i mean if you have any questions don't hesitate to ask
it a very technical question then we might put this offline but it could be
an interactive tutorial so if you have a question just race
raise your hand
speaking about terminological knowledge means representing an application domain in terms of classes
properties and
objects instances of classes and as you might know there is
multiple ways to name things so talking about classes
fields of is complemented with other notions so in more mathematical
mathematically oriented fields one talks about concepts or concept descriptions properties are well known and
also called relations or role descriptions as you want you can these
you can use these names interchangeably objects also known as instances or individuals play a
major role in applications and
with objects we capture
information on knowledge about
individual objects of our world
the first step in our view
for ontology engineering is to select names or to define a signature for the
knowledge base for the ontology to be developed so the first step consists of selecting
atomic concept descriptions in our tutorial and
demonstration we will use the university ontology because we assume that most of you will
be familiar with the notions used there so we have concept names such as student
professor chair department and so on and so forth these have to be selected as
modelling primitives if you one and the same also for the atomic
role description so we will be talking about head off
professor maybe had offered department and so on students take courses
and professors are members of department and so on also we will use individuals and
it is a common tradition to use numbers for denoting individuals here as you will
see later it's not really
the issue about selecting
ten or twenty individuals we will be talking about ten thousands of individuals so
probably one doesn't really select every name by hand so the names are generated automatically
but the basic view is that one defines the signature first and then we use
so called axioms to impose constraints or restrictions on the possible interpretation of these names
so the next example would be that a chair must be a person or professor
depending on what you want to model
persons are no departments those two things are disjoint
next we build up the model by
defining these axioms and
i will
continue the
tutorial by introducing different types of axioms different languages such that at the end you
will be familiar with this kind of modelling
maybe you've already made some experiences using these modelling languages so
if you already have
some knowledge about this what i present might be complementary
so basically
the hope was that
this picture doesn't work critical of
so basically
ontologies consist of a class level and an instance level
for historical reasons the axioms put the view is that the axioms are put into
a box so we call the
class level t box and you can easily imagine that one can define classes here
he said the classes into relation to each other
the instance is also very important so we model the relations between instances and the
relations are usually directed or we might
use both directions and so on we have to explicitly model this and this
knowledge about individuals
these surgeons about individuals are put into a so called a box a search box
this then
for two
the same
try trying to get the ball
so people
why not
we also wish to you good at something not
but i
you know we know
you need to talk
i mean
are you know they will
so for the one i want to try it
well that make
don't use
you might
so should and hopefully
and i think that
francis bach
so this is the use of the
this is
the addition as he
on features you
so this was going to happen
so the in the past and
the laws of the
these were
actually that's a
last much less work
we were able to solve this problem
at the bottom
so what
the whole
and should all
i think the problems
he tried
also the problem of moral hazard
is no a solution
o point
and also is
the which
i mean you
and then one
and although the russians actually seems like
so i can't see some kind of
observations it's possible to actually see section one
there's a reason why they want to
i just want to see the russian
so the first approach to the
in new space by projecting
into a high dimensional
to the feature space
and is this much higher dimension is
for example
in two dimensions
projected into this
o dimensional
which is actually
thank you for
then we can actually write a
live in the place for a time
we can't rely on
and i agree with that you
this is know
but by the she
she is a
the nice demonstration of
three locations
so you see one
one hundred times
and there is
we can change for the
i also right
in nineteen ninety
and you
that is a linear function of three dimensional space
the graph
the image
he was
the plane
and ends we with
the when i get back the original space using that
the linear separation
in fact
the fact that she i don't
OK so
now we can use
the same
just show
actually there is a direct relationship between the dimensions of space
feature space and as is basically
dimensional space
you live brain
as you mentioned in the song
so even more
and so on
i would like to see
the years