divergence or distance
happened in this paper in 1951
and Kullback and Leibler
called it the mean information for
The definition already immediately recognizes that what we are defining there is
actually the expectation of a certain random variable
and you already see the word 'information' there
and in fact in the paper (title) on information and sufficiency
so what was the motivation of Kullback and Leibler to introduce this measure?
OK, so here's the first paragraph from the introduction
generalizes to the abstract case shannon's definition of information
we information is essentially the same as shadow although the motivation was different
in china
apparently has investigated the concept more completely so the last sentence
a big understatement
in fact i will come back to this later in and out
i'll tell you more in detail what was what was it that we never had
to do with this
but you not show
shannon was interested in in what we say the operational
the role of these quantities setting up an engineering problem and then just showing their
this quantity as well as entropy as well as mutual information and the answers to
those problems worse whereas winner did not they he only used one of these quantities
and essentially said that he thought it would be
one interesting exercise to actually optimise this quantity when the variance of the random variable
is fixed
OK so the most
state the most important special case of
relative entropy
is the mutual information so as as we're going to come in later
the relative entropy is a great way to measure the similarity between two distributions and
asymmetric way off
of doing that and i
we can apply that definition two
the special case where the first
distribution is the joint distribution and the second one is the product of marginals
he for
if this random variables x and y
independent then of course we're going to get zero otherwise we're going to get a
and the negative numbers
OK so this is extremely extremely general way of defining of gauging and the degree
of dependence
of course we all
have grown up with correlation coefficient and so on but
for example that one
only applies to
real valued random variables
here x and y can be whatever you want x can be discrete y can
anything you want
you can
you can throw it inside these mutual information
of course you could also define it the other way you could define the
the the relative entropy of the the product of the marginals
relative to the joint distribution and that's what we call a loud tomb information was
mutual this spelled backwards and the it's not as famous as this one as mutual
information but you can still
at least right one paper about it
really relative entropy is the mother of all information measures
mutual information is a special case and to business for this special case of mutual
if i
you have a finite alphabet then you can see in the bottom equation here
there the relative entropy of
of a distribution
with respect to the
equally likely distribution
uniformly distributed on that alphabet that's as the logarithm of
the alphabet size
minus the entropy
OK so you can you can define
and to be in that special case through relative entropy in the more general case
just do it like this you say the entropy of a random variable is as
the mutual information
of that on the with its
if you think about it then it's going to be just the relative entropy of
the joint distribution with the product of the two marginals
the joint distribution when x is equal to x
OK so
but very important
it is
the conditional relative entropy just like regular shannon entropy it's very important to also have
the the conditional entropy
here we can do the same thing and here's the definition and in fact
conditional relative entropy is more general
the relative entropy by
is also the other way around because
this is just a special case of the other definition of the definition of conditional
relative entropy
so let me explain this a little bit what you have here
is three objects so the conditional relative entropy is defined for three objects rather than
the relative entropy is defined for two
here we have the conditional distribution of y given x another one z given x
and px so think of this
all these conditional distributions
sometimes they are called transition kernels or markov kernels things like that you can think
of them even in the absence of having defined joint distributions between
x and z
in end
now y and x but in any case if you find those
we could get the same results by going through pages of mathematics using the sum
product rule is just much easier to look at the picture read the results of
i get a little bit like my background in physics and physics are the single
fireman diagrams doing perturbation expansions in field theory and essentially could do everything without the
diagrams with the diagrams help you set out the calculations very orderly way and therefore
avoid repeating what's the same calculations over and over again and so makes the calculation
very easy and efficient
on some issues efficiency
the diagrams also lead to efficient software implementation so we have algorithms for doing inference
and learning on graphs and you'll see these are expressed in terms of message passing
algorithms express them in terms of sending little messages around on the graph to lots
of local calculations we can build software that reflects that structure that software will be
very efficient
so what mentioned two kinds of graph the things even may mention others
and the talk about use directed graph in order to design the model
and having designed the model
we can turn it into a different kind of graph called the factor graph which
is convenient for
inference and learning using that model
so this graph all about well let's
it starts with an arbitrary distribution over three variables x y and z
and if we apply the product rule twice
we can write this
symmetrical distribution rather nonsymmetric way
as the product of the distribution of each of the three variables x y and
z conditioned on other variables so to do this we chose the particular ordering of
the variables we can represent that by graph
so each of these variables is represented by circle in the graph
and the relationships between the variables are described by links between the between circles between
the nodes in these links carry parasites like for the directed graph
the interpretation of the graph is that it specifies the way in which the joint
distribution decomposes into this product of conditionals in particular there one factor for each variable
and the conditioning variables are the parents in the graph
so there's an narrow from x to y then x is said to be the
parents of y
so this graph has the joint distribution of x y and z decomposes into p
of x given its parents well it doesn't have any parents
p of y given its parents has one parent is x
pz given its parents which x y
so that graph is equivalent to that decomposition
we have a rule about these graphs in order for this to to work properly
there must be any directed cycles it is if you follow any loops in the
it was never be the case that you can go around the loop following the
direction of the arrows
just related to this ordering of the variables
so directed graph
more generally has the property that are missing links and it's the absence of links
in the graph really conveys information so in this example this is any distribution of
three variables is described by this graph this graph is fully connected every variable is
connected to every other
once we start emitting links here's a graph of the seven variables were not every
potential link is is present makes missing is missing links
tell us about independence properties
this graph with missing links therefore describes more restrictive family of distributions therefore encode some
specific knowledge is still looking all possible distributions looking the narrow family distributions
so we can write down
factorizations specified by the graph the same way as forces seven variables
with seven nodes for each variable
and so the joint distribution is the product of the conditional
one for each variable
and these conditionals conditional on its parents
p of x one to x seven
is written as the product of p x one given its parents there aren't any
solution x two and x three
if x four given its parents and parents of x four x one x two
x three px one given x one x two x three and so on for
the remaining factors
and that's i haven't said whether these are continuous variables of discrete variables or the
gas distribution gamma distributed or whatever this is
really describing the whole family
of distributions the family of distributions that have a certain independence properties
so we can use directed graphs two
to specify models and capture prior knowledge
and the other thing that i won't dwell on too long but the direction of
the arrows can be thought of as representing causality so if we think about little
boxes of fruit example became the first of all we in the the the physical
process in the physical world is we first of all choose box and having chosen
box regions side which choose a piece of fruit that's the sort of ordering relationship
we have in the physical process
the machine learning we want to go in the opposite direction we observed the piece
of the identity of the piece of fruit we want to infer which box it
came from and so that's a typically each of these graphs is examples later the
arrow specify the directions of causal physical process in the world and they we typically
observe notes down here
we want to infer posterior distributions of nodes higher the graph yes question
yes we'll see examples of temporal
what you show some examples later actually we have time information creates a lot of
questions or questions
yes indeed there are there are other kinds of graphs there is that the undirected
graph for example that don't specify
sort of soft relationships between variables without giving them the status of one being the
cause of another and also we might introduce variables that don't necessarily have an interpretation
in the physical world the unobserved variables but there is part of the modelling process
we don't necessarily
we may or may not wish to interpret those is being
some actual piece of physics in the in the real world
you explained how many variables and then you at some point discourse flattens out and
then you will say well
i'm i'm
explain almost all the variants but one hundred sixty two hundred twenty six
only could use under twenty six dimensions
if you look at the course in LSI either much much flat so you can
use that as a heuristic for choosing the number of dimensions so
as far as i know it's always done
by tuning people try different values and choose the best
values like a hundred two hundred and three hundred very frequently used
reduction to one hundred dimensions to other dimensions three hundred much which is quite amazing
because you
if you think of a space that has
tens of thousands of
dimensions are reduced to two hundred that's that's a lot of reduction but
that seems to be good
and no
no i think there really so different that as far as i know nobody has
tried to reconcile the
well maybe i should answer your question so this is so that i mean this
type of analysis there are many more ways of doing it and one of them
other models you talk about the semantic
there's a allocation models
they are
so this kind of progression from latent semantic indexing
which i presented here probabilistic latent semantic indexing with which which has a better probabilistic
foundation to these ideas models
that that are even
i mean have a even better modeling of the
of the domain because probabilistic latent semantic indexing also some problems in that it does
not really
b model of the document generation process
i'm not sure
i so that the relationship between these models as far as i can see
one advantage of this is that it's much more
efficient than display allocation these layers colour allocation i'm not sure whether anybody as far
as it can be pretty hairy to get to work for large collections and get
good results and this is this is a unique solution
it's very well understood mathematics so that's the advantages
yeah that's a good question because if you actually did the decomposition
as i claimed that you should do
this decomposition i mean you can actually do that for
very large matrices so what you need to do instead is you need to do
it incrementally so that compute one singular value and one single dimension after the other
and then
you tell the system i want to compute a hundred and will only computer hundred
and there are iterative algorithms for doing that
and it's called the land trust me
it's basically iterative method for computing the singular value decomposition up to a certain
she was
so i
i've been in
what would
what's the comparison again LSI on the one hand and the people who
it's not for everyone
and then
it was yes
it may be that the
but i'm not sure with a
i recommend semantic indexing for that because it's a
i mean it's really
he had orthogonal dimensions and the topic is really define a combination of thousands of
different dimensions and it's not clear to some additional work work to actually find the
topics to extract topics out of
science so
so i could only be the first step in that problem which something else
the claim is certainly that
the dirichlet methods can do that directly personal skeptical that they
work out of the box and
once you're done with hand holding several aspects of them i'm not sure whether you're
better off than some other methods i mean if you if that's not the focus
of europe and you just want to fight extract the topics i would just use
personally clustering
simple clustering of
question i guess the whole issue of
well this is a
so it seems that
this is
try to capture something
causal relationships between to the
the next generation
relations between two
these approaches
four how
compress space doesn't necessarily mean it's going to be easy to
what is actually
maybe i would like to find an automatic way of saying well i want to
obtain the ten percent first
basic would like to specify such a fraction beforehand
and we want to make everything automatic after we've got the computer to do it
for us and it's too late the computer the hard work and we just at
the parameters
the idea is actually quite simple
just take an adaptive hyperplane rather than the to the x equals one we say
stated that sequel wrote
and then this threshold rho adaptive
and depending on how this is picked
i will get an automatic solutions
same problem as before
the only difference is that we have now is we have minus in times new
times wrote
it turns out
this is just the right way
penalize sister they get a fraction of new points essentially which are classified wrong
this is essentially because well
the one thing that you can get wrong about i other points exactly on the
if you try
and insist on those points you get the rather nasty optimisation problem if you say
well you don't really care about how many points it exactly on the margin yet
and my second problem
so a small change became change from dramatically
the difference from a to before is
well essentially objective function is the same in the dual problem but you get one
additional constraint namely some of the alpha i honest because new terms in
and then the linear term in the objective function vanishes because well we know what
this has to be
so if you
look back that was the previous problem
with the linear term in the objective function
and no constraint
and now
we have
non linear term in the objective but we have a constraint
this theorem is
at most a fraction of new points
well lie on the wrong side of the margin
in other words the most that many points
will satisfy
OK so that's the top which would say
f x i
lacey could list and wrote
and that should be f of fixi greater than one
it's the same as it stands here
it is written for classes
you may need to create the new handouts
so how do we prove this
also in the limit
the number of points
lying in the fraction of points lie except on the margin because to zero
so proof idea works as follows
at the optimal solution
we've got
some points here
some points there
now that the optimal solution to make a small parallel shift
of the margin
all the way
now if i move it
closer to the origin
the origin is here
those points which lie on the margin or on the
those points here
for those
my slack variables will be decreased
it will be decreased by
at the same time
delta rho
and it
in one of of those
so my improvement here is a minus times delta rho
but at the same time i have to pay a price of in times new
times filter
of course optimality after seeing that into in modern times filter rho
this less equal
what they have to pay for it
like as if i go in the other direction
those points which sat on the margin
or which are already in margin errors
i will come into play as well
so i think it
one minus and plus so the points which sits on the right-hand side which i
have to pay say the least efficient after the bit
if you work out these optimality conditions you'll get
the fraction of new terms in points
essentially will
end up lying on the wrong side of the margin
and then
wind limit those fractions will become exact well because
a hyperplane is a set of measure zero
so this you get an answer distribution
in which is a set of measure zero can possibly have well non-zero measure
just by the fact that you get convergence
you will get the fact that well
the fraction of those points will go to zero is just like
we seem to what you ask is how what's the probability for point lying on
the on a certain light line as opposed to lie anywhere else
you could
to classification again
all the time that
let's look at
the connection between gas process and support vector machines
classification what we have is that we looked at the log of the y i
given x on theta
and this normalisation here
now what i'm trying to convince areas
that the support vector machines this is actually the margin you're looking at
it looks considerably more complicated than what we're not showed you
so open
that will basically you say
well how far
a point x
ly away from the separating hyperplane
and i'm showing the big east
OK let's match
but this just for the moment this
think about what it takes in order to classify something correctly
well if i'm estimating p of y given x and theta
thing in order to
why i correctly for example i need to ensure that p of why i given
x i is larger than all the other p of y given x size
in other words the observed label is more likely than all of the other guys
to the to the port minus one
which is basically
which relates to the the that the identity
so it means that if we define a dot product the identity then we can
propagated to the the reaction action to any point on the manifold
but there is another condition
the dot product the identity should be invited by the isotropy group
which means that if we apply rotation
then the the point doesn't change the
that should be
the same
and we can show we can try to find all
the rotational invariance kind of product and we end up with this kind of formula
beta the conditions be on the talk here is just to ensure that this is
positive define it
so we can we can
that's where we
we have all the fine
romanian metric on the space of kansas and we can show that the child is
x can be expressed through the matrix exponential
using this from
and the distance
it's is giving in in across from using this formula well this is the logo
of symmetric matrices
OK so i
just just a few references this metric all i should say this family of metric
was some of these metrics were already proposed so this is the
fisher information metric which is well on information geometry but it's and which was rediscovered
for surpassed processing over the last years
actually what is interesting is that very few works proposed metrics was be that different
from there is one work which is obtained by embedding the
comment metrics and the mean into homogeneous coordinates
it's actually we can generalize this construction and obtained the title
well this is an embedding of the of the space of into a high dimensional
which has this metric
and so we can generalize this construction tool in the box and press
any integral there
depending on the dimension of the space we consider
OK so what is the difference with the start metric
so the first thing we can do is to try to patrol the geodesic that
goes from this time so here to to the big ten so there
this is the
interpolation along the geodesic for
the euclidean metric
so the
and operation on the coefficients and this is here the interpolation
with the fine environment in metric and we can show that
it seems to be
malls schools on the on the orientation what is interesting is that the
determinant which is this curve there
it is
interpolated in in one
norway there
well it go through mexico if winter determine to some kind of probability this is
kind of
the euclidean which
OK so now that we have a metric how to the statistics
so from the general point of view
there were many metric is giving us a forum from which
with which we can define the intrinsic probability density functions on riemannian manifold
so this means that we can define interesting
quantities like entropy
we can define the variance which is expected expected expected squared distance this is an
with only two but we can define the mean value with an integral
because we have this would be an interval was result in the manifold manifold is
not linear
so this is not possible
so there are different ways to compute the mean what to generalise to me
and the most
use definitions is the pressure of culture medium which is basically trying to minimise the
in the manifold which is just equally complete
we can show that it is the
ratio comes is characterized as exponential by some
this means that if you take the main point i knew the everything in the
tangent space
and i mean and mean value is new
which means that it corresponds to
the usual it's it's somehow the mostly male
representation of the manifold for this kind of distribution
and what's interesting is that once we have solved for the mean that we can
go to to the tangent space and define all the moments like arrangement mattresses or
higher order
the moment that
so this is
covariance matrices
metrics in on on the riemannian manifold is some kind of object while symmetric matrix
which live in the tangent space
and we can do some PCA
and some simple analysis
we can also define some generalisation of the gaussian
with which we can compute and some other this distance but they will not
in two that in this talk
so just a few examples this is an example
in the language like c it's called mala
or language like
called new
the large table
to create a larger table
remove the items
from the old table
then we
three the OK
let's do an example
let's say i have over here a
table of size one
attempting to begin with and i do an insert
sorry do is
i stick it in the table that's
OK so we're not going to do with hashing is going to do it
as if i just had table is filling up with elements to to abstract
the problem would work with hashing it will work with any kind of excised data
i insert again
groups doesn't fit
OK so what i do is i create
and new
much space
create new
table of of size two
doubling the size
my copy
the old value into new
three this one
and now i can insert it into
why do it again
another overflow
so now i make table
size four
how these guys and
and then i certain number three
sir here
i guess i should be you know marks
so far
OK what
and i do
now make one of size a
companies or
and now i can certify
i certainly understand the basic idea so whenever i overflow and create table twice the
let's do a quick analysis of this
so we have a sequence
insertion operations
what is the worst case cost
and sir
what's the worst case for any
yes water and
order and
whatever the overhead is copying if we counted this one basically an
in plus one copy all those and
four and
so therefore if i have a i have and those are the worst case
of an answer
is equal to
ten times more
which is water
and and square
any questions
it makes sense
not all of them can be worse case good
and that this is totally wrong analysis
just because one can be
worst case or and doesn't mean and necessarily or and
OK so this is totally wrong analysis and search
in fact take
or entirely the worst case
that is parallel to this curve will simply not change anything within the article
this is often portrayed in this two-dimensional where this is possible velocity locally are two
and vx and vy y
and a single linear constraint
which again that's all these emotions have the correct
but in the end
visual system can locally in system can locally figure out the motion
so the emotions and along this line but in general we just have the linear
constraint or a similar constraint in two dimensions
so this oppose this was realized very early on emotion perception and
these researchers most famously until recent her book decided to get rid this person is
about to
so this suggested that the visual system that is to minimize the cost function energy
function has these two terms
which is again linear we have a constraint so it's quadratic constraints are equivalent constraint
at every pixel
possibly noisy
and you have to do with this regularisation term which penalizes deviations from smoothness
just first learned about this i was very skeptical that the brain does anything like
this and this sounds like something that physicists and mathematicians would make up these two
energy functions you add them up with the constant lambda
the square all sorts of things in these cells and not surprisingly this very mathematical
description of perception is surprisingly powerful
so it is a large range of percepts actually are protected by the solutions to
the energy minimisation problem
so here's an example
i'm showing free-standing that i showed you before
and now let's which which you remember appears to rotate
this led to the fact which you will remember appears to be four
non rigidly
and the same value let me just four points
which you'll remember appears to rotate rigidly
so we can take these displays and just feed as input
into this energy minimisation
note that since this is a quadratic energy function and we can
the that is enclosed found by just solving a linear system of equations
and we do that for address and others that does this is what they found
that indeed the
is these arrows pointing in the directions consistent with rotation
the fact that you'll notice that these are pointing out
and he's pointing and so it is predicted to be for non rigidly even of
course is rotating in the same value lips
when we have this for decades
when we minimize energy is predicted to rotate rigidly
and i'm just showing three examples here but if you look in some of these
papers you'll see the wide range
of percepts
which to my surprise are modeled by this energy minimisation framework
but the problem with this with the simple energy functions from the early eighties is
that they failed miserably whenever the display has more than one motion
so remember this display had fifty four that's
and the process was one of separation into two layers of this kind of energy
function is completely incapable of modelling segmentation really tries to find a single velocity field
that's consistent with all this data and so this is what it finds somewhere here
averaging together of the point of rotation and the vertical motion
and this family of these these models led to the number of
researchers to develop protocols models motion analysis
and the model that is if you get the visual input such as the one
shown here
the hand rotating like this over checkerboard
the goal is not to have a single velocity field rather multiple velocity field in
this case the stationary velocity field corresponding to the checkerboard
and the rotating velocity field corresponding to the hand
so these algorithms try to automatically decompose the scene
into multiple articles calculate the velocity of each layer and the assignment of pixels to
layers and the number of layers
and my thesis i developed another one of these models which was also based on
the energy minimisation
but the energy minimisation i was much more complex whereas we just had the signal
velocity field
in this case we have two velocity field v one and v two
and also these binary indicator variables which indicate for every pixel whether it should be
grouped with linear number one
number two
and that each one of the energy function in water
the term again
which just takes into consideration the labels
the excitements every one of the largest wants to be smooth
pixels this these assignment variables and also wanted to be small meaning nearby pixels one
go together
to go from b to e we can go by sea or by the
our life is going to be much easier if we focus on singly connected graph
that's what we'll do
and then we'll start to worry about how to deal with multiple connected graph
our goal is for some node access
we want to compute the probability of x given he which is some evidence
and evidence is observations of other variables in the graph
and that could be a whole bunch of different variables of the node x to
be this one here in our observations could here
here here and there for example
here's the really nice property of singly connected graphs that we're going to exploit
every node x in the graph
the by the evidence into
evidence that upstream from acts and evidence that downstream from x
so if we take
this to be our node act
some of the evidence will
from upstream of the direction of the arrows and some of them will come from
downstream of the direction of the arrows
you might as well what happens is another singly connected graph let's imagine there's no
that is the parent of e
next e with an arrow going this way
is that upstream or downstream of the node c
we're going to consider to be downstream of of the because whatever effect that has
on c
will come to the
so was really like
reverse system and you drop pollution somewhere in you see which way it is that
which was going upstream or downstream
when richard c
now similarly
every edge in in the graph for example the edge between x and y
will divide the evidence into evidence that coming from upstream of the x y and
evidence is coming from downstream of the
x y
and obviously there
it doesn't work for
multiply connected graph
there are multiple ways in which evidence can come in
taking into account all those ways is is going to be computationally very hard
so there
i think of them i think there has been three key ideas behind belief propagation
imagine we have a graph
and we have some variable x
and there's about upstream of x then there's the downstream effects then there's a whole
bunch of other nodes imagine the graph is singly connected so i don't imagine that
there's any way to get from here
here OK
now the first idea is that the probability of the variable x
can be found by combining upstream and downstream evidence
so the probability distribution over x given all the evidence
we can write as the probability of x
and all the evidence provided by the public evidence that is not a function of
evidence we can
split up into upstream of x and downstream of that
and then
pi in the denominator is the constant let's ignore for now
this joint distribution of x
upstream evidence and downstream evidence
we're going to split up into
the product
x given the upstream evidence
the probability of the downstream evidence
x and the upstream evidence
the graph is singly connected
the probability of the downstream evidence given x and the upstream evidence
it's just simply the probability of the downstream evidence given x
that's the term we have here
and that
comes about because for this singly connected graph
these separate
from the upstream variable
we used our key
concept of the separation here
and now what we have is that the probability of x given all the evidence
is the product
you know normalized
product of something that comes from upstream and something that comes from downstream
and i've fallen following the notation in use that pearls
the book
which talks extensively about belief propagation
and he calls the up coming from
upstream high messages and the stuff coming from downstream lambda messages and you might wonder
why well
from upstream corresponds to
this prior so stop coming from upstream we're going to think of as
stuff coming from above this is like the prior term
and that the downstream is like
the likelihood term in normal bayesian decision
so that's why we have high
coming from and lambda is likely to come from the world
although this is you know
i don't take that too literally because the high
fact depends on
data that we but there is not just prior information
it's just depends on data we observed by parents
that's the basic the first basic idea
the second basic idea is the computational idea that that the upstream and downstream evidence
can be computed via a local message passing algorithm between nodes in the graph and
we'll see that in more detail
and the third idea is
really an idea about
the messages that need to be sent around
and the important thing is that
when node sends the message to another node
for every point to define a small neighborhood you look at what happens when you
count how many times you have positive and negative patients
and use that as the prediction like you think the majority or discount the prediction
and the conditions for consistency to occur are
that these neighborhoods should become smaller and smaller
i as assume as you have more data
it seems intuitively
fine you are correct about the smaller neighborhood because you have
more dense coverage of your space
but at the same time
you should average
many points in that
the larger the number of
o point two average more accurate prediction of the problem would be
that's kind of the
very large numbers here
an example is the following
if you think what i call histograms in
so that is ki i two party widely at sorry at least a bounded subset
of five
of art
it's a bit more one the party
and within that set
you define cells that actually make it will just take
it breeds in all directions and you find yourself and what you do that
you take the average of the state over the sale of
council of positive and negative labels
and you are so that
the size of the same age and which is the you know the size
make it so that has any increases the size goes to zero as a simple
does not go to zero too fast
so that you ensure that
eight enter the power in that's the volume of sales
these volumes
multiply by
go to infinity which means that you
i mean the number of
the expected number of points that will be in any given cell
the value
is n times the volume after you have observed and point
the expected number of points that you have in the cell is n times
it and with the i
these expected number of points that are in the cell
should go to infinity so that
you have these
increase the number of points averaged
and to prove that this is the case that these kind of algorithm is consistent
you just use the fact that
continuous functions with bounded support so we have to assume these bounded
what about this
dr dense
lp space
so i mean essentially want to prove some kind of convergence
of two functions i
this convergence will happen whenever
you have convergence in LP which is kind of the
no natural space to define functions when you have a probability measure
on your space
because there are continuous and on the bounded domain domain they are from a continuous
which means that any such function can be approximated arbitrarily well
we ways
it's the ground is the run being like
piecewise constant function something like
so in function
which is continuous on the bounded domain can be approximated arbitrarily well by some function
like this
by just increasing the size
you know making more steps
ultimately that will converge
and this is this convergence is provided by the fact that each and goes to
but then on each cell
you want to convergence of
towards the true probability densities the true probability of
below a given the set of measurements
so get this convergence you just need these
these will guarantee that on the values of these steps will converge to the right
and the other nation with
guarantee that the step size with zero so you have approximation
yes the question is whether this is related to the same things here in
information theory
yes yes
you can think of it this will it's kind of
i mean that's interestingly connected but it's not really i mean does not the same
mathematics but
but get the point was to show that you know if you want a perfect
algorithm perfect in the sense of being able to learn anything
it is in the countable case you're in the non notable
it's not hard
so why bother
the question is how innocent is this assumption that are considering measurable functions
that's the point
it's kind of connected to the fact that you're
introducing the probability distribution for the data
if you introduce the probability distribution then
the best
i mean and this probability solution satisfies the regular actions for probability on the company
continues space
this best function will be measurable so you can restrict measurable functions but this means
equally the concentration of the
the protein ID it's virion and therefore the
it is exactly the value of
pk one
what happens on the other extreme
what happens if all of a sudden there is a rise in ph
if there's is a sudden rise in ph
how does virion response
sudden rise in ph that means
the concentration of protons suddenly fell
we use the list should tell you principle again
we use should tell you principle
go back over here
look virion we say OK what we've got right now
is a sudden dearth of shortage of
proton how consider i respond to that sudden
shortage of protons
all the neutrals virion has proton sitting right here so it's better i can do
in response to the sudden drop in proton concentration is donate
become a proton donor and start
adding protons to the solution
sacrificing its neutrality in order to minimize the impact of that sudden
rise in ph so let's
let's document that reaction
as this one here that's where
as the iron
does the following
will start with the neutral again
that's over year
h three n
so here's the neutrals virion experiences sudden
rise in ph
and responds by
protons into the solution
now the
the left end is the protein eight
leaving neutral
the proton is now donated to the solution and if the solution is in fact
hi in ph then this protons can go and attack
xs hydroxyl
and neutralize it so this is how
xii response
and what we see here this is neutral
this is not neutral but now
the positive and has become neutralized by the loss of the proton so this is
known as negative
this is known as negative
so we can call this
reaction to and it has a k two
and using the notation that i've developed up there the neutral variety
denoting h a so this is where i minus this
proton so this is just the a minus its making sense this is not negative
and if i take a two-way from HAI get
and then this is the age plus
so that's the reaction we're looking at
and we can write the
the case the reaction as
concentration of protons
times concentration of the protein eight is very high
divided by the concentration of
the neutrals better and
take the log base ten of size
pk two
log base ten
on the flip this oversight after promyelocytic here's the BHA divided by
a minus
and again we have fifty percent
neutralisation of and that means that there will be fifty percent of the species consumed
fifty percent of this left
the log of one is zero and that ph we have the
the value of the
acid dissociation constant
i think this
this slide shows what's going on here
but all it does it plots
these two equations if you take the first equation here the logarithmic the sorenson form
the first equation that's the lower part of this graph
the lower part of this graph applied ph
versus the ion dissociation so if you turn this around ph versus the amount of
this that has been consumed
and what you see is that when you have fifty percent this is fifty percent
there are
many questions that
one can ask about language
the most fundamental one truly is a
what it is
so what is language
to the extent that you have some
grasp this
one can proceed to
for other questions
lacking at thing
necessarily curtailed
for example no biologist with
seek discredited
development directly evolution the i
without a fairly clear conception of the
what i
it's essential nature
so it would not be for example to say that
it used to be
order for language that
it's used to communicate among
numerous other users
on the basis that
tentative account
what languages
the more far reaching
we can proceed to
ask how
the concepts principles and results this
characterization of language
other important study acquisition
the neural representation
historical change
reciprocally what's learned about
these topics can
leads to
this here
that was proposed
hierarchy questions not
the first thing
every sensible approach to language must recognise these
is used by individuals
and that
passes uses depends
primarily on the produces
it should be
every approach to language
that's what it is
presupposes tacitly
concept is sometimes called
i language
i you
it some system that
internal to an individual
and that
the problem first
well at
it presupposes
but also conceptions the
that was
i itself presupposes
and senses
the most fundamental issue
line here
i mean
so in that sense
something in terms of an individual
is a system that can all discrete
six seven
system that's
has be determined by
so fundamental computational procedures
we can procedure
which is a special kind
the first one
he says
which is
according to the same
first consequence of mister
almost universal
and with the
so what
this presentation
it's pretty simple basically
anything parameter
it has been added
see but more
this is the
that's the first
for example the number
if we understood
general expressions
thank you
and for each other
the you know just in
so you
use on the array
this expression each which is on the internet
and he
one is essentially
in some form
and is
roughly speaking
francis four
so that means
so is it
sound mean
in fact was limited
we now
the sounds as
only one o
the sensorimotor
well the sound meaning
it is in principle unbounded
the brain
long island
rich history
studies language
we found a few days
the government
one year
many different animals
so only
it is almost infinitely large power
there is a
sounds years
that have been we
the grammar
the only thing
is traditional that
very similar to
could be made to
the reason
the amount
characterizes she
is the basis for what can
according to marvelous invention
it's time to start now
it's my pleasure to introduce you to mark ring
our never mind
o comes from the university of was then y is a very active person is
on only from the university of malta
and he does
i think is five years now collaboration between the institut
the university
very much loss in evolutionary computation on various problems like then
talk about
and i say where two areas
one is
this kind of is
usually station
and applied to the data
i guess exciting news
the latest design is a
these are
well this presentation talk about the solution as well the additional classrooms
so for those of you are familiar with additional tracks
and those so familiar with it
it's been quite active use in recent years
and the problem of clustering data
also as many of you might know is computational problems
so that for many people who apply
such heuristics to take this but you can so
these kind of problems
general exact
so that has been quite using selection and the
it's actually was looking to the literature of define this is all papers published there
is no genetic systems
which was quite a surprise to me because it's full already dimension
and work together
missionary computation
also for quite a while this is actually one the best way i can
so i just
the value of about
everybody genetic
the question to get bench general
of course made that experience over many years not
but when it comes to numerical optimisation there also
definitely needs to consider
so for instance strategies
this sort of like to bring to your attention to to
the this revolution
the had
that's what
they should not very
also the community they specialized numerical optimisation
no particular
what's funny is two examples specialized
on the same time as the time of optimisation of both introduced the same year
nineteen ninety five
but this optimisation is really very popular in lots of the sessions and conferences and
the station was this differential evolution has very little attention
it actually is
i will be able to demonstrate this presentation differential evolution should be
there many
also you should consider both when they think about american optimisation three is of the
o should say
invented myself
this is not the case
but i have to admit my to be something to consider america
of collaborators is working together
so we to
and they were already qualified through the the statistics so
the interested case of clustering news
it has to be great variety of applications not only
this is called a series
so but also by the maximum
the fact that he should be sent to the fish were reliable
and the
interior but if you look do what's what's the existing techniques to find any
least find today
satisfy all these criteria so there no
it's to creating an additional clustering algorithm hat
well defined as well so far
right so
meadow evolution
so there is a heuristic search methods same data objects to the
adequacy according to some statistics
let's try two
so for those of you that
with the mining and statistics when they first met
this must not be confused with the text data points in your data set what
they mean
and the second
the term centroid is they think about
any kind of representative for that
representation of data as
OK so it's not the the mean if you like the centroid of the cluster
but it can be any more that would could
as sensitive data
so you should ask
problem can be formulated in this way
given a set of objects over the properties which is to matrix the
it to tissue gene
with the property that each of these classes here is subset all nonempty
the intersection of these clusters is
all of clusters can range
and i would like to give you
o which is o
she has not
compared to other people
OK county
by the time the topology such that it is
this not the minimum expected
so many ways that
in this here we investigate
this is one of the trees with
so now we are talking about
we don't this calculated from the
thanks the company two
and then
like this
area of the capital
and let's assume that the positive charge so that the electric field lines come out
the surface like so
perpendicular to the surface
always perpendicular to the potential
so now if i play goes as well
which tells me that the
the surface integral
of the electric flux
throughout this whole surface
well there's only flux coming out of this
surface here i can bring that serves as close to the surface as i wanted
i could almost make it cuts and everything comes out only through
so what comes out is the surface area eight
times the electric field
in the same direction
remember is perpendicular to the
the surface of the potential
and so this is all the for the surface integral
and that's all the charge inside
well the charge inside is of course the surface charge density times the area a
divided by
after non-zero uses gauss law
so you find immediately
that you like to you
divided by zero
so whatever you have conductor if you know the local
the surface charge density
you always know to local
electric field
and since the surface charge density
it's going to be
the high is here
even though the whole thing is in the potential electric field will also be higher
here than it will be
i can demonstrate this to you in a year
a very simple way
i have here a cooking pan
the the cooking pan
used to more lapses in their large and
the cooking pan i'm going to charge up
and the cooking pan
as the radius
however this may be twenty centimetres but looking at the handle
a very small radius is so good for charge on their
and i'm going to convince you
that i can scoop of
more charge here
the radius is small than i can scope of here
i have he is small
flat space
and i'm going to put this building on the surface here and on the surface
we're going to see
from where
we can
the scope of the most chart
still chart from the previous lecture
so here we see the electroscope that we've seen before
i'm going to charge this cooking pan
with my
favourite technique which is the electrophoresis
so we have the cat for
and we have the glass plate
i'm going to
rather the first step for
put my finger on get a little short
charge depends
put my finger on
get another shock
charge of the band
and another one
part the pan make sure they get enough charge on their
last again
what is on top
i put my finger on
once more
and once more
let's assume we have enough charge and there are no
here is my little school
i touch it
outside view of the camp
of the band
and go to the electroscope
you see the charge
very clear
what i want to show you now it's very complicated
is that when i touch here
the handle
very small radius that i can take more charge
there we go
substantially more that's all i wanted to show you so you see now in front
of your own eyes for the first time
even though this is a conductor
that means that it is an equipotential
that the surface charge density right here
higher than the surface charge density here
only if is the sphere of course versus spherical symmetry reasons will the
try be uniformly distributed
if the electric field becomes too high
we get what we call electrical breakdown we get to discharge into the air
and the reason for that
actually quite simple
you have an electron here
and this is an electric fields
electron will start to accelerate the direction
i will collide with nitrogen and oxygen molecules in the air
and if the electron has enough kinetic energy to ionize
that molecule
one electron
become two electrons
originally elected was the electron
from the i
and he's now
start to accelerate in this electric field
and if they collide
with the molecules and they made
each one
become two electrons
so we get an evidence
and there is evidence is an electrical breakdown
you get this spark
when the ions that are formed
become neutral again
they produce light
and that's what you see
that's the light that you see
this part
and so is part of occur typically
at the
it's sharp points
areas where the curvature is
strong whereby the radius
very small that's why the electric field i
the highest
how strong should electric field we
well we can make an back-of-the-envelope calculations
good morning everyone feel free to interrupt me whenever because we have a lot of
time as you know my name is rowland i'm working in the research group on
complex event processing in counseling and complex event processing as you see is that is
about real time streaming data
and we're trying to combine that with what we learned from the semantic web research
of the last decade
you see how these two go together
first of all
i need to attribute these slides there from
several tutorials that my boss my supervisor gave on other occasions together with people from
the event processing community pedro bizarro from coimbra portugal
o for its from IBM in hi-fi
my journey from caltech california these are people walking researching on event processing
now y
this tutorial
real time
is for many applications crucial today
there is often times on the move we
so far we we heard a lot about it
how to model static data
now we also like to talk about flowing data that we need to process on
the fly
so we need to find results immediately on this flowing data without having to store
the data in the database we want to process this data while it's moving and
possibly be able to throw the stayed way to deal with large volumes
very large volumes
this information is transmitted in the push manner so the information searches for the relevant
consumers so that
so that information reaches you more efficiently you don't have to go wrong such as
this system did something new happened and the next system that something new happened but
information events about things that happened will be pushed to you once they happen so
we want this this real-time automatically updating system with flowing data
this is if you compare google search for example you post the query and you
get a fixed set of results of the current state of the system google and
as opposed to twitter where you post subscription to the people you're following and they
will incrementally update you with what they find all your twitter friends and you'll get
updates whenever they will find something new so
we have these if you will standing queries
which will give you results whenever there is new data as opposed to
a traditional query which oppose only once and you get the results only once
OK real time
is essential for for a lot that we're doing and it's been around for quite
awhile now only we're trying to formalize this as as a research
i want to be informed immediately this is really all use cases of my luggage
is not onboard of my playing when it's about to start i don't want to
find this out later posting a query but i want to inform and when this
or when two friends of mine this social media application sitting in the cafe close
to me and i want to combine different events in the relevant context of sitting
in the cafe so
processing events is always having to do combining many sources in different events to get
an interesting meaningful results
and inform me immediately after it becomes very likely that there will be a general
i wrote so even predicting future events is possible if you have learned and train
just system about his stories histories of events and you will be able to to
predict with a certain likeliness of what events will follow a certain set of events
that just happened
real time in examples
how much real time data is really out there that needs that this sort of
on the processing twitter world record was eight thousand eight hundred tweets per second on
the singer beyonce is pregnancy in was that on august twenty eleven so you can
see this is is an event frequency of
two weeks we get and the point is that that we want to process these
and and learn about
this event that happened immediately we don't want to put the tweets in the database
and see at the end of the month what happened but we want to be
informed that something meaningful just happened previous records were about the fee for women's world
cup seven thousand per second and this is all just one system on the web
which has this
so the frequency of events
another thing which is more well known as the financial market where you need nano
seconds time to trade once you get new information about stock price of all electronic
health you need remote patient monitoring where you have the lines of about five seconds
smart meters in the smart grid the upcoming
possibly upcoming energy revolution we have smart meters which help you
optimize the electric grid has periods about fifteen minutes
in real time
when i talk about real time this is the sort of relaxed notion of real
time though if you've learned in computer science or electrical engineering real time in my
case does not have hard deadlines
so i'm not talking about hard constraints but i'm talking about what people say is
business real time or near real time so i want the best effort processing of
these messages but not necessarily support hard deadlines so if you hear me talk about
real time this is the sort of relaxed
the idea of i want to process data as soon as it is there but
not necessarily guarantee new millisecond processing time
just so that terminology is clear
my goal
for today is that
there's a source of information from above and the source of information from below
deparle who wrote of classic texts on this
and and develop belief propagation large we call this the
and the land
messages hyper prior on lambda for likelihood so the stuff from above
you can think of is analogous to prior in the stuff from below you can
think of is analogous to likelihood and you're multiplying this prior likelihood and then renormalizing
to compute the probability over x given the evidence
so that's the first idea is is the separation
between upstream and downstream components
the second idea is
this upstream and downstream evidence these messages sorry
can be computed by
these probabilities these things that you're trying to multiply it can be computed via a
local message passing algorithm between the nodes in the graph
so we'll see that later
and then the third idea is to make sure
when you're sending messages
not to send back to a node any part of the message it sent to
so you basically want to send
each node is sending messages to other nodes but it needs to make sure that
the messages sent to other nodes is only collecting information from all sources
other than that
note OK
and only if you do that will you get the right probabilities coming out
but all this stuff is not sort of who do it just follows
you know you can prove it all tediously just by applying bayes rule and the
factorizations of on the graph
so i
and again i'm not going to go into the details of this because it would
take you know actually
i talked this before it takes about
an hour and a half or two hours just to understand the details of belief
propagation i want to give you a flavor and again you can kind of look
this stuff up
or try to code it up on your own at some point
the belief propagation algorithm involves messages
that are said top down
in other words
a node to its children
so the message that URI
sense to node x
the probability
distribution over u i given all the evidence that's upstream
edge u i x
OK then they are also messages coming bottom up from downstream so the message that
why jason's acts
is the probability
evidence is downstream from
the edge
x to y j
as a function of x
so these messages are
are vectors i mean we have we think about how we actually implement these messages
let's say x is a binary random variable so can take two values zero or
the this message is
two valued vector
with the value corresponding to the setting x equals zero and value correspond to the
setting x equals one
and similarly this message would be a
two element vector so here's your messages are being sent through vectors they get multiplied
for discrete random variables
and then the probability that we're interested in the probability of x given all the
evidence is
the product of
all of the downstream messages
times all the stuff coming from upstream
we normalize
and these are just additional equations for how to compute these downstream and upstream messages
so if you want all the gory details
you know
this is all you need to actually implement this algorithm if you wanted to and
of of course i make my slides available for the summer school
belief propagation is
very useful algorithm if you want to do inference in large graphs
were also executed that's really slow
we had to change approaches he went and rewrote this entire program in different language
called CPL which is related to see and the b programming language came before c
and of course it's very low level it's very fast but didn't have these nice
high level features and and you got it working but it took a lot of
and when he was done he decided you know i'm never going to tackle a
problem like this again until you have a proper tool for the job
in up eighteen t bell labs which is the same place c programming language came
out of back you carrying cannon ricci who invented that
they came with the language called c with classes
the precursor to c plus plus and people what that
it combined the best features of stimuli which is that object are to design
with the best features of c which is the runtime efficiency and said it was
fast flexible and help to think about problems
what he would do is work on the implementation
you had people actually using the language and when they need new features they said
are doesn't work you go fix it
and we have this cycle of real programmer solving real problems
with this developer said OK let's go fix it
and after a while you end up with c plus plus it's been around for
think this is the thing the twenty fifth anniversary possible so
but how exciting
i want to talk about the flat but what's really driving the development of this
language was expected to you
you have some quotes from this book called the design evolution c plus plus good
but you should read it
the first one
c plus plus is evolution should be driven by real problems and you don't want
to get down in the quest for perfection
basically this languages are designed to solve real problems in the real programmers like you
are going to run into
and not necessarily the best way it could try to do a good job is
not intended to be perfect there are some sloppy edges but it works
and because it is driven by real problems in real design issues you can solve
real problems with it
if you think that's a good thing in language
i personally do i think it's good to have a language they can solve problems
then c plus plus is a good choice
this is the one that you've seen them most don't try to force people c
plus plus gives you so many choices that your question should not be well how
do i do this in the language but more which of these hundreds of options
is the best choice for me
it really trust you as the language will give you an incredible amount of flexibility
even in the world let you make the wrong decision
c plus plus the language that will let you ride a bicycle without helmet because
that one family to go under bridges exactly quarter inch over your head you what
have you not you by
do you have to worry about a lot of risk but in the end you
have more flexibility than you will find most of the languages c
and finally i think the most important one
is this
c plus plus makes programming more enjoyable for serious programmers the two things here are
serious programmers and more enjoyable
this is a professional language is used in industry everywhere it's very fast it's very
efficient and has a bit of the learning curve it is kind of tricky to
get into the language but once you've got it
the second part the more enjoyable is so true
this language is find to write things
once you've got it down you will actually step back inferencing while i just wrote
something took every single word of the said that i had read has against contains
specific letter in a single line of code
or i wanted all the contents of this file into my set one line of
code or ideas for a template that is a multi-dimensional array any dimension i want
that's those not trivial accomplishments and you can do with this language it's fine
it's a great language and if you think that this sort of philosophy is what
you want we will trust you will really like you make decisions rather than forcing
into anyone paradigm
learn c plus plus
i think a lot
possibly there's lots of it but you know i'm not going to fly across them
here to teach about c plus plus let's and some of the details what is
this language look like
and the first thing i want to do is talk about what channel about it
since day one you probably have seen things like this
how include german very first one right here
what is in the scandal things everybody actually looked in german before and we call
that the german while looked inside
no one
if you look inside channel
it looks mostly like this
there are basically three important ones need to know
can include strings so we talked about the strange process there was built like and
or double it's a class
it's like any other object like the vector map you do need to pound included
we care for you because since you use it everywhere and it's easy to forget
and you can get some pretty nasty compilers if you don't include it with you
well then i will do that for you
the second thing is the error function using error german just give you from for
the end
but this last one right here using namespace std
using the standard name space
one hundred is slightly
it looks almost like you know english sentence you know compiler make my code
what's going on
well i'll show you
suppose i have this sort of program that incivility
so i just want to know how to do it i was very happy with
string if you know here i don't have german
i'm going to make a string and printed
so the question is when i say string my strength
one of my referring to
when this happens the compiler says well go look for something called strain
and we have included string
it put inside the big bucket of something called space and
the idea is that the real name of string is standard during the roman see
out is standard see out the real name and all the standard and it's just
that if you make your your own versions of the things it doesn't have the
same name as the standard conflict in your approach to compile
but the problem is that if you try to run this
what what happened is that
the compilers strange looks up here and this wall
says oops that's inside the namespace i can go on there
and again really nasty compiler something like strings not defined yet not find and else
now time in your program you kind of want things like c out and strange
actually exist
so rather than saying you have to standard string standard CEN standard and l
you can introduce this little phrase right here
using a standard
and what this says
is take the floor and get rid of it it's like mister compiler tear down
this wall and the result
is that this kind of barrier to its well that kind of
ten times it's all still include inside the inside of the centre namespace not accessible
when you say string goes oh yeah that thing
and actually compiles
the most they are not going to be hitting you with c plus plus and
say you must know this you must know this you must know this is not
enough time to go over everything
but this a line might be something worth committing to memory because it's the most
noticeable change you'll see when you stop using german if you don't put that line
your code to get lots of areas in just kind of scary
so if you put this line in nineteen ninety percent of from our problems will
go away
that's that one that's stanley and if you want to work
if you write this code you basically replace all german for ten if i have
concluded this one STDIV the c standard library
i'm i'm thinking when they invented the seagram language across them several million dollars per
hour consonant they put in the header file so
they put it is small parcels delivery
and the idea is that you have these two live important ones pattern strings using
the standard name space
the circuits essentially multilayer neural net but for booleans
as as a boolean operations and are cases you can construct way you
can show if the number of stages of computations in a boolean
circuit is not sufficient the number of layers
then you might need to represent certain functions when
an exponential number of units within
layers of that that boolean circuit would be to shallow
the idea is maybe that allows us to compensate for otherwise requiring
an exponential number of units and you know just in practice i mean
you're aware of this but in each recognitions been shown to be
game changing the use of deep neural nets and same thing in computer
vision so this i guess like this into thousand six there was
suddenly soms success training deep neural nets and so i'm
labeling the next few concept and talk about as like deep learning
concepts that could presumably have been invented before like what
i talk about so far is mostly things that were known
you know before the thousand six but
part of the motivation behind them i guess to some extent was like
how do we train if effectively very very deep neural nets potentially
very deep neural nets i'm going over some of the
considered difficulties a hypothesis for y
for given deep neural network a given problem you might have difficulties
fitting to your data get in the book good
performance generalization performance
one first hypothesis is that the optimization problem is to hard
for some reason for architecture so one potential difficulty
that's well known as the vanishing gradient
problem if you remember when we covered backprop at every
every second stage you would multiply the weight matrix the activation
gradient and would go through the nonlinear already by doing an
element-wise multiplication with the activation func tions
their of and if you have saturation you might be in regime
for some of the units where the gradient
did there essentially zero to actually be blocking
the gradients or not passing in the learning information through
that unit and to lower layers that's one thing that can happen
actually also multiplying by the weight matrix might
there might be some problems associated with that
i think maybe wash over cover has problems
with it does not are dense so so that might be one problem
and it is you could also make a statement about how this is nonconvex
optimization problem there has been some interesting theoretical
result show doing that if you have a very large neural net with
a lot of parameters some of the
issues you suspect in small dimensional problems are non-convex
are much less harmful them with thing essentially
in high dimensions when optimizing function that lives in
very high dimensions the local optima tend to be
a lot of local optima them to be fairly close to the global optimum
in terms of absolute performance
so that's it seems that says come from some insides that people
and neural nets and those are fairly reassuring results and that
would explain why in certain cases we don't really see optimization
problems yes
so this is on studying actually random neural nets
which random weights and it it's i what's the reference for for
for the the fact that most local optima
bad in neural nets let's dimensions or a
yeah ok yeah from yeah ok right or
saddle point
so another about this might be that when using deep neural nets
might be in a difficult overfitting situation so if you have
fairly complex functions that we're fitting to data
then we might the situation where there's a high variance in
our estimate of our solution from from our our training set
and so maybe the also potential probably might face is that
we essentially overfitting compared to fitting smaller networks
if you're layers and which you know situation your n will depend
on the architecture of the problem the amount of data
so this this discussed use solutions
and how they relate to either one of of these issues
so if the problems on the fitting you want to do better at
optimization one solution effectively that has grown is to
use unils faster computers faster computer hardware so use cheap
use if your say on the plateau and this is essentially why optimizations
taking a long time well if each generation is actually very very
what about us
there are
i i
OK so
i can
it's also
an approximate
so here's the diagonal
these approximate kernel in the
number of sample points the
point is
so it thousand
thousand one million ten million
so you can even more than
the problem was
approximate kernel games
if this is feasible
giving still significantly
here's the clustering accuracy indian cuisines
i hope you're all clusters no points should be expressed
so that means that small number of data points
san approximation guarantees the accuracy drops a little bit but still significantly higher than
the kings
tiny images dataset was what
it is the right
the idea is that
which is the eighty million
thank you very much
thumbnail images
seventy five thousand classes
and this is represented by two hundred fourteen
you need information this
so the from e
the event
based on some key words
this in features
and a small portion of the data set
he see far ten
these ten classes
sixty thousand images
manually annotated
these classes
so do you really want do this
small subset
to determine the accuracy of classification
on the last year
so we cluster these tiny images
the last time approximate
thousand and once it's only one player as in this example as
that's the accuracy currently uses about
thirty percent approximate kernel
the global spectral clustering is twenty seven percent in
he was tremendous
missus three percent three
centre of large number of images that is very
laughter is
but best ones
classification accuracy
see by
people person
so we can also now this to be approximate kernel
gain is far better scalability and fast the
the two main challenges in it doing clustering for large number of points one is
signing finding the closest cluster centre put all the
and all processes
just a few points and find
so in the end
for example employees
and that's
union miners
and around
one to be partitions
the sidebars
you must be
and approximate the game
he's easy task you find cluster centers
assign each point in the task is to the
the center that's an
combine the labels for each task in the cluster
so example
that we now you have multiple clusterings
they don't and then combine them together
so you be
distributed approximate
keys to the conservative circles
i dataset
ten millions even
it's given you know
so what
additionally approximate the
even the approximate
you more than ten million points
it would
so we need to something for so
that's the new example
that's one of the approximate the beginning of the points in the cluster
so now
we do this sample and cluster
one year labelled one
clustering one billion points
so today
seven one million points
and this is what to be
sampling quality
he said that don't have to be
one million by one million barrels
so now
will be
only time he's this sample cluster
sample and the
and it was
three minutes per game is one point
sampling cluster
forty by forty
and the clustering accuracy so
these amazing fifty percent random splits
sixty five percent
so some
now is to
the application the
this is
it's not easy to get access to the data
reason you
what are you
is these hyperlink
it is you
one of
you lose something browsing data
challenges of sparsity so reduce dimensionality and position
how do you the evaluation is not
reasons why
the accuracy of such databases
repeated his insistence
and or
this is just a way of actually understanding
high dimensional with graphically understanding the behavior of the system in terms of what actually
the system does what it does you can actually see what this seems to settle
in the same place that never is actually in the same place to hold equilibrium
according to
as you have something there which is more stable
i'm going to talk about
conditions of
the office of complexity what by complexity
and what we mean by the organisation
it's no use are really doing ethnographic work which is basically the tools that we
have use
available to us what technical systems and there is a whole
research technology and development digital marketing methods structure during
and for example monitoring tracking various ways to capture data issues like trust
and see how they actually work
types of systems that are both physical rational
virtual choir
that's when that's done not far behind by actions in his life in san diego
UC san diego
we need to actually trying to model
former so complex theory focuses complex nonlinear open systems
so was one
motivation using this vision from the diamonds on the inside of the kind of like
pushes new possibilities for new pattern or there's something from the outside is the system
shown for example in new EU regulations be something to do this is show and
you have to organize and around the quantitative
o you can predict from the as any parts have actually use the term is
one of the companies have with ethnographic research temperature
focus on the actions of individual
and i think can put together
you know we can just extrapolate and unfortunately it doesn't work like because was removed
from his
so it's looking organizational systems that you get different
we need it on a one-to-one basis however under certain conditions you can actually see
that you can model
and there's lots of work done by center women
institute you can actually model
as an an individual agent and simulations
and the same
units should be in the same way under certain conditions
so my interest in the trust
you appear distorted around the
from simple occupied secure simple states in complexity theory large-scale water as complex apparent to
order the local scale
so you've got some different ways of approaching this one's got very
the only stuff something really crazy happens on the other side
order arises
as a result of art
measures of complexity OK
i two
measures to write about types
and also organizing systems are
well if you on
complexity theory studies also called position
what it's all things that organisation emergence cooperation
so these are
the same
the sphere of interest
around the notion of system and what system systems
so i deterministic complexity based on information theory algorithmic content strings of bits to find
the length of the shortest programme the standard was computed and destroy the
and hold OK so there's an measure complexity
so in the computational complexity and that this process time
the complex is equated with around so
OK need to ask questions to use
then we have to say
this part of statistical complexity measure the degree of structural pattern present in a complex
this is a little bit more about what i'm talking about
so it was a second problem statistical complexity have randomness equals the maximal complexity served
keep the key idea here is that
entropy gen
the entropy measure is the measure of order in the system for organizations systems
so it's on the opposite to what should be dark energy entropy and y is
the measure of the current level of organisation system sort of a contradiction
the above basically what
so far as i understand
that you have the org conditions in stream or disorder and
these vanish our