these are different aspects
so the DBLP inferred from co authorships citation networks
but for blocks
people explicitly specify
their social network
or inferred from links
comments on of these
in the communities communities also different
dblp the
school site citation networks
they are relatively
stand a static
OK they don't change as much
as the block
black communities
you can
tell for example the last week
you can see a lot of traffic about olympics
all those controversies
OK now let graduates last night probably about
i don't know if it's if people would be interested were probably that's the basketball
did you watch that make it so close from europe of course you probably can
anyone from spain
and i am sure today
it will be what about the democratic convention
the jill biden
so running mate
and all of these things because this john mckay already had the new at about
to this
joe biden it's interesting how they do very fast
so they want to reach people so then
blast is under the
are the change so it changes very fast next week will be republican convention
so that they different
they share some commonality so that's why
when with the research
we try to use what guess what the simpler more static easier one right the
but when the work developed something really
important and useful
you have to work on the real to me OK that's what i
i think it's time for
me to stop to hand over to knitting and to talk about
blogosphere research issues
and we try to make like thirty minutes
many sessions
let's look at some of the current research issues in blogosphere and
some of the representative works in blogosphere i would try to boil guys down very
detailed data quickly go through all these research issues
OK so let's look at the
first decision which is like modelling the blogsphere so
why why do we need models for the blog search for understanding the structures and
properties in the blogosphere it also has been gaining insight into the relationships between bloggers
readers blog post comments different blog sites in the block
and these models also has been generating artificial data sets and you can tune the
parameters to simulate the special scenarios and compared to study the different algorithms
they also have been studying peculiarities in the blogosphere and inference patterns
and structures that could
help explain certain phenomena like influence diffusion splogs community extraction we should go through in
the next few slides
so there are some key differences between them and the models and lockheed martin
would not many blocks for specific models have been developed so
we review some of the models developed for the world wide web and how other
works have modified and extended these models
into the blogsphere
models developed for their assume dense graph structures
due to the large number of interconnecting hyperlinks within the pages which is contrary to
blocks really because you don't have so many links because it's a very casual environment
people tend to miss gentleman linking two
the source their citing over the differing
so the level of interaction
is also different in that and blocks where you find a larger interaction blocks as
compared to to as pointed out by one
the highly dynamic and short lived nature of the blog post makes it different from
the web because the models do not consider that kind of dynamicity in the web
the market in the pages containing over time which is not with blogsphere
because blocks with the links as soon as the topic is that nobody cares about
the block so they don't inside that
and then
different things like categories and tags and by the users in the logs very different
than that because you don't find that kind of flexibility
and then you have descriptive filenames for the blogs as compared to the pages
so these are some of the differences between them in the blogosphere
i mean you go through some of the models
for the remainder what has been adapted for the blogsphere
so there is a preferential attachment model
but basically say the probability of new edge to a node to be added depends
it's degree
that is in the creation of an edge between
but this to be a and b g depends on the
edges incident upon the vertex media
and this also leads to all the distribution are you going so confiscated redistribution will
explain it in detail in the slides
it is a question of intervention type it's not as sociation can not
solve this problem by collaboration
five years ago my linear model i spent so much time in this tutorial on
the linear model
look again at the linear model
you scale covariance and we tried to answer this question why
so the regression coefficient measures
about the size of the data measures the importance of variable exchange in terms of
what people call association but what it measures
the importance of this defect of a j
on y and outcomes important stuff
when keeping all other variables fixed this is what the regression is still
and in this gene example nobody believes that this is the case right if you
make an intervention in the gene or genes will change the whole stuff
i want to quantify
the effect of the total
to my response of interest
so this keeping the other fixed is really not realistic forty intervention problem
OK i think
keep that so you can define using pearl's do calculus what it is
and maybe this is
so it's defined
i bring you more tools all of the problem is time here so we can
define an i think some people knowing how causal effect is defined so this is
using the framework of say per or many others
this definition you need to go through that can make the markov assumption on the
then you have a defined effect and what it actually these causal effect but you
have to find
it's just the same as if you would have run the randomized trial to see
this effect
so this is kind of the idea of what you want to do
so you have a causal effect which is defined actually is the same as if
you were to run a fully randomized trial
this study in order to find out the fact that the goal is of course
i want to infer this effect without doing the randomized trial
so here is we can take that the definition of the causal effect of of
course is been an abstract definition in this way
but i assume if i had y x one and x all jointly gaussians make
things easier
and i'm interested in the derivatives of the expected value of y
when i do an intervention at the j th variable
and said it to evaluate lex
the gauss in case this derivative is known to be a single number single coefficient
called theta j
it's like
another classification regression regression must data j
here theta j
this is the causal effect this intervention effect of the j th variable on my
response which is
here's an interesting and important characterisation was there are several ones but this is an
interesting one
you can find theta j
these regression
use of the link graph forest illustrations
here is my response of interest
here is the variable there are two dimension
and the first back door criterion is telling you
is that for example you can find the causal effect of x two on y
by running the regression
of y
on x two and now
the parents
fixed and
so this is all what you have to do in the gauss in world
just run the regression of y
other variable very two-dimensional
and the parents of the interaction with
and you can run your statistical software on that and you get the confusion
OK so the interesting thing is you only need actually local information from the graph
you only need parental set which is a hard problem but you don't need the
full graph
i only need
parental set for every variable
OK so from a more distant point of view what's going on here
again causal inferences only
but it's hard but only in regression
and conditioning on the right variables in the right variables are the parents you doing
your intervention
OK so so
how can you try to estimate that stuff to make points clear i really and
also amazed example
i do not have to grab
i don't know which are the parents and which are not that try to learn
from data
and so the experts say come on i mean this is impossible of course it's
impossible you cannot do that
the main problem is inferring that parents from observational data you cannot do that
the these example take two bivariate gaussians you have infinitely many observations here and you
can not distinguish whether it goes this way or that way
so what kind of breaks down
the ground truth the usual statistical principle doesn't broke the usual statistical principle if you
have the data generating distribution p
observational data is the observation that if you have enough observations we can find or
identify the parameters you are interested i think it depends on the distribution p which
generates the data here you need to p
and the true underlying causal graph and the parameter causal effect is a function of
the distribution on the graph and the graph itself so much harder problem and the
problem is you cannot find the gene from p so it intrinsically involved the gene
so it's impossible because say this by various gauss and nobody can tell you the
direction so
this is a slide problem here
but what is possible and try to spend my last minutes on this
is don't give up here i mean this is a huge identifiability problem you cannot
get the causal effect in general but
you can get something which actually used in example you can get lower bounds
when your quarterly
and just to give you a conceptual procedure what's going on here
somebody gives you the probability distribution p the data generating distribution
what you can do is you can find the equivalence class
of that seventies only considering that's here
you can find the equivalence class
by clever algorithms
and then conceptually what you can do is to find all members conceptually not practically
enumerate all
that means your equivalence class
enumerate all of them and then you apply
per stu intervention calculus to be that member
so for every DAG member the g bar and every variable
there are two and invention exchange
i can compute by integration formula intervention effect data rj thirty intervention effect in the
graph g or
but i sure will do all the basis of the key posteriors everything's
i think that makes sense but i can see why you know it's it's certainly
not very pure way of looking at things but let me let me just argue
for a little bit so here's the argument that
or at least here's how it plays out
what we'd like to do
is handled gridworld like this gridworld
or real world would be even better but let's just say this for today
so here's here's how the dynamics of this gridworld work there's each cell this is
an elaboration of the problem that you can find in the russell norvig AI textbook
which people probably have access to the same dynamics but different grade configurations so each
cell you've got north south east west
each action takes you with eighty percent probability in the direction that you intend ten
right angle from that and ten percent the other right angle from that ls is
the wall there in which case you get by back to where you work
in terms of local dynamics
well all the cells are kind of the same but the different inasmuch as there
is what different wall patterns around so for example this cell
and this'll have very similar dynamics if you go
then the probability that you end up over here is point eight probability and appears
point one and probably you stay put this point one and it's also true here
to shift it up
OK so you can generalize from the dynamics of oneself to any other so that
has the same book award patterns
but they have different local wall patterns and it's a little weird right because you
can get pinched and so you're slide actions two different riverside actions culture not to
move so it's usable dangerous to generalize between
a different world
so how can you also if you knew that if you knew that
each each of these cells out there has a particular wall pattern and all the
ones with the same while pattern have the same local dynamics then what you could
it is run very variation of of
r max but takes into consideration these clusters this is the so-called ram r max
and that would actually work really well
this seems achieve because it's actually taking advantage of the fact that you know we
which cells should be generalizing connected with each other so if we don't do that
and just say they're all the same
we're not saying that there all this what we say they're all the same that
would be really problematic because they're not and you learn of broken model that will
cause it to make really bad decisions
on the other hand if you say they are all independent of each other are
completely separate then it's then it devolved back to our maximum learns about each cell
completely independently
so what would be nice is if we could sort of
so we had some kind of prior that says that so walls with similar kinds
of wall patterns tend to have similar kinds of dynamics
in but not necessarily right if there are different there are different but maybe the
say well if that's the case then when
the agents visit to sell the probably like some other cell that has really good
guess as to what the local dynamics are there that's for sure but i think
if it's the case that that guess is has high enough probability
maybe it should just act on not really worried that call that's the unknown anymore
and try experimenting and it just kind of go with it
and in fact if we want to achieve PAC MDP tight bounds on the probability
wrong is small enough
then we really can
ignore it and it won't hurt us in terms of achieving our objectives of having
PAC MDP is because why because
the delta probability says that this whole procedure can fail with some small probability so
as long as we
only ignore something if it falls into that
underneath the delta rugby then we're going to be OK
so that's the basic idea is that we is on keeping problem which tracker things
things that are possible but not very likely can be swapped swept under the delta
rock and we can still have
pac mdp
so for example in this case well
the grid for ninety nine percent sure that we're in world x first worldwide
we can still be PAC MDP by just forgetting about worldwide
if the
error probability is large enough
OK so that's the sort of the basic idea we were able to generalize this
to two
two an algorithm
from DP it works like this it uses optimism and optimism uncertainty not bayes optimal
we sample model so it step in time it's keeping the posterior in some form
it samples of a couple models from the posterior side of the world i mean
but let me just choose a bunch of fairly likely world can now got a
bunch worlds that i might be and what it does is it then stitches them
together to form a kind of meta MDP so late in learning when one is
pretty sure about which MDP etc and it does a couple draws from the posterior
in public it's the same model each time so
the stitching together just leave you with the true MDP but in the beginning when
there's lots of different possibilities it states together and creates an optimistic MDP one it's
actually better than any of the ones that really saw
four through an act optimally with respect to that optimistic MDP
at that point OK so solved to find the best of the best of the
sample said that's where the name comes from and acts accordingly it acts according to
that policy just just created until something new is learned to visit the state has
been to before something surprising happens in in that shifts the posterior dramatically causes reset
to the top and resamples models and then acts on the resulting models
so what we were able to show is that if the set is big enough
still polynomial but actually fairly large we pull budget models together stitching together then we
can actually get this the PAC MDP
criteria to be satisfied with near optimality with high probability
we we gave way in this paper we gave one particular algorithm for doing it
i think there's a whole family of things that all work as far as this
this criteria is concerned and you know the bound that we get
looks like that got states and actions in it and
i think that's lines deltas in dallas so
applying these methods too much more general data types than was apparent when we started
and that's almost as an accident of what you know the other
strategies that have been born
so certainly you know this is a nice property and now
you know talk a little bit more about that in the time i should finish
tenth edition that's that's my
and we've gained and this is crucial this more flexible regularisation generalisation control i think
that's absolutely crucial to the whole strategy you know because of these kernels being able
to throw in very high dimensional
data very easily
we need that lever
to be able to control the generalization and so that's crucial sort of step
well you know normal
approaches to learning would require much more
careful control of the capacity of the function class here we were able to throw
in very high dimensional function class
generalization and
but control through the
through the use of this weight
and again this convex optimisation problem
and so we don't have the problem of local minima
OK so i should just mention that the
very briefly why is that convex well it's convex because that matrix that i've described
is positive semi definite so actually that property of the kernel required for it to
be a kernel is actually exactly the property we need to keep convexity so in
a sense the you know you might say well right away doesn't matter and we
can get around perhaps but but it's also trying way something valuable which is this
sorry of convex optimization
so there is is connection
OK i want to spend a little bit of time looking at the algorithm exp
for solving this
so to convex quadratic programme as i mentioned this you know people out there who
spend a lifetime trying to solve these things and you can apply standard optimisation
but they don't exploit the specific to the problem and they can be inefficient
one thing that's important is to use chunking for large datasets chunking is where you
look at a small set of the data to solve it on that sort of
the data and then start to expand
bring in more data and
more training data and extend
the application
just do you know picking vanilla
maybe for matlab
plugging in your
quadratic optimisation problem pressing the button it'll be a long time if it's a large
dataset you want
come up with a solution very quickly
but there are packages out there you know which do this for you so it's
not a problem but actually
you can use very simple gradient ascent algorithms
yourself or individual transform just going to give you know if you really wanted to
do it yourself it's actually very very easy
and i think i'm just going to show you
an algorithm called kernel adatron which is extremely simple to implement and it's pretty good
provided you include the chance
in fact very so if we fix the threshold is zero so this was the
point i made where we assume that b is fixed to zero
so we don't have that extra
some outcry y equals zero
then the following is the gradient descent algorithm will well let's work out coordinate wise
so you work out the gradient of the optimisation you're trying to optimise the value
trying to optimize with respect to an individual i and you actually end up with
one minus the
margin of that
examples of g is the function that the current version of the function that we
got so it's alpha
remember i said there was this extra wages and some alpha j y j that's
just the sign that tells us whether there should be positive or negative and the
inner product between the test examples and the corresponding for training example
so this is just the margin of that example
and of course you know our aim was to get it up to one so
if it's less than one then we need to increase that i'll try and if
it's bigger than one we can deduce that alpha i
basically sort of very natural
and this is the update then you just take the alpha rai and here is
the gradient and you
if you adding this extra factor here
then you actually go straight to the sort of best value of itself right
of course this may take alpha i out of the interval which is supposed to
be an you remember it was the boston transit so that authorize should be within
the interval zero to see so what happens is you do this update and because
outside that interval you just pop it back inside
and that's basically so you just work out these
you know picking out work out this updated if it was outside the information back
to the thing and you keep doing that until
none of the authorized change
say if you wanted to work fast you need to be a little bit more
about the order in which we choose alpha basically choose the ones where there's lots
of error
you know that the
the thing is either inside the marginal
now SMO is just this is probably the most popular algorithm is just an adaptation
the video and the the powerp the PDF version of the PowerPoint okay so
this is something you are going to see twice more before the end of the
week this is the cosmological standard model that is the framework of
the series of lectures and we've been working our way around here and today we're
going to reach possibly the most dominant and most important aspect of the present composition
of the universe dark energy now in the first lecture I mentioned that the the
only evidence that there is dark energy or a cosmological constant comes from measurements which
tell us something about the expansion history of the universe now the ex
maybe I should close this I guess no telling what it might have said right
so the expansion rate of the universe is the key most fundamental quantity in
cosmology and to be able to predict that on the basis of a theory and
a model and to compare that with observation is so important it is a very
fundamental quantity it comes from the excuse me the zero zero component of the Einstein
equations the zero zero component of the Einstein equation gives the expansion rate its this is also
known as the Friedmann equation and the Friedmann equation can be written in terms
of the present expansion rate of the universe Hubble's constant and the contribution of various
components which scale in different way with time scale factor or redshift and it is
a fact that these different components scale in different way will allow us to disentangle
their magnitude and their contribution the first term is a curvature term and the curvature
term is proportional to one minus the present value of the total value of Omega
and this scale says one plus the redshift squared and the coeficient of one minus
omega total can be deduced from observations of the CMB and that in
fact is zero according to the observations with an uncertainty of maybe one percent
the other contribution with which is a matter contribution can be deduced from observations of
large-scale structure and that is omega today of about point three the contribution of radiation
today can be determined from measurements of the temperature of the CMB and
this is about ten to the minus five but of course since its scale says one plus
Z to the fourth if you go back to large Z eventually it becomes dominant
so there is an additional contribution that's added in order for the observa observations to
be accounted for in terms of a model so there are two ways to think
of this if you measure the expansion rate as a function of redshift and it's
not fit by these three known quantities then you can think you've discovered something that by
the name of dark energy or you if you were a cynic you might say
well you've added an epicycle in order to make the observations agree with the theory
so the dark energy that's added is a coefficient that's determined by H of Z and
scaling is one plus the redshift to the three times one plus W the simplest
model is W equal to minus one so there is no scaling with redshift that
is a cosmological constant but in fact people phenomenalogically have W as a
function of A or Z so there is some function that you can add and this
won't surprise you if you can add an arbitrary function W then you can agree wonderfully
with the observations now the expansion rate of the universe is the key quantity
that enters cosmological observables and most observables depend upon something like the integral of the
redshift of one over H of Z so you weigh the different terms in H of Z now among the
cosmological observables that we will talk about to get information about H of Z and inferred information
about dark energy is the luminosity distance redshift relationship the luminosity distance is defined as
the equivalent inverse square law distance if you measure the flux and you know the
luminosity that defines the luminosity distance there is also the angular diameter distance again defined
in terms of the newtonian result if there is some object of a known
physical size and you measure its angular scale then it's related to the angular diameter
for bayesian modeling got dave macon nineteen ninety
three i guess starting to publish on bayesian approach models for neural networks so you
really have all these theoretical stuff being absorbed by the community and the community moving
to an extent
such that i think in many areas we actually
overtook um
the fields we were competing with in terms of statistics which at one stage was
regarded as more rigorous the machine learning but actually machine learning has really you know
it's putting a lot back in towards statistics
so my personal view is the machine learning benefited greatly by
incorporating these ideas from psychology but not being afraid to incorporate rigorous theory and one
of the things we're seeing now is this return to those type models with deep
learning these models are difficult to run
analyse models but they're doing amazing stuff algorithmically and actually doing some pretty incredible
unsupervised learning with these models
but instead of just people playing with those things in sync algorithmically his this
you've got people like ian murray doing great analysisof trying to do the annealed importance
sampling to estimate marginal likelihoods in these very complex models trying to understand better what's
going on and i think it's a very powerful community as a result of
so i think learning machine learning with u
with a lot of scepticism by the statistics community
but certainly for me
i'm saying that you can take a lot of people i'm most interested in talking
to are statisticians doing bayesian learning
or what i think the bayesian modeling
and this now
interaction between machine learning and statistics
but i think there is still a difference so when people tell you
what's going on and they say to you i just
just statistics done in a hacky way whatever
i think that's not true my personal view is that the
the philosophy the two fields are fundamentally different
whatever you're doing at the moment
whatever your tasks or if you want machine learning you want to replace the human
in the processing of your dataset so there was this i had lunch next we
were doing gaussianprocess workshop
and zoubin
gharamani tonio hating with any hagans leaving statistician
who did a lot to introduce casting processes the statistics community and a very well known bayesian statistician
anthony cities said i don't believe you can ever take a dataset and-or
this analyzed by computer without human being involved in the loop to interpret the analysis
at which i agree with in terms of the technology we have today
but zoubin immediately said well but unless you believe that the humans doing anything
magical unless you believe there's a ghost in the machine
put it one way
you should be able to replace whatever the human is doing as well now i
think that statistics as a community is about summarizing data
to the extent that humans can interpret the data so you try and say
the mean if this data is seven so if you look if you go back to the
when statistics became field in its own right and they are often working with social
science so if you want to understand poverty in manchester verses poverty in london
you could take be
average income
other people in manchester
and find that it's twelve shillings and sixpence
yeah and you can see the average income the people in london and find its
eighteen shillings per year and then you want to know
the difference the fact that these numbers are different doesn't mean anything
these populations different
so statistics itself we know what that's like baseball you say batting averages one runs
batted in this point four orient cricket
you know you say the batting averages thirty runs that's what statistics means when we
say statistics we're talking mathematical statistics which is really the study of whether the fact
that those numbers different means that the populations are different and that's what statistical set
out to do so it's set up to be
so understand the numbers you're feeding humans
the machine learning set up to eliminate humans
fundamentally we're aiming for me i singularity okay
i mean which fortunately anyone in the field notes so far away from it we
don't have to worry yet like this going out but there is really are that
we don't want
you know i'm
i presented the
guassian process latent variable model to the the stats group in sheffield
and tony hayward there actually built the end of it
one of the lectures in the group say okay that's okay that's fine but what you tell the client
unlike who's the client
statisticians always worrying about clients the someone comes to them with data and they're trying to say
something about the data tell the client computer peabody i don't think we care about
the client because in some sense which is trying to integrate it in a computer
program which i'm trying to write a module in a computer program that has an
end result like those faces you can animate faces right the client varies
graphics guy
so i don't tell him anything the computer does all that
so i think that's the fundamental difference
but for the moment the two here
overlap very strongly
why do they overlap in the moment
because we're not capable of replacing the human so very often we need to say
something to the human about the data
so we are interested in computing these numbers and the sort of thing statisticians do
i think also
one of the main roles statistics again is a personal view is that you can disagree or agree or whatever
a lot of statistics in terms of what the film is set up to do
with solved quite early on so in terms of being able to infer draw conclusions about data
about if you've got two sets crops and your fertilizing them in different ways you
want to know which fertilizers better randomizing the samples these sort of ideas came out
early this a model free they allow you to infer things about the data clinical
a lot of those questions again solved and statisticians have moved into the things which
are much more model-based which originally the field try to avoid so bayesian i think
bayesian statistics personally is a complete oxymoron because statistics set itself up as a field
like this
OK some content from bristol university this is my first talk to really introduction support
vector machines are just doing so classical story started binary classification
the multiclass classification soft margins that sort of stuff
my second talk after break have to sort out what the hell on the break
is so we get to it but be on more general kernel methods in fact
the idea come as this is can define many types of learning machines many types
of kernels many types of things you can do with this kernel based methods so
the second talk after breaking trying to to make the subject much more general OK
this often known as opportunity to actually try and support vector machines now that's really
sort of four levels of cover archibald talk when we come to it symbols levels
and i still graphical thing done by steve gunn we click points on the screen
and you see the actual support vector machines setting up the boundary to separate data
and then the first other options as
package around myself where you can use UCI repository data and download data do classification
time problems
finally feel with matlab you can try the quote proc programming optimization toolbox actually write
your own SVM learner so we will come to soften them
but this is support vector machines and my own interest i was research for a
lot of support vector machines in the past in the second talk will be
quite a few bits which are on my own research seems novelty detection i worked
a few things that make mention the bayes point machine worked on the remaining interest
in the moment probabilistic graphical methods and also work alot and applications to cancer in
fact which is a nice article cancer formatting right at the end of using these
support vector machines for example to decide relax versus non relapse predicting the future
where the cancer patients will have a relapse or not and it's quite successful problem
i did with
staff the issue for cancer research in london so but we get onto applications at
the end of the second talk so if you like
this first talk i want to
first of all just to the simple story with the support vector machine for binary
and this topic of soft margins are come onto to that the course many real
life applications of multi class
then elaborate the story pun class to multiclass classification
the schema uses finally christian is in in my department it with the john platt
and then briefly also talk about regression so
that's the plan for the first talk a second
in the first talk i really use quadratic programming to learn the problem
in the second talk i want to really show that is a big subject out
and it's not just quadratic programming you can do kernel methods with linear programming and
indeed sort of nonlinear optimization and many other things
i'll be talking about how to train SVM
model selection there is potentially one parameter you have in your SVM which is the
kernel parameter
how do you find it well you might find the data you so the kernel
parameter from the data
using cross validation
but there are other ways of doing it from various theorems which mean established so
this is the topic model selection come onto then
different types of kernels come on to that and then i thought just now but
actually using phantom practice in same medical applications
so let's first will start what are the advantages of SVM well
is the principal approach to machine learning in particular
at all the various different times machine learning classification regression
novelty detection etcetera
svm system good generalisation in practice when i first encountered this subject we should be
in the year two thousand ninety eight i tried out i've been doing your networks
and point i tried out the multilayer perceptron against SVM across a whole lot of
UCI datasets
and my impression was for classification SVM is better
the the multilayer perceptron though for regression they were fairly similar
but in any case exhibits good generalisation
two new data
and the hypothesis has explicit dependence on the data
these are courses support vectors which i come onto
when i say he is devoted to take somebody neural network model its dependence on
the data is not so clear cut
i can interpret
depends on the data quite simply from the model i generate
hence it can be broadly interpreted
various advantages when as principal approach to the subject the actual motivation for the subject
to support vector machines really came from statistical learning theory various bounds was approved in
that subject and so
unlike many other approaches to in machine learning neural networks rather sort of ad hoc
so the approach
here you've got learning theory learning theory motivation approach an approach is successful
relatively few if any
parameters you have to adjust to the operator doesn't come into it you simply percent
data and your learning machine goes and learns
now the really big box of the subject is the optimisation task is convex
again in contrast to a new network the new network typically the function i wish
to optimize has false minima now has local
i have a problem finding some sort of global minimum well actually
the task was to do with the support vector machine is a quadratic problem
so it's convex one solutions
no local minima unlike neural networks is a big plus
for this approach
relatively few world very few parameters to adjust the tension is the soft margin and
the kernel parameter
if do medical data like gene expression data i use later on don't
use anything more than in any kind i don't have a kernel parameter
i don't have anything to adjust unlike say your network again where i have questions
about how many hidden nodes are the how many hidden layers what to do about
some of the parameters and updating functions etcetera OK
also can implement a confidence measure
very important for classifier is not just says
relapse among relapse for my medical application
but it should be able to assign probability
those two categories OK
so these or classes of this whole approach
so one of the first of all just recount story for
binary classification OK
first or just something someone notation
the inputs will be this big x OK potential vector
the attributes have never attributes components i will label the particular sample and considering
associated with this particular input have a corresponding output which should be denoted y
i OK
and i'm just going to binary classification to start with some outputs my labels i
call them will be possible minus one OK
medical application talk about much further on
will be a binary classification task where possibly the patient relapse minus we may well
be that
now call these the labels
you could also called the targets
and these guys are the
a range from one to n where n is the number of samples or
the pairings of x and y k
so these excited to find a space which are called input space OK you probably
seen input spaces in the previous
in the input space consists of labelled points label plus and minus one
now it is at the beginning that so what's nice about subject support vector machines
you will be used to supply milady and postal addresses in the system
the match is not based on those million
matches they created two different groups one is the control group one is
treatment groups
so is the treatment group were people who are exposed to the readers whenever they
came to the our website
you know they were shown these retail that treatment
not exposed to the editor
and then these users were followed for six weeks and the
you know that although their online and offline purchases were tracked
it turned out that the people who got exposed to the display advertising
the revenue the revenue from people who do you get exposed to the
the single was significantly
higher than those who are not exposed
so this clearly shows that
brand advertising works it's not
it's not the advertisers do get banned for the back well for doing display advertising
and this is a controlled experiments so
there are no confounding factors here at all it was difficult to conduct such an
experiment was conducted
it clearly shows the brand doesn't work so so this is good news
especially since the advertiser takes all the risk and the brand advertising so there's really
good news for the users and the good news for this brand of advertising
ah yes so
based on this data there have been several so this paper is going to come
very soon you have done a lot of other analysis like that they analysed the
amount of online sales were offline sales on their feet they have done a lot
of slice and dice analysis to see that section of the population actually did respond
to it with a lot of details on this work and
you know i would have distributed the paper but it's not submitted but but yes
but the goal so the main point here is it's a controlled experiment and a
good reasonably confident that
the results for some closure believe artificial the discourse
so that's good
OK so now let's go to the printer display advertising so first the two key
players this advertising of course the advertiser like in any retail you have an advertiser
buyer and the seller
so advertiser here of course is the bias and they buy ad space
from publishers
these acts this is about the and so for instance if you're a big advertisers
like GM i should not mention GM sorry if you have a big and would
like that so i talked about the affair began advisory
you might buy ad space is when you're in landslide OK i what i want
to put about i want to put my water and i want to make sure
do my booking right now
that's one way of doing that i mean small advertisers are going to that because
in few book things superior
so just by and from the spot market as and when it is available so
that different ways of buying are typically if you want to guarantee
you pay more that's quite reasonable
and then publisher who cells
they demanded well in advance and you the guarantee that they're going to deliver that
many number of impressions if they don't then
there's a penalty
since charging more to make sure that you do guarantee what you
as promised
and while they can't sell everything in guaranteed market
that's what they would like to do but that's not always possible so they
the remnant inventory as it is called
it's sort in the spot market
and of course there is the idea the that connects these two as the mentioning
publishers by and then you that network to connect these two in the exchange model
the there are several ad network so there are some small network and big networks
and the small networks might lead to the big networks so it's a very complicated
revenue model ecosystems pretty complicated like call it
so you have an EM saying ad network doesn't mean to single out network it
could be a chain of networks
work together descartes
and then becomes complicated but i mean this discourse simplified scenario
OK so again as i was mentioning the traditional so the display advertising and movies
more close to traditional advertising like television advertising which we know has existed for a
long time and that's really targeted a particular demographic so these are some examples but
you might want to target ads GM ads on yahoo autos
to be shown two males above fifty five and that's one wales this is targeting
the penang on
no one thing so something which which happens at the beginning of justice
something of advertisers both
but so that's not
you are the seller and you really want to
show you that what but showing at like costume
so what you might
say well
the white book my what they book campaign on yahoo help you know
he said well
the book book campaign on yahoo help but i will want to target
users who have visited yahoo articles recently
so instead of directly trying to book
your campaign on yahoo autos you indirectly target users who have been exposed to auto
or what interested in articles and at the facilities like that do allow you to
users who are interested in a particular
who have recently so this is again another way users to the various creative ways
to users can actually target areas and actually read stories they want to
the use targeting schemes if if you see netflix and on help is don't be
surprised if they might be targeting people who probably are interested in movies for all
you know the
so it depends on the publisher right and yahoo provides this particular set of characteristics
by which you can look at and that depends on the salesforce that you know
depends on the relationship with their customers if you are in new publisher you might
want to
create your own set of attributes
and so them in the open market
and you can just go and edit these things and you know i community the
kind of resources grow
freebase is also has its name implies is free so anyone is able to go
on use it and powers takes advantage of this in two ways one is we
download all the data in a similar way to other resources like wordnet and we
use the offline in creating our index
in addition we were able to throw queries to this in real time by their
API should example of that moment
but that's all the pieces are put together from multiple
the semantic resources and composed together in a natural language search system
and from this it's pretty clear that the more the system is able to derive
broad value
even with very limited knowledge
but the more knowledge that has the better it can be in the deeper can
when you look at these kind of community resources the more every time somebody goes
in and something in wordnet or every time somebody creates some new information in freebase
that's automatically able to help make ourselves kind of natural language search better and better
to give another example
because it's fun
who said something about WMD's
WND is the abbreviation for weapons of mass destruction
think from moment about how you would express that kind of query in in keyword
any ideas
it's really hard you know you want the concept of someone saying something and that
can happen all kinds of ways and you also want to be about
WMD's the number it's a i i can even think about how you express this
in keyword search only for the events keyword search you really need that to basically
be hitting a very rich semantic index essentially this is a kind of you know
complex query over you know RDF type of structure
so the results because powerset has done that the results are things like this
it's not the
these anonymous officials said that in our judgment the CIA's work on wmds has been
set back ten years
OK so that that's actually capturing the notion where you WMD itself is the
objectivist saying
o two rho say that she worked at the agency on WMD once again
now here we have the the attack was to current was to occur in july
two thousand six and about the twenty one year-old lebanese man identified only as youssef
prosecutors said youssef another man left suitcases stuffed with crude propane gas bombs on the
so that is the same event and we're we're now getting crew propane gas bombs
mismatching there's no mention all in text about WMD's
and the results go on
we we have pepper spray
we have the china stealing the report also says that china still design information about
neutron bomb
and and so on
and once again how is that happening well i won't go through hell the processing
for someone saying something about something happens but it's pretty clear as result of syntactic
semantic analysis
i have to say i was actually surprised when this query work because i had
no idea that i system knew anything at all about WMD's it turns out that
we're has a fairly rich
the amount of information about weapons of mass destruction
here we see bioweapons
chemical weapons
you know there's a poison gas and so on
it's really interesting that you take these kind of community resources composed them with a
rich general purpose natural language system and one of being able to do you know
incredibly rich and powerful queries that would just not be possible otherwise
now let's look a little bit out
power sets some powerset semantic database that automatically created our testbed right now is wikipedia
wikipedia is about two million articles it's a great open community resource growing all the
time and covers many the broad topics that people care about it's a good match
as well as people in this community center web community have clearly locked onto that
i think the probably like maybe ten papers at this conference on using wikipedia in
various ways
this thing crosses at some other place
which is this point q
but it's not really the fact
this the thing crosses the two place because the wind could be weakly the curve
could be weakly and it could cost back and forth the number of times that's
not what distinguishes
the tangent line
so i'm going to have to somehow grasped this in the first two it in
and it's the following idea
it's that
if you take
orange line which is called the secant line
and you
think of the queue
the point q was getting closer and closer to p
then the slope of that line will get closer and closer to the
the slope of the red line
if we tried close enough
that's going to be the correct line so that's really what i did sort of
in my brain when i drew that first line and so that's the way i'm
going to articulated first now so the tangent line
is equal to
the limit of what so-called c can find
new tends to
and here we thinking about he is being
and q is very
all right so so that's the
the g again this is still the geometric discussion
but now
we're going to be able to put symbols and formulas to this computation and we'll
be able to
to work out
formulas in any example
so let's do that
so first of all
i'm gonna write out
these points p and q again
so maybe we'll put he here
q here
and and i'm thinking of this line through them i guess it was orange so
will leave it
and now
i want to compute its slope
and so this gradually will do this in two steps and these steps will introduce
us to the basic notations which are used throughout calculus including multivariable calculus across the
so the first notation used is
you imagine
here's the x axis underneath
here's the next year the location
directly below the point p
and we're traveling here the horizontal distance
which is denoted by delta x
so that's
delta x the so-called
and we could also called the change in x
all right so that's
one thing we want to measure in order to get the slope of this line
p q and the other thing is the right
so that's the distance here which we denote delta which is the change in
and then
the slope
is just
the ratio delta f delta x
so this is the slope
of the
the secant
in the process i just described over here with this limit
applies not just to the whole line itself but also in particular to its slow
and the way we write that in the limit
as delta x goes to zero
and that's going to be
this is the slope
this is still
a little little general and i'm going to want to work
more usable form
i want to work out a better formula for this
in in order to do that
i'm going to write
delta as the numerator more explicitly
the change in
so remember
the point he
is the point x zero
after that
all right that's what we got from formula for the point
in order to compute these
distances and in particular the vertical distance here and you have to get a formula
for q as well
so if this horizontal distance
is delta x then this location is zero loss
so the point above that point
as the formula
which is
x zero plus
so i don't act
and this is the amount
x zero
right so there is the formula for the point q here's is the formula for
point he
and now i can write different
for the derivative
which is the following so this
after to that zero
which is the same as an
is going to be the limit
delta x goes to to zero
of the change in as well
the change in as is the value of f
at the
of point here which is zero loss don't act
minus its value with lower point
which is that zero
divided by
dimension for this is still a long way to go
maybe i imagine other people contribute ideas and have different objective functions my work better
than the one we have we have so far
but i think it's the right direction
to have robots come from
these manufacturing violence two hour home environments and have been learnt about this particular geometry that they encountered
now the story gets shorter and shorter and shorter three three stories i wanna touch upon here
let's start with the first one
here's something with a little while ago
and we said let's look at how
optimal control tends to work
you try to find a control policy that we do is you specify dynamics model
specify a cost function or reward function
you sonoma control problem outcomes controller
that's nice it's often a lot easier to do than
specified here function and then a smaller specify a control policy
still specifying both those can be difficult
for the reward function
if you look at the number of parameters in your function has own a lot
less than the control policy that's nice
and so one thing we've been looking at is
in practice can be hard misspecified reward functions so why not learn it right but
so you know your she cares about being in the right place for car and
having a safe driving business we don't know how much to weight each one of
the practical process is one of our weight in some way
orthonormal control policies see what happened
also or not caring about the saefong distance lightweight up you go back in and keep repeating this right
so the question we looked at is he takes demonstration every covering the weighting between
all the features that contribute to your reward function
it's not a work has a long history start common back sixty four who invented control way
and then he said well if someone gives me a control policy
can i decide whether the game is something that's optimal with respect to some problems that are not
and then
stephen boyd generalized from one meter high dimensions with linear matrix inequalities
then further down the road entering stuart russell
can looked at it in the reinforcement learning setting
then we started our work
the tides
this to address entering work was mostly
pointing out that there's a lot of ambiguity is not a unique reward function associated with someone demonstration
we start looking at ways of
these putting a prior to tell you how to disambiguate
and then there was a whole lot work different ways of putting in priors
that is any greater weight function make a choice among the ones that are all consistent with the demonstration
some to some other applications
when the show that this one here
is a four legged robot
the problem is to get it to walk across rocky terrains system cannot climb across
moving the robot legs into a particular configuration was a solved problem where we worked on this
in the motors and with a good model for what i'll move defeat
the hard part was choose where to place the feet so the robot would get
across tipping over a sliding out of the train
you'd say why is it hard why we talk about reward functions slipping and sliding tumbling sounds like dynamics well
that's just part of practicality forty robotics
you have the enormous volume reward function you dynamics small of isn't good enough
and you might never get a good enough and we end up doing is saying
i'm gonna put some of my knowledge about the problem that has i don't like
slipping and sliding
i can similarly reliably quickly enough and put in the cost function and just say
don't get into situations where you would slip and slide
and now we avoid the parts and dynamics
they can simulate well
thanks for tuning a reward function but we wanted to and it will learn it
sort of thing that our processes that tuning it so things work
so here are twenty five features an example features what is the distance the centre of gravity
from the boundary support triangle the three feet currently on the ground ideally inside the support triangle that's when stable
but how much money have will affect how stable you walk
what is the slope and then each other defeat what's the height differential between the front feet and so forth
we have twenty five total
so we said okay
let's demonstrate a robot across the rocky terrain
let's no run are apprenticeship learning approach which learns
and there's a theorem that says
if you run this thing
sufficiently long
and then pick one i got a very sensitive ongoing
that getting bigger and bigger and bigger
many take the very last point
probability distribution over all right
from a distribution is ever closer to the distribution
along and this
so that's a beautiful property
it leaves you with a lot of question marks that you don't have a longer run this thing before
and you have to invent new
as well so what do
how long after i
but nevertheless theorem that says when you run it for long enough
you will get point
and indeed if you run it for longer than such points also have
property that they are coming be didn't come independently it
there doing of a random walk so
each point will look a bit like a little bit more
the probability distribution and anyone
if you are on the table and
is he
and that's fantastic
i'm not going to tell you about
it's something
and get something is
markov chain monte carlo methods
which only makes sense if we have two dimensions
so what i'm going to talk about now is a problem has two dimensions namely
the inference of the mean and the standard deviation guassian given and points from
so i just get something work
i'll be done in five minutes
get sampling
the assumption is that this is a big assumption
that's even though
he itself as the read distribution
we assume that we have
the conditional distributions
these dimensions conditional on all others so he is a nasty rash thing
some complicated
the assumption is that slice
well this think
x two x three x four x i
just like you know as one we can actually draw from this conditional distribution so we can draw from
you want connect to
yeah that's to
given x one indicates that problem there are two variables
an algorithm works like this stuff somewhere
the rule
x one new values from the conditional distribution x one
given to
at is she
juice plus one value
the conditional distribution
next to
seven x one is you about
so you
the new value
and then you feature which means that you to show
that's how you do it with just two variables you've got pay variables
just cycle through growing each of them from its distribution conditional on all the others
so this is a big assumption that you can do this but there are examples
where this is quite easy and the gas in distribution is a good example of
if i give you some data is five points and i said what the posterior
probability u and sigma chi you know the answer but you can enumerate hypotheses of
it's dependent
distribution where
she calls out concentric
that's what it looks like
but he slice through this is fantastic news and simple
so even though this is a slightly complicated and distribution
slice in this direction
many of these
a guassian
the slice in this direction is just a gamma distribution
so these are gammas
and these an almost
and the properties of the general gamma distributions you can do it says
just alternately to one another one and the size of the earth
in red i'm showing you what the true distribution actually looks like that's what the
blindfold man can't see all the blindfold man can do it so i'm starting somewhere
where there
so let's start
showing you in data space hypothesis looks like as well so this is
a very broad question women
and then you tell allocates update new by drawing from the gas in distribution
leaving significance that is about
you can roll back at it's a simple thing that you can work out in five points
what's the conditional distribution me
given sigma so he doesn't at
that's first set
and then the second step
is there
sigma y
draws from a gamma distribution
and that changes the the standard deviation from the broad value we just randomly initialize to
the new value
then we have me
and we have the means and sigma
and there is a dependence between these points is one of them is
created a weighted depends on the previous one
and every other step and highlighting in yellow when we go through
to be more
you understand
he was going
well i think of link
another running and you can see in yellow what was happening is that
on the right is a summary of what happened
is that if you look and can predict some uncertainty  some predicted error ellipse that
the area of this eg error ellipse in the W zero W A plane
where the central value here is the cosmological constant W zero equal to o z minus one
W A equal to zero  how well will observations or projects do in de determining displacements
from this and  we modeled various things and what I think emerged is
that the key to this is going to be systematics so you can say how well you can
ask how well we all LSST do in determining the dark energy parameters well
if you ignore s systematic errors this would be the error that you would get if
you take very optimistic sys  projections of systematic errors the very optimistic was defined as
taking what the project claims that we will be able to do and multiply it  by three
or four you would get a number like this an error ellipse like
this and if you would be pessimistic if you would ask the people who
would do other projects how badly is this are this group gonna be they would tell
you they would do this fairly badly systematics are  going to be the key for
the first ten years of this game we were limited by statistical errors we're past
that the important thing now is systematic errors another thing that we discovered is
how important it is to combine techniques so this is an example of one looking
at two  different techniques done individually so if you do this technique this might be
the projected error ellipse and if you another technique this might be the projected
error ellipse actually one of these are weak lensing the other is a supernova projection
so  you can say how well will you do in the Fisher matrix estimation technique by doing
combining the data of both of them and if you combine the data of both of them
that's how well you do now this might look suspicious and you wouldn't believe this
if this these were the only two parameters right so if you combine techniques how
can you do so much better than the intersection of those two and the answer is
there's really eight  dimensions in  this in these cosmological parameters space and in the Fisher matrix you can
have contours of of uncertainty in this eight-dimensional space and you project it down on two
dimensions and the different techniques are sensitive in different ways to uncertainties in other
cosmological parameters so with this what this represents is a projection of the intersection of
these eight-dimensional error contours onto the two-dimensional plane so you want to look at
the projection of the intersection not of the intersection and combining techniques are very powerful
so my personal feeling is there's not going to be any one single measurement or
any one single technique that's going to run the table on this but rather we'll
get the best information by combinings the results from different techniques and different approaches
they are proposed  so in this procedure we call it the White Papers
are various proposals and so these are actual proposals that do exist let me go up a
couple let me skip ahead and skip back so what's ahead in this game of dark
energy well again different techniques are being pursued weak lensing baryon acoustic oscillations supernova clusters
and CMB gives us a lot of information and in lensing there are many different
projects that are propose baryon acoustic oscillations some of them are being done many more
are proposed supernovae the same and studying clusters of galaxies now includes space missions so
na we  all of these won't be done but if you add-up the price tag
it's a couple of billion dollar  enterprise so I know a billion dollars is not
much in euros right but you know t  in the U.S. it's considered a lot
of money so it's a big expensive problem and of course at CERN people don't
red black trees are interesting the kinds of changes they make are very simple
and they also don't think very many of them
the competitions here's the rotation
this is the a way engineering drawing generic part of the tree we have seen
as a and b there is some subtrees hanging on the tree draws triangles we
don't know how big they are
we know the better all have the same black kite for to reflect tree
but in general just looks like this there some parents some rest of the tree
here which we don't draw
give the subtrees names greek names
beta gamma
and all define the operation right rotate
in general by i having b
i looked at it and i want to derive rotation look at its left child
and rather picture of the subtrees of the students
i created
this tree
so i've done this
turn this edge
ninety degrees
the pair was the parent to be
it is now part of a
a is now the new parent to be
the subtrees rearranged before the repositories of these two are subtrees of a and gamma
was said to be the most also three BNL still a data
switch to
being subtree of b
the main thing we want to check here is that this operation preserves
the binary search tree property
number the binary search tree property says that
all the elements in the left subtree of nodes are less than or equal to
the node and all the elements in the right subtree are greater than or equal
so in particular if we take
some node will a and alpha
we'll be in data
little c in gamma
a is lesson equal to capital a string literal little b
system equal to
capital b
let's recall two
a little seed
OK and that this is the condition both on the left side and on the
right side
because out is less is left everything is in between a and b
and gamma is after b
the same thing is true over here is still suppose we all the nodes that
come between
capital and capital b
so this is this is good
we can definitely do this operation still have a binary search tree and we're going
to use rotations particularly careful way to make sure that we maintain all of these
that's the hard part
rotations will be asking this is the right rotate operations
the reverse operation is left
this is left rotate of a
in general of the tunas that are involved we list the top one
right rotator b will give you this left able to do this
these are reversible operations
feels good the other thing is that they only take constant time
these are constant time
o operations
because we're only changing constant number of pointers as long as you know the b
that you're interested in
you said the the last owner b
so that's a sparse
that's a matrix
and you wanna treat sparsely one exploit the sparsity
and exporting sparsity and at the same time
benefiting from parallelism
approach computing is
this is difficult
okay let's go back to the
slides here
just had a print out here of
my code for solving a problem
this particular problem had
well one thousand three hundred fifty
one hundred forty six
my code is
general and then allows for
very very must be nonnegative or they can be not nonnegative that can be what we call free
they can be
positive or negative
or they can be bounded which means they have an upper and the lower bound
so these are treated a bit differently
and so on
my code reports
the breakout here
and also the constraints can be equalities inequalities or what we call range which means
it's a two-sided inequality
constraint can be above this and below or below there
so this problem had
i forty six equality constraints and thirteen hundred and fifty nine negative variables
but look at the aim matrix here
this has only five thousand two hundred eighty eight
nonzero entries
so that's per column is about four r this has four nonzeros per column so
they matrix is extraordinarily
and so
the code exploits that's and it took this particular problem took fifty iterations self
and iteration
ah i print out
these primal objective value as you currently have it
the dual objective value
as as you have it the primal
infeasibility so it's basically the norm of the vector rho
the dual invisibility is the norm of the vector sigma
end as we know it to be primal feasible system rustic it's small
we have to be dual feasible so this abrupt has to get small
and that's the bizarro duality gap so the difference between these two numbers has to be small
and these lists that are the statistics i summarise over here
so idea means dual feasible
so once this this number gets below ten to the minus i think i have
to i six is my default
i clearer
the problem dual feasible tomorrow the primal feasibility
here are not primal feasible
well i guess i used to analyze five is my threshold
here i am
primal feasible
so is not but you can see it is much better than just bad
it got way down the determinize twelve internalize fifteen which is almost machine percent precision
any objective function values have to get
i s the stopping this column here reflects the objective function values how many significant
figures in agreement there are are between them
and so
and my and my rule is if there are eight digits of agreement between the objective functions
so you know it just agreement in your primal feasible dual feasible you stop and declare yourself optimal
and you can see that this is behaving as i indicated before r that the infeasibility has dropped dramatically
at fast
right from the beginning
although i am i still plagiarism ninety nine percent otherwise so
go can go quickly
but they
but the objective function values you know they they sort of don't do much
until you get starting close the feasibility
and so
you know around here were forced both the primal and the dual turning cluster feasible that's when the
the objective function complementarity starts to kick in and we started a closed valley and
so these numbers come these things always starting later than getting feasible
and that's what the theorem was telling us before
see i started a few minutes late which we take a break
well actually maybe them if i feel there's a few more slides and take a break
so this whole idea
so i'm gonna generalize to nonlinear programming a few minutes and so give give you the framework it's
natural for the purposes and generalization
if we start with a
optimization problem and are favorite form
like this
standard form
end introduce slack variables like this
and these are the same steps we're gonna do nonlinear just a few minutes we start with a problem
we're gonna introduce slack variables
and here's the next step that's you haven't seen
but we're gonna get to the same place
microscopic description of these energy so OK that first president
second here you don't have any time evolution don't describe
the time evolution from the beginning of the from the fissioning system fragments
and then here
you don't have all these possible fragmentation was two
from the same as big one school
the small one so we have to this graph we should describe
all these different fragmentations
so that
to summarise what was missing this schematic view
that's why
we have done an approach with these assumptions the first suppose
that's the
fission dynamics is governed them by not only elongation but also asymmetry so we have
two degrees of freedom
and then all the shapes are
law allowed so this one is important
so these ranks priority
but it is important then to have a small one into one
we also have to make an assumption
which is in fact very valid and strong following education
with support there are two different speeds
one speed is for internal structures of that the motion of the nucleons inside places
so it's something very rapidly
and you have this small motion which is efficient so long
time which is bigger than ten minutes nineteen seconds so it's slow motion so you
can separate
the two motions so that's why do you suppose that at each stage of the
collective motion
you have internet structure which is at equilibrium
so that's why we can have here
these basis states so
so is that for different information which do not depend on time
and then so this is the lowest energy state for each deformation and then you
have this time evolution here
and you can constrict this wavefunction depending on time as a linear combination of these
static state with different
weight functions
when you do that you really have fission dynamics
which is the time evolution in a collective space
so how do we solve that it's a two steps formalism so first
we have first determine that
and second to determine that one
so to to determine these things
so we have in fact we use these
i admit that presented yesterday two days ago
which is the constrained hartree fock method so we impose some constraint i look at
the energy
of the system when you impose information for example
just recall you that it's based
i mean the musician principle his lack large parameter approach so you
and we impose to minimize these
so i mean name is constrained
we some imposed constraints here
the second part
we have to determine this time dependent weight function so
i just put the equations some equations just to explain what it is so it's
also based on the minimization principle what is important is that the same and so
we don't put any
all the interactions are all that
parameters of
it's the same and that we use that's very important for the query runs
of the method
and then at the end we have to collective shouting that equation depending on the
to explain the collective soul here it's like it's the kinetic terms like the square
of the two and so this is the inverse of these cases the potential
this is a o point energy corrections because we have
to deal with the quantum mechanical approach
that means that this is the potential so imagine
q is no translation
for example you have to go from one point to the other point so what
you don't like to climb more plain so you don't like with the potential energy
is very high
but you have also uses the term here
in this area you
when you're dealing with concentration this initiative this b here is the mass your mass
so it means that when you have to carry
a suitcase are bag you don't like to go there so there is a compromise
between great
when you want to go from one point to the other one
there is a compromise between the lengths of the way
the height the mountain that you have to climb
and the average that you're carrying so sometimes prefer condiment without any bags rather than
going through something flat
but something very heavy
so that's our really dynamical effects
so the balance between energy
and inertia
so that it
what this equation means in fact
now i'm going to present some results so
i will present some typical results of properties of the fissioning systems
we can see some potential energy landscape of the fissioning system
properties of the fragments and then i will present some dynamical reasons
i remind you aesthetic reason so i presented yesterday you have imposed information whether poland
and these so it on gation asymmetry for uranium two hundred thirty eight
and you find these problems state second there is
i minimum and then to valley the valley which leads to fragments with the same
and here this one which leads to
a big mass and the smallest mass so
static properties of the fissioning system so from the ground state to scission configurations
if you do that for many many actinides we find that all the topologies of
the surfaces are different so for example
of the system and the users but
even a simple sale
biologists do not know
the overall structures the underlying mechanisms of
of signaling of control
the current directly measured the these particular things
and so consequently there is a huge amount of uncertainty and the coming to two
to people with machine learning backgrounds in machine learning skills and ask them to help
understand this data to mine this data to help them design subsequent experiments that would
be maximally informative about the systems that they are trying to study
and so this whole area is motivating
an awful lot of development in machine learning methodology which is really great what's motivating
the development of methodologies not just its own
could what has previously existed in many ways it's it's developing novel methodology and and
pushing for home use tons of methodological research so
there are lots of opportunities for people there
on the other hand on very much more classical machine learning problems are i also
work with a number of companies
microsoft national cash register's appear they are interested in very classical pattern recognition problems someone
is in front of an ATM and you put some money into it
is the person standing in front of eighty in who say is the money that
has been deposited into the aegean is actually genuine
or is counterfeit and these are very
as i said classical problems which
some of the machine learning background could come with toolbox and say OK this is
are a regression problem this is a classification problem let's look at it from that
perspective but again these are very non-standard problems that do not
i can do this the the the don't you
two saying can i could use a neural network to thank to the neural network
to identify counterfeit currency well enough to fight we can't because in many cases we
don't know what the counterfeit currency is like
you've never seen counterfeit currency counterfeit currency depends on the counterfeiters how good they are
what type of inks whatever equipment use in so far as to subsequently again novel
methods have to be developed to track these sorts of problems but i should also
point out and this is the
something that is been mentioned sometimes you don't need to bother with developing novel methodology
sometimes you just have to be aware that there are
methods that can be used for example
on the problem of
identifying counterfeit currency and i had doc you want to this problem for six months
the solution that he came up with was one which the company patented
the higher the post-doc to develop the technology and now every ten years
images of euro banknotes will be scanned it will be processed by the method developed
and that was the methods
well and he actually just used
OK statistics
just use a level of significance so there wasn't so in terms of getting people
published in that's the people would never be published in that's five because you're using
something that was developed in the thirties
something like that it was the solution to the problem was required so we might
perhaps one to engineer more elegant type of these variational
one of
at the end of the day all we need to do
was defined outlets
and there are standard tables which devastated the levels of significance of that particular taste
testing so the problem provided a robust solution to the problem so
i guess the message here is that on one hand you know you have to
be invented and in terms of the development of methodology in technical aspects of of
machine learning but on the other hand you should also be just looking to solve
the problem and the most elegant way possible and that means using
simple statistics are simple
algorithms that are existing and that's what that's we should develop and you should use
maybe i'll stop about but if anyone is i i do here to the to
the notion of machine learning as it is at the moment is applied statistics and
designer branch statistics
and what to buy me obviously to get heated debate
and maybe just collecting nineteen ninety n
going around in the last interventions is of course one of the reasons for this
panel is trying to do
but i still feel to you for that we want to want to do for
the field and
something i would like to propose maybe can use a is is that i think
that one of the richest of machine learning is that if you are having with
background in it for you can
probably make yourself useful in a variety of fields many more than if you're doing
cryptography computational geometry we have a very narrow field of application the
you agree with me that actually works
six to
i mean i think certainly examples i gave my work my my phd
i have found themselves i is no academic or working in companies like NCI like
and working on various and diverse ranges of problems so
you will be channeled into one particular area which is really nice
now usual grading
then you begin to understand the idea of spectral resolution
you will now begin to see
the individual
former lines nicely separated for ukraine
so we'll turn this on
i will make it completely dark
and then
i want to thank you and i want you to
i appreciate this and spend some time looking
these lines
is really quite remarkable
this of course you could never do is to show
these many many lines you look so about sixteen hundred
this very strong
yellow in the
in the helium
is a well-known helium line
and it has a year
the wavelengths of five hundred and eighty seven nanometers
the brightest star in the
in helium
you can see them in first order you can see them in second order
and then gradually when you go to high order the various colors
begin to overlap with each other because each live their own lives
the angles are only depend on the land of the
now i can show you neon
which has even more lines
so you can you can you grading amazing into is growing doesn't cost more than
a billion dollar
it is absolutely stunning
and it has an incredible spectral resolution
because you need a prepared line source
to take advantage of that spectral resolution
and as i said
you will probably approach
certainly there
the audience all the way in the back of six one twenty
one approaching this
angular resolution ones that closer
may not approach because they see the line source
of course wider
the angle at which they sing the line source
may well be larger than
this which
the ones in the back of the audience
i therefore little better off
forty angle that you
c two the line source
with some the line source become smaller the farther away
this is remarkable isn't it
absolutely incredible
i think this is a great moment to rest and to digest this wonderful experience
and to have the form minute break
thank you very much
so what i want to discuss now
is the logical consequence
all this whole concept avoiding sources where spherical waves
come from each point
the aperture
we're not going to expand it
through a single opening
not notable with one single opening
and the opening
is now
this separation is now these openings the
think of them as being is that which has with these open singles slip
and we have plane waves coming in
like this
and now the question is
if i look
in various directions and that's my famous angle data
what will i see now
on the screen which i placed very far away
these points in this aperture
can now be considered according to the audience female principle
as a source of spherical wave
and they are going to interfere with each other strangely enough already
don't be
we call this the fraction
this is exactly the same phenomenon as interference but we draw strange distinction in physics
between interference which was degrading in the doubles
with a double split into two and no one would ever see double slit diffraction
is the same thing
somehow when we deal with individual openings we call the fraction
so it is the same you can use it anywhere you want to you can
call it in the field but the individual point sources
there they are all going to do the wrong thing
and i think this one of the top number one
and i think this one number two right in the middle
i don't the right you will see why do that
so now
i can calculate what the past differences
between the hurricane source right in the middle and organ source right at the top
well this past difference here
it's clearly one have the
by the sign of data
we did that before we had a little the
if i make that one half
i claim
in that direction
there will be darkness
while there the dark
because it's source number one
tell number two because they hundred eighty degrees out of phase then the source just
below one can kill this one belonged to
just check one activity
and say well if this person
more than this then he will never before the
and if he learns less than that he will the full
if you could see
there must be very happy
probably you can not
the same
we have found that you would
on the split
one keeps splitting we would see be in the in the
to measure how it was in use is the set of observations
and try to
use this heterogeneity
one test that uses that originated and this way
splitting and you at this time of the process we would see them in
after they decompose input space in axis parallel cuboids are kind of high dimensional
the best community in a number of ways
this those value equal set to be equal to the value or comparison is more
than or less than
and of course also these are several possible notions of originality and they didn't write
it in that once you are in the leaf you can either say what for
the majority are applied to are just for enough find way by any known professionally
the differences between
nice algorithms and i feel that is how do we how they
this same the tests
when the qualitative
and what happens believe
let me spend a few minutes saying what it was in a piece
in addition it is this
what do you mean that this just a few seconds would be enough to value
two possible values
there are high or low
so if you must
or low order must have high
it iteration eighty is low
if you have of them high on fire half of the metro
if there is any i
so this
axis x axis is right here of observations that fall on one side
this is the
when you hear almost all of them forty one side when you here almost all
of them same
when you're midway half of them
which way
half of them which way iteration it is high
when most of them go the same way
it originated low
but when this
o to one of these
i don't care
when you to choose
you have to program intestinal helping compute that originated and you may choose between in
dexter which you know these are eventually shannon information in the values of entropy and
this this
on the idea of doing nothing
but the outcome is if
and decision to howard pair or audience
very small changes in the data
make your changes on the page
your classifier to has some sort of very likely act as part of the
hyperplanes decisions to be just one test site westminster before you do one test
and this is what from here
the left from here to right
in this is you are doing unions like this
in a and b and knn have much complex shapes the most natural generalisation is
pretty much
with a hyperplane separating
not necessarily in the same input space
and not necessarily with hard threshold maybe you can get a password in the other
the first the hyperplane west indicating just before logistics missions
which way way even though it's called logistic to john correct me if i'm wrong
but logistic regression
its ability to classify
so g is not english
an example of you have probably the nice
the mother of predictors this a single fly out to sea and sand will show
up and they have shown up
things i have two place
this slogan of the CMCS maximum margin so they don't get any closer than then
you need to any of us
and this can be done by maximizing
the distance
of the hyperplane both
this means that
the labelled
thanks the prediction
as it should at least in yes and yes and with a high value possible
or you say no and it is non with high absolute value
you will want you might want to capture that structure as well so you can
say OK with that spherical space which have got by doing PCA then choose basis
that's well aligned
so that i can pull out particular pieces of structure
and the way that you do this
is you
typically maximize some kind of measure of kurtosis
nongaussianity of the distribution long tail of the distribution of particular you do this with
an iterative process pulls out the basis vector
and then what should pull out one suspect you do it again with the residual
second basis vector so in particular signals which are like this so some two nongaussian
signals which have been some together rotated and some space you know seen by many
different observers some linear transformation matrix from the signal source to the observer then you
can do it in a short tension PCA
two to get rid of the overall
magnitude the second moments in the final analysis by CA
to pull out the particular
individual cell structures
so you can do this with images and you get filters i want to show
it's a good way of pulling out independent information
genetic signals
onto another set of descriptors
another way to do things is just based on
very crude morphology
a great was storage so is there an nature this position in the image or
not is
the pixel next to me bigger than me or smaller than the
in terms of its great intensity value so local binary patterns basically take small patch
image here three by three patch you take the central pixel is threshold the other
pixels as with a smaller or larger than the central pixel and you get a
binary code corresponds to that the digital bunny victor here it's long which you can
use the code for the local structure of the image
that code you can for example
histogram locally of somewhat larger spatial region just to say what kind of structures there
are in the image
and that local local regions
OK this recruit is quite variance in lighting and things like that it turns out
to be a fairly powerful description if you want to do for example face recognition
is one of the best description face recognition
simple to do
OK another thing along the same lines
shape context here you have a low polar cities spatial bins
you have some kind of innate structure or
but binarized image in some way or another doesn't really matter how but it is
probably the easiest thing in what you're doing is you're going to place this descriptor
on all the edges and count the number of
the edges of the rich pieces that fall into a particular events so the count
of the bins
is the signal for that particular age signals multidimensional sigma fridge
for each piece of age and then you run it around to get sit these
different signals
which you can then use the characteristic of the image turns out to be very
good for matching
in particular things like text and things like that
this is quite characteristic of got clear binary signal gives you higher highly characteristic
i think we use it for example silhouettes to characterize human poses we get good
results the machine learning approach for the
t to use that information later
i think this is the final descriptively going to talk about so
each gradient orientation histograms so these have been very very successful descriptor over the last
ten years or so
again divide the local image into a certain number of orientation bins
and simply vote into been that corresponds to the orientation of the pixel typically with
the vote depends on the links
of the gradient at a pixel so you can see all per preferentially waiting
pixels of high gradients and then you pull that information in some small so special
so in spatial cell
there's a little histogram over orientations
and the whole descriptor is
six of histograms for each of the cells
so this is the basis of
SIFT scale invariant feature transform which is one of the best image matching techniques moment
histogram of oriented gradients which is one of the biggest human detection techniques at the
moment i think generally shape context which is business equipment use the shape const exist
no polygons we saw in the previous slide
but some things that turns out to be a very good arrangement as well
that's all of script is now we have to figure out where we're going to
evaluate and the the number of different choices
on the it's good of image location so that's the most obvious choice we just
evaluate descriptions that every pixel or if you pixels typically will do this also multiple
scales because we want to be able to scale invariant analysis things
so the output will be scaled spatial pyramid of local descriptive vectors and if we
want for example to do object detection in an image will typically take a small
window that corresponds to the size of the object around it over the image multiple
scales and positions and do some kind of local
classifier based calculation based on the descriptors that we have in that the wind
in order to decide whether this account our personal something in that particular window runs
over the whole image like that so that's
very classical way to do object recognition types of tasks we see some examples of
this in the next slide of course in the next lecture course
because regular simplifies the details of
so the extraction
things like that
another way to do this is to just sample randomly
and i think that's crazy there's no structure in that at all
but it turns out because patches are actually quite characteristic of images