my problem matrix with the random matrix of plus minus one and the target was
just the first column
if you two linear least squares
then you have only small weights to stay around the good weight is going to
pick up very slowly
if you enforce
just nonnegativity constraints alone
then you learn about two
you make take it takes about half as many examples is still have this cloud
small weights
and the good weight is picked up at about the halfway point
now however
if you enforce nonnegativity constraints and sum to one constraints
then you know you do with the multiplicative problems to your home and you go
very fast you pick up the weight of the logarithmically many examples intuitively
hugh constrain the one norm
it's the black thing it's similar
so he applied in various norms
of the weight vector
people in this tutorial so we'll talk a lot about norms
regularizations various norms
OK sold
here's a plot
in blue
the two norm of the LS LS algorithm it goes up very slowly
however the one norm which is the dotted line
is very big
so what happens is the two norm
uses a lot of small weights this cloud of different weights
which doesn't have the to know because you square it but
if you can help if you look at the one norm it's huge
if you constrain the weights to be nonnegative
the two norm goes up a little bit
faster but the one norm is still rather large
these are the arguments to constrain the one norm black one for instance
and the
much better
and then you see here the generalisation performance
once to constrain the one norm
very often very quickly the error goes down to zero
for the other ones it goes down only very slowly
after seeing half of the examples you are still
outside information is very important constraints are very important
the kernel algorithms
i have no constraints simplicity
is a multiplicative algorithms
they have these implicit constraints of nonnegativity and something to one essentially of one norm
and in the part of my problem
they have radically different behavior
to make
to make the point that outside information is hard i'm going to give you a
problem matrix
the multiplicative algorithm is not good
can be beaten very easily
so here's the following situation the instances of the n rows and the possible targets
so if you see one of the instances
you know exactly what target is because the bits give it away
and you're done
so a single example gives the target away
dg algorithm would still have this kind of performance
it wouldn't exploit this so it's all about outside information
you always want to take care of as much outside information as possible
included as much as possible
it turns out
these constraint c
which is sort of sparsity constraint
they very nice
the very natural
they don't lend themselves to kernelize ability
intuitively the if you add those constraints did not
the problem is not rotation invariant anymore
general discussion which metrics characterizes the problem many people use the kernel matrix
which is the dot product between the instances of the expanded instances
i wanted to
posted to use
the problem matrix which would be instances rows targets as columns
if the eigenspectrum of the kernel matrix has and heavy tail
and this kernel isn't useful
so that means you picked the wrong kernel your problem is too hard
but what we showed with spectrum of the problem matrix has an heavy tail
then it's not learnable
we showed that
the heart of my problem
matrix has and heavy tailed and ending random features i didn't show up but discuss
it off a little bit
and makes the tail heavy
some sense the kernel matrix only
only encodes half of problem it doesn't connect with the target if you really want
to see what's going on you need to do the problem is the problem matrix
so we gave a problem that cannot be learned by kernel based algorithms
the question is what is the optimal kernel for a given problem
and what is the corresponding hard problem for the multiplicative updates there must be one
can multiplicative oglesby kernelized
if you could
then you would be very very famous y
multiplicative items they had this logarithmic dependence on dimension
remember learn disjunctions for instance
this loss of k log n
i also
so is
one so
i i
or something
i mean
and you only use a subset of a single period of the sequence
now i thought i had written down here
yes OK so i get to other generators in just a second
so this idea of having a long period is an important property but it is
clearly not the only property that we interested in we want
number numbers we get to be uniformly distributed between zero and one
well what you do you simply take the and of values and you divide
the largest possible value which will be close to this model and that will give
you her number that's that is in the interval between zero and one
but that doesn't necessarily mean the random
and the idea is then to choose the multiplier modules such that the resulting sequence
of passes various tests of randomness and for example
if you choose this value for the multiplier and this value for the modulus is
what's been suggested by creating you can find it indeed the
distribution comes up very close to be uniform between zero and one of only generated
very small
sample here you could generate much larger samples
and you also want for example there could be no correlations between
in a particular pair of points as opposed to the points came out the first
one was there
the second one was in the bin just to its right the third one just
to its right
and so forth and on line
and then back to the beginning well that would be give uniform distribution between zero
and one
but the principle because between neighbours and so one of the other tests that you
could look at for example would be to make a scatterplot of here is also
verses are
i so so i plus one
so you can see that there is no particular pattern there is no particular correlation
between neighboring points and you would not want to have correlations between any
a pair of points
so this is for this EM lcg the multiplicative linear conventional generator in practice we
don't use it we use much more sophisticated algorithms that have in fact much longer
periods and if you're familiar with this fifty random class in the room package it's
the generated human three in fact
has an enormously long period two to the
twenty thousand something which is a is the mind-bogglingly large number when you consider that
i have only been
there's only ten tended the sixty years something protons in the in the observable universe
his and then the whatever six thousand or so
random numbers so it's trivially easy to place yourself within a single
periods of that sequence
there's a couple of interesting references both these there's a paper by james from nineteen
ninety that describes i think a lot of the mathematics behind these these algorithms and
very understandable fashion and also chapter four in the book by sigmund part i think
describes the mathematics behind random number generation in a very accessible readable way
OK let's start to wrap up
one of few more things
that was actually just step one
deriving the sequence of uniformly distributed values
so uniformly distributed between zero and one
given that sequence we now want to find a second sequence x one x two
the fall a different pdf
f of x which we specify
a number of ways of doing that and the first way i want to discuss
is what is called the transformation method
the idea is the following suppose that is the PDF x that we're interested in
and here's the uniform pdf
we used to generate the first sequence
and the idea of this transformation method is the following if i consider specific
o value of one
uniformly distributed variables are so let me call that all prime
what i would like to do is i would like to find a function x
of or so that would be ten x of our prime there
such that when i evaluate this function with our values it immediately gives me
the desired x values such that x follows
this distribution
so if i can find that function i have an easy way of going from
my first sequence of our values to the second sequence of x values i simply
evaluate that function
so how do i find that function well if that is all prime then what
i want to insist on is that the
area to the left of that so the integral from minus infinity
from from zero in this case to all prime that should also be the equal
to the area
to the left of
x of or prime so i want to find the function x of r
such that i have that property and that will guarantee that this distribution
will the exit four will follow always distribution
so here's what i need to require and the probability that are is less than
or prime should be equal to the probability that x is less than x of
our prime
but what is that that is simply the cumulative distribution
corresponding to this
uniform pdf
so i can do that in the rule because g bar is simply a constant
it's simply equal to one
so that rule is just equal to our pride
and then here on the right-hand side i have the cumulative distribution
corresponding to
f of x
so i write that capital
of x so far
so i have all the time
is equal to the cumulative distribution of x of our prior
OK so now we drop the prime and i can simply write that are is
equal to the cumulative distribution of x so that's the that's the equation that i
have to write down
and i simply saw that equation for x
and that would give me
the desired
and two
to show that we're here is an example
so let me consider exponential pdf
that's what we saw
just a bit earlier
and so on
what is my prescription i have to compute the
cumulative distribution
corresponding to the exponential pdf
that's given by this integral
and i simply said that
equal to or
and in this case it's a very simple it also i can do it i
can solve the equation and i find that active r is equal to minus c
from the launch
of one minus r
so that gives me the desired
now if you think about it
if are always a uniform distribution between zero and one
what is the distribution of one minus are
i think clearly don't have to be uniform between zero and one and so in
fact if you look at the computer programs that would implement this unit you will
see that this is something like that because it works just as well as you
know why why why one minus or you could just write are
so here this illustrates that really works there is an histogram of our values
and then for each value if i evaluate this function and put it in the
and i find
this histogram here
following an exponential pdf so it really works
and then but then the big question is how how to how to compromise
well if i if i do this with willing to
say about is just the transition model
but i agree with
in this part
this is
four four four this five
as it is now i think i have an idea how to do it
for this part
i would like to think
o here right or all so what i what i already know how to do
is this despite trying so given the graph i can estimate this one
right and then and then
all of what what what we need to define is this transition modern houses
parameters can change
and then we should be able to estimate the i mean it's sort of a
complicated hmm
i don't
that's the i think something that we have to
i know
deal with so right now the idea is to
to generate the whole graph even if this is not
entirely through
the case
what we could try to do is
actually we could try to
two seems to be no
basically one part here is also to estimate kind of node correspondences so we could
go on then madden ultimately here so that that would also be doable but in
some kind of approximate set
right so i i i mean it's
inside the model that and victoria part comes from matching the nodes in the synthetic
graph with nodes of the real graph
so then i could go
this way and also have a matching between the nodes
across but again it will be it would be
you are right in the sense that it would be a sample from the parameter
but on the other hand
in an email network right i can i can do that
because you're just an on and off
so i think that would be the more realistic so for example in an email
i could use
just go up and again down to to the
node correspondences
and samples
just independent
what you
one of the things that you or someone
the issue
it seems to be the
i want to read the book for
the definition
if you want to do that
so far
so i think it should be should be specification because
the the
no no notification would mean that the constant aerial or a constant fraction of all
possible edges is that we're we're
and that's because
the thing is people so that users are able to run away
the other is much more
what's interesting
i'm not sure
is a
thank pasteurisation
my guess is
this was
can find
well actually
change size
in addition
less one
this is part
while region a linear time you start see
jealously time
now you shall
here is how organization
that is what we see
starting close
these are actually
trying to model always start around
inside the station
one of the is
he is how
cost of changes
five hundred
well o
and also
right while at the same time
the class of probability distributions that can be represented as vision that
the class probability distribution might feel
so we see that the graphs
he said to be the man
four dependency of the distribution
we have essentially
graph g
it is the
distribution it
graph g
is the map for distribution p
if every conditional independence statement satisfied by the distribution
is reflected in the graph
conditional independence day
that the
a graph is said to be an i map
before independence map
of distribution
if every conditional independence statement implied by the graph is satisfied
the distribution
it is my
it lies every
all right
well you
slipping you should make you
four all conditional independence
for all
associated g
graph separation
a graph g
it is up to par effect map
four p
if it's all
if it's
the map
said to be an p map for perfect map of a distribution it's more than
the map and an i map for
why definitions well because the commission will allow us to see when remarkable interview how
mark fields in vision that to
if all conditional independence statements associated
with a given graph
are reflected in p
the is one
that's the that
that's on my map
there's one graph on n nodes
this an i map for all probability distributions
which that is this
the graph which is fully connected
there is no conditioning
so what you say is that all conditioned offices you are reflected in p
if there is no conditional independence statements
it will always be the case
you don't have
on the other hand same likewise
there's one graph
which is of the map
for all
the natural
every conditional
take any probability distribution
they all the set of conditional independence assumptions that
that probably
all those
condition samples will hold will use it to witchcraft
graph with no edges so basically
know it's
now comes
the important
is the set of all distributions on y
is the set
of all distributions virus
that can be represented as a perfect map
vision that by that
is the set of distributions by that can be represented as a perfect map
so what you see is the full
there exists a set
which is the intersection of these two sets
that can be written this set of distributions can be represented as a perfect map
ball like bayesian networks and markov
and there is a set which is outside
which can not be represented as opposed
the web is enough to know about life
but this is only for maps
that means that the usually essentially i copied the same argument as
for the first example
how can be
prove the factor base
the the law of large numbers were i showed that the average
growth rate
it is close to the fact that the log return before the reason that using
because the portfolio vector b
the average growth rate
the expected log return
but if you choose that positive that part
any positive there are
and large enough
these even has large probability
very close to one
of camp
which means that the the average growth rate
is between four numbers
if you make order
arrangement than the amount of money
in between these
two numbers
which means
that that the center is approximately equal to ten times the expected log return
the large profits
but then is close to you could be ten times expected log return
this is one part of the calculation
the other one is the calculation of the
expectation of the capital
at the time
remember that the amount of money at the time and is the product of inner
products of the portfolio vector the return vector
while x starting are independent identically distributed so the expectation of the product is equal
to the product of the expectation
so you may be right he e to the end times the locality
of the inner product of b
and the
aspect you read there
you know that ten is close to this number
you either side of the library
and the expectation of f then it is here where
the expectation
the logo
so i can show that and then close with expectation
if i can verify that these exponent in the exponential expression in
not close to this one
which means that the expected log return
it is and the and the local authority of these expectations are different
but you can use the
the the the and so you know what
if you have a concave function
and your your called where
the concave function as an expectation
and compare it with the fact that the the expectation of the function at random
you make a decreasing it because they have you know what it is formulated for
convex functions
which means
that the
comment function as an expectation is smaller
then the expectation of the convex function
this is for four recall if so you have just the
the river
which means
the exponent here
is larger
that the exponent here
which has the consequence that the s and is much much less
then its expectation
in our example of
these had the
value was the
the large probability
and the the expectation had an exponential
and why i i told you all of these one
because the naive approach for portfolio selection
could be
you want to find an optimum weight
column bases of the matrix
you simply
or the columns in order of nondecreasing way
and choose one after the other so that what you choose
she maintains independence
when you can add any more
what you have is a
most valuable basis
but of course the same thing works for any matroid right
and the same thing works for any polymatroid and that's what this is saying and
that's how
i mean the they
true for matroids
it is the
a polymatroid
here's the thing and the vertices of the pollinator
vectors at a
this form
we've we order
we've ordered the
the e in an arbitrary order at all
any or or at all
a survived means
initial subsequent of i am
now we get a vertex
express it this way
if you restrict yourself to the rank function of a matroid
this is exactly you know
this this is
this is all this is the one
in other words
element one goes in independence that this is the one right
the rank for matroid rank is only going to go up by one
this is going to be a one
i mean you're element goes in your and your chosen independence
so this is exactly
the greedy algorithm for nature as we describe it a moment ago
except that it works as well
polymatroids by saying
all right you want to know how do we prove that these are the vertices
talking and what i show again
the way
he is shown
a set of vectors is the vertices
it is to show
they are what optimize any linear function
over the public
a point
that's feasible
is a vertex
it can only have
you can find a linear function that's optimize over the polytopes
only by that point
it's simply the greedy algorithm that's proving that those are the vertices of the parliamentary
in particular that those are the vertices
of the matrix
all the time
so here we have
look at the linear programme maximize an arbitrary linear functions
are there
of our pollinate right
there's are polymatroid defined by are
polymatroid set functions
we a order the coordinates in the order nondecreasing
the coefficients of the objective function
an ace of i simply means initial subsequences
so something like that
oh yeah OK
we're solving the LP
we're also going to solve the double LP
we're going match that this is this is this
this is the LP do
of this primal LP maximise this
so due to the
the deal
minimize that you see we have a dual variables we have at the variable for
any quality here
here we say
and this is the number of parameters unit with
some of you are nothing but the good news is that we we can do
OK so
of course if you try to estimate it from the likelihood then you will have
to be resolved if you just maximize likelihood
it will be you will have a thousand nodes and one partial funding to the
solution will be completely stupid so you have to penalize this kind of solutions that's
we selected we can select a bayesian model that is you will be my stupid
solutions by putting a prior which is high
and the nice solutions
OK i think every
right OK
bayesian inference
so we have here
the likelihood which is written here
going to multiplied by the prior to the two avoid to be
and so we end up with the posterior distribution of the parameter
how to select the prime
for example we want
to avoid having one so the
so we put a prior on the number of nodes which will
a small number of
with this kind of things we can
select a good set of priors
OK but in fact
as i mentioned earlier the
the way you select the priors is not only inspired by the physics and by
common sense but it's also inspired by the easiness of the computation
so as mentioned by chris bishop earlier we try to select a conjugate priors
which are much much easier to use
for example here assume that the number of nodes is no
but we could also assume it's not
OK so now i added some of the priors which can be used and explain
why selecting
this is the real problem
the amplitude
we want them not to be to be
because if we have
very big
no it with very high amplitude than probably the mother we try to put another
exactly the same place was
the corresponding very high amplitude stories
you see what i mean
if to create an artificial with the amplitude and the opposite artificial severe high amplitude
so we want to avoid this says that's why we constraints the amplitude to be
and what we do this is to us
location distribution for example
that the remark amplitudes here can be negative
and positive
because we have assigned to them the cosine
we have no initial phase that sense
OK so
the dimension of the prior distribution
let's say it has
the diagonal
covariance matrix with them and they will all just an idea to
and it's i mentioned depending on of course the the number of partials
so this prior
is not always fixed
i two
i'm going to talk about it my side two is what we call a heap
parameters are
frequencies and so on
but in defining the prior
you may need to define to another parameter
if you say well the prior distribution is a gaussian
with mean zero and variance one
in fact you could say it's a gaussian distribution with mean zero and variance sigma
this variance
it is nice if you know that
here we assume don't know that this parameters so we defined the priors but we
don't know everything about crime
so i'm sure can we can learn about the prime himself
OK so
this was for example now how to build
model fuzzy
frequency of
as you so this is the frequency
no number k
and partial and then
so we know from the physics very close
the fundamental frequency of the note multiply
by the number of the partial
but you know it's not exactly so for example we can have the correcting parameter
that here
which will allow it to be a bit beside the true predictive
and we can also select this kind of trial but it is just an example
in which you have
an independent prior for the fundamental frequency and the tuning parameters
so we select can select this
because it's more easy to compute
so again is a compromise between reality and the closeness physics
and the easiness of implementation
so this is another kind of prior you can use for the fundamental frequency imagine
you're playing the piano
some notes you can play show in between two
the kids you can
put it into the primary model for the frequencies
for a small motion on each other possible frequency
and the
people want to share with the tuning of the
the fact that
so we can use both of these within the right
OK so and there important parameter is the number of bottles
this is the model
this is guaranteed to find the size of the model for this is if we
now going against it selected going into the electrical gradients but that's not the end
of the story
what they are also
two other interesting functions one
after a certain amount of time
after a very brief time interval
this channel also has the property that close
so now when it closes what's going to happen
the postal start work again re-establish are negative fifty
it's going to take too long
i mean the happen you get back to minus fifty this can take a long
it's good to the channel that the voltage gated sodium channel closed but
even better
nature is arranged to have a voltage gated
the last century
and what happens to the golden gate gated potassium channel is around plus thirty million
it opens
and admits capacity
now instead of having to wait for the relatively slow ATP driven pumps
what happens when i potassium
if the cell is positive on the inside negative on the outside
what happens for potassium
potassium starts coming out
because there's more potassium on the inside
and there's also favorable electrical gradient
so passive
explosively starts rushing out
rapidly re-establishes
the resting potential
all this happening in the middlesex
very impressive
so in something like one millisecond
we open up the potassium channels now if this had happened that the channels go
in the first place had to get to minus fifty
that's the work of these dendrites the dendrites integrating a signal from all the things
impacting on it will get the solar minus fifty
but once the cell gets minus fifty and attacks on him
being the the action potential fires
the cell is itself plus fifty in a big rush of sodium is
and then zips down to minus seven again
in a big rush of passengers
remember as it was only like one part in ten to the fifth the ions
to trivial actual the number of ions necessary to set up these little things such
a tiny fraction of concentration the through this whole thing those concentrations not noticeably change
that's what's so cool
is there are different regimes
those that they do change they change by one partner ten to the fifth of
those numbers
it's really cool that we haven't screwed up or concentration gradient we move tiny numbers
of ions to accomplish all this
this is a very clever engineering
very clever engineer now
how we managed to transmit the signal down the cells
let's talk about how we properly i think this is really cool is one of
the truly great mechanisms the
it was invented
transmitting an action potential
suppose i transmit my actions suppose i have neuron here
and over here
the axon hillock
i transient we depolarized so minus fifty
then i fire
and fire
what happens is this
part of the cell
it was originally minus minus minus plus plus plus
it becomes possible to temporarily
right it now becomes
plus plus plus
so it's good minus along the whole cell here
plus plus plus plus plus
so little patch of membrane
at the beginning of the axis
it has become positive inside
because whatever local effect here
cause this to flip
if this becomes positive this part of the memory
what happens to the negative charges over here a little bit further down the axon
some of them will be pulled over
so the positive
whole whole
some negative charges get pulled over
but what happens when some of those negative charges get pulled over to my mind
seventeen syllables
is it is negative as it was before
no becomes minus
minus fifteen ovals
what happens when this becomes minus fifty models
there's actually potential
what happens is
here's my ackson i fire an action i have an action potential here and in
the course of that i pull over some some negative charge
that of course trains the depolarized here
and causes an action potential
that of course this becomes positive which pulls over some negative charge
which causes the action potential fire here
etcetera etcetera
so if i can manage to get things started
with my dendrites causing a transient depolarisation from minus seventy minus fifty
then the action potential itself will draw over some charge
and start the process of the next patch remembering the next patch next memory the
expansion the membrane on the expansion memory
and it gets all the way down here
to brilliant mechanism
we can calculate
these i'm not flat surfaces there are trees
he on the ground building on the ground which i like sharp point where the
electric field will be locally higher
and so you will get to discharge
at the sharp points first
and that means the potential difference between the cloud
and you could then be less than the three billion that we have
calculated here
but it's only a back-of-the-envelope calculation
the details of the physics of the discharge very complicated
but i want to
share with you some
facts without giving
detailed explanations
the start of the lightning
i went back tones begin to flow
from the cloud to the
therefore follow which is about one to ten meters in diameter
and we call that the step later
the seventy the most about hundred miles
a second
so it comes down to about five millisecond
five millisecond from here to here
and it takes about half cool
to the earth
topic long for about five millisecond that means the current is about one hundred and
this template creates a channel
of ionized air four lions and electrons which is an extremely good conductors
and was when this step leader
reaches the ground
there is this
highly conductive channel
and the electrons can now very quickly flow
from this channel
to ground
and that starts first right here
at the surface of the earth that's very electrons will first
go to the earth
and then
electrons which are higher up in the channel will make it down to your
and so you're going to see
going through the channel
the earth
the first electrons i
closer to the
and the electrons far away
and then
even farther away
and this is actually where most of the action of course the
current is now enormously high
ten thousand two
some hundred thousand amperes
and you heat the air
get a tremendous amount of
light ions
and you get
pressure he conclusions pressure and there comes
from there
so most of the action
is not in the
leader but is in this second phenomenon which we call the return stroke
which is from the earth
the club
and the speed of the return stroke is about ten to twenty percent of the
speed of light
during the return stroke is about five school exchange between the cloud
and the earth and five can always a sizeable fraction of the total charge
that was on the glass on the cloud first which is to start with
after the return stroke maybe twenty millisecond later
this whole process can start again
you can get to that later
you can get the return stroke however the step will now follow exactly the same
that was made
before because that's where the air is ionized so that's where the conductivity is very
that's the easiest way to go
and this process can recur five ten maybe fifteen times
so what appears to you s one lightning bolts
in fact could be ten
flashes back and forth
between the cloud and you're
and the real life is not in the step leader that's very little i realized
is in the
so that can return stroke which may be twenty thirty forty millisecond apart
here to you
and to me only has one flash
which will take place may be in as little as a tenth of a second
and during these
five or ten return strokes
you exchange between the cloud and you may be a total of twenty five to
fifty cool
and then of course the lower the potential difference
and if the potential difference becomes too low
then the process stops
you have to wait now
forty clouds to charge up again
and then lightning will strike again and that can take anywhere from a before
o five ten twenty seconds
and then you get another
lightning bolt
the study of the
of this process of the step leader and of the return stroke
can be done
with a
camera which is called the borders camera
let me first explain to you
detail in principle how it works
this is the
every year
on the film is exposed by your comments
suppose that i move the film very high speed to the left
and suppose this that comes down and see some light from the step leader
then i may see
on the
the film this
the light
and from here to here
or ten b
five millisecond
which takes the step needed to go from the cloud studio
now the return stroke
takes place was way higher speed
so i see a tremendous amount of light because there's a lot of light into
one stroke and of course this
very steep
because it goes on the times faster
then this template looking down
so you can measure these times and so you can get the speed of the
return stroke
and then later in time maybe thirty forty seconds later on the film
you may see another return stroke
you may see another one
so you can see then how long time was between the return strokes
and you can also calculate
their speeds
with the real camera it's not really the film that is moving but at the
moment that is moving
and the way it is
pictures are taken
i'll show you one
this is the photographic plate
then it is the camera moves over the place
with a very high
speed about
three thousand
revolutions per minute
and so you would get these
this information than not
horizontally but you get it right
of the
phil but you get the same information you can calculate speeds and times
during the past decade
a new forms of lightning have been discovered
which occur way above
the clouds
where a hierarchy
red colors have been seen red sprites they're called also blogettes
the light is very faint
because only for a very short amount of time
first of all very quickly walked out of the heterotic strings well heterotic strings are
closed and oriented like the type to believe everyone in space
the are close things there are no the brains they don't get stuck anywhere
and they have the degrees of freedom now that's the novelty compared to what i
said yesterday it turns out that you can take half it was on extreme than
half superstring
and put them together and still make a consistent string theory now that sounds awkward
but remember that waves moving on the left and the right to this thing were
totally independent never interacted therefore why not take half-and-half
that reduces the supersymmetry of the theory already in the critical dimension but that's OK
we don't need so much seemed to start with
so in practice this means that one has the use of any
coordinates of the superstring
the film munich partners of the which are now only left move right moving you
so i forgot to cite them use that were there yesterday which were left movers
and instead of the left i have an extra sixteen four minutes to go up
to twenty six as required by the masonic string
however it is more convenient for many purposes to think of these sixteen
two dimensional bosnians as thirty two
two dimensional family owns
two dimensions is very special is is that there is no spin there is really
basic distinction between bosons and fermions there's something called personalisation feminisation you can the borders
and for two fermions or derivative of abortion far from your
so that's simply technical details
OK now
you can go through the same steps as yesterday and construct spectrum of these theories
and here in our goal much faster here are basically the massless states you get
after projecting out so as yesterday
so first of all by applying the oscillators say new
and eighteen that these remember what it was on the coordinates x new the left
moving excitations
so by doing by considering the states
you get as before the graviton and all replacement company up in ten dimensions except
this supersymmetric company slightly reduced now
there is only one gravitino actually
and the reason is that the supersymmetry is not maximally it's half maximal because we
cut out one half of the superstrings
so it's what one calls in one one supergravity in ten dimensions
but there are some extra states what instead of taking the left moving excitations from
the coordinates of spacetime
eighteen then you using this extra degrees of freedom of the boys on explaining which
i found my own eyes and when you work this out a little carefully you
see that this precisely creates a thirty two gauge fields disaffected two because there are
thirty two
in family here and they have to be anti-semitic prize because is fair use
so you get this gets fields plus the support partners which are going to mention
so by the similar steps to yesterday one gets an effective theory in ten dimensions
what are the massless modes are in about one supergravity coupled to equal one super
yang mills with gauge group which is either fifty two or that is the second
possibility turns out which is
an exception group a cruciate is out of the only two possibilities that if consistent
anomalies theories in ten dimensions
this is the famous kannan schwartzman
that they want to explain
now let's go very directly down o four so that's our basic theory
we need to get the standard model out so obviously we have to compactify six
of the ten dimensions and you have to do may be all sorts of things
you know there are known background fields in this compact space and so on and
so forth it doesn't matter so much what they want to focus is what the
theory we look at in four dimensions well he had his first of all the
effective field in n dimensions if you compute it it has the einstein action this
is the curvature in ten dimensions
this is the end thank you both hearing and dimensions
and this for dimensionality zones
has a quite efficient in front which has powers of most of the aid
in four dimensions you get massive square that's one of urging you to newton's constant
independent mentions you get more powers you get eight hours and i defined this to
be the string scale to be a
and then there is also here is the coupling constant of this closed strings which
is a free parameter in string theory and which sentence has one of the existing
square and then using here some conventions that get rid of numerical factors
now likewise the young men's theory in ten dimensions for dimensionality zones has
a master the six
and it has also existing squared the factor that the factor between the two is
one crucial point and one that will come back tomorrow again in the more important
maybe even way
is that here we have a calculable theory of quantum gravity so these numbers are
calculable you know you don't have to wait your hands you can just go ahead
three or four point amplitudes are measured this company mentioned compute this happening in ten
dimensions so these are absolutely calculable from the theory
now we go down
from ten to four
so there is some compact six dimensional space
if we do naive dimensional reduction what will happen if you see here there is
an integral over ten dimensions it will become an integral over four dimensions that the
volume of the compact space i is v six
likewise here you get the volume of the compact space
it turns out you can also get an integer here some
natural numbers
because by going down from ten to four
you may actually decide to embed the gauge group in a different way in the
original this offensive toward a cruciate and this gives
just the natural numbers that the kids here
and of course this out of the coefficients now often very little einstein hilbert action
the one that matters for us in our experiment if you wish this we usually
call one of two times the gravitational coupling constant or one of sixteen five times
newton's constant g
so this we know from the experiment
and this is the coefficient of the young mills theory and that's what we define
as one of the largest quite young men
at each
i mean
we're pretty good
at modeling relational data but we're not so hard to doing that with spatial and
temporal information and many of the social systems are deeply
there have lots of dynamics which we need to come up with ways of being
able to effectively model
but key problem there is feedback really what we what we
are headed toward are trying to learn full simulation models
they can express the dynamics of these systems as they move through space and time
we also have challenges of understanding even the algorithms we currently have
one of my realizations of over the years has been that it often takes a
very long time to fully understand how
an algorithm really functions we've got to start with some of these relational learning algorithms
there's been work on collective inference about how it is that these algorithms actually do
their work and infer collectively across the whole set of entities but deep understanding of
these systems and new algorithms can be really challenging two examples one is that in
this community don't work association rules for a very long time
and i was just amazed when at KDD a few years ago geoff webb and
and then some a team including hiking manila
shows results which said that many of these algorithms will produce large numbers of association
rules even when there is absolutely no associations to find in the data
both of these papers take a stab at having a statistical hypothesis test of the
associations that association rules find and it was really the first time that that kind
of work is being done and been done kind of the general way
two months and i did some work on classification trees some forty years after this
technique was first developed and published where we discovered the basic performance basic behaviour of
those algorithms which was that the size of those classification trees continues to go on
with the size of the dataset even when there's no additional signal to detect so
the size of the tree that depends on the size of the dataset not on
the complexity of the underlying distribution
finally in this area i think there's a there's an issue about acceptance by social
we regularly develop new techniques and new technologies and it's great for us to develop
one technique one year new technique the next year we're constantly changing our representations in
our algorithms and that's fantastic social scientists have their heads
when we come up to them and say oh by the way all the social
science you learn all you also need to learn all the stuff were doing and
we just did last year that stuff you learn the year before now that's really
not relevant anymore
we need to talk with the social scientists and try to figure out what it
is they need because frankly
there so the only votes that count in terms of whether stuff gets used within
social science
OK so now when we talk a little bit about causal analysis
well that's no need to infer
well the only new set of variables that were associated with cholera
but what he wanted to know was what caused
and needed to do that without doing an experiment you need to do it from
observational data
now what i mean when i say causality well causality is really about manipulation
that is i want to be able to say if i change facts
why will change
that is at the core of what we mean by cause and effect is this
kind of remote control
i change one variable and if it's causal for another the other one will change
why would you want to focus on causality is an association good enough we've been
doing that for a long time
well correlation or
i'm i'm going to say statistical dependence unfortunately under determines causality it's not that it's
not the it's not
necessary for but it is not sufficient for causation
statistical association alone is insufficient to distinguish among a set of different causal models if
a and b are correlated or dependent but it could be either a causes b
because as a some third variable c causes both a and b or even that
a and b have common effect on which we have condition
all right so often unknowingly well conditional on third variable it will render those two
and what we want to do is the fact p
these different models have radically different applications but do that
now this point you may be saying well can we actually even figure out causality
from observational data and the answer is yes there is a well-developed theory of how
to do this just as an example if we know that acts
why are conditionally independent given some other variables that don't include e
then there is only one causal structure
but can result in this pattern of association
this isn't generally true there are many patterns associations that you cannot disambiguate but this
is one of them that you can under some some reasonable assumptions
so there no
the idea of developments in causal analysis the really you know most frequently cited in
groundbreaking work by pearl and is also has a new edition of his book out
just now on causal inference has been set of really great work by a team
at CMU spirit is clearly more in china is also two editions of their book
on how to develop algorithms to find in data construct causal models for this dataset
and then there's a set of work in social science that i've been reading lately
about quasi experimental designs and i'll talk a little bit more about this
but i think it's really a wonderful opportunity for us in machine learning and data
so it's not was asked to do what he calls what was people called the
crucial experiment or experimental increases
they said in order to figure out which of the hypothesis is right you have
to do this experiment basically you in fact somebody with color when they're not in
that's really not ethical
it's not the sort of the kind of thing doctors going to do
but fortunately snow found in the massive data sets that had access to
a subsample with exactly the conditions needed to essentially perform an experiment what he did
was to find what amounted quasi experiment
in the work that william far produced in one of his his weekly returns
he had a footnote
the footnote ready
in three cases
the same districts are supplied by two
different water companies
the same geographic region the same socioeconomic class the same that share the same elevation
supplied by two different water companies and snow happen to know
those two different water companies drew their water from two different places on the thames
one company
through the water upstream of all of the sewage the other through their water from
he said it was the perfect experiment was an experiment on the grandest scale he
had three hundred thousand people that were drinking water
often not knowing where the water came from and with essentially no rhyme or reason
OK so
i was defining
previous slide was this one with defining the
various type of analysis and now that we have to defined all these concepts
i want to give you an example
again these bayesian inference and as i told you so if you look at all
these items the third generation for the called number that you can
i have
a bayesian version of them doesn't mean that patients would accept all of these as
the definition of bayesian inference but
these are
bayesian evaluation of all of them
so for the generation of the data
as i told you before you can assume
you don't have to but you can assume that this function is sampled from some
prior and the data is sampled
and labeled according to this function
you typically have some kind of offline
protocol where all the given the examples are given and then you want to
the function to predict the next example
the last measure is typically the expected there because you have the probability measures so
you can take expectation and the this probability measure
and the type of analysis also typically can be
the average under the prior that's why you
make this assumption that the function is sampled from some prior
it's only for the united states
and sometimes you have all you have also
other assumptions on how the
labels are
corrupted by noise
OK and of course you don't have to
take all of them as it as the definition of bayesian inference and you can
make all sorts of combinations where you can
make an average case analysis in a setting where in the different protocol or with
the different was measured it is that i mean there's no
the reason to see that to see
distinctions so
you can combine all these things in different ways but the important point is to
see or to understand what you are combining
and what it means to combine
so in
in my case i will be interested mainly in the worst case analysis
because i want to provide guarantees that
i hold no matter what
the problem that you're looking in
that you're looking at is
try to avoid assumptions as much as possible
of course
under these conditions look for the best algorithm so
the kind of quantity that
i want to investigate is this one
so i have to say predictor of learning algorithm i have a problem i can
characterize the loss of this predictor on on this problem can be a function that
i cannot
actually measured can be expected error
but is something that i cannot is approximate
and i want to
i don't want to make assumption about
what the problem is actually because i don't know i just at beta i don't
know what
where this data comes from the comes from
so i think the maximum over all possible problems
and hopefully
i would like to have another reason that minimizes this quantity here
and the question is whether this is possible
and reasonable
they like this
it's not really possible you we can show and i give examples of serums that
show that you cannot do that or
you can do this this minimum will be always trivial
and the point is that you can always construct problems that will make your algorithm
thing no matter which algorithm that you're using
again it's again amount of point of view but i think
hopefully it will be the last time i talk about point of view and then
i get to
actual formalisation
i think it's important to understand this distinction
rewriting this quantity that day
shown on the previous slide
several ways of looking at it one way the so-called minimax point of view
the main point of view is to say well if i can do
if this doesn't make sense when i take the maximum over all problems there
i can just restrict the class of problems that i'm allowed
to consider and then have a quantity that makes sense
it's perfectly fine to do that i see
i just rewrite the same thing but now i restrict my problem to be in
a certain class so i make a certain number of assumptions on how the data
is generated how the noise behaves how the
how small is my function is and so on and they say well
given the worst such function or the worst such debates are
how what is the best algorithm what the algorithm that minimizes the worst ever
and there are two versions you can also consider
this quantity here where you subtract the best loss
so some kind of the the best predictor that you could have obtained if you
knew the problem entirely
and this is why we can i mean
there is of
domain of study the minimax estimation
serie where you can improve results about such quantities
another related to point of view is the so-called learnability point of view
again you assume that the function that you're
trying to approximate or your so called target function function that does labelled examples
belong to some class
and then the question is whether
you can
learn this class in and learning the class means being able to identify any of
the functions in this class with enough examples of given enough examples you can construct
an reason that will learn
any function in this class
which means that the minimax error that they should previously we go to zero when
the sample size increases
OK and again this means you make assumptions you assume that your target function belongs
to some class so that your data is generated in a certain way
and if it's not the case
then your result does not hold any more
they are not useful anymore if this is not the case and the problem is
can never
for almost never be sure
that your assumptions are correct
in practice you cannot say
whether the noise is gaussian or not gaussians
it is it seems like it is just
we have no way to prove that the noises as a certain form
another point of view which is about even worse in my
my opinion
it is the so-called model identification
so in this case you don't want to minimize the error you want to identify
the function itself so what you look at is the distance between the function constructed
by organism and the true function
if it exists
and usually you cannot define it but
fine in certain key i mean you can
make statements
to meet the check that you right at at the end of next month
they only start to care
when they feel that there's something in it for them
so you need to know them inside out so that you can position what you're
in the context of what they'll get from it
so one of the critical thing if you want to engage people every charismatic leader
the the lowest and the highest simply
translates and interprets the vision that they have
in the terms of the interests of people that work for them
it's an interesting thing it's worth reading about if you've read about o thing called
emotional contagion and we we touched on this morning when we spoke about smiling
and here's here's what built into you as i say into the reptilian brain we
automatically mimic the body language of the people around us we automatically mimic when they
when they smile we find ourselves smiling you feel like an idiot sometimes
i don't know about you sometimes and watching the TV and very susceptible watching TV
and somebody comes and a big smile i'm sitting there with a grin on my
face because africa TV
and i got this big smile and and you smile and then somebody else miles
and so on and so forth
in two zero sum is one of those emotions is one of those behaviour which
is just so extraordinarily
it goes around the room like this let me ask you
let's go to the dark side from
does anybody know someone
don't shout out any names
who when they walk into the room
socks all the good out of the room
as they say in the states sucks the oxygen out of rule when they go
in the movie goes down does anybody know someone like that is not going to
ask you for names
there are people sirbasku used to call them psychic vampires
he said they walk around with an umbilical cord
attach them and just look at the plug to you and so every bit of
motivation and positivity that they possibly can out of you because
as the expressions as misery loves company
when you're really feeling as miserable as negative is that then they feel OK
it's not just me
but the reality is the location is just the
you walk into a room
as the leader of people
not only is smiling and you're using a language that suggests that you're at least
enjoying yourself which are genuinely energetic and enthusiastic
it costs nothing
and it has an extraordinary impact on people you watch yourself next time around somebody
into CSD what you find yourself doing is mimicking the
you can't help but because that little reptilian part of your brain says whatever god
i like and i want some of it and you start to mimic and whatever
they are doing
the interesting thing is
when you may make it actually causes you to feel the same feelings and so
you get that as i say that contagion this is critical
if you
are enthusiastic and energetic you will and susan energize people over time
not the first time
if you're one of these people is really not that terribly enthusiastic
i don't expect when you go back to the office to go to the boys
are back let's go let's have a great day
but obviously got OK OK boss let's do it
it takes a little bit of time for people to trust but the first time
that you start becoming enthusiastic letting people see your enthusiasm
i mean sometimes my mother used to say to you know if are you happy
yes i am well please tell your face
you know if you're happy if you're enthusiastic let other people see it share it
with other people it'll spread through the extraordinary impact upon people
and it was one of the things that came out highly rated by our four
hundred thousand followers they said
are turned on by people who are excited and enthusiastic about the things that they're
doing it as i say it doesn't cost the centre
and if you can be enthusiastic about what you're doing you're either in the wrong
well you've lost your way a little bit
and here's how you know if you lost your way
if you don't have for yourself some pretty clear idea of what you're doing what
you're doing today
and what is going to mean for you this time next year personally well then
you're slightly off the track
and the way you get that enthusiasm back
you get yourself engaged for a set of personal goals that are aligned ideally with
the business schools or find another job that our language are business school which i
have to be enthusiastic you can't take it
we've be telling people forever
no in fact let me go back a little bit further
if you go back to when i first started working which is used to
about thirty years ago
these are the traditional role of the leader was really kind of policemen
it is job our job was to catch you doing something wrong and then smack
your heart
you know is like the spanish police at the the the football matches step out
of line you crack your skull
and then fifteen years ago probably blanchard and those sort of people started writing books
is that i got an idea
what if we catch people doing something right
what if we go around catcher people doing some and we say a great job
i wonder what that work
so since then we've been telling people recognition
is critically
now recognition is important not just because
it's a nice thing to do
but because it has the same effect
as even smiling were talking about earlier on their two critical effect in recognition
the first one is
when you give somebody some positive feedback on something that they've done when you give
them a genuine recognition for something positive they done
you cause
an injection a little squirt dopamine in the brain
dopamine is the chemical
that those of you
who get really pleasurable sensation from chuck
when chocolate of
that's dopamine
it's what people get from sexual intercourse
it's what it is like a
anybody here run or cycle you know do vigorous exercise
there must be somebody this is not a trick question mark
OK so you know what i'm talking about when i talk about the runners high
you know you finish run if you just feel like god i could take on
but you see the past alive rather than digging it out and see the bones
of dinosaurs and so when you look at the light from the sun it comes
from as it was eight minutes ago although the four times to come out from
the centre of the sun all the way out two million but you don't want
to get to the surface to you it takes eight minutes and we are not
sitting in the center of our galaxy we are seeking about a particular but six
out and so
when we see the light from the centre of the galaxies to twenty eight
two twenty metres does
twenty thousand years ago and when you see a nearby galaxy like andromeda
we see slide as it was as you started from there was admitted about two
million years ago and one c
the large-scale distribution of galaxies you have seen the universe as he was about to
three billion years ago
so when we see these very nice pictures for example you probably have seen this
picture even in t-shirts like this is an image from the hubble space telescope it's
an image of the stellar nursery where start a more
now this is a beautiful this column of dust and here the stars main created
these are not direct useful cosmology
because these things is some structure that is you know some small-scale structure inside our
galaxy is a member of most of cosmology scalar galaxies that point but cosmology is
very interested in exploding stars
exploding stars cause supernovae this are very useful and we see at the very end
why basically because when this kind of stuff this for a very short time there
as bright as an entire galaxy and so you can see them are truly cosmological
distances you can see them almost to the edge of the universe
so that's really good way to work cell unit test
how do you know what is the geometry and the distribution of that universe
but just to see some poetry we are stardust
because as we see the primordial universe was made very light elements
so all the elements that make you me and everything you see around were created
inside stars and it's thanks to exploding stars that all this material was generating starts
with three distributed and then ended up forming galaxies planets you accept x
so just to get an idea
about the structure of galaxies are galaxies collection of you know between ten to the
eleventh the twelve start
and so this is the schematic view of the galaxy like our own milky way
so sold
there is typically about in the
and then there is that these on
and the that starts living here and here around
these in the bottom there are these blobs blob representing globular clusters these clusters of
about ten to the sixth stars and we're gonna see globular clusters again later on
this kind of scale is going to come out naturally from some of the arguments
these blocks you could here represent nearly spherical halo of dark matter
i'm showing these because today we know that most of the mathematics of the universe
is that it's not even made like stuff like me use computer stable and one
of the first evidences for the
the existence of a lot of unseen dark matter came actually from the study of
galaxies so that's why i'm going to show this here to introduce the concept
and nice image of the galaxy as we have seen before this could be not
too different from our own
and but there are also galaxies are much more irregular than than that this is
the learning cloud is this moment cloud but there are also galaxies that clearly undisturbed
in this case you see these tidal tail is probably underwent an interaction with some
other galaxy reputation interaction probably galaxies pass by and then formed identity love
of gas and stars
and here is another famous one distant galaxy because it looks like a sombrero and
this is the something of dust
and now
going to larger scale so this is a schematic representation of our local group is
our galaxy local neighborhood
so remember this galaxy was seen before in this graph just points and now when
we talk about this kind of scale we're entering the regime of of cosmology
so groups of galaxies is an example of a group of galaxies held together gravitational
you you know
three or four of those
but then
in a way
it is really
it's really this thing of of sampling from your posterior OK sort of looking what
are all the possible values of pi that you believe in
after you've combine your prior with the likelihood
now solving this integral for the two models we have to remember
this guy was the guy with the flat prior
and this guy was guy there was a bit more
optimistic in thinking that there might not be cheating right let's just remind ourselves what
model a and b is
so what so what do you expect which
which of the two models
do you think
is going to think that on average
OK let me try from the question but
which of the two models is going to give approach
of pi that is closest to one
it is
so so b
is more is still closer to half right
in other words
so we need a sort of but it's not an overwhelming difference right
so the whole thing here is that you
you have only observed one head but you don't believe that the probability
of heads is is is one just because you have done one experiment and came
out once right you believe something in the middle
now how quickly
you're gonna update your beliefs depends on how vague prior was
all right
so it's it's just nice to have this machinery available basically
OK so let me see
how we kind we have
three more slides about the coin
before we move on to something else rather quickly so
i think i'm going to skip this
because otherwise we don't manage to go through the rest of the
the thing is you can also have
this this prior things you can also have priors over models so instead of having
to choose between model and b
you could also say
on choosing you know i'm going to say that
i believe with a certain probability that that the model is correct and i believe
with some probability that will be correct what i mean with model is aiming the
prior that i'm choosing so imagine now two very extreme priors OK this is a
very very extreme prior this is the delta on zero five so this guy
it's completely convinced that the coin is fair
and actually the data to him is not going to is not going to matter
much right because when you compute the posterior is not going to change his opinion
right this prior cannot be changing anything by by by observing data
and this is our agnostic guy from the beginning who actually turns out not to
be some gnostic it's guy who sort of things that you know
there's a fair chance of the
it's bent
and now we observed
we make ten tosses and we observe two heads and eight tails
so now if i didn't want to choose one thing i could do is i
could either go with smaller i can go with this model but the other thing
i could do is i could actually say well
you know
if i if i have a prior that sort of says
that we the the probability
zero point eight
the coin is fair and then i have this of the guide the bendigo was
sort of things with twenty percent probability
it could be anything
i could not actually update
the i could basically i'm going to go through this quickly because there was never
going to make it to lunch OK so let's let's jump directly to this equation
so what i can do now
it's like i can actually compute
what my posterior belief on the on the model is OK
this isn't normalised so basically if you want to normalise it
what you get is you have to add
the two so this guide this will be two-thirds and this will be one third
so after observing the sequence we've seen
i now believe with probability
two thirds the coin is fair and with probability one third it's not fair anything
i wanted to make a prediction what i would do is i would combine the
two models
by waiting what they're going to say
by my posterior belief on the model itself being correct
so how does it work as it was two-thirds and one-third
and this is what both models would say the model that that has the piquancy
five is always going to say zero five right and the other one would say
three twelve and if you want later we can we can sort of work out
why if a toss the coin ten times and observe two heads and how this
flat prior how do i compute that number how do i get the the three
twelve OK and this is basically
the prediction i would make so what i want is
the point i want to make here is that
very often
in in bayesian modeling you end up being a hierarchy of priors on things OK
you sort of say
i have a prior on the number of
hidden units or whatever and then i have a prior on
once i have fixed that have a prior on on the values of the weights
and i can i can always sort of
average over those things eventually so i've been posteriors and i average over all these
OK so now i'm going to try to show some pictures before we go
for lunch
OK so
this is borrowed or stolen from radford neal's two thousand four
on bayesian
learning let's just give this slide because it's unpleasant let's move on to the slide
which is more pleasant
what the previous slide said was in equations what these slides so it's much better
to look at this level of zero
OK what does this slides
the slices says
and to do this innovation we need to understand how
so documents
and here see some progress in time
the time for a during
and in ancient egypt
what they had had only
presentation oriented text format
what does that mean it means that representation of the document was
it was some layout of the document
this layout is somehow connected real
information that we want to extract but it can be not connected with this information
at all
like in this example we have to call on document
we don't need to extract more
as one line what i call on everyone to extract it felt were from one
column then switch to another
presentation oriented former months and this is
all graphical format
and many old formats from
text processing
it's RTM it it's
talk format
PDF is a good example of this format
you you need to
you need additional special rules to to extract the linear form of document
later people discover that for computer presentation we don't need to be connected to with
we can be connected but it is not mandatory more in their lives
and you're four months they usually structure and so they presented some structure of the
document and
as far as i know the first popular format this as jimmy wales and
and to those of the former fish them out
x amount
and in this form until you have some some structure of the document
and usually
is it to the linearisation extraction war from
specific field with specific attributes from structure are in
but there are such people as web designer
they don't like people who the information available
and therefore
in their life in a game against different examples of of all this stuff
OK so we extract
works and we need to present them in memory of a computer or maybe they
related represented in our document but we need to put it into our in the
and for
index first of all we want to present all
letters of the alphabet
what this for this particular collection
and then
of course it's possible situation that in the whole collection there i five
usage of
the word naive
that is the reason these i was double doors and it's not relevant for you
and you can replace it is
even is wonderful it is OK
but usually you want to keep all letters of the alphabet
but for many languages in
four for many human languages for on communism
people are doing something more and more complex and so
theoretically they invented this case
to make life of information retrieval developed simply because using case theoretically we can easily
extract the beginning of the sentences
and beginning of the named entities because this is the name of somebody from capital
but in real life first of all
i don't know why but they're putting
capital and lowercase but there a
therefore usually people doing information they will simply ignore this attribute for church
but for information extraction they usually use it
for some languages again from for non reason
they decided that
there is no such simple rules
that what can be in capital cases in case in this case in its input
to replace this character this character
thinking that it should be
complex kalai two
and this is correlation
and correlation rules is
such a german-language for example you that
all this to all this round of
a one
it's one one letter and can replacing the one we can replace all there is
for example small
for some languages it it became
a disaster
for example for a bit
language of this long string
and well
we train on network layout which actually like that
the network of all wikipedia during about four weeks
was an increase in detroit size
and a lot of things
and after four weeks
we took the buildings produced and we initialize the second which model that we train
well wikipedia plus white
and it was against sri additional weeks of training
so after all this time
we looked at
the walls buildings
and they look actually pretty great the networks into really touch automatically you know some
good semantic there
so we just like
dogs is one of the things
the initial list of networks for the task you know like
part of speech
drinking water during shown
some ontologies and just train as usual i was
just by initializing by semantics
it's just a domain
but by the time is not that expensive because it's basically like to talk to
match the computational small because
it's due to the is almost one billion of examples
you could actually polarise it's usual did some know try to colonize it but you
know we we didn't want to mess with basically it's just place to train on
one computer
we have time today the computer slightly faster than ten years ago
so here we applied this things like two
on natural language processing task of interest
and as you can see it flight for
for all the test was really like a huge boost
we have an additional boost mainly on animosity entity organisation for the second
i mean the larger language model
this is not really surprising because when we look at the world gradually
again a lot with the second
so the language model
we may want to challenge
so well
we thought is always what it was it would start
but still you know we've got to see the whole presentation which like seemed to
work pretty well on all tasks so now knowledge
you know the next question is why no training everything together and see what happens
so that's what we did
squadron during training which does came
it it has been used a lot of the networks and you can find a
good value for our networks in ritz-carlton disease in ninety seven
it's again quite
basically what we are doing here is that we are considering for example to task
we all the networks two thousand and
so these networks can receive you know different inputs they like
but the parliament house
going to be shown
that is the parliament of this look at the words are the same than parliament
of statistical because they
and the obama does of the first hidden layer are going to be the same
as well
the idea so that i also like to get you know independent but the first
they also reassured
so we trained
is based ranking on any alltogether
and we have a look at what it
what does that
and basically what it does is that it gives a kind of significant boost for
and linguists would tell you that it's not surprising because
part of speech is often used as a good future for change
the other that he doesn't change anything because
now we have like a quite reasonable results for all tasks
but it's
of course you know there is always like
the temptation
we can always do likewise of people you know try to see if you know
if we this part of speech into this drinking does it help the if we
put the change into the semantic labeling just how simply so that's what we did
we consider actually like stemming as
good future for part of speech it's of you know it's always is actually part
of speech
we use only like the talk of a tool as characters
each one has an additional feature
we try to actually to use three or you know prefixes if was also exist
but did
it's mainly like that
two characters which were important to let's go
we consider actually get it tells that is like a list of names it's kind
of cheating i think node could everybody does that so we consider that form they
wanted the organisation
and there there is like about its eight thousand locations specimen organisations given actually by
the core and the challenge itself so you know everybody else use this
they that's i mean some years
the idea that but we stick to this simple one
we also tried part of speech as a future for drinking on them onto your
and so maybe
i got myself and committed to giving this talk
he told you told me that it's always like this
most of you heard of guantanamo he did all the studies with mister ski on
indicating that people don't reason normative
he won the nobel prize in two thousand two for prospect theory
give talk
two years ago
and the title of the talk to people really happy here in california
because of the weather and
now by see the weather here i think might be true is great weather
the talk was
it was very similar to the
the stuff did and with the people reason rationally wanted to know if
if people's reported happiness was the consistent with the actual experience of happiness and of
course he found that wasn't the case for instance
this research showed that divorced women tend to actually be happier married when know they
reported that were not as happy
you can think about cancer research obviously installing because i hate giving powerpoint presentations the
on the second one
the first one band miserable even though i had a lot of
animation and voice and everything is just i don't like the medium but let's let's
see how it goes
there's talk is called statistical causality and that's me that's my website
i could be talking about quite a notion of causality
and it's the notion that developed and these texts and other places to i just
you know found some places that i know about
it concerns variables influencing other variables
and since the smoking causes lung cancer so what do we mean by variables influencing
other variables
yes in population in this case people
is a random variable the population smoking is another random variable lung cancer
the more
people tend to smoke
as you indicate the more they get lung cancer so the value of one variable
probabilistic effect on the value of another
right that's that's the kind of causality etc etc so probably lung cancer driven by
smokesa being you manipulate them to smoke greater than the probability that they do not
it does not concern token causality which has to do with one-time events we have
no population
a classic example is the the gopher running into my golf will cause it to
go in the hole
they we don't have any population there is one golfing and
you know by balls going this way conference into goes in the hole and walked
right but is that is that the causal for use on skull token causality and
that's not what i'm discussing discussing the first time
here's what matters
what i was talking about a minute ago about
what kind of personality this is an formalizes
it's a common way to to always learn causality even if we don't find it
this way
and manipulation experiments
drug manufacturers to this all the time you take
seven people you put have to them in one group and half in the other
that's the manipulation in other words
the probability of being manipulated to be in one group is point five probably be
manipulated to be in the other group is point five
so you've got this people broken up into two groups
everybody in group one
you make small
the probability smoking given you one is one
everybody here knows this notation conditional probability
it's the probability of this event given that this one takes the value
and the problem smoking given that smoking this with the two stands for example
giving your in group is zero so everyone everyone smokes
everyone in group two
it was not small
smoking causes lung cancer
group one
we have a higher incidence of lung cancer in group two
and the more that's true
the greater the extent to which group one has
and this the incidence of lung cancer the more we believe smoking causes
one can search
so that's classically learning causation and that's how drug companies do it all the time
they want to see if the drug is across the
and some cure and they do manipulation experiment
i know we don't really want to manipulate people and make them smoke i mean
there's a certain
kinds of experiments you really don't want to do
especially in this country trying to eliminate smoking almost no no i can't smoke anywhere
starting january first
virtually no
so can we learn something about causal influences from passive data some people have other
words for the i passive data means
data you just mine data that you don't
purposely created in anyway
also smoking example again
from passive data
we've learned that smoking and lung cancer are correlated
and that's the zero here this line here means correlation
now that could be due to smoking causes lung cancer
right so much smoking causes lung cancer like i just said they would be correlated
so from this data
i want to conclude that smoking causes lung cancer
is smoking and lung cancer correlated it could be the reverse
people go along cancer that kind pick of smoking
because of the domain that seems so all right that this was just x and
what seems so slowly
i don't know of one case of is actually from the man and woman who
have one cancer and quit smoking but then she found out she was terminal
which is an amazing out smoking and so in her case the
she really care no advanced lung cancer she started smoking so in that case it
can actually cause the a small token almost all
but the point is that this is just the x and y from the correlation
smoking causes lung cancer lung cancer smoking we don't know
and the other common explanation is that could have a hidden common cause
the understanding of why this would correlate smoking and lung cancer is essential to understanding
this talk
if two events have a hidden common cause they tend to be correlated
why is that because if you smoke
it makes it more probable you have this causes which makes it more probably would
also have one cancer
so there might be correlated through this through this change