OK welcome to
september first
my name is dave fly
i'm going to talk about a topic models
i'm from books and from princeton university
in new jersey
where it's four o'clock in the morning
and so
this is what it's going to look like to teach at four in the morning
OK and please interrupt me a lot in this talk so that it will help
stimulate me to wake me
OK good so
what topic modeling is about
is that as
you all know is almost redundant for more information becomes available to us it becomes
more difficult for us to be able to quickly
access it and search for things in it and understand it and basically get something
out of it
and so we need new tools new algorithmic tools to help us organize search and
understand these vast amounts of information things like text archives and image archives and all
different kinds of data that we're all just for creating and having access to constantly
with a topic modelling provides are methods for automatically organizing understanding searching summarizing exploiting these
large electronic archive and the basic idea
are is is these three steps first we take a big corpus like wikipedia as
a and uncover the hidden topical patterns that pervaded so
wikipedia has got some number of millions of articles and there are about some things
those things overlap and we want to uncover what those things are what of the
different topics that pervade this collection
then we we want to annotate the documents according to the topics so i understand
what say you know two hundred and fifty topics in wikipedia are now if i
plot the document out of wikipedia what topics is that article about how can i
edited that article according to the topics they discovered in step one
and finally we want to use these annotations to organise summarize and do whatever it
is we want to do obviously actually but doing this in a vacuum is only
so interesting we really want to say OK now that i've been able to my
essentially markup my collection according to these automatically found topics i want to use that
markup collection
you can think of it as if i had
ten million people to go through wikipedia and carefully organised it then what i do
with their organisation since i don't have those ten million people i build algorithms to
do that one
this is backwards it's the same
have almost hit by cars about six times already
the same idea OK
so we can do with it
with topic models things like discovery
topics from a corpus so here are some topic so a topic is going to
be a distribution over terms in the vocabulary and these are the top most probable
terms and for topics that were uncovered by analyzing the text in in the journal
science so here's a topic human genome DNA genetic evolution evolutionary
species organisms disease host bacterial diseases computer models information data computers these are words that
seem to go together in some kind of semantic thematically coherent way but i should
say that part of this talk probably on thursday we're going to discuss the pitfalls
of overly interpreting these
probability distributions over words but for now since we're learning about it we can pretend
like those pitfalls don't exist and interpret them so
these are for topics discovered from the journal science
the there is no good reason not to stand
so you know sometimes stemming i mean when i when i feel the topic models
sometimes i use stemming it can be when you're looking at these topics if you're
doing this for like a system for someone to be able to to quickly browser
navigator documents some stemmers can be overly with word aggressive and you can't really recognise
the rights that they
but they get back but then there's one that i know my student likes
i can remember what it's called but it's more conservative stanford just it will remove
things like computer computers
but now there's something is a good idea
other questions
things like so discovered topics discovering topics in understanding how the words change how within
the topic through time so here are here is time from eighteen eighty until two
thousand and here two different topics that i've named again ignoring the pitfalls of naming
topics and here are some words on those topics and and see how their probability
is changing over time can we can uncover this time changing topics with topic models
we can model connections between topics so
here again are lists of words that we are interpreting topics and again this is
from science
ask label for in order to learn the most about this database
and this you is interfaces for search engines based on this
now question i'm going to push the idea for because active learning when we reach
active learning we start looking at decisions
and in this case i was being myopic about my decision to not what i
was only looking one step ahead
to make this is sometimes i want to make plans look several steps ahead
in order to make the best decision
so if i have a clinical trial one to consider
all the events that could happen when i bring to patients and to determine when
to best administered drugs
this problem tend to be actually some of the hardest character
and chapel will be talking to you about reinforcement learning which is a way of
doing this
i will introduce you
u two
simulation to solve some of these problems so i'll just basically for the next few
minutes just described two case studies
so icon
so can you pick up like
hot coupling
can europe the question i'm struggling to understand
we get no repeat
you know it
this is such a radical neighbors
i mean you see is that arise from
if you want to write
OK thanks for the question so
the question is
if we have the that graph
he's asking do i start from the local interactions and
and in particular
the range and then move on to these
the answer is no
what you might do is to try to look at the strongest correlations in the
potentials and try to build the spanning tree to weighted spanning tree for those
and then you add
edges that your questions are very good one because how you constructed graph
you construct this graph the beautiful thing because you have a dynamic system is you
can construct this graph by adding edges and when you encounter trouble
the importance weights divergence something you can backtrack
and you can grow some other different way
and you can even do some sort of planning to decide how you're going to
grow and you can have different heuristics and play with them
and in fact that's what's done
in the field of protein folding using monte carlo methods
they do exactly that sort of thing
how to construct the graph is tricky it's not there is an optimal way using
one among the techniques and i'm going to describe the problem is that those techniques
are too expensive
so this is sort of a
trade trade-off
because you're coupling partners
and we wanted to be the best porn stars on the web
the title of the page
well the reason is why we actually don't had to the the edges
the details this i'm trying to just give you a taste of it is supposed
to go into the details when we have an edge we just don't add the
network to note but we do that by by raising the temperature
we any of the agent
that way that all the edges are here
or some of the edges
this different games we use
the protein folding one is important actually there's a lot of work
to be done there because the connect the idea which is how you grow the
sequences and how you across right to self avoiding changed to concentrate on the prose
regions of high probability
it's quite it's quite an interesting research
the area
more to come soon
OK so here's an example
i wanted to some control examples of something before we go
and slow down a bit
you want to go
the beach
you have a rough map in your head
of what that wooden bridge is
so what i five and machine learning do actually need solve any of those problems
i'm going to claim that will need any new type of machine learning
i was showing before r
low those problems are really
known problems in some form
however there is specificity which is
pertinent to the three data and network traffic
which unit cell
and also there is the question about
where these things are actually operating what is our infrastructure how do they sleep with then
decisions on what to build what algorithms should be applied
applying and there's also of a really dependent on
this kind of infrastructure implementation issues
the problems are trying to solve
so missed out
by saying we
more let's try to apply machine learning the social networks that there is a social network
you like
and this a social network where lv information comes in the form of text
what the really
tell us i mean doesn't stop
we probably can get away
with using fairly simple models
and what can i say about
well is like a long long long line of of
research papers
both by
people academia and industry
which tend to show that formal problems involving text thanks
and especially large quantities of text
it pays off to use fairly simple models
which can actually brought lot of data
rather than concentrating on
complex models which most likely really cannot handle data at all in the first one
and you actually can tell they that they
accuracy gaze up small
they actually exist about
the second plane
which is probably more important is
we want to use
machine learning for social networks in a way which is really easy use
not everybody is a machine learning experts and even not everybody's data sciences
so if people want apply those models need to be able to apply them in
a way which fits with their day-to-day
dealing with data
if you know
user of some kind of baltic pipeline you probably have york
o to settle things like today you know how to do
and to the extent you would like to play with models
you want to be able to integrate them very easily
and last is the key
requirement for making this happen
machine learning for social network of course social networks
as the name suggests graphs
but is graph processing really requirement out say
the existence of graphs really provide an asset whatever we do it necessarily hard requirement
for whatever machine learning want to plot
it really stems from the power of the social graph so the guys are connected
by users usually
for purpose and the signal propagation in the graph
that's the bring relevance so when we apply simple models
over a graph the aggregation over the graph increases the power those models
making them more accurate
so the plus
now the real requirements scalability so we scale all the data we have
and all that they were going out
with the scale they
time of the data
arrivals suppressing over data streams
and we need to update is mostly fast
straightforward adaptation buildings together
and you get a bunch of engineers and researchers and scientists in the room
the natural tendency is to
built a lot of stuff which is called the thing up
yes i mean possible to build everything from scratch
but what the real benefit in doing so we probably will actually be able to finish anything
there are questions are
i mean what do actually need to build
in our infrastructure to make it happen
and how can we possibly
re-use existing staff from wherever it comes
social buildings the link low-level machine learning libraries feature extraction pipelines
maybe they distributed processing platforms
maybe the good cold
the whole visualization called so support
so the the kind of the questions which naturally come to mind and it can be answered
in order to build a real system
so forcefully
when we started looking at this problem
we're not operating in a vacuum
to some extent the answers are constrained by
whatever infrastructure was already in place
just the shows some of the things which are
operating in our pipeline
it's how apache hadoop essentially
at with a lot of fun surrounded
so they
the languages such as scala and java and pick
there's things which make it past the happen such as
me cells and zookeeper
and tell stories components such as founder and those based on full support
so those things provide real
constraints to how it gets built
naturally we decided about
we want to capitalize on the use of of the
so they can be processes in
in many different ways
but because our analytics pipeline already produces everything do
wanted really did everything had the best well especially is
as fitting into the map reduce process
was pipeline operates
using one particular
technology called
so for those who don't know
what about much about pages because they a high-level data-flow language
the people right mapreduce jobs with
it is much easier to
work with big
there were working
with the low-level java code for example
so wanted to integrate our pipeline as close as possible if they
to make it easy for users take two years
the end
we wanted to avoid certain processes that
from the height say
and that's a hundred metres
let's calculate how long it takes for example
two hit which for you will be trail of course
yes the
the mass of the earth
it's about six times ten to the twenty four kilogrammes
you edit distance h
which will take a hundred metres
it is apple and
it's a
has amassed a half kilogram
there is a force
from the earth on three apples
this is that forces
the magnitude of that forces and g
and that is
five new
i think you can strike of little
how long
does it take
this object to it
so we know
one half
GT squared
because h
doesn't start with an initial
that's hundreds
these standards five for career
about four and a half
so after four and a half seconds it's too so far so good
according to the
the earth must experience exactly the same force as the apple does
but in opposite directions
so therefore
the first
the same force f
five newton in this direction
what is the earth going to do
well this is going to fall
towards the apple
as he calls them a
the fourth
the earth
the mass of the earth
i'm acceleration over here
cause we know five
know the mass six times ten to twenty four
five i six times ten to twenty four
it is about eight times ten to the minus twenty five
the second square
how long will the earth well there's was willful roughly four and a half seconds
they collide
how far was move into four and a half seconds
well it moves one half
the square
the distance that it moves
we know a
and we notice create which is twenty one halftime twenty years ten
so that means this distance
becomes that number times ten is about eight
times ten to the minus twenty four meters
move eight times ten to the minus twenty four meters
that of course is impossible
to measure
just imagine
what a wonderful concept this is
when this ball
o back to factory
and i m i t
falling towards the ball
every time the ball comes down
we're falling towards all measure but i have overview an overview
you may want to think about this
if i throw the ball up
going to be away from
i bet you anything useful also go away from all
so as i do this
believe me that gordon was feeling it is
this is going down is coming first the ball
was going down and part of the earth
i'm shaking of that
i simply
was this form
that is the consequence
newton's third law even though
the amount by which the earth move is of course too small
to be measured
i now want to work out with you
a rather detailed example
of something in which we combined
what we've learned today
down to earth first problem
the kind of the problem
that you
your exam
or site
an object
on two strings
in one string
makes an
of sixty degrees
with the vertical
and you are makes an angle of forty five degrees of food
so this is the one
that makes an angle
sixty degrees with right
thirty degrees with the vertical
and this one
forty five degrees
let's assume that the strings of negligible mass
so to test here to the ceiling
and i have a new object
there's an object
there will be a force
gravitational force
this object is hanging there's not being accelerated
the net
acceleration must be zero
and so one string must be pulling in in this direction and you string must
be pulling in this direction so that the net force on the system is zero
let's call this pool
for now t one
recall that the tension in the string
and we call the attention industry
the question now is the largest one
and how large is
t two
various ways you can do this
one way that's always works pretty safe
you call this
x direction
you may choose which direction you call i call this plus
i call these negative
and you could call
this why direction you make all this plus
and is negative
i know from newton's
the second law
f equals m a
that there is no acceleration so this must be
so to sum of all forces on that mass must be zero
the three forces must each are up so to speak
well if that's the case then the sum of all forces in the x direction
must also be zero because there is no acceleration in x rection
and the sum of all forces in the y direction must be
so i'm going to decompose and something we've done
before going to decompose the forces
in two
x and into a y direction
the x component of t one
its magnitude
sixty one
times the cosine
of sixty degrees
i want to know what this
one is
this one
if you want
of sixty degrees
this projection
first of all what they say is if you have
a structure like this
anywhere even in
OK so this is the example so you can do this
rule here left push tells us that this
so it says that we can get this
from this we those as well
so the proof goes down in the end the way you construct the proof
you start at the bottom and say how can i get this new to you
build up and by the length of the the error
left and right to left
i know that you sometimes use terms
right left and right arrows are what we are raised
and i was looking down
OK now
roman to the
reject k
because k tells us that if we
structure so we had just get
from that we can get
and what we want to build up to
OK i know i posted to do working up but this is show you it
shows us that if we have any here we need right here
to get from
i think it is different from that
we can get this from there
and end up with
our the paradox
it tells you bring your premise
the real relevant and not
and it can
and implication
right so k is something is ruled a relevant logic but intuitions
as much effect on the big list everything that there are axes except to emissions
so intuitionist logic
or without again because we're not talking negation is the sort of maximal system we
can look at
not quite the logic because once again purses law we talked about is not derivable
what is not derivable but
so what
how do we get
relevance logic well we get relevant logic or something pretty close
with this
with control strong contraction
it's too sensitive roles
start coming to
but it doesn't give us all rolled what's missing
but once again this annoying thing distribution
distribution is something we can prove
with this
and that's fairly not just talk about the system
with the distribution and the proof i've given use for and once
this system
but without
and the red star system with the distribution of and with negation
distribution is kind of pain right i mean we've seen already the pain in the
system and i showed you ross brady is way dealing with that with getting his
streams approach is quite an elegant way of of dealing with
back in the nineteen seventies
in developing sequent calculus
relevant law
mike dunne and a russian mathematician named romance
developed by the
developed very similar
so the one rascist and more recently
but it's different interests
what they did was they distinguish between the same and well
connecting premises
and karma
and the comma is more like the conjunction you know not
so they think of conjunctive premises and sort of
rather it is
or more intense and more intentional form of finding premises
which we call fusion but i'm not going to fusion for that
now called the common
louise for extensional
once again
so that looks like just like the
with a comoros replacing
a semi called the same thing with
now this is a weak form of commutativity one you used to
living things around
this is a weak form contraction
most play
as of the form k
you can
so does that for us
well if we can so this tells us
if we had actually like this embedded anywhere in the bigger structure or by itself
we could
replace it with just the same and so on
OK that allows us to prove
the contractual allows us to prove distribution
and the proof is become long
and i thought that are in you know it's
now the interesting right
it's not by accident the ross
we have a complicated problems with belief probably session is terrible trying to find a
and that's been well known for a long time
they all scale
pretty badly when
when you really get lots of perturbation and of course that makes sense in the
sense that what is the shape the shape when when when when i don't want
to mess things well when the very different so i guess you would expect a
performance to always be perfect when you have significant perturbations anyway
so what we do is going just remind you we measure the percentage correct assignment
as a function of the perturbation
of the positions or orientations or whatever it into in this in the same
is a practical one
well actually to what we do a lot of work in that division
i'm not if use some people to think about
the mapping industry the cartography industry is a multi-billion dollar industry
most countries have given up
being able to update maps
you can afford it
was eighty percent of the cost in any
making and that is not in the satellites it's not in the
gps sinus camera sitting in place
it's in human labor
they need drastically really advanced techniques to help
my computer writing techniques that will help cartographers
do not happen quickly and a big problem mapping is corresponds to have already typically
now training about data
so you have to align what's there with with new data and then and on
so it's a very good example we have one approach is going to play just
go and this is the typical situation where trying to update roads
i want to be do here is partition rajinder segments
and then i'm trying to match those of and this is really the sort of
performance to say that relaxation methods loopy belief or to strike legislation enabling from pretty
single pass goes really well and i you expect
i'm adding more neighborhood information more information about the clique potentials
arm or what more
more richer clicks and the potentials and performance goes up in this case ninety percent
and this is quite a difficult task although there is no benchmarking on this because
this the practical the practical problems
it comes up
but show you how powerful is exact
so i don't want to develop the money
go to more on this stuff
what's the stuff is when you're trying to think of structural pattern recognition as one
of matching discrete graphs
with larger graphs
attributes are not
i think we've been we had two hours yesterday and now this morning and i
have just convinced you
that in fact that there are committed is going to be doing the same type
of logic applies
you know
of all the spectral
least squares
and bayesian formulations
that at the moment the junction tree approach seems to be the best approach
not only because this provably optimal because because because it seems to be robust even
when they get quite significant perturbations and in particular when we're trying to find small
things in large things
this is often the problem in computer vision
and we you can't afford to say move the window
the piece wise do this
so we got a polynomial but there's also nothing you can say that this stuff
is quite quite useful so what else
so we go to
the governments now
well not really because this is in some sense of still being giving you a
pretty simple problems
i have also known explore here how we can use the same type of thinking
in the context of the basic supplies for many different tasks in understanding spatial modeling
not just matching
so now i'm going to generalize what we spoke about
two really some really case study
one do
this sort of comment on this case study
the show you how
a lot of modern computer vision people image understanding people GIS people spatial data people
and they are thinking the bayesian way
about inference
right from
image encoding
o two matching sings to three d models
and even computer graphics
we'll have a little bit of a sub division into stochastical systems
so that's my task now just to give you a sort of a final
situatedness time situation
you in this new literature
but i think it's got tremendous
so now go back to canada where it came from
seven months ago in western canada
we've been involved for the last four years in the project with the
federal provincial government and the company i'm trying to improve forestry inventory
well canada has one third of the world or forest
but presumably you want to say anything about the color of
you know this block one pick it up
so if we don't say anything about the colour that means that we're i trying
to figure out what the color the block is
after doing a sequence of actions i won't be able to conclude whether it's white
or not white
can conclude anything about colourable
in other words i really need to write some information then about how the colour
the block is affected by each of these actions
so the frame problem really boils down to
describing those parts of the state
that changed by any enemy reaction
OK now
does that sound counterintuitive
that's absolutely right that's the exact and that's what we want
but what of the planet trying to make is that if we don't write that
in first order logic
then we can draw that conclusion
so the
as someone trying to point out is that
in a sense the problem with using first order logic of you don't want to
view it is the problem it's something that you're going to have to take care
of if you use first order logic
so what you said makes perfect sense
if i have an action
and the action has absolutely no
you know nothing to do with the columns so pick up has presumably them into
the column
then i would say i should have to say anything about i should just naturally
assume that nothing stays the same help
and that's exactly the problem that if we don't write something down about that in
logic i cannot draw that conclusion because there's no way
well is this why after i do these actions all have actually describe that
how the whiteness of this object is affected by these actions are not affected so
i can say anything about what is
and that's the whole point of this lecture but you know this problem is essentially
the thing the main thing to get out of this lecture is one thing is
going to have to describe and sort of counterintuitive has said the reason i ask
that question at the beginning is because i really do think that if you look
at this set of things
you know then i think it's really quite reasonable to assume that that should be
sufficient to describe this problem
and the thing is that that's not sufficient just writing stuff down the describes these
is not sufficient for logic to be able to
reason about
OK now i'm going to fix this problem so how we can have think might
fix this problem
i think there are two
ways of doing
and i want to show you can get
let's give it again
anything he might fix this problem
one way is on the board
which is we write more stuff
the right order
and the other way to do it would be to change the logic that we're
using sonar not perhaps use first order logic right
if you remember back to what i said about nonmonotonic logics in the previous lecture
so that trying to capture this notion of common sense reasoning and in particular
they try and sort of characterizes topper this is this should normally be the case
so he muses normally fly for sorry it birds normally flies i don't really know
anything more
then i'm going to assume they fly if i'd like something like the
but in a new then i'd like to withdraw the conclusion and if i learn
something for the like for instance extract jetpack to their back then i might even
change the conclusion again
so one possibility is to replace first-order logic with
some four nonmonotonic logic which makes exactly this assumption that you said and it's often
referred to as the common sense principle of inertia
in the common sense principle inertia says that
in the absence of any other information
something had that's a particular color in one state
if there is no reason for me to
i suggest that changed i'm going to assume that stays the same
so if the pick action doesn't say anything about the colour of the object
i could try and use the nonmonotonic logic to say that the
color is then carried over to the next day next next as long as the
actions that are applied and not
actions that can change the colour like a painting action or something like that
OK so it's sort of two ways of doing things right more down
change the logic
now what i'm going to write more down but we're going to look at the
way of
coming up with the stuff i need to write down
by making the this
common sense principle of inertia assumption
that if the effects don't say anything about a particular property so if the effects
of an action that say anything about the color of the cap
then i'm going to see the colour the cap
remains the same in the next day
OK now what we need these frame axioms and is that we're going to try
to automatically come up with frame axioms but frame maxim just something that says
a statement about things that stay the same so the first one he just says
the colour effect
what is the colour ecstasy in a particular situation if i did the point action
i put the object somewhere in the colour remains c
one problem is that of course you know you may have
many actions and each action like any effective fuel the flaunts
OK so the one problem is that we're going to need a lot of these
frame axioms because there's a lot of stuff that doesn't get changed by by action
OK let's just take just to slight digression
the frame problem is anyone of the reasoning problems it's introduced when you first order
there are two other ones one's called the classification problem and the other one is
called the ramification problem
so the qualification problem which is the the lower half of the slide is the
what we said that we can pick up an object if
changing the frequency of the green one and all
and then of course the green one goal
so you see also here apart from the fact that it's nice to
he now the idea that there point standing still
they have name we call the nodes
and there is system is also leading now
in the third
the natural frequency
we only excited in one
i'm not sure i got all the lights on the
when we have a violin string
or another string on cello
eight whatever
there is no such thing like someone who is vibrating at the end so you
have to make it vibrate
and you do that by having the ball
so effectively robs history
and when you run it
that is
sort of the same as saying to this string
do whatever you like
and what the string like this
and that
and that doesn't like anything in between so what strange is now going to do
if you just it
or even if you
like it or even if you would hit with a hammer which is what you
do with the piano hammer comes down on the string that's all that happened was
the piano it then
it starts to oscillate simultaneously
the combination of these harmonics in general
the lowest
we can see is the strongest
the first time on in general but not always
that depends on where you would block it
now comes the question
how do you tool in
people have a violin maker one play
you may have noticed that the it
well there's nothing they can do about the weight the food of the strings four
strings of the violin that's against
so that they cannot change that
the length is fixed
a violin the length of the city so the only thing they can change his
and that's exactly what they do you may have noticed that and when we see
later the demonstration of the violin will ask the person to to
they did they turn these knobs
change the tension in the listen
he he and they
and they don't all four strings
so you have to learn a string instrument
by changing the tension
was the and it would be hopeless
so there you hope that it is properly to the piano is eighty eight keys
how do you play an instrument
was violin wanted properly tuned
the only thing you can do now if you want to make every tone that
you would like to
you can only change the length and you change the links by putting your finger
on the string
and making a string shorter and longer if you take this train
and you put your finger on here who supported here
then the fundamental
has a lower link and the lowlands remember
higher frequency so you get a higher tone so as the violin player moves the
finger in one and the same string will produce
high tone and that's the way you play it it's an amazing thing when you
come to think of it all the time you got to move the fingers in
and out to always get that says that the right length
and if you just off by a little bit it sounds awful
you don't have the problem with the piano
you go being and
right just the right tone
again being sold as a whole different ball game playing piano not saying the piano
playing easier because you don't know which is the key to push but in any
case you don't have to adjust all the time the length
of the of the strings
in principle
you could
design and
string instrument whereby you do change the tension
and there is such an instrument with one string
the person place it
with the ball
and as the person plays it
he or she changes the tension all the time
and when my daughter was three years old which is a long time ago
if you build such an instrument
this is one
this is the box
and this is one three
and when you put this on here
i will not strike admissible we go through that only three hands now and i
only have two
but i will
and then you will hear
i can markets
and change the tension by moving this to the right i increase the tension on
the strings you hear high tone then when the tension is low
link is not change
the weight per foot does not change without attention is changing
listen carefully
so in principle you could design an instrument and they do exist the value chain
tension all the time
and that of course
a lot of practising
so instead of changing the link
the chains attention
all right
so far
so good
on our string instruments
it's going to be more difficult
before we demonstrate the string instruments
i want to discuss with you
wind instruments
these probability distribution is very general is actually the generalized
it generalizes cost by no multinomial possible gamma ray
we show and several other types of distributions
so it's convenient to work with them in the very very convenient from the optimisation
point because it looked like
of those
the function of probability distribution and the exponential families
he's concave of the negative log likelihood is convex
so you can actually solve that optimisation problem
efficient because it can be a convex optimization problem
which is the case here
it's convex function so that the challenge is to help prove the design other size
you can try to prove that these
the the
prostitution the
partition function is
is a convex function this log partition function g of it is the name of
this object
and the like
the negative log like is also
and the the same game to the optimisation OK take the gradient set to zero
and this is what you think
so let me tell you what is is
this is essentially telling you that
the gradient of the log partition function
for the maximum likelihood estimate is equal to the
expectation of the sufficient statistics
with respect to the distribution
you can be sure that
what's the
the big question here because if you wanted to optimisation you need to compute the
gradient of function
full the gradient do some type of gradient descent
convex function you're going to compute gradient to reach the minimum of the function
computing the gradient of the function involves computing the gradient of these g of heat
which is the complicated part of the great because this is linear
this is the linear function of theta so computing the gradient is just the function
of ft
but computing the gradient of these obvious to be more complicated and requires compute these
what's in expectation its estimation
this is the summation of of these objects
of the sufficient statistic with respect to this peak
of x and people so if this p of x these factorizes
you have some of the factors
guess what you get
the distributive law again you can compute
these expectations efficiently if you have three or you have a chordal graph well
you can compute this is
in other words
the maximum likelihood estimate
must be such that the expected value of the sufficient statistics this distribution
for every clique has to match the sample average of
it's a very intuitive notion
the same way as what's the maximum likelihood estimate for
the average of one gaussian distribution is just the average of the sample
in this problem is a convex problem
how the show is a convex problem essentially you need to show that the log
partition function
is convex
we have g
this court here g
g of theta is the log of this function is convex
it to show that
only show that you just take the second derivative of this function
with respect to the initial positive everywhere
in particular issue
people if you have
back to if the thing in this case in the general case of factors who
this second derivative
here this will be a matrix right because the number first three with you will
be the gradient vector second derivative will be the hessian matrix
and that has to be positive semidefinite
which is the equivalent of positive numbers for multi
the mission objects for
so basically you we need to show that
the two
g of to
the a
positive semi
good exercise
so this is very nice this function is convex
and then you can solve exactly the optimisation problem OK
the here i have written a particular instantiation four keyser have multinomial reliables what tool
just keep these equations here because
it's just more technical stuff in know this
pull tarts
so let's
for the last part which is
what we do when
we have
learning with older in the wild
first how we learn the potential functions when we have observed the doctor for all
divided into my
and second rule see how do we learn the potential functions
when you have lead-in fighter so he didn't like the
first case
i want to learn the model
love parameters
and i have
observations of my in time
so for example
let's assume i have i want to learn a particular model
are images
i observe one sample of speech
one observation of speech which is
an entire set of nodes are being observed one old correspond to this part of
speech part of speech the first sample o thing it's an entire observation of my
down here the
here the most frequent cascades
we know that stars stars are more common than chains and seven out of the
ten most frequent cascades and the
in the original data match ours
so we know so here's the data are represented by circles of the model is
represented by the dashed line
so we have real that cascade size distribution cascade in degree size stars in the
side chains so this is pretty pretty surprising results
this is a course
is the last
this means
all this
he was just this
i my my guess is that most of the
currently the pass along ones turn out be stars
because if i see video i might not really add anything to it
so if i link to it my friends is that they they might or might
not actually link to my blog
the i is that what happens in
how much do or violates
based on
are you a thousand years ago people better at in our
that's an interesting question and
i'm not not sure that i a
knowledgeable about the content some of people in this room might be so
my background is in this these structure structural ideas and i know that it's very
it's it's blind it's blind to a lot of the content and i think that
too to really do a lot of these things we want to use both structure
and content
are we
right that's kind of what we're going for is that we
we realize that the drawback of this is that we're already assuming this
built in the blog network we know who is linked to in the past
so we make this assumption that will somebody's link somebody they probably read his blog
a regular basis and so therefore we
probably want to use that that knowledge when
that knowledge we're actually
generating our cascades
as last
so far
right right
this some early workers we're trying to identify some general patterns and then
and build upon
of higher order correlations
o or in other words nonlinear correlations they are
you can you can measure them by some good by looking at
looking at
correlations of covariances of someone non-linear transformations of these components
then the question is that what kind of changes would be useful here well we
will see in a couple of sites with michael
yes and
one way of using these dependencies there needs to
these are by is to define some kind of topographical order that something like in
a self organizing map
so that's you would say so that's or actually you could it smallest like defining
using these dependencies to define some kind of dissimilarity that you can then import to
any kind of visualization and well we have more details of this
so the idea is when we
if i use this idea of topography
the point is that we
that we assign each other components into into a location on the lattice which might
be two-dimensional in the the basic case
this is just in just the same way as as in a self organizing map
is alcohol
now the point is that
we define the model so
that's components
so that is the goal of sort of the components are dependent
the closer the other more dependent the closer they are on this topic
so companies that are far from each other on the topography or more-or-less independent so
which are close to each other on the topography creates dependent
so we have actually to we could actually use two different approaches either we
smallest like to ICA first and then we visualize the components by
ordering them on this kind of the topography
so now we would at each node here then we would then somehow not representation
of each component
but the but the more principled way
one is to define the probabilistic statistical model which has this property that
so far components which are far away from the top of the independent and then
there's not that close to each other somehow dependent
then we have again we have the problem that we can not we can never
talk about dependencies in general i mean well it is it's very difficult to define
model where we just says components and and and then we have to choose what
kind of dependencies we actually modelling
well we have some words that the more
no the son of the linear components
we don't know we don't have yet subspaces
i mean it just the components is not the subspace but just linear components
the intensity images
so in terms of these in terms of image image features
each other each other knowledge will be just one of these windows
which one each of these windows is one linear components one linear basis vector in
the linear decomposition
how that actually in moment
but the one thing that that remains from all
all these previous models of images well i'm talking about images again but this is
this framework can be applied to other kinds of data as well but in the
i assume smoothness each manifold
so that's what we wanted
so the building block is actually this
if you have a lot of unlabelled data we're zooming onto the dollar signs up
zooming on part of it
if you have a lot of unlabelled data
and if you look at
the neighborhood of any anybody to point and you compute the covariance matrix there
that shape actually tells you something about
the manifold structure so here you will see this
sort of flat pancakes but they gradually curve and this vertical pancakes somewhere in the
middle they will have because you have
points from both manifolds the covariance structure will be more likeable
so the idea is to say that we can measure this week actually see which
kind of pancakes go together
and one particular measure can use so-called hellinger distance
it's between two distributions p and q
it's it's a nice distribution it's kind of like
kl divergence but is symmetric and the actually lower bound scale
it's easier one
and well so
if you have two
covariance matrices you can
the hellinger distance there to be the distance from the
normal distribution with that covariance matrix that gives you a nice closed form solution which
only involves those covariance matrices
and here's the intuition
if you have two
the covariance matrices
and i'm showing the hellinger distance here
the distance here is small because these two of not identical they are somewhat similar
this one is bigger
and they actually have the same covariance except that this one has a larger variance
also it's more big
if the pancakes the covariance matrices differ by dimensionality you actually have a very large
as well as if you they have a slightly different orientation then you get that
very large distance
and what we can do now is to
instead of measuring
the graph
instead of connecting two unlabelled data points where the edge weights is
related to the euclidean distance
now let's do this
with the distance
between their corresponding covariance matrices
so that the intuition is if they
pancake around
they will be connected with a large
hatch weight
and if you do this for example the dollar sign
you have agianst this is the k nearest neighbour graph edges like this where red
means large actuate and yellow means small edge weight
as we hoped
this will give you more edge weights when the different types of manifolds cross each
and that's
good because then we can separate out different manifolds
this should be fun
the and machinery
why do we want to ask the question whether human performance so much was learning
or not
again as the example
we gave before
i think children really
learn by e
combine both supervised
teaching and unsupervised observation from the world and it would be really nice too
see whether humans can
make use of those kinds of information
so we'll be discussing two
psychology studies
that has some flavor of some unsupervised learning
one is in the setting of a single class
the is in binary classification
so the first study i want to connect this to others self training
and basically we want to
show that
test data
actually changes
you're underlying classifier
so instead of
and learning algorithm now we have participants there the ground by the way
that's how do psychologists study u
they have to take a class for credit part of the classes to participate in
some psychologists study
on the ground you think of them as learning
and we're going to make them
former task that's very similar or we can formulate that as learning task
so here's the first experiment
we're going to give
each participant
the training set
of l labelled data points
but these elderly points all come from
class one so it's a single class prob
it's just class one
and then
later on
if i tell you where the object is with the pendulum i gave you the
initial angle
my data zero i tell you ready object is
so you know actually b
i tell you what's been i gave it so you know this one
you can calculate what the maximum display exactly the same idea
and if you want to apply to work energy theorem of course
you'll get exactly the same results this is in fact the same thing
so let's now
thirty two
universal law
of gravity
and believe it or not
i think i even gave you only exams
the gravitational force
newton's universal law
i don't think you need to you will find it on the example
that's the idea is going around the sun
and that's approximate orbit by
here is the US
here's the son last summer
and were two
radius is capital are
the earth has an orbital
college v
all the time
there is on the object the angular velocity is a
goes around certain
thank you
and it has to be
the force on the system
the gravitational force
it is the same as the
centripetal force that's the only way he object to go around
in a circle holding gravitational force
called mass of the sun
mass of earth
times g
divided by our screens
the force of gravity
but it also must equal
so centripetal
acceleration and this year
the my
and so it also is
the mass of of the earth
i'm orbital speed
this grid divided by orbital radius
and if you prefer to write that
in terms of omega screen are
that's fine too
OK this year
you know this year
earth masses if you want to know what your little speedos
you lose one are
and so you find that you to be equals the mass of the the sun
times g
divided by or
the power
one half
and that is about
thirty kilometres per second
given in kilometres per second but of course
when you calculate it make sure you always the MKS before you make
conversion to other units
so you know the period is to go around
the sun
that is to are
divided by d orbital
and that's about three hundred sixty
five and a half days that's one year following takes us to go wrong
the sun
now i wonder what is the kinetic energy
the earth
in orbit around
the sun
well that's completely trivial you would say because
it is one of
the mass of the earth
times the orbitals spacecraft
that is not
very difficult
so the kinetic energy
of the earth in orbit
one half
last year
the orbits
so i take this equation and iswc i lose half their
so i get
and so on
i i
that is the kinetic energy
the commands
things in the object form i could write down changes will show you the changes
would be
the difference between
this is what i did constraints the constraints failed
the change
what's more distracting because the different individual between male and female
i can use this you roll things
so i could undo
that change
which would again return to the to the unsatisfiability
of course i can do it again sort of silly but a fun
and i can see these changes and i can search for the missing
and we all know about
revisit the whole ontology and again usually very comfortable making changes because it's important
he is the only thing that i would
we're not going to the of
many many times
explicitly and it was released under constraint hold
that is actually kind of interesting that they didn't bother to put in the
the to the
inequality between the two
so that was how we get there when we get
we got there by show reference
four again
to think about how you're navigating through things
and it's got a long way
you should be OK there's two ways
these is the most commonly used on the whole drama class in your right click
on the negative control like get
you can show this is
so this is how to do so
what is
of her
so this is what the
see how i was going to go
this is again
so the thing to
the class
and fact show
that immediately gives you some sort of structure we're trying to figure
part of relations
and everything is referred to
this is true
you can change
so started structure
you can also do a lookup returns just is very similar
in this case if i want to look for male
i can see every place that has this its an now the
when you have turned
this will be some more
or the
also being forced to some
first was
very high
well first of all you
to get some ideas about what the whole ontology
to go brought to find points
what's on
period of
we might not honest you can also do this is by iteratively exploring
the ontology
so here i
this is quite this is reasonable sort
this is too small make it something that
OK so here is to the wall
some of the other
so obviously this book exposes across subclasses student to soon it's going to be very
so i understand
a graduate student
we need to understand student and that's a reasonable thing to do
go look at seems see what with song and then go back
clearly graduate student has some sort of refinement and also has had a particular degree
so i don't understand how to
this kind of back-and-forth local exploration where
explore and information
for the class
the force
this is
this figure out what's going on
i find it helpful when we don't have a particular
on the four
the large majority of us is is more effective for me
these explain but that's it that's against the you
have to pick up
just to him you know
everything behaves pretty much like a normal
web browsers so you had here
history there can jump that is they have not just the fact that can jump
further you can bookmark individuals and entities to come back to look at now it
so it's all pretty pretty normal from the best perspective
so we do a little bit
so to get into editing
you need to click the edible
and you'll get a number nine but
the art of graph are going to
three just text worked
i recommend that strongly
you of you lost
all these
this is one
the right
so there's a fairly strong subclasses are weaker than
often what most people use or some sort of across becoming and you get
OK like this
so that
if you have a very limited time so restrictions
restrictions are
that's not a function
recall function is
mathematicians called generalized functions
but that's not a function
it's just a way
making you feel comfortable about talking about something which is a function
it has the name was given the name
introduce formally
the mathematics by
this is iraq and its
looking ahead to the future that many people do
if you do something similar to which the formula or function or something which they
think is going to be important
he was to they never named directly after themselves but they always
uses the symbol for the first letter of their name
i can tell you how
they needed oiler called e
and for that reason although it
claims it was because what because
so the exponentials
well this what we need OK so this is
that that's
paul dirac
delta function
i won't dignify by the name function by writing out by putting function were function
but that is called the delta function
from this point on the entire rest of the lecture is a slightly fictionalized
the entire rest lecture series in
negative quotation marks
i'm not entirely responsible for anything i say
this is non function but you put it in core function
and actually want to complete
it's a function that must have all plus transform
even though it doesn't so the diagram is completed
it's all plus transform is declared to be one
start making list properties of this
we are thing
delta function
this applies transform is one
one of the things are one
we haven't yet
express the fact that the unit impulse
in other words since areas
of all these
boxes we all have areas one has shrunk this way they get higher that way
by convention one says that the area under the
orange curve is also
remains one the limit
my god expressed as well
it's not by the following formula
the integral over the total impulse
of the delta function should be one
where y integrate well
many places zero
places here on the other side of the vertical vertical lines
but in order to avoid controversy people integrate from all the way from negative infinity
to infinity is zero for your time
this is the function class transformers one
it's integral from minus infinity to infinity is one
whilst we calculate for well i'd like to calculate it
o OK
is there for the
so what happens if i convoluted
with delta function
well if you go back to the definition
of the convolution you know it's funny integral
you get
do a lot of head-scratching because it's not really all that we are at great
with the delta function
instead of doing that yet let's
i assume that follows was transformed in that case it transform would be well
the whole thing and convolution is available as transform of convolution
it is the product of two separate transform that's going to be that
times lipgloss transform the delta function which is one
what was this thing well
there's some ambiguity is what it is for negative values t
but if we make a brute force decided he
does active learning
it should down and after sixty well posed queries learn the role perfectly OK
so this is an example of active learning working
there's a lot more to subject just say
what is the sort of context we might uses the state i got from google
right to so years ago but this is a drug discovery context you have the
vector of a large number of binary shape features and you want to know
chemical biologically active or not active so what i mean by this
it is you've got all these chemicals you don't know which ones
relatively small number are going to be active in the biological context considering so but
passive learning be simply pick these
chemicals random find a way out
active learning would be
you know the characteristics of a of these chemicals they have drug discovery companies have
huge libraries of such chemical chemicals and you know the characteristics and you can therefore
presenter molecules so what happens biologically active yes
and i love this way
and in this dataset consists of a thousand three hundred of which thirty nine with
positive biologically active if passive learning
i for the local here
whereas if active learning
with an SVM then rapidly declined and eventually
quite soon i actually
got nearly all the active
biological compounds in the dataset
but sensitive of active learning so
just pointing out the sort of variance on the SVM story
any questions
well passive just pick
well you can see actually
personal and then pick a random
but what i'm doing is i'm not exploiting the knowledge of what gained OK
active learning
i've learnt something about the problem
that constrain the space should be searching
so now i suppose the query is probably better than totally random improve hypothesis
which actually improves by getnext gets better and i have run away
shortly answer OK because i'm using the hypothesis to tell me
we should be looking next OK
two crew then you can actually come up with counterexamples
where you can sort of defeated query that on the average you have problem it's
a good strategy
right so it's in
training SVM sinco common what's in this section so far less because of their involvement
in the output of programming
linear programming is just comments about the method used column generation techniques
if using quadratic programming these comments been out-of-date now the packages like minnows loco use
i would go to the kernel
machines all
site we've got a whole lot of software
i think this is slightly out of date
you have three general categories of learning machines really all this has to do with
what you happens if you have a huge dataset
well you can't extract the kernel k
you can construct kernels
as you go along discard
you also working set methods
in which an evolving subset of data
and which is specifically supported structure the problem so these are sort of different ways
of doing this trend
so what i'm on about here let's suppose we go right back to my
svm scenario
the quadratic programming problem i mentioned in the beginning it's all very well but but
kernel matrix was k i j
well i ranges one number patterns in the data now suppose that a thousand patterns
that kernel matrix is a thousand one thousand seven million it's not all that difficult
for me to therefore is also memory
of the machine you will encounter this problem certainly was quite with quite a few
dates for the beginning become large
the several ways round this problem if you actually encountering one is
something are noted already
if i took a hundred data points that have a data a thousand but just
pick out
a hundred from that i train would actually find that twenty five are support vectors
and the other seventy five and on support vectors the idea of the sort of
evolving subset is if i know that they are not support vectors i just dropped
them out
OK and have got this twenty five
then pick another bunch and in the course of the support vectors is probably increases
i'm going along
but if i'm lucky
then and do by chunks then i can probably avoided problems
so i just want to say here
the work that the drive these chunk process until the margin exploits of course this
procedure may fail because actually
we've got ten thousand by ten thousand chunk is going to do for it so
decomposition methods provide a better approach these algorithms only use fixed subset of data
with the alpha i for the remainder kept fixed OK
so i just always use a fixed subsets
got ten thousand data points but only ever use the hundred of any one time
and indeed
there's a street named of this stream into is algorithm proposed by john plant which
is small of sequential minimal optimisation which the two to only consider two samples anyone
can OK
so this is extreme limit of decomposition in other words only two alpha i wish
optimise this is a small subset the parameters i can consider i can't do this
one must always consider two you can prove this because if from this criterion can't
we change one of to time because it violates whereas from data at the time
i can maintain that
criterion all along OK so this is the extreme case
but now
after all
so much
there's only one man
one is
well i would
of these are
or that he
ninety five percent
the other
and from all
one of them
he says that
i mean
she says
problem then
you me two
in here
so far
as apostle variable
OK so
the first two we talked about
were not strictly speaking probability density functions they were just probability distributions for discrete random
variables but now i want to turn to continuous random variables so we describe
using PDF probability density functions
so the first one i want to consider
is the uniform distribution
and the
the formula is given here but it's easy to graphically illustrate what that means you
simply consider two constants alpha and beta and you say that the uniform is a
constant value between those limits and zero everywhere else
and because the
distribution has to be normalized to have unit area
that means that the height of the curve has to be one minus
the width
so one divided by the
which is here
so the area under the thing is equal to one
and here because the model is so simple you could actually work out
the expectation value and and variance
by hand very easily so i've written in the way that title notes just before
so if you're looking at the lecture notes had you'll notice that square is missing
but it's obviously better myself squared
so what some applications of the uniform distribution it is easy to show
but if you consider a random variable x
the falls any can continuous pdf such that the cumulative distribution is capital f of
OK so so
that could be the cumulative corresponding to an exponential or calcium or anything you want
now with the that cumulative distribution simply as a function
of x and consider the random variable y equals capital f of x
that's a very
so i'm remarked yesterday that the function of a random variable
it's also a random variable and if i regret that is the random variable i
find it will be uniformly distributed between zero and one
that turns out to be very convenient property and we will return to that
in just a bit when we consider the monte carlo method
but there are so that's that's mathematical
property which is very important but there are also physical examples of the uniform distribution
of for example if you consider the decay of neutral pions
most of the time it decays into two photons if you have higher moving along
and in the case into the two photons and the energy of the pion will
be shared
between the two photons and the show will be different depending on the orientation of
the of the the k
so if you look at the distribution of energy
all the come out you find that it will be
distributed between a certain minimum and maximum values which i've written the formulas for here
and it will follow that a uniform distribution
the minimum and maximum
the data refers to the
of the of the pizer
so so
that's the uniform distribution
it's gone
here's another
very important
continuous pdf with the exponential distribution
it is defined by a formula that i have written here there is the exponential
as a function of this continuous variable x it is of course only positive
it contains the single parameter which are written here is the letter c
so there it is for different values of
if you look at the expectation value and variance we find that they are able
to succeed
and ixi square respectively
now i very often use this notation the use of a latin letter
for the random variable itself and sometimes for the corresponding expectation value i use the
the corresponding greek letters
right so the random variables x and its expectation value xxi
but one of the most important applications of the exponential distribution
in particle physics is to the decay time of an unstable particle
so the the proper decay time t
it is also described by an exponential distribution so therefore
for the expectation value i would use the corresponding greek letters tau
so we would like fifty with the parameter tau
the entire line corresponds to the mean
the lifetime of the particle
now the exponential distribution
has some very interesting properties one of them
is what is called lack of memory
and this can be expressed in the following way
if you have a collection of particles that are all present at some start time
t zero
and if you look at the
distribution of the quantity
t minus t zero where t is the decay time t is the time after
which the particle decays t zero start time
and this is the conditional probability given
the particles all existing
at this start time they had indicated beforehand
then you find that conditional probability is simply equal
to the original exponential distribution
independent of t zero
so that's what's called lack of memory
bias and some voxels very large bias and now what you can do is you
can use pattern recognition techniques to analyse the information contained subtle information contained in each
voxel but you can accumulate this information across a large number of voxels
this is just to show
project this is just side on the project work in magdeburg and leipzig with the
post-doc of mine so you can see here this is the human lgn so you
can get subcortical structures and what this shows is the subdivisions macmillan published subdivisions of
the LGN but you can obtain with high resolution high field imaging seven test flight
and you can see here
different types of voxels showing quite different types of parametric responses and there's a bimodal
distribution for example of the c fifty the value in the u i mean most
people i guess not visual so you might not know this but it's basically tells
you where the steep part of this curve here is that relates the response amplitude
to the contrast that you're stimulating with
the point is you can fit a parametric function to each voxel and then you
can for example do some kind of clustering and what you get out here is
you get magnum part of voxels out of this with very high resolution one point
one millimetre
so we can get this fine grained information but the information each voxel is rather
unreliable for example you see here that the information also looks rather noisy so these
patterns and all that kind of you can't reliably identify each individual voxel but you
can roughly get the topography and the topography is reproducible
so how do we analyse this
so what we do is we take root this is just an illustrative example so
you are interested in the pattern of three by three voxels here then what you
do is you turn this into a pattern vector were ultimately these different entries in
this vector
contains the from my activity in each of these works all positions here and then
use this as an index to appoint in an n dimensional space where the n
dimensions are just the number of voxels that you're introducing into analysis and you can
illustrate this if you just look at two dimensions so you're stimulating with two different
stimuli and you take the first two dimensions which you can use to just get
the euclidean x y coordinate system and the cartesian coordinates for a cartesian coordinate system
here and what you can see here is the different possible cases in which this
information can be distributed across these two voxels
so what you can see on the left is the case
where blue is the image two and read different measurements of image one
and this shows the activity values into voxels
and you can see here that get a high value invokes the one when you
showing image two but he had low value voxel two and for the other type
of image it's the other way round
now this is the case where you could separate
you could classify based on each of these individual voxels you don't need to voxels
to classify here you can just basically put the criterion somewhere here and then you
can separate the blue and the red simply based on books one or voxel two
now but they are difficult cases
and these more difficult cases you can see here
for example the second
it is where you don't have any separable information in
each voxel
but the discriminative information is carried by the covariation pattern between the two voxels
so you can see here if you just know voxel one or you just know
voxel two
you can hardly separate these two but if you know voxel one voxel two together
you can separate these very well you can put the decision boundary in there and
you can separate between these two
and this is very important for this is also the reason why
if you want to do multivariate according
you can't do this properly if you don't have simultaneous measurements for example of multiple
cells when you're doing invasive recordings because the covariation pattern is something that is incredibly
important and this covariation pattern if you first measure one cell
and then you measure another cell and then third so anyone use decoding techniques this
covariation pattern is lost you lose this fine grained cooperation and then you can apply
the coding techniques anymore you can get up to ninety percent accuracy
now this this post is like a virus
all that happens is that
particular blog we will infect other bloggers other blogs now
link to the particular post
the block can compute in the next time step so that we can have claimed
that you can have a case the
two blogs just goalkeeping influence each other and we would get like a long chain
of of influence
and so if you go and see a more like this and and compare it
to reality and this is what we do so
the particular details are not important here but what i'm showing here is some distributions
or some because some some
statistical properties of the cascades of for example would be a cascade size distribution the
dark side of the day
and the line
is what is produced by the more or for example i can go and we
take the star cascade we have set central but then has a bunch of nodes
and again we can compare the results from the model with the results from the
through the results and you can see it's it's very close to i can only
be changed and again measure the
the size distribution of chains and compare it to what more gives me
and also
if you remember from previous slides these are the most frequent cascades the
one is in there and they are very similar to what we saw before the
the larger cascades the the less frequented his and also there are some nice topological
things going
this is in relation this simulation
o it ensure it was it was the result of iteration so i guess would
be saying that i was overfitting
manually overfitting four
the developing any money to use an iteration tried you have many intuitions that you
want to exploit
o there's a lot of things missing here and there is no topicality that i
would be following there is for example here i'm just picking the end of the
blog that starts the thing uniformly at random but if you go and ask what
the distribution of the number of posts per blog again identity some heavy tailed distributions
like most of the blogs have like one post and there are few blogs have
a huge number for example
that are
and this is not but
now i want to move to the last part of the park and here i
skip if you think so
we saw that we saw
what are the models we saw how
you can go into the data and measured the cascades and find them so now
the question is
given this cascades how can i take quick so
what we are doing is a network and a set of cascades or set of
propagation patterns and the question is which nodes should be monitored to detect this cascades
and here are two motivating example so for example if you if we have a
water distribution network of city so we have these houses and let's say that there
is some was introduced this particular not now the infected water spread and infect the
rest of the network
and what we would like to do is we would like to put
a sensor at some locations
so that if if there is a there is an infection that spreads
when it hits over-sensitive we will raise an alarm rate we detect the of
and the question is where should we put the the sensors detect this breaks as
effectively as possible
and effectively or efficiently can mean many different things
similarly for blocks right you can say
i have i have blogs as a child before i have blogs that have posts
and i had this
the hyperlinks between posts so i can track how information propagates through the network
so the question i want to answer is
which blogs should we read to be most up to date right if there is
an important story going on i would like to to know about it as quickly
as possible so for example if i go back here
you could say well i mean these blocks it is this the the
this excited to be a big blogs because six posts so i have to read
a lot of posts but i i capture all the stories right i would get
to know the story i would get to know the story and i would get
to know the story but i would get to know them very low
the solution to the problem what could possibly be that i go and i read
block one and block c this would mean i i need to read posts
but i can get to know all the stories all the cascade and i captured
the very soon right as soon as they have i know of
so these are the types of trade offs between the try to explore this
line of work
what is the problem right we have some dynamic process spreading over the network and
we want to select a set of nodes to detect this process as effectively as
possible and before i was
then you about finding the most influential set of nodes right this is sort of
similar but different right then are trying to find people that but that are most
likely to influence others here we are trying to find people that are most likely
to get influence right it's like sort of but i want to find people who
are most likely to get it so that if there is an epidemic and they
become i know something is going on right and there are numerous applications of extracted
you can use it in epidemics network security and so on
and there are two parts to the problem the first one is the reward to
the objective function right so what is the function what is the criteria you want
to minimize or maximize for example in the water distribution you could say i want
to minimize time to detection whenever there is an academic i want to detect it
as quickly as possible so
the amount of time between between the introduction detection then the second thing that is
different you could say i want to maximize the number of detected outbreaks so whenever
the outbreak happens i want to i want to
be able to detect it i don't care howley
and so on i just want to detect
and then the the the last one is we want to minimize the number of
infected people that's so
here we we have basically paying more for the gulf exactly what to say
between the time the album was was introduced in the private detective on the smaller
number of people to drink was poisoned water or something so this is the first
part of the problem in the second part of the problem is
the cost is location dependent meaning that there is some cost of to read off
reading a blog so big reading a bigger blogs is more time consuming than leading
a small or
placing a sensor
at some remote rural location may be more expensive than placing the sounds of summer
in the city which is easily accessible or or vice versa so that there is