for for many problems it's hard to think of sensible real valued feature functions but
the formalism
allows for the
here's my
OK f sixteen of x and y
the length of y
length of x
so that's the example of a real valued feature function
the length of y minus the length of x
and supposing that
x was an english sentence and y was a french sentence
a lot
french sentence when you translate from english into french translation tends to
be longer than the original
the length of one minus length of x
it is
it it tends to be positive for correct translations
and if length of y is less than ninety five x and y is probably
if we were trying to learn to log linear model the translation
then this is the feature function that would probably end up with a positive weight
and this is the this is a real valued feature function
for any application of log linear models
including conditional random fields
the first thing you have to do
define all your feature functions
and the
then the learning process
is to find weights for the feature functions
so that
when the feature function is positive and the weight is positive
the y
more likely
and when when the product wj fj
the why should be
less likely
let me
try to
a little bit
yes yes
i don't think there's any particular
of having a real valued and binary feature functions versus having just binary feature functions
more ink think it's but some problems naturally lend themselves to binary feature functions you
may not have any real valued functions at all
and the problems may lend themselves to both or lend themselves only two of them
will valued
feature functions
my it's and
the it just depends on the problem and i certainly wouldn't summer try to create
feature functions of one type or the other type if they were natural
yes so it could still
right right
and even the the normalisation of the model
the normalisation of the range of the feature functions
that's important if you're going to be doing stochastic gradient with single learning rate lambda
single stepsize lambda
it may be less important any user different training algorithm
let me
and by short i don't mean to pages but but something like seven pages eight
pages on something that you want to write about now let me give you some
examples just off the top of my head if you have any interest in painting
for example would be more interesting to take to take
look by
impression to impressionist painters like bizarro and and and run while in the sea how
they viewed the transformation of nineteenth-century paris the big boulevards and all of them
or you could take another novel i mean you me now one of the interesting
things about it is that it is the document of history you the novel
so these are invented people
but if the document history in some ways as is lost the great literature on
world war one and there isn't any period in
modern history that has so much much griping literature
about it as great war
the british war poets like siegfried sassoon and lies people you know we're dead after
they wrote system wasn't immediately camera days nineteen eighteen or not but i do take
to take some of the poetry or the writing of the war
and writer paper by
or three in the diplomatic history something like me consul paper reevaluating order the crimean
and then you put you to sleep before the put your change but we don't
you can imagine a good a good paper and that you can do whatever you
one of the lectures and when i do the enlightenment brought from my good friend
bob dart you know the thing at the beginning about why the line was important
and what it is
this is the secularisation rational inquiry and all that stuff that you may already know
maybe not but it's in the book but then what i do is look at
some of the the third string kind or the third division in the european football
sense of enlightenment hacks and what they wrote about royalty about aristocrats and the way
they can undermine the traditional hierarchies that would be swept away
to a large extent by the french revolution
or you could take somebody out of the french revolution such as the steely size
used in raphael's mother silver age sixteen or something and one on the grand tour
of france and talk about him and the committee of public safety signed away the
lives of what people may have also saved the revolution you can do whatever you
well you know like it should have something to do with the course in the
time period where we're talking about i mean nothing at all on the red sox
or something but but you have you know work with their teaching participate and i'm
an email animal i'm always available and email and office hours well the people come
much anymore setting
NBA dotcom because email made office hours are oblivious i mean irrelevant not oblivious but
people are oblivious to my office hours but anyway there
where are they are monday's one two
two thirty
used to be free but i said to myself one to two thirty i in
branford college
k k thirteen
there are also two other movies when we get to fascism
we get out of it
we and and he was only one of a whole bunch of dictators there's hardly
parliamentary regimes left and in continental europe nineteen thirty three nine comes a woman many
reference style who just died in two thousand two with eight hundred two
she in when she was young woman did propaganda film for hitler and hitler like
mussolini believed in tech is one of the first people to use the radio franklin
roosevelt used the fireside chat the radio mussolini was already there is no piling falsehood
upon falsehood and an italian to can barely forty e all had the radios in
the same thing happened in germany as well and she did have a book which
is the movie called a documentary called triumph of the will
about nuremberg and is truly chilling is an amazing
looks like a political convention or something in some ways i and it's all these
movies you can see in the privacy of your your luxury suites and brentford appears
in college or wherever because they available now in ways i don't even understand what
i'm here under the internet we used actually show them here
used to use movie great movie called the serendipity the ground
and it was four hours long and and people described the two six-pack movie
i the the generous complained get somebody robot over rattling around the course before the
drinking water core of our was raise of course i don't show that will be
i think that kind of thing that would help but anyway i don't i don't
i don't show that movie anymore but but but i you should triumph of the
will and you can watch at home and the other one is a is
because one of the last lectures i talk about resistance
and collaboration
in europe
because i live in france much of the time i i talk about france
and what is a form some good by children some of have probably seen was
made by the man who just died a couple years ago
and was about when he was
call as he was so he was equivalent to seventeen a great
and there's a new boy shows up at school
during world war two in fontainebleau which is just south east of paris
and he
a boy invented before
and he's jewish boy
and it's about his friendship with this boy
and what happened
you at the end it's not happy film this is the great great films on
what else
but to say there's a midterm i don't like to waste the lecture giving imagery
rather give lecture but we have to have something
to report to you
if you if you to but if you don't do very well at all
we don't count as much as do well
i people ask these questions i know how much is it worth while images of
is more like the great but it's it's something like twenty five percent of papers
twenty five percent section participation is ten percent whatever we work out and then and
then the final
so it's just it's an exercise in seeing how you're
how you doing it know really is is is no big deal
it will help you pull the themes
of course together and it's no carry situation and we all live in this sort
of a minus b plus
range rdf a couple years ago i ran the student
this means make them so they don't change it since that they don't change over
time really
zion them the way that that once you have assigned to you i change
a second use different UIC different things this is especially in the context
when we talk about the page about something
and the thing itself
document about
the distillery
it's not the same as the mystery itself so two different your eyes
so i think
but still the URI for this solution should be possible to look it up
still if you put it into web browser if you do an http request
you want to
at the end of the day get get the document
and we see how to hold true
how to
combined these two words they seem to contradict each
we don't want to we want you
we use different URI for for the agent for the thing but still we kind
of want to get
two three if the page
when we look up to
so what we were seeing how to
how to do this
and last important thing URI ownership so there is the principal
if you have registered the domain then you open despite few i space
so don't
don't squat URI space by kind of saying that this URI in someone else's URI
space means the certain thing it's just something kind of that violates the social conflict
of the web so something that you should have
you should avoid doing
so you have some
URI is
for some some some potentially guys for this
is going to be don't want to use
for example wikipedia dot org slash wiki first telescope
no this is a URI of a wikipedia article is not that but i offer
brand of whisky so it's two different things don't do this
and at the same time it's in someone else's space so we need to be
if they didn't if wikipedia didn't plan to make this an RDF compatible URI that
really identifies the particular and then don't go there
the next
you this it's whiskey com
brian talisker about RDF
no this is the document the the RDF variant of discontinuity the document
so this is the document is also not a brand of whisky
same with the next one
brand telescope about
this is the generic document
so it's not the whiskey that of different things
and the final
we use the i and here
the thing is this you and it's not you can't look it up so you
can put this into prose or if you just
make an edge you can make a request
to look up the definition of the i
so it's also not a good choice
remember generic document is this URI brand talisker about
and now we have two approaches that
how we can
like two approaches that we i would say this is how we should do it
first this
use something called actually p three o three redirect
here we have
so we end up with the URI for the brand
called wiskii com brands slash talisker
so without the slash about india
it is different from the URI for the page
it fulfills this requirement is different
and we can set up a redirect using the special
three we HTTP status code
this means that if
client makes best to this visualise
it will be redirected to another URI
and in this case we just redirect it to the slash about the generic URI
and this means so if put those u i if we make make you request
to this
to the URI of this brand
we will end up
at the document so we will at the end the HTML document or web browser
or our data browser will load the RDF description
so we have different UI so there's is no ambiguity
between like which which thing is which things meant here by this year
it's actually appears several state status courts
this field he one is especially
it's the one that should be used in this case the if you
a redirect from
the square
you can write it like this
you get traces suppose a times the easy transport vector matrix c
this that we get a linear this is now a linear function and the variables
policy and
so this problem that had this hard combinatorial problems according to this
the problem
there have linear
the objective function in the table constraints here
and a very common and now all the complex is in this second
basically this is saying that c is a one matrix but this
small so that's a very difficult
it has to be difficult because it equivalent to the original all the complexity now
is in this
using exactly equivalent so how do you obtain relaxation vol
if i replace this equality is equal to the inequality the rhetoric you before
and the second problem becomes very easy
so i just place this
constrained the inequality
and that can also be written like this
that's the that
that should comply couldn't this is greater than the fifty and suppose that semantics linear
matrix inequality everything inside here is linear in the variables in problem
because the matrix is the variable that is able
so this is an SDP linear objective
having equality constraints and mechanical
so that's the problem can so easily
it's not equivalent to the original problem because i replaced the quality of inequality is
to maximize over a larger set
this problem solving
minimizing the same cost function but over a large set so this will always give
a lower bound on the actual problem
that's why it's called the axis is lower bound on the action of the original
lower bound can computed efficiently efficiently
and sometimes just the fact of having a lower bound if it's another lower bound
is a very hard problem can be used
and then after solving this relaxing the excitation can also think of good ways of
actual guessing good suboptimal solution for the original problem
and he could do different things right for example of this is the p
and just throw away the matrix c and keep the vector
all the other as your this for the suboptimal solutions for problem
you take this policy
around the components to plus or minus one
and i think that there are several
another more sophisticated method that's often uses randomized rounding
so in this method you interpret you also try to use the matrix enable computers
i interpret this constraint as
saying that the see effectively is the mean of the distribution
this matrix is the is actually
the second moments
of the distribution
and this is a condition that says that this this this this matrix and vector
can be interpreted as mean and
covariance of the second moment of the
that's how you interpret that
thank see in the matrix
and i suppose we assume it's because distribution every generates random vectors from this distribution
and then random two person months
and then you can do that multiple times and just keep the best solution x
is called randomized rounding
so this is an example that occurred and the fifty five the matrix a
in this case it would be possible to compute all possible choices
then we solve the SDP relaxation and so we normalize
for example axis here so that one is the lower bound on the
that's a lower bound on the podium
the problem
so i'm not sure that the optimum is because it's difficult to compute the it's
of less than one
then another heuristic would be to just solve the least squares problem without the peak
border constraints solve the discrete problem and around solution might give this
and this histogram is the result of the randomized rounding applied to the solution of
the SDP relaxation
we generate random vectors x
some all of them are much better than to find the best solution
so you can tell about this but then is that the global optimum of the
border problem by some
back then
then have another example of an SDP approach probably skip this
it's about expanding
the standard chebyshev inequalities probability
well known classical inequality would be you have greater than the table x
with zero mean given variance
the classical chebyshev inequality gives a lower bound on the probability of x having that
one minus the of
and it's tight bound exist distributions that have achieved or
so tried to explain possible extension of this would be followed first u
extended from the scalar variable x to factor variable x
with unknown mean
the second moment
suppose that so you know about the distribution mean the first and second moments
and then instead of just an upper bound on the scalar x here we look
at a set defined by quadratic inequality
not that could be indefinite i to be convex set of quadratic inequality
and i want to lower bound for probability
that x lies in this set
and that sort of generalized chebyshev inequality you're bounding the probability that it has a
palace one
here in the probability that the fact that x lies in this set described by
thank you
credit card
well that's probably can actually can find the bound by solving is the
and again it's five and are distributions that achieve that
the example of this
to just to finish this part of con programming we talked about the
second order cone semidefinite programming
so actually reflects the change in how people view convex optimisation since the nineteen nineties
so the more traditional view of convex optimization is that it's a special case of
linear programming
and united in the general form minimizing fcx the picture and i think this is
a special case of linear programming that con functions happen to be convex so you
have some additional interesting theory
so in this core programming notation you actually and as i said that the
articles related to LP
right it almost like an LP except that using non non-political inequality
two tropical rain
lp norms and one and so on the popular in russia
a different set of axioms
surprise different set of axioms
no cases you need seven
i will mention the culprit of this
the modified distances what i mean by this is an example of where things start
to get out
there is an example of a fortified that was going to fly command number four
which is embedded in the
this inspired
because of course there a lot of color transfer is often involve
it was an evaluation
if you look at this particular
colouring of the scheme
the shortest distance between two points
is all the decision to appoint is in two cases in the in the same
or in two
that's going to far more
so this is the green line is the shortest distance between two content of our
so if s is the length of the edge of the
hexagonal tiling
x minus one of the most tool as if x y are in the same
this is
five was
angle of one hundred twenty degrees
and it would be greatly full then
seven as if x y have same color with the financial
that means we have a language with s
they would still give us
a because of the plane with seven followers
so now we can take our graphs and
inflate them
and that is as long as as between these two numbers get caught the this
is seven cars
and this is the study that was
we generated by jeff x two
and yes what that just relaxing that have more edges what we
an edge between two vertices if the distance between two points is between one one
y that
in one class
and this is where it gets really they managed to produce a graph with at
least two hundred seven votes is
and with exhaustive computer searches
claim that is seven com
we started
a different variation and this is what i call the distance one
this was done by an international school
i'm not good at
highway authorities are quite stunning to appear me as if you
the other one being
this that's whole
two something i do not know how to
despite either
slovak and they all canadian smallpox
i don't know if these two
again american-israeli always the american
and simoncelli whose israel israeli if we we're seeing jerusalem
OK so it's the quick description of the this is what
the six distance is
by four points in the plane cannot be altered
this is the problem the putnam exam in nineteen ninety two
there was more
general observation that in the paper by one what was what the as follows
the maximum number of points of these such that all distances among them is an
odd integer
is the last slide
unless there is
fourteen months sixty o in dimension fourteen you can actually have two simplices
actually each other will the distances
the two surfaces are each have edges point nine
and then these
connecting the two in
eight says if distance five
using an elementary that's for this once short very nicely only four points
so one of them is the origin
this is the old cosine inequality
and you let me stop for a second and i'm going to use it
assume that all the instances of
that means
you might be square this for all the integers therefore this square is one with
and therefore
minus two times you've is also one of the one with a probability model
and then you form my i
say we actually make links of these
three that forest
so this is clearly a flag most to the the
and use this one eight and you get
the matrix and the determinant of this matrix is for an clearly deal with a
and this is the country
so not all
can be an odd integer
actually this is the same thing as in the unity since the unit distance graph
can the full
but this is
the form of a four because north pole
six this is equal to one
so in nineteen ninety four of i ask for the query was whether he can
be called in a finite number of features
so the two points of in the this instead this thing colours
obviously the all these four because already for this one needs
she made the input is only
classical ask what is the maximum number of the distances my
and points
in the plane
we can easily have an upper bound for the maximum number of distances both for
the unit distance and four
the or distance
because we know
you have an influence
this is a graph on n vertices that does not contain the k four
so we can use to still
and we have an upper bound immediately on the number of distances before and by
the way is to numbers
so i'm going to the local economy i don't live is that
yeah good
i want the locals simon godsill and signal processing here in the engineering department the
same department as zoubin
well i don't mind that but it's not
OK i going to be talking about sequential monte carlo methods all particle filtering methods
it's in two sessions the first session today
it's pretty much a basic session so people that already know about particle filters will
probably not very much about this will have maybe some insights perhaps they can point
out their own
views on particular things i say feel free to
ask me questions on point things out along the way within reason
the application area domain within is where we're looking at large sequentially evolving datasets we
don't necessarily want to do
an inference in batch learning a lot of time shining through all of the data
in one go
and clearly there are vast numbers of applications that fall into this category sequential data
evolving data
tracking is where this methodology probably first started out with the is organised in earnest
in the nineteen nineties with the seminal paper by new gordon
and his collaborators simon smith that says adrian smith great bayesian nearest
but also in computer vision i start up around about the same time with andrew
blake work and various other applications where these things are used routinely nowadays
so basically
as you expect in machine learning
workshop summer school remaining going to be distributing with dealing with probability distributions and uncertainty
so we'll be looking for ways to take a bayesian approach to sequential updating of
probability distributions as the data evolve and in particular the probability distributions are some latent
state variables that we want to learn as they evolve
obviously for this talk focusing on the sequential may make money monte carlo methodology
i think that's synonymous with particle filtering i don't think there are any differences between
those although there may be some subtle interpretations there are numerous papers around about this
i'm just pointing to a handful of them here
that's gordon salmond and smith was the first in recent times although there are papers
going back to the nineteen sixties and and and before where people were using sequential
importance sampling of various types and
and then these other papers are sort of review papers that that involved myself but
there are numerous other papers in this area you took out
so we're looking for estimating or finding the posterior probability distributions for some hidden process
which we call the state of the system and they results have be obtained from
noisy convolved or non linearly distorted observations particularly interested in this methodology with things that
don't limit the class of functions and nonlinear processes nongaussian processes that we can deal
with so that they in their final form
a very generic they can work with pretty well any nonlinear state space model stochastic
state space model if you throw at it at least in principle it may take
a lot of monte carlo samples to do so in principle they can do that
you'll find that some of the more tailored algorithms the things that have come about
over the last ten years or so
research may then be directed more towards specific classes of model for example
a major classes model that's been a a big success with these methods is that
those which have some partial
the gaussians structure so the bit about model because the model which you can handle
using a standard kalman filtering methodology and you should do that if you're effectively marginalizing
that the posterior
probability sense from the equations and then you just do the hard particle filtering part
on the non linear nongaussian that's left behind so that's an example of a case
they are very tailored methods for a particular class of models the most of what
the understanding was that atoms were the most basic constituent of matter meaning you could
break adams up into anything smaller that was that you're done
and with using newtonian mechanics it was assumed sense this this type of mechanics worked
so well to describe everything we could see it even describe the universe planet that
of course we can use newtonian mechanics to describe how an electron
actually we didn't even know what electron here but how atoms behaved and it turns
out this is not the case
and the first step in and discovering this is not the case
was accomplished by JJ thomson and JJ thomson is credited for discovering the electron
it was a physicist in england and what his laboratory was studying is something called
cathode rays
in cathode rays are simply rays that are emitted when you have a higher electron
a high voltage difference
between two electrodes so
if you look at this set up
what he did when he was studying is raised as he had been evacuated to
which is schematically shown here
were evacuated of all air field instead just with hydrogen gas and he had this
high voltage difference with between anode and the cathode and he actually put a little
hole in and out here so these cathode rays that were produced could shoot out
of the cathode and actually could be detected the luminescence by spot on the detector
so what people were studying at the right time one reason they actually gave us
the bright glow if you put them in an evacuated glass tube about these crazy
patterns and glowing colours though
after that even with very high issue in terms of research
but also no one really knew what these were and thompson was seeking to figure
out some more properties of them and he had the theory that maybe they were
actually charged particles of some sort and others have proposed this in the past but
they didn't really have an experimental setup to test and that's what thompson dead
and what he did was he put two detection played
on either side of the cathode rays
and when he
put a voltage difference between the two plates he wanted to see if we could
actually bend the range and tested are actually charged and i
so when the voltage difference between the plates is zero
when we just don't have the place they're all those that cathode rays are not
bent they just go right in a straight line and they can be detected on
the screen
when he actually cranked up the voltage between these two players what he saw was
really moving to him which is that he actually was able to bend these races
had never been observed before in any capacity and able to detect on screen that
there was this deflection and you could even measure of the degree of deflection that
he had
so we know now that we have charged particles are these negatively or positively charged
based on the evidence
yeah that's right so
so what we have here cathode rays we now know
are negatively charged particles
and in fact
he had been this negatively charged particles if anyone know what he named them
no not electrons very good captain corpus of has only one part of corpus so
little then yes o
it was later named that these particles were in fact electrons and that's what they
i did something continued to call the proposals for many many many years after everyone
else called the electrons but i'm sure no one minded because he did in fact
discover them
and was actually
able to find out more than just that these were charged
in classical electromagnetism you could actually relate the degree of deflection that he saw to
the charge and the mass of the particles
so using that you could say
that act and we'll put some negative because we know now that these are negative
is proportional
the charge
on particle
over which is the mass so we have
e being equal to the charge of the negative particles
and of course
it equal to the mass
of those particles
thompson didn't stop here
he actually continued experimenting with different voltages
and what we found was if he really really ran the voltage up between those
two play
you can actually detect something else and what he could detect here is that there's
this little
one of them and after that you can see on the screen that was barely
deflected at all certainly comparison
how strongly this first particle is deflected the second particle is deflected almost not at
all but what can tell
from the fact that there was a second part going on the fact that it
was in this direction is that in addition to his negative particle he also of
course had a positive particle that was with the stream of rays that are coming
so course he can use the same relationship for the positive particle
so delta act
now of the positive
is proportional
the charge on the positive particle
all over
the mass of the positive particle
derivative of the mean squared error loss
is just the inner product of
and the
the area between t and put the model predicts
and then we have
some ten here
so we want to say this to zero and hopefully solve for w
so again
for those of you who are not familiar with this sort of notation and the
manipulation of
derivatives out of calculus vector calculus then it's it's a good idea to become familiar
with that is going to be doing a serious machine learning
but before we go ahead we just need to satisfy ourselves that this is
the stationary point is the minimum
and again
if you remember
you're still
calculus then for single variable
the second derivatives at stationary points
i have to be strictly positive
four that stationary point to the minimum of the function
and the multiparameter generalisation is that
the matrix of partial derivatives partial second derivatives are called h
requires to be positive definite
so in other words if we take any
vector eight then the the inner product does this quadratic term here always has to
we typically this after this
matrix is the haitian matrix so we need the expression for that so again we
just do some more schoolboy calculus
and you can stack all of these second derivatives
in two are
a two by two matrix in this case a more general case of the parameters
b d by d
and i'll leave it as an exercise for you you can see that each of
these elements
basically corresponds to a constant some of the actual values of attributes in india in
in these
elements here
and then this failed diagonal term is the sum of the squared attribute values
again we can write this matrix we can write this
matrix of second derivatives in
matrix format and it turns out to be
transpose x
this is actually
a very important
matrix and i'll talk a little bit more about it later
and the interesting thing is that
the target values don't appear in here at all the only thing that appears of
attribute values so we have this and a product of the the attribute values will
return to this
later on
x transpose it can be inverted
can be
it will be positive definite
providing that in where n is the number of observations is greater than d
where do you
is the number of parameters
then the his
will be positive definite and can be inverted in this case
and as n is for of twenty five and is o the two then
this is positive definite so stationary point
of the mean squared error as the minimum
and everything's good
because this can be inverted then we can obtain
the estimates of our
parameter vector
w hat where hi corresponds to
and estimate empirical estimate
we obtain
the estimate
which minimizes
minimize squared error so it yields the least square there
and if you remember
let me just
quickly dived by to this here
the expression for the
was this
so we said this to date to zero
this something
again schoolboy algebra and we can
immediately solve for w
and it turns out to be
the well-known least squares estimator which we all know and love
so w heart
here is that expression
at the heart again this reduces to
this expression
and if we take the logo of the score
the amazing thing that comes out is that the log of the score for any
item we're trying to score
it's simply going to be a linear function of
the features and that idea
this is about as simple
a scoring method that you get
coming out of any possible model
so essentially
this is the linear function of the
features of that item x don j
is just
the j feature of item axis
and that can be either zero or one
the business park binary data and now hughes of j
is a vector
that represent
query set
as some direction
and the base of the features of item
so we had a set of items in our query that's going to be represented
by some
vector in x space
and then we score
items by the dot product of
their features with that particular factor
and it all came out that we didn't make any approximation this actually came out
from starting from that probabilistic model and doing the integral and doing some simplifications
so if we take all the items in our universe and we back them into
giant matrix
of the number of items in our universe by the number of features then we
can people log score
by just a single
matrix vector multiplication
which is what i promise before we
i tell you in a minute
the question was a repeat the question and then i'll get your question is how
the the bias that and i'm about that
until this
depends on
the query that
so we have two kinds of data we have in the query set which we
the system the eight elders in the
the output filters in the battle that depend on the query set
and then
we have x which is the item that we're trying to score
to come up with the rank with the by them
the album better the don't depend on x
that was the question of priors
what we're gonna do for priors is the following
we have a whole universe of items
and in our universe of items we we can represent the matrix that might look
like this we have items on this axis and the
so far binary features on the fact that
and now
we can compute the mean
the mean over the rows of this matrix
and that gives us
the mean frequency
with which we
observed each of the items in our universe of
and we're going to come up with a broad empirical prior
is proportional
two the main feature frequency so we're that out to be
kappa and the mean frequency so alpha is the vector of the ranges over the
features one two j
and and is also a factor and so we just set out
some proportionality constant times and and we they'd have to be the same proportionality constant
times one mind
and for all the examples we use
cap-i-tals two
and we never came to work OK
so those fairly robust to changes in half and now
people right
well a little bit and they might say oh but the prior here seems to
depend on the data
which is a little weird but
in fact the prior here
is remember it's the prior on the unknown concept that we're trying to query which
is a subset of the data
so what this prior does is simply
depends on the entire universe of data it simply depends on the average frequency of
in the universe of item OK
so it's not really
the thing that would be really problematic is the prior dependent on the query that
would if we're not doing that we're just say a
we can use some knowledge about how frequent features are
this site
what we think we are a are
are query concept might
involved in fact the prior is simply saying that are query concepts are going to
have on average the
the same each frequencies as far as our universe items
which are frequently
it is very similar to the basic binary model is similar to naive bayes
where you some of the features are independent
naive bayes
usually thought of as the model for classification where
what you have is given each class of the features are independent
we have also
given the concept of the features are independent
but we are not getting the parameters of the model
maximum likelihood
or map or anything like that we're saying
our features are independent we don't know the parameters are so we integrate over the
parameters so yes it is related to the naive bayes in the sense that naive
bayes assumes independent features
let me just be honest
you know in real data i don't believe that the features are going to be
we have the trade-off here between having more and more complicated models that we actually
believe in
but for which these integrals will be very difficult to compute and having a simple
which we think might give us a good approximation
two what we believe it and be able to compute these things extremely efficient so
what we've shown is that for this simple model we can compute all these integrals
extremely efficiently
in california loma linda you see this is the same content which was fermilab way
this injector linac synchrotron this to other people to go there
in a very short time and then that for doing this and almost the entire
which are structures
we support magnets which bend the the up
and down so that you can turn it around
the body of the page to you this is the first hospital-based center which is
treating now fifteen hundred patients a year each patient scams about twenty times so fifteen
one hundred missions twenty times to make a statement
this is the first
the the
singletons i being bedroom in japan
mitsubishi in japan and axel in germany and by i in the states c so
this at two cyclotrons normal cycle
superconducting cyclotron into singletons you recognise this shape
so in short i think this is now commercial producing centers for portal therapies are
commercial and you see here the IBA
this is the same which this cell
a hundred and fifty to thirty million euros
there is a reception
for the visiting visits of the
patients seem
and then the beam is reduced in energy by these energy selection system and then
it goes to the gantries and this is the patient
this is laying here and this is the end of the being which can be
located according to the action chosen by the oncologist
now that is being are more than sixty thousand patients along the eighteen ninety two
thousand you see
now we have and we have about the same as most of them now motion
which are either of those
working of stuff too
treating patients so potent that it is moving because effect
it's certainly better as tissues and it is also i really really
the moment it is certain qualitative quantitative qualitative better than thought
the next is it is not the case for carbon ions because the carbon has
different types
o of therapy it is qualitatively different you make it different to the cell so
that's something which is more recent and that's what i want to discuss
in china back to built by professor lower
twenty years ago and directed since fifteen years first associate medical doctor who was if
physics bees is
this started working ninety two is a genuine carbon therapy it is made of single
you see them in the next to inject in fact there are two singletons very
big ones and there are one two and three to three patients treated five thousand
in this year five thousand patients
it is the
just the center in the world
in germany in the years last ten years
what about the first craft damaged his side and under the leadership of professor the
use of heidelberg clinic is a medical doctor has been in this laboratory to my
lab at GSI
damage that it being carbon ions only horizontal stock going three to treat patients mainly
brain patients in about five hundred being treated that's all what we know so sixty
thousand patients for both only fifty five
for carbon ions
so what have we learned this is all the patients have been treated see this
is a typical body and woman and you can do it but for instance this
could also call must encode almost so we can do something
in the brain
this is soft tissue sarcoma very dangerous tool and is locally advanced prostate carcinoma
a in particular cases for prostate
it's been shown that carbon ions but this is still not a very large number
in spite of the sixty five thousand patients so there's lot of clinical studies to
be done but one can only say something about this for instance the first important
results which has not in boston harbor side then confirmed many other places and has
a long long story because people have been followed for fifteen years
he was in the
i had called control sarcoma single domus which after five years can be controlled ninety
percent to about seventy percent where all conventional radiotherapy
to control them at thirty five percent more recently served as that the jump this
may be due to people with here but still there is a clear advantage was
support of for these students and many others
and for that
this is a complicated table put in so that you do it but only want
to tell you this story numbers for two most of the
palestine as soon as is here you see
in high park
there will be in control only to six percent and the standards twenty distribution for
two most which have to do is very typical to of this kind of therapy
they about eight hundred percent a five-year survival
instead of twenty five percent and for salivary gland tumours was
boasting high sitting at about seventy percent with respect also came to twenty five percent
this at all three and you must you must which is known particularly resistance to
these two match
so the sequence and before
just text
x y
fairly simple just tack on x i
that's the case
is it going on up to
minus one
that's certainly common sequence
x y
i minus one
one to
this is the longest common sequences along its sequence is
from x one i y one j
and we know what the last character is just
equivalently y j
so therefore everything
except the last character
most of these common sequence
i'm much what i might one y one j one
everybody with me
there must be common sequence now
what he also suspect
we also suspect
he won to common sequence of these two
so it's longest common sequence
so that claim
one particular one isn't it
longest common subsequence of x of
i like this one
why j much
so it proved that
claims of several version approved claim
so so us
it is
is there a link to w
the figure
and came minus one
common sequence
the you want to became minus one so it's going to be handling
minus one longer
now what we do is we use the classic argument c
multiple times not just this week which will be important for this week but
through several lectures it's called cut and paste or
the idea is
let's take a look at w
made with the
that last characters UK
this is
it's not just mine
reality for string concatenation
so i take
well acquainted with the longer common
and i
in i nasir pages
that is certainly
common sequence
i one
he has
because basically what is it's like
like the w three c minus one i one character
so this
combination here now is playing bigger than k
and that's a contradiction
thereby proving the point
simply saying
queen this
suppose longer one
let me show you my longer comment sequence the first
prefixes were dropped the character
both strange with long hair
made the whole thing wrong
that be
so therefore this must be a
longest common subsequence
so good afternoon everyone my name's additional i'm going to talk about the UN recognition
in videos by learning from web data
this is joint work with my professor professor to she professor i've gotten from nanyang
technological university in singapore and that the capable of from kodak research labs rochester us
so this is the outline of my presentation
first give you an overview of the event recognition system
and in the system
there two issues
the first issue is how to measure the similarity between videos
to address this issue proposed aligned space time pyramid matching
and the second issue
it is crossed them in his quest to problem and we propose adaptive multiple kernel
learning to solve this problem and give you more details on these two issues later
after that the experimental results followed by conclusions
so first that's looking to the overview of the system
the goal of our system is to recognise consumer videos the consumer videos ideally taken
by consumers during some events such as weddings sports
technique and so on
so customer videos have large intra class variability is
and also
there already i lived in a limited number of
videos because the customers may not be waiting to label lots of videos
so as as using a limited number of
the training samples can america so as to make use of
the with auxiliary data so thanks to the internet they can download videos from the
for example the can of the web videos from youtube so they can leverage large
number of loosely labeled web videos to learn a good classifier for the consumer videos
this is the flow chart of our system
the system is designed in the traditional way that given the video database we first
training class for
and for adding test video will use the cash for two to predict its label
as output
so just as i said there are two issues in the system
the first one is how to measure the similarity between videos
several predetermined matching methods have been proposed to address this issue
i this method each video is divided into multiple volumes on the ten axis space
axes both space and time axes
and this method you have two steps in the first step the
volume two volume distance is computed and then the second step the distance between two
is computed based on the bottom two volume distances
so in
the space pure matching method proposed by doctoral active
the volume of radio can
only in be matched to the video in the same position of not the radio
so following the existing work in are aligned space time pyramid matching we divide each
video into
my people now overlapped space time volumes
here it always the liver number and the experiment was the equal to zero and
and our method one video you might want you the video can be managed to
avoid doing it in the four different positions of not radio
so our method has a greater variability than the online service pyramid matching
for example while object may move around into videos so may appear in different positions
of of the two videos
so in this case our method can match the two volumes both containing the object
but the this template matching cannot
and our method is also a two-step approach
in the first step we directly followed
adaptive work to compute the volume to volume distances
so in that sense that to compute the distance between two videos
there was zero
each radio station directly consider as space time volumes so the distance between two videos
can be directly attend
at one which divide each video into eight that overlapped space time volumes with the
same size
and the way i don't
integer flow EMD
the worst distance to compute distance between the two videos so after performing major flow
earthmover distance we can find the best matching between the volumes so for example in
this figure the
two what is the right colour match
and two volumes in green colour amassed and so on the rest rest photos
so with the
after finding the most voters we can compute the
the distance between two videos with
and the distance between the master volume
so the here comes the second you show that there is a cross the problem
so as we know
the customer videos and naturally captured by consumers and the web videos may
maybe edited and they are usually selected before uploading onto the internet so that the
distribution of this
of the consumer videos and that we use may be different
so let us consider the customer video
consumer videos as the target domain and videos as a source domain
so too many the
the distribution mismatch between the two as we are not a criteria accord that's meets
discrepancy MMD
in this criteria
the each sample x is mapped into a higher dimensional space phi x
as the MMD computes the distance between the means of the two distributions
and also in the preserve somehow this the statistics
and there was some simple mathematical operations we can simply by the square of the
MMD distance
and the trace of
that is k times metrics this here the escapees could come and fix it is
i and we we so this already that the expectation of a nature the conditional
probability is the optimal fire risk right we can't do any better than minimize pointwise
OK so you know that's it the the the
the heart of it is just yet and inequality once we have the
the right definition for this function psi
that's all i wanted to say about this relationship between excess risk and excess phi
risk you know we have
simple conditions
we get a picture of we have the simple condition that but for convex functions
phi the only thing that we need to cheque is the behavior
at zero needs to be differentiable zero and have the negative gradient and obviously this
is the case for for all of these functions
right and any other cost function that we dream up and there have been
many of these in in the literature you can immediately check if that
does indeed make sense from the point of view of that classification
what i would look at next is exploiting this relationship between excess risk and excess
by risk to come up with some idea of of
how rapidly we are
minimising the risk
right by looking at how
we minimize the fire risk
let's get back to that
OK so i will look now at the natural approximation estimation decomposition that the PC
in the first talk we saw an approximation estimation decomposition for
for risk where we said well we've got some class of functions were concerned with
if we're choosing from that class
you know there is that the natural action of approximation error there was the infimum
over the class
of the risk
right of some function
here where we're not we're not working with the minimal risk of threshold functions right
we're not we're not really shooting for for for such a thing all we're trying
to do is minimized the fire risk and so the natural way to define
the approximation errors in terms of this virus
OK so for thinking of st ann's right it's the minimum over over here
ball in an RKHS for instance of the
one of the expectation of this hinge
a of this hinge loss
OK this is the
in the natural way to define think i guess i guess it might be worthwhile
actually that's one another example that's with with thinking about what is this function phi
look like for the hinge loss i guess i need to connect the picture there
is piecewise linear
and so
psi is just a linear function
right so the relationship between between the excess risk and excess by risk in that
case is just linear
right so we have we have the best possible convex
in that case
OK so let's
let's look at this
the approximation estimation decomposition
so step back now and think about a general
model selection kind of approach and will view
various of these large margin classification algorithms in this kind of way
right so
let's think of
two approaches to mention this
earlier i guess two approaches to
minimizing the
the fire escape are very rich class i suppose we have a very rich class
like the span of
decision trees in sense of spanish function disinterested inside or
a reproducing kernel hilbert space which means that we think of it as being a
of some
the complexity classes writing as k increases with think even more
complex classes may be bigger balls in reproducing kernel hilbert space or maybe
we split up the standard according to the number of terms in a linear combination
for instance right so so
you know this is a method of sieves kind of approach was splitting splitting a
average class up into
into this this hierarchy which using a function as
the minimizer over some
if k in in the hierarchy year of the empirical forest and the k that
we choose will eat some increasing function of a right so as sample size increases
we might choose more complex
more complex class perhaps bigger
bowling RKHS we minimize the empirical forest cover
over the bigger ball
minimizex the sample average of the hinge loss for instance
an alternative and this is where you should have used the adaboost example appear in
alternative and this is more like what's done in the SVM case we might choose
the minimum over
the the full class of you know some regularized version of the empirical fires
right so we add a regularisation functional right this
the negative f is
it's like the
squared RKHS norm in this case
we have some regularisation coefficient
written as lambda then so is the sample size n increases we would expect to
which we should be somehow decreasing the regularisation right
is there
third lecture
devoted to nuclear physics
i'm going to give you you some examples of recent studies that are made so
nowadays so these are both experimental studies
theoretical studies that i made all over the world
so i will first about the figure of merit of the present approaches so
very good results compared to experimental data
what about exotic nuclei
isomers shape coexistence super behavior
and i want to talk just a little bit concerning these weak interactions i have
question two days ago and what how can we test the fundamental symmetries and this
weak interactions
i want to
to begin with this
extensive calculations that are from now because because of this
huge computer where
we can now have two flow computer so we can really former systematic calculations so
as many nuclei as we want so we can really
check how
valid in the theory that we use so that's why a lot of different groups
have from this kind of systematic calculations
to compare with all the experimental data
so this work as big as began in two thousand seven and still continuing now
for different labels
so this is the main thing base calculations for the first two plastic citation
in even even nuclei
what is plotted here in the exhibition in energy for theory
and here experiment
so the straight line means that you have perfect calculations
and all the points out the calculated points
so two plus states have been observed and studied in five hundred fifty seven
nicky i
so calculation having banned from almost all these nuclei i except sixteen
the lightest one
so why
so the reason that i told you this yesterday that when we are doing kind
of mean field calculation we are averaging over the number of nucleons
so when this number is too small the average is not good at all and
we can not make this approximation
so that's why these nuclei
are always eliminated when you are looking at a mean field based calculations
so what are the main feature so the simplex theory experiments here
so you see first that it goes from a few kb two if you amy
so three orders of magnitude
between means that these two players depending on the nucleus you're looking at
the structure of the nature is completely different you can be
vibrational states
none collective states are rotational states are mixing all of that
and depending on the nucleus and the method that to use you can have
better results for a given class of nuclei
and here you see that here you have a very good agreement
and these correspond to
strongly deformed actinides so
let's figure shows you
that this approach based on the mean field on collective motion is good for that
kind of nuclei
when you have here
very high energy for the two plus you see that the scattering is bigger
which means that the method is not valid
this as valid as for here
it's because you neglected kind of correlations
and what is neglected here this coupling between intrinsic excitations collective motion
what is important also these points so you see that you have some but the
logical point so this is very important to know
what all these points on why you are so bad here
these correspond to
neutron for mandatory and later isotopes
and we try to know why it's not so good for these points on your
viewpoint and it seems to be
that is because the single particle levels for that region is not reproduced so well
by the theory
it's because of the shape coexistence that seems that we have
a discrepancy
so we try to improve that point and we
i think you can help
for the other so
in fact even if it's not good to have such point we like it because
we can improve the theory
if we look now for the same calculation the quadrupole deformation so quickly moment theory
and experiment
so we have these different points here
there were a few nuclei where
we didn't know the sign at the moment either politics or overlaid so we do
not know the sign experimentally
so we have to do that twice so positive
and negative
and we see that in order to to have an agreement with experiment
we predict that these nicolai should be
all eight with a negative quadrupole moment
what this calculation showing that we can make some prediction where we have call it
and it seems to be reliable to be able then to make some predictions
in other new nuclear and so what we call the exotic nuclei
so now i'm going to go to these exotic nuclei what are the
durante shows now it is
so this is the nuclear charge
so what are the subject of interest are also neutron and proton drip lines
what we call drip line i will explain to you
this limit of existence
what can often of nuclei do exist
how those genes and molecules structures are
new shared structure
nuclear shapes
also concerning astrophysics for the different processes are process no ve extreme burst happy process
and supernovae
super heavy elements
many things concerning applications
also these
new decay modes nuria radioactivity you you can a need for proton rich nuclear you
can emit two proton and neutron
in coincidence
and also concerning neutron production pairing
i have the question yesterday concerning after lecture concerning BCS state so these superb wiki
that we have in the
in the nuclei
so we know that in the nucleus i we do have these superior trinity so
that the nucleons do form some peer support and put onto neutral photon pairs we
spin that's spin down so they gain energy like that
and what is what we think now is that for a number four nuclei having
the same number of proton and neutron
you can have and you should have these kind of neutron important feeling so the
pair formed was put onto neutral and they should appear for
neutron and proton with this with an
when you have the same number of neutrons for so you have many many
theoretical work devoted to that subject
it is very difficult to to find an experimental observable for that
because it's not and direct proof so we have different ideas how to change that
but it's not so easy it's not when they went directly to check
so i'm going to talk about all these red points and a little bit of
love this one
so the main questions are what are the limits to nuclear existence what new forms
will be found in nuclei
thanks so much to the
a participants and organizers been so possible to me
especially specially jeff was then
watching over me from
for many weeks now step in and thank you
i am
i've never been treated so really before
and i'm very excited to be learned for the first time a begin to to
learn about learning about
the machine learning this is
it shows you the first pages
are some years
for this is that i didn't then winkle in the tower of ivory tower of
mathematical philosophy and poetry
most of my mathematical life though when i was closer to your age
i did do some useful things but i am
the most probable became obsessed with the
philosophy and poetry
this is going to work the flickr
they found
this is an outline of the talk first world world
linear programming philosophy and then well
i will present for
there was another
details of the
papers the ancient papers that asian artifacts just point two
look at some of the details of those
and then we show you one
application but i can promise you that is actually useful application is the beautiful application
but number one it depends on you
find something practical to do with it
a member two
it depends on you to implement
there these are happened
optimum branching systems
it is a very sophisticated applications
ah parliamentary theory
and it's c
the only reasonable way i discovered
the the
however the
algorithms for
for solving a as as
versions of
well submodular minimisation and more
as you will see
what is the branching
does anybody have a marker
it suspended in a directed graph
you have a directed graph with weights on the edges
a vaccine is a spanning tree
branching rooted at branching rooted at node v sub-zero
is this spanning tree such that every pattern the tree
from this route said there is a directed back
uses all the time
everybody uses is well
i call branches spanning tree
so is every path from the root is directed
efficient algorithms for finding a cheapest or most valuable if you prefer
branching rooted at a given node
right so this the trade off between the two
another example
it would be
one of those p norm algorithms the divergence is now
this is very weird thing it's not nice circles but it's somewhat complicated divergence
right something like this
i have the trade-off between the two
and now in this case i would go to this point
OK it's more complicated
so i want to get a flavor
to prove relative loss bounds
so now i go on
i have one of those updates
one of those updates that look like this
this kind of update
and i do it on the tribe by trial basis
and now i want to found somehow the total loss of the algorithm
the loss looks something like this
it's the in it it depends on the instance and the weight vector
the divergence looks like this
they update looks like this
you can if you apply if you move it to the other side you apply
f minus one you get the normal kind of
OK so how do i get about in the online algorithms there is always some
kind of telescoping so how do you set up this telescoping
so you take
you're loss
of any
parameter vector
you expand that loss
so the taylor expansion
the current weight vector
rights issue of convexity
of the last which you need here
this is bigger than equal to
you get this kind of thing
here you have the gradient
this gradient here
you can replace by this formula by the you can use the update now
and get end up at this
but this is the box
remember that was one of those properties so i can get these three
divergences in here
so i took
convexity had a gradient of the loss from the gradient i plug in the update
now use the box formalized and up at this
and now you can see already that these two terms telescope and this is an
additional term so these two terms telescope
so some over trials
some of the trials here the tree divergences
and then what happens is
these two the first two terms telescope
this one is positive you throw it away
and then you have these terms that accumulate
so you end up with this very concise formula
loss of the algorithm
this is the last of the i'm try one two three up until trial t
loss of the compared
the distance of the compared to the initial weight vector last these
costs for changing your weight vector that accumulate which also involved
the bregman divergence
OK so i still have this final term
this one is still amassed
what i need to do is i need to relate this to the loss of
the algorithm which are not showing in this
case gets too complicated
and then you solve and you get the bound of this type were the loss
of the total loss of the algorithm
is always as good as the total loss of the
compared to
in the original piece of the editorial was to compare was always an expert now
the compared it could be a linear combination
plus the distance
of the initial weight vector
the start with that the of the compared to the start with vector and these
are constants that depend on the learning rate
very often you get bounds that
can be one so that
the total loss of the algorithm is at most the speed the total loss of
the compared
some scale terms
he is the kind of balance that you might get
yes you may incorporate again gradient descent we linear regression square loss
gradient descent motivated by euclidean distance squared
exponentiated gradient algorithm
offensive norm my
the kind of bound you get
are total loss of the algorithm
so almost as big as
total loss of the compared to times one plus e
sum norm term this at the two numbers of the instances times the two norm
of the weight vector
where the constants that depend the c depends on the learning rate
OK exponentiated gradient algorithm very similar form
except to pay different tool norms here
p norm algorithm which interpolates between two
that your corresponding peano menu norms so this would be the in the maximum infinity
norm of the instances one norm of the comparator
it turns out that
the only norm that is rotation invariant the two norms
members that the multiplicative problems were better when the target was sparse
and actually
and the instances were
bounded nicely between plus and minus one that is hard money examples the classical example
it turns out in this case
this product of two unknowns is very small was this product of two unknowns happens
to be very big
these two are norms actually show you
which of the two families are good in particular problem
if you have a practical problem
i always try both families
each bregman divergence is going to be given or family of all updates
but the main ones are always
gradient descent and exponentially gradient
questions at this point so what did i did what did i do
i introduced
a notion of divergence
of functions
we simply
we simply say that
since we don't know what our distribution is simply
place prior directly
on the distribution
so this prior distribution on distribution
and of course
this prior
we will be using a dirichlet process for this
the bayesian non parametric approaches
we say that our axis
is distributed according to some distribution at
which we don't know
so being bayesian we place a prior on
this being the dirichlet process prior
and then again we do exactly the same thing in which we
we can then compute the posterior distribution
over distribution at
the discount we
and the posterior is again given by the prior multiplied by the likelihood
normalized by the marginal likelihood of the data
and again we can do prediction in this case we simply want to play
the probability of x our even training
beta x
and again we integrate here
of course
after that
is the distribution we interested in those
the probability of x given as is simply
well actually that that you get is simply that you have
x y
actually this is not quite correct
i will come back to this point but
but the general idea so
the bayesian approach but the density estimation is
one two
we don't know that they are we don't know the underlying distribution from which the
they data come from
we simply place prior directly on
class of the distribution and then again can we apply to be a missionary
but so that's estimation
could actually is that it yes
OK so that's kind of the PCB which is actually
really that's what i've been talking about actually the question forgot to repeat what is
this at the distribution of them
in this case the way of writing this it is a distribution
if the distribution is more than half the that the and help
equivalent basically
i'm not quite sure what the question and the question was that you were saying
that they usually the distribution of the easy to estimate but not the density
but presumably believe that is true only in that one dimension although dimensions
it's probably not true for high dimensional
in which you have been in machine learning that
what well into our
come to that is that
the difference between the distribution later
right so that that information so here's a little
not sure what what
happens OK
so in our prior we may say
the red line so we we can draw samples from our distribution from the prior
and this being
the little each of the line here lot
actually the density of the
of the distribution to to be drawn from the prior
and you know they all now look
so this might be one
sample from the prior to look like that
and another example of this is mentioned line out of town
is it around the area
another one is that this
this blue line which has little who you can see
and the grey areas again held like the
fifty two ninety eight percent one of
and all of the
the prior over the over the density
the red line is the mean that he
and the blue is the medium
the new data point will tell us anything about what they really other data points are
if we don't know the location of the red line
and we know part of these data points
now whereas the next data point going to be we can tell
it's much more likely to be in this region then somewhere over here
a conditional unconditional they are not independent
okay so now the definition that we need all that the characterization that we need in order to
at a given criterion four fore this conditional independence something called exchangeability
and exchangeability is following
we see in
we assume that we see an infinite sequence of
random variables
you know that they there is an infinite sequence of such
blue dots here for example
and now we
they they have we look at the joint distribution of these
of these
of the stadium
and now we ask
what happens if we permute the order
in which the state of these data points coming
that the distribution is called exchangeable are also sequences called exchangeable
so the probability of seeing a particular sequence of data points doesn't depend
on this order so we can permute them
and it will not change the probability of occurrence and
so very simply
the order of the observations doesn't matter
this is a very nice
it's a very nice assumption for several reasons one is it's
it's certainly true that data is i i d
see that they decided we can shuffle it around
and so it's but it doesn't have to be i i
and so it's more in in a sense it's a more
it contains the assumption that we usually making parametric origin
nonparametric statistics the idea assumption a special case
okay so that's a good start
in in a way it's actually the same thing as the idea assumption but
let let's not get into that discussion
you know the thing is that it's
one thing is it's often true yeah you thing is it's also
relatively easy to argue
whether this is true or not
now if you know something about how your data is being generated
then it might be very hard to argue that the data is i i d e
but it's it's often it's reasonably easy to say okay the order in which the data come in
contains information are doesn't
you just you know if you know that the data generating process
okay so this is exchangeability
and now there's this
this theorem called the finetti theorem
which is
really want the the very basic theorems underlying
bayesian inference
and this this tells us
in short tells us the data is conditionally idea that exchangeable
if and only if
and so we can check whether this this conditional idea assumption whether that makes sense
by checking whether the order in which the data points coming matters not
and that's let's look at this in in a bit more detail
so what we see over here
it is again the joint distribution of the data points
what we have here on the other side is
integral over r
the parameter and i've now written the parameters he has a probability distribution
in the parameters not probability distribution
this year is again the prior distribution
and now the prior distribution is a distribution over probability distributions
okay so we sample a random probability distribution from this q
then we fix it and we sample
these points from that distribution that we've just generated around
and how do we sample them
i i d e because we have this product
the product society
okay so what this here says is
the distribution is exchangeable
if and only if
we can generated in this way and we put it is some distribution on probability distributions
we draw from that we draw probability distribution grand and fix it
and then sample data from
if you have to make it
quite which
so there like
when you
so what
so the back end
what makes a lot of
by first because it can help
in which
usually but always
great going
one of the great
o she had five
approximation calculate the canadian
completely have one
so the brain and
just based on the web
complex ran
some of the little bit better
it is one of the both of
pixels which
two weeks
so you know one
and these
one our over three
the british
x y
and it is
coli like this
x y
the former
it will used to just quickly
they can do it because
one the
and the great thing about
in addition to having
we're sorry
you can also look like right
and if you like
with me
but second
let let alone take a
because there
so with that
the the
because it
and how we can move on the fact that the
i can look like
we're like
mexican hat
we will explain why
you know what was
actually i was
so the biggest
two things the moment
and we have this
we have
which really and the biggest one
the bigger
and all the during
but the main
the reason why why
it's not a it's actually
ten years later
you're think
this is
what you to be each
but you have change
with small
changes then it will be totally removed by
look like
we can apply to what was
apply the floodlights equivalent to applying first
the population was
so you have
picture picturehouse
let's go look like this
all like nick
we try to be
it will be like so you can imagine is a whole
did you
because the image
we were we
in this class in this lecture we are going to discuss things that a little
bit more qualitative rather than quantitative
but it's the kind of concept that you would not have been able to understand
unless you went to the pain of the previous three lectures
what we've learned so far is that we need and the entire chemistry
are a very small minority of the universe
a lot of the universe is made by
some type of matter that we haven't seen directly yet and some type of energy
that is even weirder than that
and this is even made it to the the first page of the new zealand
say that ninety six percent of the universe is missing
so basically the
cosmology has what is called the standard cosmological model which sees the model described by
for example the cosmic pi that i'm showing you before
and do you know we know that each of these parameters to determine we percent
but there are some
things down there despite this impressive agreement of you ever more than a few parameters
you can describe the evolution of the universe seems to be a hundred and eighty
thousand years after the big bang and basically today
there's a lot we don't understand
and so all or embody if you can the impact these a little bit like
painting by designing the funniest woman up here and there is the concordance
OK everybody is happy that rangers but when you go and look this below the
surface case there's a lot of you know less angelic stuff going on
so let's go back to the twentieth century remember we discussed this before i einstein
that the friedmann equation to make the universe started because that's was on five to
from the
and interpretation of this stand was that the matter energy density is equal minus the
pressure and if you do that you get
and acceleration equation that you can make it equal to zero and the freeman equation
you can make the size to zero so you can make a static universe and
this is static universe will be positive because you
it's like a fine balance between all the terms and then you get
a static universe but you have to introduce this for
this was what einstein called it the greatest blunders of his life so in the
nineteen ninety i stand in the theory of relativity actually predict this function of the
universe right you have an unstable
mark will make the universe the expansion of the universe in oslo down and then
the collapse but seems the universe has collapsed yet and we have been around for
a pretty long time
then it's then it's more likely to say that this actually responding rather than you
know to collapse in on itself but again an expanding universe is not aesthetically pleasing
this was equation it like that so he had the time to make the universe
is static cosmological constant in the interpretation of this term in this equation is that
this land is the energy of empty space and this was discussed before
it's empathy and it's got an energy associated with a dozen lose because how can
you do something that is empty
it's empty already
and so this is the story of the vacuum energy over also called cosmological constant
that can edit and this is a picture from nineteen seventeen of einstein and matter
because the universities actually dominated by something like a vacuum energy goes under the name
of an american university because it was this guy that actually work it out and
in this guy was was the first priest
but it was really interested in science
so let's do some
thermodynamic arguments of
what wide islam this so we so imagine you have a piece them with some
vacuuming and this vacuum and some cosmological constant so the whoever volume v one in
and if there is some energy associated with it the energy corresponding to volume one