on the open market
whereas if an editors should repeal is worth three
and by the time we add up all the NADH is that had that have
been generated
by the cycling
and the carbon dioxide released at the end of the cycle here we start with
two carbons added to four we get six carbon molecules
we we spew up some carbon dioxide here go back to four carbon sugar
and another two
go up to six carbon go around again spin around the wheel and each time
we do that we generate a lot of NADH is we generate a lot of
effort ages is and we generate a lot of ATP
in all cases these are highly profitable reactions simply because the NADH is
and f eighty eight can be used in the mitochondria to generate ATP so let's
at the energy profile of the entire
put it all together
this is where we started out
at the beginning
and this is as far as
the end this is the end the glycolysis OK so now we're adding up
the energy profiles of the whole sequence of reactions that constitute glycolysis which begins up
here and and right here because pyruvate as you recall
is the product of glycolysis the first
the krebs cycle happens or sometimes is called the citric acid cycle
so let's let's just get these words straight citric acid cycle because it happens to
be one of the
cycle or sometimes called the krebs cycle
after the person who really discovered krebs
the krebs cycle begins here you see how the shading changes from pyruvate
and here we go all the way down there
and let's now look at what happens in terms of energy exchange
recall the early on we need to invest ATP's two
kick up the energy state up to a year
we invested ATP's at this stage right here and then we began to get some
we've got these two NADH is one NADH coming from each of the three carbon
we we you we got some more ATP's here we got some more ATP senior
and but these NADH is could not be used productively
before generating ATP
in the absence of oxygen
but in the presence of oxygen
now we can begin to use these very profitably we can use these to these
makes three ATP's
and each of these obviously makes ATP's and then let's look at what happens in
the mitochondria
keep in mind here is the borderline between the cytosol the cytoplasm and mitochondria and
here's where the oxygen is actually used
and here we generate all these NADH is
here here and here f eighty ages is
and i keep saying it's still true just cut in spite of the fact that
keeps saying that these NADH is can be converted to ATP is on the ATP
is going to be diffused transmitted throughout the entire cell where they are then used
invested in organic reactions
here here we see all these NADH is
and look at the overall change in free energy
the initial steps in glycolysis didn't really take advantage glucose has inherent in it
almost six hundred eighty killer calories from all that it's pretty high up here
but by the time we get from here down here
there's an enormous release of energy
it's harvested in the form of these molecules which are then
reinvested in the absence of oxygen this entire procedure can only go from here down
here and a lot of this drop from here six to seven
is futile because we have to reinvest these and it this can be used actually
to generate more ATP as i've said repeatedly
so this means
in the end that we can generate an enormous amount of
different kinds of knowledge can be brought to bear on this task now psychologist will
do things like
compare how people rate the strength of arguments or compare pairs of arguments and say
which is stronger which is the better generalisation and say if we compare these three
people typically think this is stronger
generalisation that knowing the gorilla seals and scrolls have some arbitrary biological property provide better
evidence for thinking that horses do that for thinking that flies do or and also
better evidence for thinking courses do than if you were told that say this property
was true of gorillas chimps monkeys baboons in which case you might think it's just
something specific to primates and explain this with a more-or-less informal notions of similarity in
but we want to get a bit more formal
well a lot more formal
and so how are you going to do this well here's a way to render
the computational problem
there's a bunch of objects in the domain that we know something about
and what we know about
this domain will start off with a most concrete level of knowledge will just be
various features we know about these things so for example again psychologists have collected a
lot of data on what features people will
i will know for different animals so there's that we're in this case you're going
to use of a matrix of objects feature judgments but has eighty five features for
fifty animals and a bunch of subjects rated how
how much each feature is associated with each animal and these features are just sort
of basic are observable anatomical behavioral ecological properties the kind of things that child walking
around as you're reading your kids books about animals might learn so for example the
features that are strongly associated with elephant are
things like being gray hairless toughskin
big bulbous body shape long legs
tasks walking being slow
living in the jungle that kind of thing being strong
so there's this matrix of of sort of known facts about these animals and there
some new properties like say having t nine hormones that is less observable that we're
interested in if you think it's a little bit weird to be reasoning about having
t nine hormones
i think of a more naturalistic task where you're reasoning about whether something is good
to eat or whether it's poisonous or whether it wants to you these are very
ecologically important reasoning task which again we typically get very sparse data on you want
to be able to infer if some you know which things are going to be
poisonous from as little data as possible
but here psychologists have used the so-called plain predicates to be is in some sense
knowledge free is possible except the fact that they drawn some more abstract knowledge about
biological species and properties hence something like having t nine hormones and the idea is
we just observe that new property for a couple of objects and we want to
know how likely to other things have this property so somehow we need to in
a sense bridge from a lot of features that we can observe more densely to
some new features which are less densely observed again you can think of this as
a kind of transfer learning problem but now where these objects instead of being independent
draws from a bag are actually related in some interesting way to each other and
you can also think of this is a kind of semi supervised learning problem and
that there's a few labeled examples and a lot of unlabelled data and we want
to learn some inductive bias to generalize to new property as as well as we
from all the unlabelled data
and i think the techniques that we're developing here we have applications for semi supervised
learning in fact an earlier version of this i think in this it when not
injuries use some semi supervised learning tutorial yesterday he talked about an early version of
this with the tree based prior so here's the idea of of the model it
again a hierarchical bayesian model where the lowest level or call the level of the
data is the stuff i already told you about features you can observe these animals
and new features that you want to generalize from sparse data
and then we're gonna
we're going to
try to address that problem with two levels of a higher level background knowledge of
hi the most immediate level of what we call the structure
it's just some kind of relational system over these object categories which which we we
so this is nothing else but the gradient and when they integrate gradient
i actually get the love plus well i don't get the lot less in itself
but if i integrate gradient squared of function which was that for relational it's still
the for the famous taking the inner product between f and love plus of
so plants have basically controls how small
the function
this is
i don't want to access connections
so this quantity
is actually contrary to smooth the quantity leads directly to the plus so in some
sense alive plus
is a very natural formulation of this notion of more
and what you believe this well you can build algorithms based on that
two different things and those organisms actually work pretty well in practice
OK so let me again should gives a little bit
so this is a kind of semisupervised learning so
i hope i have convinced you that the
that the geometry isn't near intrinsically natural to semi supervised learning learning and
the laplacian is one of the natural objects to come out of this if you
formulate the problem in this way
which is
the only way but it's certainly one of the natural
ways to formulate
let me talk about clustering
so what can we say about clustering so this kind of rounds up the main
topics of
o four
this tutorial so what can we say
about cluster
and i'll talk about clustering and i'll talk about spectral clustering in the connection to
the geometry pass
business spectral clustering
so first question is the falling so the the fifth kind of it's interesting because
this is actually if you think about clustering around clustering is the mainstream
you know statistical computer science
problem in fact it's practically extremely important in a lot of applications
but the clustering but you have some data you have to do something with it
well i cluster look at what again
for one way to actually look at putting in some sort of dimensionality reduction right
you reduce information obtained from the data so instead of looking at the milan points
i just have maybe twenty classed as well that season
some summary of the
but here is a sort of mathematical question
right so i suppose you have points sampled from a probability distribution
as in most statistical setting what we have and if points are sampled from a
probability distribution
what is the clustering of the data
and the remarkably or what is a good clustering mean obviously not every day that
i don't want to go into which they can be clustered which cannot but obviously
this is a list is the natural question right i sample from from the probability
college with a cluster this point well if you sort of abstract from the point
itself support there already knows the probability distribution how should i just cluster the probability
distribution and if it's a mixture of two gaussians for example which is separated we
would expect the gaussians with the clusters
interestingly enough there is almost there is very little work on this in the statistical
literature there are some
results and consistency of clustering
from the eighties but very few those all of things
hartigan also
consistency of k means and some single linkage but
but basically the question is what clusters how if i just give you a probability
distribution what are the clusters of the probability distribution there is probably no single answer
to that
and about the question needs to be considered
oh yeah and very importantly how does one estimate this cluster scheme find the data
and i'm going to make a suggestion
about what this clusters maybe in fact maybe should discuss
so let's consider to set
one setting
is when i have
the image is given the example of what
let me just give an example of
two situation when i think there is no clear clustering which agrees with our intuition
this kind of geometry is clearly going to help us to understand what it
OK so one situation is the following
one situation
mixture of gaussians
OK so suppose they have to gauss in distribution
so imagine i have to go sometimes like this one like that
and the density is the sum of this two girls it's
in fact this is one of the
is actually one of the all the questions that this this model in fact is
one of the oldest things in statistics
from nineteen century mixture of gaussians
so here's the question well when the gaussians are separated presumably
a good clustering so you kind of have
you know
o point here the points here maybe a few points in between
presumably good clustering should be something which separates nicely those girls it's that's very clear
somehow everyone would agree
let's look at that picture
and this is partially obscured by this
access connections menu
let's look at this picture so suppose i have two spheres
so suppose might be probability distribution is the following i have two large spheres
so imagine just two
so you can see there are two things which you can imagine let's just imagine
the simple one when the balls not holding field
essentially they are
about two important livestock
one is the good news and the other one is the bad news
and simultaneously you have bought
the good news is that the
if you
get the problem for example classification
increasing the sample size to infinity
and the
hard already complicate the classification problem can be solved
which means that there are classification rules
four reach
the error probability of the classification rule
to the best possible
smallest possible error probability
if the sample by the we know any condition on the problem
this is the good news
university college
the bad news
that there is no non-trivial rate of convergence
which means that maybe you come up with a good classifier are you have a
program very many experiments
and there you are very proud of its successful
and you would like to sell these programs to make and you say that
let's see if you have a sample of size n
then the rate of convergence
our each other
you're the you are probably of your classifier goes to the
smaller error probability
the rate of convergence cannot be smaller than one of the local or global
then i can show you
one dimension of feature
and why
four reach although property goes to the smallest one
but the difference between the
you're you're are probably the and
smallest one
it these difference is larger than this one overall
the the one hand you can discover any
complex and hard part of the world
but the price to be paid for it
could we have a very high
so if you get there and medical screening project huge huge grand
on the one hand neglecting the the expert knowledge
physicians for example at a screening
of four brady being the possible hard rock within a year or something like that
then we all the
using the expert knowledge the physician knowledge
you can generate classifiers such that if the sample size infinity you achieve the
the best possible our probability
but the rate of convergence can be arbitrary slow
which means that in order to have trivial
the rate of convergence you have less human being on the distribution
which means that you have to do
because the experts of the problem
we have
go over with
physician but it was too too much sorry
the definition is here
i think that the top you the right people
nothing of it
it my my wife could come up with an idea
the four fifty and we have a definition
it could be bad or good
i don't know
we call these
elementary portfolios the
portfolio the choice of or audio has two parameters k and al
this is that repetition of the of the procedure
maybe you can
and then
so i don't quite know how they're behaving and it's quite possible that they are
actually using additional information so
for example a to the doctors using this additional information which will be part of
your strategy
which you don't have to observe in order to choose a two
as well as all everything else
so got the dotted line because it's not there when you actually applies strategy but
in the ideal regime where you just observing in my view there
there are other things that might be there
might be other so this is a very special case
but let's suppose that we can model it that way and what is it for
is that into that again
by d separation moralisation it says various things one thing it says
is that l this additional patient variable variables the response is the patient's blood count
after you've given so many cc's of this injection it says that this is independent
of the strategy in particular
how you came to choose to give that doesn't matter that there is a sort
of natural modular components irrespective of what you do and how you decide what to
do which says howell depends on a one
likewise it says the response y
if i tell you a one a two and l one
the model for how why depends on those again is going to be the same
in all possible regimes
again this is a story which might or might not be a true story
and you have to think about whether you can justify it before you use that
picture to work out its consequences but it's interesting to do the analysis might a
part of work i recommend you very highly utterly wonderful but where i think he
falls down to is he doesn't pay enough attention to getting started
he says once we got it we do these great things with which is perfectly
but once you DAG a big step you've got to say why is this the
appropriate representation of my problem and then his context argument
typically yes the there this the additional variables i mean this is an intermediate outcome
which represents the patient's progress
well these are the two actions i take but
i'm i might depending the might be about this some random coin flipping i might
or might not be able to reproduce alpha most probably not
this is this could be binary things just stop going various circumstances could be continuous
so yes to the question what do we need only answer is my story that
i'm telling here we need to
so the point is to say that
even though sort of go back even though you is in that picture
diagram represents these conditional independencies in which you does not make is not mentioned
so that picture even with the u allows me to say this is and when
i can say those things i can do quite a lot but other pictures will
not allow me to do that if for example this additional variable had an effect
on the response
then you could use the d separation moralisation
to deduce that from the picture
so my to my not hold depends on the exact assumptions you make that if
if you're lucky enough that doesn't hold
you can argue in favor of that story then you're have cost
what i care about is the distribution of the predictive distribution of the outcome when
i operator particular strategy
so i decided my strategy was sort of outcomes and i'm going to get
i haven't ever observed data doing that i've only got my observation about
so i'm i'm making this bold induction but what i do is i actually get
joint distribution for all the stochastic variables i integrate out these three so that's what
these gone and the joint distribution a one distribution by one
given sigma
that's fine because i told you what the strategy is so you know exactly how
anyone will
be chosen in that strategy possibly deterministically possibly with the coin tossing
then i consider the l given a one
really it should be l given sigma and a one should in principle depend on
the strategy but i have we don't care about the strategy because l is independent
of strategy saying the ones i know i one
again we come to a two
that's the end
conditional on the part of a one and now
and that will probably will depend on the strategy sigma notice that
the strategy sigma is an interventional strategy so this dotted arrows going away
the in these strategies only going to depend on the observed variables
and i know i've told you what that is that's written down my piece of
and finally this last is why should be given sigma but once again because of
this property it doesn't matter and i get that from the observation regime so by
combination of ingredients from ingredients from the observational regime
and some ingredients which are written down on a piece of paper which tells me
what my strategy is i competed altogether and what was so sometimes you can do
this when you can get these properties sometimes you can't it all depends on the
exact assumptions that you can actually make
you isn't so the question is you've been integrated out yes and no universal you
is not observed by in is not part of your strategy allowed to observe the
you're observing maybe using he may be observing if you don't have been integrated in
a sense yes but not directly has spinning in an integrated by being ignored this
is the law of property so forget the picture this is the property of the
four variables l a one a two and y
you i could mention you as well but i don't have to because i don't
care about it and now i sort of immediately restricted to the distribution of these
and has these properties and i just use that
so this is this is to get there are many many problems that you can
approach with this technology this is to give you flavor some
thank you very much
so the question is if it is a latent variables connected to order stochastic variables
are you in love from the is generally it generally you are in trouble
generally in the presence of unobserved latent variables which for you can't get the complete
joint distribution and you can related to the cross generally you're in trouble and there's
almost the same class, so--
so you can have classes merging.
it's just a much better way of handling data with multiple manifolds.
you go up in dimensionality and then squeeze out the excess freedom
by doing this kind of learning.
o thing
OK, two layers work better.
so there's empirical results for this. i'll show some more empirical results later.
i can give you
a rationalisation rather than an intuition
here's a rationalization. suppose i wanted a generative model.
in this RBM here
by using pairwise interactions, can create these ravines
you can't create ravines by pairwise interactions here 'cause the interactions won't do what you want.
but you can do it up here
and then we need a layer of hidden units to map these things to
so if you view it that way 'round, it's just
you somehow create the ravines here
and then you map them nonlinearly to the image
that sort of justifies that architecture,
a bit.
well, at least rationalizes it
i also did some fine tuning of this
to make it be a better generator
and i'm not going to sort of focus on the fine tuning in this tutorial
it turns out we can now learn these things without any fine-tuning and have them work
just about as well
certainly without this kind of generative fine tuning
this is in the tutorial so you can go read it if you want
and maybe in question time you can ask me more about this, but i'm not going to
dwell on it now
so now i want to show you is what happens if we
layers to model the images like that
so there is the same network
i actually programmed all of this except the interface. the very cool-looking interface was done by
an undergraduate who looked at my demo and said, i can make your demo look much cooler
so here's the image, here's 500, binary features, 500, 2000. here's the ten labels
here's the identities of the labels: nought, one, two, and so on
here's some images that we can feed to the network
so let's first get it to do some perception, some recognition
we feed in a four
and now what we can do is just run it: boing boing boing boing like
and see what it thinks
is--and we're gonna run it as a stochastic binary network
so you see these keep changing, these keep changing, and these keep changing, each time we do
but this never changes.
it's very sure that that's a four.
now if i run it faster, you'll see there's a subset of these that don't change much like that
one there,
and you can see that if i run fast
your visual systems will do nice things for you
you see this sort of static subset popping out
i have training in psychology, so we need to do a control experiment to make sure it
doesn't always see a four
so it saw a five almost all the time there.
of course we can now be mean to it
and give it things where it's not quite clear what they are.
you'll see it spends most of its time oscillating between four and eight,
which seems pretty appropriate there.
occasionally thinks it's a six or something.
let me give it one more because i like it so much
that's clearly either one or seven
or just possibly two
and since i programmed it and it's my baby, i want to point out that it's
not so unreasonable that it occasionally thinks it's a four, 'cause a four could be like that, right?
most of the time it thinks seven or one.
that was one and that was seven, and it ends up on seven. the fact that it ends up there doesn't
mean anything
the fact that this example is in this row
means that if you learn it a long time on average
then seven is the most likely bet
so that's the net during recognition where we just go chong chong chon
it turns out you can do that stochastically and average here,
or you can just do a mean field version, that is, you compute the real values here,
and then the real values here from those real values, then the real values here and the real values here.
so we
all right
this is due to
this with the
you're wrong
so i think
so c
we what
this work
we should
three days
well i
thank you
to give you some
on the
i don't you want to find
this very simple model
more four
the team
so just design problem
one each
to this
well we do
try to find out more
well does mean
it's the
the man who knows
to the
he invented
image tagging or by due to the same very quickly is because been
doing it for months so there's a commercial base image tagging
it is google baidu and not other companies as well actually
soever on version of this commercial nets
we've got this really only a few months after or the total people
within participate in the original competition this is called
the overfeat system that overfeat where you google you'll
find it is a piece of code you can download and run
you show it to image from a camera our from file and it will
produce classification on the output
the feature vector that you level you want you can use this as
input to whatever system you want to do
this saluted better than this just to network is a successor so
this this to my work on this last year someone a
join google months ago and the participated in the the latest imagenet
competition two thousand or fourteen
and k his team well on essentially all three of the competitions
are classification detection and localisation
also in the case localisation on the if they use extra
extra data
so kind of that the curve is googlenet which is
world on words and it's the performance of this is using
so this other filters on the system
me skip over some learning details and go to how can we localisation
objects localisation is we can use this idea of replicating
network over over field so actually we take
the image we scary down multiple sizes and then we run the
commercial that this sliding window over all scales so here we
only have one in here we have number of different frames those
are the yellow squares if you want and for each of those where
we get an answer whether what's the object what's score instead of
the square but what we do in addition to this so we get so keep
maps for each category and we can do some sort of voting mechanism
maximum suppression but allowed to figure out what the dominant object
in the image if you want to localize
what you need to do is also predict what about boxes so in fact
what are part is the show showing is the
the bounding boxes the predicted value boxes are are produced
by the system so this the system is looking at a particular
window in the image and is trained to classify what it sees
in the window the main object in the window is also trying to produce
a prediction for numbers indicate the position of the on both
so object scene so you could be looking at just the head of that
there are this where this size but if it sees the head and neck
knows where there is a predicts where learning about sort of actually
what what you see here are the put predictions of all windows regardless
of where they are in the original image so and so this easy
to do kind of voting mechanisms here are the dominant object here
is there that you do localisation
and or really well for animals of various kinds
words you know so you can use this for detection as well so detection
is exactly the same system except now you allow the system to
produce multiple answers per image basically highest-scoring objects
overlap to much so a to process groundtruth and that's
and the system here's another one with burrito works really well
burrito those
these are makes mistakes so the correct is a person yeah and it says
it is and doesn't detect person apparently he two ties but these
are the system as we can which is a
this is most but also at the time of of the competition we actually
got what this is a measure called mean average precision we
were ninety percent of this to teams from use of a sudden and you
see also using a convnet work so you better than us and then we
need to reach after we had a more
time which learning we got twenty four percent and then
cmos later roscoe actually from berkeley also the commercial net
and if you other tweaks with sort of attention to thirty four
percent and now the rule net technique is that for the something
so it's progressing really quick
so that's and googlenet again is a direct descendant of that system
is the same guy basically summoner so that you know
detection people and sunglasses and babies and
dogs and whatever this is
mistakes to it thinks that's a corkscrew that actually stage
doesn't like greece robberies but i x green strawberries either so
there are five
hands of five point five eight
so it takes me about to their that's a
five do to a
it takes make continues around takes me up to about
we're about will pass three
that there
two a
three a
six me around
two somewhere like about their
so each time i
multiply by
if i may add another way it's taking me another
these distance around
the idea is that
that if
a is for example on and it's not too close to power of
two or
then what's happening is that sort of
throwing it into is another slot on the different things to find out around five
k being very big
then k times a is going around k times where does it end up it's
like spinning wheel of fortune something
the unions somewhere
OK so that's basically the notion
OK that's basically motion it's going to end up in some
place so basically awareness k and
well sort of the world around and ends up at some point
OK so that's why that's
you know
it tends to be a fairly good but these heuristic methods for hash for any
hash function
you can always
find is that it is can make it operate
so the question is what do you use in practice
OK the second
topic that i wanna
so we talked about resolving
collisions by changing
is another way of resolving collisions
which is useful
resolving collisions
i what's called opened
and the idea is in this method is we have no storage
four links
so i was my training i need an extra links
in each
in order to be able
that's not necessarily a big overhead for some applications
i don't have to touch those records all
and for those
an open addressing is a useful way to
but to resolve collisions
so the idea is with open addressing is
five has two given slot
in this slide is full
what i do is
it is actually
with the different hash functions
my second hash check that's why
that's what is for
OK then i actually
i keep this probe sequence
which hopefully is a permutation so i'm not
going back and checking things i've already checked until i find a place to put
and if i got a good probs sequence so hopefully then find a place to
put it fairly quickly
and then to search
i just follow the same probe sequence
so can express and so the idea here is problem
just that way
still an empty slot
but the two observed mean two plotted here have very low value
so this is quite reasonable and maybe
quite expected but this is an interesting plot over here which
it's not so expect me so this is usually vision with numbers which are slightly
smaller than one so remember this is only have positive but they can be smaller
than one
and we still have to implement our prior belief that we are dealing with a
fair dice because all the probabilities of these numbers here a sort of identical but
what not happens if these numbers become smaller smaller than one that the probability is
an extreme values
they like
so although we've sort of implementing
and expected sense anyway so we are dealing with a fair dice any sample he
dies generated by this prior distribution becomes more and more
load and if we make these numbers even smaller than we will
almost exclusively observed these extreme points
and this
a little bit surprising when observe the first and we also have a very important
effect later in usually processes because the sort of explanation why these processes will lead
to very clustered solutions
the prior sort of essentially says on average i believe this is the a fact
that but every single dies i'm producing this is extremely unfair
least this is sort of the bias implemented by by this usually prior distribution if
these numbers become smaller and smaller
so this is the set of them of the model and to do inference in
this model
later on in the day usually processes it's important to consider how to generate samples
from this model models
so let's look at maybe first look a graphical representation of the situation so
what i mean by generating sentences we start with some i find not i
parameters could but also put together five star and based on these
the parameters describing the prior distribution we generate a sample of g
using the dirichlet distribution and then given g we generate samples from
the different sizes of the dice
in this case we do and experiments with through the eyes and patterns and observe
in different areas
of the results of the dice
and there's more compact representation of this is this dependency is sort of repeated n
times one simply draws square around this
note over here indicates how often the process is repeated this is called the plate
representation is just a shorthand notation for the situation here on the left so the
generating samples essentially means we have a factory of disassembly and we produce unfair dices
according to our
prior assumptions about
the probability of the edge in g then take this emphasizes and the diocese and
the data below a given
so the first approach is to do exactly what i have described the first generate
a sample of g of this of the parameters of the diocese and then you
generate this talk is that it's not straightforward to generate samples for g but there
are different approaches and i don't want to get too much into detail how this
is done but if you look at the literature there are different ways of doing
it here is this describing descended from independent gamma distributions to use in certain shape
parameters and normalize the service but i don't want to get into a lot of
detail here in the late NDP case and you post case this is more interesting
and the leaders to the stick breaking representation
but given that we have generated the sample from initially
distribution is a simple of course to generate samples of the of of the tosses
because this jesus simply the probabilities of observing a certain result
so this is the first approach the second approach is also very interesting we never
generate the sample of g directly but we directly generate samples of the results of
the of the of the diocese
and to do that we use the equation we have observed we have used before
before we set even
past observations of the results of of of process we want to predict the result
of the next to us and we use we came up with this formula over
here we can also use exactly the same formula two
generate samples
off and specific but unknown
and the lord that
so in this sense we have generated some samples to put them the condition and
use exactly the same formula to estimate the probability of the probability of observing the
the result of the next
the advantage here is that we never have to transcend from g a particular gene
might become late on infinite dimensional and it's not very easy to of she this
very nice equation because we never have to do that we can directly sample from
the results of the of the diocese hospital
because interpret this and in this way with probability proportional to n
he was severed from the distribution with empirical counts
and with probability proportional to alpha not generated sample according to the
distribution implied by the advocates the size of a nice interpretation of this i again
with very weak we will
by the way a from the empirical data from the empirical estimates of the probabilities
matches because it or every
i OK changed my definition event since the beginning of the lecture never mind if
for all of the n pixels made and million pixels in this image we have
to consider
and he was in in this if you have british billion again that
creativity men hoping physical constraints that make this a little bit easier
and sure enough there are good geometric constraints
if i take
two images like
here are very apparent i set one up on stage for didactic purposes
it turns out that i can preprocess the images mildly preprocessing being a mile wall
the image
projective walking patterning upper right to be squeezing in that it is quite mild
i promise you
which then brings the rows of the image images in correspond to the words for
this is a given the smiled warm or equivalently given cameras pointing straight or i
is the point spread you don't do that too easily arise because you need to
follow birds them on what you're looking at but suppose you look at infinity
the horizon
then the that geometry
horizontal lines in one i'm at horizontal lines and they have that already that because
now that means all the m squared
pixels in the middle of the n pixels in the image on you need to
look at only square root of n pixels in the writing just one lie on
the corresponding lie
so that's only an american billion
of possible matches too
look at the already an improvement
so the problem is
to look at these pairs of so-called epipolar lines
and restrict attention to the excel
like one of those lines
and explore
the goodness of match between pairs of pixels in those
in those lines and actually it turns out
that you only need to consider not the square all possible match point but only
a triangle matching point
why would only be slower trying not the upper triangle bearing in mind that this
is equivalent to the geometry in which you're
i pointing straight ahead
why is it only the love triangle
it's because
thank you
it because
in the love triangle
the coordinates in
which everybody it is greater than the coordinates in the other thing that corresponds to
rays which are con
that's the point you're making a point in front of the opposite condition will be
diverging rays that we like
trying to image something which is invisible because it behind you
clearly one does not
on ground visibility need to consider this upper triangle
so we need to do is to consider the the lower triangle and what you
see plotted here is according to some measure of how well
because the color of particular excel points in this image met matter particularly excel
at a point on the line and the other that's done for all possible
visible pairings of pixels
and so bright in this
array corresponds to things that match well
and dark
the things that don't match well now what you see is
actually this sort of bright street here
corresponding to
the background plane actually
as bit cheating going on because although i
drawn it as if it was array
along here actually to write cut through the base which i got the
and the goodness of match function here
separating cuts through the place what you see is
track follows the background followed by
the track goes across the head and i mean you know you and i can
see it because we have incredible pattern recognition machines in our brains which
actually doing something non-trivial with this triangle of
good is but if you ask you know what can you do if we ask
trajectory through this
following the best matches it's clearly
a more typical recognition problem because you know local locally
optimality is clearly not enough
you know there bits
bits of the trace that rather
you know quite ambiguous background here
so it's going to be
more difficult than just marking the highest scoring points in the right
it's going to be much more like
a path finding problem
that tracks through the right
the park which is both
coherence in some sense the corresponding to prior expectations about coherence in the physical world
coupled with the tendency of pixels to match with similar colours
in the opposite
they have the same problem in of more schematic here is
epipolar line from each
the two stereo images the right image tells pixels are and that in itself land
and the
zero disparity line so-called is actually the line of four objects at infinity
and so
you know lines where
the absolute image coordinates
in one
image is equal to the absolute on the
four image that arises because the rays were parallel rays parallel that must be because
the object is in
that makes it doesn't and then the
the disparity axis
in this direction and
or you could a psychologist in the audience this definition of disparity is slightly different
from the psychological definition this one computer science
and yes sort of disparity axis if you allow allowed yet another axis of the
diagram which already has two axes
and the disparity axis
is is in this direction
and you can see that greater disparity is going to correspond to more conversion rate
so presumably to an object which is closer to use the disparity is in some
way varying inversely with that
in fact
the disparity varies in proportion to that you read out the disparity
and take the reciprocal in principle that
gives you the distance two
a little fragment of the scene looking at you do this over the whole scene
and you can recover the shape of the heart in the in the variogram
so now to actually recover this part one way of doing it would be
define a cost over the park itself
so the cost is going to consist of two components
component to do with kx now
is encoding
pair of coordinates
the match that k is the k point along this
the case point along with
as coordinates x x
as i defined it
they're consists of two
all right you did well
on the exam
class seventy four sixty two
always a sixty five very happy
eleven students
he scored a hundred
i believe that my exam review was extremely fair
according to some instructors
perhaps even too close for comfort
i did the problem with parallel resistors in the battery
i applied gauss law enforcement ical symmetry
i spent quite a bit of time discussing
we charge
orcas which are
cannot be located on conductors
and i hate the idea of capacitors and dielectrics also quite hard
i prefer not to think about rigid
division between pass and fail
but i'd rather tell you
that all of you
who scored less than forty seven
in my book i sort of in the danger zone but it doesn't mean you're
going to fail the course
nor does it mean that you will pass the course
he scored seventy
those people
and the danger zone
i think you should talk to your instructor
and advise those people so too
make frequent use
of course
two attempts to go
plus the final
today i'm going to uncover
a whole new world for you
and you will see how a two
comes in there a very natural way
the romans force at
is the charge
and the cross product
of the velocity of the charge
and the b field that the charge experiences
if i have here
a positive charge plus q
and it has velocity v
in this direction
and the magnetic field
it would be uniform
and coming out of the blackboards
going to be a force
on this charge according to this relationship
and the force
like so
perpendicular to v
opened it cannot be
in this case
the charged particle is going to go around in circles
the romans forces
i cannot change the speed
you cannot change the kinetic energy because the force is always perpendicular to the velocity
but it can change the direction of the velocity
so we're going to see a
charged particle
well go around
into a perfect circle
the magnetic field
o is constant throughout
the radius of the circle can very easily be calculated
using some
of our knowledge of eight o two
the force
is q b
because i chose to be also perpendicular to v
so there is no sign sin of the angle between them
this one
and this now
has to be the centripetal force
we encountered in a new one
which is and histogram provided by are
and now being the mass of this article
so you'll find no
he calls and he
divided by b
and this by the way i want to remind you
is the momentum
of that article
if you look at this equation it's sort of pleasing if the charge is high
and the roman forces high sort of radius is small
if the magnetic field is high
the lawrence forces high
sort of a small
if the mass of the particle is high there is a lot of inertia
so it is very difficult
to make it go around so to speak so very high mass
you expect a very high rate
so it looks all
intuitively quite pleasing
let's do a numerical example
i think the proton
the central protons
and i think one MTV proton
the same i took during my tests
one MTV means that the kinetic energy
is one MTV
is the charge
find the potential difference over which this proton was accelerated in this case
delta v vd one million volts
and this is now
was one half
times the mass of the proton
i'm the velocity squared
in this case
if i have a one MTV
it is million volts
you will find
this is one point six times ten to the minus fifteen joules
i gave you the charge of the proton
you multiplied by million
and this is the energy
so now you can calculate the velocity because you know the mass of the proton
i give you that there
so you will find exactly what we found during my test review
one point four
times ten to seven
i just second which is five percent
of the speed of light
low so we don't have to make any
relativistic corrections
if this proton
now enters the magnetic field b
which is one test flight
by using the equation have been you know the mass of the proton you we
just calculated the velocity
you know the charge of the proton and you know to be fields
you will find that are
o point one five metres
which is fifteen
numerical examples
it is more common
or at least often does
and then eight out of that equation there
the velocity
and replaced it
the potential difference capital v
over which we accelerate these particles
and so
what you can do you can replace this thing
by using
creation i have their the one of these square
so we have that one half
the square
few times delta v but i right for that just the capital the
and i substituted this view now in here
so i no longer see the velocity
but i now see
this potential difference in the case of the proton is v will be a million
and you'll find that are
then the square root
of two and times that capital v
divided by q
the square
so the two equations and of course
the same physics but
different representation
if you put in
four v now ten two six
mass of the proton charges of the proton and one test light field
of course you find exactly the same point one five metres
so this is all my and then the
and actually have to be very aware about don't confuse them and think they just
doing the same thing with two different philosophically distinct
any questions about the i think that's important point it took me a long time to realize actually
programs around
all right
that's an interesting lovely question good i'm glad you said so the question is along
the lines and let's look at the probability for all classifiers
and i also because i exactly so this to
i am
so you're saying that there should be high probability for classifiers living here high probability classifiers living here
and then like that's you
okay so because the likelihoods log concave
i know that this is a convex problem
has a unique maximum
so they can't be bimodal in this way
so this would be a bimodality across the threshold that somehow
i am
we've got two possible thresholds and this threshold unlikely yeah
and in fact was true that would be great but it can't be true
because the likelihood is
log-concave so we know that whatever the posteriors over the threshold that will be some
corrupted union model distribution and what actually happens is the most likely location
it is in the middle
now the question
you know was just as
it is used in the world
and you you
yet the answer be like fifty fifty
so you might as well not around the model you
well you don't have you don't quite know because this nasty situations where you might
start becoming confident let me give you an example where you become confident back for
the regression case
so this is this is actually the easier examples see where this problem arises with bayesian inference
here i have eh um
nonlinear function and i'm gonna fit with a linear
model mismatches problems occur
so i i think with a linear function one my error bars
for this linear function
so what am about the gradient if i wanted the gradient this all i wanna
be i am and see for this function
i might hope the answer the bayesian inference gives me is like this
there's a lot of uncertainty and i don't know why i am and see is an
you know will do with a few data points
but what it will also happen is it was i increase the
number data
the use it becomes really obvious
this is a non linear functions on the unit circle
becomes completely obvious that this is a nonlinear function
what happens with the error bars
there are bars are actually only dependent in the linear regression case on these number data
the error bars for
the gradient and-or offset
and so you end up with a collapsed uh posterior that
collapses at
the value of this gradient and it becomes completely confident
that's the right gradient and offset it will have a noise that says that and
there's noise because that's the bit
the responsibility for the mismatch between
the model and data is with the noise but
as we saw earlier so the noise will correctly say and there's something weird going
on here but you will you see more data
instead becoming a bimodal or something so in this case here
as you see more data and the same thing happens what incentive you know full
data you actually cover these two possibilities
but you see more and more data you become massively confident that right threshold for
this thing is right in the middle
now you will you write okay depends on the all if you use a sigmoid
what you're saying is if you use a sigmoid the sigmoid
class conditional densities if you look along here
well on
it will be very so diffuse in fact there might even be fifty fifty
but if we get an even worse model
i don't know like a threshold we don't allow it have the flexibility you could get massively
confident about the wrong answer
as far as your model goes
good question
i have to think about it more but i think that that's quite a good question and there
i m i jordan once explain this to me
in about twenty minutes and all made sense but i can't remember
he the way he talked about is philosophically in the statistical learning theory framework you're
doing the expectations over all across all possible datasets
i think his point was
in the statistical learning theory you're doing expectations across all possible datasets
and in bayesian theory you're doing expectations across all possible models
on see when up with if you do both i think this is point is the bayes risk
and that's including the loss as well but i'm a bit shaky on their
but it did make a lot of sense when termites described as a split the
actually can be reconciled and he doesn't in so the thing to do is not
to listen to me but turns a video lectures where
the cambridge summer school
where might there and actually think he does it in a lecture
and describes what happens if you integrate out both
and then you recover i think
these claims that's the bayes risk and it's a nice clear explanation
but i don't wanna
re-created without having to look through it
so the right thing is somehow to do both you typically
so the the bayes bayesian choice
OK let's continue
so now i come
two powerful take the kernel trick
and what it does is it reduces the function minimisation problem so
when you have a large class of functions for reasonable functions to optimize over them
how to reduce it to finite dimensional optimisation problem
displaying regression was already some instance of it
but let more generally consider any loss function so you have your y will you
every function
if you don't have a small one last four years for very large one and
then you need some
regularizer it's college a of and you minimize
the loss
the total loss plus some penalty terms
which is the bias a towards most functions
like the
like minimizing to
and i make no assumptions about the loss function
so the important part
but the penalty function needs to be quadratic in f
so when you have such as minimisation problem of the class of all functions you
can show that the solution has the following form
f of x
a weighted average over these so-called kernels
and the kernel
OK i j
it's just the function of x i and x j
which can easily be computed from the penalty
and the output the coefficients
other ones with minimize
expression here
so this is a simple function
which just depends on a finite dimensional vector a of finite dimensional optimisation problem
so you used the functional optimisation problem
finite dimensional one and in case the loss function is quadratic
this expression is quadratic in have closed form expression if it's not quadratic then you
need some numerical tools to solve
OK that was the kernel trick
in brief
maximize margin classifier
so i mentioned that
if you have such a classification problem
so for instance i mean this as spam point
many messages on them
if so label plus one label minus one
if you do a linear regression
points far away
from the decision boundary so is what's critical have high influence and
they will be
too bad results they cause the line
to be not so good at so what you really want i mean you want
to separate the spam from the long span so somehow i mean if it if
you can separate the linear
a line like nicely
between these points if that's possible
this is called vmax so OK that's the
OK so what does it mean it lies not between point i mean this line
points lie close to the will also line between what we have a feeling that
OK i mean
forty points you may be
the plane which is far away
all these points is are good plane and you can formalise that in the core
maximum margin classifier so what you want is
so first
so you make your
the feature transformation phi or not so then you find here
weight vector which is the normal on this plane
the number should be have norm one
so this year
i will give the distance from
the distance of the plane
from a data point
phi fire rex
so this is the distance
the signed distance then you want that the
positive points lie on one side and negative light points lie on the other side
so you multiply the label
the same as
roughly the same as taking absolute by
then you look for the points which are closest to this plane
in this case this this and this
and you want to find
plane w
which maximizes this distance
so which is maximally away from the closest points and that is called the maximum
margin classifier
this plane is determined completely
the so called support vectors of the points which are closest to the plane and
all these other points they have no influence over here the data point here or
here you very far away
they don't influence the result all
quite contrary to the linear regression case already reduced classification two linear regression really have
heavy influence on display typically better
if it's not separable so i mean sometimes if i mean overlapping
and then the margin might i mean you can be there
OK this is the linear case of the boring case
with this feature transformation phi already indicated here
you can
to some
impressive classification task for instance i mean if you know the blue crosses the red
you have that in some feature space
do either the maximum margin classifiers before
the support vector machine
so what did i want to say
OK so in general you have non-linear boundary
so then we take this feature map
you can show
solution is a weighted average over features
for some weight a
and then the function
simply i mean this scalar product between the weight and the feature vectors so that
the estimator
which can again be just like that in
be written as the weighted average of the weights are a
and here you fly
times y
you pull the sum in
and what you get
that is five times five
some over
and the bees
and give this kernel here
so i mean you have to plug it in and pull one summer
and you get this expression here which is called the kernel
so what you see is once you have this curve
you just have some here or in
and this sum be is
in this kernel and maybe computer implicitly defined is going directly
so if d is much larger than n
you save of computation time if you just feel the current directly and is called
the kernel trick
OK here's some example kernels
the whole lecture and actually the next lecture about content
OK now we come to model selection assessment
it comes the function of the group
and outcome something
which is just a bunch of matrices right so this is the weighted sum of
each representation is going to have a corresponding fourier component and each fourier component is
going to be a matrix so the fourier transform it just a bunch of matrices
of different sizes
set aside this seems like a very different object than what you started out like
a function on the original space but it turns out that this is just a
manifestation of a deeper
between groups and sets of
in equivalent irreducible representations
i was told that
they should take a break after sixty minutes so what about fifteen more minutes that
should be just about enough to
to finish this general part the
one on the math and then we can start with the
machine learning applications in the second half of the lecture
thank you
so much for the structure of the
fourier transform how about its properties
and in particular
i mentioned translations
what did you even mean by the translator function
so the idea here is very simple
we have a function f from complex number
if you think about
generalizing the idea of translation in the real line
which takes
in two dash so that after a few translate by the dashed line is it
is going to be original function text
today the natural definition of translating of functions on the group
is translated by f
sorry translated by c
at location x equal to either zero the x value functions in inverse six
the value of the function at x being
so again
noncommutative playing tricks with us we're going to have to distinguish between two cases depending
on where we translate on the left translate on the right
but apart from that it's a very similar kind of idea to what we had
on the real life every and all that happens is that what you expected to
find that x is now going to happen and a set of x and then
you find the translator function or in the case of right translation is going to
happen at x z
and the translator function
and if you look at this formula into the
the formula for the fourier transform trying to compute
the fourier transform of such translated function at particular representation write down formula
it's going to be sum over
the group of
have said x
four percent of x i substituted the definition of the two
it's going to be
so the inverse
it changed variables
by the group properties summing over x is the same as something this new variable
so this is going to be some why
of the of x which is just going to be z z one new variables
but now we use the definition of defining property of representations and replace this rule
why by rules to align
two new last
and we looked at
the nearest ferry
so this is the process
to expand
the problem is
after suppose that i have seen
one and the
i can
the fifty mind
which variables defined
and expand
based on
this is very
but this is problematic
because i suppose
the distance between the two
variables that we find the diameter is zero point five
the second used
zero point four ninety nine
if i'm using a greedy strategy
cedar point five is greater than zero point
four ninety nine
so why
go away
this is problematic because if
after if i see one example for more than example
of the distance
called sex
home c
the problem is
i i will expand lead if
in the
information and s
in favour of a particular
the choice of variables
and this charge must be
this is why
of born to decide
if the information that i have
from data seen so far
is enough
but it
tools to support
the choice of
if we suppose that the one is the
distance between the
corresponding to the diameter of the cluster
and p two is second five
what they must guarantee is the difference between d one and d two
it is greater than c
is so
we consider
this is the
the the difference
is greater than x one where x comes from the off the ball
because there is information in that
to do so
in favour two
best to do so splitting variable
you think about it
the have
it is the language
of the random variable
to proposed probability level this is use for
the limit
the user can help i want system
with ninety five percent
i the idea that he has a one
and the degrees we
number of places
so if for a given that the given point
that's all
we don't expand class
we need to see
it off when we
with increasing number of situations the
so this is the
the main point
is that
you are not using pvt
we want to have a stable
in fact
what about doing
the evolution of system
at each node
closed form
have done using time window
o for the study
at the beginning the first set of examples
we'll fit
after split this set of examples will
they the sufficient statistic this level
first place is
they are sufficient statistics at these
it is the
discourse forms to a kind of it's not as
but the last time window
data streams
another one
check that
if they
this special
hopefully but
we'll apply is the expansion
but you know that sinks sanctuary
so that during time
correlation between variables
can set
o can we do that something
was sacked
the splitting criteria
that we can prove that
every time the
an expansion of
of the
fresh data the most recent data plates the information that
i believe
any point in time we also
three is not from the same distribution as the y twelve
in particular they are not independent so
it's it's important to realize that the this model specifies the distribution over the entire
sequence y
not just individual models why this is the comment about plates which i forgot to
take out because we didn't cover the plate notation but don't worry about that
so just as the conditional
markov models like conditional random fields and maximum entropy markov models
which had the arrows instead of going down they had there's going up
just like those models you can think of these models in two ways you can
think of this as a markov chain on the hidden state variables with stochastic measurements
so that there markov chain going on in the background but i hide the markov
chain from your output available in front of of probabilistic output and you can only
see the wise you can think of it as a mixture model
the state of the mixture the choice that the mixture model makes is coupled across
right if you got these links here
these horizontal axis this would exactly be a mixture model of a discrete random variable
which you can see
and based on that you select an output distribution and you make an output
so this is exactly just mixture model with choice of which mixture component to use
is coupled across time
so you can see that if i ask you please tell me
which mixture component you think was used to generate y three
it's no longer entirely trivial calculation
because there is some evidence about which mixture component was used based on the data
like three
but there's also some effect from the previous mixture component and you need to somehow
incorporate all the observations when making that decision so this inference problem is very very
hard and that's what we're going do
a study in this in this class
that is
the search for hidden markov models and then i'm just going to go to the
other notes
in which we talk about inference
hmm some kind of motivation to study more general inference problem than than the one
we studied in the last class we really
as inference formerly is the problem because it was so easy we could always just
write down the ratio
which correspond to bayes rule and then we're done but now we really want to
examine the problem that more carefully so
here is the sort of formal
set up for the problem of probabilistic inference we partition the random variables in our
domain into three disjoint subsets
one of them x e
is going to be
know that we observe so e stands for evidence those are the evidence nodes OK
at the query nodes the nodes that we would like to know something about their
and the remainder are the nodes that we're going to marginalize out nodes we don't
care about we're just going to sum over them during the course of our of
our calculations okay
so if the joint distribution is represented as a huge table the inference is actually
now of course
no such table could ever fit into memory but if somehow magically you managed to
fit this table into memory the inference really trivial just be lookup
right you just index into a table along the dimensions x e and slides along
the values that you actually observed
and that would leave you with a smaller table they only had the dimensions x
fnx are left many would say x are
and what would be must be a table that had only dimensions of x then
that would be your answer
so in principle
inference is if you could write down the hall
joint distribution explicitly is the big multidimensional array in matlab inference would be easy you
just selected based on the evidence so the
marginalisation notes and what would be left would be the distribution you want after renormalized
OK but of course storing a joint distribution in memory is completely ridiculous in doing
this sum for the marginalisation would be very hard and during the last some for
renormalisation will also be very hard causes a huge tables so we can really consider
that the best approach here is to try and take advantage of the structure in
the models of the joint distribution is represented by graphical model we can do inference
much much more efficiently and that's what we're going to study today so before diving
i want to convince you that the trickster going to learn today are not very
hard and i want to convince you that by showing you a two line formula
and here is the question how many multiplications
does it take to compute this quantity
one right
OK if you understand how i seem to work by going from here to here
you understand everything you need to know about belief propagation
that's all there is to right
seems like magically i went from two multiplications one multiplication how did i do that
because there's some very particular distribution of property of these operations and i can rearrange
them in a clever way to get the same result that's what's going on in
belief propagation so
when we started to get into like these equations and stuff don't panic just remember
that this is that happening is no magic it's just distributing rearranging operations in in
a clever by taking advantage of some properties
that's the trick and now we're going to try and set it up for a
three is more
complicated models so review the simple case which we have been doing all along kind
of without formalizing it which is just a brute force application of basal so up
until now we've we're really looking at the simple
graphical models here and imagine a graphical model like this one where there is no
x is unobserved and this nodewise observed in the joint distribution here is can be
written as the probability that that would be like the mixing coefficients times the probability
of y given x o to be like the class conditional model
and now if i want to write down the probability of x given y
i just use bayes rule right i just wrote down bayes rule and i noticed
that in the denominator involved this summer
that's because this was just a single random variable
an architecture function approximation architecture that the weights
so what those architectures look like
so you have the rights and those of modern applied some basis functions
the fire facts
it returns the vector
so i can ride this i can expand this
twenty two
make it more there
so you can
just right
some here
two the
i and phi of i think that's where i was from one to be so
theta and phi rt dimension of
just stating the product of the guys
so you have your business functions so maybe you're business functions like bombs in this
and you have the state acts OK so what do do
you need the values of of these basis functions so this will be
maybe this is five live so this is phi one x
this is phi t
so this is
phi two x
and this is
five three attacks
easier ways combine is that
the universe that
OK if you compute the gradient of this so what you get
so if you compute the gradient of this land
one of the key here is just an oriented
taking the derivative of something that
it turns you
something that doesn't depend on the guy so it should return
the graph should be just fine effects it is indeed justify attacks
so if you want to spell out this particular are given for this case
i think this very very simple form
so the
is still see here
the the the update is
all forty times
after pleasant common themes
the next
value the next day
due that
one hangar space
minus the value of the current state
times the gradients was gravity and just can't it just five weeks
so that
first easier
this linear
function approximation
OK and you can have a similar good forty land are using this as the
long long returns
the game that's the
before but you so that's an argument and this not so easy to calculate
st london was this infinite sum
so again if you use this linear function approximation and
OK i want talk about that
and if you want to generalize
the back to you
so the previous target
for t lambda two
function approximation
it turns out that you have to turn the adage traces
to be vectors
of the same dimension
as the
the dimensionality of the parameter vector trying to estimate and you have to do something
so the good thing about this is that this is a straightforward generalisation of td
lambda also in this a specific choice
the basis functions
you get back
the original graph
so the chances that
these are getting really does something
it converges in particular your imagine you're following policy pi and this is some nice
this target is converging to some value function v
well we start here is the
value function underlying policies that you're following so
notation is maybe not
what effect so the difference between the
and this target
is less than
the difference between
the target
and the projection of the target function space so by the projection of a part
of the target function space is the best approximation of the function
given a function space so you have your basis functions you have chosen
you have chosen them
and you just compute the best place in retrospect so of course you cannot
however it is born in practice but it's good to know
that if you have function space is rich enough so that this projection
is very close to the original function
and that there is going to be really small
OK so what you want to do
is you want to have
really big
approximation architecture
that is able to capture a lot of features
and then you can run these are
OK so
again this was just for weighting of policy and question to consider is if you
learning controller
and it can in a state for that matter
generalise or these to to learning good controller just using action value function
OK so this is
just generalisation of TV zero
for this action value functions
and this is the way it should work
this eligibility traces
i don't have much time
so he here some results for this to term to mean that you will see
a lot if you
studied reinforcement learning that surely someone think of the main
you have an under-par card it should go to the goal
but it's on the part so it starts from what
it can i just actually two years ago and the attention is not strong enough
so what it has to do that he has to collect some energy by going
for lot it and then going backwards
so it forms an edge into into some the system
and then once it's the
it can use its potential energy just curious
so this is a non-trivial problem for traditional controllers
try to reach the goal very high so that proportionally
so there are increasing the force proportional to
the distance to the goal so that one for here
at all
and so
these are the results of using
for learning the value function
the children of a may be reversed
but it's just the same picture
this because in case two we care
the case one we didn't really care
in case two we say well
cases of there
is x the right child of the parent for the left child if it's the
right child or in case two
so now i really know the next year
his b is the right child of before i don't know i i didn't care
i'm assuming that this way
OK why still here
now we know that y is black
why over here
the black nodes so self-guided the contraction trick all these nodes a b and c
with conglomerate into one
now we have four children and actually looks
pretty good why not involved because it's black
so in this case we're going to do less portation
on a
so we take the search
we turn ninety degrees
what we get is a
and the last
the on the right still preserve the inorder traversal c on top still
otherwise hanging office before
we have one of the subtrees are the other subtrees hanging up the in the
other two now paying
this is just the generic traditional picture applied to the search
OK that does this before we had to zigzag between x and its grandparent now
we have the zigzag
we have this straight
path between
so x is still here not changing x in this case because after i do
case two i immediately do case three
so this is what case we will look like and now continue on
k street
so finally
there's case three and this was finally complete the insertion of the
we have about black c
we have
the left child from c
we have already left grandchild which is x
and then we have these black subtrees all the same kind
hanging off
which is exactly what we had at the end of the case two
so that definitely connects over
and remember this is the only case left in category a category we assumed to
it was that you know
parent of x was left child the grandparent here c
so we know that
we are in the case when y over here is red that was case one
so assuming wise black
we look at whether x y is the left child and right child if it
was the right child we made it into the left child
x actually did change here before x has been now acts an
OK and then case three finally is when x is the left child of the
parents who is the left child of the rev
we have to worry about
what we do is another rotation just like the last rotation we did in example
in this case three
so we're going to do the right rotate
and we're going to recover
what do we get well now becomes the rule
and i'm going to make it black
remember that this is the root of the subtree there's other stuff
thank you for your relation draw
next appearance in
all these pictures are somewhere in the middle of the tree
i don't know where could be a right branch could be left branch
we don't know
c becomes the child to be i'm going to make it to read child
a becomes
child b as it was before
keep reading
but this current will be seen from above clockwise
sort of it produces a magnetic field in this direction
to oppose the change in magnetic flux
and we call these currents any currents
any occurrence
any current
produces heat
in here
is the product
joules per second
the power
times i
i agree are always comes down to the same
so this this clearly not a little bit
the resistance now is the resistance there
and that means
that this will slow down at the expense of kinetic energy
it is produced
and in one go
as far as feel
then the situation would be if there were no fields
and we call that magnetic braking
you can easily convince yourself
what you should do it home
but if you look at the current right here coming out of the blackboard
you calculate the lawrence force right there
you will see that the lawrence forces in this direction it's pushing it out it
opposes the motion
and i can demonstrate that the u
i have here
a pendulum
the pendulum
his conducting copper plate
like so
which i'm going to swing
between magnetic poles which are here
when you swing it in this direction
i've two pendulums
one way this is solid copper
and have another one
it is slowly
like teeth
if i'm going to also made this one in the magnetic fields
you're going to get
there any current sometimes clockwise sometimes counterclockwise depending upon how the magnetic flux that surface
is changing
where it it moves into the magnetic field will have moved out of the magnetic
always oppose its motion
and so it will then you will see that
and it's at the expense of kinetic energy
he will be produced in this copper
if you do it with something like this the damping will be substantially less
not zero but substantially less
because now if there is an EMF
i want to drive the current
this current has to go through these openings which is and which has a huge
and remember
power is times i and if there and his i square or any of the
if the kernel is extremely low because the resistance is so absurdly high
you don't dissipate much power
and sort of not much them p
and i can show that to you
by the way this is damping this magnetic damping is used sometimes for scale that
you will use cellphone
so it doesn't also late for too long to the dems very quickly
we're going to see the oscillations there
it's going to be a little dark
that's the best way
i can make you see it
and on the power
so you see there the look give you the lights
and first
i will oscillate it without
any magnetic field like in politics
magnet because the solenoid
so this oscillated no magnetic field
if you feeling i would also
what you see on the left is the reflection by the way against the magnetic
to give you an idea of how it oscillates
and now i will turn on the magnetic fields
it's like going into one of the it again
hitting the magnetic poles we don't want that
amazing isn't it and then when it goes into when it goes out
and now i'll use the one with the teeth
and you will see there's is damping
but substantially less
so this is without
the magnetic field
and now with now
because you is them being but it's
know nearly as much
as there was
on the
one that was
then that is
i have here a remarkable example
of how
our economy is run
i have their some
mining is not just some
we don't even know how many thousands
copper wire going around going around going around going around one wire
and then there's the light bulb
in that
here the magnet
we don't know the strength but
i would say is not more than the kilogram probably little less
and when i moved this
between these poles
magnetic field let's say is going in this direction i don't know what this that
i don't know to color code
but there is no magnetic field going through here for is the change in the
flux through the surface
very crazy surface if there are thousands why is this the goes multiplied by the
and then there is going to be an induced EMF
and i'm going to be an induced current
and this light
if i going very slowly
the sea
he really wanted to go very fast
and the magnetic flux changes high
a lot of light
so make it dark
so you can see that
but we don't want this to
we don't need that
little all
so if you can see me
i have no
and i'm going to bring in the magnetic poles and i go very slowly
i do we know
what about a little bit of light
going a little bit of lights
i'm writing now
holding it steady nothing happens why because there's no exchange
magnetic field is very strong now
thirty slope
i don't care about how small it is the only cares about the change
flight within a little bit of life but i pull in what i pull out
doesn't matter
if i do it very fast
i may be able to generate so much current
both even blow trying because i know you like the idea of breaking things
well the
you and know alone
let's see what i managed
yes i did broken now
so you got something for your money then you
that's runs our economy
conducting windings that are being moved forcefully
through magnetic fields
i was once interviewed by reporters
when he
i came up with this
and they said to him
so what
so fine so you move the winding through the magnetic field and so you get
a little bit of electricity so what
and his answer was
someday you will taxes