so maybe we can we can have this as a public discussion because maybe other
other people also confused i confuse them so maybe you can
ask the question
that's right
that's why
yes i would very in in very much detail talk about this in later lectures
but the
some people imagine playing piano with the left hand and right hand some people if
they imagined foot than they imagined to kick evolve
there are some are imagined to clench his or to squeeze the balls
i mean there are different strategies
like i imagine two
some sensation in my hand for example
so the sensation of heat or sensation of touch or
things like that
OK so
this is just to give a broad overview of of of things that are done
everywhere in the world and
slow cortical potentials have proven to be very stable and
successful technique to deal with
four patients not only for healthy subjects because of individuals that you on the beginning
play in the guys playing ping-pong they're very happy healthy subjects and it's it's much
easier for them of course to do this
so as i
i remarked at some point
there's some
so there's some individual calibration phase
and you would like to
make it known or make inferences about
so the subject in ten
and this might be different from other people
we come to that
the whole question
a few years
that's a very good question this will be in
maybe one of the top school
instigated here
if you're a city
but yes
it depends very much you would you upload
anything with the time not
depends on your the state of your brain
and you stated your brain product
of all these things
cost BCI
there some so-called more rhythms
i articles the related desynchronisation
little synchronisation
and this
big literature about them they they were
found by
four to learn the process
a while ago
people have ties
that there's so they come from the from interaction of talamanca cortical connections
activity responsible for that so
in a sense
what you see is so so if you very tired say
so you offer them goes up
oakes is on the occipital side here somewhere here
and so this means
you signals have this structure that i showed on the slide so this
this is like spindles
and if you
now intend to move or a few
imagine two more or fewer
two something cognitive then this aphorism is suppressed
this is called event related desynchronisation so so to say the idea the brain
suppresses your idling rhythm
to do something
this was a very sloppy explanation but but i think it gives you a good
intuition of what is happening
and so if you imagine your left hand c
on you
contralateral hemisphere
i on the right hemisphere there's some activity
imagine your right hand
and on the left hemisphere there would be some activity
and this is
basically that's going to target the joint distribution by two
because so if you want that to the algorithm makes well you cannot obtain sample
which are basically as entity to be distributed according to pi two that ends their
model their component in x is going to be according to prior to this with
the reason OK so what the case where that this this thing might work OK
so if you look at what's basically try to give some four
target distribution
by two
you learn that the conditional obviously distribution of u
next and applied to the world simply is important is the uniform distribution
of these including tells you will get max the importance of the issue to someone
by removing the compute the normalized version of the target you on the numbers between
zero and pi gamma x that the value of x OK
OK so let's say that was basically
i was having next
then this is basically
so i drawn into a small number of all on this into old zero DMX
on ten new values you here OK
this is what i think
now what i want to do
if i one basically
not to update the company x
given you end by to talk about something that under this artificial target distribution where
one is this this time distribution
well so be essentially is going to be essentially proportional to one
if gamma x is supposed to do
o zero otherwise so what does it mean that actually
so essentially
what he tells you
so you have you feel OK
so basically you're gonna slice
the target distribution at this slower
on you're going to solve for x uniformly
basically in region where gamma x
he said to you that is
this to entailed OK
so what you like to do
once you have basically
the sample you
you basically slides the the target distribution
OK this lower on you want to some poor basically x uniformly
on this interval that's what you want to do
OK so this is slice sampling so you could send me sampling from this target
this new like slice
this is the solution may not be obvious because you need to know something about
the geometry of the target distribution
OK this is true but actually is the lot recipe that have been put forward
to sample from that automatically in the paper by what from the that appear in
and out of statistics if two years ago so i'm not going for it
but if you want more detail you look at the paper by what from the
that appear in and out of stats
in two thousand three i think OK
it turns out that by just having this kind of scene paul
o que se i
violating this policy i five or can help you can't help you come l basically
coming up with much nicer in santiago reason which i know a lot of case
rejection for OK so i refer you to the paper our from the for that
another thing that has been proposed in the literature
proposed by physicist because you see that the ideas coming from or a physics consideration
is what is called a meeting of the multicellular OK so suppose that for example
you want to some of the target distribution pi x where x is basically a
real valued
a simple in this case
OK so
i mean to multicolored that
well does something that looks actually quite silly to start with is basically is going
introduce new target distribution
pi two k which is the point at which is proportional to the initial target
distribution of interest
time basically
you have basically someone the liability eye on the valuables v on the simpsons space
OK which are assumed distributed according to a normal distribution of means zero all
on the identity clients it seems like we do something with nothing here OK so
we had essentially
this is the original target distribution we multiply it by the motion
OK independent ocean
so it seems like a pretty useless from a politician point
OK well it's not because this is a very clever to spend a lot of
time working with the count so
to say so we're just gonna basically
defined mediterranean is essentially minus the log of pi to that
OK so let's consider
this what is called a meeting at which the function of x and v
so this is minus log of by two thousand is minus log gamma which is
called the energy
in physics applies basically you have to take minus the logo based on the notion
that divide gauche and you have this them coming
OK so
no basically
if you look at the physics literature
there some scholarly opinion dynamics which are essentially determining dynamics defined by its importance or
which as such that essentially starting from a point x v
you know the whole
suite of analytic tasks like
machine learning itself has several well-known stay just one example formation
evaluation and deployment
and if you look at these
some concrete numbers value from worked at yahoo on user activity modeling
the number of pages
per user
might be ten two hundred
ah but the total number of values here as
in the millions or tens of millions for the cytosol
the number of
quine's of things that people do
can be an order of magnitude larger hundreds of millions
the number of atoms that displayed the people actually click as much possible
right hundreds or thousands
and with this
you want to get a sense of which uses respond which acts
can that's in a nutshell what are trying to do
if you try to do this
u create features
and try to predict events as follows
there is a window
if you look at the things that people dead searches
or browsing activity
in the window
and you see whether this is predictive of some event of interest that they click on a particular action
in a target window
then you sliding windows
i did a peak
this is how long standing cases okay
hand if you look at the numbers involved in all this
you're talking about a few others for data acquisition
four to six hours
four the
demanding that gives you features
the actual model training is a relatively small fraction still
it's significant wanted to others right and does not for a single model so many
many models which yields caught in flight
let's look at this in a little more detail
you might think he made
and so on this rule extraction who have the idea of email
and the words that characterizes it from a click on you might get label
is this something that's is this action that the user did
that is the label good about
spam or not
the construct cases you might be doing essentially a very large scale joint
fortunately these are data parallel functions
in one year
by essentially reporting are pipeline we use
how do
incidences plan spam detection became the reported plan
went down but there forty percent
basically because
the time taken to build the filters went down dramatically
and the sooner you insert filters four new kinds of spam
and classify them as financial people never see them in their inbox
the less than one reports back
scale matters
learning the language classifiers other example
use feature extraction from a variety of internet sources
then you learn from them
but if you look at what's going on in each of these scenarios
on the one hand things like mapreduce
on the other hand in your modelling phase you want on iterative algorithms are various kinds
which today are not well supported and mappings
so what do you do
the performance and among for example
leaves much to be desired
if you want to do the kinds of deep learning that you read about at scale
trust me there are using multiple
how do bring those kinds of platforms
to be generally available
this what we're talking about
so if you want a scale model building
learning is fundamentally attractive you apply the model data you observe the errors you better model and to keep
doing this until you have a good enough model
am four
here are the weaknesses in mapreduce in current model systems
that kill u
mapreduce can deal with one iteration
and in between iterations
you need to
rescheduled get fresh tasks
tasks talk
this expensive
unit to persist your data
reading and writing data the ios an issue
the serialization deserialization costs
are equally an issue
all this
know a dozen papers that talk about how to have some way or the other
to do machine learning on the
they all have a universal speed up from thirty
at the conclusion is
you need to award these round-trip overheads
and no matter how you do it
it's a pretty robust factor a factor of thirty
the tool that you're trying to say
in terms of performance
let's go back to object
they don't just want to build a better machine learning system although that's something i will talk about it
we also want to build a better other kinds of analytics systems
if you consider building
the next generation a sequel as indeed many people are currently doing
you worry about four dollars
all the time should get used to that
here's another one let's play this game one more time we can ask how much
is the volume of the body came when he
the ten the volume
again would be proportional deciding what you
times the increase in temperature
put another number
this called the coefficient of volume expansion
and that depends on the material
if you take copper
copper will have a certain alpha
i reliable different alpha will will have different out you will have different out
this is the property of the material
if you say well i had something
and when heated up by one degree increased by nine inches
another one increase by two inches
is it clear that the first one expands more readily
it's not because the first one could have been in my long second one could
be in a foot long
so you have to
pick out certain factors that universal and the rest of it you put into a
property of the material
similarly when it comes to specific heat
you ask how much he does it take to
some object it depends on the mass
it doesn't matter what your heating
but an increase in temperature because the whole purpose of adding it's always going to
be linear in the
delta t
this one is the property of the material and by definition sequel to one
television gram
on one here locality
what what
once you've got
so remember one
calorie program for walker is the definition
once you've defined water
to have a specific one calorie per gram
you can define specific it but other materials
by the following
so what do you do you take
a container with some water in it
let's assume the container zero mass i don't have to worry about approximation
if you're worried about that you take a huge containers so that the volume of
water dominates the surface area of the campaign
anyway containers neglected you've got some water
this water is of some initial temperature t one
and i have some new material led
i want to find its specific heat
i take the lead in the form of pellets
and he the the lead pellets
some temperature t two
and a drop these guys
and that's what
be an example where initially the lead
is an equilibrium may be on the furnace the temperature t two
what is an equilibrium may be in the room temperature t one
then i put the pellets into the water
the period when the temperature is not defined
and so on they own settled down
for some common template quality
we will now postulates
this is a possibly
or a lot
the total change in q
is zero
in other words if q
it's lost their one body and gained another body the loss in the game was
it's the new law
you can make up all the new last you want you don't have the right
to the line first make
it in that case what can you say in this particular problem
in any of the problems they are due to draw the following picture is one
it's not the temperature is the final one
which we don't know
what we can measure what thermometer and measure
then you say
the mass of the water
specific the water which is one
and delta t
with the the final temperature minus initial temperature
ditto for the lead pellets
so the lead
this kind of symbol pb
time specific heat which i don't know
times change in temperature is the final
minus the two
this is equal to zero
the sum of all the incident that is zero
this is the game
of heat
of the water
this if you work kind will be a negative numbers
because you can see the final is below initial t this will turn out be
negative and positive and negative latter zero
so what is it you don't know
well you know the mass of the what specific in what one by definition
the final and you want to measure the thermometers
as of this for you to measure
these are non you can find c
so this is a birthday present for you guys this is an example
jump on this first because you've been doing this and i still i know kids
love this kind of calorimeter problem
that's correct so
the point is that everything expanded linearly one have the disagreement difference between different among
so it turns out
two an excellent approximation
the change the length is proportional to the length
but it's not exactly proportional to like that would be terms involving higher power so
not only that
set of nodes
o p is interpreted as this industry and its let's p if you prefer p
to score a because this is what i
what they should do this time so it means that it's own set of nodes
that are labeled by a
the given tree it is fixed set right
so in the stream
the mapping
is the constant function
it takes any set of nodes and that maps it
on to the set of nodes that are labeled by a
so the least
six point
how how do you make it seem to have
something which maps on two on two PN which is the fixed point it's pizza
and there's no other
OK alternative so
this is what is written here
OK this is five
you don't even need to look at your model
two guess
what such formula
corresponds to sally take something more difficult to understand
so let me right
i mean shortcuts here so this means either the left or the right
satisfies beta
so that means that a child
which satisfies beta
and here
war child
all children are satisfied
and now are in the formula
so this news later
but there are in this formula
and what does that mean
so now i have
which says OK
one of the only six point of
the mapping which takes a set of nodes and
so here i trying to describe
this thing here is that we seem to be already yesterday
so what what is this mapping
OK let's use the semantic so if i take a set of nodes
after map it right
basically what the definition is in my
on my slice so in
it is tree
well actually the variable z
is interpreted as
this actual set of
so what is this
what this is
the semantics of p a
z does not sure
this formula i actually this one has no viable so this doesn't really matter
i mean this interpretation is clear it's the set of nodes which are labeled by
a that's it
union one disjunction is interpreted as union because negation and and conjunction well respected deputy
this compromise union intersection
and you
OK i have to interpret this formula
and this
so what is this
this is if you know
get the bit
how we writing this is the set of nodes
a child with the is left to right
because this is
left or right child which hits z
but what is and what is the semantics of that
the semantics of that
is the set and
so this is simply
the set of nodes w such that
belongs to
the right and left some of the body belongs to an or
the rights on w belongs to and in other words
is the set of nodes so that in one step
you hit
the set and OK that's it
thank you
and this is as we said well just
all the nodes that are labelled by a so either
so what am i mean in the in the
the image of a set of nodes and either
and labeled by a man and
i mean f of probably of n
i labelled by and by a or
in one step a heat and
skin is
the label is
one in the is the label on label that you can find on the on
the tree
a is an element of this
alphabet used to decorate
you treat OK that's the proposition
now i want to the least fixpoint
so computed
so my another mapping the mapping is this one
it's very easy
very clear
so on the least fixpoint how do you compute the this fixed point wanted to
get the this fixed point of this one you start with the
this element of the the latest here
the bottom
but i is and
it's the mt
and now we going trade so i'm supposed to compute OK try to this one
and the more risk from the context so i want to compute
as of the empty set what is evident is that look
i it's simply
the nodes that are labeled by a
union union what
so that the chinese the right child belongs to the and set number
and as you know china
but you assume
a tree which is the full tree
then we can have a set of things
if you meet if you take a month trees but
here let's mister in this way so here
so that means that
the ratio of lambda squared off for a squared is a constant
well when i went to school what they taught me in math was that if
the left hand side of the equation is constant the right hand side of the
equation is constant so that means even though theta
is varying with hkl this ratio varies in such a way as to remain constant
that's the key
so whatever hkl is at that theta the rate the signs were that angle over
the age group was k squared plus elsewhere remains constant as you go through all
of the lines so this is the underlying principle
so let's go
let's go into the so the first thing i want to do is i want
to build science where theta
so there are they are those that theta values and i've taken divided by two
and squared taking the science where is and i got a new column and then
analysis is normalized by dividing science where theta by the first member of the color
so all i did was i took everything and divided by point one four three
so this point one four three divided by point one four three is one
this is you can see one ninety divided by one forty one thirty four and
so on
OK why because look i'm going to this
going to this
what's next thing clear the fractions from the normalized column i don't like this like
one one point three four and so on one point three four to me alive
for some experimental error
isabelle roughly one third is is roughly four thirds and that's two point six seven
that's roughly a third so someone multiply the whole darn column by three
and throw away the little residuals and sure enough you get a set of whole
numbers three four eight eleven twelve and so on
this is good
we're getting somewhere
so now it says speculate this is where you get to participate speculate on the
hkl values
that if expressed as h grabowski squared plus elsewhere would generate the sequence of the
clear fractions column and remember what you have to go on
you've got that set of
simple cubic
face centered cubic body centered cubic so what set of hkl would give you this
well what's what sum of integers squares would give you three
i one
maybe one one one how about four
so you can see what's going on here this this i've gotten from the feet
and this is my speculation
just right
here's the punchline compute for each theta the value of this
the signs were defeated over eight squared plus is
k squared plus elsewhere
and if you get constant bingo you must hit the jackpot so let's do it
science feet is this a squared plus k squared plus elsewhere to square to three
that's all four seven seven you do it for the next one in x one
x one allowing for experimental
error i got constant so what does that say it says that my speculation of
what the hkl are
is good self consistent
and what do i know
those are all even or
they're either all even or odd that's the sequence for face centered cubic
that's the sequence for face centered cubic so on this basis i can say
that i've got
something that's face centred cubic
so i'm happy about that but further more
what else can i get
well i know the lambda value and i know this thing this is that this
is that constant there
so what i can do is i can take this constant and plug it into
this equation and furthermore i can determine that the a whatever this crystal is going
to be lambda
of copper KL four
divided by
two times square would that constant
and if i plug in the numbers i get three point five three
three point five three angstroms so it's FCC it's three point five three angstroms if
i look at it and it looks metallic i want to say it's nickel
because i happen to know the decal has a lattice constant three point five three
extra i know what i gotta do some other things but certainly that makes me
thinking think about whether i've got nickel present
here's the
i think this is that was just very modest
so for that we need to get the notion of cliques
so clique is a subset of the graph
which is fully connected
and the maximal clique such as well
at small ones in the graph and they obviously also define the graph
drawn three cliques here
on the graph
can you tell me some more clicks
that two more clicks on the maximal cliques of the graph that happened really strong
otherwise without randomly pick somebody
this one here
very good
it's one maximal clique
there's another one missing
somebody else
there's more
is very good
so what we can do is we can write the entire graph to
is the set of maximal cliques
this one
one and this one
this is actually fairly
well behaved graph in
terms of graphical models inferences will see afterwards
so we wouldn't have to do anything like pluralisation transposition and all that so is
actually a really nice
so this will allow me to specify dependencies between variables
then a is just some graphical models inference algorithms for inference
so what
i think we'll started on you know is that these exponential families
the models that was talking about actually fairly closely connected
you can just roll those models instantiate the various terms as will see
the right side of sufficient statistics
and everything will work out quite nicely
well might be quite that obvious to you it is how this is all connected
to say something to talk or to chance talk
the idea that will be that
in many cases
you can look at conditional models
so for instance let's say
i have
a binomial distribution
additional once is here
it's a it's apples and oranges
and that's a condition this
on the picture
what get classifier
so now modelling the probability of
apple orange
conditioned on
well the picture of an apple or norwich
so immediately i get
the classifier
so let's say
i have a normal distribution
that conditional on some locations
well the input data get the regression estimator
then on estimating the mean possible the variance
that gives you
the actual give heteroskedastic regression estimator
which is something really nice
but it's very very simple
OK now
let's put this is
so perhaps the cafeteria
o thing about another fifteen minutes or
most of you think
from another fifteen
OK good
so this MC is
if i have
some undirected graphical model with these conditional independence properties then the joint distribution pfx
decomposes into some
on the maximal cliques
so this is why
for instance in the way the example
i was able to actually model the joint distribution of us all carrying umbrellas around
in such a simple way
they only had to
model the connection between
the cloud
and my carrying the umbrella or somebody else can
these functions here
can depend considerably fewer variables
the joint distribution
we still have to
the problem here names normalisation today need to take care of
but other than that
this is all really nice
OK is small catch
pfx needs to be nonzero on the entire domain
so if you have some serious main you just need to exclude it from the
domain in the first place
and everything works fine again
but it's completely mixed with each other something can never becomes zero
it can be up true closer but never
if we can use this house to posterior for the exponential families
so far you would think well
in talking about
graphical models
exponential family models how they relate well actually in this case
these two are really master connect
the what get is that
sufficient statistics for fixed will just decompose into sufficient statistics on the maximal cliques
it doesn't sound terribly exciting sector in approach between those terms
they get something that will decompose into inner products between
functions defined on the maximal cliques only
if you michelle phillips stop this was the crown
so what happens is
the kernel
on the big set of random variables
decompose into cross
on the maximal cliques
if the conditional independence properties
so can begin fasting complicated
dependency structure
just look at the maximal cliques
you know what the problem is to decompose like
this is also something that you can actually actually then useful feature selection include determination
sadly proved
but just matching terms
and here we're doing the same thing
OK the martyr later often converts as a signal sequence
two of baseband waveforms and then converts the baseband waveforms to pass band waveform
and just historically
people used to think of modulation
as the process
if taking something at baseband and converting it to some past bad
now it is recognised that the interesting problems
it's not how do you go from baseband the past and which is just multiplying
by cosine wave is not much more to it than that
and there was a little more to it but not much
and the interesting problems
is how do you convert
the way forms
which is why we went one of the reasons we went through all of this
about l two waveforms an orthonormal expansions and all of this stuff
OK so
the timing we're going to look in modulation and demodulation without worrying about
what bandwidth any of this occurs at so we'll just look at it at baseband
OK so the simplest example of all of this so simple that it almost looks
like it's silly
is to map the sequence of binary digits
in a sequence signals from the constellation one minus one
OK so what you're doing there
is turning
this mapping zero into one
a mapping one into minus one another with the zero and one binary digits are
mapped into one minus one why do you do with this way which is a
little confusing mapping zero into one
instead of mapping one to one
well primarily so you can look at multiplication
of signals
in the same way as you look at modulo two addition
the binary digits
it just turns out to be a little more convenient that way
and it doesn't make a whole lot of different the point is we're going from
zero ones to signals which are one minus one
OK then this sequence of signals
is mapped into a waveforms
which is the sum of u k
times the same function t over capital today
minus kept in other words you're thinking of each one of these signals now
think of it as being some
of impulse is delayed impulses
and then think of taking a little sink
seventy over t
captain putting it around each one of those impulses another would think of passing each
of those impulses which is weighted by one of these values use k
into a linear filter
his response
it is a sign of
x over x
anybody see anything little bit fishy about that
if you are able to filter whose response was signed x over x
one hour
it's hard to y
because it's not causal yes
OK we talk about that more later today
communication engineers
hardly ever talk about causality
hardly ever talk about whether something is realizable or not
and the reason i want to say this the number of times
is that one of the parts of any receiver is the timing recovery circuit
and what the timing recovery circuit does
is it tries to figure out what the transmitter timing is in terms of what
is receiving
and when you figure out what the transmitter timing is in terms of what you're
the most convenient way of doing that if you're sending a pulse or something
he would like to receiver timing
to pick up at the same time that the transmitter timing is picking up in
terms of both in other words you want to get rid of the propagation of
the lie and just ignore them
the receiver timing is going to be to be delayed from the transmitter timing
exactly by the propagation to lie
now if we always do that
causality becomes totally unimportant
one of the problems with the same function as it starts time minus infinity
and even if you like the receiver timing by an infinite amount of time you
can never use the communication system
until it's time to tear it down and and bring in in new ways
which unfortunately is what happened to the third generation wireless system by time people figured
out how to build them everybody was saying that
old-fashioned stuff
we're going to go directly on the fourth generation
and they might go directly from fourth-generation fifth-generation who knows
well anyway
you can implement these even with the receiver timing different than the transmitter timing
but you can always approximate things with enough delay between transmitter and receiver so that
you can approximate any filter you want to do without worrying about causality at all
and it's hard enough designing good filters without worrying about causality
you don't want to bring that into your picture
at the beginning
so communication engineers usually say that those timing issues are not important
and a little bit of the light is not going to hurt anything
all shannon's theory
it was as successful as it has been
and transform the whole communication industry
because he never talked about the lay all
he just ignored the question of delight from beginning to end
and when you look at his capacity formulas
they are assuming that you have as much the layers you need
between transmitter and receiver
and assuming that that is an important and in terms of the propagation delays in
and the and the filtering delays in most modern communication systems those delays are not
if there is a soul as well as the body
and there's always something immaterial then when the body dies when we have been ones
to be an and the death of the body occurs so at the end of
the any of the body stops repairing itself decay sets in you know we all
know the sad story is the one crawl into the worms prolog the end of
the day
well may take longer than a day the body has decomposed
yes all that
this speaks to the end of the body
but if the soul is something immaterial
then that could continue to exist even after the destruction of the body
that that's the that's attraction
i was one of the attractions of dualistic view the belief in the soul did
you something to continue to exist
after the end of the about so what death
it normally there's this super-tight connection
between my soul and my body
death might be
the severing of that connection
and so
the body
breaks and no longer able to give input up to the soul
so longer is no longer able to control the body and make it move around
but for all that the soul might continue to exist
so at least the possibility
that i'll survive my death is one were taken very very seriously if we are
a couple of
things to point out about this view
one is i've been talking as go
a person
is that combination
kind of are us
old anybody sandwich
so a person has true
the basic building blocks
the bodily part and the sole part it's natural to talk that way
but if we want a belief in the soul to help us
hold out the possibility of we weeks that there might be life after death then
i think we need to actually say that strictly speaking
it's not that the person is a soul
plus body
strictly speaking i think we need to say
the person just is
the soul
after all
if the person is that combination if the person is the pair stole plus the
body destroying the body you destroying the pair
if the person who is the pair and the pair no longer exists
the personal longer exists
so if we want to belief in the soul to help us we open the
door to the possibility that i survived the destruction of my body
it better not be that the body is an essential
part of me
it's simpler more straightforward
to say instead
what i am strictly speaking is a soul
as long as the sole exists i exist
course my soul meeting
i have a very tight connection to a particular body
but still you could in principle destroy the body with the without destroying the look
i particularly close connection to the house i live in
but for all that you can destroy
my house without destroying me
so that i think the position that we ought to strive to
to do list
the person is strictly speaking the soul
so has a very intimate connection with the body but the person is not the
soul and the body the person is just the soul
so even if the intimate connection gets destroyed
the person the sole could continue to exist
second point to clear clear up is that
three different issues
that might interest us
one metaphysically
our bodies and souls distinct
is there is the mind to be understood
in terms of this immaterial object the all
so i there are two kinds of things that the first question our souls and
bodies distinct
the second question though is
does the soul
even if it exists does the soul
survived the destruction
there are body
it could be something separate without surviving that's what i'm trying to say
if there are cells at least that opens the door to the possibility
that we will survive hard
but doesn't guarantee it because as it further argumentation there's no guarantee that the soul
survives the death
of the body even if it's separate it could be that it gets killed at
the very same time were destroyed at the very same time the body is being
destroyed maybe when
these physical processes b one through bn take place
they set into motion remember after our interaction is listeners is very tight causal connection
between the body and the mind about the soul and the body the body and
the soul
just like when you prick my body that bodily process sets up certain things taking
place in my soul
maybe one b one through bn take place
they set up some other
processes in my soul
call them
as one
through s
and maybe s one through s and results in the destruction of my soul
so simon will taneously with my body
o my soul
because here to draw
so the first part as one that that that that that that's easy as an
the question how do i draw the so i don't really know
the mere fact that we decided we do ultimately decide that there is a whole
something non visible separate and distinct from the body
is to go over all the edgesand multiply the probabilities of the edges and
go over all the zerosin the graph and multiply the correspond one minus
the co responding values right so so for this for zeros I would take this for a
one minus these four guys and multiply them here and for all the ones I'm multiplying them here right makes sense right yeah sorry question when you get all possible
combinations good question good question I'm coming to that yeah
if you do the sides of your we need to cut them so that you will have the exact right size of your final waves
that's also a very good question I'll come to it so basically this is a this is a
model selection problem right you are asking you know should I fit the linear function or a quadratic function so
that's that's sort of separate let's assume that somebody tells us it's two by two
and let's also assume that the sizes match what you can do if the sizes don't match
you can just pad here with zeros okay and this is what we do in
practicebut if it's a good question but if you put it aside let's for
now assume somebody says us that this is two by two and that the size of the
graphs match then the likelihood is very naturally defined right since I'm doing this
independent coin flips I just ask what's the probability that I observed exactly this coin flips
and as mentioned there will be two problems one is this node correspondence problem we don't know how
how these nodes map to these nodes right so we would need to try the all of them out
in the second one it's scalability right even if I know
how these node match so maybe I should I should this way right so let me first talk a
bit more about node correspondence right so even if I know the adjacency matrix so even even how
how I number these guys I will get different adjacency matrices so my likelihoods will be different right and
the reason for this is that when I have a graph I just have
the structure I have no node labels I have this this numbering of the nodes is
arbitrary right I can number an one two three four or I can number them some other
way and the way I number them I will get different adjacency matrices so
if I calculate the likelihood as I showed before the likelihood of this graph
is different than the likelihood of of this graph even though I have the same graphs
so the way how I want to get around this is to consider all possible permutations
right so I will consider all possible numberings or labelings of this graph and average
the likelihood of each one of themto get the final likelihood and
of course this won't work because there are n factorial of of these and if I want to
work with graphs of ten thousand nodes then this is ten to a million or something okay and
there is another problem which is just just the calculation even if somebody gives me the
permutation and the parameter matrix calculating this is still non nontrivial because it's quadratic in the size
of the graph right I need to go through trough every cell compare and multiply
this number so whenever I want to calculate this I need to go over n squared
number of operations and there are ways to get away so doing this naively would would
have this prohibitive complexity n factorial n square and you need n
factorial for graph isomorphism sort of testing because you need to consider all these labelings and
you need n n squared because you need to go through this two adjacency matrix cell by cell
and count how many I just match and how many don't and we have a way to do this
in linear time so now I show you how to do this very quickly and then we have a nice paper where
where the details will be clear but the idea is the idea is for
for labelingsthe idea is we we won't go through all the labelings
but we'll just check some of the important labelings so the idea is to go
and sample the labelings right so we are sort of you can think of it as as
doing some kind of simulated annealing over the labelings and this way we are
able to calculate the likelihood or the the derivative of the likelihoodefficiently
and I want to leave it here so this is called metropolis sampling we'll start with
with some random permutation do do do do local moves on the permutation so
right we will be making swaps on the node labels and recalculating the likelihood
and ja so for example like this I will go I will pick two
nodes and change their labels this will change my adjacency matrix right the two rows and two columns will rotate
recalculate the likelihood and there is another thing that comes out of this right so
only only only thing that we need to do is only swap two rows and columns
but that they were
of course
o images that can
have only
on the
the only way to make a one hundred million gallons of the
following this
there also the when you objective
it could be a
it may been there
of course
i that's
OK by you
they essentially
that i have shown
so as such by
the but they went
the get
and my
no of course
for example
the last three
we do it like that
all right
and and actually i think they
they believe
i don't want to know
it stated basically every textbook i don't know it's singer textbook which explicitly states which
technology bronze medalist but that's actually what the text was written
because it turns out that if this set is the set here is in fact
tried it is infinite so
but there's different kind of infinite sets
countable and uncountable
and if the set is countable
then refine sigma algebra on which this measure is defined which is implicitly defined by
the proof of this theorem
and the sigma algebra is
it is useful sigmod rather we can actually reverse it's exactly the kind of forensic
my brother would like to work with
but it turns out that if the set is uncountable
then the sigma algebra on which this measure lift and therefore this measure as well
is basically
and so
in particular in the uncountable case the sigmod but does not include the one point
we can't put probability two and one points and that's not the same as saying
we can't it all the one point sets of zero probability
it means that
putting the one point set into the probability measure simply undefined probability measure see that
and the problem here is that this this sigma algebra is is too coarse
its resolution is fine
the situation for that is if you
if you think of this
if you think of this picture here again
basically you have an infinite dimensional space here
and this sigma algebra that you get
on which this measure lift is generated by the sets so basically you start with
all the all sets that look like this
which have finite adaptive are defined by a finite dimensional marginal so this year is
finite dimensional
then you apply this sigma algebra operations
to them and combine them into countable intersections complements and so on
and c and takes sigmod above all sets that you can produce in that way
and intuitively speaking if
since the signature operations always countable
we can use it to produce
we can use it to produce sets were very where this is nontrivial number this
is non trivial subspaces count
but still is an overall space which is uncommon which is much much much larger
so what that means is these these these sets that we can produce and that
we can put her abilities on are basically sets which are which are non-trivial unaccountable
number of directions
and look like it's in all other directions are in terms of random variables
that means if you
each dimension corresponds to one random variables in our infinite vector right
and if we have a non-trivial shape here in some directions some number of dimensions
and for the corresponding random variables we can make nontrivial statements like they take a
value in the set between this value and this like that if the set looks
like a cylinder for in the direction corresponding to one random variable simply says random
variable takes some value in space
so that's that's attributed statement so
what this allows us to this allows us to to put probabilities on events that
let's say something about a countable subset of the random variables
but not about already
in particular we can say if we want to have a one point set we
if want to stay around takes one particular
o point as its value
then we have to make a statement about every single entry in this long
four for almost anything you want to do you want to be able to measure
the singletons
if you this this is
these sets really look like like the sets that you can put the probability on
really look like in long cylinders but i think you are actually i think
maybe maybe
standing in terms of random variables is better
if you if you think of a random draw from this as a function
and then you can only say you can only give the probability to the event
that this function
take certain values and a countable number of points but you can't say anything about
the overall function
well OK if you if you're happy with that purpose quite well
there are actually you actually always have to reverse congo
but basically you start from this and then in order to if this is uncountable
then you have to make like a second step to turn image into something useful
as a lot of people
my guess you might you might but for gaussianprocess process for example you would like
to say something about say the probability that
that you draw one particular function
even though problem is there are you want to condition on
that's something you can do it here
very quickly i can't really tell you how to fix this problem because this is
where things get really quite difficult
you really have to
starting quite a really a lot of map
and also there's there's i'm not aware of any
kind of unified way
two to fix this problem for all
for all processes that you might want to to construct
so you know there's there's one way to fix it for constructions of agustin process
so it it doesn't depend on the process depends on the space
down but
in the gaussianprocess set up this one way to do it in the process and
this another way to do it and i don't know of any way to to
unify the
but basically the the intuition is is again the situation that for example for continuous
they are completely defined on on a on a countable subset
of our unconscious
and we're not really interested me want to define something like girls process we're not
really interested in defining measure on arbitrary functions from the real unto itself
because almost all of these functions are seen to jump at every single point
we can work with that we're interested in is you know
continuous functions may be piecewise continuous functions
and in the sense here
continuous and piecewise continuous functions have
countable complexity havoc on the the number of degrees of freedom
and how we leverage that is a difficult question because the space of this this
product space setting doesn't doesn't really apply anymore you can simply write the space of
continuous functions as the product space you can embed them in the product space
but then they are basically like like the cloud of points in this products
there are techniques for starting with common goal of construction on the product space and
then restricting you measure to the subspace but you have you have to take into
account how sigma algebra looks you have to take into account quite a bit of
and similarly for similar techniques are applicable for probability measures we also make an argument
a bit like actually in the common theorem itself that they are defined by by
their values on account of the subsystem of the signal
so the idea is always like find something comparable completely defined
defines the probability measure and use that
to get around this problem is uncountable dimensions
that's the gist of it
OK now in
fifteen minutes
let me say a few words at least about
something that you that you can do with this and this is where
this were my work starts so
we find formula this set
well well the practice the answer to that question is that
you get more and the new terminate the program because the authorities for not well
you don't know
that there is
whether this plan or not
the only one only one that you know that this plan noticed that you actually
want to plan
you're right selling his soul
that you know that you have
about all possible class
and this is for us to link
equals the maximum possible roughly equal the number of states in your
the problem
and this typical is like this or
hundreds of millions or whatever and what i can imagine
in practice you can be
this thing
so the only thing is that it's just run the school and you find something
but you don't know what they supply
so there's not
practical it
so in this example here you generate homeless plan is zero one
three four
all of these form laws
unsatisfiable simply by
the university also
unit clauses in the results the formula
for the initial state and
if the goal is to construct an awful it also one of the only that's
also also
in many cases allows you to infer that it's impossible to leeds
from the initial state by short
so this is the case of
what are planning i the satisfiable
this fun
after of really three is so in the next slides
it was something planned
i have access or seven access depending weights
satisfying valuation is that going one
the optimal play with the band that has the smallest number
actions as well that is most
so what happens is that the SAT solver
yes the
well the
SAT solvers can be understood as
maintaining partial evaluation of the
process variables
these the ecology
correspond to the unit clauses in the origin of online
well if you have be developed well before the actual search task consists of unit
clauses in your example formula plus
then unit clauses opened by interaction so things that can be
we now planning problem
well i'm only showing the variables
corresponding the state variables the
variables for the axis of course
are one of
column here
so the values of the state variables at time point zero which is the initial
states of the
initial goal values of the
there is also
so the initial state what i what i sort of feel like for example
and he are clear
so these are two works that
clear on top of the stack
then the remaining of your relation
based on a system b
so the
looks a and b
one is very proud of is
so first of course corresponds the initial state and
the call for fun
you can see that it be on be
so a b see
c and b
and dr
and in
all the remaining
values of the process variables
we need to show was the typically what you know that
in the initial state something is true
and none of the actions
the preconditions of all the actions that change the value of that
state variable falls
none of those actions can be taken so also in the next timepoint one
that they have the same so that's why we have been able to to infer
a lot
process variables
so this is the
data sets off before in the first place
and what being said so
does this situation that's not
falsified any part of any of the classes
in the in the south problem yet
and some of the data
most people
i don't know about so it doesn't know whether this formula is satisfiable
so article tries to make
the evaluation of complicated
so either
satisfy all the clauses or to derive the course or not know what
this that's or in this case
well there are several choices which were believed would have chosen for browsing
it's always variable here b
and i mean that was one of the
they have also been value
in the world in order to search for this that's what's going through
not that they able post chosen
it's not red on the of their
decided to make the
process there was
so what
are going round italy
not be one
making the decision have one mil one unit clause to continue nutritional
so i clicked game and you see that we're left with no
unsatisfiable classes
so if the ontology
before the
some new work on fine grained justifications
any questions on justifications are repaired
so an example is seen here is a good question we just we just take
it's very removing one axiom from each justifications for deleting axioms from the ontology this
may you'll see that this is a
the problem in some sense is required to the next part
but could also rewrite the axioms in a certain way so that we didn't lose
all the information in that play more realistic scenario this is common in the repair
we've got axiom we incoming which is essentially right section so that it the right
enough you can select one of the rewriting so that entailments broken
or will play at some support for going on directly editing the axioms
we saw in the example sometimes we have to do you want to just delete
the actions made some cocoa can drag and drop problem or whatever
an ontology we didn't realize about stealing classified everything turn red
and we go back to pinpoint reason why i'm complicated we did that
OK got any other questions
now i want to talk about some kind of the kind of justifications
and i want to just talk about some issues that justifications half so the first
of these is superfluousness
so one of
if we just recall
one of the nice things about
o justifications was that they
i took a large set of axioms they now these down into a small set
of axioms to focus on so before
we we
have clue maybe which action is responsible for the interment particularly through multiple particularly
if there are multiple reasons and i think about justification is that it take the
axioms playing a handful of very large ontology
and now sits down and we can focus on this nice small subset
but the problem here is
the main parts of axioms that are actually responsible
for the given entailment
that would a good justification for to be superfluous parts
what we really like is
just to identify the parts of the axioms that are responsible for home and discovered
the superfluous parts in some sense because it is superfluous parts
can the hunt for our understanding we might if we got larger ssific ation and
justifications can in realistic ontologies that we've looked at can sometimes be over twenty axioms
to twenty actions in size
and sometimes they contain very long axioms people we find that people of some people
we've added some tools like push a open like rising very very long that the
axioms axioms containing class descriptions and some of these contain superfluous parts of for trying
to understand the reason for justification and they have some contain superfluous parts my distractors
from really focusing on the past that matters and this is one reason and then
if we come to repair ontology
if we were to remove one axiom completely may be moving too much
so if
so we had something that was superfluous entailment we might actually want to keep this
this might be a valid model with whom i valid modelling going on here
might to keep this again would like to really know for sure
which part of the axioms in the justifications are required to support entailments which parts
so here is a small small example for you here we have
the justification for
d being unsatisfiable
and in this justification we have the audience is supposed to be business of clusters
exist RC
and across the frolov bottom
and in this case for the purposes of entailment this
the disjunction left inside the first axiom
it's superfluous we don't need it for the entailment
and also
for the second axiom
the failure of this restriction c is also superfluous for the entailment so we only
need to know it is of course the b and b is a subclass of
least one everything that needs to be at least one also to that we don't
so the follows the possible worlds semantics
so i will use that to illustrate the meaning of query and the meaning of
the results and now we talk about how to do the koran to efficiently
first of all i will introduce some indexes sponsored in data one i will introduce
one example for the answer numeric data and one for categorical data
so this is the tree introduced by professor in hong kong is published in two
thousand five so
it to be particularly handles the numerical data and the probabilistic threshold queries
so let's take example here we have four hundred and after with arbitrary shape
and i the jury within the possible area
so if we have query range
kill here
so we want to find out as objects who lives in the currie range with
a large probability lists zero point five
so how to solve such inquiry
first of all we want to compute the probability that object lies in query range
which is the cause of pure with probability
for example if we want to compute the probability that c lies inquiring range q
how to compute that we just use the integral of PDF of c which can
be arbitrary on the the intersection of c and q
as we see here that computation could be quite quite costly so the goal of
tree is to do the car answering and try to avoid this computation of appearance
probability as much as possible
so let's give you an idea of you treat
first of all this is that object keep all with very arbitrary shape
and in order to do the in order to add some additional information to help
car answering we do the fall falling things
first of all we partition that they adopted horizontally
so the poses the to the object
we first partition them horizontally so that we we have three parts
the latter part of the object
its probability is exactly p
p can be specified by the user
and the right part is often also exactly p
so i think it's projected into the
and so it's
one dimension which is easy to compute
and we also partition the data vertically
also the lower part is p and the probability of the other parties of p
so how to help car answering
suppose we are we already have the partition and we have another query
thank you
the current range is the pink orange
and as such hold is tau which is zero point eight
so from this we can see that
the current range is disjoint with the right part
with probability zero point two
so which means that the probability of the intersection
it is
o is smaller than their point eight
we could see that because we we can draw the conclusion without compute it's real
problem at all probability so we can prove the pop up to all safely
throughout got to the range query
that's how we use the idea the partition to help from the primary for an
and also can be used to validate object
so with the help of the partition and the minimum bombing range
this is the minimum ponderings of the object
so the post we have
probability range query q that carry range is that pink our
critically it covers the minimal bombing range
and the horizontally it covers right part whose probability zero point two
so by only looking to the two dimensions separately we know that the probability of
the intersection is greater than zero point two
so we could we could safely put this object into set without computing the probability
so this is the idea of how to about that it was adopted without can
the computation
so that we know that if we
the partition with respect to certain p it can only help some inquiries
so when we want to do the partition a few times the wall currents can
be helped
that's why we let set of p and computer that partitions
and the the punisher were presented by the
rectangle just inside it's called the probability probabilistic constant region
so what information we want to start
it's just to all those rectangles about the object
and to organize the information we use are like structure is called UP tree so
you only know that it contends that this address of the object the minimum bounding
rectangle and the set of PCR we computed
and a is the intermediate node we in index the pointer to the child nodes
and as the minimum bounding range of PC
so instead of that likely are two we have them in morning and followed that
up to here we for the PCI because so we want to help the range
powerful for probabilistic data
so the current evaluation is quite similar to the correlation in archery we just search
from the root note and in the e
each intermediate entry we just try to check if the car is destroyed or overlap
with the minimum bounding rectangle the PC
so this is the idea of you treat
but in some application area
we do not really have an answer to newmarket data instead of the data is
for example this them this is
car repairing record one two record is the problem of car
but we will not pretty sure which probably exactly is
so we have a field possible values for the problem of car
for example t one whose problem is break
and the confidence is zero point five
and the tyre with confidence point five which means the problem this car is that
at the break of time each have their point for probability
so our user may want to ask what we want to find the temples whose
problem is break with probability there seem to point three and the tyre with probability
there are playing field
so here
the query is represented by a few possible values and uncertain attribute with their confidence
and what we want to find is that couples who can match the query with
a large probability
and large probability is represented by the threshold to o point seven
for example we compared to one and query we compute the probability of their matches
so really
it's more like this usually goes in this order well
i mean it's it's like what we want to know the answers to these questions
we want to know what is what we ultimately want to know what is good
what's a good filter to choose
we would like to be symmetric with good properties that
we would like to produce a nice solution in fact would like to produce smooth
for pretty reasonably small solution
we would like the solution to be useful
to have this approximating power because what do we do with with function we
so here's what we hope
we hope that this basically zero captures
quite successfully our signal
continuous time now so captures the typical signals
of course if it's really difficult signal to capture then it's we're going to need
more of the details but what we hope is
we hope we
i hope to choose a zero
so that
so there are
we can say that in many ways a continuous time i can hope to choose
a zero so that he is a really good approximation to bicycle
maybe try to match my signal well actually here
you're specifying it's the function fy
raises the tricky question is really never got result suppose we wanted to
suppose i signal we're looking for is like a tank
the shape of the tank
so you might say well
shows fee
to look like a tank
it will be shown
by by using these functions as a basis will
we will capture tank if
which shape of the tank
i have no idea what ages
what give such a thing
somehow the direction hasn't been very fruitful
we are more likely to ask
one feature is a good approximation to
reasonable shapes
good approximation to reason
and then
five it's a great
these are all very good questions
after the war
these features or the function phi
let's see
well first of all
teachers are finite feel automatically find the length is just matches five three features in
this example
the feature will go from zero to two
and that's the kind of
the first surprise
about the solutions to this equation
have finite life becomes zero
the solutions of
differential equations generally
go up exponentially with the
exponentially but don't
cut off
it's the
that's only possible because these two scales in here
well that somehow somewhere in the number of terms so he will go from zero
in our function will also go from zero
that's pretty neat
i guess the answer do we don't have to stay with
finite length
i mean but that course find like functions correspond to finite length filters is sort
of natural starting place
o but then have no
the first keep coming in of constructions that
right down to this old and say well
let's use infinite length filters
get more freedom in the function
it's a
let me just mention one another example i was going to mention two
two or three other examples OK there's
this the challenge
suppose i look at this
particular dilation equation
just that
what's the filter that goes with what's the
it's not one of the coefficients
on the right hand side there
well there's only one coefficient
and that's what
fact two is the two
OK so there is
please that's called alwasy felt
it doesn't do anything at all
just i
right pre-defined five matrix is a matrix of one on the diagonal
if i do the convolution
nothing happens
now tell me what's the
the scaling function
that's the right for fifty years scaling function i don't think i don't believe me
these are scaling
not especially early by the way
know what function solves that
delta quite
delta question
which i would like news to me
sophie in t
delta two
that's kind of funny i never really thought about delta two t or something and
maybe we should think about this
why why
because then you can do anything
and you can be
part of those very rare people who can put it all together
i was just the seventieth birthday party or when jacobs
this past week
and when jacobs is the CEO of qualcomm
which is the company that started to build
CDMA wireless systems
for a long time the CDMA systems
were thought to have
that's probably better
in TTMM ANF TMI
but much more expensive
and eventually
or in the situation where all the new systems being designed or are using CT
as result of this sermon jacobs is a very wealthy person
we went to a symphony
friday night out in san diego
which was given specifically for him
partly because he just given one hundred ten million dollars to the san diego symphony
so you can figure from that that he's fairly wealthy
well the point of all of that is he started out as a faculty member
he was one of the authors of wasn't crafting jacobs which is the
which is sort of the bible
of digital communication systems
from the sixties and people still use it is still an excellent book
and in doing that he really learned the communication trade
from soup to i guess you can nazis the way we put it now
and then he could do the whole thing because he could do the whole thing
because he understood coding because he understood modulation because he understood channels this is why
you could design systems are really work
i was talking to the chief technology officer out there
and the chief technology officer said it was really very easy
because they're meant that all of them himself
and he still does it
OK so
so it really makes sense to know something about all of these pieces
if you want to become a billionaire
if you want to become a billionaire without
without cheating
now many people become billionaires by cheating
and you for many of them but
anyway and after that
i mean that was really wanna be billionaires and and anyway this
but i think i mean there's nothing you can do with more than a a
billion dollars right
it's always
let's move on
we've gotten rid of digital coding saying we're not going to deal with that here
let me take the PAAM out of here because i only say what it is
if we take this box i call modulation before which was one of the one
of the two main pieces
the channel encoder
we can break it down into two pieces
namely namely we're going to be layering things again
we start out with a symbol sequence which is what comes out of the encoder
which is usually just
just a short sequence of binary digits
so the symbols can be thought of
s two binary digits
in a sequence of four binary digits
four six two possible binary digits or what have you
and all of those are common
there's then a single constellation the turn symbols into signals
now notation in the field
totally non uniform
because most people
use symbols
and sequences and waveforms
and binary
and two poles
all totally anonymously
and the station will try to make here
is the symbols
things like binary digits
but don't have any numerical
meaning to them
i mean no one zero
the only thing important there is that one zero are different from each other
all computer scientists call ones and zeros alice's and bob's
lots of other people calling plus one to minus one doesn't make any difference what
you call it it's just
an alphabet with two values and
we talk about saying also we're talking about numerical values
so in fact you could have a single constellation with two elements and were what
you're doing is mapping one zero
in two plus one minus one now that's a pretty silly kind of situations but
it still has the value of saying you're turning things
where is just an alphabet size two into something where you're saying these are numerical
values and you're interested in the difference between numerical values and the difference is measured
in the ordinary way
measuring difference four numerical values
who are these can be vectors also bit vectors in an inner product space were
again you have lied and you have distance you have numerical values here you don't
have numerical values here
so we want to talk about how you do this
and then
for the most part we're going to define modulation is what happens when you go
from the signal sequence
to the waveform
you might realise that our notation
is lousy here
because i'm calling modulation this whole thing and i'm also calling modulation just this thing
i'm doing that because there doesn't seem to be any other reasonable word for either
one of these things
i'm gonna later split this into two pieces also
but that will come later so anyway we're going from symbols the signals to waveforms
might look remarkably similar to what we did was sources we just it backwards what
sources we went from waveforms
o two signals the symbols there
the explanation would be this perhaps some genetic defects mutation
all right
that would make you crave nicotine
and also make you get lung cancer
i actually think at one time the
so cigarette manufacturers what we're arguing this point never seen that somewhere
but again this was just x and y
that explanations as good as others they always make
smoking and lung cancer correlated
it seems like you can learn causal influences from from correlation from passive data
but the problem here is that we only have data on two variables
all right well will
in the nineties has shown that we can learn something about causal influences
if we have data on at least four variables
that it might seem while getting data and other variables
other than smoking and lung cancer may enable you to conclude that smoking causes lung
and that's is actually the purpose of this talk
right well why that's the case
anyway if you have more data you can learn something
first i need to define a causal graph
in general when i have something written like this i'm not going to just say
satellite like powerpoint presentations and and
there's no point in saying what you can read or even necessary leaving it up
to one another
read what i want do is is go over examples more and you can come
back to these definitions later and
and look at them so in general not going to be reading these things
here's here's what we mean by direct cause this is the study in rats by
lugg et al nineteen ninety five
they manipulated testosterone levels
and found that they had a causal effect and DHT levels dehydratase testosterone
they also manipulated
testosterone levels they found that it had
causal factor and erectile function
so first faster on
DHT levels
found it also causes erectile function
they manipulated DHT itself
all right well testosterone fixed and found that it had
and in fact
and erectile function
so there's an error here
now why didn't pietronero from t
why is that there are missing
well because when they held DHT fixed and give them what they they held at
it didn't matter whether testosterone was low or high
the the level of erectile function was the same
when they text is high
the same thing
it didn't matter
whether what the testosterone levels erectile function levels were the same
OK so
is not a direct cause of the that's why natural and nature by direct cause
we mean there's no variable
amongst the observed variables that mediates the causal factor
now what if DHT wasn't one of observed variables will then there would be an
error directly here so whether something is the direct cause in that is
this dependent upon which the able to actually observing and we can argue falls off
there's always some
intermediate variables and things just
you know unfolding in some sense way and we only as humans articulate certain variables
that we observe
right so that's what we mean by the red cross in the causal graph is
a graph containing
variables and edges that i direct classes
here's another thing
just say right because the saying it isn't going to
i'm have just accuracy how many people know the causal markov assumption and i'm going
to get a feel for my audience
so the majority are not really familiar with problem networks motivation networks right
you're not
so fact that
to me there are like
well causal networks special kind of asian network it's one where the parents represent causal
the station that we're just represents conditional independencies
and you don't necessarily given causal meaning but then a certain kind of patient that
because the causal network
in other words it's a subset of all patient networks with the edges to represent
but in
this is the most people don't know either in this audience
so i'm going to this is part the causal markov assumption
and again i'm not going to read what i need to show it by examples
i don't know what's going on the bottom things this is the probability distribution satisfies
the markov condition
if the probability of each variable
is independent of its non descendants conditional on its parents
and then we assume that the causal graph containing the variables satisfies that assumption we
make the causal markov assumption
we get for whom
can show
which is that the people of one
four years later
they also
i mentioned the problem of the
is people
one of
of course
how old are
all the
we want
we're not
use of
o or one or more
all right
you know i
robert the world
from the model
you know go
one of his
the road to the point of incoming calls
they can
so more recently EPA human to design a car he did not catch because of
but you think the that the problem of parking not navigation your pocket because the
main difference is that every trade-off
some of listed here
and so on what we did was also human driver to actually drive the car
around the parking lot francis a
started here i want to talk in that spot gigi there from you and just
tell me how you do it driving nicely trying different styles
and so on
you should algorithm on the training set parking lots and think about how human traits
of these differences are as and they can take the car instance simulations in new
parking lot and here's one result if you have a human demonstrated nice driving style
meaning in the opening also wrote trying to stay on the road and so on
on this is the trajectory that he chooses to their
and this is the seems pretty reasonable way
to drive your car
he goes the park in nineteen forty
and of course
just to show this is hard coded you also human demonstrate the driving styles one
is called the sloppy driving style where you you know if you demonstrate cutting diagonally
across the parking lot some was that then this is sort of
one of the you get words here
we have actually does planning as it as it is possible the map of the
environment so this learned that should cut narrowly between those two cars in order to
get quickly
the last one of in some drivers required running backwards and so if you have
no if you have no aversion driving backwards and some people drivers backwards and forwards
then then
actually does the
backing up
and puts in a great position to
this is just the sort of range of behavior you can learn using imitation using
can do so this is another fine example this zico kolter work
on some of and i think he was also a lot of so
for some problems it turns out to be very difficult to demonstrate exactly what to
do with the robot so give quite a robot like this turns out to be
very difficult for human to sit down the joystick robot robot six leagues economy is
actually very hard for humans to demonstrate how to control quadruped robot like this
fact even given the reward function in terms of the planet completes the footsteps is
very difficult very high dimensional problem
but taking a page from
hierarchical reinforcement learning intersecting into hierarchical apprenticeship learning in the same way so here's what
i mean
if you're doing for the planning for the control tasks we are probably going to
decompose the planet passes multiple levels of abstraction anyway
and so what we're going to do is also human to specify the demonstration the
same multiple levels of abstraction
so here's what i mean
if you want to solve the planning task again robot from the initial state to
a goal state gonna use hierarchical RL idea pioneered by his rich doing here and
i think is wrong and time director fields on and some high-level body motion planning
part we first two to be part of the problem of how they get from
how they get my body roughly from from the initial state goal state and they
also have a little tiny tiles of exactly how you place the feet to get
from the initial state to a goal state
and so given the decomposition of the robot dog problem to high level and low
level tasks you can then ask the demonstrations of the same too high level and
low level tasks to complete the the high level it turns out that we expect
on dolls like physical cause there is we can look at a map like this
this is the height map by the way with the lighter shades to higher places
and that in those locations that exposed
go well you should follow approximately this part the this demonstration of the higher level
of abstraction
and his demonstration of the low level of abstraction which is you should i say
you know OK my doctor this position the height matter where feet are and have
been explored the dark legs eco is you can actually look at this and say
i think you should find that to that position
so this turns out to be as all the demonstration that you know that there
it's much easier for people to come up with
and we put these together it turns out his attitude to equation listening to of
you can put these things together to learn a reward function for the everybody start
get over difficult articles before i show you the result after learning that essentially show
you the result of the
before learning result against this is on
if the
dog does not have the reward function
and this
try to use central pattern generators step regular pattern the position
it's part of the state
this this failing dying motions always fun to watch
so there's this road was built by boston dynamics of is usually smaller
and so
and i should say this one more those examples are all i think are all
has had many successes by many crews in many different countries and on what is
like about this example is that we genuinely try lots of things were motivated to
do whether whether it takes to get the robot to to to work we try
to assess things we genuinely try hand tuning for you know i don't know maybe
about a month and we actually primary motivation was not to show of our approach
is getting work on january the best thing we found was appointed sort of apprenticeship
learning reinforcement learning how
they are more
yes that is the
all the tricks and there's not only stupid tries to maintain balance in the law