so that you have
a total forest of something like two million decision tree nodes so we've got this
extremely complicated classifier
and yet it's performing really well on this dataset
which is really kind of surprising was also surprising even more surprising is that the
test here
continues to drop even after the training year has reached zero
so if you look at these numbers down here
so after five rounds the training here
after a thousand around the training year course is still zero
what is occam's razor say
here you've got
an explanation of the data which is two hundred times more complicated
then you have over here
so occam's razor says
this once it should certainly be people performing worse
and this one
and that's exactly the opposite of what we actually observe
instead what we observe is that the test there is a point four percent after
five rounds
after thousand rounds down to three point one percent
question about
so that's the one thing that is only going up for one round and round
so some of this
it but it's very exaggerated on this graph because it's a logarithmic scale
so it's kind of a
kind of analogous to what happened on that toy problem that toy example
where we started out with an of thirty percent
it was
let's say
right so in that example you started out with an area of thirty percent on
the next round
the weak classifier had an area of twenty one percent so would have higher
weight and on the first round so it tends to happen is
in the second round
the second we classify tends to have higher weight
in the first week classifier to be taken into what weighted majority vote of just
those two
the one with larger weight will always dominate
the other one so effectively you're just looking at that second we classifier which tends
to be worse
training in
the training here in principle can go up
i don't see that very often i'm not sure i've ever seen
other than that second round of boosting the bound on the training are always decreases
i'm sorry
question is do we need to prevent overfitting the weak classifiers
so if the weak classifiers are really overfitting the data then there's nothing boosting can
to help
right so
they do have to do some kind of prevention of over fitting of the weak
there have been some experiments where people are
term pruning on or off
for decision tree algorithms pruning is supposed to prevent overfitting
and that turns out not to make much of a difference for boosting but certainly
need to do some prevention of overfitting
i'm sorry
if think is coming one
i still quite a really loud
it was producing a combination of four by
o was that what we're doing here
that's what i would like to think
that that's
that's exactly what we're doing
there goes OK
that's what we're doing we're using c four point five is the weak learning algorithm
in this particular experiment
we're using boosting on top of that
he is so i
so if use
OK so so again it's a question about overfitting
so that says i'm holding the flag which represents the likelihood that has the right
here at this time and i'm going to go for it and make sure they
are properly represent
right so
in which each node you replace the birds arriving at that node with a single
about that carries the sum of their values and now you don't need an exponential
number of bugs
you just need a quadratic number of bugs
you end up here you have to take them in square and then it is
representative democracy thing you get back down and then you replicated in square back down
and and so on so you never need more than and squared where n is
the number of states
so the trail is called dynamic programming
extremely powerful algorithm comes up and all kinds of fields from statistics to engineering to
computer science
and it can be used whenever you have any kind of summation or search for
maximisation problem that can be set up on the grid in in this way so
that the values
something as it arrives at a particular state
depends you only care about one
o point in the greatest
that you don't care about its history once once again
so ago
don't have to be time state they can be anything else that that you want
they can be you know position and and high or anything else to compute various
difficult some
so this is exactly what population
it's exactly dynamic programming on the screen
so that was the trick for computing the likelihood and the last thing here is
just to show that you can do the same thing for computing in particular marginal
this is now posterior marginal probability of xt given y
at some time so there's a simple
equation here for computing this which involves another recursion variable data energies run recursion backwards
and i can show
the corresponding trick is here on the graph
we need to compute the marginal probability on this HMM graph in egypt
lot particular note or some combination of state in time and ask what is this
the termites
what is the probability that in generating the observation sequence
i going go through a particular state at time xt
if you do that then you could just divide that by the total probability that
would be the first year of being in that state at that time
as i see that
if you ask the sum of the paths that happened to go through this node
then just by dividing that some by the total sum which we already saw the
computer you can get the posterior
this is to do this we just basically equivalent trick from
both sides so we
we run this recursion for
from time zero up to this time t here
and we compute the sum of all the things that land upon this node using
the same trick i showed you before
and then we started the end and one of the bugs this way and we
compute many of them end up here and that we add those quantities together and
that gives us
the sum one
so actually
and this is the the same triggers in belief propagation we can actually just run
one forward pass to compute all the alphas and another backward pass to compute all
debaters and any
what we want is the product of alpha and beta that node
so it looks here like you to do special recursion to get the posterior at
it's the solution if you like to the differential equation that's a fancy way of
saying it
the y dt
equals a times y
now course test is not unique we can make it unique by putting an initial
value so if i want to get this function and not constant times the i
make this an initial value problem and say that y is zero should be one
and now i will get only the function
in the eighty
so in other words that characterizes this function
it's the only function of the whole world which has that property
now if you could call something into the i data
it should have
we want that to be true
so here my question is it true that e to the i data one
let's use that time the i th data two
i see i'm on a collision course here but that's easily fixed
does that equal to e to the i data one state two
if that turns out to be so
that's all big step
what would we like to be true here well will be true that the derivative
with respect to t
of the i th data i would like that to come be equal to or
a times
e to the data
so the question
i think those are the two most significant things now the nodes do a third
thing talk about infinite series
i since
we haven't done infinite series was anyway is not officially part of the syllabus
the kind of power series that are required but i will put it down for
the sake of completeness as people like to say so
it should
hey right with there is the infinite series should be nice
infinite series should
work out should
work should be
there's no way for this should work out let's say
it was a little music
we are music i is it only me that here
you have
somebody up there i feel i'm being watched up there was a terrible
so there's one guy
here's another guy
and i will put a box around the infinite series is i'm not going to
say anything about it
these things in fact are both true otherwise why would i be saying and why
would oiler made the formula but what's interesting to see is what's behind them
let's select and that gives you a little practice also in calculating with the complex
so let's look at the first one what it say what it is asking the
question it says please
calculate the product of these two things OK i do what i'm told i will
calculate the product of cosine
they don't want
plus i cosine created two
so i paid one
that's EDI the i data one right that corresponds to
the other factor times the other factor
data to class i sin theta
OK what is that come out to be
well again will use the method of grouping
what's the real part of the the real part of it is co-signed they a
cosine data two
and then there's the real part which comes from these two factors
it's going to occur with a minus sign because of the i squared and what's
left is signed data one
signed data two
and the imaginary part of factor out the all i
and then what's left we'll but i want to keep repeating the eye so it
will be
data one cosine data two
and the other factor will be
cosine data one signed data two
they two
cosine data one
well looks like a mess but
again high school to the rescue
what is this
the top thing is nothing in the sky
a disguised form
cosine if theta one plus they two
and the bottom line is
sign theta one of the two
so the product of these two things is this
and that's exactly the formula
in other words this formula is the way of writing those two trigonometric identities for
the cosine of the sum and the sign of the sum
instead of the two identities taking up that much space written one after the other
they take up this much space and they say exactly the same thing
those two trigonometric identities are exactly the same as saying that you the i th
data satisfies the exponential law
now you know
people ask you know what
was beautiful in mathematics to me that's beautiful but i think that's great
something along turns into something short and it's just as good and moreover connects with
all these other things in the world differential equations infant survival
i had to sell oil results themselves
how about the other one
that's obviously
has been well i haven't said something because i for one thing a differentiated this
eighty here
t down there are clouds OK that's easily fixed
but at what says how differentiate this
what kind of the guy is in the i data well
if i right now
take a look at what it is it's cosine data
plus i signed data
i stated very is the function
the variable is real
fate is the real variable
you know it's the angle in radians better runs from negative infinity to infinity
so what if you think functions as a black box what's going on is a
real number but what's coming out is a complex number
so schematically
if p is the
i data box and you like to think that way
data goes in
i'm very quickly going to recap the first half i talked about people in the
very can think that
that will be useful idea and then
as i promised gonna move on to the topic of the
first off i started by saying that we need to get numbers into a computer
somehow so we have a data which is
in matrix of implications things like
amount of aggregate my concrete amount of sand in my concrete say
each of the columns will be a feature there
the amount of standing
concrete type one man standing concrete type two and so on
and then i have a second attribute
and i'll continue so i have
matrix the inputs
and then i have the vector of
which could be
real numbers for concrete strength or plus one to minus one for classification problems
and then we need to build some sort of
description of this data set which i can use in order to
do useful things in the future
so one of the
ways of describing this dataset was using the parametric model and one of the parametric
models with logistic regression which was the model for when we have plus one to
minus one
so the logistic regression model said i think that
these labels
are noisy draws from a distribution that depends on the matrix
one of the rows of this matrix which i'm going to call x so this
road here
it is located vectors being
i'm going to assume that the label y
y one
came from
which was equal to
something i wrote down
and it depended on
the weight vector interacting
this in fact right
such that
if the weight is strongly aligned with the input direction
so that really likes it says very high probability that you're going to be a
plus one
w and x are orthogonal at right angles to each other and this is zero
and it's going to be half probability this it's zero or
but it's the one or minus one
and similarly if x and up to point in opposite directions and there's a high
probability will get minus one
so then what we do is
we come up with an objective for
fitting w such that the the probability of seeing this particular data is high
so that was the basic setup logistic regression
and it turned out that we could get this simple description of the data and
make it into a much more powerful method
with this trick of adding extra columns to this matrix
only five you miss as i spoke quickly exactly where this extra columns came from
and maybe the reason you missed it is it's kind of arbitrary so
this is a column of numbers that i actually am i was actually given
from my problem you know this is the amount of sand or something like that
and at some point the real columns well and and it turned out to be
useful to add a column of ones because then it meant that the decision plane
could not go through the origin w transpose x will always be zero if x
is also sorry if w is all
there is a
the effect all there then
this will always be
there are no matter what WS
so adding this column of one stocks
then we add extra columns
using any rule we like so an example is we could get
these numbers in square
so this will be twenty five point something
and this will be twenty five points more and
we just take this column we square every element and create another whole column we
could also
take the first two columns and multiply them together and that could be another column
we could take it to the calls of this column make
make that's another column any non function you want to cook up in theory you
could do that and add an extra column
then you just the the same thing pretending that
the right
x was actually longer than what the application person gave has all these extra things
why do we do that well
in the
if i only had two features to begin with we could plot some problem in
two d so maybe all of the two classes
and the negative class is
location since we've got the two d input space
of x one
it might be impossible
find a plane that separates two classes describe the data center
so this logistic regression model is limited to fitting planes because this w vectors just
described plane
so one thing we can do is go away
and build a more complicated model that describes more than planes and that's what neural
networks and a lot of models that are well worth knowing about do
a simple thing
which isn't quite as powerful that can get you along way
do this trick by adding extra column
and now
this algorithm
still can just be supplying but if it's the plane this very high dimensional space
rather than two dimensions it's in many dimensions depending on how many columns with added
and if we look at
what that plane is doing in the original three dimensional space
it can be a curve so we can end up with the decision boundary that
actually separates classes so we take a linear methods to make it nonlinear by adding
these extra column
OK this is a simple version
the kernel trick which
something you can hear a lot more about in future lectures so those who heard
about the kernel trick or support vector machines which often use the kernel trick that
something slightly fancier than i'm describing here but it
based on this idea
that's sort
overview of all types of models i described and then we had a question
what we probably have many questions that one of them is well how many extra
column so i had when i add extra columns i can get
funky really weekly decision boundaries which is more powerful but maybe
it's not justified by my data maybe i don't have enough data to fit arbitrarily
complicated models
so maybe i want to limit the number of columns
it turns out that
big flexible models with many parameters often work well in applications fact reflecting the fact
that the real world is complicated
you just have to be careful using them so you have to be careful to
stop your fitting process from fitting
massively overconfident
weekly decision boundaries that when do very well when you deploy your system
so that was when i talked about regularisation
the idea of regularisation is two at the beginning before you look at the data
you know
large weight vectors have lots of very big values probably correspond to with the solutions
essentially commoditized a lot of the stack for operating large scale distributed systems
things for managing clusters the kind of techniques that google has pioneered published like mapreduce
and bigtable are now being heavily developed in the open source community
a kind of small
interesting anecdote for me was that i was we
we were approached by people have any chance of making a very large korean search
engine and it turned out that we were already
we approach because we were already collaborating
powerset has made a version of
our own open-source version that we're given out and are shown the open source community
for enabling very large scale distributed storage and manipulation tables and those folks at naver
nhn we're already working with us so without even anything at the business level are
engineers and developers are working together and by the way there are also applying this
in conjunction with university two
deal with RDF storage on top of the table
there are a couple of our age basically large scales
another major trend is a commodity computing you no longer have to have all your
own computers they're now increasingly sets of players providing services where you can essentially pay
for the computing resources as you go
amazon has been a pioneer here with their elastic computing cloud and their simple storage
system and tuple stores
so you can basically get large-scale access to computing resources without having yourself
OK now known into some examples of power how it's actually working
so i powerset reads each sentence one of the time
so for example sir edward heath died from pneumonia
powerset passes sentence on the page so in this case
there's the verb to die
so edward heath is pneumonia is now
extract entities and semantic relationships sir edward heath is not just about the name
and pneumonia
OK the relationships here are sir edward heath is the subject of the dying
and pneumonia is the the from or the cause of the time
and then using some level of inference powers identifies expands these things to similar entities
relationships and abstractions
so far he does but he is also UK prime minister
and as a politician
pneumonia is also a disease
and to derive from something is also to be killed by it
so for each sentence this kind of information extracted and then a lot facts
are indexed so that our are index actually already then derives benefits from the results
of these kinds of inferences
thereafter multiple queries can retrieve the same facts
what killed sir edward heath matches the sentence about or he died from pneumonia
and so does which prime minister died from pneumonia
and from what it said ahead were he to die and
so on
ultimately something like which politician died from pneumonia
or politicians who died from disease these are all capable of matching the same the
sentences and at that point there need be no connection between the actual words in
the sentence the words in the query but at a conceptual level the relationships are
OK i'm go show humor like really light screenshots moment but
in addition to
extracting information from the tax and doing a text search powers that also integrates diverse
resources so
you can see that here
in the middle of this page the query is what is steve jobs say about
the ipod
and mill this page a bunch of search results highlighting things like steve jobs states
that everyone listen to music and the ipods for everybody
and steve jobs argued that the ipod nano was necessary risk and so on
so those are web search results clubs
as web search results but in addition to
powerset can go out and access the resources and pulled together to decompose view
so from resource like freebase and i'll talk about freebase shortly
powerset gets bioinformation photos steve jobs
and then from a video search engine labelings powerset is able to formulate queries out
and then pull back the information from the video search
and this is unlike normal keyword search which we which only pulls back information for
the keywords you entered when you actually have a natural language system you can pull
back information for the answers or other significant concepts that are derived from the query
the ventured as related to from the text and other sources
OK and in addition you can do real-time queries to databases so in this example
who won an academy award in two thousand one you know one of the answers
halle berry
and this is this is converted into a database query thrown at database in this
case that freebase and then because the system comes back with this kind of result
and also creates a presentation page strong other information structured database
i think i'll actually jump into jump into some of the demos
right now
can you i hope you can all see that this that this resolution
OK in the back there
so so
i will also try and talk to it so here's the query politicians were killed
by disease
you know one of the results that comes up here is dengel paying died on
february nineteen nineteen ninety seven
at age ninety two
from lung infection and parkinson's disease and disease but his influence continued
another result lower down
it is and what he
sir edward heath died from pneumonia at nineteen thirty on the evening of seventeen july
two thousand five
at the age of eighty nine
so those are two results and out this edward heath won this is one examples
i was using before
there's no word in common with the query
and the and the texas returned
so now let's go look a little deeper at how this is actually happening
OK here's a view the parsing process
for that sentence then jumping died on february nineteen nineteen ninety seven aged ninety two
from lung infections and parkinson's disease but his influence continued
so here we see
and these this particular terms class subclass and so on have some extra meaning additional
semantics which ensures that they behave in the way that we expect them to behave
so for example RDF schema we have things like
class property types of cells and so on and so i can then begin to
use some of this vocabulary to represent the triples that were examples but had in
this graph earlier on so i can talk about persons being kind of class i
talk about hascolleague being a property professor being a subclass of person and so on
so i can begin to build up some terms that describe my domain and the
relationship between those terms
just skip over this
OK so so what is this what is this then begin to give us and
this is at this point we can begin to get into this notion of inference
and this is where the
the power this begins to detect
OK so here i have an RDF graph and i know that i have this
class of lecturers have a class of academics and i have a class of persons
and i know that all these things are classes
and know there some subclass relationship between lecture academic person
OK so that's the thing i can now do because of the fact that i
know that the because of the underlying semantics interpretation i'm giving the subclass property
it's like you know for
the lecturer must be a subclass of person
OK now this is
on the face of it this is a rather simple inference to draw
OK this is a one level one if it one could say on this is
this is obvious OK but the reason is obvious because we have some
interpretation of these terms and this is the way that we know that subclass behaves
what i have to ensure that have to ensure that within the the sort the
semantics my language this is how subclasses interpreted so i do actually have this transitivity
transitive relationship and i know that if lecture subclass of academic and academic suppressive person
that i have this inference being drawn
OK so it's important i have this enshrined in the in the semantic my language
so the language behave in a particular way
similarly i know that there some interaction between the type relationship the subclass relationship so
sean lecturer and lecturer is a subclass of academics i can make an inference that
must be
an instance of academic and again this is something that the but we can can
clearly see if we look at this it's obvious to ask OK but we have
to make sure that the the the
semantics of the language semantics of the representation of such that these kind of side
effects happen we can draw inferences
so what RDF schema than this is
pretty much what we have solve the case we have this kind of
to model we have the ability to use your eyes can share we can integrate
but we know that we get
some kind of consistent vocabulary used because i know the game being able to define
a kind of simple terminology some simple vocabulary is described by domain
i consistently uses market share
and i began to get some simple inference which allows me to then cannot draw
some inferences about the integrated data
however the schema is still still suffers from some problems
OK so
the language that we have an idea scheme is very weak
OK it doesn't allow me to describe resources in sufficient detail i really wanted to
characterize my domain in some way
OK RDF schema doesn't allow me to do this so there are no what we
might call localised range and domain constraints case if i want to say that
i have published by relationship
OK so i talk about papers being published by a publisher
i can't say
if it a journal that that OK when when i
the journal is published by a publisher
OK and the technical report was published by institution
these are facts these are kind of relationship i would perhaps want to represent my
domain constraints on the way in which published by can can be used i can
represent this in RDF schema there's no language that there's nothing in the representation of
allow me to express
there's a relationship
so in this this talk about discrete random variables just for simplicity is alright some
the integrals but you can do this with was well see find the f divergence
between two measures mu and pi
as f of the likelihood ratio
and the integrate or you average with respect to the pie
OK so that's how i killed divergence in fact if f is chosen to be
u log u
you get a little versions
right but if f is chosen to be absolute value minus one for example
then you get out the variational distance which is here just the l one
distance on measures
after the any continuous convex function so these are particular examples here's another one if
you like that one and you get out the hellinger distance and this goes on
for several pages so you plug in a continuous convex
when you look at you now define a new ali silly or after versions
right so why these guys use the f divergences well were somehow intuitively appealing but
there is a little bit of kind of underlying theory behind that choice
it's not entirely satisfactory that's it's not necessary at all but it is a good
starting place and the theorem was due to david blackwell nineteen fifty one a classical
paper well well worth reading had a big impact impact on economics
so if there is to the following procedure a some kind of an estimator has
a smaller f divergence the procedure b
for some particular choice of f versions
OK then there exist some set of prior probabilities the class probabilities here in one
class the other so some set of prior problem classes such that procedure a has
a smaller probability air the procedure being well that's what you care about that's the
risk so we now this procedure is a small risk the procedure be that's good
we should not use proper procedure a
and we were told that by looking after versions is after this gives an average
i would just an existence statement that says there exist some sort of properties we
don't know what the problems are always that after versions give this ranking
we don't know in our particular problem which after three years
OK so it is not that helpful in several helpful practice but it does at
least suggest that after are not unreasonable objects to be looking at if you're trying
to minimize the probability there
and that's a good thing because when i probably areas course nonconvex problem the risk
of zero one loss is not convex
so you try to find some other kind of function you can optimize and these
things are convex
and therefore you might try them by just there
so that's what people did as famous paper skylark nineteen sixty seven and so on
jews in particular divergences and just kind of in some sense hoping that the priors
our right for that after the particular problem
another some supporting arguments for asymptotic show this divergence also arise in other ways back
the original kullback leibler divergence arose by analysis of hypothesis testing it still carries the
power function in hypothesis testing we're two class sustain a fixed distance apart as the
number of data points gets large similar chernoff distance arise same analysis in a bayesian
setting we have prior classes these divergence were you know kind of in some ways
talking about probability air directly in this case but it's an asymptotic arguments hypothesis testing
so anyway it's still heuristic literature
announced on the the other side of the coin had to the discriminant function
and so you can now know this stuff this is the machine learning can one
one you choose a loss function that measures the distance between your class label here
you you are we could start with zero one loss is the loss we're trying
to optimize
and in the binary case you can write that is the indicator function of when
the labels disagree
OK the labels disagree using why is is one minus one the discriminant function outputs
also one minus one are real or real number general so they disagree in their
sign that's bad and that's you pay loss of one in that case the logic
OK so the main focuses on the discriminant function and now we know also from
this point of view it is intractable unless you one last this argument as well
so instead what people have done if it picked the surrogate loss function which are
convex upper bounds and zero one loss so we've all seen this picture
here's the
zero one loss expressed in terms of this margin value i the product of the
y and gamma c
and if you disagree on this side you pay loss of one of the ways
you pay loss is zero
and so is intractable optimise this instead people look at these are upper bounds and
the blue line is the more it is the support vector machine the hinge loss
the the red one here's logistic the green one i think is the boosting of
the exponential loss which is what are what you should boosting
and there's a whole bunch of others there that this page is littered with examples
OK so all the references are different from you know optimisation point of view this
write down these most of these particular choice of curves
for each of the features
and on the other extreme got the
fifteen with minutes
which converges faster
simply because it's got
the fewer number of features
filter log histories
OK so what we do here
we use nine the data training held back some set testing in each time we
one hundred trees
the forests averaged over one hundred trials these are the
test error rates using standard random forest
confidence interval parallel technique also using a two stage
cart rebuild a single country to begin with
we don't currently billed as large as possible and because each stage is optimizing over
features you get an optimal information gain value for each feature and explanatory so build
a single tree
to the average information gain for that
and then use that to fix
the feature set happiest nation and then build forced from their
it is because it does form
actually very well in this case there is no guarantee
on the reliability of this method
and a composite math because is actually
particularly for the two artificial data
significantly improving performance
and quite importantly never significantly worse so this problem of initially overweighting features
has been avoided in this case
OK so there irrelevant features
we said that the average information gain is the name of the non negative samples
so we get
expected information gain irrelevant feature is going to have some non-zero value
now if you apply this to the sampling distribution
you have a high proportion of irrelevant features
although you may be giving them small
the probability of being sampled when you actually
it combines
the total probability of choosing an irrelevant feature
is actually
still significant and will still degrade performance forms
so what want to try and do is calculated this expected information gain values
these irrelevant features
so we got a parent node to the parent node and
when you put this we could lefts and rights and
so there are no
examples in left descendant iol positive examples and then we know that there are n
examples and the parent node i
positive examples in the pattern
so from that we can work out
the corresponding numbers right center
what we do is for each possible arrangements
when you project the data down to the one dimensional space for each possible arrangement
you can try these difference the values
and so give values for an hour and i l and you want to choose
split which basically minimizes expression
it gives you the values of an outlier which minimizes this expression is the parent
we tried this before
some values
but note composition so here we have three to know because was the number of
negative examples in the number of positive examples
and so if you take diagonal segment
along here we've got to fix size
basically just changing the class proportions with the money
we found the of something in this matters
hugely expensive because you have to build each of the narrator arrangements optimise information gain
the average
overall the
we did find it for fixed value and
the the
highest value expected information gain actually occurs when the class proportions are equal
so down
center line here
actually increasing the size of the node is actually half of each class
and the minimum is occurring
when we have
one example of one class
and all the other examples from the past
OK so if we to just take the value and
so we the notion of size n
because there is a lower bound is given when we have
only one
example of one class
and we can actually
calculate this lower bound on expected information gain irrelevant feature
and we found that we could approximate
the upper bound of the past portion recall
basically by plotting the
the function of a logarithmic scale family approximately straight line
and so these then gives the bounds
on the expected information about for developing features
so it is we just below
one hundred reasoning artificial datasets
the two relevant features features one and two
and the remaining seven are irrelevant
these stars represent the
average information gain is achieved by to the features
and then these bounds are bound on the expected performance of relevant feature
as you can see that there features are within the bounds are expected to be
two relevant pages actually
above these ground
OK so what we did then is just to see
how are these were b shows feature selection threshold
which is basically
the halfway point between these two bounds
we try the three mandates that which is normally regression we threshold at two
a binary classification problem
which was
pretty much equal balance
you start feature selection scheme using our feature selection threshold build one hundred trees
i got the bounds expected
information gain
is the threshold is the halfway point between towns
and then selected features which had
on average information gain about this
and we found that
over one hundred trials
argmaxy puts out the five relevant features all the time
and some of the irrelevant features
sometime now CFS
is an organ competitors correlation based feature selection
which is symmetric uncertainty to examine the correlation between
feature and the class as well as the feature feature correlations actually analyse redundancy in
the data as well
and this our room
doesn't use any of the the
there is
but actually drops
some of the relevant features as well
and it turns out you need about a hundred galaxies to even get its texans
and one thing this
so then yes
the great
yes really really yes OK good question
OK so i showed you very very beautiful picture which was very extreme cases where
you can see that there was
the actual distortion was different different parts of the galaxy
that's a very extreme case i said because i just love that picture and i
think it's very beautiful but it's actually very atypical so only in you know point
o one percent of the sky will you see anything like that not less
so it's not
that's right with you
yes yes that's exactly right so we that's right so we can't help or anything
galaxy whether it's been sheared
what we we we had we the signal that we have measured is where you
more than one galaxy at the time
and for example you're looking for
pairs of galaxies which appear to be pointing on average in the same direction because
galaxies which are near to each other will pass through similar dark matter distribution to
the destruction of similar amount and if we take pairs of galaxies and cross correlate
is the the measured shapes then we find galaxies tend on average to be aligned
with each other
so that's exactly the signal that we're looking for me and so in fact to
to do this you need hundreds of thousands of galaxies to even detect signal at
and we need typically a billion galaxies to do the dark energy measurements we want
to do in the future
good question the questions stage
great so the rest of it is is i'm sure you'll find really trivial so
so we have to you we we have an atmosphere
we often observing through and have the telescope and both of these induce the competition
with with the kernel
so beautiful galaxy with spiral arms becomes this blurry blob
and typically in fact the size of the galaxy is typically about the same size
has become the completion kernel
so it makes it quite difficult because the kernel tends to be elliptical
slightly and that doesn't actually much bigger effect than she were trying to measure we
to remove this kind of very very accurately indeed
pick asian we have detectors which pick up the light and these detectors roughly have
square not overlapping elements so we end up binning the lights into the square pixels
and typically the size of the pixels depends on your definition of size but typically
the pixels are the bigger than shown in this picture here
about twice the size
and then the sleeve got noise
and we've got what's on noise because we're detecting a certain number of photons and
you can also have some noise and bad pixels induce the detectors
and typically we're looking at galaxies which are the knowledge this we've typically going around
the total amount of light about five percent
and we tried to measure the intensity of these galaxies
so this is just sums up the whole that picture
so the key the top line here we've got a galaxy being sheared
that's what you want to measure
we've got this combination with the kernel
we've got the pics isolation noise and typically with real images what we do is
we got stars which are effectively points and so we can use those stars to
measure the
and that's how we managed to do you can vote kernel
OK so the typical image customer the clinic and here's a typical star
that's used to decode evolved to find accommodation kernel and here's a typical galaxy which
you can't really
which is used to measure the shears
and in all this mess up here for example this is very very bright star
these that it's saturated it's it's no longer linear we we haven't measured it properly
it's lots of mess as well
so the great oh eight challenge we have identified a small part of this whole
problem now we are stuck on and which we need your help with
and so we're just looking at
measuring we we're going to give you the kernel accommodation kernel
and we want you to take a few million galaxy images and extract the shear
and typically in cosmology we would then apply some statistic for example correlations of shapes
and compare those with what you get from simulations and measure the doctrine dark energy
but we just going to focus on this box here
within great oh eight
so the data that we we will provide you with is this three different datasets
i certainly
we've got some warm-up data some fairly high signal to noise
no noise data and which one is that we give you the shears
and is that is blind
there's about ten thousand images that and then there's about a hundred thousand images in
the main challenge
scared you don't like large data sets that was a bit frightening in the previous
talk brain that team this to the high enough precision it's necessary to have this
many galaxies
they're all the same format that there's just one galaxy in each in each image
but unfortunately it's necessary to have a huge amount of data they would like to
hear your thoughts on that there's a number of simplifications we've made each image contains
just one galaxy
and the kernel is given
this one shear per typically
and huge background
i did so it's almost guaranteed in fact
so what we would like from
this is what at
and we will then compare that with the truth
we do want a that make a large number of good
and so then we propose to have an active leaderboard showing the results ordered by
this quality factor q
and where we are at the moment in our community is a q of about
about a hundred and this this obviously is not done this exact challenge yet so
we'll see on this exact challenge and then this is what we're aiming for the
future surveys is the a q of about a thousand
so what we were going to do actually is over the next few months we're
running our own methods on the exact simulations which you're we're going to to make
public this challenge and we'll put our own methods on this leaderboard so you can
see where we are
and we also make our code public so if you want to just tweak our
code a little bit then that's that's far but what we actually really hoping you'll
just have a fresh look at this whole thing and come up with some brilliant
new method
and after the discussion earlier i think it would be great to have some kind
and you might expect
it that they would come to speak a pidgin
but they don't what happens is in the course of a single generation they developed
their own language
they create a language with rich syntax and morphology more in phenomenology
terms that will understand a few minutes
and this language they create is called the trail
and languages that we know now as creole the word refers back to the history
that means that they were developed from pigeons
and this is interesting because it suggested to some extent the ability to use and
understand and learn language is part of human nature it doesn't require an extensive cultural
history rather just about any normal child
even when not exposed to full-fledged language can create language
and more recently has been case studies of children who acquire sign language
there's a wonderful case nicaraguan sign language where they acquire sign language from adults who
themselves are not reversed in sign language disorders second language learners struggling along
what you might have expected to be the children with use whatever system adults use
but they don't take realise
they take this makeshift communication system developed by health and again they turn it into
a full-blown language
suggesting that to some extent is part of our human nature to create languages
i also
every normal human
has language not everybody in this room can ride a bicycle
not everybody in this room can play chess
but everybody
possesses at least one language and everybody started to possess at least one language when
they were child
there are exceptions
but exceptions come about due to some sort of brain damage
any neurologically normal human will come to possess a language
what else do we know well
the claim that language is part of human nature
supported by neurological studies some which were referred to in chapter in the brain you
read earlier that talk about dedicated parts of the brain
that work for language
and parts of these brains parts of these parts of the brain damage you get
language deficits or or features
where you might lose the ability to understand or create language
there's been some fairly recent works
studying the genetic basis of language looking at the genes that are directly responsible
the capacity to learn a new language
and one bit of evidence that these genes are implicated is that some unfortunate people
have point mutations in these genes
and such people are unable to learn a new language
in general there some support at least a very broad level for the claim that
language is in some sense part of human nature
what do we mean by language what are we talking about when we talk about
language we don't want to restrict ourselves for instance to english or french
what what all languages share
all languages are creative
and this means a couple of things
one meaning is the meaning emphasise by renee descartes
when renee descartes argued that we are more than merely machines
his best piece of evidence for him was human capacity for language no machine could
do this
because our capacity for language is unbounded and free
we could say anything we choose to say
we have free will
and in fact language allows us
to produce a virtually infinity of sentences
so we could create understand things is we never heard before
and there are a lot of sentences
if you want to estimate how many grammatical sentences under twenty words in english the
o lord
and what this means is that any theory of language use and language comprehension can
not simply appeal to all list
when you understand the sentence i said
you have to have the capacity to understand the sentence even if you've never heard
it before
and this is because we can effortlessly produced and understand sentences but no human
has ever said
before on earth
would anybody volunteered as a sentence
none of seems non derogatory has never been spoken before
there are all star
it's surprisingly easy to get a purple tie on ebay if you don't care much
about quality
i can imagine no one else in the world as it was before
i am upset that one not easily download buffy the vampire slayer through items
it's possible somebody said both those sentences before
but you probably have not heard of but you understand the medium
so how do you do it well
you have rules
you have rules in your head you've learned
what the words mean
but you have abstract unconscious rules that take these words
figure out the order and in a fraction of a second
give rise to understanding
that's the sort of thing linguist
take some standard examples from the linguistic study
and bear in mind the rules we're talking about here are not rules you explicitly
there are automatic rules of the same sort of talk about in the context of
visual perception in that the implicit and unconscious
and not accessible
two two
explicit understanding so for instance i immediately read the pig is eager to eat
versus the pig is easy to see
and in a fraction of a second you know
there's an important difference the pig is really means the state of affairs that we're
talking about is one to pick those thing
the ECB
is when the pig is being eaten
you see a sentence like
bill knew that john like ten
and you know without even knowing how you know
but this can mean that bill knew that john white
or it could mean that belong to the john light
but it can mean that bill knew that john light john
natural interpretation factors that belong to the john like built
the two words corefer
contrast that will build new that john like himself
which only has the meaning belonging the john light john
and this is what linguists do for a living
so if you hear me talking with is that i want to spend the next
four years of my life stating that
you should become like this
but that this sort of those are sort of phenomenon that we're interested in
it gets more complicated those are examples from syntax
we're going to focus a lot today on the whole issue of biochemical reactions and
the issue of energy
and this gets us into the realization
that there really are two kinds of biochemical reactions some of you may have a
lot to learn this along time ago either
x organic reactions
that release energy to produce energies are produced
as they proceed
or conversely and organic reactions which
require an investment of energy in order to move forward
so here obviously if this is this is a high energy state
and we're talking about
the free energy of the system which is one way to depict in thermodynamic language
how much energy is in the molecule
if we go from a higher energy state to a lower energy state
then what we can draw this like this and we can realize
then in order to conserve energy the energy that was inherited this molecule the high
potential energy is released as this ball of this molecule rolls down the hill
and therefore the reaction yields energy it's actually gonna can conversely if we want this
energy to proceed
we need to invest excuse me want this reaction to proceed
we need to invest free energy in order to make it happen the free energy
happens to be more often than not in the form of chemical bonds i e
energy that can be invested for example by taking advantage of the potential energy stored
in these phospho diaster in this phosphate phosphate linkages indicated right here
here by the way the space filling model of ATP just for
for your information that's the way it would actually look in life and this is
the way we we actually brought
now having said that
if we look at the the free energy profile of
the biochemical changes then we can depict them once again this very schematic way here
and by the way
free energy is called
this is called g the gibbs free energy after joe site gibbs who was thermodynamic
which is in the nineteenth century at yale in new haven
and here what we see is that the change in free energy
between the reactants and the products is given by delta g
so by definition we start out the reaction with reactance and we end up at
the end of the reaction
with products and overall there if the reaction is actually gonna get will proceed forward
it releases energy in the release the net release of energy is indicated here by
delta g
but more often than not
biochemical reactions that are energetically favored
there ex are gonna make
actually can happen spontaneously they don't happen spontaneously because for various reasons they have to
pass through an intermediate state
which actually represents a much higher
free energy than the initial reactance process
and this higher free energy that they need to acquire in order to move over
the hill and down into the valley is called the energy of activation the activation
and therefore if i were to supply these reactance
the energy principle it's whatsoever to heat up these reactants and therefore give them high
degree of thermal energy which they might be able to use
to move up to this high energy state
i gave i supplied them with free energy by giving them heat
then they might be able to move up here and then rolled down the hill
but in the absence of actually actively intervening in supplying with them and then they
remain right here and they may remain like right there for a million years
even though in principle
if they were to reach down here there would be much happier in terms of
reaching a much lower energy state
to state the obvious all these kinds of reactions which to state which to reached
the lowest energy state possible
but in real time it can't happen if there is a high energy of activation
now what do enzymes do
as always i'm glad i asked the question what they do is they lower the
energy of activation
and this is
in one sense obvious and in one sense it subtle
because enzymes have no effect on the free energy state of the reactants they have
no effect on the free energy of the products
all they do is to lower the hump
and they may lower very substantially
and because the lower it substantially
it might be that these some of the reactance here made just through chance
acquisition of thermal energy
be able to
move over the much lower home and moved down into the state right here
that the actual
difference in in the gibbs free energy is totally unaffected
all that happens is that the enzymes
by lowering the energy of activation make this possible in real time
the fact is that ultimately if we were to
two plot many kinds of reactions many reactions as is indicated here
i have a very high activation energy
and therefore we look like this
but there could be other reactions which might have an activation energy looks like this
almost nothing at all
and these reactions could happen spontaneously in the room temperature in the absence of any
intervention by
an enzyme for example let's say we're talking about a carboxyl group which discharges the
we've talked about that already
well that reaction happens spontaneously at room temperature doesn't need an enzyme to make it
happen it can happen because there is essentially no energy of activation
but the great majority of biochemical reactions to have such a an activation energy and
therefore do require a lowering
like this in order to take place
now let's imagine other
other versions of the
of the energy profile of reaction
and keep in mind what i'm showing here on the abscissa is just the course
of the reaction
you can imagine that i'm not really plotting time i'm just talking about the situation
where to the left the reaction hasn't happened and to the right it has happened
but but but
and proceeded cells are
it's really hard to say
so is all
who were team room
all of
now let us hope
it's not homework one embarrassing to come to
people who do devote move back for a lot of time like say to you
the whole world which is the
we're not going
and that's why stuff like that we have in the nineteenth century when farmers shopkeepers
that is that is
house councils so we're going to work
one of the specialist players have and i think it is it's
so we know how to use this
this the last slide
in person together with spend more time with a
one with
now that the technology is in the
all the these changes in the middle of
for different media all but this is medium this is going to have to get
around reading
stuff like that that's all the more or
come back to the magazine
i work
for services process and we found
on the first numbers are interested in those of analysis
all but one ratio of field work in biotechnology this is what this
this five four
one percent seven percent of all he was saying you don't think about
technology which basically similar to that of course is
part of their lives
we treat web science is big
the way something like twenty to so that there
speak for yourself
i think
so what we're going to
once again this is just an assertion of american data once it
you can see that were part
of the every household has
fair amount
can will see that was going to say but i don't you one of our
so is this
more individual mobility parker
many interesting here
this was agreed with the way
well i think find injects get out research
dave in nineteen sixty five to my first
i'm interested trying to do
he speeches switch switch and stuff like that place like the bus
and the slide what may show
this page is more pieces in the developed world there has been a major
know that similar
many of words but this is cheating we know are three trials
three right track
between north america and europe is
so willing to push these restrictions on the sovereignty
but still
it's pretty easy for all of us to
this is not
performances and my grandmother was the challenge is to show that the
just make sure
it was on her now we can get on sky to easily of talk to
each other
how many people all the
in the past few days
and then i will leave it alone
i'll get into the state
you will see
is really normal modes
they have is one and only one frequency
the country will hold at the same moment in time there in phase
you will clearly see
this distance
more than doubled this one then have go this one
i will try that
double pendulum oh my goodness
this is the double pendulum
so i have to
private little but it really only very little
and then i will stop driving it
this is the model
is at the bottom one is further away than
but what
this is the normal mode
you see that is not a straight line
it's hard to say that this one was the square root of two of course
from seeds
but this
that's what it is
no excite
second normal mode which is the residence
that's it
i can almost stopped swinging it
notice that the other one is much larger and due to the lower
the ratio
one with the square to you know to the out of phase
it's the minus sign
out of phase
and the animal they were in fact
so all of that will follow
the recipe
if i give this problem on an exam you would have
OK let me because the pages long
i would certainly where border professor
on campus
that these because you have symmetry
this doesn't have symmetry
c o c one c two two
i haven't justified what i call woman two problems i call this one
i call this time
so c two oversee one plus two point four
it's good that you asked that and here i change the sequence because i noted
this one was larger than this one so you seen one obviously two
it's minus two points for the minus sign means out of phase
good that you asked very good
and slowly slowly going to turn you into exports
and now we're going to try something else to see
good you're
intuition is
i want you to understand
you intuition is no better no worse than my own
in other words there is no way
i could have done any better than you did when i was
in high school or whatever it was maybe college when i first saw this i
also my first impression was
what the hell is straight line
give a little thought fuel
consider conclusion
cannot be
then ultimately comes out of this so don't feel bad if you intuition that you
i'm as that you are with
so now we're going to
evaluate the system
which will take you
not going have to work out the general recipe
and that is for strings and three
one car
three cars
and also things that spring constant k
nicely symmetric you think
and all have all objects of mass and
i want to know
i want to see whether we have any intuition
without being too complicated
forty three
normal mode solutions there must be an omega minus
all three are in phase
then there must be an omega plus
which is more complicated
and then there must be an omega
plus plus which is the highest of all three
in the highest possible frequency
object two adjacent objects always out of phase so if you have twenty objects in
the highest mold
number one is out of phase was number two and number two is out of
phase with number three number three is out of phase with four and so on
let's first look at omega minus
i won't even asking you whether you have any idea what omega minus is you
don't have that i don't have
well object to be
so for instance i displays than the first one
over the distance which ideas normalized to plus what i call that plus one
and the idea here where this one will be any idea where that one
what you think the second one will be
plus one
what will be the third one b
why does it have to be wrong
suppose this one
is a plus one
and suppose this one is also a plus one
this approach
it is no longer than it wants to be and this is no longer than
it wants to be so there's no force on this object
so that's not possible
object cannot go anywhere
any suggestions
which of those
is wrong
is this correct
it's plus one
about the middle one
he wanted to for a little less
all have to be in phase don't use one minus signs
if you use the word minus sign then how can you do that you have
to be in face
must be on this site
we make the distance larger or smaller
and i tell you what it is
tell you what it is
you want to know
how you really want to know
i do
that obvious
now the next one
the next one is interesting
i will again
put this one plus one
because that is my
my starting point i always put plus one
now what
this one you can guess
really can
i think now about the symmetry of the system
very middle one they still
and this one comes to mind one
now to figure out what
remember the highest mode
they were always out of phase with the enormity home many you have
so it's already certain that this one must be on this site
and there's already certain that this will mostly on that site
the following content is provided under creative commons license your support will help MIT opencourseware
continue to offer high quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
his MIT opencourseware OCW MIT that EDU
so let's start right away with
step we will need to to see before we can go into more advanced things
so hopefully yesterday in recitation you had a bit about vectors
how many of you actually knew about that before that
OK that's
the vast majority
if you're not one of those people well hopefully you will
none about the task right now i'm sorry but the learning company it's cheaper for
the first week but hopefully
you will be just fine if you have you know
probable factors
do go to your instructor position is because of his cells for
next practice if you feel the need to
you see it
pretty easy
just to remind you
is the quantity that has both
the direction
and the magnitude
so completely the way you talk
it is
by some wholly that's OK
and so it has a length and it's pointing in some direction
so now the way that we compute things with is typically is we introduce the
coordinate system
so when the plane x y axis if we're in space
x y z axes
usually i will try to follow
my x y x is consistently to look like this
and then i can represented by a vector in terms of its components
along the coordinate axes so that means
when i have this whole i can ask how much does it go in the
x direction how much is it going to y direction how much does it go
in the z direction
well it's called is that a so small convention
when we have a vector quantity we put on our own remind us effect
if it's in the textbook sometimes it's in bold because it's easier to typeset
if you've tied into your favourite word processor does bold is easy and the cells
on the easy
the vector
you can try to decompose in terms
unit vectors
directed along the coordinate axes so the convention is there's a vector that we call
i had
that points
along the x axis and has length one
this effect called change that does the same the y axis and k had
but does the same along the z axis
we can express any vector in terms of its components soviet annotations
a one a two a three
these square brackets
it's angular like
the length
the vector
we denote by
if you want to the same notation as the absolute value so that's going to
be an number
as we say now a scalar quantity is scalar quantities are useful
numerical quantity as opposed to effect
and its direction
sometimes called
the of a and that can be obtained just by
scaling the vector down to unit length for example by dividing it by its length
well there's a lot of notation to be around
so for example if i have two points
then i can talk about from p to q
that is called the coffee
so maybe would a
but that doesn't really have necessarily starting point and the ending point
this we find
decide to stop here
and i go by the same distance in the same direction this is also the
topic it's the same that
so a lot of those will host anything at the origin but we don't have
so let's just cheque and c
how things went in recitation
so let's say that i give you the vector
three two one
and so
what do you think about the length of this vector
i see
and so forming
so a lot of you are
and in the same thing evidence for photos
OK i think the overwhelming vote is in favor of and so on the two
i see some six is i don't know if it's a perfectly good and so
too but hopefully
in a few minutes if you want to be
i don't know any more
so let's see how do we find
the line
of the vector three two one
so this that a
it comes
towards us
along the x axis
by the units
it goes
to the right
and on the y axis
by two units
and then it goes
by one unit along the z axis
so it's pointing towards here
he help paul
how do we get life well maybe we can start with something easier the length
of the vector in the plane
so i self
that you know a is obtained from the to be
the plane x b
i had to change that
and then we just have to still go up by one unit
OK so let me try to take picture
in the vertical plane that contains a and b
if i do it
in the vertical plane
so that's the xerxes
that's not any particular boxes
for this task is the localisation conference
and you for instance we are looking for car
organizing where they are
and task will be identification
and differently from verification and detection
what task is
discriminate between different classes
of objects for instance
identification will be especially related
to identify
an object within a specific class
for instance here
we recognise this is a human face
we want to identify
this special this box within
the cost of faces
b identification with the task of categorisation we want to distinguish between different objects in
the scene scene
well this guy
well being one phase and so on
and how are we we want
i understand which kind of scene is
like endorsing
other seen all which kind of
showing pictures like traffic
of course
you system
is one aspiration
so built
artificial vision systems
although the computer vision
the recession do not
and later
in approach
the outcome
and what is the motivation behind
but the per cent if it were your city
are provided by many many many applications
of computer vision
in industry
this link
you can find a list of combining
collected by david lowe
which sells computer vision problem
and research efforts are going to develop
solutions to improve forest and
image search
or there are
very challenging projects like
like that to build
portable visual system
so people like people in find rather in the supermarket
assistive technology
to give
the ability
the dark forest in the eastern part of the process of
learning is that key component for sending intelligence system and because
c is intelligence
learning is an essential component
just to the study of
we just visual system
far from the point of view
neuroscience and computer vision
what is on their science
concentrate on mechanism that load the cortex
two task and that it's a great
computer vision times advising
fifty retrieval system or artificialintelligence pakistan vision vision
and vision systems
the that
represent one of the most trained in computer vision so
but the recognition
a key component for these and russia learning to become one of these so
is a key component in the study
of computer vision
and the mother computer vision the categorisation task
it is seen as
i supervised learning task
so given an emergency input
the desired output
is a need is labeled
they indicate the class of the image
and the machine vision system after training with a set of sample
very slightly
to these
we represent images as vectors
and you're presenting images as vectors
we should take into consideration
invariance specific informational emotional elimination
other changes that
are within the scene
and typically
dimension reduction are applied to reduce
the space the dimension of the space
and or to provide a powerful
the more powerful feature space like in the case of negative i think fertilization
after representing images
that i use it
together with statistical learning making mechanism to infer the costs of the scene or possibly
and these are very keen
ingredients in pattern recognition
but also used in computer vision
to solve some kind of problem within the of
pacification queries
but why computer vision is scene is so difficult because we have a similar problem
in classification
in many domains
first of all
a lot of data are collected
each second
we we need to
be very fast in understanding images because we want to
recognise to understand the images real time
this is the first challenge
and also
we were we to be
representation after the war and projection
the generation process
so it's theoretically possible to invent
and we need to find assumptions
to recover three d structure from two d
knowledge and context are key components for human visual system to understand images
so we we need to
try to embed in our system
and giants two
understand the context so
we should put priors on knowledge in in our system
to better understand the scene for instance if i ask you what is this
probably you
say this is the car
but why you
recognise this part of is transported
because you are looking probably
this part in the context
call this kind of you
to understand
what i'm about
is it
and another
aspect this must be taken into account
and the sending images is that a pixel value
is a result
from many combining
but this
an image that main child measurement of the real world
there are many
so it's ability
that lead
of the peaks you take from your fish that camera
and i'm going to tabulate
some of the major part of the human visual system can do with very well
and that should be taken into account
vision system
in which factor going shopping involved
the first thing
o thing that influence measurement of pixels
the routine way that we analyse
i think the potential functions so the costs of MTF
of s
it's just the summation
of the individual costs
OK by definition
and that is just the sum
michael's one two
the amortized cost
plus the
minus the change in potential
do this right now the princes in the wrong place
i right to
so this is so in the past what i did was i expressed
the amortized cost
as being equal to psi i plus the change that are destroying these two terms
over the other side saying what's the true cost
in terms of the amortized cost
i get
the i minus one last piece of ally lines one minus p of l i
by making the substitution
that's less thirty four two surfaces is a linear by now with some of the
ties crosses it's at most four c i
so the some of them is at most
that some
i equals one s
four c i star
and then this happens in all these things you get telescope
these terms every term is added in one subtracted out one except for
once to limit so i get
plus b
l zero minus p
of health
so the cardinality of s
and now this term is
and this term is
great inequalities zero
OK so therefore this whole thing is less than or equal to one what's that
that's just four times
at cost
so our for competitive
this is
this is amazing i
it's not that hard
but it's quite amazing
that just by doing this simple heuristic here nearly as good as any
i'm nations
algorithm could possibly be
they are nearly as good
in fact in practice this is great theorist server you have things like a hash
table the axon by changing
OK what often it's the case that when you access
the elements bring them up to the front of the last anon sorted this that
put an into just bring them up to the front
you can easily save thirty forty percent in in
the axis in the hash table
because it be much more likely to find the elements inside of course it depends
on the distribution
and so forth and you know for empirical matters but the point is that you're
not going to be too far off from
from the ordering that an optimal
algorithm would do
optimal offline algorithm really amazing
OK for offline
now it turns out that day in the reading that we
science we signed you
later in the margins of original paper
in that reading
they actually have a slightly different model where they count
the move
accessed element x
the front of the last
as for free
and this basically models
so basically is the ideas by actually have a linked list
then when i chased down once i find x i can actually move x up
to the front
we just
a constant number of pointers
this place it output up to the front
i don't actually have to transpose all the way back there
OK so that's kind of the model that they use more realistic models
OK presented this argument because of its simplicity
OK in the models little bit support but in their model they have accused it
when you access something you want to bring it up to the front or anything
if you happen to go across during that time you can bring up to the
is this a
does the data point i belongs to and here when you when you hear class
so you have to thank god OK
so basically
is basically a random variable that can take capital k values OK
and now we give these random variable we give it we give it a prior
and we call it by k
so pi k
the probability
so if the prior distribution over the alphabet of values that this random variable can
take OK so what he says is
a priori if i'm gonna if i'm going to generate the data points
which got i'm going to pick
and this one
you can see it's the distribution over over capital k values
it's sort of says
what the probability of picking the ghost in small k is OK
all right so once once we have that
if we if we write
the likelihood of the data
going to be
for each data point
i sort of first of all multiplied by the probability of choosing
girls in component OK there will be this i take the case one
and then what i do is i evaluate the probability of the data points under
that specific goals and OK
then i do it with the next one with the next one with the next
one and it just average overall
the other girls
so to simplify a little bit the notation although that might confuse you some more
capital p
i k
yet another symbol
is simply
the probability of the data points are evaluated under discussion OK
and each of the gaussians is going to have its own mean and its own
covariance matrix
all right
and now the learning problem here is we want to learn for each galaxy we
want to learn the mean and the covariance matrix
and we also want to learn the mixing proportions
so far if i manage going to try
try to show you
are there more reflect
cynicism go since moving around
the gaussians
and actually those are very very poor run i must say
but that's OK because we can always resort
exactly that's what you want to use k means
OK so this is just you know
the charm of life the most
anyway that's the idea you can see the initialisation is definitely
the problem
i'm going to give you one more chance
could have been better
so the reason why in here
there's this few yellow points and and it's mostly dominated by the green is because
the pike k
associated to the green guide is much much bigger than the pike k associated to
to the yellow one so although you only have a yellow component here it's it's
prior probability of picking it is very very small so effectively the model is using
three gaussians rather than for OK
so the points are colored according to the to the product of that k
and the their probability under the ghost OK OK
so that's sort of the the role of the pie case if you will
OK so how
can we actually
how can we actually learn
the parameters
any any questions
so remember the means we the covariance matrices and the mixing proportions all right
and we remember that by k is the prior probability of picking one given
and PIK
is the probability of the ice data point why i evaluated under that goes OK
so as usual we assume that the data are some sample independently which which doesn't
mean that that the components of the data points are are independent right
so what i what i get is a get a fairly
uncomfortable product of sums
uncomfortable because when i take the logarithm now i cannot push the algorithm all the
way through into the gauss and as a as i would like right
i hate to some
semidefinite cone it
i find set
so let's look at some examples in each case will for many problems like this
these are somewhat similar to the examples of linear programming that we saw yesterday so
we have problems not immediately
in this form but by introducing some new variables and extra constraints you can put
them in the standard form
so suppose a of x is a symmetric matrix and it's fine in some variables
constant matrix palestinians transonic
and the first problem we are interested in minimizing the maximum i value of the
symmetric matrix as a function of x
so yesterday seen as a convex function of x
but it wasn't clear how you actually minimize it
semidefinite program gives us and practically of actually solving this problem minimizing this nondifferentiable functions
so and this is the current is the
minimize an auxiliary variable t scale t
subject to this matrix inequality constraint
so this is at x the symmetric matrix is this article t times an identity
again this is matrix inequality means that the i minus e x is positive semidefinite
and these two are equivalent because if you fix x and this constraint
and he just
try to find the optimal t that minimizes the mean multi subject to these constraints
then this constraint really says that he is created all the ideas values of x
so the optimality is the maximum like value of a pixel
and so for fixed axis just to maximize value if you optimize of ex ante
jointly you're solving this problem
so this allows us to write a complicated nondifferentiable constraints as linear problem but we
have these matrix inequalities
based on
and we all know no experts have to be diagonal the optimum
so the
i values of this matrix t i minus e x
will be equal to t minus the values of x
so this means that this page is positive semidefinite if all the icons on the
negative so t minus the values of x are nonnegative
but it have to be done
if x is diagonal then this will be just linear inequality
and there will be a linear programme
so it's
quite marginal
so this is a similar problem we minimize
and on the function of the same variable x so is be transposed times inverse
of a times b
so that's a differentiable function it's nonlinear
and you can actually show it's convex
and district x to the set of
tables for this matrix is positive semidefinite
in fact it's positive semidefinite singular then actually have to explain what i mean by
the universe
but if we just ignore that and just assume that h is positive definite
you can write this
the optimisation problem again this is the p
by introducing new variables t and the matrix inequality constraint of this form
very ornament expert column the robie transpose and t in the
the lower right corner
and the reason is that if you fix a x
so first of all x must be positive semidefinite because it's a block of this
matrix so that's gives the constraint
fix x and you optimize over t
then the minimum value of t is
b transpose inverse to be
using should complement
and again you see these are equivalent this is nonlinear
defensible but quite complicated this is a linear constraints in x and t
because it's symmetric matrix on the left
and it depends linearly on x and t
right so it sounds quite convoluted
but it follows four are
process saying
situations where
the true model
is truly
a complex saying where
all you can do about it knowledge you can use from it is
only simulating
to the data
there are
again many ways of implementing
this principle
there are many choices to to calibrate the methods
for instance
once you pick up pseudo-model model you can use directly these are maximum likelihood estimator
r four r subsidy model that so much more likely is to mirror and from
there compare
you are bit ahead do observations we
beta had at
the sample
of pseudo-observations
or else
in the study way you can use
the score vector
in the same
now doesn't work well
if you look at
the creators of the mess grew
and of war
the of
rather vague about
that the cases wait wait words but there this interesting sentence that would
find again
in maybe see
namely that's of course be
must contain enough information
two recall ver the parameters theta and so in a sense within
must be
the equivalent of
and then
the get
to this interesting sentence at uh recovery later
maybe that's
the best case
if i interpret the words the best case
is when the parameter r
see is just identifying namely when
the model to the model
is parametrized
in the sparsest possible way
not to induce
extra dimensions that
would slow down
convergence and
leads to more inefficiency
so that's missing feature of indirect inference
of course there is a lot of arbitrary its justification is you can write literatur
is a justification of consistency
and the convergence of those estimators at
a given speed so
we cannot recover
four hour problems with a given
sample size
that there is an interesting follow-up to be indirect inference paper
and offered you see
england injuries be
and fore where
they tried to
have more practical evaluation and the methods by comparing choices of the models and of estimators in
vidio situations in the game is
the conclusions at
bit ahead
had to be dependency that's so
in statistical terms if you pick
and ancillary statistic is not going to help very much
which makes sense but the same time once you get information about sea ice that
is when you had varies when senior
there is
you must have
concentration as possible
the distribution of bit ahead of cedar which again makes sense because
the more concentrated it is
the easier it is to get info together
the relevant information about parameter it
there will be a talk
in one of maybe stations about the use of indirect inference in connection
these maybe see by their crystallinity
another project i put under the head of econometrics although it's growing debt
is empirical likelihood
and the original it's not a matter that is directly related to stimulation
nor is maybe see
but i will make the link in minutes
likelihood is another way to process
complex models
you don't want to make
the assumptions you need to
create a complete model
you introduce a parameter
that your primitive interest and
link with this parameter you define expectations
define the parameters so essentially
you introduce a parameter that's
you defined moments or behaviors of the data that are of interest to u and
you create a function of the data
and this parameter so that you get a five little quantity age of wine seat up
with expectation
at cedar is
as you
the french and if he is the mean otherwise it you just get a
you flyboys to tell you quartier here
and based on this definition the model which is not a model just
a collection of features
about you are your problem
you define the empirical likelihood
when you start from general that puts weights one hour end to each point in your sample and you start
twisting the weight so that's
the constraint
it is fulfilled
is satisfied and so
you must get some other people are age of why i see talk to be
equal zero which is a translation of this
of these constraints
and this is not a new this is due to a heart or in in in the late eighties
has not been very much
the bayesian approach
although this is coming in particular in this
meetings there will be an entire session
dedicated to
empirical likelihood and division approach
so i mean this is illustration in the case of the mean
you start picking the weights so that's easy
a weighted average of the wise you see
optimize the product of the ways to get the largest possible
empirical likelihood
and the more senior the father are is from
the true seat the one that corresponds today of the harder it is to fit
this constraint and therefore the smaller
they will talk about linear programming hand
according in the course on
monday will
move on to
convex and
more general nonlinear optimization
linear programming i guess we should start with what is it
so we want to maximize or minimize
eh linear function
so constraints
chris burgess maximizing a linear function with no constraints probably rather
infinity would generally be the answer and
order constant
so we have constraints and there's different ways one can
oppose the constraints
i called standard form
if the constraints imposed exactly like this that u
has some inequalities
linear inequalities as with this matrix eight
i'll try to be consistent and my notation later and it will have an rose and columns
so if x is less than or equal to be
and by less than or equal to
be as an analytic vector and by lesser equal to i mean that each component
of the to a vector on the left is smaller than or equal to
the component on the right
and also the vector x take to be nonnegative now you've may have encountered
linear optimization problems already in here work
hand they may not have been in this form but it's very easy to convert
from one form to another form and and i like this format this i call
it standard form
for reasons that i hope will become very clear
has these lectures proceed
so that's the problem many many applications
it's important course
uh broadly and machine learning applications
the first thing we gonna do
is have algorithm end the first step to
the simplex method is to introduce something which are called dictionary
and so
all i'm doing here is i'm using notation for the objective function
and i'm also
introducing slack variables that represent the
much this inequality is deviates from being equality
so w is just be minus x it's the difference between the right hand side
and the left hand side and so because this inequality w should be greater article
and i call this a dictionary
because the variables on the right x
define the variables on the left
and this is of course completely trivial right here but
we're going to modify this dictionary and the next slide and and the whole simplex
methods based on iteratively modifying how we represent the dictionary
associated with this dictionary and the subsequent ones that we're going to see
it is what we call a dictionary solution
and that's a particular r
potential solution to the problem
sort of itself
candidate for solution but what is called a solution
and with this that distinguish it from the final solution which we'll call the optimal solution
so that
dictionary solution
you simply get by
you get by simply setting the
x variables equal to zero
and rating of the w is completely trivial in this case
but it will become more interesting as as we iterate things
now when you so that a particular solution associated with this way of writing the equations
end if
o and as we do the course then w is just equal to be
end if these critical the zero then w critical zero and and this dictionary would
be feasible it satisfies the constraints of the problem might not be optimal that it
be is critical zero it's feasible
if these particular zero which makes it feasible fantasy is less than or equal to
zero then there's no further improvement that you can make and this dictionary solution would
be optimal for the problem
but not very many problems have the property that zero zero
is the optimal solution
and so we need to
iterate generally
see here okay so i
here's how the simplex methods goes
there's two things there's feasibility enough melody and first discuss
getting a feasible solution
sorry stuff
going from a feasible solution to an optimal solution
so the primal simplex methods
it refers to exactly the word feasible
and we are working our way toward optimally
so the bee in this picture would be great article zero but the sea is
not or less than or equal to zero and so i did that to address
the fact that the objective function can be improved
so i look at the objective function so well there's the index
jay for which the coefficient on the variable x j is positive
that i could improve things by looking variable increases
from the from zero which is worth
it is in my dictionary solution
so at the very will increase from zero
end and and will call that the entering variable
maybe i should say right now
be at the word entry refers to
these the variables are over here are called basic variables
end here
entering the basis
and these are called nonbasic variables because right now these are just the original variables and as slacks
but eventually the more
so we
so x enter it will become one of the variables is not zero
we want to preserve this property having a dictionary so if i take one other variables on the right
and put a number on the left and you take the labels on the left
and put a number on the right
my system of equations here so i rewrite my system of equations with one exchange swapped with one other w's
so how do we figure out which
it has to go
so we take this index jailer increase in a particular order
variable x j all the other ones are equal to zero
and as we increase it
the column of this matrix associated with
index we were very lax jay
starts to get subtracted of
from the vector be
and that be was critical zero cause are feasible
and eventually slow
one is done when the components and w will hit zero
he might happen right away but
eventually it certainly should happen end