so it's sort of a real life thing as close as you can get
OK so this is
with the long term memory
right we cycled and you came back to the same experts again you pulled out
from the
from the intermediate league intermediate waste back up to the
if you
she about
the start of the two
then all the segments look the same
you don't have a long term memory
there you can prove bounds the time the loss of the algorithm is as good
as the loss of the best partition
x you know it's like the composite
expert plus the number of bits to write down the number the
the partition
OK this details the constant factors are not perfect and this action on the complete
problem is the constant that this would be tied to use on a complete graph
let me show you again
sharing to the decaying past shared past protesters following behaviour this is just one segment
it pulls out a good way
and then
the second which comes up in the first which goes down to some kind of
intermediate layer
we're kind of sort of long-term memory a second stage from that one can be
pulled up again if it's needed again
if you share the start of a vector you don't have this behavior
now this is interesting
if x going on in these updates and i'm completely fascinated by the imagine from
moment the first expertise good for y but is a short spur with second expertise
and again first good short for second
so what and what happens is
the good expert has most of the weight
but the second
but the second expert is ratcheted up
it's like it gets a little bit
the weights
get wrote a little bit
and the k of course one of the the first experts good
they can't and pull so your rationale
the second best expert
so quite curious
here the case where
i did
one two three four five six one
and beta two
and then a lot of one and beta three a lot of one and the
better for a lot of one and a bit of
the good expert the first expert this
is always on the top of the second
the experts
are actually as well so there you can overlay the two phenomena
back to sharp is crucial
fixed uniform past mix and look the past average is the easiest
stable algorithms beta because one of the ian of
shifting great
half percent works way well it's very stable
he is the overall thing
this was the theory we can prove things but now caching
the theory doesn't apply
we can still use these algorithms as heuristics in terms of the world
so we process request on virtual caches
we apply lost in the sheer charities
and then process the request on the real based on the combined weightings of all
and we
we object if necessary so that sort of neural
virtual cash gives me a ranking of all the objects
world that it is
not improving any more and so
where there used to be some intrinsic reward there is no intrinsic you want no
more sometimes so
the reinforcement learner
have some some serious
task to do
and the first
methods that we use for that very very simple and and all of you probably
have some experience with those in nineteen ninety one twenty years ago
as of prediction machine be just use
neural networks as you as you
as you often use how many people in this audience use neural networks occasionally
hands up
so maybe twenty percent was actually more like
fifty five that there's another so it's about twenty five percent
twenty years ago the we have this this little
prediction machine which as you know is compressor every neural networks that predicts the future
it is also compressed because what you don't
predict well you have to store extra so it's not good in compression in whatever
you you predict you don't have to store extra so you're compressing the data and
what you cannot predict well that you need access
storage space
just store and then see
the act
it was just the standard q learning algorithm plus neural network functionapproximator and there was
an environment you know twenty years ago people always had these little maze environments and
that the agents could run around
and get sometimes it's only war but then some parts of this environment where more
easily predictable than others and so on
prediction machine like to improve more in certain areas and less in others which means
that there was more intrinsic reward in certain areas where the but there was more
compression programs and more learning progress and so the system like to go there and
then we had examples where with sometimes actually helps to speed up the because you
are you know more about the world and sometimes this helps to speed up exactly
what is wrong
twenty years ago we did that and
i'm mean one
kind of happy that today but only recently this house
picked up steam and lots of people are starting to get interested in this sand
and build their own little versions of of clear systems like this
now neural networks can be replaced the pass with support vector machines and all kinds
of things but they are now
and estimated and they are really good at what happened just a couple of months
ago is not be used plain standard plane or backup networks to break the minister
of one to the handwritten digit recognition
one rocket it is anybody in the audience who knows this on this dataset
which can be quite a few of which has a long history of broken back
record since nineteen ninety eight the county find and
and you look at these
these wreckers
and in the very beginnings of multi-layered perceptrons but then it was all support vector
machines certain special cases are computer convolutional networks or
so combinations of classifiers and support vector machines combined with something and more recently deep
networks for example by canton and bengio
and others who
pre training unsupervised fashion these deep networks with have which have many layers and then
texas system and and the train the supervised fashion to to mark one of the
and all of us
it's not really necessary
it turns out he other guys who really did works instantiated sound and within my
and down there is is look government and my my office neighbour who is mostly
working on swarm intelligence and artificial and and who has papers with thousands and thousands
so obviously the answer is to take t equal to the largest of those lower
that's the maximum
so for sixty the optimal value this expression
and if you allowed to optimize over x and t jointly
then you
choose the value of t and four x which is the optimal this problem
so there are some applications in machine learning probably all know about that are very
well known so basically if we want to separate so the basic one basic problem
is if you want to linearly separate two sets of points in rn
the dark
circles and the open circles
we define a hyperplane are separating hyperplane like this so we look for
the coefficient vector and constant b
that takes
therefore it is i find function takes positive values on the axes and negative values
and that's one strict set of
a set of strict linear inequalities
it was a and b
and the exercise and why is unknown so this is the set of linear inequalities
in a b
it's not strict space can easily it starts its districts inequality but you can easily
make it into non strict inequality
by noting that this is homogeneous or if a and b satisfy these conditions
any positive multiple of a and b
set aside
so you can also make this right hand side equal to one or negative one
and then just replace it with non-stick inequality
and then you have a set of linear inequalities in a and b any solution
if it solvable defined separating hyperplane
as an extension you can look at problems where the two sets are not separable
and then try to define an approximate separating hyperplane
that separates most of the sets of points x and y
so one of our formulation would be the following so a piecewise linear optimisation problem
in the same variables a and b
so the first term you look at the max of zero and then for each
point x i dislike one minus i suppose x i might be
so fx i lies on the correct side of the hyperplane
that's zero
and this max is zero and there is no contribution to the sum
if x is on the negative on the wrong side of the hyperplane if it's
misclassified by that hyperplane then the penalty equal to the slack
in the court
and we do the same the other set of points and uses the penalty on
the separating hyperplane that he
to can minimize to find an approximate separating hyperplane
obviously piecewise linear because it's max of
linear functions of a b
you can easily write to
using the same trick as before
so the one this because i used one in the right hand side here
and one doesn't really any positive number will be
good here
so if i scale one then the a and b would scale homogeneous
sorry but there's only there's all the term objective so if
i scale one then a and b if
it would be optimal then it can be scale
that's because you're defined
separation strict inequality
so if a and b satisfy this that i can always kill and b two
make greater than any positive number on the right
and if it separates with right hand side one negative one then obviously satisfies this
would be different if i define separation by non strict inequality here
and i just don't strict inequality and then
also excluded non this UAB has the solution then this step could be equivalent
so what the common problems that are result in LP's are infinity and one optimisation
so i think the one norm of x minus b
the one norm is defined as the sum of the absolute values
then i can be written as an LP again by introducing extra variables and y
vector y
and then linear inequalities
and again it's easy to see that coolant because if you fix x in this
problem in this LP
then you get an easy problem and why because
these are
componentwise inequalities
so each component why i was to bounce lower bounds
and why i an an upper bound on minus one
so combine these inequalities say that's why i created than the absolute value of the
i th component of x minus p
i components between one minus y
so that's an upper bound on the
absolute value
this objective function is separable so can minimize of each why i separately
because the constraints are also uncoupled
couple the difference and entries in my
so the answer for this problem fix x will be to choose y equal to
the absolute value of the i th component of a money to be
if x is a fixed
and then
so that's the known as the one norm
and if you're allowed to minimize of x and y then you choose this made
the same choice for y
for x u
the point with the minimum one
right hand side
so here we minimize of x that's in nonlinear but convex
optimisation problem
here i introduce new vector variable y and actually that should be
if a and this used
rule dimension of a
and i minimize jointly over x and y
so that makes this an and into NLP because the objective is linear in all
those labels
and the cost also linear just linear inequalities in x y
there's a synaptic activity here for the chebyshev norm infinity norm if i'm interested in
minimizing the maximum
after the value of x minus b
then this would be the equivalent of an equivalent b
so here the extra variable that introduces scalar
set of effective
and then the
the constraints are that's
so what do one here the boldface one is the vector of ones
so each constraint users that the components of x minus b must be less than
each component of x minus p
and created and minus one
for which
so that means that the absolute value of the components of x minus b
are bounded by y
again to see the equivalence we can fix x here and then we minimize over
the scale of the y
that's very easy optimisation problem
because you just have a bunch of lower bounds and y
and quite equal to the largest lower bound
the first this talk about coordinate ascent which is just another set-back box optimisation out
of this
and to describe coordinates and so on
i just consider the problem just one should consider the problem of we want to
maximize some function w which is a function of alpha one three alpha and
with no constraints
so for now forget about the constraint the alpha rise must be between zero and
see forget about the constraint that you know some of what i alpha i must
be zero
on the distance the coordinates
out of one on one repeat until convergence
what are you want to on and the inner loop of cord in the sense
hosts all the parameters
except for i think
and then it just maximizes the function with respect to just one of the parameters
expected just one alpha i
so let's write as alpha i guess data as
argmax over writers i had
of w alpha one alpha
and this is this is really the a fancy way of saying you know hold
it's alpha i and just optimise wrt lies by optimisation objective with respect to only
alpha i
this is just a fancy way writing it
on and this is called an ascent
one picture
this can be useful for coordinates and on
if you imagine you're trying to optimise a quadratic function
on the look like that
so is that these are the contours of a quadratic function and the minimum here
this work or the center look like this my
you can call itself into the columns of one mile for the other two axes
and so let's say i start down here
all that begin by minimizing disrespect alpha one so go there
and and then when you point minimize respect alpha two simon that
and then minimize respect one
respect alpha two
two and so on
he always taking these axis aligned steps to
it's the to try to get to the
it turns out that design modifications to the sum the terms of the variations of
this as well
the way to describe the algorithm will always
you know doing this an alternating or that we always optimise respect alpha one and
alpha two and alpha one and alpha two are
one about to say applies only in high dimensions but it turns out that we
have a lot of parameters alpha one alpha and you may not choose always visit
them in order you may choose to you have a heuristic to choose which alpha
update next depending on what you think well i make no progress and have only
two parameters and it makes sense to use alternate between them doesn't but if you
high dimensional
if you have high dimensional parameters that are sometimes you may use of update them
in a different order doing so they make faster progress towards what's the minimum to
and it turns out that common sense is on
compared to some hours he saw previously compared to newton's method called the the centre
usually take a lot more steps
but on the chief advantage of corners and when it works well is that sometimes
the optimisation objective w
sometimes it's very inexpensive to optimize w respect any one of the parameters
and so called centers take a lot to you many more iterations than newton's method
in order to converge
there it turns out that there are many optimisation problems for which is particularly easy
to fix
you know all but one of the parameters and optimize respect just that one parameter
and if that's true then the inner loop of cornerstones sense of optimizing to alpha
rai very quickly
and called semi be very low
and it turns out that this will be true when we modify this be to
solve SVM optimisation problems
questions about this
so this been applied is
two our support vector machine two optimisation problem
so it turns out that on
according to census in its basic form does not work for the following reason on
reasons with constraints on the alpha rise we call from
you know what i previously we have a constraint that summer i y alpha i
must zero
and so if you fix all the others except for one
you know then you can't change one alpha without violating the constraint because if if
i just had to change alpha one year while alpha one is actually exactly determines
the function of the other alphas because because this was an interview
and so there is a lot of
which is the centre of gravity john has a colleague at microsoft on december out
of them
on therefore is trying to change one hour for the time
we were trying to change
o two
so on what this is a simple algorithm
sensor sequential minimal optimization and terminal refers to the fact that was choosing the smallest
number of alpha rise to change over time which in this case changes to the
actually quantify this behavior as you can see here this is based on the latent
amount these are normal males
and this is the female treated with the prostate gland in this is the male
treated with inhibitor and this is normal females so we've completely sex reversed
their behaviour
so that's type one sex dimorphism that we have correlated very strongly brain behavioral change
with the brain phenotype change let's go quickly to a second type of this sex
dimorphism which is sexually dimorphic nucleus that i mentioned the SDE and which is some
five times larger in males versus females so it's dark collection of spots each one
of those black dots a single neuron if we treat the female near-daily with testosterone
and look at the st adulthood she has now email sized STM there's an to
this nucleus in the human brain to generate a lot of excitement when it was
reported in the nineteen eighties it's the sex differences not nearly as dramatic as it
is in in the rats but nonetheless is there
so one could ask the question how does this sex difference come about
there could be multiple ways right you could say well because males start with more
neurons in one on surviving males males make more neurons something about sort but in
fact the work of art on old and several other investigators found over the years
that males and females start with the same number of neurons but since the male
gets the as dial from is just as strong his neurons survive but in the
female they die
and they died during a specific sensitive period and as a result the males sdn
is much much larger than the females
now we know that this is a general principle for a way to make a
brain region larger and one sex versus the other and we know this is true
from multiple other nuclei
all of which are directly related to reproduction so this was considered the only way
to get more neurons in one sex versus the
but as i said there are other types of sex differences right many that are
not true dimorphism
the other just variances and averages along a continuum
so we turn our attention to the hippocampus this is the brain region not directly
involved in reproduction instead major brain region controls stress response and spatial learning it's very
very heavily studied for its role in learning and memory both of these two things
should differences between males and females
so we first asked is there sex difference in cell death in the hippocampus
after exhaustive studies we could find no difference in the number of neurons that die
during development of the male versus female hippocampus so then we asked the opposite is
there difference in cell genesis between male and female hippocampus
to study cell genesis you take a different approach in which you give a drug
called BRD you
deoxy uridine which will recognise as an analogue of DNA
and it becomes incorporated into sl when it divides because the DNA is replicated we
can then use antibodies to visualize the BRD you
and we can thereby right
date the birth of a new cells
so what we did was injected animals females with male hormones we can build compared
males and females in the presence of BRD you to ask are you making more
neurons collected the brain's some days later
what you can see is that the first just look at the female versus the
male is that there's a dramatic sex difference the males making many more neurons than
the female during this period of time this is in a couple of days after
birth and the image that you see over here this is the hippocampus all those
little black dots newly born cells
and this is the male or female making fewer of these newly born cells
so we can conclude testosterone stimulates cell genesis in the developing male brain but at
that point we can only conclude that they are cells not that they are neurons
i misspoke when i said that
we have to ask what kind of cells will they become because stem cells can
become multiple things they can become neural progenitor cells which will lead to
principal neurons
such as the program on the answer the campus or interneurons or they can become
that will become the den sites that make them myelin for the astrocytes that i
spoke about earlier to find out what kind of cells are going to become we
so we should
one the more
say in you to be able
always all
is all
one this is the first
call letters were this follows
o thing
o one of
one of the
the problem was
so the situation
o four
there's of
what want
it is
so this is
so the
this is
it is
OK so
i was in the middle of some vignettes yesterday but i got a couple questions
i've that it's from the board and now how do i do this
and we still have vegas tried like this i don't believe come on really think
that's going work
it does
so i did a little bit of decision theory yesterday
and the couple questions afterwards provoked we want to respond so
i have a couple of different kinds of expectations
of the loss function so there was an expectation
the unconditional expectation the frequentist looked like this
so no conditioning
and there's is being held fixed
and the expectations the threat the axis the provision of x given data if you
want but indexed by status by the way frequencies one saying
the unconditional expectation
and it's important to note that this state is the same as the state
that's really critical so just the function of of one theta not of two different
kinds of data
in the bayesian expectation was the conditional expectations
so you might want to put a little exercise because that's being held fixed rate
is now the random variable and this conditional expectation conditional x
but they get in their way is a random quantity
OK so those are two different things and so this object here
is frequent expectation the kind of the definition i was given yesterday what it means
to be frequentist the least and if you look at the paper he says are
frequent sounds are going on here was that there was an expectation of the sample
that's the kind of a giveaway
and in particular to two examples of the loss function squared loss is the one
that you know pattern that talk yesterday and today but in the papers it does
the causes of this loss function is just three
the los angeles now called delta have access to share statistical procedure let's call it
they'd have to simplicity
so my notations some
and so this might be just data how does this square with a particular example
of a loss function already familiar with the case that the loss
this is a random quantity for free point of view and that's around the query
from a bayesian point of view of
and now for the frequentist a risk we take expectation of this thing
or this user and query that to is fixed
OK so if you do that you would write risk of data the expectation that
they have stated square
just manchester mean square
right in the traditional thing to do at this point is two
added subtracted quantity
that quantities is now again in expectation of really care or all those expectations the
frequentist expectation over the sample space
OK so that's not just a number
and this is still random
right now you can
paul all part the square and you get two pieces which are square get across
product across vanishes because the cost always fashion statistics is called the pythagorean theorem
so you get this one here
that's called the variance
and then you get this quantity here this is the constant
with respect to that expectation as is this so we just simply get data minus
caterham school
that's called the square by
OK so that's the bias variance decomposition that's all you've heard about that i just
want to make clear that in doing that you're writing down these expectations with respect
to data that's the frequentist expeditions over the sample space
because when you are the words by very european frequentist
but it's not the only thing that three-quarters do they don't just write down by
the variance decompositions which just one of the most simple things you can do is
very useful
if you would square at least two separate things out of these two pieces and
after you can argue separately on these two pieces the bias for example might go
away asymptotically that's popular public desire and you also like the variance perhaps to go
to zero asymptotically if you can show those two things together
you've shown consistency either they'd had goes to theta in this case in mean square
and that's that's what we mean by consistency in this particular setting i would talk
much about consistency today in general consistency just means the number of data points larger
converge the right answer
OK that's what we mean by consistency and so one way in the simplest kind
of parametric setting to do that is that if you would square loss to look
at the by seymour et cetera okay so any more questions on that you will
use the data means that the frequentist expectation other sample points and when you've got
to bayesian thing to bayesian response to focus on
the fact that they got
was the only other thing that i want to say that i didn't say yesterday
so this was just now
cut through some of the slides by myself aware i was so we're talking about
f divergences in experimental design surrogate losses
and this was the first if i think for little vignettes in frequentist analysis so
the goal here is to show you here is a kind of data analysis problem
here's a fancy machine learning style algorithm of some kind of you not try to
much datasets and that's great works fine all that the whole goal here is to
say what it means to do some analysis of this list let's you frequentist analysis
was convince yourself it's actually good method in some sense that it works well on
dataset for the clever
OK so i'm going to show you have that kind of thing is carried out
in a bunch of little little vignettes because the first one had to do with
the experimental design problem where we sitting in developing the quantizer as well as a
discriminant function jointly so we can have that kind of setup where we had xis
which are in know available and environment principle you can measure them but you don't
use them centrally was distributed classification problem we first quantizing the easy access by an
experimental design or a quantizer q and the disease are small numbers of bits and
transmit them to a central site we can do the quantization for the discrimination which
is the function gamma
so this is kind of an example of lot providing an emerging field of distributed
show that that's equal to the variance of the original variable x
divided by the number of observations of x so that the well known result that
you've almost certainly see this is that the standard deviation of new had is equal
to the standard deviation
of the original variable x
divided by the square root
of the number of observations so that i just guessed the function i just guessed
that that would be inappropriate estimator
and that claim that if you worked out those properties that that's what you get
OK suppose i consider the the variance of x as my parameter i want to
an estimator for it so sigma squared had what would that be
again if you look back at what the definition of the variances it was something
like the expectation value of the quantity x minus mu
so if you think again about these expectation values is being averages
then you might be led to to write down some kind of a
i guess for the estimator like this formula here is sort of the average of
the square of x minus its
arithmetic average
that's also is sufficiently important estimated that has a special name and notation
you've probably seen this before you've probably seen that has this
very often people use this one over n minus one
and you think well hang on why not use one over and it's supposed to
somehow represent an average why why use one over n minus one
and the reason is the following the reason is that if you define it this
way with the one over n minus one
and if you work out the bias of this estimator then you find exactly
if you had one over and then you would have a small bias
it actually we have a slightly smaller variance but but it would have nonzero bias
and so
people somehow would prefer to work with estimators that have zero bias so that's the
entire motivation free for this
for this formula
so now things get complicated now if you want to work at the variance of
the estimator of the variance
then fine you can work that out as well and here's what the
you get you get some formulas that depends on what are called the the central
of the distribution u four and u two
which can be related to the PDF in this way
i think we don't need
the labour that point but
so the point is that i simply wrote down some estimators for mu and sigma
by guessing
by looking at the original definition of the parameter and saying well if i had
a finite data sample what would be a good way to
to estimate the parameters
now in general
there's only so much mileage that you can get out of that type of approach
what we need now is more general
method that will allow us to construct functions that can be used to estimate parameters
and so
i want to talk about the by far the most important method is the method
of maximum likelihood so to introduce that i mean the first say what the likelihood
function is
so the idea is the following suppose the outcome of some experiments is this set
of numbers
suppose i model that is coming from some joint pdf that
it is characterized by some parameter or vector of parameters theta
now the idea is that you can evaluate this PDF with the data you got
and regarded as a function of the parameter or parameters
that's called the likelihood function
so the likelihood function
is the same
as this joint pdf for the data
but i'm regarding it not as a function of the data i regard the data
as constant look at that as a function of the parameter or parameters
so that's the general
a way to write down the likelihood function now a very common situation
is it i i have a random variable x that follows some pdf f of
and i observe an
values of the variable all coming from the same period
well i insist the observations are independent remember we just we define what we mean
by independence that meant that the probability for all of them
was given by the product of the individual probabilities
so if i insisted i have an independent observations all following the same PDF
then the joint pdf is simply given by the product
of the individual pdfs
and that's very often the situation we find ourselves in
so that's very very commonly the formula that you'll see written down as the likelihood
but that's that's really only pertains to this special case more generally the likelihood function
is simply the probability for the data
given the parameter
evaluated with the data that you got
and then treated as a function of the parameters
here's some examples of
of likelihood functions
here what i've done
it's not likely functions which is to illustrate the
the idea
what i've done here is i've taken a guassian distributions and using the monte carlo
method i generated a sample generated some values that came from that guassian distribution
the idea is that if the hypothesized value of the parameter is very close to
the true value
then what you expect is a very high probability
to get data
at least similar to the data that you've got
engendering be manifest knowledge so this is what knowledge representation
and a few readers like me i really don't understand what he's saying
it's actually he's trying to make two
two points and i understood that because in nineteen labels on a new label the
but first the a one says that knowledge can be interpreted proposition another which you
can have an attitude which
is either true or false
so the knowledge is just an attitude and that it can be interpreted as propositional
both some straw polls
and the second part is that determines exactly how the system behaves so
the reasoning that you do the manipulation of the symbols you perform on explicit knowledge
is going to eventually
determine the behavior have been works
so knowledge based system is one that's designed in this way the stuff that explicitly
represented can be interpreted propositional true false
you've done plenty of true false stops
you should be fairly comfortable there and
furthermore the as you crank handling you manipulate symbols and so on what gets better
at the end you can use that to figure out how the thing works
OK i'm not sure how many of you can make a little bit of problem
so let me try and explain this programming language now the beauty of prolog is
that when it comes straight from first order logic
and i see this idea of taking first order logic and turning it into a
programming language
let's look at this program each
line can you can turn accentuate take to be
an implication
i'm going to write the error
that one
if you think of implication is our narratives that one
sorry i'm looking at my and your screen should be that way
OK so basically it says that
this thing on the right-hand and left-hand side sorry this goal
it is true
provided the things on the right-hand side true
let's look at the bottom of which we use the terms in the first half
is just a fairly
can sort procedure approach
let's have a look at this one
so this rule basically says that if the the colour of some object z is
and x is made of z
then the colour x y
and then we've got some other information here might say that
grass is native vegetation and the color vegetation is great
so the the things done the bottom just single
sort of propositions and the things above with this call dashes just an implication is
location one
if we try and execute this program essentially the way it works is we we
ask queries for instance if we are sort of fairly simple query
we twitch natural first program if as query
pretty colors no truth
well it says well in order to figure that out
i've got to see if i can prove things on the right-hand side because the
implication is that way
so this is the things on this sort of implication the true
in the things on this this sort of implication true
so it works backwards you say
what's the it's pretty colours notrel falls
he goes well i can figure that out if i could figure out where the
things on the
right hand side of the implication true
and in this case all going to do is going to write something to the
screen and say yes
similarly for photographs and so on
so the the first program is what we would call a fairly sort of procedural
it doesn't really contain any knowledge is no sense in which there is any
you know there's any sort of inference going on in trying to work out whether
you know pretty colors not
in the second one in the second programme however we've tried to
it is out of it we try to write down some facts about the domain
in the logic which when the program
execute so when you ask questions this program it will need to
so to figure out there will need to do some inference in order to work
out whether
the perceptron
the question is true
so i've down some facts and some of the facts well colors snow is white
the color the sky yellow the colour vegetation is green
grass is native vegetation
if i know the colour of something some objects that's why
and x is made of z
and i know the color must be one
so we could some simple sort of knowledge
and these things we to take to be true by
and then you for us to carry well we can just go through our inference
process and what is
in prolog even though you can sort of the work is itself by the sages
going backwards
solving some calls it turns out that the essential inference procedure has being used just
just the resolution proof to work out whether some question is true or false
OK let's not going get too worried about how prolog execute and so on but
the main point i want to make about this example is in the lower half
we've tried to explicitly write down some knowledge is the knowledge that we have is
the colour of certain things in the sky vegetation
what things are made of so we know what crosses made of
and some rules
like how we determine the color from
nine how something is made
and the suggestion is that the bottom half is this is a better way of
doing things you have written down what you know
you derive new knowledge
so the question would be why
why is the bottom half
look more attractive than top
or if you think the top looks more attractive than you can
you can let me tell me
that's the question to you
the even agree with me that the so the bottom half somewhat more intuitive leap
the top
it does definitely does something it does the same as the talk about the equivalent
it turns but but notice well we're not quite there yet
it turns out that you can't get rid of this is actually a lower bound
matches it
so so now that we've almost got an algorithm for
approximately optimally solving
an MDP
if we can express
w needs to be
to guarantee if w can be independent of the number of states we've got result
now we can pick w the way that we just we did earlier for the
uniformbandit because notice that
you know these values here
are only approximate values of the star because there's that propagates up the tree
and so the real sort of contribution
theoretically that paper is to show that the doing a careful analysis of this recursion
and showing that these errors still propagate too badly
and in fact you can pick you get to pick larger w then what we
did before but can pick w in a way that does not depend on the
number of states
that that is the basic theoretical result in the in the current paper this is
the journal version really occurred in nineteen ninety nine
which is surprising
it's a major that problem so the good news is that we can achieve near
optimality for value of w that's independent of the state space size
and this is the first sort of near optimal
mdp algorithm
that was independent of the state space size so i was
one of the landmark result the bad news is the theoretical values are typically quite
large always the case and were exponential in h
they show a lower bound in that paper that shows you can
is the title about you can't get rid of h from the exponent
right so
so we sort of trade-off depends on the number of states to dependence to the
horizon more less
so that's what you end up with
in practice
you know if you have a heuristic function is a small value of h
you'll get some improvements
it's an MDP
no it just assumes it's an MDP
so the markov property is all really assumes it can be cyclic it does it
doesn't matter
so i think they also some bounded rewards you could probably get rid of that
if you want
so that's sort of the theoretical result that that sort of
there are for historical interest it's not the most practical algorithm obviously have to build
the big tree
and it doesn't actually seem so good from an intuitive standpoint
if we think about what it's doing is generating a huge amount of work
for this action here and what if we have two actions that
sort of one is a lot better than the other one
it feels like a waste to spend the same effort generating history is history it
would be nice
how we could adaptively
control the amount of work we put into figuring out the values for these actions
so actions that are clearly suboptimal early on we don't worry about we put our
resources into disambiguating
closer to optimal actions
so it's for that case for that reason i'm referring to sparse sampling is sort
of a uniform monte carlo approach is not very smart about where it spends its
it's just let's just do this thing and return the action
now we're going to get into the adaptive monte carlo and we're going to start
out by going to the single state case again
so we end up with a monte carlo with a multi armed bandit problem and
the change the objective and this is actually the
the original objective of the multi armed bandit problem from the nineteen sixties
this problem in experimental design that sort of where it came out originated
we're going to call this the regret minimisation
objective for bandits
or loss minimisation has been called that as well so we want to do is
find the arm pulling strategy such that the expected total reward at time n is
close to the best possible
so you know if we went to vegas we have the slot machines and some
of them were biased positively and some biased negatively if we knew that best are
we go there and pull it and that's the best we could do
on average in the limit
now we we we don't know the biases of these arms and so the question
is what we want to pull arms because we want to make money but after
and poles we'd like to somehow
ensure that we're close to the optimal
if we had no
the best arm was so if you don't know what the best arm is how
can we do after a particular number of samples to if we had known the
optimal arm
this this sort of problem that exploration and exploitation
because you need to explore arms at some rate
in order to find ones that are promising but you also need to exploit arms
that already looked promising in order to make sure your profits don't go to
the one thing it's pretty clear is that the uniformbandit is a really bad choice
four if you're in vegas city what have a slot a bunch of slot machines
in front of you uniformbandit will start at the first one paul w times second
one w times and so on and so forth but really would probably sort of
walk around and paul different arms and keep statistics of these arms and pull the
one that looks most promising the question here is other algorithms that can get some
theoretical bounds on how close
two of more you're going to be without knowing
just begin the this the
there's an extraordinary
a sense of verbal chaos kind of word hoard that modern poetry and modernism generally
kind of linguistic environment of great complexity from which modern poetry and modernism emerged
this is an image called rotterdam by the artist edward ones
it's a woodcut image from blast i like it because it's the kind of image
of the modern city that makes the modern city look like language look like letters
look like a kind of scout scattered alphabet a kind of babble
i read it it's picture for me of linguistic environment if you will of modern
behind this environment are the great social processes of migration and modernization
that produced that new urban form
the metropolis
all the poetry even that new england hayseed robert frost begin their careers in metropolitan
primarily in london and new york
all that is solid melts in the air
karl marx said
evoking the accelerating transformation of modern economic and social life
the metropolis is the centre of this unsettled world that marks describes
coming to the metropolis
a hundred or ninety years ago now entailed for the writers that will be reading
as much as for anyone else
i can break with the world that they had known to break either with the
native language
and this is what the
immigrant or the expatriate experiences
or perhaps with native ways of speaking in knowing familiar spheres of reference
life in the modern metropolis was
the familiar rising it d naturalized language where there are many languages in use
well language comes to seem arbitrary rather than natural as the product of convention
not something you simply born into but something that you learn something that is made
and that can be remade
this is a presumption of all the poets we'll be reading modern american writers and
artists immigrated famously
two london
to paris
another key event in the making of modernism as the great migration of african americans
from the rural south
to the urban north
langston hughes's poetry comes out of this experience in the community of black intellectuals and
artists created specifically
in harlem
and you'll see on your hand out two quotations from poems by
hughes the first of one twenty fifth street giving as well here images of black
life in the rural south transpose two
there is in those images i think kind of utopian promise that the familiar ordinary
pleasures rural life can be recaptured in the society of plenty
but also something hallucinatory and and troubling about those images and vaguely disturbing
that's brought out i think in the related famous poem harlem on the
the next side of the page where well if we had faces is food in
the first text something possibly reassuring those spaces begin to look like dangerous objectification is
in the second one where that reason the sun threatens to
metropolis is in modern poetry set against a backdrop of
war and violence and conflict and
modern poetry as it absorbs the world of the metropolis absorbs that
that violence and energy as well
the metropolis well is it's it's a place of ambivalence a place promise
and the threat
of exultation and also of dread
ambivalence that i'm describing is is that the the centre modern literature generally
the metropolis
is crowded with language
crowded with faces but there's also a pervasive sense of
in loneliness and of loss capture also again
paradigmatic lee in the wasteland in i've i included there more lines from that poem
the nymphs are departed ellie says
is speaking of spiritual and imaginative state
modern poetry arises in only its case
with the death of god
with the loss of the theological justification for life with a sense of disenchantment
sensor depletion
depletion of meaning and value
the metropolis which brutes people
takes them away it takes them out of traditional cultures
also approves traditional religious beliefs and practices
well it's poetry the poetry created out of this experience is the poetry of spiritual
modernity is in his work a condition of social and psychological
which is both but the private personal dilemma and in public one as he
understands that
compare two elements
well it's sense of the city
this one this is a photograph by alfred stiglitz
city of ambition
this is the modern cities
not as the
cena fragmentation or despair but rather place of ascent
and aspirations
it's also
a scene of
past and future this is a photo by another american photographer walker evans a photo
of the brooklyn bridge you recognise it
and here is
another image
and finally this is the matrix t of decomposition
it is an n by n square matrix where n is the number of documents
for everything
that follows the process six because we don't need it be only one
so what we do
i'm going to
actually what does this mean and LSI dimensions but for completeness i'm putting here
this is again an orthonormal matrix
the column vectors have unit length
each document has unit length
and in two distinct column vectors orthogonal to each other so
the document representations you all
orthogonal to each other so it's
it's the basis and that's
these are again the semantic dimensions for matrices u and sigma that capture distinct topics
like politics sports economics so too is again the borderlands dimension
you can see that we have three
was not important
no it's not so these three are one documents
and these three alan documents because these are positive valence and piece of the negative
and so this to capture
the values of documents on the semantic dimensions
and here's the decomposition in its full glory
this is used sigma dt so if you multiply this matrix with this matrix with
this matrix you get the original matrix
so that size of the composition of
the term document matrix
in two
a representation of the terms
a representation of the documents
and the representation of the importance of the dimension of the semantic dimensions
we've decomposed the term document matrix c into a product of three matrices u sigma
the matrix u consists of one row vector for each card
document activity consists of one column vector for each document
the singular value matrix
it is the diagonal matrix with you about ways reflecting the importance of each dimension
and so when we do this
because i wanted to dimensionality reduction
the key problem is interesting not only tells us how important its dimensions
by setting less important dimensions to zero we keep the important information but get rid
of the details
these details may be noise
in that case
the reduced size of better representation because it is less noise
this size
all these details may make things dissimilar that should be similar
the reduced LSI representation
representations better representation because it represents in low similarity
and his analogy that may help you why fewer details can be better
consider an image of a blue flower image of a yellow flower
if you mean color
then we can see the similarity that's more easily so sometimes it's good to omit
details because then you see similarities between things but
OK and how does it work this limiting of details in the dimensionality reduction is
very simple we simply set all dimensions to zero
up to a given point i mean you want to keep so the dimensions always
ordered according to importance one is always more important then two then three then four
then five and so what we do is we
decide we want to keep two dimensions for example and then he said all other
dimensions to zero
and that's what what i have done here so
three to four
three to five cities every year
three to five cities in europe
three to five percent to zero here
actually really zero singular values sigma this has the effect of setting the corresponding dimensions
in UM mvt two zero when computing the product sequence u sigma v t
and that's just your basic matrix algebra
so these are the original matrices from the decomposition
and the only change i would to make is that i i'm going to set
these three numbers to zero
and then i have multiplied three matrices with each other and this is not reduced
representation of the term
document matrix
and this is this matrix has rank two so it's effective dimensionality is two
so i reduce the space to two-dimensional space
so this is the original
with these three values because of
and that
product gives me the original matrix
and then the first set these three to zero then i get this new and
this is our reduced representation but i'm going to work with now
that's that's the way to compare the two matrices on one slide
this one here
and this one
and if you do that then you see some of these have changed much for
example here we have one of two point five
but some have changed for the better
for example from zero to minus two
o point three nine
now here's an example why
perhaps this
it's better than this representation
let's look at document d two and d three
if e
compute the dot product of the
the similarity
it is zero right because
she competed are likely to be to constantly
then you get zero
if you compute the dot product of two and three
in the new matrix
then you get zero point five two
so the two
documents are called to each other
completely dissimilar
in the old matrix and they are quite similar to the new metrics
and that's a good thing why is a good thing because
if you look at the terms in the document d two contains both
and ocean
then the computational complexity is linear
there are data structures where you actually get rid of the the
it turns out that once you have this the representation of the data that the
way to compute similarity measures
you can
the writer of
anomaly detection algorithms
that use some geometric notion of an out
here are three examples
so one of the most number of centre of mass
where you started
think of the data is concentrated in some
in some compact part of the space
and you've got an analogy of points as distance from the point
from the centre of mass
the whole day
so it's a very simple measure but it turns out to be quite effective for
certain kinds of applications
if you want to do feature space you have to be somewhat tricky there is
well known for the
central feature space that you cannot do this online so that's fixed
speed up the station
another way to do anomaly detection is to used clustering
measure and of point but it has as the inverse of the carbon out of
the cluster
o the point get fired
you can also do some local density measures like the one he uses
notions the cancellations being appointed clique in nature
point in order to
and now here for example rationality
the point is far away
from the point in clique
that this counts towards the knowledge
if all points in the clique a well separated
well separated and this is the fact that
sort of indicates and sparsely populated
the body
but the balance of the
in fact we come up with the score
that is relevant to an analysis point
so there are some technical details of how to run this algorithm
incrementally perhaps
if the slide show some experiment
as i said
our goal was
evaluate the ability of algorithms to detect unknown attacks
and of course i wanted to to
run experiments on sunday
realistic data so
we have
creating our own dataset
our institute where we have invited the penetration testing experts
it had model system that set up an ambush by
so penetration testing is
like white hat white hat hacker in know the companies that
run this business basically testing
mechanisms of companies and happen to know one
which people and we have divided into this work for us to say
data extraction
so we have
tax in this way and also collected data normal environment by
inviting people to use this
the second dataset considered the intrusion detection evaluation
carried out by dublin nineteen ninety nine
so this is the only publicly available dataset for evaluation
it has affected much larger scale datasets collect several weeks
the main from the data set is that it was created in a simulated environment
they basically models
large scale
have a system
and sense of tax in the system
the system is similar to the artifacts have been heavily criticized in the security community
that's the only
publicly available datasets we have also run hours of their order
c he
to make sure the results consistent with the world
we have
evaluate the impact of various different algorithms
this kind of data
so as i said you know there are many ways one can
define the notion of analyticity so we basically run algorithms on the set of features
that characterize
so the question
i come back to the estimation error it was later found to be actually what
the show this model is actually multivariate autoregressive model
and what we were doing actually is we're we're estimating this multivariate autoregressive parameters from
real world EEG data
and then from this estimated delta aggressive parameters we computed all these coupling measures
so what i'm going to to talk and the next minute
we can estimate term here
that's true
the thing is that in each analysis where we are very used to look in
specific frequencies
and so the parameters itself doesn't give a nice representation on that and the parameters
itself depend also on the sampling rate
converting this into
into the frequency domain it's easy to compare the data with different sampling rates because
we have to spectacle presentation so that's one of the of the advantages just two
percent data
i agree that it's not for it's not really
necessary and so sense so but if you want to look at specific frequencies then
we need to convert convert this into into the frequency domain
OK the data will be applied to this method this because the public available the
data set to be also provided to the BCI competition two thousand three
and this was basically a motor imagery task with four different gases
in the following i will present just one class because it's just too much data
and then just for to demonstrate the purpose it's just percent on classes the left
movement concerning the
timing the q was presented that second three
so the area before second three
consider this the resting into by the difference in the world and the actual activity
done after
after the q
there was in this case there was no feedback given so this was kind of
training sample training session which could be used to train i guess if i and
subsequent BCI experiments
we recorded sixty channels
but in order to provide somehow to keep it simple i just selected five channels
and these are marked by just five starts to keep things simple and
what we get is from from this is what we do
time frequency analysis as it has been already proposed it several blocks really so here
we have the time axis from second o to nine and the frequency from silhouettes
to sixty minutes unfortunately here it is in the top ten sixty below kilos
just the other way around and again be that they're going on is the time
frequency maps of the all back and we did also significance testing whether the coupling
is significant different than zero
in this case and on the right-hand side the significance test is whether there is
a significant change from the thing in devoted to the to the actual actual activation
that's the kind of event related analysis
this shows the body here in the all-time cost spectrum in the absolute values
it's very difficult to see
anything here
if we look at the event related analysis then we see that there are significant
changes in the i find peter in chapter thirty in this specific dataset
which is clearly task related
in this case again but lieutenant
left hand finger movement
the left hand movement imaginary movements
if you look at the coherence but we get this coherence is also significant all
over the place so that's what the and here we see that event related father
to coherence
this session is especially prominent in the general received four is included so he before
you have set c four to c three and so on
also here is a little bit but c four is the most prominent activity
you see more please much more prominence than in dbs related to c three so
it should somehow explain but that that's the subject of on the right and left
hand movement and so the corresponding area is on the seafront of the electrodes four
if a computer face
face is not there were significant only where we have large power
so that we have a large amplitude
and the event related but we see here again c four c four is involved
if you look at the imaginary part of coherency we get some somehow similar picture
eventrelated part of imaginary coherence here so so
the c four is is very much involved in that part
maybe just for curiosity and interesting aspect is that here
we get
b here
we get an increase
as well as here but if you look at the absolute value of the
imaginary part of the here then we see here that before the before the q
the image gradient is zero
and then becomes positive
and in this should be payoff channel its first it's first negative and then it
becomes a hero in those cases this results in the positive in an increase in
the imaginary part of the
so let's just somehow interesting which says that
it's not sufficient to look only at the event related analysis but it's always good
to look into the at the absolute values
if we look at the partial coherence
the picture looks very very different what we see here that the coupling between
c four
in this role that it's very much change here in this case have said this
is very much involved in in
in partial coherence so that should already thing about that something is not
as trivial as this one that
OK let's let's continue with the directed transfer function that potential function
does not become much significant but only in the best of c four
then we need to see some significant changes
so i gave you
a very broad brush
big picture of
it all works in energy and distance
and i want to look at the particles
more carefully
and then in the third lecture the forces more carefully and in the fourth lecture
bring it all together so this list is going to be about particles
starting with
if you like a bit of history
that's the
the structure of matter
there have been two
independent uncomplimentary ways
that we've discovered or deduced the nature of the structure of matter long
is the discovery of spectral
as in the case of the atoms for example the discovery of atomic spectra in
the nineteenth century was what gave the clue that something must be going on
and led to the
discovery of the
eventually quantum
theory is results in the pattern of spectral lines the series of
energy levels
and then scattering from the heart center
for example rather and his team discovered atomic nucleus by scattering so these are all
very familiar in the world of atomic physics and atoms one makes in high school
and first university and
qualitatively the same story has been replicated throughout the as we will see
quantitatively it is different
and the reason it's qualitatively different is
as we saw in the last lecture shorter and shorter distances require higher and higher
energies resolve them but as we will see surprisingly the pattern of the physics qualitatively
stays the same so let's just look at this for example if i showed you
at some stage in history you think you've found elementary objects in which everything is
made and then later you discover that there actually structured systems made smaller pieces
the critical thing is that quantum mechanics
constrains the behaviour of those smaller pieces
so they can't go every which way they have to go in to particular quantum
states and is that structured system jumps from one quantum state to another
the energy
is omitted
in the quantized form and it is the detection of the quantized energy b
photons all
articles that tells you what the structure of this system that originated it is
so suppose i showed you see energy levels that you deduced i've listed here
on the left molecules calcium atoms so the nucleus and even the proton and the
reason for these energy levels of the molecules are collections of atoms which can vibrate
and rotate around each other and individual atom as electrons in different levels around the
nucleus and electrons can jump from one level to another
the nucleus itself with neutrons and protons they can vibrate and rotate
giving a nuclear excitation levels and the protons
themselves we now know are made of quarks
if the quarks in the lowest energy state the quantum mechanics allows
the energy adds up to what we call a proton those quarks can be excited
to higher energy levels and you get what are called resonance excite ations of the
proton and the neutron so forth if i showed you one of these patterns you
couldn't immediately
which he was but the moment i put an energy scale on it then you
see immediately how different they are
but the excitation scales of molecules are fractions of an EV
expectations of electrons in atoms on the EV scale
the nucleons the generic word for protons and neutrons the nucleons in the nucleus
are excited on the MTV scale and the quarks inside the proton
we are excited on the hundreds of any scale
so clearly to the same story quantitatively smaller smaller distances
higher and higher energy scales of matches
so that is the
route of spectrum
showing you the structure then you have the direct experimental evidence for it by scattering
beams of your object
and discovering that has got constituents inside
the classical example of that's was back in nineteen seventeen when ready
originally manchester
later on the cambridge
in his original work it was done in manchester
in fact he didn't do it kind remarks and in rather got the credit that's
another thing you learn about the priorities in science the your bosses will get credit
but they
they scattered alpha particles produced by naturally occurring radioactivity and alpha particles have quite low
energies enough energy to resolve there is an atomic nucleus in the center of the
atom but not enough energy to resolve anything
inside the nucleus so for the for the nucleus was the point charge
fifty years later when got beams of electrons
scattered of nuclear electron beam to some hundreds of MTV able to resolve the protons
and neutrons in nuclei and
by the nineteen seventies
electron beams
of tens of g
well able to resolve the quarks inside the protons and the experiments were done at
stanford in california
by collaboration involving people from stanford and people from MIT
and those of you who know these guys stakes at MIT in cambridge massachusetts
it's sort of inversion from manchester and cambridge and the also was invented in nineteen
seventy one hundred seventeen bit of artistic license OK so
let me show you some things about relevance
discovery of the nuclear as this is something you all know but there may be
some features of this which you might find novel that has been
remember being targeted detector was the rules
he's been alpha particles from natural radioactivity the target with a thin piece of gold
leaf the detector was a small scintillation screen screen
and this i thought you might find interesting you can't read it here but you'll
be able to properly look at it on the web and zoom in and see
that's the simple way of getting in works when all we're dealing with is
once all you in one solve but to make
richard so that we can treat
the conditions where we have more than one solitude
the other approach is to use a
turn on as solubility product
the solubility product
in the solubility product is best shown by
example let's look at
salt dissolved in water but very sparingly silver chloride
silver chloride
it has a lattice energy that's all said
we can get some to dissolve in water but only sparingly so
so i'm going to put equal sign if we move from
left to right were dissolving so let's call the reaction
and we move from
right to left that's called precipitation
precipitation and so silver chloride dissociates it dissociates to form
silver cations
and to show that there dissolved in water on the right a q
i mean that's in aqueous solution
and the chloride
and lines again a q
and this notion that when an ionic solid
it dissolves in water
it dissolves not as a molecule of silver chloride but rather as cation and anion
was in fact what one arrhenius his nobel prize he got his nobel prize not
i think is really good work on activation energies and so on the paved the
way for our understanding of catalysis and so on he got his nobel prize for
which was called the theory of electrolytic dissociation meaning that when an ionic solid dissolves
it forms an electrolyte that is to say
an ionic conductors so that was his
nobel prize and what we do is we can express the solubility of silver chloride
by the solubility product denoted KSP
as the product of the instant concentration of each of the ions and art first
blush you're going to say well that's just the same as
talking about the concentration of the of the salt dissolved and that that is the
case in this trivial example
we can move on to something a little more
sophisticated in a moment so i'm going to take the concentration
using square brackets to denote concentration so it's the product of the concentration of the
silver catalan
and the concentration of chloride and
concentrations here are in units of models per litre salt plug in the value of
the silver ion concentration and the chloride ion concentration and that gives me the
the solubility product
and then this goes up to some
master value and that's the
saturation so now i want to show you that that we have some evidence for
so here's some evidence what i'm showing is the plot of conductivity the conductivity of
the solution as a function of the number of moles of silver chloride that has
been added and what do you see first of all
here we have the conductivity of pure water
pure water is a very very poor conduct we should really properly call it an
insulator and in units of this reciprocal which is the same in units of seaman's
per centimetre the conductivity of pure water is less than ten to the minus seven
ten to the minus seven it's some number times ten to the minus eight seems
per centimetre so what's happening when we dissolve silver chloride we're adding this is the
same as doping
we're adding charge carriers only instead of in adding holes to the valence band or
electrons to the conduction band that's going to help us because water is water is
capable of dissolving iron so we're going to make an ionic conductor by injecting carriers
the more silver chloride be dissolved the greater the number of carriers the greater the
number of carriers the greater the conductivity so by measuring conductivity
as a function of concentration we can determine if we are
dissolving the silver
as opposed to we keep adding it just seems to the bottom so let's look
what we find is as we add silver chloride the conductivity of the solution rises
up to a maximum value at around ten to the minus five models of silver
chloride per litre of solution so that would be a concentration of ten to the
minus five more
and then what happens if we keep adding silver chloride but
the conductivity doesn't change so what do you think is happening if you could stare
at the beaker is the the silver chloride just fall into the bottom so the
knee in the curve indicates that we've reached saturation solubility
that's good
so we have evidence to to support
we can do
then compare the solubility with the solubility product in the following we can say that
the relationship between
the saturation solubility
really equal to the concentration of silver chloride dissolved
which arrhenius is told this is really the concentration of silver ion which is equal
to the concentration of chloride ions all of these are the same
and so a little bit of algebra we can show them that
relationship between
this and KSP is
since the concentration of silver equals the concentration of chloride then we can take sp
the one half will then pull the sea start saturation solubility
and for silver chloride it turns out that
the product the solubility product is
one point eight
times ten to the minus ten
which then means that the saturation solubility for is the square root of
one point three times ten to the minus five and sure enough that's what you
see on this plot you see that some just a little bit higher than ten
minus five more
the plot has flat now but now
let's look at the more interesting case
and put the solubility product to work and ask ourselves what happens if we add
silver chloride not to pure water
but to a solution that contains already some other dissolved salt is that going to
have an impact on the amount of silver chloride we can dissolve
the null space of A
has got what it
only the zero vector
there are no free variables to give other values
so that the null space is only the zero vector
but but but but
and what about our solution away x equal the solutions
back to a x equal being what what's the story on that 1 so now
that's coming from today's lecture
the solution x it
what's the complete solution
it's just x
particular right if if if there resonance if there is a solution it's actually equal
x particular
there's nothing but the other is just 1 solution
if there is 1 at all
so it's unique solutions
unique means only 1
unique solution if it exists it
it exists
so in other words I would say that we put it in a different way
there either 0 or 1 solution
this is all in this case are equal and find all the because many many
applications in reality the columns will be
well you will be what out later call independence
and we'll have a
nothing to look for in the null space
and will only have particular solution OK
everybody see that part possibility it but I need an example right
so let me create an example
what sort of a matrix
what's the shape of a matrix that has full column rank
so can I squeeze in an example here
it exists let me put an example and that it's just the right place to
put it
and example
because the example will be like tall and thin
it will have
I mean here's an example 1 2 6 5 3 1 1 1 brilliant exam
so there is a matrix A
and what's its rank
what's the rank of the matrix
how many pivots will I find if I do elimination
to write to
I see a payment there
act I've certainly those 2 columns a headed off in different directions
when I do elimination of certain get another pivot here find and I can use
those to clean out a below and above so
actually tell me what it
role reduced
reduced row echelon form would be
can you carry that
that elimination process to the bitter end
so what it was
I subtract a multiple of this role from these rows cleanup all zeros that
I've got something image here what do I do with that I go subtracted below
and above
and then I divide through and what's the what's R 4 that example maybe I
can you'll allow me to put that just here in the next
you also have issues
just by men makes it
and just identified nine
issues to consider
we need to make for study
first one we talked about sample integration
that is where
you might have different sizes between the qualitative and quantitative and you want to be
able to
your conclusions
OK the question is to what extent you justify to do that
when you have such different sample sizes
could then you have inside outside
so you have a situation where in the quite a few more outside looking in
and coordinates that's you know activities and make sense h one one infinity
and so when you have any study may be used in both those so what
extent to those
work together in a study
because realizations you might do in makes reference study
to overcome the which is the one in some weaknesses one side you get my
generalization you have the quantitative component
to what extent
is that we these risation met
sequential this is a really important one because a lot of
people to like to the sequential studies
sometimes people want to combine focus group research into media interviews
people have found which when you do first can make a difference
if individually in if we got a couple of presentations here about lee interviews and
and expert interviewing going on
you do that first
then you folk fully outfitted with focus groups
you might get different information if you focus first
do you really care about what your goals are an individual data collection that so
that's within you might yourself that sequential we've been
we've been paradox so in qualitative you have
focus group that is in the museum of those observations
that and makes behave across
sequential issues
when you convert quantitative qualitative data and vice versa
that might be an issue
there are times when you count things
is misleading
what does not always mean important is you know so something may say something
many times
say one thing once
and that one thing may be the most important experience they had she had
so there are times recounting you have to be careful about you know how to
not always
you what you need
but there are times when it is very powerful
then you have had the most amazing when you mix
the paradigm
this knowledge intelligence so forth within your study
the idea of making guest starts which is going back and forth
multiple validities
you have the ability for the different phases that you have to examine
and the political
a lot of political issues going on
for writing your article
when you write makes reference state is one of the big challenges because you know
lot of times people read your work
by the strong one not on the other so
what kind of language to use to make sure that they try the whole article
not to skip the courtside skip the side
that's always the challenge also
for those decision makers policymakers
you know a a lot of time
for example in the US is a huge bias towards quality about the government level
and so they are often
they want take is not seriously
the qualitative findings
so that's number child we have to try and make
make all our findings
pam porter
so these
nine issues
to consider
when you do quality we do make efforts study
sexual when you write that report
these issues i said you need to consider
different styles of writing
i am i most as together additionally
OK audiences i said you have different audiences different backgrounds
reports also tend to be longer this is a big issue for us
so long time we tend to
be limited to how many journals because mean something to
because there's some journals have strict page that means you can't call it a mixed
methods study
and it my number three quality studies well
and still for some people so the conversion emerging field
we have a long long way to go to those it just makes method can
play really big well
in this movement
the newly formed the question so when you have
that the study should be able to that we we don't believe that one study
is definitive one study and say OK we have the answer
we believe the second part of the world you have to have the case study
because you may be something like sample
effect the findings
and after time you may
if i may need to be formulated the questions you change the question
study or a lot
and we do you study all possible people to do it
so part i was
the city has been seen somehow that was going on
but also outside may not be explicit
but it may be
a situation where it's just like infected in textbooks and articles or what journals publish
you might see a bias towards one of the other so these different ways paradigm
was manifest themselves
education of united nations but this might feel differently now
that's a pretty big
especially literacy research looking at reading
a lot of great studies in reading
but a lot of them tend to be simplistic an opinion makes everything because what
want to do is which
answer questions like which method is best
but if you do the other pole here
and i asked you
the way you know
meet when you're in school
i bet you can we can find an array of different ways that you know
how to it wasn't all one way
very very few
of the
of these ages active most of them will be zero
typically the sum of the ages with thinking of them being positive values i mean
that can be guaranteed if age
always contains its complement
so every h and h has a complementary function otherwise you take the absolute value
here doesn't minimum
but with thinking of this is sort of measuring a measure of complexity
of the function
all that we we create and so
we're going to bound that by some
constant b
and we can think of this as a convex combination convex hull
convex combination up to scale b
of the functions in eight
and what typically you do in boosting
this is not always completely explicit but you can be seen is you minimize some
function of the margin distribution
so adaboost is an exponential function of the margin you optimize
two your
you're you're
and you end up with a reasonably sparse set of these ages
and so
we'll see how to include the margin analysis later but what i'm gonna concentrate on
now is looking at the rademacher complexity of this class of functions
in terms of the rademacher complexity of this set of weak learners
so you would expect because you've got you know
weak learners sound weak right so
you expect low rademacher complexity these like decision stumps or something at this title
and you would therefore expect this to be much more complex
and therefore you pay a price for doing boosting
however if you do the analysis this is the analysis
here is the rademacher empirical rademacher complexity of convex hull of h
at scale b
so that's the supernova
choosing an h and h the whole set of ages and
a set of parameters that are bounded by b
of this
quantity the correlation with with this random noise the expected value of that
OK so what do you do you swap these two sons
and you're going to some of a bring that out
slightly increases things potentially
but now you can just replace that by most b
take the b out
and you just end up with this some super over h j
h of
this correlation
which is just the rademacher complexity
of the the weak learners themselves
so actually
you don't add anything
by taking convex combinations to the complexity
except in the sense that you scale up
the multiplying factor of these so if we set b equal to one for instance
we just take a strictly convex hull
of the set of functions
we don't increase the rademacher complexity at all
so this is
you know a little bit counterintuitive we've increase the set of functions massively
and yet we haven't increased its complexity
the reason is intuitively is that the
when you take the convex hull
points of the
polytope defined that are the functions in the weak learner class
o or some subset of those functions and we plan to cast
and the rademacher complexity is always extreme at some
o point in the polytope
so you know enough
at a point that was already in you know when you're looking for that suit
in the rademacher complexity here
you're always going to end up with the point was already knew we learn actually
not going to get anything worse than you had before
so this is for me
that's the key is to y boosting works
in some sense this
in some sense you're increasing the complexity but you're not paying any price was like
too good to be true you know
and you know boosts
maybe i'm not sure possible using the similar
strategy of taking com which means convex combinations you take an average over the
function class
yeah it's not really a convex combination of with
but maybe maybe there's something could be done
so this means that
essentially moving the convex hull incurs no complexity penalty as far as rhetoric complexity is
in if we take the course one
so i'll show you the end
how this can be factored into bound for
boosting but before i do that i'll go onto looking at
the rademacher complexity for
so how do we we approach that's well
svm some these you know slightly weird functions that are defined in terms of the
but of course we really think of them in terms of the
the linear
functions in the kernel defined feature space so this is the projection into the kernel
defined feature space and this is just
a linear function there with bounded norm
which i'm going to gain bound by a constant b
so really were interested in the rademacher complexity of this class of functions
the two all approaches that
kind of our based on bayes
i'm gonna first talk about rule based directed models
and this is one of the ones that have probably the longest history
and this is an exhaustive but
there was
a lot of the original work
by the pool
darwin co
and then some of the
more recent work
is included here but there's lots of others as well and let me kind of
build up giving caricatures
each other approaches
at an intuitive level
we start off we have logic programs
and in the logic programme we're going
can change your example of bit from before i will say OK
the author of the paper is famous then there will be a
probably true lilac time
not all the time so we want to make that a little bit
less categorical
first way to do this is with very technical term called the fudge factor so
added something that says
now what's the probability of being accepted
i will say
that again we have the same rule
and now has a probability point six
intuitive meaning here is
for all p in a if a is the author of p and a is
famous then p is accepted with probability point six
so that seems
kind of the right idea
but then we have to think about
how does this
really work in the case where
for example
other possible
ways in which paper could be accept so
ideally there is also the case well if high quality paper
maybe it will be accepted two and maybe it would be nice if that probability
were little bit higher than the probability that
accepted if it's by a famous
one way of dealing with that is we can change maker
interpretation is probably a little bit more precise and so we can say that
this point six min
if there are no other possible causes for the paper being accepted
this probability is point six
and then
if more than one possible cause holds
then we'll have to introduce
some sort of probabilistic combining rule
to take that into account
we can
kind of appeal again
are intuitive notions
one logic programme what would you do
while logic programming as the disjunction
and so what the
two disjunction the probabilistic setting
we can do probabilistic disjunction which does
we are kind of doing the or
these different
because the
and to make this tractable
kind of causal independence there
each of the potential causes
is independent p myself but
obviously this is
often times and approximation so
in this case in particular
the quality of the paper and the famous author may well not be
independent but still it's a useful
kind of approximation that we can make
this fits into
computing the probabilities so
the probability of the paper being accepted
and let's say
alice is an author and alice is famous
the paper
is high quality
we can
compute this
the probability that at least one of the
cause it succeeds
is simply
one minus the probability that all of the true
possible causes fail
it's one minus
this is first rule