so that's that's correct much a part of the feature function is to indicate
which y values have higher probability
and if someone is intrinsically have higher probability then you can model that was the
feature function doesn't depend on x
but if you have a feature function only depend on access
what what would actually happen is that
mathematically would cancel from the numerator and denominator because you have some after actually have
corresponding wj
so far
for every different y here
you at the same contribution
up here
and so for itself so you could divide through so that that contribution to the
councillors from the numerator denominator and i wouldn't have any influence on the relative probabilities
of the different wise
it's the d
let me
ask another question so
they to a set
so after a for j equals one
j equals
so and the
if i want to talk about the dimensionality of the problem here the dimension as
the number of feature functions
and d is fixed
more often
the length
and the length
is not fixed
axes of x's words and y is waiting for a hyphen
or axes
so sentences and y is part of speech
so one of the more
one of the machine learning issues that
you know feature funk resolve
how to apply supervised learning to objects that don't have a fixed length fixed size
you can have a fixed number of feature functions
even if the
the length of the axes otherwise is not fixed
we can have so
then we can have a special
but what i wrote up here
so f j of x y
it is the sum
over the length of ax
little fj
and then
two neighbouring values in the
label sequence
and then the input x for
and then the
position i
well you would be essentially unchanged expanding by one so in fact
maybe something that's closer to what i would actually do in practice and maybe some
i equals zero to ten plus one
where n is the
length of x
i corps
one to n plus one
fj of why i minus one y i
x y where
i define
as a start
and why and plus one is and
and so
so far come
when i
thinking about trying to predict the output sequence y
it can be computationally convenient
too much to just say well why zero is always start and y n plus
one is always and
and then what i want to predict is whatever comes in between
so the
the the big restriction here
the significant restriction
is that each fj
i can only
examine two adjacent
why i minus one
why i
month and so i have a
the terminology is going to use as a high level feature function
and then
so sixteen to nine that doesn't seem like a big deal but if it hadn't
been for if i could draw you know hundred we would have gone into the
hundred down to something like four times one hundred
as you go from two to one hundred more than the number of atoms in
the universe to roughly four hundred numbers
and that's that's quite reasonable
and if you think about
you know if you're trying to get one of these models to data four hundred
parameters is
not unreasonable worse two to one hundred
well datasets are big these days but not that big
right so it's very important that kind of compression in terms of the parameterisation of
the distribution
is anyone bothered by this factorisation
is there an inconsistency between what i wrote and what state it up there
here i was only using maximal cliques
right there i sort of sets over all cliques
right so the additional cliques that we left over the nodes the nodes are cliques
but is it wrong whatever it here
yes absorb
you're a man of few words but correct words which is good right so you
can always absorbed these things so
we haven't so this is unique if you sort of string parameters out of it
you can get unique factorizations the the way we written these factorizations are unique but
that's not what is actually important right now what's important is that the factorisation is
very compact
OK so
an important result in this area that i'll come back to later actually says you
might be wondering OK so
high-level just recapping we said grasp probability
we said OK i can look at vertex cutset and i can look at conditional
independence or i can look at cliques and i can look at factorizations
you might say well why did i introduced both of them
what interest both because they are actually equivalent this this is a theorem known as
the hammersley clifford theorem it doesn't matter which way you go
if you start with a fixed graph and you say that you want to factorize
across the cliques that's the same as you want saying that all these conditional independence
statements hold
so the markov chain is a particular example of a right the markov chain you
know when you build markov chains you don't actually typically write them like this you
typically write them is an initial distribution the conditional distribution x two given x one
x three given x two
but that's a special case of this kind of factorizations
so that's one way to understand markov chains the other ways in terms of the
conditioning on present breaks the graph into two
right so for markov chains we can sort of see the
which doesn't matter where we start we end up with the same answer but hammersley
clifford says actually for a general graph that that's also true
and that's not obvious
one direction is not hard although the not hard direction with your in the other
direction is actually quite difficult
not quite difficult but it it's more
OK so
all come back to that in a minute let me just start giving you some
this is an example that we've i've already does mention the markov chain
what i'm doing here is actually implementing it to make it what's known as a
hidden markov model
so hidden markov model you have both these variables x that are evolving over time
and you also have
variables hanging off the axes these are wise these are shaded in because that's typically
what you observe
right so that actually the visit big success of of markov models are one of
the really big successes is in automatic speech recognition which i personally don't like because
it's part of the reason that you know whenever you call a phone number for
a company you get a computer these days you don't get customer service
right but speech recognition
you know speech models is way speech evolves least humans can be modelled very natural
is a markov process to sort of the sequential dependence in the way that people
are forming phonemes and the problem of speech recognition is exactly it's well modeled by
exactly this graph of course along graph so these are the sort of hidden phonemes
the sort of units of speech that you're trying to infer and the shaded circles
those are other the random variables that's what you observe so if you're speaking over
the phone you're getting some sort of noisy version of what the person is really
saying or things like you know people might not be fluent speakers if i speak
french there be some certain amount of noise we say for the speech recognition devices
and so on
so it's an instance of this is what the computer services noisy instance what is
trying to infer is the actual phonemes and then it would pass them to get
words and what is exploiting is that there's a lot of temporal dependence in the
sequence of all words phonemes at all levels of language there's tons of temple dependent
so really the successive of automatic speech recognition is an instance of this
and it's an instance of some algorithms talk about tomorrow
some of these message passing algorithms
so markov models are great but
there's many things you want to do in practice that are
more complicated
what various people have done an interesting sort of extension of speech recognition is if
you have a video that has both audio tracks and it has speaking
let's assume that multiple people are speaking and
hence multiples people's lips are moving or maybe it's slightly different times if you want
to source all the different names for the cocktail party problem
you have many people speaking
and you'd like to separate the audio track into multiple tracks to get each person's
one way you can do that better is if you have a video
and then you can somehow use the synchrony between my lips moving informing certain things
and what's been said on the audio
so now what you have is you have two temporal models you have to markov
chains you have the video evolving over time
you have the audio evolving over time
so you'd like to model both the temporal dependencies would also like to synchronize
if you'd like to synchronize across streams
you might actually have multiple cameras if you're lucky you might have camera one camera
two audio one
and you have a whole coupled set of markov chains
so this is a much richer model
and we're going to see that
is maybe and so we'll have something to do with the entropy and shannon information content and that's the thing
and that would
again reinforced the claims we've been
and then the practical question
is taste of theory i just wanna know how to make a good one how to make good symbol codes
and when we say good or optimal
we need to define what we mean by
so let's do at
what do we mean by optimal well after compression so we want a short
link there are some really that's our main objective function
so there may be others
so the find the expected length
or at ensemble
on the ensemble being
the alphabet with all its probabilities
well defined it can be out of three at x is
some overall your elements in the alphabet
and multiply the probability of
the outcome
by the length that you have assigned with all i
is the length
in bits of
the code that you've assigned to be i
haven't okay nothing profound going on here and just defining the expected length
and it's probably a good idea to
immediately use an example
so let's give ourselves an alphabet
now what's going to be eh
and let's have a probability distribution
one eight
this is a toy
probability distribution with
on even probabilities
one thing we might want to know about this
ensemble is what is its entropy and the answer is half-time model
plus a quarter times to
less than eight
three thousand eight
these one two three and three being respectively the logspace to of this this this and this
and that's is
one intercourse
give ourselves
symbol code and then try and make it better and we need pin down what
the rules of the game are actually going going to be here
so what do we want
let's let's define it
the rules
first and then look at some examples
the first rule is it had better work when someone code this and then someone
else and decodes the better get back what we first put in so what comes
up must be what comes in
we wanted to decode
we wanted to guarantee to decode correctly not just have a ninety nine point nine
percent chance of working which is already quite good in our
a slightly silly approach last time
we wanted to always decode correctly
let's just finer the rules and then say a bit more precisely what we what we mean by
by this
ideally we'd like it to be easy to decode as well
so we don't have
the recipient having just spent hours staring at the codebook trying to figure out where
the punctuation where the missing punctuation marks go in these in this received string
so easy to decode would be nice to have
but is not essential if if we can get a big win
on this final objective which is small expected length
small el
let's just be precise about what we mean by it's got the code right we want the code to be
uniquely decodable
so when you receive an encoded string there should be no ambiguity about what was said so
string x
hand any other string why
such that's
x is not the same as one
we want the encoding
of x
not equal
so that's the definition of unique decodability
andy just check my notes section is clear
the is the way we encode a particular element alphabet and then have see all
the string like that's that's just a concatenation
of thanks from
thanks to
so i'm overloading the symbol see to me
the way to encode a single symbol or it could be the encoding of an entire string
okay we've got ourselves an ensemble let's define
some simple codes and have a think about these
object is what it means is say it's gonna be uniquely decodable what is
what does that imply how do we get a small expected length
is this a good start for english
to something
and almost
o also of data may contain huge amount of noise
and if you want to detect anomalies in the noise data this is quite different
and difficult because
sometimes a regular
the values
chapman into
in the noisy environment this is especially true for time series data and temporal
when you're trying to detect anomalous subsequences so for example if an animal
anomalous subsequence is
for any reason the different than anything else
if you have the noisy data single individual instances may not be
maybe in the perfect range of so few examples it would be
clear to what
so also in the world data
normal behavior keeps evolving so for example if you create the model
when you want to detect anomalies this behavior is changing over time so you the
model should be updated as so the question is
how frequently you need to be the model and you know how you do this
one because the computational efficiency is very important
because if you distance data coming at enormous speed
so you have to figure out how fast into this
and of course
if you have thousands of features in your application
all these thousand features important which features are important for anomaly detection this is not
the classical feature selection problem like in every data mining problem definition you have the
class label
here we usually do not have the class label in trying to identify what
relevant features is not that is not easy
so different people are doing a different kind of
feature projection and so on in order to protect the
among in different dimensions
so there are several aspects of anomaly detection people try to cover here
first what kind of the data we had the nature of input data what kind
labels do have
type of anomalies
but i'll alex this means
output what kind of output the animal protection of data is provided to
and also how you do evaluation of anomaly detection techniques
so let's assume that you have some data most of the data is a
it's coming into the form of the univariate or multivariate and it is the only
way they usually have
just one one available which is
not very often the case
and if you have a multivariate
future of maybe tens hundreds sometimes thousands of variables
and you have to find anomalies in this dimensional space
so the question is
if you have
anomalies that appear in only one feature that is find but for example
if anomalies not obvious in any of the individual features
how to find these anomalous and was the right
the size of the itemsets difficult
so also you may deal with different kind of
the type of activity also familiar with all of this from the
money perspective you may have binary attributes
you may have categorical attributes continuous and hybrid for example if you're dealing with
network intrusion detection
you may end up using source IP destination IP addresses and sometimes it's not clear
how to convert this IP
and i think this is into the future that you can use in your calculation
OK so we also have different data types you may dealing with sequential data for
example stock
market data collecting from
some engines your car lane
also you may have the dynamics data like this is
genes data you may have to
data from the traffic
know how certain carson moving someone to the accident accidents
if you have heard sounds data
if you want
you have basically spatial and temporal data because you have two dimensions
also this is some data from from the ports all across the US and sometimes
it's important to understand the location as well as other attributes to see that sometimes
you have to make sure all these attributes plus spatial and temporal domain and you
have to deal with all these issues in order to detect anomalies
according to the data labels that are available to you
you may have seen situations when we talking about supervised anomaly detection in this case
the labels for both normal
and anomalies are available to you so in this case you just supplying some classification
techniques in order to detect both normal and anomaly core for whatever
since this is usually imbalanced datasets usually have to tweak
classification of interest to work on this kind of the problems different people were doing
different things and i'll have a small section
also if you can labels available only from the normal may be talking about some
unsupervised anomaly detection techniques in this case usually build some data-mining the model to represent
this normal behavior
and then you are trying to detect deviations from that normal behavior
and then i i can look at aragon i look at your target and then
i i tried to come up is an example that screws up here again
right so even the class and the is is really huge
then maybe i will be able to pick some such an MDP by the class
of family business pretty small
the and surely maybe if if the classifier and if it just contains the single
and EP
then found
there is nothing single
i could write so
because there are good could be very
that you need to that single and EP
and then i cannot come come up with a counterexample right so we knew that
a largish class fmdps and the question is how large the class family has to
and it turns out to be that this is really the best class of mdps
in my opinion at least
the transition probabilities
could be
any uniformly lipschitz transition
probably is what do we mean by saying you know but small so the idea
of small spaces that
closings resulting closings c find that states which are close by
and i'm taking the same actions then there is something transition probabilities of sorry that
is acting
probability distributions are going to be close to each other so that
the idea
and the idea is that you have this live has property that if these two
states i'm getting closer to each other than the probability distributions are getting closer to
each other
OK so that's one constraint on the class family piece
the constraint is is
she showing this class
by quite a big stand
so that constraints is that the transition probabilities and the rewards are uniformly bounded
so why is this a very strong constraints
it's a very strong constraint because if you take the gaussian
and you increase the dimensionality
and you keep the
very and speaks
there and the height of the gaussian is going to grow to infinity with n
so this means
that if you have a uniformly bounded
transition probs if you have a uniform bound the transition probabilities
then you're rotating gold is gaussian zeroing out noise in the transitions which we would
have to fix various you have to as you increase the dimensionality
you have to increase the benefits you have to increase the variance
so your problems become
more and more noisy in chennai noise should be helpful in this class of problems
why because well in the limit if your problem is very very noisy
you have no control right
so in the limit
if i if the noise is so large that no matter what action i am
taking i'm pretty much everywhere in the state space so that the
the limit for
a large noise
that i don't have any control them was the value function
it will be constant everywhere so it's very small so it's very easy to learn
OK so large noise generally have in this problems
when you want to learn a value function
and the this condition he laments that
so it seems that you cannot have large noise in the
this seems like
that's right
so we should start thinking about five functions than because this and just say that
if you want to estimate value functions for what is reasonable cost family is so
you have smallest control problems
the noise is pretty large and the control problem and yet you are not able
to come up with an efficient target
maybe there's not much overlap
so we should go to the beach because the sun just came out
anyway so it turns out that you can do a few things so monte carlo
concert risky game
actually the game is going to be that that we have this negative result
and it you have to do that the conditions some all you have to change
the problem otherwise value there is no chance of a full forthcoming coming this by
them right so the first thing that we are trying to do is that we
say that
well maybe it's enough computing of a function just forget about the phi functions
just come up with good actions
that will be the next thing that that we try to do
and so these given was proposed by
currents and his colleagues in two thousand two
i guess this newspaper
so the idea is is very very simple and it's classic so if if you
forget about all the stochastic stop
and you face the planning problem one the
european the search tree right
two latin each and you have to choose a good action so classically it would
so you've given state
and you want to choose a good action
but you don't know what the action is so you try all of them
if you look at that lead
and from those states
what do you do you have to try these actions until you get to the
or until in this case we are considering this content problems
and so it turns out that if you do this this content just think about
it like
so we had this discounted sum
some forgot to the prior p times the rewards if the rewards are bonded
i can try this summer
after a certain number of turns right
i want change the values too much
why because the tail
if i start to some from capital t to infinity
and this guy said bonded let's say by one
in absolute value
then this whole thing is going to be
born the
by going on to the part of captain that he right so i can just
put it out
otherwise this semantics some sounds to one over one minus common for this whole thing
is only by
government to the power of that if i start to some after cavity
five just
for about
and missing after
a certain amount of time
because this is going to be a very small number so if i want to
compare the values
so we want to compute the values of the actions if you want to compare
compare the values of two actions
you don't have to build this free after infinity
so you can stop after a lot
so you don't need a superposition so just want to come up with a good
enough action
and so this is the the
effective for rice and so this is
if you are shooting at selection accuracy that and k i is born and the
today i'm going to be following up on the lectures on graphical models just to
recap what we did last time i comfort
the basics of
factor graphs undirected graphs and directed graphs what they are how they represent conditional independence
and then i talked about
inference algorithms
namely belief propagation factor graph propagation and a little bit
about the junction tree algorithm elimination other ways of doing inference
today we're going to do is we're going to be talking about
graphs from data
in particular in the talk first about learning the parameters of the graph from data
and then we're going to be talking about learning the structure of a graph from
data and they're all
in the second half of give you a little bit more of a
sort of research flavor question in graphical models and try to relate it to other
lecturers at the summer school
so you can hopefully see relationships between a lot of these different topics
so let's just dive right in
to learning the parameters of a graph from data
and let's start out with directed graphical models like this graph here
i'll talk about undirected graphical models later undirected graphs are harder in some way so
i leave that for later
so here's the a directed graph over four variables and it corresponds to the following
factorisation of the joint distribution over these four variables and this should by now be
incredibly familiar to you because most electors have used this kind of thing
so what do i mean by the parameters of this model
so let's look at this graph in this factors station
it doesn't
define the probability distribution over these variables just to say that there are factored in
this way right we need to actually
consider each of these terms and define
of what that term actually is how would you implement something that would generate values
x two given values of x one
and for simplicity i'm going to start out by talking about discrete variables
so assume that each variable
x is discrete and can take on k i values so we don't need to
all take the same number of values
for example
in particular let's look at one of the variables
next to it depends on x one
so there are some parameter that relates x two to x one
if x one is a binary variable x two can take on
three values
then the relationship between x one and x two is given by this to by
three table
and i
rows of the table represent
possible values of x two given x one
and because this is the probability distribution over x two given
the value of x one
these rows sum to one
OK everybody happy with that
it's just an example of a particular case here in general the parameters of this
it can be represented as four tables
one for each variable given its parents
they one is the table four x one given its parents well x one doesn't
have any parents north and something so
it has only k one
entries it's one by k one table
they did two has k one by k two entries et cetera
and these tables are called conditional probability tables
and they have the following semantics
theta one k
for this valuable here
is the probability that x one takes on the value k
more generally
we have a variable given its parents
theta two
OK OK prime
it is the probability that x who takes on the value k prime
given that x one its parent took on the value k
all right this is all very straightforward so i just want to lay out the
semantics make sure everybody is happy to ask me questions for sure
if you're not happy
now this this is a nice simple picture but imagine
we had a variable
it had more than one parent so let's it had two parents
for example
if the node has m parents then there are two ways of representing the conditional
probability tables and they're completely equivalent
one of them is to say that table is represented by an employee's one-dimensional table
one for each of the parents one of those images for each of the parents
and no obviously one dimension for the child and it's over the child mention the
things that the sum to one
so in an impulse one-dimensional table
something that we could do is we could collapse
all the possible states of the parents into one sort of superstate
and just represent things as a two dimensional table
r where the number of super states of all the parents is just the product
over all the parents of the number of possible states that that parents can take
so obviously set of three by three by three table we can represented as in
nine by treatable
OK that's going to be
because then
the number of indices we have on these matrices is it can be variable so
you know our life with just get annoying if we have to have a variable
the fact that
don't know how much
i have not seen
that's line
at the show
and for completion
the thing to do
it's actually from
i'm not sure
i thought
thank you for us
the time
so the question
i ran
i don't
it's a
so that was
so to clarify
that change
and the
i mean that's
you can
so what
that's a very fine
project which i think it's time
in fact
the row space what's in that
it's all combinations of the road
that's natural
we wanna space so we have to take all combinations and we start with the
rows so the roses
spans the rose
on the road the basis for the row space
maybe so maybe not
the rows are a basis for the row space when they're independent but if they're
dependent as in the
my area from last time
they're not those 3 rows are not a basis the row space would would only
be two-dimensional I only need to rose from bases so the row space now what's
it's all combinations of the rows and then
combinations of the rows of X
but I don't like working with row vectors all my vectors have been column vectors
I'd like to stay with column vectors
how can I get a column vectors
out of these rows I transpose the matrix
so if that's OK with you I'm going to transpose the matrix and I'm going
to say all
of the
the follows
a big transport
and that allows me
the you is the convenient notation
the column space of a transpose
nothing you know mathematics went on there we just got some
vectors that were lying down the standard
it means that we can use the column space of A transpose that's telling me
in a nice matrix notation
what the row space
OK and finally
is another null space
the 4th vector the for fundamental space will be
the null space of A transpose before the sky is the null space
of a Trent and of course my notation is the end of a transfer
that's the null space of A transpose
there we don't have a perfect name
for this space as us as a connecting with a
but our usual name is the left null space and I'll show you why in
so often I call this the
just write that were the left null space
so this way we have the row space of a and we switch it to
the column space of A transpose
so we have this space of
guys that I call left null space of A but the good notation is it's
the null space of A transpose OK those therefore space
where are space
what what big space so they can work
when a is there might
in that case the null space of
what's in the null space of A vectors within component
solutions to a x equals 0 so the null space of A is N. R.
within the column space of well columns
how many components of those columns has
so this column space is inputs
and M
what about the column space of A transpose which are adjusted disguised way of saying the rows of
range here's one this is amplitude versus time
and the second one in phase
so i'm going to drive directly beneath
and so the crests line up the troughs lineup so if i take great one
plus rate two
i'm going to add them and i'll get
the additive sum of amplitudes
because are in phase
so this is called
in phase
radiation something or the other term applied to this is constructive interference
that's the one extreme to the other extreme is
totally out of phase so in that case re one of draws i did before
but rate two
all draw
symmetrically opposite
so that in re two
the crest of re to align with the trough of re one
the trough of great to align with the crest of re one and for argument's
sake let's say that these are equal in amplitude so if i have to
raise equal in amplitude and they interfere with the perfectly out of phase
if i had these two signals what i will get is
they will cancel
complete cancellation
so this is called
d struck interference
destructive interference
and those are the only two principles we need
and we can describe
and very
a reasonable level what's going on inside
which is being irradiated by
electromagnetic radiation in the x region of the spectrum is on the uses these two
so let's not go to a simple
model here of
world rawson here
there's the talk
let's go down to second
make this cubic
so here's two planes of atoms
and let's say i've got incident light coming in at some angle
here's some incident light coming in at some angle theta
so one re i'm showing striking this at
and if i observe the laws of specular reflection this will reflect from the mayor
at the identical angle
so the angle of reflection equals the angle of incidence and let's put a secondary
school to secondary coming down here
and it to world reflecting the same
angle and come out like so
others self on somebody's leaving the room
let's go
i want the cell phones off no compromises
charles respect for classmates
this route
disrespectful to me it's disrespectful to the class
don't get
that happens on wednesday i'll tear your paper in front of your eyes and give
you a zero
mark my words
i want to look at what happens when i have light coming in
at a particular angle and furthermore i want to specify that i have are in
phase radiation in space radiation which is also termed coherence so i have in face
incident coherent radiation and furthermore i wanna monochromatic
monochromatic so these are x-rays that are coherent and monochromatic monochromatic means
a single wavelength a single waverly
so here's the incident radiation on the left
this is the incident radiation on the left and this is the reflected radiation on
the right
and what do i want to see here i want to see what are the
conditions to give me constructive interference
because i don't want destructive interference for destructive interference i will see anything
let's mark this by showing some kind of away form do is show
just the first sign so i
i'll show the first signs site and then i'll show the same
on the second ray so to indicate is that i have in phase radiation coming
down from the left
and then over here i want to indicate that i have in phase radiation leaving
so again all indicate the sinusoids in the same
there's an issue here
you can see
re one
travels a shorter distance
then ray to re two has to go farther
so i can actually calculate how far that is if i drop and normal
from here
normal from here
i can label this a
and c
we can see that rate two
as the travel far distances a-b BC
what's the condition of a plus b c
to ensure that these two
are in phase
they must equal
some path length that is a whole number of wavelengths otherwise i'll get some amount
destructive interference
and and of course is a whole number i don't care one two and so
on and actually we can call this is the order of the reflection
this is the order of the reflection
and if i go through the math we know what theta is what's this distance
between successive planes if i'm showing you
adjacent hkl planes then this distance here is the
as we defined it before this is the distance between adjacent hkl planes and if
i go through the trigonometry here and lambda will equal two times d
so i
of the two
got the angle theta we know the distance between successive planes if n lambda equal
all right last time we talk exclusively about
completely inelastic collisions
today i will talk about
collisions in more
let's take a one-dimensional case
we have here
and two
to make life a little easier to to make the two zero
and this
has velocity v one
after the collision
and two
a velocity
the two prime
and what
that have a velocity
he one prime
i don't even know what changes direction
one it is in that direction
you was see that you one is possible
to find the one prime and to find
the two prime it's clear that you're no need to equations
and if
there is no net external force
on the system as a whole
during the collisions then
momentum is conserved
so you can write down
the one
must be
and one
he one prime
two prime
now you may want to put errors over there to indicate that these vectors but
since is a one-dimensional case you can leave the errors off
and the signs will then automatically take care of the direction if you call this
then if you get a minus sign
you know
the velocities in the opposite direction
for now
the the second equation
nine physics
we do believe very strongly
conservation of energy
not necessarily in the conservation of kinetic energy actually have seen last time you can
destroy kinetic energy
but somehow we believe that if you destroy energy it must come out in some
other form
you cannot create energy out of nothing
and in the case of the completely inelastic collisions that we've seen last time
we lost kinetic energy which was converted to heat
there was internal friction when the carrack ploughed into each other labels internal friction no
external friction and that took out kinetic energy
and so
its most general form
you can write down
that the kinetic energy before
some number q
the kinetic energy after the collision and if you know q
then you have the second equation
and then you can solve for v one prime
and for two prime
q is larger than zero
then you can gain kinetic energy that is possible we did that last time
we had
two cars which were connected by his points
and we going to wire
and each went off in the opposite direction there was no kinetic energy before if
you want to call it the collision but there was kinetic energy afterwards that was
the potential energy of the spring that was converted into kinetic energy so q can
be larger than zero
we call that a superb
elastic collision
could be an explosion
that's a super elastic collision
and then there is the possibility
equals zero very special case we will deal with that today
and we call that
elastic collisions
i will often call it a completely elastic collision which is really not necessary elastic
itself already means q is zero
and then there is a case of which we have seen
several examples last time
of inelastic collisions when you lose kinetic energy
so this is an
the last condition
and so if you know that q is
then you
can solve these equations
whenever q is less than zero whenever you lose kinetic energy
the loss in general goes into
now i want to
continuing case whereby completely
elastic collision
so q is zero
momentum is conserved because there was no net external force
so now kinetic energy is also conserved
so i can write down now
one half
and one
the ones created was the kinetic energy before the collision
must be
the kinetic energy
after the collision one half and one
the one primes career plus one half
prior square
this is my creation number one
and this is my creation of number the two
and they can be solved you can solve them their souls in your book i
will simply give you the results because the results are very interesting to play we
thought we would be doing today
three one prime
will be
and one minus two
divided by and one
plus and two
time times
v one
and the two prime
will be two and one
divided by and one class and two
fifty one
the first thing that you already right away
that the two prime is always in the same direction as the one that's completely
the second object was standing still remember
so if you plough something into the second object they obviously continue in that direction
that's clear
so you see you can never have assigned reversal here
he however you can have assigned we first
if you want the ping-pong ball for billions all the ping-pong ball will come back
and this one becomes negative
whereas if you plough believable into a ping-pong ball it will go forward and so
this can both be negative and can be positive
depending upon whether the upstairs is negative or positive
so this is the result
which holds on three conditions
the kinetic energy is conserved so q is zero
that momentum is conserved and
that the two before the collision
equals zero
let's look at three interesting
cases whereby we go to extremes
let's first take the case
and one is much much larger than n two
and one is much much larger
then and two
another way of thinking about that is that that
extreme case the limiting case
so it's like having a bowling ball
that you
collide was ping pong ball
if you look at that equation
when and two goes to zero
this is zero this is zero
notice that v one prime
equals VY
that is completely intuitive
if the bowling ball collides with the ping-pong ball the building wasn't even see the
ping-pong ball it continues its role as if nothing happened
that's exactly what you see
after the collision
is an implemented in the lab and in things like this and in
we tried different from in FSL
with the e we wanted to to and makes it into independent time courses
and the fmri just into independent maps with associated time courses so we doing temporal
ICA here and spatial there
we can do that either separately or all together
this just we do that separately then we can do it on single trial level
with fmri that this has been presented in the previous talk is what you what
you do and if you makes the time series by voxels into
maps by time courses
indeed you get time courses by special topographies with a single file weights within them
i tend to
if you're my own bias with the data that i'm working with so
what i wanted to do is to do the whole thing for the whole population
at once
i really like to push just one but not many buttons
because it simplifies detection of group independent components
you get a single set of i sees the distant that projected into this into
the individual data and they get back to that
there's no additional clustering
i mean what what you can do is to individual ICA's on your easy or
data and then have some kind of clustering idea and start clustering
there is
an additional complexity in that clustering algorithm choice of closer to detect or when you
do that visually there is bias
so how do you treat that in your
group inference later
that's the that's difficult thing for me
it on all it's easier to keep track of things you already dealing with two
very big things
to make that
and you have twenty subjects twenty fold
problem is probably unnecessary for me i don't have these big computers very small computers
the idea that this is a line in in two papers that in the special
in international journal of psychophysiology preprints if you will if you want i can send
them you
right after the talk
so let's put that into the graphic again
well we want to do is the group ICA of the data
not just use ICA for architecture it could correction and then get back to you
i want to do
group ICA this step
get the canonical components within our population see whether that correlates with
the group i my data
that idea has been around since two thousand one with windscale came out with his
group inference for functional neuroimaging toolbox that's the action from gift can also called just
called give al
and we can do that as i said pele or in joint just squeeze them
together into one big space
and then we can do an additional trick which is to start off with the
group ICA for the fmri
take the
time series here from the independent components and deconvolved
deconvolve the traffic out of this time course and then use the HRF estimate to
get back to the parametric modulation of single trials
ideally before the convolution happened
that's been going if you're doing SPM analysis or
DNA analysis you going the whole thing backwards
you start out with the result in the go back to the primitive modulation
which makes sense if you want to predict the EEG with many sources in the
from right rather than predict fmri with sources from the easy
depends a bit on how you
one thing it work
first off we did simulation just check whether or or not
the group ICA
i think that's
i'm getting to that but basically the the description was given by the court
in the previous talk
i'm getting better
so we're doing this saying this ICA will explain why it right away
we put sources
which sources is are defined as
time courses over trials
spatial distributions
e responses and EEG topography is
in one big bucket or secondly if you will
and we mix them together
and on a single trial you don't see anything of the sort which he
some blogs and some noise here you could physiological noise onto this mixture
and some some technical noise some some gaussian noise and all kinds of things that
we could think of our existing in real data and then we just use this
group implementations
to get back to the sources
well we don't catch is easy fast transients
whether or not these are very relevant for event related potentials is a different question
so basically just saying that this whole framework technically looks OK
this is the group ICA works
you basically
starts at this point we have some kind of event related
that makes it easier to get your head around it which is then implemented in
sub in subjects basically which have consistent or relatively consistent activation maps and time courses
which are then mixed by
individual mixing mattresses
the the signal that you with the tag
so that you would require
in the from my side in new volumes and on the aegean there in a
single trials with then do is
typical preprocessing of
from my data for group study so we
put the brains the individual brains into a common space we feel that we normalize
we smooth
and the easy part we doing artifact reduction with with individual ICA some powerful drain
and parking
then we can do is to group the grouping step then we concatenate
these these data after we reduce the so we take the
the fmri
images by
by time points and you reduce it with the PCA two
over the temporal dimension
so we defined we define graphical models now what i'm going to talk about his
inference and propagation algorithms
so this is going to be
probably a bit heavy
four lecture but you know
i just want to cover the main inference and propagation algorithms
so the you
at the moment in the slide
let's think about the problem of inferring consider the following
directed graph which represents this factorisation of the joint probability over the five variables
the inference problem i'm going to think about
as the problem of evaluating the probability distribution over some set of variables
given the values of another set of variables
while something out integrating all the variables that are not interesting to us
so for example we have a graphical model which is an expert system of some
big nuclear power plant with ten thousand variables
we observe a whole bunch of readings of different sensors that we might have one
big variable in the middle
of the graph that represents the probability that we're having
meltdown of the core
and we might want to run our inference algorithm every once in awhile to to
check with the idea that is
how do we compute
let's consider for example how do we compute the probability of
the variable age
given that we observe the value of the variable c
so imagine for now that the variables are binary
and let's just naively tried to compute that so
we want to compute the probability of a given c
so let's start out by computing the probability of a and c taking on the
value the
well the graph has a total of five variables
we have to the variables here to compute that we take the joint distribution and
we sum over all settings of the the other three variables
OK so that
eight summations
because this is two times two times two but we have to do that for
each of the two possible values of the variable a is well so that the
total of sixteen operations
now to complete the denominator that we want to compute the probability that takes on
the values c so we take this every summer over the two values of a
that's another two operations and then for each of the two values of a we
divide up
this guy by that guy and that's another two operations so we managed to compute
everything in twenty operations which isn't bad or five variables but it gets really horrendous
summing over all the variables here
when you have n binary variables would involve summing over
two to the end possible configurations of all the variables so essentially what we're trying
to do is we're trying to do inference which we can do simply by enumeration
we're trying to do it efficiently
the key idea
so here's the slightly more efficient method
we can take that joint probability distribution and that's on and we can take some
of the terms in the farm
so for example the some of the variable e well all these guys
don't depend on the
only this guy depends on the ability to think that the mission over the all
the way up here and then later notice that the probability
the other variable when we sum over all values equals one
and this gets eliminated that gets eliminated and if we did
things a little more cleverly
we could do
the first step in for operations that sixteen so this is just another toy example
just to make you think about the fact that the order in which you do
the operations and using the conditional independence relationships can save you a lot of applications
so what i'll talk about in this lecture our belief propagation methods
and these methods use the conditional independence relationships in the graph to do efficient inference
and for graphs which are singly connected which i'm about to define
we can get exponential gains in efficiency over the naive method
so let's talk about belief propagation in singly connected undirected graph
so directed exactly graph is singly connected if its underlying undirected graph is a tree
another way to think about that is
if there's only one
i have between any two nodes
so the graph on this side is singly connected
because they can know there's only one
have between this graph is not fully connected
so we incorporate this in the objective function and then we have
usual magic and it can be very easy to see
but this means that
we are
we start the above the origin
we start from some way
w t minus one
and then we have some
some x being
on which we don't actually have a large enough margin
OK i suppose that x the for for simplicity
if x is a unit normal
but now
we want we want to achieve the margin of
a one of the next to the origin
so now we take the perpendicular here
and we make the projection
which is
the meaning of this
of that and one on two
which defines the basis of the solution
but the solution
that achievement in exactly one
on the
on the example
so we predict that the here
and this projection is our
we predict that the human mind to protect our new updated weight
so we have a single linear constraint passed solution we project our solution onto the
single that drink
and we obtain the neuron
the one
very simple and we very
four so it's easy
we can run these diagram and these are great is
so is the version of
they have additional properties
of course
of course i mean
here we are making and very aggressive update that
our mining more
in the same way
like variable to the SVM objective function in order to what counts the
four datasets that are not linearly separable
we might want in this set up
two and a similar feature
well boy the that in the case of a stream of these highly non notable
these are just too much aggressive updates
are going through
because of them
so we learn that we see in a moment the variance of the updated take
into account the
the if you introduce slack variables for out
is texting kidding amount equal to one the next or the next example
and the
closeness the possible
so we use the slack variables for exactly balance things that you know that could
be better within with nonseparable streams and then we'll see how to analyse
this is the other up
first of all
we see
combination of things in between so if you want you can condition on certain evidence
variables and then you can get the posterior over some query node given the evidence
or you can just use it to compute the marginal
other big distribution
so if i give you a joint distribution for that
evidence i just give you a joint distribution
over several random variables
and i ask you what is the original
p x twelve flights
so that's a perfectly valid question it doesn't involve observing evidence
but it's just a question about this joint distribution and elimination algorithm can be used
to answer that question what do we do we just don't introduce any evidence potentials
we just some of everything except x twelve OK
so i think of elimination is just a way of trying to some efficiently variables
except our single query variable which we want to be left with the and
so there are some tricks that we can use to save some time elimination in
directed models
we can ignore
any nodes that are downstream of the
query node
and do not contain any evidence
so if you have a a graphical model
that has some structure like this
and let's say this number is observed
and this node is observed and this is the query node here that we're trying
to gather information about
so these nodes down here
in the aftermath model the any effect
because there's no evidence there and not part of the query system so we know
that if we sum the just going to contribute eventually factor of unity
so we can save myself some work rather than
laboriously doing the sums only to find out that they come to one we can
just erase them structurally from the graphical model at the very beginning and we can
do inference on everything that's left
so it's only a few observe some evidence or if you're part of the query
that you're going to affect the model otherwise we can just train the graphical model
from the leaves back towards the query and evidence nodes so this is actually the
model we would run the elimination algorithm on would introduce evidence potentials for these two
and then some
these three notes we would get some function over this renormalized and that would be
the answer
so this is just the idea that
if we know that this sum is is supposed to be unity then
we shouldn't do it and i would just like to point out you can use
this trick in undirected models because there's this partition function and you don't know
how that set of nodes will contribute to the partition function the normalizer and so
we cannot we can't get away with that
and there
let me just go a little bit more into the details of this of this
algorithm but always keep in mind
this equation which is really the crux of what we're doing right we're trying to
efficiently so
over joint settings of these variables by
taking advantage of the distributive property and pushing the sums as far into the product
as we can
so the nomination is really just a sort of graphical algorithm you can think of
it as a graphical algorithm that takes each node in the graph does an operation
which allows you to remove it and because of that operation it might introduce new
edges in the graph
OK so i'm going to try to convince you that by just looking at the
simple explaining away example
that we had before so imagine you had a
let me just to raise this
i intentionally kept in reserve over here and somehow all three of them are bacteria
so imagine you had a graphical model
that looks like this
now if we observe this note
we know explaining away that once you observe these nodes are
distributions over these two students become coupled
so i think this is a graph algorithm in which you start with a graphical
model and you need to know to get the new graphical model human node in
each stage of the graphical model which represents the belief about what's left
then we kind of know once we say that this notion
there has to be some coupling between these two notes here
we have to introduce some dependency on these two nodes which indicates that because of
explaining away in fact we we
i have some
correlation our beliefs so there no indication algorithm
the operation which removes each node from the graph but that might introduce new edges
into the graph
so more precisely what happens is for each node in the ordering that we pick
you connect the neighbors of x y and then you remove exiled from the graph
which algebraically corresponds to something in
use that one
the police arrive can give all the information about the noise and then you can
figure out the mystery observation up to time t
and then the police can
figure out what
the probable
position for each the burglar at each time step
all the police can do is also to compute the most likely path
the most likely sequence of positions
for each time step which is what i show in there
in the fourth line here
then again maybe i effect i'm sure there will be the
in this case is seeking work quite well
it depends a lot on the problem there are cases in which my work
that's why
i give you know another example of modelling with an item
suppose that we have established thing
stipe is that as the tendency to
it the core of key on a all neighbouring key on the keyboard
and based on the type of secrecy one thing for that
what is the most likely war
this sequence correspond to
and again we can represent that would be the marker modelling which is the
is the intent electorate
at time t
represent the letter that was actually type at time t
as the transition before
the the bible we can use just on studies of mathematics of the of the
english language so probably don't see that about
for example
is very highly probable that
the letter you will follow the letter q and what has indicated here
like all of
and you also
i assume that
typist will probably type d
according to p
with high probability as well
he show
but the is the probability that the word types some of the
the key in the wiki
so again you can do
a kind of there b
according to and
given that the type is type with this
sequence here what is the most likely wore this correspond to what you can use
the more set the most likely than sequences
using said kind of terrorism and disregard the will those that don't correspond to the
sentence in the english dictionary and then take the most proper english war as has
the same
and anybody can tell what the answer can be
who said let me
OK so i still have
o thing twenty minutes or
so so far i have described
several types of graphical models and how to do inference with that
how to understand independence but i have always assumed that
we knew the table entries in our distribution so
for example
in the case of the action man i assume that i knew the
that we knew the transition emissions
probability now i want to discuss the little bit
OWL two to less stable and and therefore suppose that we have a model of
random variable x
the pair which depends on the
unknown parameters theta
and from the set of observation i want
for something about sitcom
well i guess you assume that these observations are independent the identically distributed according to
this model
and the forty second season of the joint distribution of all our
observation given
but i think that i can
right it does the product of simple groups
and they can also
introduce the prior distribution of prior preference of mine
for me to see
and then as with bayes rule as we have seen i can infer the posterior
of theta
he's given my observations
and i can view this as an extension of i believe that to simply considering
an additional note my belief that which has lead to all the observations
and you can also use more confrontation during which
i have just
one statue the giving from p two
one the site and they have played
i think that indicated that the addition of the same structure
and balance
if you want to summarize the our posterior to very popular way of doing it
is the maximum of posterior in metal
which simply compute the model
of the posterior
all the maximum likelihood method and you talk a lot about yesterday
it wouldn't start running on your data sets
they have been generalized to capture correlations new topics coming in all dumping going away
they have been applied to other types of classification problems
just you know when to apply naive bayes
they have been applied to build cluster ensemble something so that's art
and of late if you look at the machine learning literature there's quite a bit of discussion on nonparametric priors
so i didn't get into what kinds of graphs are maintained or what is mixed memberships
usually these additional distribution is the most basic one like people are sort of
the beginning of the nonparametric statistics literature from the seventies and eighties
leg usually processes and pitman yor processes and so on and somehow they making this
work they are they are being used in
you know image segmentation computer vision application text analysis applications computational biology applications it's a very rich class of models
and being used in many many domains i just showed you an example of text and that's okay
so so so the last problem discussed in the context of graphical models
the canonical recommendation system problem
right and again in this problem graphical models have been just very very successful
this is the netflix amazon problem right here's a bunch of movies my interviews and
they have created a bunch of things and then but most of this matrix is
empty and you're trying to fill out the matrix are trying to predict how weather
sort of somebody lights
a particular movie are not may have some information about the movie are the user
now it turns out that this problem of course shows up in a recommendation system e-commerce
it also forms the basis of many other problems so this is how to advertise
this advertisments on the web so these are the web pages and these are advertisments
and u measuring five
advertisment for this particular product on this web page
how many people click on back and based on the idea of trying to guess
where are actually places that's right so so that was more people click on it
and we make more money
and again you will have some side-information
the problem i am particularly walking on is actually a problem in forest ecology so
we have
i'm working on some of the largest database of
plant information that has been put together color try deep you can take it out it is the single largest
information on plants that has ever been put together and working with studied and peter
record what are excellent bicycle ideas
this has information about six thousand species millions of observations individuals
and fragmentary observations like leaf nitrogen content phosphorylated specifically very early size and so on and so forth
about opposing traits
when somebody went into the tree and started measuring
they not measure our house and thinks it's just not possible right so so so this matrix is mostly empty
and then we are trying to fill it out to sea
what happens in just a sense of
you know only nitrogen i'm just saying that i have information and some other plants
if you actually want to know where the plants this is about those plants right
we know there are more and more trees
in on the planet right so we say we going to try to fill out
the rest of the trees are and this is sort of the british and we
have in terms of what we have and we have something like this for each
very ambitious and just starting off but i'm going to show you glimpse of sort
of the method some other methods we have
which have been successful in
netflix recommendations system by problems we are not trying to take it to a more scientific problem
which is you know this this particular are probably forced like okay
a very brief overview
so matrix factorization forms the backbone of this class of methods
right matrix factorization has been around for a while
we can take the ratings matrix and somehow ignored the missing values and try to
come up with a single value decomposition
the problem with this is that if you know the size of some of these metrices
there there are probably ten million by
one hundred thousand matrix right if you're trying to do and is really
on matlab from the best to you because it's not going to finish
right so
so ideally we would like to do something like
it's just it's just not possible to do it
given the size of this matrix and also the fact that many of them are actually missing so
what people came up it and this was sort of partly
rejuvenated during the netflix challenge and many of these methods actually were shown to work
pretty well during the netflix challenge
and this is one of those methods
by slow then reverse publishing two thousand nine
so they came up with a graphical model for doing this
right and this is the graphical model
now isomap is something different why some what you can think of is think every data point you have
has being a city
in a high dimensional space
then build roads
for each of those data points to its neighboring cities so you define a neighborhood some way
okay nearest neighbours is very common
so you say
if i look at the
seven nearest neighbours i connect them by roads straight roads like the romans yeah
so roman roads between all these neighbouring cities
and then
you say
let me compute the road distance between every city
june now data points
and compute distance matrix from a really elegant simple idea
well because
you can't go between on neighbours directly you have to travel along the straight roads
between the different cities right
now that's an approximation for sort of manifold distance so
you should never
do anything on the swiss roll by the way this is just an illustration
the swiss roll is not a real data set
no one ever comes u with a thousand data points in three dimensions and says
please reduce the dimensionality of this data
it's extremely unrealistic
i don't blame them for publishing this in the first place illustrative example but we
used to be something called is all problem
you had is all problem not interesting one person's heard this or problem
but there's all proper with like a classification problem in machine learning in which the
uh all the all the gents will remember very well which is that like
let's see i probably can't even do it right
so this is like is all
and the point is you can't linearly separate
no linear classifier will give you the right answer
challenging isn't it
now someone uses the problems to illustrate the issue with linear classifiers yeah
and then it became like every paper had to show how the non linear classifiers solves all problems
it was never a serious problem with an illustration of a point which is a valid point illustrate
that's the same with the swiss roll
it's not a massive it's funny in if you go into like applied pure mass talks
they'll say and now we're gonna go to an application of this
spectral stop which is this important swiss roll
the machine learning is very much study because people need to unravel it
it's not a real dataset and actually unless you're doing something you wanna show something
like that when you get holes in it some aspects illustrative effect which is also
been useful fine but
please try and do the
the dimensionality reduction on real data
and you know i almost switch i don't even read the section on swiss roll but it's useful
for the first papers that use which was twelve years ago so it's like this
or problem is useful and we use the teacher about all problem as well when
we talk about classification and it's still useful as a concept you know that it's
a nonlinear manifold you can see it's two dimensional and is useful for showing this
idea in the cities the road network connecting all these cities which are the data
points together and what you're really interested in is the distance
along this plane you
so that's why the distance along the surface if you that you are interested in
when you drive around europe all over the mountains
that's what you are interested in you can't quite computer see approximated by
these roads connecting all the data points together now even in this very well samples
manifold is extremely well sample considers in three dimensions and there's a bunch of data
here look at the big holes appear in
the road network back and have some fun effects but this is i mean this i think my favourite
a the spectral dimensionality reduction methods because it's so simple and it works it works quite nicely so
just to illustrate what goes on what can go wrong in
so construct nearest neighbors for each data point so here is a manifold i generated
are used a gaussian process a generator it hopefully you can see what's shape is
even though it's three
is in sort of instituting manifold living in three so some species like this
because i generated in the latent space i know the neighborhood in the latent space so i can draw it
and that's really what you're interested so you wanna know the distance between these two
point but we're not allowing more than four neighbours so the approximation to this is
to go along this neighbours neighbours neighbours this state yeah
very nice and you can compute
and there's these funky algorithms floyds and something else for computing these things fast
relatively fast rate and you get the distance between these two guys and you do classical multidimensional scaling
so that's works really well
well there
this is because the
the company
the group
first of all let me thank you very much for this opportunity
a couple of things i'd like to clarify just as we will along i have
been in this business for quite a long time and not around and specialist but
being kind of talk for a long time that it's important i find to the
start to this will be a very informal
so i want to keep the informal
most of you
english is certainly at at least your second language is not perhaps even years unforced
i don't even speak english i a natural scott
so i may have
very slight accent
if you have any difficulty with anything i say
and if i get excited i tend to speak a little bit quickly
stop me and ask me questions
again as we're going through if something that comes up and you want to ask
a few questions stop we and ask will try keep the the questioning as we
go through short because of what of time potentially at the end to cover
professor jesse said i would like to cover
applications initially a little bit of chatter about reddish equipment we are
and then go to some applications with the AFM with some tears applications mainly using
basically in nano field because it come into the nano field and some stuff on
scanning electron microscopy have loads and loads and loads of material
but we don't have
we have limited time so i to take questions
as i say stop me and ask
o i thing
what is very brief cover what is roman
it is important to realize that rahman is not new technique from is a very
very old technique
i only really in the past twenty years the roman has become much much more
a user technique
this is because of the advent of lasers and computers and CCD chips which is
allowed the the actor collection of perspective difficult
i spent a lot of time in india so this slide is a well known
CV raman did the work in original in nineteen twenty eight
and you know that long time ago
the spectrometer the he used in his actually still working i original spectrometer and at
the moment six of them and they actually all
still function
ramon still goes on
i think quickly light scattering technique impinge on the sample
light scatters off
and this is the important part
place less than one part in ten million
is romany
so getting that right out from the laser light
actually the difficult part
traditionally this was done using diffraction gratings and you lost more signals
when you actually had
with the advent of a holographic not filters about fifteen twenty years ago
things improved dramatically not so much in the fact that the the raman was better
but the ability to collect farming was actually simpler
and it took a lot of the expertise
i emphasise the idea of using raman instruments like drum to be used by multiple
users rather than optical physicist and that's that's a good way to go
why obama
first though
it is extremely sensitive
i think amphetamine and methamphetamine very
very closely associated chemical the roman data
it is phenomenally difference each region in the CCD imaging and in the fingerprint raman
region which is around here
roman typically any
change in the chemical stock took a toll crystalline with this additional waste material you
will get change in raman spectra simple idea if something goes from a high data
to him high then you will get
a change in the raman spectrum
and these are very subtle changes
the problem is that people find is that the the automatically assume but we can
do all this with FTIR
a lot of can
but with one
you can do it in more samples
you can do everything from what weight samples are going to be looking at
moist materials reaction vessels this type of thing high-pressure sales these types of things from
and can run in work
so here but i think it's important to see the difference
and the chemical structures
is very very obvious
and in roman data
so the highly sensitive things
that's where we are now
one extra multiplication
compute the inner product by this in in a very high dimensional space
so in that example of the
of the
two images around six hundred pixels
rather than computing at one hundred eighty thousand dimensional vector and another one hundred eighty
thousand dimensional vector and multiplying into the components together and something
we actually take a six hundred dimensional vector not most by the corresponding entry in
the other six hundred dimensional vector sum them up
and one extra operation which is square the result
so this is clearly a being shortcut no really serious shortcuts and effectively we can
apply this algorithm
as i said you know these all you have to do is
completely inappropriate here and square
all the sorry the inner product in the input space and square and you've got
entries in this optimisation problem you solve it you've got the alphas and i want
to evaluate a new point you can do the same thing
using this evaluation here competing approach in input space and square some with the corresponding
alpha rise
and you have draw
OK so
so that that's just what i've said
he competed at six hundred dimensional inner product and then square the result
you can even work in infinite dimensional space in fact because this kernel here
it corresponds to an infinite dimensional space so you can
with this finite computation
finite optimisation problem you actually are working in infinite dimensional space
here is very strange feeling
you might say well OK
i i can think of lots of functions that will be nice and you know
it's kind of functions
effectively all i need to do is find some way of comparing two inputs
you know that would be a potential kernel function
there is a restriction however the
arises from
the assumption that the
the kernel function does correspond to an inner product in some feature space and they
corresponds to if we take in general
some of this type will be to being any
real valued
and he realizes here
we can write the following
substitute the kernel function for the
in the product that is and then bring these
beta inside the inner product and we end up with a norm here because this
is just the son peter i five a sign that the same values and this
is just the norm squared of this vector and so must be because they are
equal to zero
so this
is known as the positive semi definite property
if you think of this as the matrix
then this is the
shows this matrix has nonnegative eigen values
again i don't want to go into any details but this is the restriction
that must hold for any training set
but this is the only restriction i mean it provided a kernel function satisfies this
and obviously symmetric you know so you should if you swap components shouldn't change value
it is
a kernel function in the sense that it corresponds to some projection into a feature
so now
rather than having to worry about feature spaces and defining feature spaces
we have to worry about kernels defining ways of comparing factors i would argue that
actually isn't it might sound like a worse situation but i think actually it's
often easier to get somebody with domain expertise to talk about how to compare two
get to suggest some feature representations
it's not always the case you there are sometimes natural feature representations that arise and
again we may be able to use them to define kernels
but but quite frequently you know a domain expert knows about his data those when
two things are similar
but may not know what features of those things make them similar or dissimilar
so it's
but certainly in applying this approach
you know defining the kernel function is going to be a critical component
in the rollout out of the technology
so what have we achieved
we can replace the problem of neural network architectures by kernel definition so whereas in
the neural network
UB be saying OK got to you know choose an architecture choose how many hidden
nodes or whatever it is
we've now
arrived the situation where our problem is to define a kernel function
as i have suggested that possibly arguably more natural
but the restriction that i described on that function is natural in this sort of
positivity positive semi definite restriction is a bit weird
so you know some researchers looked at
trying to get around that are not required positive semidefiniteness
it's certainly not a silver bullet because
you know as with any learning as i suggested you know it's important to get
fit with the data you know if you
if you have a problem
and you just roll out your favourite kernel maybe there is to fit between the
problem that kernel
so you may have to design the cover for the problem particularly if you have
you know more unusual type of data
but the other sort of nice property that we're somehow manage to arrive at without
really intending to is this
the property here
you know typically linear learning can only be applied if you have a vector representation
of your data i mean that's exactly what a linear function is a linear weighting
of those different
one of the feature vector
but now
however i the situation where we can potentially define kernel
for non vectorial data so we might have a no strings or graph for
in know some complex data structure
all we have to do is to define a function that takes two objects of
this type
somehow compares them and arrived with a single number
and that satisfies the property that i described
and we can apply
linear learning machines on that data
so suddenly sort of open up the potential of
have done or or or or bought as recommendations to the other two this customer
and OK let's just move on here so
so the advantages of collaborative filtering is then you know we can apply then even
if the content is not easily analyse like in the multimedia something we can also
filter items based on quality and taste and not just content but that's also of
course as we've seen before in the web context that's that's important and they're already
be relied on human annotations namely the links to help us and here again you
know we could we could exploit the the things we observe about user preference and
then also you know it might help help us actually defined serendipitous recommendations so sometimes
making recommendations for things were based on the content is not very clear that there
even related OK but that's a lot of people who buy a and b a
and b based on the content seem to have nothing to do with one another
but still in my opinion might be an interesting connection so we can do these
types of things in this context
OK so
so so the the standard approach that has been developed i mean this collaborative filtering
technique basically that came up in the early-mid nineties and then in the late nineties
was also commercialized and the basic idea is really of what has been done there
are is the use of nearest neighbour type of approaches so the idea is well
first you compute a similarity function between the user i and the user came
right how do you do that it a popular way to appears on correlation coefficient
and it works like this you look at all the
items that have been rated by
user i and j so here we actually assume i should have said that we
we have ratings available for a subset of items that user has rated a particular
set of items think of about five five-star scale OK so we look at
the items that have been rated by both
and we compare the rating of an item by user i
normalized by the mean actually so we subtract the mean for user i and we
look at the rating of user
OK on that item j subtracting the mean
for that user OK so we we take
that inner product if you like and then we
the normalized by the standard deviations of the ratings of user i and k that
product OK so that the correlation coefficient usually which just some overall dimensions here
but since you know they'll they'll of missing values you only some of those that
are in common right you can otherwise you can really compare
by the correlation between two users you can only compare it on the things that
separated in common setting well and then you get the similarity
and then you do some type of nearest neighbour regression where you say well the
predicted rating for user i on item j
is that they
you take the mean rating of user i and then relative to the mean rating
you look at all the
a certain set of nearest neighbors typically
of user i the nearest neighbours being the ones with the highest similarity
OK you take the similarity as the weight
and then you look at
the difference between the rating of that user k that we're looking at here
the rating on j relative to
the average rating of that users so saying that well does that use rate that
particular item higher-than-average or lower than average and if so by what amount and these
increments we wait with the similarity and then we normalized by the sum of the
one of the l one norm if you like of these
adjusting the absolute values of the similarities and that is
kind of the prediction we make it so we say prediction that we make about
the rating of user i on an unseen item j is the average
rating for that user plus an increment and increment is just the weighted sum of
increments from similar users
so so this has been is a very simple idea and has been very popular
in terms of learning it doesn't really require any learning because you know the memory
based learning people call it right you just store all the information and then once
you want to make prediction just go into database and computed right but there is
no offline
imputation yes
i this
so this year
if you look like
so the question so this is it for
right for the so the simple cases where you really have to great right there
the situation where you say well i why you think of the binary by writing
things that people don't buy don't like saying things like like
you know that
might not be a descent try
but you know basically
so so in this setting if you want to move to towards more interesting things
it becomes a little bit unclear how actually do that
so this is why i think actually that methods
for instance that use more probabilistic
approach right where you could actually model the types of things
but you observe and related to the types of things that you really interested in
the response variable makes more sense here
so you have to rely
on that or you have to find you know basically if there's some other way
that you can come up with a similarity measure right you could still use
some formulas like that
perhaps but if you have right but this still as well this still assumes that
we are dealing with great
so it's somewhat limited
OK let me
so let me present now another way that might be more
along the lines of what you've learned here in the last two weeks
and that's we now can we also do this in a discriminative way so what
we like to learn really
it is the a function
from user item pairs into let's say in this case of ratings right the numbers
from zero to two are
you know referring to the number of stars or something like that find score
so you know for each user and each item we would like to sign such
a number
there are some problems so one is how to interpret actually the ratings
we could just take them as you know absolute numbers but but often that's really
not what we want rather what we often one is we only want to give
them the meaning on an ordinal scale meaning you know if we have a rating
and we have another rating that is higher than we'd like to say OK well
this is preferred over the other but the the numerical value of the difference
we don't really want to
perhaps interpret that you know that
it's not clear that has meaning so it's a different whether we talk about an
absolute scale ordinal scale so in order to deal with that we can do is
we can use ordinal regression
techniques so we treat it as an ordinal regression problem and the second challenge is
well if we do that if we want to learn the mapping how do we
actually represent
things over here
right particular user item pair can just take a number that is the number of
that user and the number just some identifier for the item i wouldn't be able
to learn the mapping i need something that characterizes users and items right
OK and so here's the first of all the idea of how you can do