i which should which i cannot decision between unfunded
with different size of training set a and b here we have the
objective function evaluated on the test set which was used for training
and we have to function and the function of the time of training
on the second city is ten thousand how can we
so yes which
i think the is really because we don't have
then becomes evident when you have that becomes whole
excuse for me to
the council of bit
here is some of the
sixteen we see here so
in the
and we had a better case and there were to this experiment in the egyptian
sitting in the let's see how we follow that is beta
then can here is even more difference between the that city in the thing that
if you go even further using
even more conditions then that becomes almost people when you have a laugh
so now
we can ask why is that it is and
you can it's also a
virtually longer
that we have to assume it and so on the first
we have to make the weight of the world in this
and by the time
and here's what you said and this set you have
so you have a mate
for the
the other is
we have a small
the same thing the here
on the left that which is even more difficult even more
there is
the difference is even
so now i want do that solve
so the last fall because
with this method have been walking
you know maybe all these small
the image was images which are getting excited by twenty times for you want to
get the image and have dictionary
but it seems to be
this is what you can get in
so he was some text from the image
and the result in a that is how many
you can be a small effect
so now
i told you also that extension of the method which are here be
and it would be nice
we can define
and then they get this
and then when they get the exact solution is the very easy to to cooperate
with the consequent on but it's also easy
two at this
we have also seen points on the walls
well dictionary to have stuff
which can be useful applications
when you can use to replace the constraints but we had the
by the consequent which induces sparsity
so it was here use the media
in the end to end one don't
c five
and as you can see that the constraint
so here is the largest images show you
what you can get
so we have played with the and
so the estimate shows get PCA
so the
the positive values
and it is a low so here we have a dictionary
which something is the
forty nine months
and when you use and if not they should have to make sure that
there more
located in the future we can look on the faces
when using traditional methods used to make the right
and what is interesting that using
one you strategy by p
we can update the same images were
all this stuff
so on the left we have seventy percent of the surface which is the one
on the right hand
so what
so we have the
i don't think about
is this
the age and let see
the image on the medium is the decision
so maybe is this
it going
you know that you can see i can see
that is not
they don't always
the structure is
well the first component of
this is
the dictionary show some structure which
if you like like we did for this on the shape of the show
there is a city which on the one
the beginning of the second half of the story
what to do now will actually so this thing here on the left is
side the
i think you get if you go to the site website and download the local
so it's the ontology
together with the reasoning engines
and it but in this one allows also to edit to add new section in
them and so on
not individual at couple of
new constants so if your social
and also make it all the
use these assertions to do something new knowledge
and not that they would have
we love the concept of oversight authority which is a collection of or
all the time in order to support the site
well the concept of michael witbrock
and about
presentation at the station here so
the first three
you have to create
it's a great here
we select the the constants through the web interface
now we know that open sector because was sector has
this is one of or
now i will eat some assertions about this new constants
that open sector tortoise is
so collection of all the tutorials
that means
it is a journalist
the total generalizes this oversight hours
what you see here that
these constraints kicked in telling us that
so as not to be
so a collection of the collection is to be collection itself first
it is one sec is telling us and suggested that you can repair it can
found this by adding this
so the whole concept of forest is a collection
thinking this
i want this to this assertion in
and if you click what what do we know about
o percent
so a collection of all the photos in its collection
these are these
constraints to talking before
then we also have the assertion that
an instance open borders
and that
four percent
artificial intelligence
is this
we have the knowledge about of it just about michael witbrock
it's not
you know it was
not yet
now you
and that he's the person so
i could be got is the first
and if you check whether that tell us so
not much at the moment
so we can ask is
but for all the things that mikey east
and he said that he person social being
partiallytangible agent
but tangible
he's come posits you
so we're just doing this
semi automatic candidate for these things
the constant
which responds to this presentation this
but it is an instance of presentations so this is this
and he also
well just to write it in the
this instance of presentation
so the ISWC site presentation
o percent talk this was given this presentation
what is this
now we already not just below the
at least in the propositional level
as we move out of that is that there are other things about such as
its ability
to give us the basis
for mathematics
that's an extremely important
classical mathematics is extremely important
feature had
not something to be a little
will talk about non-classical mathematics a little bit
in our last lecture
although we don't talk about the intuitionist mathematics actually a couple minutes
will get to the natural deduction proofs here in a few minutes
the first
non-classical logic we're going to talk about is intuitionist logic actually it's going to be
something called well intuitions logic there something called minimal logic which isn't which should have
been in your hands and the role of the stuff that actually gone through minimalist
to because the first lecture i just put in
the all stuff the huge amount of stuff on on
just as a background two
fitch style natural deduction was to get everybody up to speed
i teach that in my courses to get everybody up to speed because we tend
to use lower levels tableau based approaches and
i think for the the largest we're talking about the tableau based approaches are very
it's just
then i'll get
i mean there
the ingenious people thought of them
but they're not
but anyway
OK now
despite what i just said about it
classical mathematics being so important intuitionist logic group grew out of something called intuitionist mathematics
very mature thought the very much what he's is thinking
he could talks about the sort of mystical understanding of oneness and then
two minutes which goes to it e
which is also another unfortunate name but anyway he uses the sort of very mystical
language to science that's the sort of
directory of human intuition
and structures
and it's very interesting view what i think is actually very interesting read it it's
not solely all assessed very
strange different for people aren't used to thinking in mathematics and mystical terms
likely it doesn't have to be thought of that way
isn't just for the mistake
back in the late fifties and early sixties other people
cleaning doesn't get enough stephen cleaning doesn't get enough credit for this
but he developed was called the realizability interpretation
intuition is
and michael dominant
well he did help develop the sort of
non mystical version as well
he talks about a lot unfortunately he often
lapses into
now mystical version that's kind of
he contradicts himself
it's very annoying phosphor in that way
the idea is quite simple
the problem the problem is this
well brower was
fighting against
classical set theory
and all of you know a little bit about and one of the things about
is its treatment of infinity
what about
intended insert their what is it that you found strange when i first learned about
let me a lot of sense to the first time you heard that
the very first time i think not now right you know you understand now
right because you you've been grilled
the very first time i heard that
seem pretty strange right
different sizes of infinity
in the results
you need best
i was talking about
three or four
he he the
and animation of it
it you want
one three cluster start with three
cluster centers the seed points
assign points to the closest cluster centre
we don't do that
the to
that's all
and typically
what is
regimes extremely fast as the fastest growing
you run many times with different initializations
this is the first one
that's an isolated clusters
the measure
similarities between the
it is based on the
those are your points that they constantly distances
a sphere
so basically refers to find
just chat
of similar size of nicely
the data
has in
twenty years from and they find two clusters
it was little bit like this
the ones the
but in
so basically can be used to refer to find
linearly separated
and not
nonlinear separation
that's why are
classification you
the image
it's actually trying to decide not just that he needs any clustering together
see the
my attention
is there
you find it in a randomly generated
in this case you want to mention
and i think it needs to it
and you need to find
clusters it
so that's why we should have some
you know the
say anything about the number clusters in
the same data
it is it to be able to
you before it was five
someone who's the user
who that it is trying to form hypothesis about
so all have
quantitative measurement of
was the last round
in high dimensions
use the
but at the least makes sense
so he
think about you which model to the data
this is a very powerful message if you know the
in this case goes here is appropriate
information about the
it is found three
with the world
in fact this at the time
designed by my father
and about
automatically finds the
but if the model is not correct
then it will not work
so now
let me go through
that is the nature of
it means that the
kernel approach
the idea is to project the data
from the given dimensions to higher education
in the case
so we have two dimensional data consists
which is
cannot find
so how you
the mapping function
which can be
x one point
you do
three dimensional space x words were to explain why
at this two-dimensional three-dimensional
the two clusters
and now and
why is he is he possible
so this is this is a
instance as well as long as are
well what on
on the
this function
which currently the most appropriate that's designed parameter
and how to
there also sigma squared
so this is
the answer
cross validation
what are the spectral clustering the same thing as the we don't you
so there are no matrix is the number of clusters
and this is
the kernel matrix of the data
you got you are
we find that
the most this this is what i is that in nineteen
and data
can be easily clustering
so the representation e
semantic representation to make
so some companies
he was
please let me show you some examples you
so here's
datasets were he doesn't work
but that's the point without any
this is completely unlabeled data
like he's
it is found in
the ones one cluster one cluster
same thing this one
not finding it
but it doesn't
we have to understand the kernel
now have seen that we have we to live in the same
as early as possible
they don't they don't
chain and this would require some four
so far and some just taking the decision was example the fundamental security industry industry-funded
c which is called the fido of mary
and which is just the follow the ADC divided by the two teams
to support effective number of bits that
times has a sampling frequency so you get
p called rule of thumb to improve conditions in bone twenty five micrometer we form
this region one because this if we go to
sixty five millimetre we can expect because that's representation caulfield ADC with this kind of
if you're
so then lets example i guarantee which is we have two key challenges for the
atlas calorimeter we want to i fifteen
the effective number of bits forty million this would require two hundred and sixty kilowatt
with this technology so i think you know what is this one
so we have
we lose about in terms of using the
this technology was not alone in jail in engineering because now if i look at
what is the growth of the power supplies which are needed to put that we
quite a lot because we are not using cheap oil supplies y that because we
need to have avoid auditioned on supply so it's not something that you just by
it's it's special because lots so you could say that million two million trees five
and on the
when the ball supply and so that they can only material they don't speak of
fifteen million channels could imagine what it means you have made it would it would
you know you what's in fact apply all the tricks him but
but you see there
it's it's really important
the government that is does that yes it got something to to use
modem technology because in terms of money cost in terms of human investment because you
have to spend some time in the
what can do
what we need is at the end payoff
what would be a for the
electronics and in fact to to tell you what
if g is and how do we hold on this kind of very
so that's the typical block detector clinic so you receive
from the impending fault and intuitive that
and then you want this is where where you have to check for that the
choices are quite you have to make some data processing could be done for doing
it could be just see also questioned it could be a portion of that anything
and then you have to prepare for each event you have to prepare
and even to
thank you for your follow-up and then you have to show that
to that acquisition system
in addition to get it said that there that you will have some interface to
to the training in ten years
because you have to know when you go to three you you have to know
when there's
you also point here some
twenty clinics and some many times so you are you have to be able hear
to sample the number of runs for making look at least six
so don't think that we have
and none of the film medium i just couldn't
some of the things we see a lot of them are are using the mean
different from factor
i don't want to discard all of that but i want to talk about it
and the point where you live to be expanded called ten one but i want
to talk about all these big things here
but you see which FPGA
so what have you
and is the is the secretary which he you about six of
first of all i will block green
which are interconnected
with their a and also
with switches so you have to choose all of the place so that you can
any connection that you region between one of block in the
this is which means that when you get that you have nothing inside business and
then you will put you know and i don't know knowing that that would be
fine we define what you will
in the user's block and what we were doing definition
in addition to that you've got some input output so we could do you want
to do this
she that is in some sense
and you've got the number of possible number of input and output with the capability
of state in which a particular value one to use the syntax so that something
which looks very extreme
in addition to that the
you have inside some some generic blocks like class distribution system so when you have
when you have a second system you have to distribute the close to different elements
and you have to be careful with the flat face of the clock really separate
inside which is built in which allows you to control the face of the clock
to different places
you have some memory blocks embedded with which you can make five full-time you just
made by you harm
what you want and you have special blocks line
DSP so does posses or block
even on but michael posner selma michael berthold also you have an unbelievable influence in
this in can and you can download you can you can ask you to outline
some software that you have very useful forces you've got also i been so you
so the beginning of the
the PGA
you look at the bottom
so in the get the lookup table the number of inputs data to the but
it's it's like it's like any more
in which you are you will use millions of these would these a b c
d so before before you making the cheap working you will you will load the
the content of the mainly with the values that you want to get to the
mine you
now that i'm
i can take
derivative of this equation so i get on the left side
the dp
pt is going to be zero
so we get zero
times DVD
the DVD is the accent
the NDP
and that is the thrust
on the rocket
so what you see here is something
it's very easy to digest
and they which is the
this is the acceleration of the rocket this is the mass of the rocket at
time t
the thrust of the rocket
and that equal
the team
and some people
we call this the
the rocket equation
now this is true
there is no external force on the system
it is interesting to include
a real loans from earth
and if you have a real entrepreneurs
the rocket is going up in this direction
but then gravity
is exactly the opposite direction
in other words only when you launch vertically from our earth
what you have
thrust like this
and you would have
and you like this
in that case
this equation
has to be
just it and then you get a
he equals and throws
and g
if you have a launch from earth vertically up
now you have to do a little bit of massaging and i'll leave you with
that massaging
a couple of integrals are necessary
to convert this into the final
the velocity of the
rocket after the birth
compared to the initial velocity
and that part i believe you wish but you will see that worked out in
all the tail
on the notes that i left on the web
and then you come up with a very famous equation that the final velocity of
the rocket minus the initial velocity of the rocket
equals minus you
times the logarithm
of the final mass of the rocket
divided by
initial mass of the rocket
this is if there were
no gravity at all
just in case and only in case of a vertical launch from earth
there is also year terms
only if you have a vertical launch
when i want my lecture i noted in my enthusiasm i put brackets around the
minus gt
this is quite misleading because it may give you the wrong impression
that the product it's taking which is not so
so the brackets really should not be around to his duty
it is this term
mine you logarithms
of MF
divided by amplify
minus gt
let's now look at this equation in a little bit more detail
so we get a little bit of feeling for it
suppose we had a vertical launch from
but we had no rockets
it's possible
so but this term does not exist
what you see
that the velocity
he calls
the initial we have called that before anyone one p zero initial speed
we had that was ill during our first like
completely consistent with this equation if you have no rocket you get that v equals
three zero minus if you strongly object vertically up and we had a vertical launch
so that looks good
we learned from the earth
and we know
have initial speeds
which is zero rocket is standing there
and we fired rockets the by the way is the burn time of the rock
we write that down t
is the first time
so initial speed is zero
so now
this final velocity if we want find velocity be
anything physically meaningful positive number
this thing has to come out positive USA
how can that be
because we have a minus sign here and we have a minus sign there how
can ever become positive well
don't forget
the final math
space not what is this
what is it
so we want to be famous
he was used
what is it
so are
sixty years
and random
so this nomination is
actually smaller distances that so few month
this is at the end
most of you know that we have
so that it
since is zero
user base
the function space
and also normalize contrast skin so dimensions space
it is almost constant is close to zero it turns out that in seen significant
lots of data
is actually response to the world
use that you've seen
i just before
is well
because we want to say that
prosperity is
and normalized the
fact and so what had was
not on
but as said mister here so
so we don't lose trust
that is we can do cross his
and now we have a sense here
of data as an expression is
instance action is
there no have databases collect four points
statistical distribution
of the city the fall we randomly chosen actually
the statistical distribution of sense
is one fashion
it doesn't come close here
it's not issue
it's not really what you say about
this is what i need to grow and team decided to
play in this talk
the set of
this to is
there an industrial center but it is not
right there is the need
this is kind of action
one thousand eight inches
actually very very high
because you
you made me love you know what we see here
the transition between one constant college
one one
would like to review
and if i o
and this
this is
as soon as it was
one species
and you see that in space is
of these there is
what is
we have
this is not the right
you see
this is actually on these
and this
so that's
he is the a sense in some there's not this
so my mind is that as far as it concerns
to take this into
i the
the hardest part
missus the public
we all conditions in this
and this
it is
in response
we to
since the sentence inside out
it is
my point
have to decide which ones
not be the density estimation
there is only
one of the problems
i see
you decide
it is rational for use of this
initially i
it is
have some density estimation function
but you decide how much
so we can use named entities as well
for point
cincinnati is
one hundred thousand dollars
when you
one hundred years
we on this is the
so the model free solutions we cover
monte carlo
k k one
what is michaela sample from
the next day return full return
before it right
temporal difference
sample obviously from the next returned
next day return
the next day OK let's let's let's cut the next reward
plus the next state value estimate
get good
OK so if you with me with this thing you've got the basic idea is
to what you need
OK you need team know how this problem the probability that slowly so let's how
how do we improve on the original
OK by this is the book is very unified very nice view of all the
methods that discovered so let me discover that one more time so that two dimensions
here that we see on this on the vertical axis
at the top we have full backups
that means you sample or next states
and in the bottom we assemble backup with fifty samples from transitions
and under given policy
on the horizontal axis we have shall backups it is one step back and on
right hand side we have the backup meaning all eighty and
OK so if you look at sample backups
there are deep you get the money method selects the shell different methods
you look for backups
right these require the model
dynamic programming or value iteration some things
and we didn't have an exhaustive search
but from from from a given state
you could just to expecting that so is just expectimax search to all terminal states
and this is exactly
you know so in in games you know that you can do game tree search
this is just expected search where instead of doing minimax you do next expectation maximisation
next actions to expectation over the transition probabilities
so you could do is also search from from from a given state spent that
entire tree
is name for methods
now the key
two getting an efficient method
for RL with sampling is going to be to sort of find some middle ground
between temporal difference methods in medical methods to incorporate some of the properties of the
deeper returns
right now the monte carlo method can learn very early on because it's all a
to the end with the probably temporal difference methods that we saw in the in
the in experiments that they can learn faster
right so you know if you're in the in the graphs t
the team methods did find out policy in some problems faster than the MC methods
so how to get the best of both worlds
OK this we're asking is a hybrid of temporal difference and what happens
of course skip this
OK so
let's think about
template of
prediction that we did we previously covered
the one step prediction here
from the from this table to the next day we that we we we we
used as the values for the stage
we use the reward samples plus state but imagine a two step TD methods
you sample two states of the current state
as prime minister wilfried
now take the we were you here word here and that i estimate at this
right which summarizes the future that currently believe you would get
likewise for three steps
sample the first three wards and then use the estimate values from that point on
OK clearly all the way down to the monte carlo method you sample
all the words in every estimate
OK so there no continuum of back from one step two and step all down
to the in which is the monte carlo
start back
OK now what's interesting is these all give you estimates of the same value
so i think it's more clear from next slide
because remember looking to return
OK this is the two-step return
at time t
several more time t plus one
gamma tend toward time t plus two
gamma squared times value estimate
at time t plus two k where the summarizes all future would be expect
OK so what is a three step for step by step these are all as
being the same value as here's the beautiful in inside you get from the from
from the dual methods that is
if you have
if you have a bunch of different aspects of the same value
we just use one
because one one estimator might have high variance
but if you got but it is the same value to combine and you average
get estimate with lower variance
right now the lower variance estimates get after learning
so this is the idea of the team methods average above two different step returns
so to get lower variance in your estimate any lower variance in new sampling then
you get faster
let's do it just goes back to to the random walk example you've got five
states e
you go right i think probably point eight says if you say go right you're
probably point eight and with point two you actually go left
OK so it's sort of a random walk with scale better control that
you can search direct the walkers
OK so let's look in this example
of using different in step returns
so let's look at the top axis
you've got alpha which is the learning rate on the x axis
and on the y axis you've got the air between the current value estimate
and the
in the optimal
they are messages that just says discovered of the meteor
that means greater sorry
root root mean square
so it's just near measure
clearly the lower their measure the better the algorithm on here that the different line
different different instead of using different step backups
and what we previously covered with TD one right
OK to assess performance over the different learning rates OK clearly see here probably learning
rate of
well three given certain offers
it's going to be actually
give you lowest error estimate for a fixed number of samples
but we can look at a small example that user another intuition why light source
imagine that we have one million documents its fare collection for
during during the evening if you you want to exercise this information is available
and it's a collection of small documents
yeah i think that looks like a collection of HTML documents
so only one thousand words document if you are doing
legal that's legal information retrieval it will be
four thousand to five so and if you are doing retrieval from microblogs
you have
ten was document of fifteen work
in dictionary will have
hundred thousand why so many
it's not so many words by the way because extracting
geographical names
think the people names
and you know that
in english and russian
other languages that
been working with
usually have millions of words from this small collection five hundred thousand
it's really very close to what you get
so if you create this metric
this was semantic have
every rewards are all
and every document is the column
you will have
five hundred billion cells in huge mansion
it says sally b
at the same time how many words we have collection
we have only one billion words in collection
so it means that
only less than one percent
o point two percent of elements in this magic magic but not zero
what does it mean that it a huge matrix and all before
every element of is zero and only a small number of elements that will be
one or
for example if you put in constant fieldscount field
let's see how we can present in memory of this huge metric
the most common idea
the game
i know
i mentioned that i was walking
in the library
somewhere in ancient egypt or
i don't know
many thousands of years ago
is what we can do
because are going from four PM decision session from our going from to document what
we can do
you can take
every word
and for everybody can at least of documents
i have seen this work
during in the
with this story collection that it was semantics
get everywhere
rather and reported least
and it exactly exactly the same
that is on this for you
exactly the same you coming to library
we are looking for
actually it's not a word about librarians are smart enough to be in the
so information all the water in this in this
what an index
so they
you can i open the door
in information retrieval on shield
and you see lists of all books or documents that really contained this this is
inverted file
and again this is one of the most popular
structures for information retrieval
just it was invented as i said by librarians many thousands years ago
then it was
in the winter
in the fifties by people who are developing
just search engine for computers
internet search engines became popular
suddenly people started to talk
in all cases very good structure that they actually again that are talking about started
talking about inverted file is the main structure for change
in one thousand eight
very useful structure
as one one
around one day i'm not trivial programs
if you're not real programmer you can you can say OK
i don't want to do this because
actually it's not very good structure for me
why it's not very good structure
i need to extract work put them introduction OK i can do it it's not
a problem
but the problem is that i'm going to to report to every
all documents that are linked to this work
and if it doesn't fit into memory and i can i can create it using
using my
all the computer from nineteen ninety
in one one evening
it's not good
i i will implement the change in the way is is working exactly the same
but much more simpler because because and smart guy
and his saying OK
what i'm going to do it
and i'm going to create a signature file
maybe he
it doesn't know that signature file but what this might go to say is
OK so
let's imagine that we have a caching point
and this session functions can map
every four
to some long
but in addition to being a one b
why because we cannot have such long
one string as whole collection of the whole dictionary because the whole dictionary is
as i said millions of words
we will use the same position many times
typical examples of passion
that insurance companies
when they have independent probabilities
to estimate
of having a certain number of accidents are concerned with having too many accidents which
i'm exhausted reserves insurance company has reserve
and they they have enough reserves to cover them for a certain number of actions
and they use the binomial distribution
to calculate the probability
of getting any specific pacific number of accidents
that is the most efficient the binomial
i can expand the hand because i can't get into detail this is not of
course in probability theory
but i'm hopeful that you can see the formula and could apply
all right
the question this is clear enough you read my handwriting
OK so
another important concept in probability theory that we will use a lot
is expected value
and so
the mean or average
those are all roughly interchangeable
we have expected value
i mean
are average
but we can define it in a couple of different ways depending on whether we're
talking about sample
i mean all
population in the basic definition
the expected value of some random variable x
deflation have a random variable
is a
quantity that takes time
is in fact if you have an experiment
and the outcome of the experiment is a number
then a random variable is that number
o which comes from the experiment so for example the experiment could be tossing a
and i will call
the outcome heads
the number one
and i called the outcome tales the number zero so i've just define a random
you have discrete random variables like the one i just defined or there are also
can that was taken only a finite number of values and we have continuous random
variables they can take on any
a number of values along a continuum another experiment would be to say
next two chemicals together
and put thermometer and measure the temperature that's another invention of the sixteen hundreds by
the way the thermometer
and they learn that concept fit perfectly natural to us temperature but it was a
new idea in the sixteen hundred
so anyway that's continuous right when you mix two chemicals together
it could be any number is an infinite number of possible numbers that would be
i for discrete random variables
we can define the expected value
or use of that that's the greek letters mu
it is the summation
i equals one two infinity
of the probability
that x
equals x survived
times x by
all right so i haven't done that there might be an infinite number of possible
values for
the random variable x
in the case of the coin toss there are only two
but i'm
it's saying in general there could be an infinite number but there countable
so we can list all possible values when they're discrete
and form a probability weighted average of the outcomes and that's called the expected value
and it's people also call that the mean or the average
but note that this is based on
these are probabilities
in order to compute using this formula
you have to know
the troopers prior probabilities
there's another formula which applies for continuous random variables
and it's the same idea
except that
o also called backs
except that it's an integral
so we have in
from minus infinity to plus infinity
of f of x
times x
that's really see is the same thing because an integral is analogous to a some
or are more
four or
one of more general
not just the structure of the city looking for so
things to look for the right
is the is one the bushy what kinds of aspects with the
the user
a lot of
the school was using normal inverse is the first time
some of these
that's really all
well that are three
so we are
however are
so what this is
you will be
all of the
the art of
so a more
you will get
of all
he also understand that in the last
what are
also possible is
the more
what you see
you know
we were
it's all three this is the semantic structure people flock
he is
there's a lot
you can see that you can get
really work
and then we can
i i the more fundamental we also need to understand classes because of what of
the to
our to describe
grass roots north
and relations between
of the graph
i think will do with no is
sometimes it's important in the past
not always easy
of course
a lot of work on developing for this is about themselves are part
one this work well
all this stuff
progress on the
excellent here we get this the contributions
then you would like to have a large margin between the true difference is what
OK let's it so that does it looks more like this three more scores you
transcription start for all these to school
computer for every position in the genome and then you would like to fit this
kind of model
to use
the structure of the learning for doing this
and then you don't need to explain this again just try to learn a function
of y x
and labelling is the segmentation into different unique arts and input is this the
predictions of the SVM for the take
OK let me show you some results on that
so first of all actually talk to kind of the first one is one
predicting splice forms only so say we even started the end of the gene would
only like to predict the starts
and so in into one we would like to find all the info
and then i also have prediction have some results on a protein protein predictions very
can also identify new
OK so we
we had about four searle is four
these results selected
we had about four thousand genes which will equal this was like a quarter of
he took sixty percent for training percent for testing
and maybe explode i like
and we tested on one thousand one hundred eighty model
and we found the lights on
based on error rate was just five percent so that means five percent of the
cases the prediction up
that means
of the single or this but from what incorrect means one of the intron exon
OK so there are two different tasks one is involving only coding sequences and the
other one was what could is not only forty to
compare this to other approaches recently published
i can be with i think about you by many with four x and on
the same datasets
they got like twice as high error rates than in inspector
so like i said that ten percent and here second task sort of fifteen percent
to six percent
so this is how prediction looks like right so we start in any given that
it's like what sequence that starts at the end of the
six of them
so what is interesting is that we
we took me to our system and went to the annotation of the genome
there's already some genes right so said of those genes are completely uncalled
went to those genes and we predict the the gene structure for those genes
so there was some other tool which was you ought to be fifteen structures and
important part was that we found only if all that all critics disagreed with the
adaptation fifty percent of the cases
i mean really very high disagreement even though we know if accuracy should be much
much higher from the property
the westerners who was right so
we looked at twenty of those cases experimentally so we went to the benefits of
sequencing of them on a line those found that
in order the twenty cases non what's correct from the annotation and fifteen cases correct
for what four
OK so this is like one case this was that station and then we predicted
splice form then we sequenced
that part and you see that it is exactly matching of
so the error rate of a patient that has one hundred percent
this is a useful thing to do
now the the most interesting one
four class the
equation of state that the most interesting is the van der waals equation of state
developed by mister van der waals in eighteen seventy three
and the beauty of that equation of state is that it only relies on two
so let's build up and see where it comes from
and just frustrated and then divorced
that's a the bars where
if you take a equal to zero these are the two parameters a and b
you take those two equal to zero the musical director field as well
OK let's build this ability when this comes from when these parameters a and b
comes from
the first thing to do is we're going take gas
in a box
building blocks for here
gotta go on a bunch of gas molecules
four atoms
the box here
well these
gas is gas molecules or atoms to a first approximation
like hard spheres
they occupy a certain volume each molecule occupies
a particular volume
and so
we can
called the
is the volume
per mole
of the hard spheres
by and promoted
that is the little
fear that the
molecules are
so that the volume
that's available to any one of those spheres
it is actually smaller than b
because you've got all these other little spheres around so the actual volume seen by
any one of the sphere is smaller than the
so when we take our
the ideal gas law
particle to rt
we have to replace the bar by the actual volume available to this hard spheres
so instead of the berkeley right p
the bar
a minus b
that's the
parts here volume of the spheres
now those molecules or atoms are here
i also feel each other
of whole bunch of forces a new in five eleven two
one like van der waals attraction things like this
so the attractive forces are repulsive forces
these molecules
and that's going to change
the pressure
the molecules field for instance if i have
pressure pressure is when you have one of his her sphere colliding against the wall
the biosphere
once the colliding the water to create a force on the wall
and i have a couple of hard spheres nearby
right in the absence of any interactions at a certain pressure this thing with careen
into the walk junior
the force
but only in the presence of these interactions
get these other molecules here are watching the other partners
one two are
two damage to themselves right
that one to come back right
the attractive force there is no other molecules on the outside of the wall so
is attractive for that that makes the velocity thing not quite as far as the
force is not quite as strong
as it was without this attractive force so the real pressure is not quite the
because of these attractive forces it was
it would be without forces
the pressures of the last in this case here
so instead of
half of this piece here now
if i write this equation here he
is equal to RTE
divided by the bottom line is the
just rewriting this equation
as it is
so the pressure is going to depend on how strong this attractive forces
so the pressure is going to be less
if is a strong attractive forces
and the one of the squared is the statistical
this approach basically the probability of having
and another molecule a second molecule in the volume of space
if the molar volume is small
and one of the is large
is a large probability into
two spheres together by
the is large
it means that
there's a lot of room
for the molecules and they're not going to be close to each other so this
isn't going to be as important
so a is the strength of the interaction of the bar is how
likely they are to be close to each other
that's going to affect the actual pressure seen by the as
and a
when you
that gives you the van der waals
the question is that
two parameters the hard sphere volume
and the attraction
you don't have to go look up into tables but you don't have to have
all the values of the second virial coefficient or the fudge factor
just to
variables that make physical sense
and you get an equation of state which is a reasonable equations and that's the
power animals
equation of state and that's the one we're going to be using later on in
this class describe real gases
you should have seen a little bit
the one using this class predominantly is the notation
and then notation is pretty easy notation to master because all you do is you
from the formula you just drop low order terms
and ignore
leading constants and then
so for example
i have a formally like three and q
ninety and squared minus five and class six o four six
i say well what's the
one of the what order terms do i drop nq is a bigger term then
and square
from drop all these terms
and ignore the leading constant so i say that's made of and q
pretty easy
so that as in that they notation now this is an engineering
the a way of manipulating data notation
there's actually a mathematical definition for this
which one talk about next time
which is the definition in terms of sets of functions
and you're going to be responsible in this class this is both a man
and in engineering computer science engineering class
so throughout the course of responsible both for mathematical rigour
as if it were math course and engineering common sense because it's an engineering course
going to be doing both
so this is the engineering way of understanding what you do
so you're responsible for being able to do these manipulations you're also going to be
responsible for understanding the mathematical definition of data notation
and of its related o notation and omega notation
if i take a look
as n approaches infinity
the square albert algorithm
i data nq algorithm
as n gets bigger it doesn't matter what these other terms were if i were
describing the absolute precise behaviour
in terms of the formula
if i had and squared algorithm it will always be faster for sufficiently large n
then if haiti and cube algorithm
it wouldn't matter what those laura terms work
it wouldn't matter what the leading constant was
this one will always be faster even
if you read
the theta and squared algorithm on a slow computer
in the data and q algorithm one of fast computers
so the great thing about asymptotic notation is it satisfies are issue being able to
compare both relative and absolute speed
OK because really able to do this
no matter what
computer no matter what the platform
so on different platforms we may get different
constance here machine dependent constants for the actual running time
but if i look at the growth
as the size of the input gets larger
the asymptotics generally won't change
so for example
just draw that is the picture
so if i have and on this axis
t then on this axis
this may be
this may be for example of data and cube algorithm and this may be data
in square algorithm
there's always going to be some points
and not
and when you put results
that's where it's even more important not to make too many assumptions
so now
what you can do is
two things so either someone tells you what is the objective so you want to
maximize some
misclassification error sorry minimize the misclassification error or maximize the money you get
from applying a certain reason to certain problem or anything like this and then you
can see from this tried to
the optimal algorithm for
maximizing or minimizing the this quantity
you can say well
let's forget about this and let's try to
make another reason that
estimates everything about the the properties of the
so for example if you're in classification
you can either try
to build a classifier or first try to build something that is to make the
how the data is distributed in space and then from that from these estimates construct
moreover most often you would get
the same algorithms
but the point is if you
o was the first approach
and sometimes a bit more risky because you're trying to do things that you don't
have to do or you don't need to do
and you may
by the following that you may
necessary assumptions
but the point is
algorithms are algorithms
they are completely independent on
what what you may assume about the distribution of the data and the may work
on network independently on your assumption just because
the the problem is nice or not
OK so now the question is
how can we
two the priory very guidance for choosing priors
prior in the very general sense like what's an algorithm should prefer
he there's not much seen right away
i've kept repeating during his lectures that
all the series
cannot justify the prior it can only tell you once you have chosen the prior
whether i mean the kind of behaviour you may expect so once you have restricted
your special functions to functions of a certain form it will tell you kids with
these within this class
you may expect to upset to rate of convergence
doesn't mean that this class is good for your problem
forget about series if you wanted to the prior i would say
but still you can have
so i mean i can give you some personal feelings about how to choose the
not generally speaking you want to
make operational
all the
operational in the sense that you can derive an algorithm from it
all the knowledge of belief that you
but for that you don't have to
approach of theory or whatever just
b as pragmatic as possible i would say
it's a bit messy slides
so OK so this is more precise definition of the sentence
this prior to be what to expect before seeing the data
or assumptions about the function that are likely to solve the problem
you know it's just way to choose between two and i put these sort of
functions that look similar on your data
two to put it a bit more precisely priorities nothing but something that
gives you
number or score for each function so you function in i mean you have the
set of function and what you want is to assign a preference to each function
so you get
so any functional would be a prior that
so here are some
if you
few ways to do that
the simplest way
is two
here again there are some typos here
the simplest ways to restrict the class of functions so that the
could just prior you say well
i hope
that the target function is in this class and if it's not
two but
you can have some kind of nested structure of functions classes
you say well i hope that my function is in this class but it's not
maybe it would be in the second one and if it's not maybe within the
larger one and so on
and to each of the set to you associate some numbers that tell you
i mean i did should be something like the complexity of this
it can be anything that allows you to trade off between
the error that you made by the using function in set and
the prior your
preference that you have on the on this
and that's i mean here is where c we can give you a little bit
of guidance it can tell you what is the relevant notion of complexity for the
set and hence tell you how you should trade-off
so errors on your data
complexity in the class so
is it better to choose a function here which has such an error or function
here that a much smaller error but we within the class which is much bigger
than the exact balance
between those those choices can be
given by
the notion of complexity that we discussed before
here and then you can imagine
more general functionals like none of your functions or or anything
and usually you do that by are you consider very large set of function as
large as you can because you want to approximate potentially any function or at least
any continuous function for example
and you want to define a norm on this set the function that
from a simple alphabet with force
of size four
then for every two in you get one out
if you take a
if you take three binary digits coming in
then you need a symbol alphabet size a here
if you
if you move down in rate
from four binary digits
to one symbol
and then of course you need an alphabet of size sixteen
so the size of the alphabet here
is going up exponentially as the
great advantage that you get
is going down
we will talk about that more as we move on
you should sort of keep in mind that estranged relationship
between the size of alphabet
and the rate at which you can transmit
as you
as you try to transmit higher and higher rates here the decisive year alphabet goes
up exponentially with the rate can you can
in fact when you look at shannon's famous formula
how fast you can communicate on the channel
you find the logarithm
the signal to noise ratio
of one plus the signal to noise ratio
when you look at that signal to noise ratio and you look at this alphabet
size and here you could almost see just from that
why in fact that the logarithm is in this capacity formulas and we'll come back
to talk about that again more later also
but anyway
what we're going to do at this point is to separate this into the problem
of discrete encoding
and modulation and modulating you start out with some arbitrary alphabet symbols you turn that
these symbols in that alphabet into waveforms you transmitter waveforms you then get the symbol
back and then you put it into a digital encoder which gets the binary digits
now what order we want to study the set
well we're going to study the modulation first
and we're not going to study this at all essentially
except for a few very very simple minded examples
six four fifty one
which is the course it follows after this
which might or might not be towards
in the spring term
and incidentally those of you who wanted to be tortured sent me an email
saying you really need to take this next term for some reason or other
and because otherwise it will be given
in spring of the following year instead of spring of this year
there's another side to that issue
which is a wireless course
it's going to be given in the spring of this year
and if you want to take away course
postponed taking the coding course until the following year
then in fact it might be better to do the postponing job
i would recommend that those of you who
are interested in wireless take the course now because if you're looking for research problems
in the communication area
wireless is probably the the hottest area around the area where the most interesting problems
so you have to make the trade off if you want to to take both
courses grades so many males
so you want to take the coding course but anyway there will be very little
coding in this course very little discrete week
coding and mostly we're going to look at a simple ways of taking simple
symbol sequences
turning them into waveforms then transmitting the on channels
binary symbol
the way forward
OK what i go from waveforms directly to waveforms instead of going from waveforms the
symbols the binary digits and i just have to go back up again
a bunch of reasons
one of the reasons is that some of the stuff you transmit is already digital
to start with
when you look at what goes over network today for example it is carrying digital
data is carrying analog data this could carrying images
carry everything you can imagine
if you want to design
a modulation system
which goes directly from analog data to channel data
and you have a hundred different kinds of analog
source data
and you have a hundred different kinds of channels
then you're going to have to build one encoder for every one of those hundreds
for every combination of source channel
in other words you've got to build ten thousand devices
if you're interested in keeping engineers employed
which i think is very good interest
that's that's a very good philosophy to take
but but unfortunately most people who build communication equipment say we would really rather have
just a hundred or two hundred different devices two hundred one hundred devices which turn
all these different sources into binary digits and another hundred devices which turn the binary
digits into something that can be transmitted over any channel you want to
and this is just the general example of what people call layering
you want to turn systems into
systems with a bunch of layers and
where each layer is standardized in some way and only has to take care of
a few particular functions
and in fact that's what we're doing here also because we're
because we're dealing with one layer which is doing discrete encoding
which in fact this sort of generating
for the most part binary digits out of the discrete encoder
where as you go through all this stuff and you come out with binary digits
some of which are wrong you can do the the decoding and get the correct
binary digits and
if you look at the of a lot of coding theory
you will find that it doesn't pay any attention at all
the what's going on in the channel
lots of people have studied coding of their lives and decoding of their lives living
this mathematical theory of abstract algebra
and i had no idea of what channels are
and they survive because of this layering principle
so if you want to employ engineers it's nice to have layering
because engineers that after that was much better
course you people should know what all so
there are problems with computing the posterior bayesian
and this is statistics
but that's because you have to compute
these this quotient and it contains an integral
now the evidence term
in the denominator is an integral and that can be hard to compute that is an entirely different problem
and this is not about whether it's hard to compute this is whether about this quantity exists or does not
and with
so far the dirichlet process for example it happens i don't want to go into
much detail because it gets a bit technical
but basically
the problem is that these these nonparametric models can get
the posterior is a family is a family of distributions
right you get one
different probability for each possible
observation here
basically in these nonparametric models be this family can get too large and diverse
so the two
what you want to have
four or what you would need to have fuzzy force this equation to exist is that every single
element of this family is absolutely continuous with respect to the prior
and basically these families are too large and diverse for this to be possible for
all elements your new way that you can
you could get that is by making this measure here
down on sigma finance
and and models for rich so
basically models for which
families of distributions for which that's not possible
to make them all absolutely continuous with respect to one distribution
i called nondominated models
and so otherwise if if that's possible then you say that this measure dominates the the family yeah
one example of that are directly process measures are basically all these
the the measures based on random discrete measures that we saw yesterday
yeah so directly processes pitman yor process all these distributions
intuitively the problem is that that these
because the discreteness
they can they can put their masks
at individual points
but the space has an uncountable number of points
so there is an uncountable number of possible patterns where they can place their masks
if you would like
if you would like to have a density like this
and then what you would need is a measure here which puts positive mass every
single one of these points and that's just too much
i'm not going to dwell on this
but the
if you're interested
you know you will
you would just have to look into the literature and read it up and no it's not
easy i went through it at some point and i can tell you it's a
yeah it takes its time
just the message i want to convey is
in bayes nonparametrics really cannot think of a bayesian model has been defined in terms of basic equations
three the other way around to define a bayesian model
if you're lucky it satisfies the bayes equation
and that tells you how to get from the prior to the posterior
and bayesian nonparametrics it often doesn't work
and then we have to find some kind of substitute we have to find some
way of connecting the prior to the posterior
and it turned out that the way that it's done in bayesian nonparametrics as conjugacy
and we will get back to that
like two three slides on
i'm i'm going to spend
three or four slides
i'm trying to tell you how how these problems can be addressed
end of
i also wanted to use this at the
an opportunity to to try to show you how the girls in process and the
dirichlet processes are related to each other
okay so
this morning you heard john talking about
about the gaussianprocess and he told u
if you recall the
the definition
the girls in process is a distribution that gives us a function that
is it is a distribution that
on random functions right so we have a random function that we sample from the
gaussianprocess say on the interval maybe
and which maps to
that means that if we use this has
say a nonparametric regression
then the patterns that we are using are
continuous functions so the parameter space of our model is a set of continuous functions
on may be
and i have a picture here where we see
there we see a bunch of samples from a gaussianprocess which are these functions and then you
where they all you know where they are trained using point that's where observations are
so this conditions as the posterior conditioned on observations
and that these few points for the observations were we exactly know the value
and otherwise we answer
so here this but a specific point we have location est
between you and me
and this is the function value of the random function
so now recall the definition that john view that is
we call this a gaussianprocess because this function the gaussianprocess if the following holds if
we can take any finite subset of points down here
we look at this
vector here so we plucked we take the vector of function values at this finite subset of points
now since the function is a random this is a random vector
it has a probability distribution and we say that the girls and processes that if the distribution is a gas
whiskey dimensions because it's the vector of laxity
this is this is the definition and john said already this morning that that this object exists is not
not a triviality
and it's not
by any means clear that this are actually exist but
the kind of the intuition behind construction of because the results which guarantee that this
this actually works is the following
if you imagine we start from a gaussianprocess
like this right
and we
we look at these possible distributions that we get four different sets of points here
and these distributions are related to each other in some way right they can be
arbitrary because they are all marginal distributions of one and the same infinite dimensional probability
so in particular
if we take
if we take some set of points here
and look at the distribution that we get from that
and then we take a subset of these points
it again
look at the distribution that we get from
then the first is that the second distribution will be a margin of the first one
that makes sense
okay so
these distributions are all marginals of each other
if we take two sets overlap two sets of points that overlap
then once again the marginal on the common set of points
the two marginals on the commons the points that they have in common will coincide
so we have a kind of coherence condition between these different distributions that we get
for different sets of points down here that they all have to marginalize
to produce a
that's simply because they're all marginals of one and the same goes process
if we know all these distributions here
all possible sets of points
then we can ask conversely
if we start with these distributions and they have this coherence property that they're all
marginals of each other doesn't define the gaussianprocess
and there are results in
starting from the data selecting the day the target data for analysis then pre processing
it in an appropriate form trying to eliminate and missing data noisy data irregularities since
forming it into the programme which is appropriate for the data mining tool which we
have selected then we get the patterns or the models
which we have induced from the data and finally we have evaluation hopefully leading to
some use new piece of knowledge and as you see and interactive process when we
return back to different steps trying to improve the data itself and also trying to
improve the data analysis before the final selection and evaluation
so interesting enough the
the process of data mining
although it is the key facing the knowledge discovery process
it only takes a minor part of the entire process in terms of the data
cleaning and preparation is extremely laborious compared to data mining itself
so i'm going out to some
examples of discovered patterns and their applications
this example crowned from large project we were coordinating carpools of stefan institute
this was in the years two thousand to two thousand three the protein was named
data mining and decision support for business competitiveness european virtual enterprise which has been called
it mated by ourselves we had twelve partners involved it was the three million euro
eight academic partners and for business partners from seven different countries in europe
and the idea was to use data mining and decision support for building useful
solutions for end users they were developed until the prototype phase a and that was
covered by the money of the project and we also had the goal of finding
virtual enterprise for marketing data mining and decision support expertise involving business and academia
actually such virtual enterprise model was developed how different partners across europe was
work collaboratively in data mining and decision support tasks
developed ideas how and mechanisms how how to work collaboratively in data mining projects
there was the number of
prototype developments within this project starting from analysis of media research data were our client
was an indiana company we
worked for clean air and clean air
another marketing company trying to improve brand name recognition we worked on the data for
an australian financial house
doing quality evaluation of customers and stock market prediction
four checks check how far we were predicting the use of resources like people going
to a swimming pool people
having massage within hours and how resources will be used for
every week by new people coming to the house farm and then worked for the
UK county council and i will
illustrate the the KDD process also through this application it was the analysis of traffic
accident data of
UK accidents which occurred in twenty years
in the last twenty years
we also did an application for a portuguese statistical bureau about web page
access analysis and the idea was that based on the understanding of how people
the web pages of the statistical bureau can we learn how to improve the web
page organisation
we developed an application for for the zagreb medical centre coronary heart disease risk group
prediction and detection we had an interesting application for a small english company who's doing
online dating
and that requires defining
what is the threat to the public health
if you're mandated tetanus immunization
this is not a communicable disease you need to be clear as to why you're
doing it
is it because of the state's interest to protect children
or because of the cost to take care of people who have to this
you need to
so for some future disease we to explain the rationale
you don't want to mandate a immunization unless there is broad support within the medical
community for
you see that vaccine
the rationale has to be transparent and clear and the process of amending should engage
the public
and the washington state board of health in fact has adopted a series of criteria
with which it will approach future vaccines
decision making about
vaccines needs to be informed
we need to monitor exemption rates
when people
i asked for exemptions we need to understand their reasons
and the process for exemption should be thoughtful we need to discourage what we call
convenience exemptions which is check the box
i object in order to get your child registered for schools
fond of pointing out that in washington state to people to agencies that work for
the governor
work at cross-purposes health department
get kids immunized
the office of public instruction wants to get the kids in school
if you can get in school in most
immunize the school doesn't get paid for their pupils
so somehow we need to remove the financial incentive to opt out in order to
get the child registered for school
also i think we need to employ imposing with some of my colleagues are in
favour of which is what i call irrelevant kernels two exemptions such as having the
parents objections no rights
which i don't think
educated about the risks and benefits
and finally an exemption should be time limited
unless it's for a reversible medical condition
so that people will come back and revisit the issue
and where we have widely held erroneous beliefs perceptions those should be confronted
and the one i would like to just address very quickly is the concept that
multiple vaccines administered simultaneously overwhelmed the immune system
and it's relatively easy to
are to point out the that's fallacious
back when we were using smallpox vaccine whole self protesters vaccine
the number of immunogenic antigens
that we would inject that greatly exceeds
all vaccines that we administer today
we go through that one more time the smallpox virus vaccine has two hundred separate
immunogenic antigens
the vaccines were giving the total
somewhere around one hundred twenty five
so the actual new world is actually less
now i couldn't come to southern california without talking about the problem with selective
an alternative schedule
some new options other than the recommended schedule
one of the
objections to that skip the
schedules are they really undercuts
and then
well that's actually the
test so as the training error i guess
you're thinking of
this is what this is the test error so it's small
it's i mean that's certainly
would be the right estimation on the training set
but what i was looking for was an expression for this in terms of the
probabilities of these events
anyone else have
could be expressed in a way officially i actually was thinking of well let me
let me show you what i was thinking and hopefully will be clear so
if we take that
have to do this
we take that
x y
functions just write a s
essentially we can write that as the
thank you
we can write that as the probability
a s
so the probability that a
as of today
is equal
two y
zero because the loss is zero in that case
the probability that a
of x
is not equal to y
times one because the loss in that case this is just working out their expectations
in terms of the
different events that can occur
remember the discrete loss
it isn't perfectly
can you back and said OK
OK so
that means that of course this
his doesn't occur and it actually just equals
that the function
applied to the
new test point
not equal to the correct
so in other words this
in this case this generalization for the discrete loss
it's just the probability of misclassification
that's all i was trying to
to try that maybe i didn't express
very clearly this just in that case very becomes very simple expression
this is a everyone happy
with the idea
any questions
so i just wanted to get faced by all these i mean one
big problems with theory
is that
because you have to write things down
you get all of this sort of garbage of
and that's just i mean once you get used to it is just to sort
of symbols and the idea is not actually
difficult or complicated really it's is just you get face by simple so part of
it is to just work with a little bit and get
familiar with the symbols in the way that they
so you know this looks horrible horrid but in this case it just it
reduced something very simple
this this is really a very
i think important i need with respect
so this quantity
s a
this is the expected value of the loss on randomly generated test point in the
case of classification is just the probability
the randomly generated point is misclassified
if you think of running your algorithm with the training and test sets your test
set error
which perhaps is also what you're referring to maybe is is an estimate of this
it's the sample estimate based on actually
looking at the track the test examples which you assume again and generated according to
the same distribution so it's a good
estimate of the quantity but from a theoretical point of view we prefer to think
of this as the quantity really interested in is the pure probability of misclassification of
randomly generated
so i want to
try and
give an example of of what this
random variable is how it looks in particular concrete case because i think it if
you can build up a picture in your mind of what this random variable distribution
looks like a lot of learning theory starts to make sense you can see what
what learning theories attempting to achieve so i'm not going to give you an example
which is
real world data
breast cancer dataset from the UCI repository i'm going to do a very simple parzen
window classifier as described by bernard shaw carpet the beginning of his
so the weight vector is actually just this it's a linear function classifier thresholded linear
function the weight vector is just the average of the positive training examples
minus the average of the negative so if you can imagine the you know the
is cloud of positive put
point in the central that a cloud of negative point in the center that join
the two
and bisects the line between
that's the hyperplane that we're can use to classify
OK it's very very simple
and what i'm going to look at is i'm gonna repeatedly draw random
training sets as
and i'm going to get an estimate of this distribution i'm actually going to create
a histogram of the distribution of the errors
so each time i draw a random training set i going
compute the sky of causing i'm going to compute in the way
that we always do
estimating on on the test set
OK i can't help but because it's so you know if you have some
abstract problem where you can define the true error but in our case we got
a concrete
datasets on this can use the test error as a proxy for this
so i'm going
repeatedly generate random training sets
use the remainder of the data as the test set an estimate this quantity after
applying this very simple algorithm
possibly no estimator and i'm going to plot the histogram and the average of the
distribution of this quantity for various sizes of training set
now if i take the whole
dataset then that will give a single value because essentially there's just one function is
the average of the positive and negative and then apply it to the same set
and just just like a sort of if you like
o thing we might aim for the person the best you could possibly do with