can simply compute
i'm just saying that
if a defining white
at equally
of what the
the minus one
x being
they would have to wait
so i had to wait so i have prediction and they have a way of
the next week
i compute this
it doesn't incremental yet
but let me go on but this is something i can do well
so now
if this is this is your decision perception
yes it is because
if a b
the equal
squared norm of the
then the great
of y
who are
which is equal to to the perceptron weight
OK that's reassuring
i can it's kind of
i mean i can i can do this
i can rewrite from using this potential function
i think it's very comforting shows
this is the function in india is very simple
and then OK
i attached so the perceptron weight is the they outgoing
the use of ball
the potential for
why do i find it in terms of the great i don't want to find
because when you when you
look at the first of these potentials
arbitrary from the pensions then you need to do the analysis you need
i'm not sure from complex analysis
any convex analysis if you read enough of it
probably but you realize that it is more natural look back from a functional
like this and then use and then define the way to the gradient of the
a and this is called also the this
function is called the gradient of the potential is coming function
but i'm not going into
more data
you know what to say
the first now
so we have something that might sound my little silly
i mean i cannot be certain about
many interesting prisoners i might be
now it's tempting to think
of p
are you
four being bigger than two
you need for technical
it gets you now agree
it's getting angry
because i just using and not using
for a couple that you put on the
very common
so can analyse doctor
this is something about but more importantly
can i write this incrementally will be night
there would be no radiation incrementally
and so this is actually possible reason i
is true whenever the potential function is chosen in a proper way so i'm now
imposing more conditions the choice of phi
besides being differentiable i would like to be a convex
so now
is differentiable
strictly convex
but as i have a little work
on the
nine of because the conditions that i'm not going to spend because they're overly technical
but all the fraction of that
with a book about which is the problem i was just about to innovation but
it's not for
but that the potential with this
this condition
OK so now if we had this conditions
the gradient
it is
a few
if you like this that you've got to rockafellar
o thing
convex analysis
and you find a lot of
more than you can
the input
basically the inverse exists
and for these nice polynomial potential is easily computable
so now
if i had this
to do the convolution
this is just element wise so no cost
i mean
cost is
it is
is an
and then what
then we have to go back
one more FFT
during the
answer we want
c starting
c convolved with the DNA and you can use it to t
so there were three ffts
transform the inverse transform for three of these
and log ends
and one
but of course
i mean we saved
enormous amount here if we say if this was a factor two hundred quaker
well we had to do three of
but we're way way way way way OK
so that's convolution convolution so actually this is a good if i had to very
very long numbers
or if the computer had suppose we're somewhere
no rounding offered cutting off its sixteen bits or even double precision suppose we're keeping
full precision for for algebraic coding or something then
then we have to do these locations in full
if i what if i want to multiply a hundred and twenty eight digit number
by another hundred twenty digit number well
it's a convolution
and i can use the convolution rule to do
remaining on my
i what's remaining online
list for this lecture
so circulant matrices i want to express this express the convolution as the matrix
well one matrix is multiplying what vector to give that vector
this is nice is happy that we see the three the three
components of the answer now i just want to see it as a matrix multiplication
some metrics
is multiplying some back to give these three is the vector of values
this is
this is the convolution
three components
you could delete the parentheses around them if you like
really it's just three components
and i claim that there is
some matrix
of seas
multiplying some vector of these
these are all d one d two
what's the what's in the first row of the matrix well it must be seen
was the first roman matrix
these are small by the zero
c one should multiply the two
and c two notion of mobility one so
the role of financial the columns
these are all multiplies what
what's the column what's the zeroth column here that these are all multiplies what these
are all i see zero c one and
c two b
and the second one
d one multiply
is zero
and c one
and the third one day two more
this work to do
are you policy one right
c two and these are all well look
the pattern is
this is my circulant matrix this is my second matrix time my vector
the same result as
c involved with d
that's that's my point
these matrices and matrix of that time
of that type is a
convolution matrix
and what do i mean of that type
i mean that
down the it's human we use the word templates
four constant diagonals but this is constant diagonals
modulo three
the first goal is the same as the minus two diagonal
and the second diagonal is the same as the minus one i
so this is that this is a circulant matrix
it's a convolution
the second
cyclic convolution matrix
convolution with wraparound whatever whatever
adjective we
his most expressive
six click periodic wraparound
those are all telling us
it's not five independent diagonals because we don't want five into we don't have five
independent things it's three independent
numbers there
component zero c one c two
i think it's it's really valuable because filters in the next lecture
this afternoon
are going to be
toeplitz matrices
and you'll see
they could be infinite
so no wrap
so on so it's really polynomially smaller than and to love this period
we can't handle the willow case that's a little bit too strong this thing is
really quite a bit smaller
OK but the answer then is really simple
t event
is the data and the largest event
that's case one
is one out n is pretty much equal
so can someone please be very
and by pretty much equal i mean up to
poly log factors
so this is
log base two and to the power k
should know this station
so for example k can be zero and then they are equal up to constant
factors that for some k greater than equals zero
less than one that works is really important nonnegative should probably be an integer
it doesn't actually matter whether is an integer
but there there's could be and will always be a times blog and just nothing
again the solution is easy here
here then
it is and so log
these b
a a times
was only has to be at least times log k
it turns out it's log to the k plus one
that's case two
one more case
just slightly more complicated
to some slightly more
but history is roughly one
f then grows bigger
and log
it's been there
so should be capital mega there's one place we get mega
log base b and what steps along
some positive and so on
so should grow not just bigger but polynomially bigger there was growing just log factor
figure poly log here it's
a polynomial factor
here in this case we need another assumption about f
because we were a little bit about how quickly f grows
we we we want to make sure that as you go down the recursion f
gets smaller
can i said that get smaller as you go down otherwise you're trying to some
to infinity or whatever
i see this some on prime
for some epsilon crime-ridden zero so what i'd like is that if i just sort
of take the recurrence this here and
and just throw in as instead i get you know
f of and
should be somehow related to eight times for over b what i'd like is it
for them which is at the top of the recursion tree should be bigger
the thing at the next level down the sum
of all the values of the next level down should be bigger by some constant
so here i have the the next level down is the most someone minus epsilon
something strictly less than one
some constant strictly less than one
times the thing at the top
i need that to make sure things are getting smaller as i go down then
human is data from
that's the theory is the master
theorem what everyone calls not named after some dining masters just it's master all methods
because it's very easy to apply
so let's apply a few times
it's a bit to it much to take in all at once
and then we'll give you a sketch of the proof
to see it's really not that surprising that this is true
if you look at the recursion tree
but first this just try using it
so for example we can take him and his four times t about two
class and
OK this is a
this is the
this is after that
so the first thing we should compute is and the log based bank
this i think even i can do log base two of four log base two
like this is an square
OK so is f of n smaller or bigger than n square fenders and that's
where it is clearly bigger by a polynomial factor so we're in case one
so what's the answer
and square
it's data and a lot of experience which is here just squared
there some slight variations on going to keep can be the same and just change
let's say to you is four times here and another two
class and square and is like trail in spelling so m squared is is asymptotically
and that small fortunes diffuse flow they change how the shape
changes and that feedback on how the more
hello really it's this
this complex feedbacks between
the the sort of control signals and the structure is being controlled the brings about
the problem of understanding development
a systemic
complex feedbacks
so what this is what i've been talking about
you can see something done
so i think it's quite easy to be glib about these
you know you can say all those the termite mound
that's very big
you can say who does the brain
it's a very you know that powerful computer and you can think about development well
OK start from a single cell and when you grow up person but really when
you look at
when you look at that process unfolding it is
almost unimaginably difficult to understand how
you can start from that very very simple beginning and end up with a thinking
little foetus
you know with with its heart beating and its regulatory system in its nervous network
you know what when i when i studied
psychology as an undergraduate
this is what they should this is pretty much all they showed us about development
because it was
people just didn't know how to explain it to us
i mean it probably did know stuff
but i don't think the psychologist that told me knew anything about development so he
got this the picture for sort of classic picture of embryo genesis
you've got columns this column here is three stages in the development of
fish that says because of the all these words are in german down here you've
got three stages in the development of mensch so people
like in in between you've got
clinching which are rabbits i think really it's not so can should find is the
who is the chicken
is a salamander
i kinda see what this was but i reckon i must say think i think
there must be a tortoise right because it's got kind of cute shell on its
back but i don't know what that word is
sorry to someone know what the what the german for tortoise is right
the thing to notice here is that even though we're looking at a ridiculously diverse
set of creatures during development
they they don't differentiate really until very late on the share a lot of the
same developmental stages
so it so that the rams home this notion that
you know we also probably share a huge number of genes
with across these creatures
so there's a sense that
the kind of DNA centric view that we've we've been five people have tried to
sell us
it's just not going to answer the questions of interest
the interest is not going to be how many genes there are on the genome
what those genes are or even what proteins those genes code for how those proteins
fold into a certain shape or even how those shapes
clunk together
it's going to be
you know that there's a chain of reasoning up to higher and higher structures and
the feedbacks between that's going to have to be addressed and
the amount of money that was spent developing techniques for bioinformatics i think it's really
even touched on
the methods the new methods that we're going to have to generate
if you wanted to cross the
but that one
so got one more slide on development in some sense the thing that's missing from
the DNA story is the recognition of the physics and chemistry that support the processes
that bring about development
so in some sense physics and chemistry define a world space forms that of possible
which forms are closely related to each other
and development is like this of course trajectory through that space
not only certain trajectories are admissible you can't build you can't grow a machine gun
well don't like to show
so is it
the wraps study of a small example of this kind of ideas so right wrote
with only had three with three parameters that he could vary he could simulation could
generate every
the snail shell that we've ever seen
OK just three parameters that government
the rate at which they turn on the extradition of this and i don't know
what they say so there's three d kind of more space which this cube represents
kind point this cube generates a certain
shell shade
he's shaded in problem you might not be able to see what he's shaded in
the parts of the tube but we have seen in real life
so there's class of shells which is this kind of area the top there's another
class of shells which is down here and there's another class which is this dark
green area which she was quite large areas of this space where we've never seen
a shell like that
there are predicted to be
kind of possible
on the back model but we haven't seen them
and this is the this is the only real example of
people being able to successfully
characterise this more prospects i've come across very very simple you know just looking at
shell structure we're not even looking at the
the creature that lives in the shell you know the shell isn't even in part
the to the biological part of the creature
so here's a bunch of hydra
which are closely related aquatic life forms that brian goodwin has studied
i even though these are very closely related they're all part of the same class
of organism they're ridiculously diverse in their structure and the notion is that
there are it's you can you can't really account for this diversity in terms of
genetic diversity they're very genetically they're genetically very very similar to what accounted for this
is that small changes in genes kind of
open up
different parts of this more respect
so you end up with no coincidence with shallow and little nodules on the end
of stems and what have you done although this shell space is fairly intelligible you
know as we move from here upwards the shells get squatter or
tighter something more space isn't going to be intuitive in that sense even even for
the physical structures of organisms can be far more complicated
either that network flow problems or matching problems things like that
they have a special structure that that you know in the supply known theorems and
this is true
it's modular and training objective
we're going to get into answer
thank you
so rule
so we have
good reference for that i think that but nemhauser
and also
so in the book
the talks about but this kind of stuff and and there's a few other conditions
where you can guarantee integrality but but this is by far the most the most
the surface
OK good so
we have a way to write down
the objective and the constraints in in get a linear programs
q said that
is is less than b
that is an integral and so meaning that answers
has the same score as the the otherwise score so we have lost it
same thing here
not sure how many of you passing so go faster this so here you have
this context rules a goes to c and where it starts
and singh were severed splits
so basically these bands st
and c
spence employees want to eat
the chart representation of this
right where he basically
the span from three to five is
covered by
and he
and then
so we will have variables for each span so that can be inscribed in the
three eight spam
they're going to be variable for each possible nonterminal variables that says is that
spam covered by the nonterminals
same thing that for productions
so for each
triplet actually start middle and so there would be
and actually want to seven so what production was that right so this kind of
thing a b c start
they did so super important the ideas though
you can write down the score again like this
you have two sets of variables
at the route to make sure that
the entire sentence from here to and is covered by some nonterminal so somewhere is
equal to one
this is called school inside constraints we say
if i have a covering has to be there
it is going to produce something so as a sum over all possible midpoints and
all possible productions have been c
this is going to be on is one of them is going to be exactly
one of these
when we think about and the other way around if if
s two s and he's covered by age it must be that
this was generated by somebody else either from
from the
and so some of you know somewhere after some generated a four
somewhere before it was catching
so this this is that is going to produce offspring and this is that
it is not an orphan you know is generated by some
roughly speaking
so it turns out these linear constraints again to ensure that
this linear programme is going to give us
integral solution only part
i'm not suggesting you pass linear programs that would be
city so but the point is that you can write down there
objective and constraint in this way and
guarantee that the solutions to
the other thing to note in all these things that i was talking about the
number of variables and constraints is linear in the number of parts so everything is
small as compared to the number of possibilities that we should consider
during the time
so this is the last thing actually
again here this is this is a very simple one we have the decay
since the mapping to logic gates there's no one to one mapping between licensees
positive and the degree constraint right that at most one of the maps and most
one of the maps
and we again we don't constraint equals to one
as a function of the number of rounds but i've switched to a logarithmic scale
if you just run c four point five by itself it gets the test error
rate of about thirteen percent that's the line with at the top there
as expected the training year goes down very quickly in fact after only five rounds
the training area is zero we perfectly the training set
what about the test error
well the test there
also drops as expected but it keeps on dropping dropping dropping dropping even after thousand
rounds the test there has not started to go up again
and this is kind of amazing because
active run this per thousand rounds you're talking about some more than two million decision
tree nodes so in terms of just the raw number of parameters
this model is absolutely enormous and extremely complicated and yet it's giving very very good
performance as we see over here
what's even more surprising is that protesters continuing to drop even after the training year
is zero
if you look at the training year after five rounds the training year zero and
it stays zero
now if you think about occam's razor predicts
here you have one model
which consists of five decision trees
accuracy on the training set
here's another model two hundred times bigger
it's a thousand decision trees also perfect accuracy on the training set
this one two hundred times more complex
occam's razor says this one should certainly give better test performance
but we see exactly the opposite happening instead the test there's a point four percent
and about three percent here
so i can raise are just seems wrong in this case
good question
i don't know how you measure that it's real data this is actually
well stated that derived from OCR data
eight four cold
well are supposed to be the right answers but usually with any training set there
is almost always a mistake of some kind
so it's so nobody has gone in and deliberately added noise that's what you're asking
because it's real data i would expect that there are probably there might well be
mistakes and some ambiguous examples it but i don't know for sure
right well e so your intuition is right so if you do an experiment was
going to talk about this later but if you do an experiment where you deliberately
add noise
to the data
when you add that is uniformly over your entire space
then then that does cause problems for adaboost because what it does
like you're getting at is that it focuses on the hardest examples so it's really
spinning its wheels on these really hard examples
and so that does happen and there's been various research on how to
try to make it more resistant to that kind of noise for robust to that
kind of noise but on the other hand
you know that's an artificial experiment where you artificially and noise on the other hand
on actual data sets which are certain certainly have some kind of noise and it's
performing well which suggests to me that our model of noise
is not very good the model of noise that says you have people noise everywhere
in your space probably is not realistic prior what's more realistic is that there are
some examples near the true decision boundary whatever that means
which are
more likely to
more susceptible to noise than ones which are far
OK that's one t epsilon t is the area of the weak classifiers
OK if the weak classifiers in the this is the area of the combined classifier
even after the combined classifier has training year zero
weak classifiers
i still have significant air so in this case the weak classifiers happy run this
a few times the weak classifiers will have air somewhere around thirty percent
OK so that stays large so you can continue reweighting the examples and so on
well neural networks
neural networks are quite susceptible to overfitting decision tree algorithms are susceptible to overfitting
it depends here so other
ensemble there are other ensemble method algorithms which do not overfit so for instance there's
bagging and random forests
they will also tend not to over fit you'll tend to get behavior somewhat like
it depends on the algorithm
but this
does that into question
so the inner portion of the solenoid and that's not changing
and so when i changed the shape of this outer loop you will not see
any change
in the
i hope you
it doesn't confuse you i'm going to purposely change the
the size of the
so i'm going to do that now
to see there
very sensitive
and commuter
you're going to see here
this loop
big choir
and i'm going to just put it
over this
the first
make sure to my
beta which is extremely sensitive i can zero it
signed sensitivity the current goes in one direction you will see the needle going one
if the current go in directions you'll see
the change
so now i put this
loop around here
crazy shape this loop
so it's around this
so it once
so the magnetic field is inside the solenoid
so think of the surface which is attached to this crazy loop
and now i'm going to
during the current all and only while the current is changing will be changing magnetic
flux only doing that portion will use the current flow
three two one zero
i will break the current three two one zero
when do the direction
if i change the size of the loop
i'm making no difference
much smaller makes no difference for reasons that i explained to you because the magnetic
is not the tournament in this case
by the size of my loop but is determined by
the solar or so if i do it again now
it was very different shape of the
i mean zero this again
three two one zero
no change almost the same which is so before
now comes something
that may not be so intuitive to you
i'm not going to read this wire three times around
and so this outer loop
these outer
conducting wire
it's not like this
something like that
now i have to attach in my head
a surface
two this
my god what does it look like
what a ridiculous surface
well that's your problem not fire this problems
how can you imagine
that is the surface attached to this loop
well i think the whole thing independent so
take it out and see what you see
the so attach everywhere
on the conducting loop
and if there is room for like this
going up like a spiral staircase
you're going surface it goes up like this
but the magnetic fields go through all three of them
the change in magnetic
we'll go three times taller surface now
finally says
i find that you're going to see three times the EMF that you would see
if there were only one loop
and if you go thousand times around
you get a thousand times the EMF of one will not so intuitive
i'm around now once
i go around twice
and i go around the third time
i three loops around it now
i can see that but that's not so important
three two one zero
so much larger currents
about three times larger with the math is three times larger i break the current
you see three times larger and this is the idea behind
you can get any
imagine that while that you want to
by having
many many
no you can get a two thousands of false
and that's not so intuitive
so far this law
it's very nonintuitive
the usual rule
i was very intuitive piece of said when you go around the circuit
closed loop in the goal of you don't dl is always zero
not through
if you have the changing
magnetic flux
if you ever changing magnetic flux the electric field
inside the conducting wires
now become
non conservative
he is from rule only holds as long as the electric fields are conservative
if an electric field is conservative you go from point one to point two
and i really don't know
is independent of the past
that's the potential difference between two points that uniquely defined that's no longer the case
if you go on the ground once was
this experiment you get opinion you may have you go three times around you get
different about you're
pass is now different
and that's very nonintuitive
because you're dealing
was known conservative field for which we have very little feeling
i'm going to blow your mind
i'm going to make you see something that you won't believe
so try to follow step by step
leading up to this
and very nonintuitive result
i have here a battery
and the battery has an EMF
of one class
here is the resistor
i one
which is one of
user resistor
are two
which is nine hundred ohms
and i'm asking you
what is the current that is flowing around you will laugh at me you'll see
that's almost an insult
we should given that problem
at the first example
he e equals the current that is going to run
divided by our one
plus our
oh my goodness what did i do
i i forgot was law equals i ior remember not i over or
so are we close our two
should go upstairs
and everything that follows is correct so you don't have to worry about that this
was just a big slip of the pen
and so the current i
is ten to the minus three and these
one million
thank you
current is going to flow like this
in linear spaces
OK of
of linear functions in our
it's going to become canonical once use the car
every finite set of data points living in an infinite dimensional space is going to
be separable
there is no real reason to introduce slack variables at all want use the current
we always use slack variables when music
so there the minimum norm solution which exists
in the reproducing kernel hilbert spaces become clearer once we see the reproducing kernel hilbert
space and that is the regularized solution which also exists in this reproducing kernel hilbert
you will always use in practice the regularized solution
so the real reason these things are working is because of regularisation
the minimum norm solution is always telling you give me the minimum norm solution that
is consistent with the data
so you empirical error of the minimum norm solution is always roughly speaking zero
once use the kernel the minimum norm solution exists the maximum margin classifiers so to
speak in this infinite dimensional space exists
but is never actually used in practice
so that point is sort of an important point two
so i give it two algorithms which are motivated by
trying to come up with the linear function that fits the data
are tries to to classify the data
and i showed you that there is no ordinary least squares this ordinary least squares
they may not be unique solution therefore you have two options taken minimum norm solution
or take this regularized least squares solution
and actually also have tried to emphasise the minimum norm solution will always be more
or less zero in particular solution
the same is true for support vector machines you have the minimum norm solution which
is the maximum margin classifiers
which should always zero loss classifier
or regularize classifier
now there are other loss functions you can throw in one common loss function that
you could actually throwing is this so-called logistic loss
depending upon your favourite loss function you can always put that in and you have
an optimisation problem that makes sense
and what we would now like to to do is go beyond linear functions
so we saw that there was the bayes optimal classifier if star
and this is optimal classifier main
not to be linear
maybe some very complicated function
so we would like to actually
you have
a class of functions that have the ability to represent arbitrarily complex
so we would like to reach cluster that functions with which to make predictions
and now there are many classes which are non-linear
that you can use polynomials you can use trigonometric functions continuous functions differentiable functions and
all the functional analysis now set loose on this problem
so you might ask what properties would like from such a class
OK so that we have a well
behaved algorithms
so here are some desirable properties
so first of all it should be a rich class with good approximation part because
that after all is the real reason why we are going to consider
these more complicated function
the second property we would like that
script there should actually have some sort of the linear structure and we can add
subtract functions and we can do nice things the kind of things you can do
with linear functions
so you want don't want to make complicated functions with spherical boundary that you can
then add and so on
and the third property we would like to have this we would like it to
have an inner product structure
so that we can take projections
now if you actually follow
the development of linear classifiers you see that taking projections is a very important step
it's a very important step in another thing we did not discuss
which is the perceptron learning algorithm which maybe some of you are familiar with
it would take too much time to actually describe it to you
but in the perceptron learning algorithm you show that it converges by actually
making use of the inner product structure on the vector space rk
and in many other settings you would actually like this inner product structure so that
we have projections
and so
essentially would like then ultimately use hilbert space
it's linear
complete vector space
with inner product OK
and let me just say a few words about hilbert space just it's intuitively very
clear i think some of you should know it already
for those
who who don't
in our
which is the canonical there are n
given a vector w and given a vector u
you have this inner product and w which is given by
what how
united is the w docu which is some asian WI
and the inner product is
over the years is going to be
two on a space h
there may be connections between the way wave generated the data and so on
but if we take a sort of simple case are trying to classify cancerous tissue
from healthy tissue we can imagine there are two distributions cells that are generated from
the that are actually not cancerous and those that are cancerous
and assuming there's some process by which we select individuals take samples from those individuals
and measure those cells
then we might
i expect those samples are indeed i i d
and we just have a random
sample but you can be sure think of ways in which that wouldn't be the
very quickly
noticeable effects that will come from particular population of visiting hospital et cetera et cetera
so we have in these in this sort of theory of statistical learning theory we're
we're sort of making that distribution
the repository of all that we're interested in everything that we're interested in is is
represented in that distribution is the way in which the processes of the natural artificial
world was studying are
given to us through that distribution
how we access it as i've already said through a training sample
so it's a set of data and i'm already thinking of the classification
or at least the
supervised learning case where we have an input and an output we're interested in predicting
so here's the first example and here is the and for example i tend to
use and the number of training
examples which is
at odds with the way
statisticians were afraid and and some other learning areas but
it may be worth
trying to
more coordinated with other with statisticians perhaps at some point
anyway this is the the training sample which we assume is generated i i d
from the underlying distribution p
so really the task of learning is saying i've got this
finite set of information about which is sort of coloured by p
and what i want to do
is learned something about p that's true in in general
independent of that particular sample
so i'm going to talk now about
the generalisation of a learner because this is a way for classification and probably progression
two is the key concept
the we're we're interested in
statistical learning theory
so i'm going to spend a little bit of time looking at it and i'm
also going to plot some curves to show how it looks
for some learning problems
so i think that will give us hopefully a kind of insight into what learning
theory is actually trying to
to to give us so if we have a learning algorithm a
then what it does is it takes the training set as
and typically selects from some function space f
a function
that it considers the right function for that
training set so it does the best fit it may be an empirical risk it
may be regularized risk or whatever
method that it has has built into it that selects the function
two best fit from that training set
and now what we're interested in is how well that function performs on new data
how really how really good is that function became a fit on the training set
but is it good on on new data
and this is the idea of the generalisation and so
this is this quantity abseil on of as a path
but i i'm writing here which is the expectation under randomly generated new point new
test point of the loss
of that function when applied to x and compared with the correct output y so
x what a while the core a given input output generated according to the distribution
a if s is the function we learned and the loss is telling us how
that function fits so this is the expectation if you like a loss
as we start to use that
that learned function in
in practice
and if we think classification the loss would just be
one of the two
values disagreed
and zero otherwise
well for regression it might be the squared difference between the function applied to x
and the the correct output
so this is a random variable is is we're going to call this the generalisation
of the learner but note that is the random variable because it depends on the
training set as
which is a random quantity
remember it's generated i i d from the same distribution
so so we now
i have a random variable which was thinking of as the
the generalizations so it's
something that will depend on the training set
and what we're really interested in is not being screwed up by training set
so we want to guard against being screwed up training set in
in this in this measure
so what i'm going do is show you now an example of where things go
wrong if we have a rather simplistic learning algorithm
and how
you know
we can get quite bad performance from different training sets
and so this is again a taking this idea the breast cancer dataset from UCI
and we just going to use a very simple parzen window classifier
w class is the average of the positive training examples w minus average of the
negative training examples
and just
creator weight vector
between those two
now we
is the average of the negative since the average to positive
draw drawing
vector between them
take the bisecting hyperplane
that's the classifier that i'm i'm thinking of here is a very simplistic
we can apply it to
this training data
now we wanted to actually measure the expected value of on on a randomly drawn
test points so
i'm just going to use the
you know the second half of the sample we didn't used for training as the
testing half so it's a proxy for the true generalisation error in this case
and that's the way to estimate this quantity
and i'm going to do it
four different training set sizes
this is half of the data
and so on
the idea is i'm going to repeatedly draw
samples of these of say this size here three hundred forty two
use that algorithm
two generated classifiers
and then tested on
the remaining data so every time i do that i get one
generalisation error one sample from that random variable here
i'm assuming m fixed case i'm choosing the sample size is fixed here
but obviously every time i draw samples that size i get different value of this
so i'm not going to repeatedly draw that you know it's a thousand
ten thousand times
and i'm going to keep the histogram of those values
so we can see the kind of errors were getting
and the range of errors we get from different training sets you know we may
be lucky on some training sets to do very well
so we do very badly and so on
and just to sort of give you an idea of how well
this particular algorithm can do i'm gonna first show you
the performance on the complete training sets you know just
test error in this case
so that's this
here the sort of thing
o point one five is approximately the area you get if you just
train on all of the data
know that the
the solution announcement i'm supposed to give a series of lectures standing at four o'clock
and the title is machine learning flavors of random matrices which in retrospect seems to
be quite technical
so just to ensure to let everybody know that actually is going to elementary and
much less than normal exercises so
that's OK
OK so
not trying to be able to compete with that afternoon session
so my first i just wanted to
revisit this slide and maybe a couple of points of people ask me afterwards
throughout the things i have clarified
i think about
i think the double sample trick you know it really is a matter of just
looking at those
the equations and convince yourself that goes through
so the intuition is really
because the second sample somehow independent of the
choice of f the probability that there is a very significant deviation between it's true
error and it's error on the second sample is too small
that's basically what's behind
this one i think maybe
it is more crucial and that's where where you are now using the fact that
really all the information that we're
conditioning on
there were interested in is relating to the performance of the
function on the two samples x and y
here's text here is why
and that enables us to move from a potentially uncountable number functions to a finite
number and perhaps i didn't emphasise that quite enough and i just want to illustrate
it with
maybe some linear functions just to show you that
what is happening
so if you imagine
you know you've got
a two-dimensional
input space with some positive and negative examples
when you do that conditioning onto the i mean this is the double sample thinking
both positive and sorry both the you know for sample and the second sample once
you've project you're only interested in what the functions do on those examples these two
blue functions are effectively the same function
as far as the
conditioning is concerned they behave identically so you can treat them as just a single
although the different weight vectors they behave identically on the sample
and this is where you getting the contraction effectively the function space to just to
finite set of functions similarly these two red ones
you know they behave identically they do the same classification of all these points and
so they look identical as far as the actual
probabilities that you're estimating a concern
OK so that's that's what is meant by that
but step there
where we move from this case here
and we apply the union bound over the number of different
behaviors that we can observe on the double sample and that number is measured by
this growth function if remember two n
that's actually the number of different behaviours on o two m sample
the highest number and again somebody asked his ph of two and a ph and
the maximum yes
the age of and is the upper bound on obviously for a particular sample you
may actually have fewer functions that allow
for a particular set of points bishop and saying they cannot be more than the
number of different functions on the set of points OK
so that's and the other point that
somebody raised is what happens if you consider the case where
you know the of two and is still
the maximal you know to to the eigenvalue
can you get anywhere and we'll see what we get to the end of the
proof that actually no we can't i mean it it ends up totally trivial in
that case it's only by you know
something in this sort of
polynomial bound on the growth function that we actually going to get a win and
get the statistical result
OK so we're now in shape to go forward into symmetrisation this is the next
keywords you need the cocktail party to impress people
very good
OK so we had a few already in double sample goes socialisation so
now this is again
very nice i think trick i hope you'll agree when i see it is not
difficult thing to understand once you've seen it but
to come up with
amazing OK so
if we consider to a sample s since the points generated independently were making this
independence assumption of the way the points are generated
the probability of generating the same set of points in a different order
is equal to the probability generating that particular sets say we had points x one
x two x three
the chances that we actually generated x two x one x three is identical
i mean it's it's just happen to get in a different order
OK and that is true for any reordering of the set of sample points
and consider now set sigma of permutations
pushing more flow down the pipeline that is not yet capacity and so the algorithms
that actually do this have they have the feel of the search algorithm which are
all the time looking for
the next bit pipeline could take more flowing
and this is all going to work
o point lines all have positive capacity and it's analogy is a bit hard to
something what the negative class would mean but certainly in the original problem where i
was just talking about graphs and edges no particular reason why you shouldn't put negative
costs on the on the edges and
even though that's a little hard to visualise but what you can see is where
where the weather are just positive costs in the pipeline analogy is invalid this algorithm
in a sense can't go wrong if you keep on
that successive steps of your algorithm increasing the flow somewhere in the network and provide
you increase it by finite steps you must eventually reach the bound which is the
total capacity the network to provided the network has a finite capacity and provided you're
increasing by least one unit capacity at every step of this algorithm which is considered
continue seeking to increase flow then the algorithm must converge
so it seems like the positive
but the the versions the problem with the weights positive must be more tractable
then the other ones and so this is NP hard result is that applies to
the problem in all generality where the weights on the edges may be negative but
if you restrict to the case where the weights on the edges have to be
positive it turns out that tractable subset of this whole space problems
so OK you know let's let's do one in our home laboratory here
just to make it quite clear how all this works is my toy problem on
two nodes
and here is the energy we're going to find evidence to nodes with the likelihood
for each of the nodes and just one
i seem to cross the nodes and you know it just shows some numbers here
so the cost of assigning the node to the to the sink x equals zero
i will say that two so the two goes here remember you but it opposite
the sink not doesn't go here goes here
when you cut this that signing that guy to the sink
and similarly f f one of one that's the cost of assigning the node to
to the foreground that cost goes here and similarly for the other two that costs
and then take on gamma records one in the ising model
so the penalty for making different assignments across these two nodes is well
so now let's try to cut this network just you know cut chosen at random
this cut corresponds to a trial solution is assigns x two to zero signs x
one to one
and the energy of the solution we can get just by
adding up the
the costs and all the edges that we cut so there's seven here one here
five here
adds up to thirteen
and so the cost of this particular trial solution will be thirteen
OK now that's not necessarily the best one because i just sort of shows around
them as an illustration but now let's actually solve by using max flow
and yes one thing i didn't say which i should point out is that when
you do this max flow
so you push as much oil as you can see the network you pushed him
you pushed new person you can't get any harder so you've got the maximum flow
of oil
and you know that's the minimum cost e are you happy
no you're not happy because you actually want to know what the minimum cost was
you want to know what the configuration that achieves the minimum cost so we need
a little bit more this out this this situation it turns out that the
the minimum cut
the set of edges which is saturated under this maximum flow so you push your
britain you push you mark when you push or you can mark all the edges
where the flow is saturated that is the flow through the network equals the capacity
that little piece of the pipeline and that guy is going to that particular edge
the saturation one is part of the cuts the cut will pass through all the
saturated as you see i mark saturated is dark blue here and they coincide with
all the places where the cut passes
OK so now let's let's do it let's push flow
come on
so to begin with there is no flow the red numbers of the amount of
flow the blue numbers of the capacities of each of the these pipeline so you
know your search algorithm might start the source and and begin by looking for
edges which have some spare capacity where the flow does not leave capacity and choose
one which one we choose yes this one is on the capacity so let's try
pushing some flow
through that edge may be up to its capacity but be well because they might
not be anywhere for that flow to go
the output and so this is sort of optimistic amount of flow at this stage
but then you look at the output from the next node in UCI as this
an edge with respect and st they choose this one and then you might have
had to look at some more nodes but actually in this particular case we arrived
at the sink and so few home and dry we can we found the complete
path from source to sink which was under capacity and now we can push flow
down that path
now you go back to repeat the process now with the residual graph so that's
like you subtract all of the flows of the past is that you have defined
graph saint apology but with different capacities because now there all reduced by the amount
of flow you've established so far
now we look for something pushing to do when you find you can push we
could push five units down here but when you get to hear
you look for they may be the best outflow path and you see that's what
have is only three units so
you can't use all of these five units only three and you push the flow
three through to the sink
and there is still not finished because in the residual graph
they'll be two spare units of capacity here
and so you search again you find out there is an edge with two is
faster and then you get to hear you try this i don't know
units capacity in the residual graph here so but looking a bit further you see
edge with some residual capacity only one unit but hey let's use it and you
go along there and then is anywhere any outflow possible from here yes the still
some residual capacity here has go down here and
you establish another unit to fly
and now you go back and you do some more searching and you probably visit
this graph edge again because you see it stories residual capacity of one unit you
go down there but then we get to hear you see there's no edges left
residual capacity so you can't push any more flow
so the algorithm stops
and you know it was guaranteed that it would stop because every step
we increase the
the flow by least one unit and the
all of the edges have positive flows so the total financial flows the total capacity
of the graph this is finite so you must reach
you must reach
convergence in finite number of steps
and the only thing left to do now is to mark which are the saturated
paths because that's going to define the optimal cut so those are all the paths
o show and now
this theorem
which is sometimes not called the theorem sometimes called just dilemma
it has so many different names that goes y
both sides lambda
bernstein's counting theorem
or order theorem that's not the inside
because the sciences
he has
classical book on group theory
and people joke normally that all theorems are but inside
so and because this one was made by
it seems because she frobenius
so they call this the theorem that's not the inside
but the proof
some of the most you know
you approve of the
in book form was
in the
virus cycle
so what this theorem tells us
is that
it's very easy to the number of all of the number of orbits
the action of the group
of the number of fixed points
by that action
so in symbols you write this
this first us
the first symbol
is there not confuse this with the
notation for
four of course
this the bars in other
this here is the number of orbits
the left side
the other side you see
why whites average because have this division by the order of the group
what is some
over all elements of the group
his son something new something
the number of
of something
which is
the fix it
the fix subspace i we define this summer
but you've got to this this is the mean of all these x
with g
in the superscript
so this is the theorem is called
clock counting theory
one is
so before going to the proof going to give you an example of this
well you
visualize this first
it's nice to talk with the question
imagine you have you have accused
with and have three callers
you want to know
what the number
of different cube
we charge
rotation only
of each other
you just color kids with these three colors the color of them
and then you want to know how many of them are different
in the sense that you cannot
try rotate one
and get what they want
all possible
colorings of the two
it gives you on seven hundred twenty nine
color kid
but that this is not proper
coloring of his proper coloring and the
two i just sense faces cannot have the same color here we can put the
called we want
so two years the theorem
we need to count
five although
think set elements by the action of the group in this case here we are
dealing with
the group here is a continuous group subgroup of rotations
the group of our patient has infinite many elements
you can rotate by a very small anglican faith by a real number actually
so simple
but still former group has
product you can add
a rotation plus another dish composed of another revisionist two rotations
this here will be
clear with picture
i will explain this
this eight
route eight hundred and twenty degrees
that rotation what is back rotation in this picture here
x of rotation it's an next that cross the the cube
through the diagonal
but this is a huge amounts of unstructured data on the taxing on the website
things like sets up dates or descriptions of photos and links being shared with efficient
and so this is mostly you
textual content that people are writing form and
also of going to the which are two
there's pixels
and the centrifugal force to the user
four years you to go and
and that's what twenty two
i get some semantic meaning of it and so
one of the goals that we've been working on the same thing as much as
so let me
just use the
just a few examples of these things that talk about this structured data category
so the first one is obviously different so there's always not to people
we have million users and they all have something like a hundred and thirty pounds
and you have this
a large amount something like sixty billion edges
so that's the foundation everything else
the next biggest part of the soviet is pages
so it turns out the pages the page that is almost as big as the
and so you can find resources but this is a page about gaga but was
pages three and is about all sorts of activities and i want to do this
operation in wikipedia where we can download all wikipedia pages for all of the articles
it's all of these things are for sparse objects within this but you can go
on like that
but it was also used it and
you can think this this bipartite graph for people to photos
for every
it's connected to its owner and also connected to other people i
and the last in the long here is
places it's sort of a new product is but
it's a very exciting because it has these new dimensions of the where you were
when you that
so when we think of places just as
with the explosive i wanted to that
because they have the information and means that whenever you go into second place
know we now know that you're at the right time and we can use that
very specific
it's not the case in the market
so then finally first of all these are
but this is the IMDB page four
this movie which i like
and you can see here in the right
this will also fifth with so now
whenever you are browsing the web you'll see these things on the becoming ubiquitous that
you can go and like the page and that two
this random web pages on the web
so the when used the
we have all these relationships between the individuals and objects and various other acts
it gives us the future of structure in this part of the graph
and the structure let's do interesting it's not just the nodes and edges but
all these nodes have some sort of information and the edges also have some of
the edges have direction in in some cases in a different graph alpha timestamp attached
to them when they created
and then we can think of the structured and combine into anything you want and
that's what's this sometimes extract meaning from the context wouldn't otherwise be able to
so this is nice simple picture where everything is just nodes edges and it's all
very rosy in
everything make sense
but the relative prices of complexity
there's a number of challenges that would be more than one this one this this
a unifying different is mean the same thing
so these are three different pages are all about the same movie
one then
it is one of them is from IMDB
in one of them is it which is the wikipedia space
of course all these refer to the same is true is
in the sixties
and we would like to do is know that you know if you like the
first one it's sort of the same things like any other
and the first unfortunately
this isn't
the information is isn't
readily available
and so we have to go to some of the rotten tomatoes nine over movie
sites and percentile this is certainly the case
where you can go and see if you like in one of the same like
any other
so there is this the way he happens i checked in my life
and when i have been there for all all the these other
and therefore
and the first there's only one happens for
but people have got to this place and they take in different ways that in
athens international airport at the airport increase or decrease version
all these things
so one of the challenges we have is that these entities are being created by
and so how can we go through treat and provide but tools
times y rules
the nailsea e
time zero
and this is a of x times x is really affected ones from the origin
to this point
so we could put in that as the vector if you want to is make
it the vector
this is that vector
a y times always sorry is a of x is this one
a y times y roof is this one
and a of the time zero is this one
so the three green vector was added together
exactly identical
to the vector of p
we've decomposed one vector
in two three
we will see that very often
this is of great use in one
the magnitude
of the vector
the square root
a x squared
a white screen
there is a least squared
and so we can
take a simple
for instance
i take effect or a
this is just an example
see this in action
and we call a
three x roof
so a of xt three
minus five why rules
six c
so what it means
three units in this direction
it is
five units in this direction in the minors y direction
and six in the policy direction that makes up vector
and i call that vector
a what is the magnitude of the vector which are always write down
with vertical bars if i put two bars on one side
that's always the magnitude
or sometimes i simply leave the arrow of
but to be always on the safe side
i like this idea that you know it's really the magnitude
becomes scalar when you do that
so that would be the square root
of three squares nine
five squares twenty five
six square thirty six the discriminant of seven
and suppose i asked you
what is data
uniquely determined of course is vector is uniquely determined in three-dimensional space
you should be able to find finer data
the cosine of fatah
it is angle here
ninety degrees
so the cosine of data
is a of the divided by itself
the cosine of data
quality of the divided by self which in our case
three six
divided by the square
you can do five
just simply matter
some numbers
we not come to a much more difficult part
o vectors
and that this
multiplication of vectors
we're not going to need to this
until october
but i decided we might as well get it over with now
now to introduce factors can add and subtract you might as well learn about multiplication
sort of the job is done is like going to the dentist is a little
painful but it's good for you
is behind
the pain
this appears
so i'm going to talk about multiplication
o vector something that will not come back
until october
and later in the course
there are two ways that we multiply vectors
and one is called
the dot product
often also called
the skater
doctor b
in fact not
and that's the find
as it is the scalar
a of x times the of x is the number
was a of y
nine b of y
it's another number
was a of the
time to BFC that's an odd number this scalar
has no longer the direction
that is
the dot product
but as method number one that's completely legitimate you can always use that
there is another way to find
the dot product depending upon
what you being given out to problem is presented to you
if someone gives you
the vector a
you have the vector b
you happen to know this angle between them this angle theta which has nothing to
do with that angle theta
the angle between the two
the dot product
is also the following
so this instrument is not
was our danger
but that of course makes it more exciting to work with
so is this super emeralds
what i will do first
now is to put some
on top
and then we turn on the then graph
the confetti may at first go to the
charge domain is already on top of it and when it picks up some of
the charge
it will then spread out because it
it will repel
so let's get some
light on their
which will make it a little bit better to see
they put some of this
on top
it's just regular confetti
pieces of paper
right now all i have to remember is how to
by the
most of the action has already occurred
i will put a little bit more on
he was part
don't worry
the world
nothing left for the second class
making perhaps a little darker
hard it's too dark
OK i tried once more to the that
so look at the confetti on top
i think it's quite convincing some of the fairly will stay there
well that's
the reason that is not a good conductor
so to get a first something and it doesn't get a chance of the telegraph
then it will not
spread out
all right
that's right
for the first time to be
a little bit more quality
if i take
two charges
and we use in general we use are symbol q
so here we have q one
and here we have q two
and let's say they are separated
distance are
and the
unit vector
in the direction from one to two
i call that are
one two
the roof stands for unit vectors
if these charges equal both minors of both plus
then they were repelled
each other
so here is the force f
which i call two
is the force on two do number one
and since
actually equals minus reaction
voice here
is to run equal in magnitude but hundred eighty degrees the opposite direction
cool coulomb
french physicist
we did a lot of research on this in the nineteen
eighteenth century actually
the following relationship
that the forces
is proportional to the product of the charges
so it's q one times q two
times a constant which nowadays we call graphs constants k
divided by the distance between these charges square
and this is the direction
of the unit vector
it goes from one to two this is the force on number two
o to one
and notice that this equation is signed sensitive
because if q one and q two are both negative
the sources into the forces in this direction
and if they both positive it's also in this way
as i have
however if this if one is positive and one negative
get mine in this direction so this force flips over
and and that's one then obviously also flexible so
and yes i units
in this course
we will use for the unit of charge the coulomb named after this great man
one cool charges how well does amount of charge more than you ever see in
your lifetime
we normally work was micro sometimes even less than that
the charge of one proton
which is exactly the same as the charge of one electron
it is approximately one point six
times ten to the minus
nineteen cool
so one could always something like six times ten to the eighteen
or electrons if the charge is negative
this constant k
SR units
is nine
times ten to the ninth
and the unit you can find out because you know that
this is
this is cool squares and this square metres
the unit is noted
o square meters
square meter
divided by square cool that's not so important no one ever things of it that
for historical reasons
which may at times be pain in the neck for you
we write for k
divided by
four by
actually non-zero
there's nothing magic about that
it's just a historical reasons
and so one divided by four pi epsilon zero is nine times ten to the
ninth that's all that matters
it's actually non-zero has name is called the permittivity of free space
but you can forget about that is not important in a
notice that there is a clear parallel with gravity
law of gravity
but the force which in that case is always attracting
gravity never repelled
it is the product of two masses
and then you have your
the gravitational constant and again you have
the distance squared
so there's an enormous parallel between the two is a great beauty
the electricity
x in a way that is very parallel to the way that
gravity works
if i edit a
the third charge
for instance he q three
and if now i want to know what the forces on
so i'm going to start at
where we left off with frame based directed models and
because we've gone over the directed rule based approaches i'm going to try and go
a little bit faster here
two main
approaches and there are the work of probabilistic relational models and some more recent work
probabilistic entity relationship models which is by
recommend at all which is also very nice work on that one actually does do
a mix of some of the directed and undirected approaches as well
i mean it
in this
section mainly focus on probabilistic relational models and
i'm mean first go through
the most vanilla version of probabilistic relational models and then i'm going to
talk about inference learning
and then i'm going to talk about kind
probabilistic relational model that allows a little bit more
a richer probability distributions over structure
both for structural uncertainty and for the case we have a class hierarchy
and then
after that i'm going to go over and directed approaches
before the end of the tutorial
in these systems rather than starting off with the set of rules one starts off
with some sort of representation of
objects in the domain and the relations so you can think of this as the
database schema or
as a ontology
entity relationship model but the important thing is i have a description other kinds of
now you can kind of see
from the earlier propositional example
where i had
i have now broken into others
and papers
in addition to the objects of course i have attributes of the objects and i
have the potential relationships between them
when i describe directed graphical model
this works
very similar to the business from before
are a few important differences
for example
when i say
that this attribute accepted
has parents
the quality of the paper and the mood
in this case
i have to specify
when i'm going outside of the object
what relationship i followed to get to that attribute and now in this case it's
trivial because there's only one potential relationship between the paper and the review but you
can think of something where there's papers and authors and there's multiple kinds of relationships
between papers and authors and so it would have to specify which of those i
was actually making use
beyond that though again just like the base have conditional
probability table here
another important difference here
that this is all specified kind of that
class level so it's up at a higher level of abstraction
and to actually
get the underlying semantics
probabilistic relational model i have to tell you something about what the random variables are
so in that case
the bayesian logic programs the rules
and the instantiations for the rules told you what the random variables were going to
be in the probability distribution
in this case
relational skeleton
it's something that tells me
for each
what are the
what's the domain
what are the space and different authors and this
can teeny tiny example i see have to others
what are the papers
how many reviews to have
so it tells me for each class harmony
objects do i have in that class
in addition
the relational skeleton
besides time e
the numbers of objects in each class
at least for now
what i'm doing the simplest semantics for
i'm going to say that it also tells me
the relationships that hold between objects so
i'm saying that i know the authors of the papers
and i know
the reviews associated with the papers and sorry i can switch from reviews
reviewers to reviews
and if you want to put this in database lingo
and what i'm saying when i say the risk relational skeleton is given to you
is i'm saying
i'm telling you the primary keys of other relations
and the foreign keys
all the relations and another way this can be instantiated as background theory have the
background theory with the background theory tells me what
are the objects and what are the relationships between objects
appear and we attribute uncertainty
it takes the relational skeleton together with
that template
the bayes net and together
that can be seen
defining the set of random variables that you have a distribution over
the distribution is over instantiations of attributes of all the objects that were mentioned
and the relational schema
to get to the point that we talked about earlier with a more kind of
pictorial example
the parameters are used in multiple in places over and over in the bayes here's
a little fragment
not so large but
and rolled
corresponding to the here and so if i have the
the case
paper two
and whether or not it accepted one can use the
conditional probability table there was defined in the period
but now
i'm going to look at the particular context
and they looked at
what the instantiations for the parents are so suppose
for some reason it turns out that
the moon
of the reviewer here was not very good
and then they put it through something and then they develop it all simultaneously using
these very complex things so in a couple of hours
they can get millions of test results
each of which with human looks at that
a long time for the human to figure out what's going on
and is that a
they can generate an hour something that will keep a trained human busy for years
and they must be that every hour
because what a drug company
succeeds or fails by nowadays is do they find the right ones of these so
i am i have a hypothesis that
to cure this particular thing
i need something that will
it's called binding in this particular place
and something that buying in this particular place i know must
not like water
much like oxygen and must have three cove and again they these complex expressions so
what i do
it is using all an ontology language
i can build a very complex set of things which says
anything that has this property cannot possibly have that property
everything must have one of these four properties nothing can have more than two of
these properties if you have one of these properties you must also have one of
those properties a lot of complex statements like that
so essentially creating a model or theory of the domain
we have techniques in description logic it's called realisation
where i can take that data it takes a long time
in these cases many of these things run on very very large computers for weeks
or months but they
graham the whole lot of that data
and what they come up with is answers so you say
which of these which in these cases could possibly be revealing
a hydrophilic air aruba but
all the things i said before hates water loves oxygen has to bound
and then what it comes up with twenty or thirty of them were then those
are the twenty or thirty of them you want to test
because now instead of testing million you only have to test twenty or thirty
any extra ones the machine get that shouldn't have been there
so if you had added one more piece of knowledge that could have made ten
of those go away
that saves a lot of money because each of these you look at the expense
more importantly if you put in something wrong
the cause is one of the things not to be looked at you could miss
the drugs that could be the difference between whether your company lives or dies literally
these the research labs of drug companies have to
at the level of about one in forty so if one of is one in
every forty things they try
works your size
if one in less than forty of the things you try works
you're out of business
right so it really comes out and again i'm simplifying obviously is really a multi-part
process but
again the idea is you want
a lot of data pulled together
a very complex reasoning and the whole thing to work together well
so the important thing in this model which is very traditional i model was the
model that expert systems were built around so in a sense this is think is
expert systems on the web
it was built around the fact that they had missed answers are money down the
now there's another view
of this ontology stuff which is to happen with all that
what ontologies are really are was just ways of letting us to find the right
data at the right time and then we can use these very data intensive tools
to do things
again on exact just as i exaggerated the first few i'm exaggerating the second view
in a sense this he says we're going to build the semantic web
by simply building a lot of these little ontologies that solve little problems and then
link them up together
i happen to be
you know one of the well-known proponents of that view about you has its own
right i mean who would ever think that if you just link up a lot
of different stuff there could be a problem in you know two thousand years ago
or so
somebody stated that you know the best way if you have a bunch of people
who are trying to build the tower the best way to make fall down to
make them all speak different languages
that's the biblical explanation
of why we all speak why
some you speak german and i speak english and other people speak other languages but
again the idea was that
intuitively these guys are trying to build the tower by making it so they couldn't
communicate correctly
mask analyse genitalia has is also impacted on their brain and behavior and they have
been the subject of intense investigation
one of the things that melissa hines did is that she asked about their toy
and so they would lay out selection of toys for the children to choose
this is a little bit hard to see but i'll look into it is this
is place with girls toys
these are unaffected bigger these are unaffected girls these girls with CAH and these are
unaffected boys and boys h here is placed with boys' toys here's unaffected girls girls
c c h and boys with and without CA age now
there's two things that you can notice the CAH girls are much much closer to
boys and they are to unaffected girls the second thing you can notice is that
there is a huge amount of variability
right so there's lots and lots of overlap there are some CAH girls to play
with girls toys and some boys in play with girls toys r and vice versa
one of the things that you also might be thinking is well we do all
as parents push our children towards gender typed toys and this is absolutely true and
melissa hines is very aware of this as well as the fact that test to
specifically ask about the influence of parents on toy choice and unaffected boys and girls
there's a huge influence of parental push towards the appropriate toy choices interestingly she founded
c h girls are particularly resistant to this push from the parents and would persist
in the choice of the boy-toy regardless of pressure from their parents
another sex differences we can look at humans it's informative called rough-and-tumble play which is
basically just the way children play we call it that because what it is that
we can quantify the frequency at which they physically interact with each other and the
intensity with which they physically interact with each other this is true in children it's
true in poppy's is true and what of we say what is true is true
is the boys play
and tumble more than girls and the reason it was particularly interested in behavior is
because this activity occurs before puberty
before puberty hormones but after developmental forms so it's actually occurring during that window of
time when there are no more around so it's independent of florence boys show much
higher levels rough-and-tumble play in humans and primates in puppies in goats in cold in
rats and mice and voles and just about any species that we can measure playing
and this is one of the most robust and reliable sex differences across species
unless the history then sorry in the states at indiana university has also looked at
this and chk urls these are just two different studies just because whenever you're doing
studies on humans like this you want to make sure that you completely reveal all
the data and give every opportunity for accuracy and what you can see is that
on average the CAH girls play rougher than the control girls but these are the
individual girls
and these are put here for a reason for you again to see the enormous
overlap there are many unaffiliated girls play rougher than many of the CAH girls so
the hormones are providing prediction of behavior but by no means a determination of behaviour
and then one just last one example
this research was done in japan by distinguished investigator named arrived was also interested in
studying CAH girls because he spent his career studying rats and on his retirement he
turned to girls and he wanted to ask what's going on in their mind and
so he asked them to sit down and draw also that these were children between
three and five years old and is given a blank sheet of paper new box
of crayons and told to draw whatever came to their mind what this shows appears
the characteristics of the drawings and again you can see this very well but ninety
eight percent of the girls to drawing that had a person in it and a
flower that only
twenty five percent of the boys too
drawings had people in it but ninety three percent of the boy's true something had
a moving object to car train playing it's so in general the girls did was
is that the actual line house
two parents and child flowers the sun in the corner boys had no rise and
they had no
they often had a top down perspective in the hell out of frenetic energy that
he also DNA them give back the box of crayons and he weighed the qur'an
so he could get a sense of the color palette the girls all used up
the flesh colored crayons and the boys and they tend to use the yellows oranges
reds the warm colours whereas the boys tend to have a much darker blue greys
blacks browns powers
and so these are some of the drawings of just the unaffected children as i
said you can see will first you can see that was done in japan and
just to kind of give a little bit of revision of what we did yesterday
we essentially colour homed in on this idea that there are two big problems in
computer vision registration and tracking
the first problem is the learning for life of the ten in the second problem
is actually the feeling i had when i had one officially fit
and on the two problems are inherently interrelated
and lot yesterday we spoke about one way of sort of coupling these to these
two questions together
obviously using exhaustive search so we just basically exhaustively search through all the different what
parameters available to us
and the second thing then is because with this using exhaustive search
then if we have a computationally efficient way of doing classification say support vector machine
adaboost as all along with some interesting ways of computing the features quickly and we
covered box filters integral images we get the reasonably good job
but what we also speculated about at the end of yesterday
was that as soon as i walked space becomes more complicated than perhaps two or
three dimensions so since who wanted to start doing things more sophisticated than this translation
scale perhaps rotation
fall into a bit of a setback because essentially fix the dimensionality of the wall
space explodes and we can't exhaustively search anymore
now a major impact on now got way through this
so we kind of proposed that
OK good way perhaps do this is to
perhaps look for some sort of inherited
relationship between
a what displacement between the template
and the source image and actually the appearance despite so it's quite easy for me
to calculate the appearance displacement is basically the difference between my template my template image
in my source image at a certain desirable
but what i really want to find is this what displacement and if you guys
remember to yesterday slides i kept coming back to that p
the magical people which is the wall what factors
that's what work and this is what this important rules about how can i get
and and so
a kind of an argument that i was trying to make
towards the end of this was that perhaps this is a better way to go
because i it can be continuous rather than discrete b
because it has lost properties in terms of its relationship with perhaps don't have to
do exhaustive search anymore perhaps is another way first to search and i guess there
too big
and so
we suspect that the different problems with the noise and things so
how do how much noise and shift to why do i have to introduce into
my regressor
between the image displacement what the space for me to do the job
and we came back to initial point with the pixel coherence sort of like that
for small displacements it tends to be a lot of correlation in natural images between
pixels it only holds up to a certain certain distance
so i
that's kind of where we got up to what
yesterday and we
kind went through and we show
i think we've got to distinguish
so we've got to this
this gradient this is where
instead of covering we covered much much earlier that
if i want to do image interpolation i can use the first order taylor series
expansion but what i can also use it for is to try and estimated displacement
so if i got the image intensity here
o xo
plus delta x about the image intensity of x o nine o xo
i can define the gradient i can reasonably good job
so i can calculate gradient here
i can do in the local gradient i can do reasonably good job of calculating
this delta x and essentially it's just to see the hessian of the jacobian
of the centre of the image gradient
so pretty pretty standard stuff boscombe mathematics
and then we'll talk about how the gradients and things and all those kind of
advocating doing more regression talk approach to the
we got to
i believe lucas kanade a that's where we can stop stop
so this
this is kind of where where says
does that sound familiar everyone hopefully
so there there and stop the revision
and so
well starting out with lucas kanade i have now the lucas kanade algorithm is an
old around concurrency here that actually predates all of the other stuff are showing it's
actually comes from the idea
and in nineteen ninety and essentially it was really used for object registration such it
was much more used for just image matching
so in like stereo vision problems you've got two images in exactly the same i
want to
work at disparity map so basically
how one image it has changed compared to the other side of the image in
terms of the pixel movement some things
and lucas kanade i was very easy and elegant way of computing these disparities in
if i had the disparity of how one pixel moved between two views i could
then get an idea that
and i think get kind of like essentially get like structure
structure from the image and obviously the movies i have the better i could do
and essentially the album work what
so don't know what this really solid because well enough even though it looks kind
is old
there's been a lot of literature out there that essentially builds up of the fundamental
and the real difference between what i was talking about at the pixel level
lucas kanade a level
is that what lucas kanade does
is it essentially instead instead of looking for
individual pixel movement it looks for
what displacement
so when he originally did he did local regions so basically
say a three by three or four by four five five region
essentially because individual pixels are too noisy cackle space of so if you got allowed
to support region you know approximately
and the social aspects of the web very important they often consortium of course as
well the whole technology and society domain deals with things in fact
the organisation of the semantic web is in the technology and society domain
the MIT will looking at how
to make to build the policy aware web one of the projects we have is
to make systems which are aware of the policies associated with data
those systems which
in which there's an interlinked set of rules which express the social policies so that
machines can be built which will work in policy where way
there is also a we have transparent transparent and accountable data mining initiative tammy project
is another one which
looks at how
you can build machines
which keep track of where did this come from what has been used what it
was supposed to be used for and so that when you're just about to make
a decision on makes forms of actions you could actually check if you're responsible
whether the data that you think that you've used the machines has has used to
help you was actually come from appropriate sources
i think so
now let's see if this usually with the semantic web since we're on semantic web
conference so
a couple of years ago i remember you yourself the florida conference that's what semantic
web is about integration
probably still agree with this statement now the question is
seeing semantic web community is biased to look towards this all day i don't reasoning
can representation guys while i'm missing here many communities which
should contribute lot like
data mining machine learning social network analysis analysis community
some geologists and so on so i how this it is is this impression correct
or not
i think it's changing i think that we have had a period when a certain
subset of the the semantic web community
has not buried itself into in description logic and because that's where it was the
time when we were working on creating the web ontology language and so that was
what was necessary now i have a phase when people talk a lot in the
corridors rules because we studying other language all these parts the north components that we
need for technology which
take several years each to produce and so it so it's been the work of
several years
meanwhile there has been web community so there have been a lot of people who
are still studying in the sociology or comparative media or many
different disciplines in which people of mathematics were complexity
so so there there are people who are have always been studying the where and
when we talk about websites will be we should include
so what they've been doing this so it but
so i think we all we need to bring everybody together and and certainly the
semantic people is people the semantic web people
you should not feel should really not be justified and just putting on bankers and
staying within their own discipline they should be very careful to look at the input
they get from other from other disciplines
one hundred percent for for this website is going to be one the conference or
something separate i think we'll see all kinds of conferences but the conference has been
i suppose mainstay and has been has an interesting history as it started off as
being sort of like foo camp sort of style everyone just very exciting new technology
and then it became a place where people talk about developing the
the dot coms and then after and those of the sun and sort of when
the people there was some misunderstanding that
there was no academic work now that the weapon being down but no but then
but now it's really it's really picked up because of course of course is a
huge amount of academic work to be done around the web many different areas and
if anything the web conference is very broad conference on the things like the semantic
web conference and other conferences the huge number of conferences just about XML
which is why he when only one very one facet of web technology
this is this year's
well the web conference in edinburgh so the title of the semantic web track was
web and semantic web
so partly you answered already but well in my opinion somehow semantic web has tools
sides of our tools two sides of the spectrum of problems which should solve so
one would be these all day i like site can maybe
hello project will be on one side and on the other side would be this
web scale stuff where one will deal with this ship more like shallow logic shallow
but michelle stuff but scalable and so on so
i think the whole area is kind of more like bias towards this
representation reasoning sites would you agree with this and is changing conditions other scalable stuff
well it depends who you talk to you find people involved and the number of
people are to involved in shallow ontologies
a large scale and others involved in these very deep ontologies in fact we've been
using the word ontology i think in a way which is in fact a bimodal
there are projects in which the ontology has a very large number of terms and
the actual value of the data of the project is in the ontology itself you
express it in our things like an ontology of all the diseases
not all the parts of the human body and how they connect in that case
the ontology holds the that the actually holds information the times the ontology is just
an ontology of six terms you need to define an RSS feed forward to define
the common or the couple of dozen terms you need to define a calendar entry
or something
and so
those ontologies are like infrastructure ontologies this small they don't change very often you have
some agreed with across a very wide community globally and what's interesting is the flow
of the data which is changing all the time but is expressed it's the only
instances are changing so these two different uses of the word ontology i think you
confuse people and people have to know i have looked at the huge ones and
we tried and tried to take a lot of time and in fact when he
was was a small one and the understanding that distinction i think this is important
now the question so i will conference we had one does were invited a couple
of venture capitalists and people with this kind of skills and some of the answer
which we got some help from the message we got some of the the still
very careful about the semantic web so what holds them back actually
invest a little bit more in the semantic