so it's it's quite strong
so that's the goal of maximum likelihood basically
the idea behind the enemy's
sometimes you have a set of functions or a set of distribution here that are
that for which we we don't know how to
to solve that task directly
but it would help if we
we were able to define to introduce a new it inviable viable for which we
don't value
but if we knew it
it would help in solving the problem
first and then the way to estimated according to the current solution that we have
so we are going to have an iterative solution where we first decide that the
solution is going to be given gushing mixture model with
a given set of parameters according to the set of parameters i'm going to try
to estimate this hidden viable which i'm going to tell you what it could be
and that could according to that new estimating going to be able to find a
new values for the parameters and i'm going to go on and on and on
so e BEM is separated into two steps what people call the e step and
m step expectation state is there to estimate
currently what would be the best value of these hidden viable
and the sense that is assuming that the best value is the current value what
is now the best value of the parameters and i'm going to
do that i can actively
and what's interesting
is that you can show
it converges to
to keep the local optima what does that mean exactly so
for gaussian mixture models we're going to decide that the heat viable
is the information that
someone is going to tell you that i suppose you have all these points
and you are searching for the best mixture of two gaussians that would have generated
the so the around here are going to present my two goshen and of course
at the beginning i don't know
what we should they be so
i just put them in a way that there are better ways to do that
but let's make this i put them somewhere
and now
i'm going to to do the following two steps first i'm going to assume that
each of the point has indeed been generated by one of the gaussians but i
just don't know
which one
and i'm going to call that my hidden variables because i don't know that
you you will agree with me that if you knew the information so if i
tell you that this point was generated by this one while this one was generated
by this way you could have two separate problem you would take all the points
generated by gulshan one
eight and compute the mean
and commercial matrix of that goshen separately and you do that for each goshen in
fact afterwards the weight would be very easy to compute it would be simply the
ratio between the number of points of caution so it's in need that to solve
the the gaussian mixture model problem
if you knew which point was generated by which
but you don't know of course
the first thing that you're going to do is the e step
and the e step is basically going to try to estimate that he arrival so
i'm going to estimate what is the probability
that that point was generated by this discussion or that goshen so i'm going to
compute for that pointer pretty of goshen and for that point to pretty of goshen
and i'm going to do that for all the points
and and that's the e step
and and then
m step is that now that i know
somehow which
caution generated which point
i'm going to modify the goshen so i'm going to move my migration toward the
points that were generated by the that goshen so too as to maximize that pretty
to have been generated the point that the step
now this is
very nice graphically
but there is also a more formal way to show it
i'm going to
to show it very quickly
more formally in fact what we do is so we have this invaluable
which we call q here
and we
we have to define it and that that you are in the EMI grid nobody's
going to tell you how to define this inviable but this is the only difficult
part define it as an opportunity finally there's no longer than the flows
and if you solution
so let's suppose that someone gave you this
information about the
what is going to be the hidden variables you create artificially function that you call
the auxiliary function of two sets of parameters and i'm going to explain what they
are and these auxiliary function is is going to be expected value over the hidden
over all the possible values of the variable of the log likelihood of the joint
of your data and the hidden variable given one set of data
and the whole
the whole thing is given the data and the other set of parameters this looks
very complex constraints but
we can we can work with that but what's very interesting is that
like dialect of form of predicate logic and first-order logic and by that all i
mean is that in the situation calculus certain predicates means so special
things but otherwise it's just first order logic
so we could try to this in dynamic logic we could try to do this
in many other logics and that's
and it's the way of describing these dynamic systems in
situation calculus in a sort of fairly
the simple form was first proposed
by john mccarthy in
late fifties situation calculus in this sort of film has been around for a long
it wasn't until later in the eighties and so that it was actually developed if
a bit more to the point where can
OK now
the terms in our logics of the terms in in the situation calculus there are
two important ties terms
once in terms of actions that we can perform
and the other ones are these things called situations which i look at the moment
situations are essentially states that a little bit more complicated than that
i can as state stress situations are going to be composed of these things called
fly swatter florence florence adjust properties of the world
that describe what's true
particular situation in a particular state
so for instance now you know my hand is empty
pick up the cup
you know my hand is
no longer
OK so
the status of my hand is like floor because it can change value from one
situation to the next after performing action it may change the truth value of this
of of this pretty good so just predicates essentially that can change value y can
cannot change truth value because when you perform an action
the action change the truth value that's all sorts of things change
OK now
i just put this method one the two on the screen to show two different
ways of describing particular situations
we're going to adopt the first method the only reason i put the second method
and is because he is commonly cited in the literature
there's really no
so the first thing that we're going to do is we're going to make the
states of the things that we call situations first class citizens analogy so we're making
so we can talk about remember i said we don't want to talk about what's
true now
but we also want to talk about what is true in the past and what
might be true in the future if i take this particular sequence of actions of
this course
OK so
a particular form like on so on is the floor and he just says look
this object the the cause c
it's on this subject i call a in s one
a situation as well
see these are just blocks is
also A's on this thing which i'm going to call the table
based on the table
basically there's nothing out of the sea it's clear there's nothing
OK so
this is a particularly
stable situation
and i've described using this platform is about
so this is not the sort of made this situation is sort of more abstract
an object here has about this one so it's constant
another way is to use this holds predicate
we make on instead of making on the predictor we make it function
we say that property on same being on a hold in this one
so the others
but as i just put that there is an example of an otherwise see literature
i'm going to stick with this one
o k actions in the situation calculus name so we can have actions and arguments
like put x y so put the object on top of the object one
move x from lot white blood cells
clear so clear thing on top of their their actions before
OK now situation is a snapshot of the world particular point in time
we're not winning k one in time it is so we're not really interested in
in time so much in this formalism so for instance we don't talk about how
long we might stay in a particular state
all we're interested in is that we're in a particular state
we do an action we get some other state
how long that transition takes how long we stay in any these particular states we
don't care about
it's just the ordering that were interested
you will know that i get to that point six
well let's let's get to announce so
put it this way the
by state i'm going to mean the collection of points that are true
at a particular point
now situation differs from state in the situation is just
you know the things that are true
but it's also a history of how you got
so the difference between the situation in the state is defined
different bird types so instead of having
one to the other we take a run
of one type of murder and then run of another type of mercer we cluster
this is
clustered arrangement of types into what we call these clusters are called blocks
blocks of the same type of of more
and such material is called a block copolymer
a block copolymer that showing up here
where you see
there's what four units of a and then four units of two units of a
four units of be this is a little bit unrealistic typically commercial
block copolymer so usually die blocks are try blocks will usually have if it were
dyed block of
polyethylene within one run of polyethylene and one run of polyvinyl chloride and that's it
you don't
you don't do this sort of thing
the artist got carried away and somebody didn't proofread so
so there it is and the last thing you can do is the one on
the bottom
which is called the graph the graph this sort of a type
it's the type of the block copolymer
what you have is you have a grasp of
one more time
in the form of the side chains
on two
another type
a backbone
for the backbone
so you cluster number two clusters the very
deliberately in this manner that's shown in
and the bottom one so the backbone is all ages and the side chain is
and here's one and some of you are going to be doing some traveling side
i've put up a very common one this is a
acrylonitrile dying stiring so you've seen i'm so the last diary what what this is
the backbone is all
due to die
and the side chains are alternately
acrylamide trials
and stiring and this is what used for hard sided luggage and also this all
these old
are made of this graph
and by playing with the the nature of the side chains we can obviously make
this so that it's somewhat flexible or we can make it so that's rather rich
again examples of
of architecture
at at the local level
dictating properties
we have these
examples of how we can tailor
the property is the second thing is
configurations of the side groups
side group configuration
these are all options that we have
and we exercise them in the synthesis by playing with the synthesis conditions and also
the catalysts that are present
and that's shown here is basically three ways you can put the side of science
so the the upper one
the other one shows
methyl group
randomly going sometimes it's above sometimes it's blown there seems to be no pattern this
a notion of side configuration is referred to as taxes
texas city it means
the placement of the side groups so you said i mean there's only three choices
here you put them all on the same side of the chain that's the bottom
one ISO tactic or you put them on alternate once it's on one side of
the chain then it's on the other side of the change alternate back and forth
with regularity that's india tactic in the third cases come what may there's no
no seeming plan and that's the tactics of those of the those of the three
types that you
you need to be
aware of
i tactic
cindy tactic
and a tactic
in figure those out i so obviously means they're all on the same side of
a tactic as as a moral political so this is random
and then by elimination this must be alternating
alternating current
in the next slide little doodling for so here's just to bring home what's going
on the first one of the top is a tactic polypropylene so you see
there's the there's properly
and what what's happened is this double bond has been broken and now can propagate
in this method group in some cases above in some cases below the chain here's
polystyrene this vinyl benzene or phenol
at the
four styrene and the double bond is broken you get these feel groups hanging off
the side and this is just vinyl chloride which we saw
over here so
again seeing how the the surfaces
OK and the last thing we can look at is is the backbone
his backbone architecture
four chain architecture
chain here referring to the main chain
she architecture
and this falls under the general terms of conformal mality
con formality and we're going to revisit this we talk about proteins very important biological
systems and it it it's the direct result of this which i showed you last
day that this bond is free to rotate
and if it rotates in certain ways
so that all of the
side groups line up perfectly
you end up with this so-called eclipsed version so if you look at the chain
on the very and you'd see one dot represents the backbone or actually zigzagging so
you see the
the edge of the zigzag and then all of the pendant groups would be lined
up in front of one another you'd see nothing except the very first one that's
the eclipse and that's the most regular straight line and this is staggered were that
it rotates were wishes and i showed you this one where this is this is
hardly something with the polarisation index of thirty six hundred but it starts giving you
the sense of some more nearly straight and some are
very heavily coil
both of these are still called straight chains
of these are still called
straight change but
there are some things that we can look at so first we have the linear
the linear
the linear chain molecule and
so that's one
and furthermore if you look here there some fine structure you may even see that
at some point along here there's even some attempt at
crystallisation but
i don't think this is one
this is a
let's get
said well i want to
and so it proved
all the
this really what something is is just like
what will choose
so what
time should
can process
so just
john shawe
so and
two is
last week
what he also
with a
we had
this is the best of
was one of those
so the
there must be a lot but there is
so for instance we should
the rest of the world
he was
what is also
when he
his real name
just check
say you want to do it
there is
you want to
we're patient
so what i did wrong
all of these
that we
was just
i don't know what he said
OK so
regret say
six months
so it is just
you new
but range
what i'm going to talk about today is learning graph matching
so i have to add i'm not really
not expert on the graph matching or on graphs and so on
we came into doing this by
well first solving a web page ranking from then we realize that by modifying things
a little bit
we could actually get something that works quite well this graph matching
i is the bottom line of this talk what you should remember
besides well i'll be talking a little bit about various graph matching algorithms and you
can use them and i can make them better is
well generally
o thing in science so
quite often people work very hard at finding answers to questions that somebody gave them
or questions that they spend very little time thinking about and they were very hard
on the answers
this is an example of world
and algorithmic example of well if you spend quite a bit more time on asking
the right questions
the answers will be much better and actually easier to obtain
this is what we are able to do is for graph matching which is known
to be hard
that if you restrict yourself to
the set of graphs that you really interested in solving
in matching
and if you actually tried to use statistics to learn
the right question
you will be able to find the answer by well
what are we talking about the hungarian marriage method so linear assignment
and we already talked to look a little bit about linear assignment and so on
in the previous two days but i'll briefly explain anyway
master that actually
the outline of this talk is of the first
actually explain in a little bit like graph matching is a good idea and by
all means don't think that this is a fairly complete list for two reasons first
the fall
i'm not very much of an expert secondly it's more about the others namely how
to learn this graph matching
the know
about some existing algorithms for graph matching
and the one be talking about specifically are linear quadratic assignment
there are there
methods out there which were instances junction trees and so on but
these actually some of the more popular ones
and dean
this is
this section is actually just going to be one slide is too
but stop and realize well maybe we should have
a better question rather than working really hard in finding an answer
and once we realize that actually
finding that better question is very easy
so then three justice it down and cracked the handling and stuff
and i say that it actually does work reasonably well
this is where i need your help
in the context of extensions because there are a couple of
straightforward extensions where it's very easy to see
i will design the algorithm
and the issues of the we
in some cases not quite sure
what the problem for that will be so it's like hammer look for
well graphmatching well why do you care about as well
biology and chemistry many might have molecules stored in the database you might want to
match them up
you might have regulatory networks and you want to match them
you might want to estimate functions of proteins
another application that's
maybe a little bit more easy to visualize is
object matching in computer vision
so for instance wide baseline matching would extract features of two images
and you need to actually match up the feature points news that three d camera
camera calibration sounds a lot of geometric computer vision algorithms
need such
matching beforehand
another one will be for instance let's say you've got
a road map of
say a
princes italy and you have updated satellite images
you want to add all the roads that were built illegally
and you could do that by simply matching up with what you already have so
far and then you just identify neurons that to
and you want to do that recently automatically
two just to show you that this is not such a trivial problem
i mean here two identical graphs
and if you use a little bit of imagination you can see well they basically
reflect those
to age down
paul notes down and will see that those graphs are actually identical
this is a fairly easy case because actually this is a plane graph so matching
planar graphs is not at the heart
but what this feature is that
very simple objects are so easy to match
at least three months
and so what would expect the computers have a very easy time
you also have all sorts of ambiguities
so let's say
this is
the graph
the same graph here
and well how match one in this case i've actually got
different rotations and i can flip things as well right
and it's always going to be the same graph
but these actually things that will make you live very hard afterwards when you want
to design an automatic graph matching
and it should actually be showing those
pictures now and i don't know why
OK so what you
you should have seen an output of the slice after those pictures afterwards is
they are
if you
if if you have
images as in computer vision and extract those features and you want to match up
so for instance if you see a person at two different positions
the in
you want to match up that he has moved in a certain way in the
hands and all that you can then use that for the processing
i don't know why it's not showing up to class
the problem is that there is no currently known polynomial time algorithm for matching
but checking is actually fairly easy if i give you match between two graphs and
let's say they unlabelled it's a fairly straightforward thing
it's not a straightforward if you have an issue with the two graphs are not
identical and you just want to do an approximate match
three hard
so in that case we might just want to find the best match that's actually
much more common problem
for instance
as in computer vision i mean you get to
pictures of the same person you want to match features between them i mean what
is the same person i mean the
picture might look slightly different if it isn't it's kind of trivial problem
you might have for instance several surveillance cameras in you tracking the same person
and those cameras were installed by different manufacturers at different resolutions may be somewhere column
and retrieval models
it defined
by the representation of the information need
and your
document or object that you want to be true
it is also defined by
the function of ranking
six which computes the development of
object to question
so we will look at that
yesterday which model curtsy quite popular
i mean field so
also the
i included
very recently whole
with regard to antecedent
which was on the way
i would think about
that's fine
i speak about questions
so is a much more focused
in this this
then we will very shortly
x one x two x three which
i think also the application that out yesterday
it's very much in this topic
and finally i fly anywhere
many of the search problem that it could be
the second thing is here
i have
the problem i think my mind that was copy
the large computers
i'm sorry
well maybe maybe not
i think it's part of a large
to be sure that you can copy
mean computer
OK i've not seen it it might suitcase
in fact it is
i think it was because was the better
but it's not
i don't have
so by
but they come to my talk
to complete
i think
on your part which
i can think
i'm sorry
it's a very old computer in my
my better to you
it's not
so we were have able to probability my
and the probabilistic models
actually the problem of estimating the probability
given the surface you can have different kinds of can be query
given a document collection you be estimated the search
and then you rank the documents according to a prob
that means that the time had come to
so there are many different models
which can
and i think that language and
so the support
random variables
the document the document q query
and around on
i which can have a value binary
so i think the question
we have to estimate the probability
given the document and query
which can be
collins is by value
it can be translated one minus the probability
that to you
a number of
given the document and query
think i right
generative relevance models
so we estimate the probability of relevance given your documents and you query
we use the
for the estimation
if we use the two
we obtain
we have to estimate actually the probability that
the probability that you think well
given that are relevant
now we can also use the line
which need to be
computer ratio
of dallas
given document and query from the of the number of a given document and query
by using these rules
we can actually draw the denominator
i know her
so i want to have a little bit overweight have
we get actually is
the language model that we of
the probabilistic models and
the only actually
published in nineteen sixty seventy six by
robert and karen sparck jones
actually we knew
in where
this a
in fact
so in the language models
that we are looking
this practice into the probability of document given that and the probability that your document
and relevant to generate
so actually are looking at the generative model
when you document generally
and the other
classical models of human
that's the problem
we have different structural factor here
we have to be the
generate a certain documents and to compute this problem
now starting from a lot of
we can again use the
well we can so we can
in fact two
into this
and then
by applying based on the middle here
and also in the denominator
we can some of the terms in the equation
and actually also move to the purpose of ranking
which is great
a lot of rather split into two
sounds like
we did
so actually led to it could be any more
for the purpose
it could be considered for
can conspiracy how
it can be done
now we want to do
well we want to
fifteen simple model
and we assume that
the conditioned on different set of number relevancy
the document is independent of the query
so which means that we have conceded dependency the probability of document given
just each have their own interests in mind
OK and so in computer science and a lot of interest in this frightens routing
on the internet got multiple people routing their past and the fact that someone's downloading
some big file
is affecting your
performance of your machine all this kind of stuff so that each person's behavior of
facts has an impact on everyone else but i they're out to get users there
are to do something and you want to figure out what's going to happen if
everybody act in their own self-interest
online auctions so
google makes its money by selling the lands on the side of
search pages and they have these building in a lot of different companies bidding for
the search for keywords and so each acting in their own self-interest and not come
you know
active necessarily adversarially
the company a stub is not directly to company b of this is justice to
make money for themselves so
again the case for many participants their behavior affect each other they each have their
own interests in mind
the theory of general some games kind of economics because economists were interested in studying
economics and trying to study
you know how prices change when people are buying and selling in their own interests
and doing various things
what like us on
right so here a very simple general sum games in general sum games have win-win
situations you can of lose-lose situation
so here's maybe not exciting game
so the first
the call games but the really more interaction
like the focus of again raymond someone when someone loses these are really more interactions
i think it would be initiative called interaction theory
i get again
the interaction to use the simply which side of the sidewalk you walk
you can walk on the left side of the right side of the site and
the person coming towards you can walk on the left side of the right side
i think i've done this for each person's perspective so that if you both walk
on the right
it's good for both of you
or if you both walk on the left it's good for both of you but
if you walk on the left and they are working on their right
then you know you've got to do this sort of thing to figure out why
in the same the other way around OK so these are you both when hear
you both work
there is no right answer in this game is now
optimal thing to do
everybody walking on the left is the nice thing everybody walking on the right is
the nice thing
there's no thing about optimality
you can look alike which movie should you go to see a friend you try
to figure out what you want to go see
what are the the three hundred meters apart something anyway for some you know each
have a different movie like the scene you'd like to also go with your friends
you may prefer movie number one movie number two your friend may prefer moving them
movie number one
but you kind of like to go together so
here you're payoffs are know
this and this are both nice places to be at least going to friends movie
but you would prefer this movie and friends
there's no longer any value to the game
no longer notion of the optimal we're going to look at what kind of reasonable
so the notion here of nash equilibria
so nash equilibrium
is a stable pair strategies could be randomized like we had before
it is stable pair of traditional mean by state
stable means
neither player
have an incentive to deviate
on their own
so let's look at this what side of sidewalk to walk again
so here we have
right so think of the nash equilibria
in this game
OK so
and as go over to the pair strategies could be randomized to that given the
way the other players playing you have no particular reason to do anything different than
what you're doing and given the way of applying the other player has no particular
reason to anything different from what they're doing
can anyone think of some nash equilibria in this game
so in name name one
left left everybody walking on the left is a perfectly fine actually going if everyone
else working the left usually walking left to if you're walking left data work left
the stable
there's no reason for any lady everyone can after finding and
is that the way people work and sidewalks here people drive on the left side
imagine in my work
and lastly we have the same which wraps around
so x one minus xk
science right
so here's a bunch of constraints what do you suggest i do with them
anything interesting about these constraints on the left-hand side
sounds like the right word
what was it
telescopes yes
everything cancels if i added these up is next to minimize x two there's an
x minus x one and x one and x minus xk klxk xk everything here
councils by the black ten slots so what happens if i have the right hand
side over overhearing zero
my favorite answer
and every year
the all the weights of all the edges in the negative weight cycle which is
the weight of the cycle
which is negative
so zero is strictly less than zero contradiction
contradiction women within the same anything that was false
so really contradiction in in the mathematical sense we didn't contradict the world we just
said that these constraints are contradictory in other words if you pick n values of
the excise there's no way that these can all be true
because then you would get a contradiction
it so was impossible for these things to be satisfied by some real exercise
so these must be
so there's is no
satisfying assignment
more precise
x one to xn
no weights can we satisfy those constraints because they add up to
zero left side negative on the right-hand side
OK so that's pretty
that's easy
for the the reverse direction will be only slightly harder
OK so called we have the connection
motivation suppose you want to solve these difference constraints and we'll see one such
application is actually
you go around four
four different constraints of a number of papers they care about distance constraints
and they all use shortest paths to solve
so if we can prove a connection between shortest has which we know how to
compute an difference constraints then we'll have something cool
and next class was even more applications of different constraints turns out there really
really useful
for all pairs shortest paths
that's just prove equivalence initially
so the reverse direction is if there's no negative weight cycle
in the constraint graph
and the system be satisfiable
so claims that the negative weight cycles are the only barriers to finding a solution
two design difference constraints
this feeling
yeah i detect string graph good
so here we going to see techniques this is very useful for thinking about short
it's a bit hard to guess especially if you see this is useful in problem
sets having quizzes and finals and everything so keep this in mind
i mean i'm using it to this rather simple theorem by the idea of changing
the graph constraint graph g
changing the graph is a very
powerful idea
so we're going and
a new vertex
user sourced look
and we're going to have a bunch of edges from because being a source about
to be connected to some things one and a zero weight edge
rates are an inch from everywhere
so to every other vertex in the constraint graph those those vertices are followed by
one up to be and so
have my constraint graph let me copy was one
the second change was going to back up your work before you make changes
so now i want to add a new vertex s over here my source take
my constraint graph whatever looks like at the end
we have zero edges
to all the other vertices
so what are now
what i do
but what did you do quite have candidate source now which can reach all the
shortest paths from s
well paths from s exist anger from st everywhere in weighted most zero
OK maybe less
it could have been as well
you know like the two i can get to by zero minus two so lessons
are going to be a little careful what is there is a negative weight cycle
then there wouldn't be any shortest path fortunately we assume there is no negative weight
cycle in the original graph and if you think about it there's no negative weight
cycle in the original graph we add as
to an edge from s to everywhere else we're not making any new negative weight
cycles because you can start as an go somewhere the cost of zero which doesn't
affect any weights and then you are forced to stay in the old graph
so there can be any new negative weight cycles
so this graph
so the modified graph has no negative weight cycles
that's good
because it also has passed from as and therefore it has shortest path from s
the modified graph has no
because didn't before
and it has
have from st
there is a path from s to every vertex
may not have been before before i couldn't get from p two to three for
that's what that's still true but from as i can get everywhere
so that means that in this graph the modified graph has shortest path trees has
from s
there was old fighter called the shortest path weights like i ran bellman ford from
i will get a bunch of finite numbers dv for every
for every vertex
it seems like a good idea list
she has exist that's just assigned
x y
to be the shortest path away from s to v on
so it's
in one that that's a good choice for number
the shortest path from s to be i this is finite because it's less than
and it's great to minus infinity
so some finite number that's what we need to
lots of mutation going on right to edit distance is longer while here instances is
very short right just need to be d and i get a c
right so the way to do this is every node will be will be the
quote edges are some kind of approximate inclusions inclusion relationships and edges also how weights
which means that it means let's see how likely how likely it a particular quote
has evolved from from a set of parents and what they would like to do
this in this this and the the way to construct the graph is to ensure
that the graph will be a directed acyclic graph of approximate quote inclusion is we
want you want to delete the minimum total edge weights such that each component has
because single sink node right so let me show you what i mean by that
then i'll explain why this makes sense so in this particular example i would delete
this particular edges and that would be my solution might i would have disconnected components
that all all end up in a single sink node right so i could say
that this is sort of the mother called the mother phrase from from which everything
else has evolved
right and this way i can now identify different mutational variants of a single phrase
right so what i was showing you on the previous slide was the graph like
right i'm showing you different variants and how including one another for depending around the
better for right of course the question is how do i do this kind of
partitioning as as well as pretty much or as many kinds of partitioning by this
deck partitioning is also NP hard
but there are some very effective heuristics the observation that led to design the statistics
is that basically the idea is that it's enough to know
notes parent to reconstruct the optimal solution by terrified so if at every node i
that the true parent from where the nodes evolved i can reconstruct the optimal solutions
of the way the way to our heuristic works is we start at the top
and the and we then proceed sort of topological order of these back and every
every step we ask nodes who's who when you think you you you have most
likely evolved from and that we also include the size of the of the cluster
and the parent of the node belongs to this way we sort of can extract
this kind of thing is that the approximate this inclusion relationships and give different mutations
variants of the same piece of content what is interesting here is that we don't
assume human supervision be identified short pieces of content identified how how these pieces of
content through there and we can start looking good at them and so this is
this is the plot again before the two thousand eight u s presidential election of
where xx is time and y axis is the number of mentions but i was
right and what is nice is that you get now you get to see a
very nice description of what was media talking about in this
three months before the presidential election right you have sort of this first spike is
that the republican convention of such democratic convention this was republican convention this was the
famous lipstick on a pig
quote there is that was then sort of thing the the statement from the fundamentals
of us or our economy are strong and then a week later they realized that
it's the opposite so the entire economies danger and so on and so forth right
and this way you you can basically just but just by doing this you can
get very nice insights into what works what was the online media and the blogosphere
talking about another thing that you can do is actually not looking like rank sites
by how how quickly they tend to mention information and in particular what i'm showing
you here i'm having the rank leg which means negative length leg in our system
is that this method website dance tends to mention use before they reached popularity so
zero speak popularity and the negative means you have developed cities before the
and what you start seeing here for example is the professional blogs tend to mention
information much much sooner before it becomes the most popular and then these are the
mainstream media sites there are still some that but they still creek but they appear
after the
professional blog site and of course now we can go and select sub parts of
this quote unquote and a particular topic to do find finer resolution analysis so here
is here is an example example of how we can define the a finer resolution
analysis with this kind of
this kind of approach so this is something that we did together with the new
formations project on x excellence in journalism right and they really wanted understand the
media coverage of the current economic crisis right and then they try to see what
are the main statement of the main phrases that that that got the most attention
on the web who who mentioned those phrases and so on right here is here
is use an example from the from the report that you have to create right
so this was for only two thousand nine these are different from the phrase is
all about the economic crisis this is who was the person that said when they
said i mean this was the number of mentions in our in our dataset and
what is interesting to see here is that basically it was the first to get
the most attention on this particular issue was actually barack obama right and then you
know the
but the key to the chief of the federal reserve bank he was only here
towards the bottom the top republican voice was ranked only number forty nine on this
particular issue
and the
i think that was ranked number five was this cartoon from the new york post
web sort of the policemen should the monkey and then they say
we need to find someone else to write the next stimulus bill so this sort
of a controversial they had to pull it off but again he got like super
under this probabilistic model
and this is the function
which is differentiable convex we can solve in
and the number of different ways very very quickly
so has that solved the problem of saying how we came to pick which algorithm
again to use
it solved the problem of
it doesn't matter which optimize use because all of them again to give the same
the school
this thing is convex it turns out that you always get the same answer no
matter which optimisation kg
but there's another problem
which is
it's always possible
to get an empirical loss zero
what i haven't said is
how we should should choose how to extend the dataset
the reason i'm talking about linear rules remember the fact that i can to talk
about just decision planes is that i'm allowing myself the freedom to add extra features
to my data set so that any problem can be solved with the linear decision
so now
if i'm optimizing squared loss
i have some black points which is the data set
i could fit
a plane which is the blue line
or you could extend the dataset to have seven columns
and i could magenta line
magenta line has very square square there
under that objective the magenta line is the best curve but maybe we don't really
believe that if we see an input here is likely to have a response down
here given the all the data that lie
lake close to the slide
it's a
there's something wrong with that objective
in the classification setting it's very easy to get an empirical loss zero is so
the nearest neighbour would do that
what's the nearest neighbour to this one point which is itself it predicts itself and
remembering the whole training set in just spitting it out again
so that no interesting learning has gone on if you just remember the whole dataset
and you say
well now i can predict that dataset because i happen to know all the answers
like cheating on an exam
we're going to need to do something else
this is the tough issues there isn't one right way to proceed because
it depends on what a problems like
i said that this magenta line was on an unreasonable fit to the data
who am i to say that so maybe you know
the data definitely lie on a sixth order polynomial and for some physical reason and
given these observations you're sure that it's going to happen
and so
you need to introduce
some idea of what it means to
generalize what you need to know about the problem what learning means in order to
formally say why we don't like the magenta curve
and there's multiple different ways of going about doing that
and i'm going to mention two of them
later on in the lecture
but there are fortunately some very simple practical things that we can do right away
you could go and write code to do
this afternoon if you wanted to
one of the practical things we can do
this whole that was called the validation set so
instead of fitting my whole
i'm going to draw a line from point and say
OK i've got this big dataset but i'm only going to use
this is that
i'm going to
it might be squares i'm going to fit my logistic regression model whatever to this
dataset and hold out some of the
because it might be useful later and so the rest of it i'm going to
call validations
it's a
the blue crosses here are my training set the data that i'm actually giving to
the training algorithm and i fitted
and back again to curve the green curve which use different temporal representations of expanded
them out using different orders polynomial
these cats are generated using different number the columns of x
the red dots are now this validation set that i held out so the kids
didn't see the red dots when they are being produced nothing about the computer codes
or the red dots
these red dots now witness to the fact that the magenta curve silly
the gender can actually shoots off the board and extrapolate really wildly
very poorly predicts these held point
this green curve which is under fitting is not capturing this is actually a non-linear
doesn't predict
this held that data nearly as well as the black curve so this gives us
a principled reason for rejecting the curse which underfitting not overfitting so now we've got
a score for picking
what model we use how many columns today include in
my data set
it's the choice that gives me the best validation performance because
that's the
procedure which is actually generalize to future data haven't been senior
so you don't want to necessarily have to visualize what you're doing
no matter how complicated your problem is you can always draw this plot
you could
but the different models along the x axis so this is a different number of
columns of text and my input space into
and then on the y axis are plotted
error that i got from the validation set in this case the mean squared error
so now the blue curve shows progression progression of training
so this is something that's always a good idea to plot sanity cheque
he's your algorithm actually improving the training costs monotonically because
if not then it's probably a bug in your code so that's was a good
character plot
and the red line shows the validation performance so
here says well
on different data it's reasonable that you're going to do
a little bit worse because you've actually fitted to
your observations so you're never going to be quite as well
on different cases and exactly the case using fuzzy that's why the red curve is
high but follow the same shape it is true that
you won't fitting the flat line so
these terms
give you non-linear effects is a good idea
up to a point
it's a
the good case you've seen where i think by the political polynomials and this red
curve shows that yes those are the ones that do best and then rapidly
as you overfit as you put in spurious curves on really well justified by the
the validation set picks you up on that and you did very badly
this kind of says don't actually fit these really complicated models
holding out validation set is something that
you should always do routinely i think because it's very easy to kid yourself
that you've come up with a great idea
because you're going to try out a whole bunch of different things in the data
and one of the more then seem to be doing really well
and that could just be by chance unless you've held out some dataset you didn't
look at
you're never going to be really sure whether you're just fooling yourself or whether you
actually made real progress on your problem
once we make some assumptions about probability distributions of right of the centre
we can actually compute the probability of an item act
given the query
how probable is that you don't
given the query that we might want to score items by their probability given the
well see how to compute the date but let's think about this
it turns out that
it's score by
this you get terrible results
afterwards you think about it you realize why
the problem is that the probability of an item given the query set
is sensible ranking criterion because it depends on the properties of the item
that have nothing to do with query
some items may just be more probable than others regardless of the query sets of
items are just more typical
the kind of you can think of it as they live more in the middle
of whatever feature space you're measuring the another idea in those will always be ranked
higher by this criterion regardless of what the query that is
and also if your items are things like documents let's say if you were to
actually model something like documents
or any other kind of strange
the probability of any string
decreases with the number of characters that string
this sort of measure would have a bias towards short documents are short strings which
seems also really silly
we don't we don't really want that
arranged by
criteria that are not exactly relevant to our query
so what we really want to know
is the probability of the idea given the query that
two here that the probability of the data before observing the query
so we're interested in is how much of the query that increase or decrease the
probability of that item
and that's what we're going to use as our ranking criterion
so here is the basic idea
after getting the query that
what we do in
we rank all the items by
it by score
which is the ratio of the probability of the item given the query set
the probability of the item before observing the query set
now how do we actually compute this ratio
well do this we need to make some assumptions
well we're going to do is we're going to have some simple
parameterized model
objects in our universe so the object represented by
that there's the features
and for any probability distribution that we define on x
parameterized by some set of parameters
and then if we define the prior distribution on what the parameters of that concept
it can be
we can actually compute all the quantities of interest
the let's go through that and try to understand how that works
the nominator here here back
is simply
the probability of x given theta pi the probability of the data integrated over all
under are bottle
this is the prior probability of observing item act
the numerator
the probability of i observing item x
given the query that
expressed by exactly the the same equation
the probability of x given the parameters but now instead of averaging with respect to
the prior over the parameters
we have the average with respect to the posterior over the parameters
given the query that
essentially when we observe the query that
the person enters into the system
we go from the prior
over what the parameters of that concept could be
the posterior over what the parameters of that concept
could be
and so that given by bayes rule here
the posterior over the parameters given the query set
the likelihood of the
query set
for the setting of the parameters
the prior normalized
so very basically
uses of marginalisation and they will
any questions about this
well i'll get get to that
in a minute but the way we should think about this is
it's going to be a representation of what we think
the items in our universe are are
how we think a cluster will be represented or concert will be represented in our
universe so for example if the items are documents
then we have a huge history of
been there
the thing
so far the
so here we are
that he
a lot
two years later
we are
one year
so they
you are a
the last thing they need
or few more
the median
o two
the same thing
he might be
what are the
the next
i know
if you lucky
he also
and if you are sure that point cannot be
an outlier
you just can
discarded from further pruning it from further consideration
a second second sorry it's taken over there is a nested loop based over
the other
learning memory buffer is divided in two parts and the second part is just used
this can
and compare all points with the points from the first so you can just load
one part of the the data
based in the first part of the back buffer
and then the second part of the buffer is used to go through the
the whole dataset
and compare the case of classical
and the third kind of government grid based approach so here the idea is to
below the grid such that any two points from the same grid cells
i have distance of at most epsilon
to each other and then it's clear if you think about it a second time
it's clear that points it only
any pointed only compare
with points from neighbouring cells because
other cells
can only contain points that have
a distance of more than epsilon to the point
OK so
this is just reduces the number of comparisons between points
in order to compute the sets neighborhoods
then there is an interesting extension to the original work which is not really an
outlier model but i think it's worth mentioning because it's one of the core points
of the data mining the two authors here came up with the
the solution to one
derive knowledge about the outliers to be clear
what describe the outliers that
i found
and so the idea is based on this distance based on family just
discussed here
what what they did is they try to find minimal subsets of attributes that explains
the outlierness of a point
minimum sets of
in which the point is still an outlier
so maybe
i just tried to
make it clear by this example here
so for example the following
players in
this is just the sports statistics
dataset for
some hockey players you have some measurements like power-play goals short-handed goals whatever
not to be in pocket expert
i understand that so the point is
well these four guys
detected as outliers with this model here and the intensional knowledge derived from this result
the following summary linear is an outlier all already in the one dimensional space policy
they also just considering only this attribute means
or would already find
this player is an outlier
also the two dimensional space of shorthanded goals and game-winning goals so just considering to
these two
attributes here but also
be enough to identify
as is an outlier
OK so
hope some of the year so the method tries to
find the minimum subset of attributes
it is already sufficient to
make this point and of life
and the same for the other
the other guys here
and this can cause very interesting because that gives the domain expert more
insight into the data dataset
just set telling hockey free camera lemieux an outlier
the frequency of course is an outstanding player
but on the other side you can say OK he's out outstanding because as
how goals seems to have a lot of power play goals and
a lot of shorthanded goals
and whatever
so given a little bit more than just the outcast but also an explanation
what constitutes the
other alkali other distance based approaches are usually based on
the distance to the k nearest neighbors of objects
so they are
basically two two variants here the first model just takes the k nearest neighbour distance
is the distance to the k nearest neighbour
o point
the k nearest neighbour distance of a point is an outlier score
the higher the
the distance
the higher the outline of
the smaller the distance
the more the point is
and normal
and the second variant here is
that not only the k nearest neighbour distance is considered but
and commissioned at the end of the
talking to you about modern financial time series using grammatical evolution
this is basically
based on work by myself and steve phelps
grammatical evolution is just basically genetic programming approach
but unlike in genetic programming where you work directly under solutions in grammatical evolution you
on integers strings and
natural selection happens
programs basically
generally when in modeling financial time series when
you find finer function
effects like an econometric model modelling
the basic you know
such that
the function f x explains your data
are which here is is really just the log returns
given the constraints
and when you have so many parameters to deal with
the search space
it's quite big
you need
some sort of
heuristic in trying to
look for promising areas in that search space
and our approach basically we use and grammatical evolution to try and find a mathematical
for the return at time t
and in assessing we want that model to be profitable basically
and how we assess the profitability of the models is basically using the sharpe ratio
we have omitted the risk free rate
well we trade in high frequency and bandwidth assume that in high frequency
the risk free rate
it's in significant
along the return the predicted return is greater than zero
or short the project
it's less than zero
in doing things this way
a model that basically learns to predict
to get to get writes most of the time
would make a high a higher sharpe ratio
while the model that kind of
get it wrong most of the time is penalized
what we do in this
in the words of marrying you
heuristic search is like
having the gumball machine
you stick acquired in
and you get the gumball out
so you you make an initial guess is
and you hope and that you know evolutionary operators of mutation in
natural selection will natural selection mainly
i would move the search
tools like a promising area
but i mean because you have no knowledge regarding the search space knowledge and knowledge
of the state space you could end up in area that's
so you kind of need to
sample the search space several times
which is what we have done so
for thirty experiments were done thirty experiments and for each of those thirty experiments we
two hundred solutions
we run the algorithm and we take you know we observe basically the
the distribution of fitness
along the way and the distribution of fitness in the final solution
basically we use and
we're testing this
use in
high frequency data
four three forty stocks
these are basically it's basically clean data
take take data samples at five minute intervals or cleaned and everything
we test for autocorrelation user lose
i'm not going to try pronounce that and basically the test is negative for the
hypothesis that
there's also correlation
and of course what we expect this is what we've done is we've broken the
and to four samples
so and what for each run
we train the algorithm
in sample
and then we used
for the saturdays all three of sets of data in evaluating the algorithm for on
use the second set is basically a fold cross validation
as expected in sample
what happens is
natural selection
so to move the distribution of
towards the
positive tales
which is what we want so basically that's the initial distribution
of solutions
and and that's the final distribution of solutions
natural selection kind of
final distribution of solution
towards problems in areas which is what we get
this is
pretty much saying the same thing what we're seeing here is the average mean fitness
four thirty experiments
as we go through generations
and as you can see here for the three stocks we have improvement standard deviation
in fitness
is reduced reducing in the
the entire population is sort of convergence to one area of the solution space
how do we know
the prediction wall how we know what this is basically out of sample performance thirty
best solutions
produced by GE
the three stocks
compared to
fair quite
so what we have done this
at each time interval
mind you it but we're basically making decision time away in our holding period and
frequency of training is the same thing
at each time interval with flipping a coin
well it's going long ago short and that's what basically for the FCS is quite
and we're making a decision whether to go along the schoolgirl short with the generated
basic a thirty by
it's often the final stage of long-term relationships that have gone back
we don't share information with each other anymore
so there's no intimacy
we don't feel physically attracted to each other anymore
there's no passion
but we better stay together for the kids
always better stay together for appearances sake
or better together because financially it would be a disaster if we don't
all the reasons other than intimacy and passion
that people might commit to each other that's what star calls and you know what's
is in societies where marriages are arranged
this is often the first stage
of a love relationship
these two people who have maybe never seen each other before who have never shared
secrets there's no intimacy
who have that don't know if they are physically attracted to each other or
on their wedding day revealed to each other and committed legally and sometimes religiously
to each other
right the common is there but at that moment nothing else might be there
what's interesting of course is that such relationships don't seem to have any
greater chance
ending in divorce
people who marry for love
but there's a big con found big problem
in studies of those kind of relationships what might have be
what might be the problem in this statement i just made these kind of relationships
are just as likely to survive people who marry for love
so they they the data
the cards are more likely to occur in societies
that frown on divorce
make it very costly socially costly
to divorce so they they stay together for all kinds of reasons not always such
good ones i now
who was who was it who sang the song
two out of three ain't bad
seven meat loaf
it was not presently professor as it was meatloaf it was life
are all saying there was a so called because
we love saying on two out of three above let's see if two out of
a band what you have
intimacy we share secrets passion we feel physically
attracted to each other but we're not making any commitments here
star recalls that romantic love this is a physical attraction with close binding but no
commitment romario and julie when they first met
this is the way relationships start
we like each other physically attracted to each other due to you
i enjoy spending time with you but i'm not making any long-term commitments are not
even willing to use the l word in in describing what it is we have
right many of you might have been in relationships of the sort that that's wrong
that's romantic love now what we have intimacy we share
secrets with each other
but there is no particular physical attraction
but we are really committed to this
this is what the system recalls companion in love this is your best friend
we are committed to sharing intimacy to be friends forever but physical attraction is not
part of the equation
this is sort of the
maybe the greek ideal
of some kind
well what if we have partial
and sexually attracted to you
but no intimacy i don't really know that much about you i don't really show
anything i
but i am committed to maintaining this physical attraction
well that's
what system recalls that she was love it's a whirlwind courtship it's a hollywood romance
and might lead to a shotgun wedding
maybe you find yourself in las vegas and you get married for a day and
a half and
and then i realized that this wasn't such a good idea
maybe it was britney in years ago well you get
you get the idea
that's that's fatuous love
we are we are basically committed to each other
for sex
but it it's very hard to make those relationships last a long time because we
might not have anything in common we might share anything with each other we might
not trust each other we're not particularly bonded
to each other on the other hand if you have all three intimacy passion commitment
this is constant love
according to sternberg complete love this
is how
he defines one
OK so now we have the definition of love and you can now
as a homework assignment sit down tonight
and make a list of every person you know
by the three elements of love
and just start putting the check marks in the boxes
and telling up your personal love
box scores
and we don't want to collect those we don't even wanna see those but
you can have fun with that then you can ask the other people to do
two and you can compare with each other
and you know if you will survive this exercise you will be
better for you know what doesn't kill you makes you stronger that's the idea behind
that exercise
now the social psychology
of love really has been a social psychology of attraction
what makes people
find each other attractive what makes them want to be intimate what makes them
physically desirable to each other what might lead to a commitment
the decision to make a commitment to making
this is just so that giving this lecture level two if you're holding hands here
and in the front really
all three elements present in university passionately
just just checking just check
right now when we look at how that appears in the theorem
it is the theory tells us that if we got a class
a class of
functions that take values in some bounded interval
then expectations are uniformly close to sample averages
where provided that
this notion of complexity is small
right so if we are in the case where you know we're not doing much
better than
if we try this supreme away and we have just single function this thing would
be zero right if we have a much richer class than that in the supreme
lexus lineup up really well
this is a large value then the theorem becomes weaker
right we get a much bigger
here on the right-hand side the we can't guarantee that the the
expectation is not much bigger than that
the sample average that's i've written inequality in one direction here i mean i could
have put absolute values around the difference between
the expectation the sample average it
you know the interval being zero one is not really crucial it could be any
bounded interval so i could consider negative functions
the the set of
of negative g where g comes from g and get the same thing so you
know i
i mean i i can get exactly the same inequality but two-sided i guess i'm
and i should say in everything that that i'm doing really relying on the fact
that we have bounded
random variables will see later that this is this is crucial for the concentration inequalities
that we
what we need
i think it it could be relaxed if you know something about the tails of
of you know certain distributions will appear but i that
and in that case for binary valued functions nine in fact for everything that we
do know these tools are powerful enough we can we can always work with bounded
loss functions
OK so
so let's
take a look at
how this theorem is proved
what we're looking at here i guess one crucial thing that
they should emphasise again is that we're talking about a result that is uniform over
the class
right so
so with high probability
every function in our class
has expectations sample average close
OK and that means if we choose some function to minimize
the empirical risk minimiser sample average of the loss
then we know that the loss for that function that minimizes is is going to
be not too big
OK so
you know it's a it's a uniform convergence results
it tells us about
the uniform deviations between
expectations and then sample averages
OK so what we really concerned with here
saying you know that the probability of the event that they
the maximum over this class of the difference between these two
big that probability should be small
OK so
so we're interested in this quantity
OK the maximum over hough class
of the difference between expectations and sample averages
OK and the concentration result that we use for that
particular theorem is is
a general one
called the demons inequalities also known as
thing is among
there there
there's another name that
skating for a moment but you know this is this is the result i guess
appeared in a paper of
o something equivalent in a paper of lifting
you know a very long time ago
so this result is the concentration result for
founded random variables
it tells us that
that if
it in particular you know we have a random variable such as this one
that depends on x one through x n right so this thing is just the
maximum over a class of expectation one sample averages OK that's random because it's it's
a function of the random variables x one through x and through the sample average
OK now make demons inequality tells us that if we have a function of i
i d random variables as we do here
then we get concentration of the
one of the random variable about its expectations
o provided that no one of those independent random variables has a big influence
how how do we
formalise that so the random variable with thinking of is this one
in our case but let's think now about well OK so so this thing is
a function of x one through xn
and the crucial
condition that's supply-and-demand inequality is that when one of these independent random variables changes the
the function that we have to changed by much so how do we measure that
will the sample average of g
g is a function that takes values in the interval zero one
so the sample average
can't change by any more than one over n
OK might go from one extreme like zero and in particular x i
gnx i might change from zero to to one if we change that excite
OK so
the same thing must be true for the supreme if we change one of the
excise this thing can change by more than one over in
and that means that this random variable is concentrated around its expectation so
precisely you know the the former dimon's inequality is that you know this random variable
is not much bigger than its expectation plus a little bit this little bit depends
on the
the the fluctuations that we see when we change one of those random variables
OK so this is a very general and
nice easy to apply inequality we just we're talking about a random variable that can
be expressed as a function of a bunch of independent random variables we change any
one of those
does the function change but not too much and if that's the case then the
random variable is is
concentrated around its expectation at this kind of a at a level it depends on
the size of the
the fluctuations
OK so that's at the heart
of of the profile right so
let me state this concentration inequality
so we have
so an elegant program
it doesn't matter
if it if it's very very slow as long as it's the smallest program that
calculates what it calculates
and it calculates an infinite amount of time
OK so that's important
because if you put a bound on the time you you you you can find
an elegant program for something
it's only when there is no bound on the run time
so anyway so let me repeat crucial result is you can never prove that program
is elegant
except with financing exceptions
so let me write that down
now there may actually be a finite number of exceptions but the infinite number of
elegant programs so
let let me give you a more and more precise statement of this this is
an incomplete list result by the way like that of nineteen thirty one
it could be result
saying that there are limits to what reasoning mathematical proof can achieve let me let
me give you more precise statements
you need
on n bit theory
to prove that an MBA program development
so let me say it another way
two two to prove that you can prove some things
i have to tell me what methods
what methods you're use
the normal way you you prove something can be proved metamathematics is the idea is
you don't discuss what can be proved informally because it's not clear so usually the
chen for a result of on probability is you talk about what's called the formal
axiomatic theory or formal axiomatic system that consists of a set of the finite set
of axioms and you using symbolic logic that normally would be first-order logic but but
i don't care
and the idea is you start with some axioms and then you get all the
consequences of the axioms and the consequences of the consequences of the axioms and so
on and so forth and those are the theorems in your formal axiomatic system
the ancient greeks in in alexandria
and that in simple cases but in alexandria
the euclidean put where there was a library the famous library
put together this wonderful book the elements
and and there you have it the sample of the mathematical theory where he starts
off with axioms or postulates and uses consequences
starting from there
and the notion of a formal axiomatic theory
is very similar but instead of using ancient greek or or or english
use of an artificial language use symbolic logic
and it has precise grammar
the key notion
in my opinion one of the key fact about formal axiomatic theory of formal mathematical
is that there is a mechanical procedure for deducing all the consequences of the axioms
for producing all the theorems
in principle you don't need mathematicians
in theory
because what you can do is just systematically started using using symbolic logic to use
all the consequent the the axioms so you go through all the proofs are one
step along the positive two steps on all the proof there are three steps long
there only a finite number of such proofs
and in this way
you could in theory when you have the form automatic theory
you have a mechanical procedure which will deduce all the consequences of the axioms which
all the theorems in your in your mathematical theory now this will be slow
and in fact is useless and to do this in practice
because to get interesting mathematical results you in such a long prove that you know
the number of possible proves that is
and steps long grows exponentially on n
so it's there are only a finite number of proofs of any given size you
know uniform one
axiomatic theory
but in fact you cannot run through all possible proof systematically you can go through
the tree of all possible
deductions all possible process in a practical way
but you can do it in theory because it's it's a large but finite set
the number of proofs of any given size and in the english literature on this
the the shape the curve will go a different direction
so here that on the ROC curve
random would be one here and the performance of the this
whereas in our case it goes down this small
look at the better
so those little thing to make it makes it quite clear that the different forms
now we're going to be looking one complication with this is that
once you've found in the county
if a set of particular threshold and say that this account is now four we
should really be keeping in in out of the peer groups from that point on
so the set of of complications of how to
following analysis of a very simple way out of this is just look at this
on a daily basis
look at one day's worth of transactions build building
look it up here but we don't is that they these days with of information
about what we believe is being defrauded
well the use of pictures to determine outliers
and then just make a performance because each day in the test data so this
then ask the question how do we combine the
performance curve
so the most straightforward method here is that we we average over a horizontal line
which basically means that
assuming that the number of
accounts activity today
reporting the same event
what we're saying is that
our for given number of for investigations of the company might assume that the same
each day
that's kind of what we should be everything online
so for the experiments and
look at a smaller subset of data the ones which had i've ordered transactions eighty
transaction the first three months before the forty three
that left me actually just four thousand counts six percent of those were defrauded in
the final fourth month
we use the first three months to build the peer groups and
the final each day than to to check out forms
the the number of parameters involved so close the building of the ips so many
segments subdivided the data into is initially just as it defaults for seven to eight
some assuming window that we use to find out whether it's an outline of the
set seven days
the size of about one hundred
and we got a robust method but what is an issue
the first thing to look at is
contamination helpful will contaminate picture so here
well looking at basically the area under the curve so
the smaller the value the better the performance is between zero and ten percent the
size of the
of the data set
but since we know where we have a lot of old well fort actually occurred
what i can do is i can just artificially remove them from peer groups once
defrauded the fact that you can see this is
these dots underneath
it makes a big difference with a small group of people it's because get so
attenuated because the the because of the amount of distance
can absorb these to better
but is initially
and to the can
changing the
the degree of granularity of the
building the pictures are just silly some entire
time series
which is one three-dimensional point
that's how
we know how good the form to be
this segment of the the market more detail about
the times is performance gets more modestly better
after about
sixty so we get a modest improvement with more details about the times but again
with segment data already by
using the high-volume accounts so they are based on the right
the summary statistic window this is what we use to one point for draws occur
you just use one day's worth of data
we don't have to do the performance as the data
in the data needs to summarise
this is a larger force could look that up to seven days and it's kind
a which is used for instance
major is in
critical for
the banking engine
so this the beginning that one
issue about useful thing about using pictures the outliers results last the entire population six
hundred fifty investigate this
and the support is just
based on wikipedia decides on top population minus the target account you're looking at
well in the next room is the some
percy we don't robustify using some of the parameters set by the beginning we get
this kind of performance
if every
removed four fourteen ten
like an organ within the contamination before it's likely that form the song down here
robustifying will still get a modest performance again
but compared to
the global methods this is quite correct the impact four
the labels
here we
if you are
in the winter
are a part
is a
you never
o thing that
are you
the other thing around here
so it's which
it's probably not
and the international community wrong
can't see all
so that
are the
for example
we also see
he a
the best
a lot of work in
in each
we use
so here here here
and my very first lecture
and the one that we used yesterday
in in the laboratory
it was the second function
so that they
this our true function
and we make IID observations
at each x
target value
of course is going to be the deterministic component so our true function
contaminated with some
some noise
so let's not take functional view
of modelling
rather than
the parametric view that we took
on the first two two sets of lectures
so things simplify no because of what we see as well
we're going to have a set of functions
and they going to be conditioned on
the set of attributes that we have
and and then in the parameters that define the covariance function
associated with my
my prior
so i'll just define
the prior my functions as this multivariate gaussian
it was a zero
train function
and the covariance function
well the talk about larger shortly
the likelihood of our data
i really specific realization
of our
the noise variance we know of course there's no just a product
of gaussians
which is now centered on the value of the functional value
which has been drawn from a gaussian process prior
and this of course is not just are
a spherical goes in
in n dimensional space seeing this
of course we are all good bayesians for the next hour
we really want the posterior
of function
let's remember we started we started off with a prior
a gaussian process prior are functions
we've observe some data in the form of the likelihood
i mean i want to update our prior belief
the the the likelihood to the posterior
this should look familiar now
we have a gaussian process prior on our functions
our likelihood
is gaussian
and it doesn't look as if too many of you have lost any sleep and
actually how we
the product of two gaussians
will lead
to another
in and the fact that the ratio of these garrisons in the marginalized form
all turns out to be gaussian
but it does
which means that our posterior over functions
no has a mean
and the covariance function
which is basically defined
the prior covariance matrix
the covariance
over noise
and of course the
the actual target values
when we want to make predictions
the predictive distributions
are also goes in as well and i one
boy was the details
so it's a very simple example based on the function that we're trying to model
yesterday afternoon
so we have the the true
the same function in red
and we have some data samples
right which
the the the values of the function
and have been contaminated with some noise
and we have
i decided to just for the purposes of this exercise to not sampled uniformly along
here so we've we've sampled
the data in little clumps
so the posterior predictive
values of our function the posterior mean
it turns out to be this little black line here
and the predictive variance
again all comes over
very naturally
and here the values here
and as you would expect in areas where we have the top
then of certainty
four prior posterior uncertainty
and in areas where we don't have a lot of data
then posterior uncertainty
remains fairly high
and if you
for those of you who are a layout
because we're using ago simply because there is no radial basis functions
to define the covariance function here
then the prior variance
it's going to be one
plus and minus one
so what you see
in areas