that measures how far apart these two lists are
and the idea is that if
so let's let's define that then we'll take a look at it so we can
potential function
mapping the set of
MTF's list in the real numbers
feel i
it's going twice
the cardinality of the set
so this is a
this is the preceeds operation in list i i
we can define a relationship between any two elements
it says
x precedes
l by
x precedes y YNL also by
as an actor singer from head i hit expert first
so what i'm interested in here are
in some sense the disagreements between the two lists
this is where
x proceeds y
in MTF's list why perceived x in obsolete
they disagree
and what we're interested in is the cardinality of the set
multiply by two
so that equal to two times
so there's a name for this type of thing we saw that when we're doing
sorting but remember the name
briefly very briefly i expect anybody remembers somebody might
conversions goode
twice the number of inversions
it was just do an example
so let's say also by is the list
OK let's see it
i used
characters for us
the order
just to keep things simple
in this case
the of l i
it's going to be
the cardinality of the set
so we want to do is look to see what things are out of order
here i look at e
and c are in this war
but c
and he in that order so those are out of work
so that counts as one of my element c
and then ian a
OK so those are out of order
and then you die
d out of water
and then e
those are out of work
and now i go see
see a those are in order so that doesn't count
the so nothing with c
and a
eighty those or a b
maybe those are in order
so then DB
PD so PD
that's the last one
that's my potential function
it is equal to
therefore ten
the cardinality of the set is five five inversions
between the two lists
OK so
so let's just cheque some properties of this potential function
the first one is the notice that p of l i
is critical to zero for all i
number of inversions might be zero but is never less than zero
OK it's always at least zero
so that's one of the properties that we normally happen we're doing
with potential functions
the other thing is
what about female zero
z equals zero
that depends powerless they start with
so you know what's the initial were so zero if they start with the same
and there are no inversions
they might start with different we'll talk about different this later on but let's say
for now
it is zero because
they start with the same list that seems like a fair
so we have this potential function now
deconvolution problems so once you work out the math and if you're interested the masses
in the slide
so when you were out as you've got that you have an unknown g which
is essentially
the derivative of the picture well with field at the surface which is just is
this is something that you
i get directed to
to measure
and the beautiful thing is that this kind of measurement g is actually related to
what you put in
the as simple convolution equation
right so
what you get to here is
the system higher excited the system convolve with the derivative
of alpha
which is this function alpha prime time two
so to recover a or equivalently to recover outside its will be sufficient to recover
its derivative
and so
what you have to solve then is deconvolution problem
you have the excite asian you have what you hear
and they're related buys this convolution function
the convolution by alpha prime and so you just need to deconvolve this product to
find out what alpha is
OK so we've got a very simple problem to solve now since now everything is
well we have what seismologists calls the reflectivity function which is prime of tower two
so we have the deconvolution problem to solve where if hours of prime of tower
two i need to solve f was are equal to
OK so now the
this is the
so the basic point here is that the earth is irregularly layer
and so
if we think about a of the first things this profile for primacy
fuzzy well it's centralizes minus an offset so alpha prime it's going to be zero
except at the locations of discontinuities
right so the earth is the real services irregular layer as a consequence is
that the vector are that i wish to recover is an irregular series of spikes
what people call the sparse spike trains
characteristics of seismic experiment is that the wavelength of the thing to do
the wave function i used to probe the system is bandpass
that is it's it is only supported in frequency in an interval because economic cycle
frequencies india's it's physically impossible
so the expectation is is bandpass which mean that this convolution equation kills a lot
of frequencies it kills low
and high frequencies
and so as the a consequence of this is that the seismic experiment is missing
a lot of low frequency or in other words the problem is extremely opposed this
because you don't get to see
the high frequency response of the reflectivity function
OK so here's what i'm
i am explaining you have the earth's
the impedance that looks like this
and of course the reflectivity function which is essentially the derivative of this thing looks
something like
OK now this is the kind of function that we used to probe the system
so wavelength
something that looks like this so this is fifty and this is what i get
to years what we call the seismic traces the echo
comes back after excited me
so to explain how this thing is bandpass
well this
x citation function missus out in the frequency domain lots of components because it sharply
concentrated around a frequency of interest
all right so
you can have
very important paper so
of course people have been interested in finding or for very long time
it's so in very interesting paper john care about suggested for the first time in
applied science the use of an one minimisation
and so
john about essentially formulated the problem exactly like this
and then he said listen i mean what i need to kind of recovery something
like this because i need to kind of reconstructing the discontinuities in
in the first upper crust
so here's what he wrote in nineteen seventy three paper is said in the convolving
any observed seismic trace
it is rather disappointing to discover that there is a non-zero spike at every point
in time regardless of the data sampling rate
one might hope to find facts only where real geological
geologic discontinuities take place perhaps in one and can be utilized to give an output
rates like figure thirteen
and so
essentially what john had to do is have to solve an underdetermined system of equation
in new that because of the physics of the problem the right hand side with
sparse any points although it doesn't do it in the paper he points out the
use of l one norm to get
a solution that looks like this and not something that would look like
anything else
because when you news minimum energy what you find is that there's a non-zero spike
at every point in time regardless of the data something rate
the course that is not physical
OK and so
a little later geophysicist started to crystallize these ideas so they were really crystallized in
a paper by taleban macquarie which
if i write my deconvolution problem matrix form
g calls f are where f is the convolution matrix
two banks in macau actually proposed to fit the data by an one minimisation
and so they said OK what we should do is we should minimize the l
one norm
OK so that's something kind of an interesting point that explanations of success tend to
be longer than expression
now how do you explain i didn't mention it did in the case of planning
the dome in the background knowledge in sense matalan instances that plan would be carried
in everything
goal is supported by somebody
and that was what every step in the plan
if it has any conditions somebody else is supporting them such that those support structures
not violated
OK so nobody else is coming in which
so you actually true
this explanation on your plan and which are features of the plan take part in
that explanation those are the only relevant features
that explain why defectors and the rest can be removed through sort of
a subset of the region
so there's been a lot of work in exploration research controlled rule learning pre nineteen
ninety five what i said there was a big
the increase in performance of domain independent planning staff nineteen ninety five there have been
so before that there was a lot of work which showed that the the planets
could be improved significantly using UBL analysis and more recently i think as i said
in general the interest in speeding up using learning techniques over the used and are
but there's been some examples that is where i think for example that the planet
which i want to discuss the plan and invite now
most implementations of grassland lined up using some sort of explanation based
learning from failures
improve performance and that seems to work quite well but are it basically uses EBL
almost as explanations are correct and complete explanations of
what i want you to understand that in general if you have background knowledge it's
sort of
it focuses you as to what part of your big example
i can be blamed for its label can be created for
OK and if you wrong it's still be
it's like saying the feature selection that is on that space
and i spend as much time talking what be allowed to say a few things
which i might have rather misconceptions to you in your mind you know you if
you read about this in literature or the literature of this sort of stuff comes
up so one is a
you know the idea that maybe explanation based learning on the complete and correct background
as i mentioned in my card example
OK so you explanation that as brazil background knowledge and to the extent you have
any background knowledge that you believe in it introduces it focuses your learning of what
in fact i think that sort of components the in that he was this analytical
arguments and with knowledge of what knowledge four dimensional
OK so if you have a background knowledge you want to use it in general
not and unless you're going to be completely but why would you not want to
so if you do have completely acknowledged that the learned knowledge will be the deductive
closure of the original image so if you just had to get them to work
i just kept spewing out of that effectively
and the knowledge from the existing set of knowledge if you had complete correct explanations
originally then you think that would be that detective was
it's not for me that
so it's more likely that the learning where you always making jumps from what you
know what you
OK so again i think the idea of thinking of these other the feature selection
step is useful one the second thing is that maybe elizabeth competing connected and i
don't think it's that much in vogue right now but there was the a time
when people would actually think about this and i would say
i think of another feature selection step twenty learning algorithm and you don't have a
the third thing which actually comes in several description fabio if you look at any
textbook level descriptions the is some mile mileage is a bad thing because knowledge was
used in the lndl had do
the problem what was the problem it turns out that if if you learn a
whole bunch of rules
if you learn a whole bunch of rules of this farm saying don't exist right
the following is still the biggest rival the following is true
and then you have knowledge among library you know can be things don't do this
don't do this don't do don't do that and then i will you have a
new plan you are looking at you a large library of all the do's and
don'ts to see whether or not he should take a step OK and if there
are too many of these rules you could be spending your lifetime matching
the left hand side of the rule just to see whether it is applicable
OK now
this has nothing to do with explanation based learning policy in general search control knowledge
which tries to
which is organised in terms of a new bunches of rules you know you have
to match those rules if you have a large number of plans that you stored
in a library so that you can use them to solve new problems if the
family becomes very large then you know you can give you a very small problem
to solve your be spending time looking into this very large library trying to see
whether or not
another that i plan for the day in the life
OK so i think that the problem is the real one but it's real one
but in general it is absurd control knowledge it has nothing to do
in a knowledge base was a small amount this one
OK so that's basically what i wanted to say and on the part one other
thing that actually i think something that we hopefully will learn that john as a
and this lecture today is one thing that would be useful if you want to
learn complex
OK with a few examples examples
you just have to use that knowledge i mean the classic what we did this
for that right now i think it was in the audience to me i will
we have in the humans basically only look learn those things that we are the
most of any normal
OK this is exactly the reason why you are not our own methods and you're
the shorter the wavelength the higher the probability ever take a three
you going to see the location of the qualitative division
blue light is ten times higher probability
to be scarier than red light
and so whenever i going to do my
scattering experiments on very fine particles you will see that light is going to be
you can miss that
now if the particles of which i scatter larger than the tens of micron say
one micron this
effect of color on probability of scattering is
highly reduced
and if i scan of very large particles and microns or so
and there is no dependence anymore at all
and in this lies the
secret why the sky is blue
i'll get back to that later today
the reason why cigarette smoke can be blue if they smoke particles
a very small and it's the reason why clouds of white
because the sunlight hits the clouds the light scattering but the water drops in the
clouds and not
o point one microns but they are much larger they are more like ten microns
enough so
there is no preferred wavelength that scatters and so the clouds look white
and so the first demonstration that i want to do
it is very much like what you see here
i'm going to send unpolarized light up here
straight up
we have bright spotlights there and the light goes straight up
and here i'm going to put a very small dust particles
and i decided to do that smoke simply cigarette smoke
so i'm going to hold cigarette smoke in these beings
and the light that will come to you no matter where you see it must
have scattered closely over ninety degrees right it comes up like this but if you
see it almost for everyone in the audience
ninety degrees
angle scattering
so we should many polarizes
you will be able to see
that that light
is polarized
it's going to be polarized in this direction
which is the direction that i have here
that's the first thing i'm going to do
for this demonstration
so i need
and i need to smoke
as much as i hate to this
so the light
it's like an
presumably you
for this
OK but i really
well you do this
number one
that the light
is bluish
number two to this
take your time for that
if you don't see it is blue
and the reason for that is that at low light intensities
your eyes are not very sensitive full-color anymore
looks quite close to me though
now i want to do
something in addition
i mentioned
that if the particles
grow in size
that the scattering is no longer preferred in the blue
and i can demonstrate that
i can kill two birds with one stone
what i can do
it is i can hold to smoke
in my mind for a while
and when i do that the
the water vapor in my
will precipitate on these dust particles
and they will form small world graphs
and when i post that out
you will see a distinct difference in color between what you see now
and the smoke that comes out of my lungs
when these particles can microns and even larger you'll see then that the light is
so this is
this comes extract over and above come for free
in order to make you see the difference shortly before i profile to smoke in
i will again show you this smoke as it is now
so you can compare the cause
and you will see that there is a difference even though it doesn't it may
not look very blue is to you
the reason that i mentioned in darkness
you don't have very good sensitive for calling
so i'm going to hold is
smoke now
as much as i hate it is one of the worst demonstrations that i have
to hold it in my lungs for a while
i see you get very close
the second
i was very wide compared to the first one
so we were able to catch two birds with one stone here
the sky is blue because of this phenomenon
you're standing
on the earth
and so light is coming in
onto the earth's atmosphere
the sun is there
so light comes in
and the lights cameras
and the light that reaches you
its canons of these extremely fine dust particles
and also scanners of the air molecules themselves
there are thermal fluctuations that go on all the time which causes density fluctuations in
the air and they are sufficient to act as catalyst
and so if light from here comes through
the chances are
that is below
because there's a higher probability than red
and this is also likely to be blue
so when you look at the sky
this guy
looks road that's the reason has to do with this strong preference
four color to be
scan when it is
blue light
if you look
in the direction of the sky
an angle of ninety degrees
the direction of the sun
this guy is also linearly polarized for the reason that we now understand because the
the first of the economic transition system of lectures on a string theory for pedestrians
and with a promise of course this podcast was director of research at CNRS
and the theoretical physics lab difficult moments montpellier
because that's not the same thing is that is the imprisoning
nineteen eighty then you would
he went most of the slack
is member of senate since nineteen eighty eight
he has been member incorporated mechanical my has also visited from nineteen ninety two
it's an expert in theoretical aspects of particle physics condensed matter and also a leading
expert in knitting theory
for this reason he has been awarded several prizes including two thousand two is better
prize of the french
the second society so very fortunate to have him introducing here first in these
thank you very much
has held thank you for the invitation to give these lectures here
i understand this is a non-specialist audience now some of you may know a lot
more of course from what i'm going to tell you about what i will try
to do in history lectures is to try to give you a basic idea of
what string theorists
i have done are doing and what we hope
four with trying to give you a particular
there a the
o point of view of the particle theories namely what
one can hope to learn about particle physics in this place this is of course
very appropriate so in the first lecture this will be
an extremely elementary one of the first one i just want to get across to
you the basic ideas of the basic tools of string theory in elliptic and up
way and then the next two lectures our move on to the two main stream
activities of string theory over the last twenty years almost a on the the one
hand the unification of particle interactions and on the other hand QCD
the strong force this as you will see the crests along different routes but which
meet at various places in interesting ways
to go back
forty years of forty five years in the sense that the whole story one may
say started with one of his prophetic paper so the iraq in nineteen sixty two
it did not as you may know the didn't likely normalisation he thought it should
be some sort of effective theory effective calculation
and that nature in the sense with finite had some optional
that of scale and may be motivated by this it's not clear in the paper
he thought that maybe he could try to understand why there is both an electron
and a new one in nature which after all are very similar particles except for
different mass by just thinking of both of them
as quantum states of one extended object in this case the charged membrane
actually if you go back and look at this paper the actor it qualifies the
membrane fortunately he did it in a cheaper way doing what we want to make
all bore bored quantization
because otherwise he would have discovered that it's not possible
with our new techniques to quantify the membrane and actually quite
surprisingly he even found the mass ratio of about fifty miles that's of course not
correct but it's a large number of which
comes out of a very simple calculation and this was in a sense the first
study of extended quantum objects in modern physics
now if you years later in a totally different to decouple development people were starting
at that time met resonances in hadronic collisions and they realize that these resonances were
actually arranging themselves in this plot where you put mass squared on the horizontal axis
and you put angular momentum or have to get to know how to use this
they get this could
so one portsmouth square the the horizontal axis and one outputs a angular momentum or
spin on the vertical axis and if you look at the experiment method brought these
are probably still the most impressive experimental evidence for the existence of relativistic quantum strings
in nature this approach are absolutely straight lines as you can see
over about a decade in energy from half GV to about five or ten TV
and this is exactly what
the theory of quantum relativistic strings predicts as i say more in a minute is
that sometimes called the the chief around shiploads
and the edge of trajectories that describe this vision resonances
this was forty years ago
however precisely these two ideas are allowed to live today they are still alive but
they have gone numerous transmutation almost unrecognizable
but still very out of
the first idea namely the fact that
all the particles could be may be unified by an extended object in particular the
quarks leptons and gauge bosons of the standard model in this
as you will see is indeed very much what string theories have been trying to
today we going talk about a new
balanced search structures data structure that maintains the dynamics that subject insertion deletion and search
called skip lists
so called this the dynamic search structure because of the data structure and support search
dynamic meaning experimentally
so what other dynamics are structures so we know just for the sake of comparison
weak everyone of
efficient i should say
time per operation
so this is really easy
question to get us
so all the last we
we shouldn't be so
three go the problems that with troops that in some sense
this is the simplest dynamics can get from first principles because all we needed was
the bound on randomly constructed binary search tree trips did well
so that was sort of first one is sort ending when you get your problem
what else
red black trees good answer
that was exactly one week ago
because the they have guaranteed logan performance of this was the
expected bounds this was the worst case order log
for operation insert delete search
and there is one more
this what recitation on friday
the trees good
and by the trees i also include two three trees to three report reason of
so these are constant or if you made your between a little bit
and these have
guaranteed or log performance the worst case order log
so you should know this these are all
search structures that dynamically support insertions deletions they support search is finally given
and if you don't find the key finders predecessor and successor pretty easily in all
of these structures
if you want arguments some data structure you should think about which one of these
diseases to augment
as in monday's lecture
the question i want to post here
is suppose
i give you all right now
which would be great
but then i asked you to in order to keep this laptop you have to
implement one of these data structures
let's say within
this class our
do you think you could do it how many people think you could go
what a couple people fifty k
all four of people
i could probably do my preference would be trees there's sort of the
simplest in my mind
this without using the textbook to be closed book
example i don't have an about us to do unfortunately
so the trees are pretty reasonable deletion you have to remember this stealing from the
sibling and what not to do which is a bit tricky red black trees i
can never remember how to look it up or are we derive the three places
are a bit messy so that would be
take a little while remember exactly how this work you'd have to solve your problem
set again if you don't have to memorize
at skip lists on the other hand are data structure you will never forget
and something you can implement
within an hour
o problem i've made this claim
a couple times before and i always felt bad because i've never actually done it
so this morning i implemented skip lists
took me ten minutes to implement link
thirty minutes to implement skip lists
another thirty minutes debug
there you go
it can be done
skip lists are really simple and at no point writing the code that i have
to make
whereas every other structure i would have to think there's one moment when
my name was get or
and i'm going to be talking about statistical relational learning
and the way that i want that this tutorial is like two
about it
an hour and a half or so
a little bit more
and then
break a little bit early for line so you can all get in line early
and then come back at the regular time
and what i'm going to be presenting
is really
an attempt
i have a lot of ideas for a lot of different people
that have been involved and
various statistical relational learning workshop had over the years
and various other workshops like the related multirelational data mining workshop couple dog still workshops
and so on
so it's an attempt at synthesis
but it's also
you know
even at three and a half hours seems like a long time it still cannot
show it's not covering everything
if you do want to see everything
so we just recently i have the book at which
i didn't bring because
like six hundred pages in
we use too much in my luggage it would have been able to take it
carry on but this is available from MIT press
and it has a lot more detail a lot more
kind of tutorial chapters on
a number of the different approaches and i'm going to talk about
the general outline of the tutorial i'm going to spend up twenty minutes during and
then the core
it's going to be talking about
four different approaches to
statistical relational learning
and then
can interact with applications and future directions
and definitely
you know make this is interactive is possible if you guys have questions
sure an interactive
ask questions and so on and clarifications
what is SRL
there's a question will why
and i kind of simplistic view
i have zero is
well if you think has that traditional
statistical machine learning approaches all of them make
really strong assumptions about
what kind of sample you have that you have an IID random sample
each of instances has the same kind of structure there are homogeneous objects from single
relation so that's one
an area
of machine learning
areas machine learning that has always dealt with structure relational learning inductive logic programming again
caricature of that is traditionally
are at least initially it didn't deal very much with noise and that examples so
we have these two
machine learning settings
but in reality
most of the data
so we wanted to know what is for stuff
multi relational and heterogeneous even sometimes family structure
it's noisy and uncertain
and so
statistical relational learning kind of
an emerging area
exemplified also by work and say social network link analysis
hypertext and web mining graph mining
and relational learning and inductive logic programming always
fields and areas are trying to deal with this can make
logical structure
and uncertainty
part of the reason
of y is coming to the forefront now
it's so many other domains and it that they were getting really exemplified so you
know if you think of web data OK that
can the classic
up where you have some some kind of link structure and you structure inside the
pages and so on the graphical data where you have citations you have authors to
other kinds of attributes
many kinds of biological data so
epidemiological data so disease spread but then also
things like protein protein interaction networks all of these things have a kind of natural
graph relational structure but then also natural noisy component
you know a lot of the work in natural language processing these days is trying
to capture both the structure semantic structure together with the co occurrence information
computer vision
there's lots of examples
i have
let me start with kind of caricature of what is a zero
this is always my favourite slide sometimes they have these all animated
well certainly
one way of doing it kind of alphabet soup
all these different
representations and systems proposed for combining together
probability and i can kind of cheese about this because i'm responsible for at least
a couple of these collections of alphabet
actually one of the things that i hope i'm going to be able to accomplish
tutorials can demystify the model that so try and pull out you know
what are
the comment
commonality is and what are they
kind of ways of characterizing
these different approaches
kind of second view
a little bit more
representations two
this is kind of
where these approaches come from well
there's certainly you can identify two different camps there's kind of people that started off
a logical
representation that did capture
the relational structure and then
added in probability
defectors started with some sort of probabilistic representation better propositional
and then added in structure
and would
the exact numbers are all sins he served under
this is a very general properties common to all analytical functions
but in the case of the function we can do
something very special
we can consider that the fact that function which is a multiplicative function
by some factor which is explained session function
its position is never zero
so we do so if you do not have any new
this function can be easily computed
and it was it is important
which changes the argument
when teenage range already all numbers
the argument over the years range or
along the critical line
this function turned out to be a deal forty awareness of it
and so we can plot
o twenty
goes here
this argument goes along the critical line and
see evidence of
functions that
so now we can try to do the following
let us
some important
he green point six invisible
our functions at this point
we don't need to find exact values
it would be sufficient
to find the evidence for some possible errors
as long as we assure
that we can judge what is the sign of our function these points
if you know that this point
the function is negative
at this point
it is positive
then we know for sure that somewhere in between
there should be zero
and in this way
we can count the number of zeros
exactly on the critical line
it remains the company's numbers
and so the classical methods long before during
but as follows
it consisted of two stages
the first stage
this number of people concluded this integral
and then
try to find
such many numbers green points
go going increase in order
and until that each time
we get the changes sign
if succeeded then they would know for sure that all zeros
the lie on the critical line
this is principle
how could you find
but this is the sign of the function
luckily gram
was the first person to publish
proof of
about initial that of the function
gave the
heuristic rules for selecting such points
so he refuses to the function
it grows almost as a linear function
because this factor grows
very slowly
sit comes here
in the exponent
this can be written as the real part and imaginary part
and this function dimension but is of interest for us
it looks like a sine function
and there are also this function
on our
gram points
the traditional unnumbered in such a way that the the function at point
is indexed families that book by multiplied by
if you look
the have that the plot of the
and the plot of the sine function
we'll see
they behave
similar to sine function and cosine function
in other ways
zero so functions function
respond approximately those axioms as the function
and so
grams points are
four be a good one
joke this i know that
grand made this
observation on
looking at the initial
below so that and that the the functions
but later
hodkinson extended it to all possible values of
and called ground floor
so grammar can be stated that
itself that function alternating sign is a growth of
but ironically
atkinson himself
following that can alone is not a lot of
following the first violations of this long and nowadays know that there are infinitely many violations
look at this picture
he is the negative
here's a negative
but we can judge from the picture what happens here
and fact the middle is also negative so we have city negative images
in three consecutive grand points
so we can distinguish
between good ground points
and background words
what would you do
and we need to find a place where
that function is positive
and then just make some shift from this point
all that we need this you would be
would keep the point between the consecutive grand points
in this case is rather small
and so
the classical methods was
none before argument was as follows
the first stage company
this integral
try to find a small numbers age minus one and so on
go on sex in some schools in increasing order
and verify that the change
of science at this point
he succeeded
you know that all zeros
held the critical like
and t why would not succeed
and very very simplified situation a bit
when we speak about the number of zeros
we can count
them into ways
this is the basic
object of interest
i mean the
basically to characterize a markov process
what i'm telling you
is that
so the markov process
i'm going to assume full second simplicity
that is the emerging markov process
on its own tightly defined essentially
by the distribution
the initial state x one
but this is applied to the new
o point you don't see
all basically
well i also need to know politician density
markov process xk
so what i would assume
is that
assuming xt i just wanted to put this quantity here
then xk is distributed according to these conditional one of
but when you don't
on the
the same thing
the bits of people
so this thing is nothing but the probability
in human xk parliament twice but
i'm sure you all know about the model
when xk to finite
a finite markov process is finite
but the market change
in the case of being twice
i'm interested in the case where particularly
the next day
if x is already but also in my opinion this kind of detail state space
markov process
it doesn't have to to be only value depending on back
no problem
so this is the notation i'm going to use new initial distribution f transition density
although we also use
the following matlab notation i'm sure you're all familiar with
i j which is a collection of state
x one phi i phi j
on the other side information because fine but also the market process
i know that if i look at the joint distribution
the first newspaper is x one x two x then obviously i can't always we're
right that it is you have explored the next the x one and p of
y one on and so forth all because of the markov assumption i can also
arise these things as initial distribution nu x one time to hold
from two two and the transition from time from experiment one
but that's it
this is
these things five
the prior distribution as stated the state
x one to x
those market all sets i'll try to convince you that they are ubiquitous in science
and applied science so very popular very popular application of the thing is i'm going
to describe it in the case where you have the right to some walking
OK so you interesting talking
whatever object
and so the x y plane are
you tried to put
modelled on
on this process on the way simple fold our would duties consist of introducing
o state x which correspond to say
coordinates on the excess axes
coordinates of the y axis is the city on the x axis is the one
model to describe the evolution of the target in plane
it the following basically
constant velocity model
all this is simply covering everything in the simple
this is
thank you
the is just
so the problem is that the rate at which
you can do that in and
it is
the point
this is
this is the solution
the point
it also
she is
let's see what he
it's the one
in the case of
and c
so so
this year
eighty percent
what he saw
one of my vision
the second approach
you be able to give
OK go
that's what
that means that all
the show
we have a
one hundred years
set c
the national you to do
born into this world
in the image
he said the school
so this is all
this is
this is just the
the next radio show
the station could
these are
so i think that they should
i call this
all right it
right so you would start again with now
you come up
with a similar expression alpha densities say the likelihood
function for new
and sigma squared would be again if i assume that the set of data
x one to x is generated independently at random
so i would form the likelihood
of these data
right then this would be
the something it's clear two phi sigma squared
e to the minus
two sigma squared x minus
square so this would be
the likelihood
and then was always
so the people with specific background i always love to minimize things rather than maximise
i think economists try to maximize sort of other people like i mean i have
an education is a theoretical physicist like this is always kind of energy should be
minimized things like that although we have entropy such that maximizes
and it's a different kind of the risk should be minimized
right so
so often it's people put a minus log to the likelihood and you want to
minimize that is just a matter of taste
no big deal so just to the negative effect take the log of this you
get the sum of logs and since i have an exponential here then the nice
thing is exponential in the log of the exponential gets this
o thing in the exponent down and we have this
and here is also belong
two pi sigma square and so this is what we have to minimize now
we can do the same trick is before we differentiate for instance if you're interested
the estimate from you
well you have to do
so first of all there's always the part that doesn't interest you because it does
not depend on get it
when you differentiate so you take the
the mu
i from one to n
x mu squared
two sigma square you want to set it equal to zero but even if you
because you set it equal to zero
you can even forget about that
because this is just the multiplicative thing
well let's let's
i believe the two years
so we know this there should be zero
then you get to from here
you get a
x y minus mu
so i want to n of the minus sign in this should be zero
now you have two parts of this you have some over x y
i from one to n
and you have the somewhere you sum
in times the factor mu
so you get equals you get a plus n times mu
and this is zero so yourself from you
and you get
again one over and you take all your data some them up divided by and
you get the mean of the data well again why bother i mean it seems
like the obvious answer everybody would do that but
as i said there are other models were maximum likelihood looks different
and especially here is a specific class of models for which maximum likelihood looks terribly
simple this is the class of exponential families and they are considered to be the
simple things these are the building blocks for more complicated
so let's look at on that
i haven't done the second part
you can do the same
o thing then for the variance in which you would get
it is an estimate of the variance squared
with the similar trick so you have to do the deed by d sigma squared
and you can also estimate for the variance
so now
let's relate this maximum likelihood
well maybe i should just freeze have
i have a glass of water
ask me questions if
embarrassed me
yes please
this is not always assume that
you know what is going to be yes yes it's your model u s four
yes yes
what if you don't
we have one
the goal of the model to come up with something
if you don't know anything i mean you can make it more vague and they
got will
talk about probably tomorrow about girls processes where you have a very wake kind of
idea what you functions that you try to model they are so you could actually
say well you know they are just kind of well actually said
i believe that my data come from some function you know this and x and
y is some function and i believe there actually well is a continuous function is
differentiable many times and well consider the input of free parameter tells me how we
can see this is so it's very wake thing you can put in
the models that are the nonparametric model is parametric models got one single parameter
in it or two
then you can think about models that have sort of a number of parameters that
actually grow
with the number of data so you must come up with more parameters after this
is what you would call a nonparametric semiparametric problem
so we can do that as well
well there is probably one but
OK i can look it up if you want but OK well first of all
it's a clear thing whether what i mean by a parametric model i mean the
number of parameters are completely independent of the number of the data here so i
just fixed my
well if you know nothing
and it's a bit hard you always have to come up with something because you're
kind of
you have some domain knowledge always and then you can come up with some ideas
that might fit
that might be applicable
so now
using this good old friend that you also know from before and also from the
from johns lecture linear regression
well you try to fit
straight line through the cloud of points
and now we can do that again as a probabilistic from a probabilistic model point
of view
of that allows invariance as a special case and so if you prefer one of
those special cases think in those terms
now that's half the problem is is the the rolls on the other hand the
problem is the
discriminant function i the classifier so we have this family classifiers line some family
big gamma and it's probably going to be a large families were not symmetric family
and the problem is to find a decision like in decision theoretic framework at the
node incision this is now is two parts is to choose the quantizer q
and the two the discriminant functions
that's the output is this this this this to people
i mean what our loss function well the risk is going to be the problem
is here
so the y the point the quantized discriminant function value was not equal to the
the correct label that that is the way of one zero one loss function i
take expectation like get the probability that an article so this is the risk function
as a function of q and gamma i it's different notation but it is it's
my decision theoretic framework we talked about earlier
OK so there are many applications for this
OK so if you look at the existing literature there sort of help on two
sides of the equation but not both of them simultaneously the classical signal press processing
literature define this problem decentralised detection and it assume everything is known except for the
everything means that all the problems which are known the class conditional probability distributions the
class problem prior probabilities and so on
although it's not known is q
and so how did you find q
nine symmetrical drawing do
slide here is the trying light over here
i didn't come on the idea that wrong
no i didn't work
so in original space there is the next phase over here had class one
and class zero
maybe looking like that
and it's hard to be discriminate boundary among these two things one might want to
use them as you go over to space the
which places as far apart as possible
right that would be a good choice of q
and if i did a bad choice of q it would smash them together even
right so all i can do is measured some ways the
divergence among probability distributions
and then optimize q expected divergence
what version should use
i will try to maximize divergence here not with minimum divergence is the maximum divergence
so these guys said well what are some divergences you can maximize and so they
wrote down lot of kind of functions functionals on probability distributions and they found some
of them were easy to maximize some were not and so they pick those and
that's what they did so hellinger but i have a whole bunch of others kind
came out of the literature and became famous in other fields and they were set
up because of this problem of divergence lots of radar has been done this way
big literature or people have just picked the divergence a hellinger chair for something and
then it's function properties you should be using those properties are known
so just write down the expected divergence maximize q and pop up that you back
to the user and so can you put that in your radar radar quantizes in
that way called signal set selection
all right so that's the story i would be this is basically heuristic literature to
to turn the lights off or i could control
so it's
with the what they do
alright so it's basically using a plugin and they're not really worry about how well
it performs you put it in
and you don't then try to evaluate how well that does
all so the systems unit and the china has its focus on problems where the
whole problem to find the discriminant function and not all about experimental design so you
assume that that's known you try to find that and the way it's done is
is that by the time the certain loss function to boost indiscretions for the machines
are all based on surrogate loss functions and this is the kind of more rigorous
as a decision theoretic flavour discusses the results and so on and so forth but
it really facing the whole problem which is to find the q and the gamma
OK so it's unbelievable machinery this talk about these f divergences these are the guys
that have been discussed by the signal processing literature course then appear many other solutions
as well
a kind of part of part of this this talk is going to be to
somehow unify these things is that is the list of things and in minor there
on the predicates are not inside but
the actual critical state
of the predicates is in the apart from these ones and if you a few
of his council along path
there are about one million
the solutions in open source
i believe and five hundred ninety six thousand two hundred fifteen of them is a
relationship so relating individuals
including individual predicates the types of things they are so
the predicate is
is predicted so that's one hundred ninety six thousand two hundred fifty
o five hundred ninety six thousand two hundred fourteen more
i guess is the predicate for example that accounts for another one
ninety nine almost a hundred thousand generalisation relationships so saying that
was saying that US president generalizes to
politicians for example is one of those two generals relations it's saying that
so i saying that city in
country from german germany generalizes to city
there's another one of those generals relationships so have
the relationships between functional terms and
not functional terms so these are all the type relationships to have instantiation relationship type
relations and
between those two we have used up about seven hundred thousand of them
the rest of them
destroying this sort
for example you know
city is a piece of fruit
probably that hasn't decision the knowledge base directly but it's the thing which allows you
to infer that from the is generally relationships and thus destroying this relationship is in
being able to prove that i could is not a material being for example from
the fact that he's a that he is a son and therefore a human being
and therefore a hominid therefore a primate and therefore
a mammal and therefore it so that all objects and therefore a something is still
in something as this thing is disjoint with the material things and all the way
all the way down point of this was the ethereal being just stating the distance
of the top that allows you to prove for example that buffer zone is somewhat
of an ethereal beings with marko certainly
with similar relationships we improve the markers that are present our trusty and the
one of the largest not peaceable on furniture and so on and so forth so
these sets are disjoint efforts relationships are extremely
computers improving the sorts of things that grow
people take for granted
the result in all for the functions for example the relation which is used to
say that city in country from germany produces the city
so what if you put in whatever country you put into it
you give a collection of cities back
and he said that using a relation but this is
this is sort of an overview of these cover most of the these cover most
of the sorts of things that you can get out of
open in full sight of the relationship to use more widely because we're in the
ricci stating facts rather than its nomination
and so on
cruising at to a few thousand meters by the knowledge base where sort of look
look into some areas of
there's a good deal of geospatial knowledge there
there are seventeen thousand terms related to cut the fourteen hundred genes related apology
a thousand translated topology so that's the top quality of parts
information about the geographical region bodies award the graphical for underwater plants
and their relationship to the relationship between those types of geospatial entities and other represent
for those participation in these such as the USGS representations
these representations for the sorts of things which happened in
so for example
then an ecological system has the boundary a resource a resource and synthesizer released resource
synthesis inside a closed system is done by something is a providerofmotiveforce for that resource
in size
again these sorts of things are represented as systems inside like the vocabulary for representing
them is available
open inside and you get to site you can see examples of how these this
representational vocabulary is used
because of ecosystems
credit lives to inspire ions is a consistent problem rainforest ecosystems
hundreds of years whatever they are graphs the larger there are lots of the terms
of human knowledge this cycle is much more about it than i do
it was produced by people who liked
representing obscure things sometimes it seems to be the worst scenes
terribly down
the ecosystem so is
line for prospective application but parts of it have been used for previous applications for
example in these areas things like mediterranean skype between training scrub for example is used
for military applications to work things like traffic ability so the type of the type
of ecosystem that's in the region and as you know what sort of vehicles can
pass through
so again these are some examples of how to use the book relates things together
so the climate of h temporal ecosystem
a mediterranean climate type and the training of the climate is mediterranean scrub
and military discovers the type of true
geographical region and the territory of crab creek greece
i had the time high mediterranean climate cycle so these
the things on the predicates existing programs you can just find look inside and you
use them to quit represent the relationships between the
the land
violence the type of vegetation
the location and ecological system you have to start from scratch during this if you
didn't use for purposes but this would have the terms of existing is very useful
to have them all really connected the background knowledge available background knowledge
talking about transportation events we have hundreds of
for hundreds of
first of all possible lecture this you should consider going back to current just to
seriously the
in the early nineteen eighties and became part of the power law distributed
research group
he co-inventor boltzmann machines turns nasty in nineteen eighty three
members of the researchers who introduced back propagation algorithm
the training of new networks books in nineteen eighty six to an explosion in the
growth neural networks and actually the nips conference started in nineteen eighty seven american way
excitement around books
jeff has received many awards including the fellowship of royal society in nineteen ninety eight
the data david run in two thousand one
and this guy award for research excellence in two thousand five
since nineteen eighty just continue to be high
contribution such as variation learning
how does machine politics expert architecture most recently he has been
working on deep belief networks for unsupervised learning and they be
talking about deep learning multiplicative interactions thank you
thank you
so today i'm going to spend the first ten minutes also give you background about
the learning and for many of you know this stuff but i want to give
the general background and then i'll show you one recent example where the ideology of
deep learning worked perfectly
and then going to talk about how to make
the basic learning module works better by introducing multiplicative interactions into a restricted boltzmann machine
i must say why we need to do that and how we keep the number
of parameters under control
and show you how the inference and learning is still
structure relatively straightforward
and then describes three examples
from student in my lab using the
multiplicative interactions
one is learning transform images that is learning and just change over time
another is having a model of human motion and using style able to transform models
that can come in many different motions and the last is
modeling the covariance structure of images so that you can do better discrimination
so restricted boltzmann machines consists of two layers of
you're like units binary stochastic units
and there's no connections between hidden units
and also no connection between visible units
given the state of the visible units which is right for the data the hidden
units are conditionally independent so it's very easy to do inference in this kind of
machine and that's good news
the rule for turning on the hidden unit is simply you compute
input is getting from the visible units put through the logistic function and that tells
you the probability turning on and then make a stochastic decision about whether it should
be an independent stochastic decisions rolling units
this network obeys a hopfield energy function
where the energy if i tell you the states of the visible and hidden units
the energy of the network
is quadratic in the states
for all pairs of the visible and units both of you take the weight between
you add up all those weights
and that tells you
negative energy low energies good
the derivative of the energy function is nice and simple
it's just the product of the visible in activity that's the inspector way to achieve
you can use those energies to define probabilities over joint configurations invisible units
and the probability of a joint configuration is proportional to e to the minus its
but that's normalized by the probabilities of all possible configurations is called the partition function
makes learning tricky
to know the probability that you assign to visible vector v
you have to add up over all possible states of the hidden units
possible one
the maximum likelihood learning algorithm for restricted boltzmann machine is conceptually very simple
but takes a long time
you start with data on the visible units at time t zero
and then using whatever what you currently have you the hidden units
and then if you to do it right you then activate the visible units again
and you go backwards and forwards
this is the markov chain to alternating blocked gibbs sampling and when you run long
enough you forgot where you started in my sampling from the visible path is the
model believes in and for those visible patterns that distribution model beliefs you compute the
pairwise statistics you compute how often a pixel of tag together
the learning rule is just the difference between
the pairwise statistics with data
and we fantasies from the model
unfortunately had to run the markov chain for a long time
i discovered empirically that if you are markov chain for a short time still works
pretty well and it's much quicker
so what we're going to do is just activate hidden units
a lot of the hidden units to reconstruct the pattern on the visible units was
to be going be quite like the data
then activate in units again
and the difference of those two pairwise statistics will tell you how to change awake
and then we'll just do stochastic gradient descent to try and get a good set
of words
the main reason restricted boltzmann which is interesting
it's because you can use it recursively to learn deep that it turns out that
the the you end up learning is a directed network which is a big surprise
people in graphical models and your learning directed one layer at a time
i'm not going to go into that any further
i'll just give you the sort of
how to use it
you train one layer of features and then treat the activations of those features is
new train another
you just keep going like that for many less you can stand
and when he finished the top two layers are restricted boltzmann machines and the system
memory and all those below can be thought of as a directed graphical model director
so that you can generate data from the system memory via some transformations on the
other hand this
i would like to prove that every time you add another here unless you get
a better model of the data
we can't quite prove that we can almost prove every time you add another left
if you do it right you improve the variational bound on the log probability of
the model generates the training data
that's good enough to show you doing something sensible
after you've learned multiple less
you can then sticks label units on top
and do backpropagation
now back propagation is now not having to design features of the features already designed
by unsupervised learning the model is boltzmann machines
all back propagation is doing is slightly changing the way it hardly changes the tall
so the boundaries between classes are in the right places
so it's slightly adjusting the features to be better for discrimination but it's not having
to discover the features
so the unsupervised learning gets into lot of white space and then the
back propagation within a group of white space
does local myopic steepest descent to tune the weights discrimination
experiments in bengio slide show that
this wins in two ways the unsupervised learning get richer better part of white space
the new would
i've got to if you just in supervised learning
and you actually
then get better generalisation as well so you winning both on the optimisation on speed
and the generalization
this is probably the most important slide in the talk
because it's sort of challenge is what most people in machine learning and is used
to believe
it uses the technical concept that i got from
donald rumsfeld called stuff
and so the way the world works is the stuff that happens
and stuff produces images
or tall it won't change amount of water you have
if you take a bunch of pennies and you spread them out you don't get
more planets
but kids according to actually don't know that
and this is one of the real cool demonstrations any of you have access to
all four five year-old a sibling something not take one without permission but if you
have access to four five you can do this is this is what it looks
the first one has no sound the second one is going to be sent come
on it and
but there's two rows of checkers yes ticket
which one has more
users are saying that you have not yet
now that
so that's really stupid
and it's amazing amazing finding his older than is the robust finding here's another example
the same
and the
so it's cool finding of that stage suggesting a limitation in how you deal and
make sense of the world
the next phase concrete operations from seven to twelve you can solve the conservation
but still
you're limited the extent you're capable of abstract reasoning
the mathematical notions of infinity
or logical notions like logical entailment are beyond the child of this age
the child is able to do a lot but still is to some extent stock
in the company world
and then finally around age twelve
you can get abstract and scientific reasoning
and this is the activity theory
in very brief forms
i j
fearing a lot better
then did freud or scanners
for several reasons
one reason is
these are interesting and falsifiable claims about child development so claims that
about failure conservation
in children
a different ages could be easily tested systematically tested and in fact there's a lot
of support for the
we actually had a rich theoretical framework
pulling together all sorts of observations in different ways wrote many many books and articles
and articulators theory very richly
and most of all i think he has some really striking findings
before we actually nobody noticed these conservation findings
before we actually nobody noticed the babies had this problem tracking in understanding objects
at the same time however
there are limitations in is theory some of these limitations are theoretical
it's an interesting question as to whether he really explains how the trial goes from
concrete thinker to an abstract thing
or how it goes from not having object permanence one derstanding object permanence
his methodological limitations he actually was really begin to question and answer
one problem with this is that children are very good language
and this may be due to underestimate how much they know
and this is particularly a problem the younger you get
methodology is going to whom heavy
in discussion of any science and that includes psychology often
ninety percent of the game is discovering clever method
through which to test
you're hypotheses
i want to talk a little bit about that regarding babies i'll give you another
example of a very different domain
there is a set of scientists interested in studying typically
so when you tickle somebody under what circumstances will a lack where you have to
take all look can you take yourself doesn't have to be a surprise and so
it turns out very difficult to study this in the lab
you know the experimental credit you come to let OK undergraduate students and
and in fact an example of a mythological attempt was done by henry like university
of pennsylvania who built the typical machine
which was this box with these two giant hands the one and
and then it was a failure because people could not go near the typical machine
vote involving laughter
but we will discuss when we have electron laughter a bit of the technical sciences
and finally factual
what do infants and children really now
it's possible that due to the methodological limitations of phd he systematically underestimated
what children
and babies no and in fact i will present some evidence suggesting that this is
the fact that this is the case
i want to introduce you to the modern science of infant cognition
in the cognition has been something studied for a very long time
and there's a certain view
this had behind it
a tremendous philosophical and psychological consensus and is summarized in this onion headline here
and ideas
that that babies are stupid
the babies really don't know much about the world
the work that this new headliners satirizing is the recent studies which i want to
talk about suggest the contrary
babies might be smarter than you think
and to discover the intelligence of babies we have ourselves be pretty smart in developing
different techniques to study what baby knows you can ask you questions babies can talk
you could look at what it does with babies are not very coordinated or skills
CD is clever methods
one clever method is
to look at their brain waves
this trial underwrite died during testing is tragic crushed by the weights of electrodes he's
he studied brainwaves
one of the few things babies can do is they get stuck in the past
you might think well you know how we learn anything from that well for instance
you could build machines that would be bizarre kind of passive fire they hear music
or they hear language
and then you could look at how much they such passive fire to determine what
they like
undeniably we know most of our not we got most of our knowledge about babies
from studies of the looking times
that's one thing babies can do they can work
and i have a picture of
elizabeth spelke e
the developmental psychologist who developed the most research on looking at babies looking times and
what you can learn from them
and i had no two ways you can learn from looking
one is preference
so for instance suppose you want to know
for whatever reason the babies like the looks of dogs or cats
you could put a baby now
i have a picture of the dog here a picture of a cat here
and see which one the baby looks at
babies can move their eyes
and that tell you something two babies distinguish pretty faces
from ugly faces
well put a pretty face here an ugly face here see if the baby first
looking at alternative dataset exactly being a frequentist from mythological point of view now that
so much analysis point of view there's analysis to show you that procedure has been
frequentist properties itself
that's very interesting broadcaster techniques
OK so
i think one more slide on an introduction to move on to more concrete stuff
so what do you do with the frequencies what kind of activities you do well
you also write down models to develop procedures that the more you know the kind
of the analysis side of the story is a kind of the hierarchy of mathematical
things you do first of all you may try to prove consistency that if there
is the correct answer your conversion that no matter what the correct answer was that
often kind of fairly straightforward and not that informative more important thing to do is
to get rates of convergence towards the rate of convergence o two procedures both good
both consistent but maybe one of them has a faster convergence rate in terms of
number of data points
i would prefer that procedure what a lot of work and that is all that
and more hard but also very important is to try to get sampling distribution that
as the number of data points slow the perhaps i converted some nice distribution like
oh or almost like that i could use that distribution
to it to give me error bars
i can get error bars by finding out the sampling distribution
OK so there is certainly work on consistency in an animal military someone rates there's
very little companies nations so classical frequentist statistics focus on parametric statistics you know in
the forties and fifties but since then mainly nonparametric really there's a lot of nonparametric
testing and there's tons of other kind of person function estimation in all these large
p small n problems where is going to infinity you know the
number parameters going to infinity itself the number of data points in of the old
city also classical statistics with parametric and so on but that's not the tools were
developed to be general nonparametric perform part of the story one of the most general
tools is empirical process theory empirical process theory talks about convergence of
objects uniformly as defined consistency reasons which uniform various basis function spaces parameter spaces measure
spaces and so on and so forth to statistical learning theory is really a part
of that it's it's it's a particular area of empirical process theory that focuses on
zero one loss
but it's the tools rademacher and all that were developed in empirical process theory all
books and this appears to vary this tools available used prove things about the bootstrap
two things improved m estimators and so on so a lot of three thousand uses
this big heavy tool and there are lots of other tools that are not simpler
but that was all that was available
OK i'm going take a little positive only for so many questions and discover stretching
and the rest of my presentation today in the next time you are going to
be some little vignettes on the research that i've been involved in this all frequentist
and try to give you better flavour what requires actually really is like what the
kind of problems are set them up and see that there are some challenges there
and see how overcome them
the kind of machine learning methods but then analyse frequent point of view chapter house
all the way through the and
so i think i probably in the rest of this talk a talk about experimental
design and then these things three things will be for the next presentation so questions
answered philosophical stuff first
yeah i mean one of my current favourite books just kind of statistics in general
is and vanderplaats asymptotic statistics
and take some of the catholic view has got bayesian and frequentist arguments throughout it
by more frequent is overall but it's
it's it's got bayesian there as well
jim berger if you don't have you not minister james berger yet you should be
he's got a great book on statistical decision theory the first edition of it was
frequencies the second issues bayesian it's kind of good read both of them
and he anyway the second is as well as a lot of merging frequentist and
bayesian ideas and
i i i just think reading his book and his papers in journals is a
very good educational experience
is objective to be also subjected well you know sure in the sense that
i have written to be complicated model and some of the parameters i'm going to
possibly able to elicit subjectively and there's a whole bunch of others that are often
called nuisance parameters or whatever that don't want to or can't was should actively try
is subjective bayesian methods for those
so you know most bayesians do this actually in real life they will sit down
and say something this problem sort of believers in this range for this for that
reason and there's a scale factor i have no idea what should be able to
put the jeffreys prior
now that's coming out hoping to do a lot about how but that's kind of
your life fact blending objective basis
so i think objective bayes kind of big
ten to incorporate your subjective as well so that idea
five yes
OK now doubt present function the the data and reference priors this is your you're
sitting there you haven't seen any data yet all you're thinking about prior should i
OK you're free to envision dataset you can get
the city of your friends and imagine possible dataset you can get
and the divergence functions in the in the reference prior is an expectation over possible
things that you could get
so in fact it has a little frequencies kind of mathematical character but it's perfectly
baby isn't afraid of what you know to dream about data sets
and i just wanted to say
i have been possible
o one of the
she was in patagonia posterior prior to posterior or you prefer
in this season
what is known
you don't know
no not that i i wrote probability model the beginning everybody agrees you sort of
have to start there
OK and
i can imagine datasets the probability model
that defines a probability measure i can go from there now
take averages with respect that that's what the reference that to use the the the
given likelihood you do this hope this this this divergence maximisation gives you prior and
now you see a real dataset you you put your prior to give your real
like you like on that dataset you observe into posterior perfectly bayesian
yeah i it it depends on it sort of the experimental design flavor you know
and you know that which is which is arguably a good thing
one thing about how your data will be gathered
and there's a very good jose bernardo was the first person to talk about this
in great detail he's got a lot of papers talking about why experiment design should
so now you have to substitute a and b which is not very good the
critical it could change them but either your label baby
you you're labelled by a and you have a child
who is
well in the previous iteration which means we either little baby always the child who
is the or you're has labeled by a as a child was labelled a b
and so on
so this is the way you write until operators so just to show you that
with this fixed point
you can capture and although
formulas that would tell you about some eventually something good will happen
it is very much related to
liveness properties
but along you can enforce some
properties along the
the the ongoing past you using to reach this eventually
all right
so now we quickly so this is what i said here
and i had an existential quantification here for good for all
question put m you're gonna which here instead of requiring that there exists one success
there exists one child
like here
if i want
the property of
this until
to hold for all purposes
i have to require this property for all
this and
so this box
simply means that
i there are satisfied b or i satisfy a and all my successes in tree
belong to this fixed point so it means that the left one may be labelled
by b
and the right one BBC labelled by a but has a child with
it is such that all child or children will also have the property
so by just enforcing the
the way
new iterate
how the other sets propagates down the tree
if you put the diamond it means that just one successor has to be in
and if you put box
simply says that all successes should be in this set
the property propagates along all passes
so for quantification of
so now what does this mean
you can play the these you can complete rating
what they claim is that if i take new y
p a
the output for you
o why
but is this formula
it's the greatest fixpoint so if i want to compute it a computed by treating
from the full set of nodes
and iterate
my function f
what is the function
associated to this formula in the
ladies of set of nodes
so at
of this
and this
so if i take a set of nodes while it's
must be labelled by a
and it must be
such that
if i
i want to the
the nodes so that both
both children
and i one of the greatest greatest fixpoint of this
function f
so what you should understand for the
greatest is fixed by different start
looking at the computer would start with the full
set of nodes
we iterate
descending chain
until instabilities
so let's try to understand
just with one or two iterations which ones we capture
well we try and not which ones were captured which ones
and what what is not what cannot be because
in order to be in the
greatest fixpoint you have to be known as so
who do we get rid of
along this compute iterative computation
so she
who is not
in here was in here so first of all
i would get rid of for those that are not labeled by a
no way
to be in this greatest fixpoint
if you're not an old
which is labeled by a
now what's next
you cannot be
i mean even some iteration you cannot be in the next iteration if what
if you have a child
so the first iteration
you have the shape was not labeled by a
right because
the first iteration
which tells you that
well we may try to look at the first iteration has here OK and labeled
by a
who has
who was children
belong to the set and all the children belong to the set
so this is
the set of all nodes
so after first iteration of the said
i i capture well i rule out so i exclude doing all the nodes that
are not labeled by a
six next iteration what's going on the next iteration
want numbers that we report for the error bar and so what people do is
they estimate this expectation value using simply the second derivative
a logo
at the maximum of the likelihood function so that's the formula you can actually use
to get the numerical value of an air so notice here i don't have a
hat over the
the i that gives you number
i think in a number of you have probably used this program route which contains
also the programming we to do some parameter fitting and sometimes when you fit these
parameters it also gives you the areas you should be aware
what it's doing is it's getting in the error bars based on that type of
formula it's basically
numerically determining this is the second derivative of your log likelihood function and on the
basis of that approximation reporting the errors
OK now this this message
also from databases of of
closely related to the child called the graphical methods
and the idea of this method is the following
if you expand the log likelihood function about its
what you get is a lot of data is then approximately equal to
log scale of data had right that by construction the maximum like of log likelihoods
plus there
first order terms with the derivative with respect to the parameter of valuated theta had
time state of mind they have and the second order term and so forth but
let me just consider
that many terms k through second order
OK so the first term is basically log l max
the second term
is zero
right this second term is zero because the derivatives of a function at its maximum
has to be zero
and then in the third term
i have here is the second derivative of the log likelihood function
evaluated at its maximum and i can relate that using the previous over and i
can relate that to my estimate
for the standard deviation
so that means that i can write
this expression log l as lomax max minus
a data miner's they had square
and then that if you go back to the previous overhead i basically approximate that
by two times the estimate of the variance squared
so basically what it says is the following is that if you if you evaluate
this function at data plus or minus one
the standard deviation of they had a plus or minus one arab or if they
that means that this
term here is going to cancel the variance in the denominator and it means that
by moving the parameter plus or minus one standard deviation away from the best estimate
it causes the log likelihood function to decrease by by one half
right so that's an important role
to get you change the parameter away from them from the maximum likelihood values until
the log likelihood function decreases by one have
so here's an example of that with the same example that i should previously with
this exponential distribution i should show this picture really really this is what the log
likelihood function would look like in that case there's the log likelihood function is a
function of tau
it has a maximum at some point and that's how hat
and so my role here is the following i have a certain maximum value i
go down by one half
that gives me that line there then dropped these lines down here and the distance
there or the distance there
in principle they should be similar
the thing should be almost symmetric
and in this particular example the not quite symmetric here i call that distance there
delta tau minus and that distance there
delta tau plus
so well not quite important
in this circumstance like this you could do one of two things you can say
well how accurately you really need to estimate the error bars and in most cases
you would say well they're pretty close to o point one five
and that's the number that i would write down
for my error bar
you will recall that's essentially the same
the values that we got from the monte carlo method i think it was o
point one five one right so the getting essentially the same answer
in other cases where the likelihood function comes out very asymmetric
it might be appropriate to actually give
the plus value and the minus value separately so sometimes you see measurements quoted with
asymmetric error bars
so we do that too sometimes as well
it turns out in this case that if the sample size gets much larger
then this
likelihood function becomes more symmetric if the sample size is very small if you only
had five measurements instead of fifty measurements then it would be noticeably asymmetric
OK so we have the monte carlo method
the information inequality methods closely related graphical methods
OK this the only thing methods for now there are probably more but those those
three are pretty good pretty good start
OK let's let's go on now too closely related
method of parameter estimation and that is called the method of least squares
shape isomers when we are in lighter system and when we never fission
this is a very
a famous example of spin isomer that have been observed and the
storytelling is very quickly studied
it was at one hundred seventy eight so you have here the ground state
theory and experiment so ground state professional band
you have here first isomeric eight minus state
the most
important one these ones the sixteen flows isomeric state
thirty one years
so you see that the sixteen is located here around
the twelfth blue states are an event template states so mean that it
if you want to then you will have a chance of the municipality
which is bigger than six so it is not very favourable to have this kind
of position
so that's why you have
this long lifetime
so you can imagine many things with the size of the image and you can
produce it when you want and then you can
depopulated when you want you won't like you would have
like a laser so you can store
the storage of the energy here
this is far from being made completely because it's very difficult to be populated when
you want
so to populate its
you can do a reaction but for
for the population you need to we to increase the energy to another level and
then go back
but this is under study because here you imagine that the
the story of
you have a few immediately so
energy so this is something that
is under study
why is it also important to look at these spin isomers
it's because
as i told you that correspond to improve your input states so individual excitations so
thank you
if you there are pure states so completely different from the other but pure states
then we can pin down what are their structure what are the deformation spin parity
g factory you don't have all this makes in collective motion and things
there are pure states
so then they give important information for theory
this is very important to know the single particle states
because some calculations have been formed to study the spins of the ground state of
and it was
not so good
in even even nuclei is you have all these
all these pairs first been that's been down and because of symmetry to ground state
is zero plus
in on i
you have another family and so the ground state
is out of numbers so one has two three and five
what do people negative state depending on which
is a single nucleons so it's very difficult to know
even the ground state spin and parity of the ground state
of the odd nuclei
and when you perform some calculations
you see that sometimes
very quite often you don't find the good speed
and if you know exactly has been because of the ground state of the only
you better know the single particle levels
so you can
sheikh saad
by doing this study of spin isomers
it's quite difficult to obtain the ground state for odd
but system experimentally it's better to study the spin isomers because they have given lifetime
so you have time to study that so that's why people
really like to perform experiments concerning spin isomers
what are they doing so what they consider the magnetic moment is proportional to the
orbital moment that they introduced yesterday and speed
so depending on the orbital you have a given value of new
so then if you know you are if you know she
g sorry to same
then you know
what the orbital of the occupied level and if you have configuration mixing on
so experimentally what they do
they do fragmentation reactions so they bombarded target then you have fragmentation
and then they can produce nuclei
in their isomeric state so
was also what is important is that they have aligned spins
what does it mean to mean that the when they win
he came from the eyes to the ground state
there we any gamma
that will be needed all in the same direction
then they pulled by the merits in my need feel
so when you do that you have rotation which corresponds to allow more rotation so
you know the frequency
what sorry what they put are germanium detectors to detect the gamma
so then the tags and amazon both detectors
and when you played the difference between what is depicted in one detectors miners what
to take in the other one
so then you have this policy oscillation here
you can calculate the larmor frequency and then you can deduce
this g factor
so from this experiment
you can see what he we told that is filled by the nucleons
this is a very recent example this is so for forty three so close to
the end it was twenty eight
also to look at this shape twenty eight what is the ordering between these two
levels how it is in this specific meetings
what is the Commission was set up on
only free when only the result of states that is symmetric and positive definite we
had a descent direction
that's all but now we're interested
not not convergence theorem just the theory about that we get there a descent direction
that's this theorem is a respectively
yeah OK
so worker iteration order and q because that's the work per iteration in practice for
solving a system of equations were not do
and if you know that which how fast matrix multiplication
OK so we're ignore all of that stuff again because
that's what people do it of and this might come about so-called causing Newton methods
OK so prove the result so let me try and fashion approved and if I
don't finish the proof in time and the track finish the proof in time an
on in time you can read it in the notes because
I feel on superficial level the proof is just make the the proof is not
unless you spend a lot of time studying these methods then you can see what's
going on in the proof but I think for the purposes of this course so
I wanted to prove so that you can see that in fact it's true but
I'm not sure how much insight on the fashioning
In this proof but under need the following result
OK which is
that says the following 2 statements are equivalent which you're going to prove which is
exercise seven
of the homework
that is
of the norm of then inverse is less than or equal to 1 over H
is completely equivalent to the statement that the norm of em is at least h
times the normal the for anything
that is exercise seven the new nodes and for those of you that came later
which is essentially all of you
but I'm not
so if some of you downloaded the lecture notes in after about 10 AM this
you only have Proposition 2 . 1 has only 2 parts
if you look downloaded before 10 AM this morning it has 3 parts
you only have to prove the 1st 2 part and I just tell you this
is an easy proof there's you can do
a freshman at MIT could do this person OK so that it it's
you don't need any heavy machinery to do this proof you just need the definition
of the norm
that's all
maybe not a freshman in itself
the OK
we need 1 other
piece of information
to do the proof
and that is Proposition 2 . 2
for Proposition 2 . 2 states where put
yeah but to have you
what Thank you write in
Proposition 2 . 2
is the simple fact that relies on the fundamental theorem of calculus
which just says it is the gradient of f the minus the gradient vector X