all the same for all of
so this is a little bit of
this is just
the feature space
the station
some of the theory
it's called
we see that
so what is this
one is that was the
generate a new
learning is some
the chinese i is here
one of the issues
this is what she is
this is in a way that you love it
so here
but due
however would be made by
what we want
this image
you have
so yes
this all this is something that i don't like that
this is
as the error average is unknown regularities my so this means
i've only observed these five points but i'm
assuming i could get more similar points
and i want to estimate
the mapping from x to y
such that
evolved from all points in the future is likely that my
my estimate is good
for instance if i estimator point between these two points
so if differences and giving x and i want to estimate the corresponding y
five hundred my estimation function at x
i want to know whether the estimate is good or bad
so given this five many points i could come up with various estimates i could
say this is a straight line effectively underlying regularity
it should be something like this but i would also say well this straight line
doesn't explain my points for
so why don't i use polynomial of sufficiently high degree and i can explain my
point exactly
otherwise the lies that that's always that
maybe worse than the straight line
since every physicist if you're resistant measure this quantity would you would probably say well
the underlying dependency must be a straight line and all these minerals are this measurement
and if you ask why is this a bit explanation and many would say she
would say
it's better because it's a simple explanation
this notion of simplicity is exactly what's being studied by statistical learning theory so i
have to
trying to explain to you what does it mean for
an explanation to be simple
and what kind of consequences does have from a statistical point of view
i think the next slide i have another example from pattern recognition and other
it's toy example here we have a two class classification problem
it is what point and the black ones and on the left we have a
very simple
decision rule
it is so simple that it
actually gets a lot of the points wrong
here we have a very complex one which gets all the points right but
maybe it's too complex and you could say this over here measurement error in this
one as well
and here in the middle you have a decision rule which is about halfway between
simple and complex get some of the point light
some of the points wrong but most of them right
and you might want to say that this is the best ones within
what is the reason for saying that
so let's get a little bit more formal about things
and right down the problem of pattern recognition
same pattern recognition you want to learn a function
taking our input domain two plus minus one
from training examples
was still making this is something that all training examples are generated i i d
it's independently and identically distributed
from some under no underlying joint probability distribution
so the model is we're doing performing a random experiment
we have some small
of the data quality p of x y and we're generating are in the top
pairs by performing m times around the experiment described by the distribution
so for instance
random experiment where you're tossing some kind
only is the complicated here in that the random experiment every time you do it
gives you a x and y
every time you do the random experiment you such pair
and if you do it in time exactly the same thing in the results of
previous ones don't influence the results of the future ones
so all these are independent
so that's how you get your data
the goal is that
the classifier f but you should also work well on future data on the test
more generally should also work well
on average
the whole distribution
on average over the distribution means
whatever you would get if you sample infinitely many computer points from the distribution
so what you would like to be small is the expected misclassification error on the
test set so i've written down this function here
this is what people call the zero one loss functions
so if you think about it for a second this
labels y
plus minus one
otherwise here
these are the class membership
the effort to estimating takes values plus minus one
so these two quantities both plus and minus one whenever they agree three
the difference is zero
whenever they disagree the difference has one genus tool
differences plus two minus two we multiply with one of the two and we take
what you here so
whenever x and y
don't fit together
this quantity is plus-one one so whenever we make errors plus one
therefore this quantity is just the average
error if you like
or if you mathematician and this is the expectation
of the error
expectation with respect to this
probability distribution has generated the data
now the assumption learning theory is that we don't know this probability distribution because if
we knew this distribution then we will be in the room with probability theory then
we could just derive everything from knowledge of the distribution
in statistical learning theory
assuming that you don't know the distribution and the only thing you know is this
sample from distribution so here that's interesting difference between
statistical learning theory and bayesian learning
and maybe also classical statistics
so in classical statistics of course people also solve this problem maybe maybe didn't write
it down exactly the same way some certainly did
this problem that you don't know the distribution
he said well if you don't know it let's just assume it's of some parametric
form so that that a about but we don't know the mean and variance
and then we can write down things and somehow optimize for the parameters of the
mean and variance
so we can estimate this distribution from the data and then afterwards we can do
whatever we want to
in statistical learning theory maybe so little bit more radical people say well we don't
the other announcements
is that while it is allegedly working but please don't right now because i find
route you can get your hands upstairs if you have a
welcome to information theory part two
we're going to come to this
puzzle later on imminently first let's recap what we did
last time
we were talking about trying to communicate reliably over unreliable channels
for example the binary symmetric channel with the flip probability of ten percent was favourite
toy example
and we discussed system solutions to this problem where we want to achieve reliable communication
without changing the channel by adding a system in front and after to the encoder
adds redundancy the decoder does inference
and we discussed various ways of encoding we talk about repetition code to talk about
the seven four hamming code and
i showed you the performance of those codes and some others and we discussed what's
achievable and this astonishing result of shannon's
the noisy channel coding theorem that says you can get the error probability as small
as you like so the good news was always we can get the error probably
down but we lose in terms of right but the fact is no you don't
have to lose in terms of rate you need to go down below the capacity
which is the property of the particular channel you're working with
and below that capacity there exist encoders and decoders which can get the error probability
as small as you like which is stunning
i define the capacity of the binary symmetric channel with low probability
here using the binary entropy function and his a sketch of what the binary entropy
function looks like and might think well where this
all one over possible about whether that come from all that information theory and it
would take about a lectures to completely explain everything about information theory and and fully
prove the noisy channel coding theorem for any channel but today all hope to fill
in a few of the highlights of that topic
this theorem can be proved for
any channel in a broad class of channels so every channel has got the capacity
and we're going now is i'm going to tell you about source coding which is
the other bits of information to reveal the main bit
so we had encode and channel
like this and
the encoder was adding redundancy but in real life the things you want to send
over your unreliable channel probably already have some redundancy in and it's very wasteful to
not get rid of redundancy and so we have compression all source code have compressed
and uncompressed and the first half of the lectures about the response to sparse
so that's the big picture is conventional to divide the communication problem into these two
steps that you first compress your redundant data then you add some very carefully to
defined redundancy
to help you with from the noisy channel whatever noisy channel you're dealing so this
is called the noisy channel coding and this is called
coding is also called data compression
and it's also called machine learning
as well it's like
OK so i'll take you through some
key ideas about source coding of describe how to make optimal compresses of a particular
time called symbol codes
and i'll tell you about another idea called arithmetic coding
then we come back to noisy channel coding
and see how much time we got left to sketch
a few more of the final ideas that have come up in noisy channel coding
and how it connects to what you've been hearing about factor graphs and message passing
algorithms which you've already heard about in the last couple of days the lecture notes
for all of this chapter four five six and forty seven of the book which
is available
in the bookshop bookshop is and it will be here until lunchtime
and it's free online
so offer you why are we doing this compression thing well here's an example of
these are the kinds of results you get
so of is are reasonable
and some of these are not
the the the problem here is that the data is extremely noisy
so there's is a show
what's called polysemy different meanings of that word
forty percent of what you have is you could upload a collection of hundred photos
and enable them all
santa barbara channel
it is not of much use when you're trying to get something out
the argument is tags are not enough
that's what we have to do
i mean let's acknowledge the fact that this is currently how
the work is done
that's probably what it's going to be in the immediate future
but there are some limitations
we hope to go beyond
OK so let's look at the field of
so there was a field of content based image retrieval somehow invented in the
in the nineteen nineties
just ignore these things it's not quite important details and what
and the
find project was actually an idea the so called cubic project
those words that we did at berkeley and this is from santa barbara
mean is the project and mostly these projects what about
using colour and texture
and why
use colour and texture
well it's this all story of
somebody went somebody looking and looking for somewhere first as down the ground and this
person said what i'm looking for
i'm looking for my keys
and then the person said that it was the mrna with their by looking them
this is where the light is
OK so as i said to begin to look under the light
and the light was
the picture histograms because he knew how to model
and here are the basic ideas
so the color histograms are you can imagine divided up into blocks
then you find the distribution of media scholars
what percentage of blue green yellow red except get distribution that characterizes an image
this is pretty good for finding sunsets
if you try to find images with a lot not already get sunsets
so the canonical example from any CBS from the nineteen nineties was showing the detection
of sunsets
the second example was a little bit tricky
OK you can do something based on texture
and take sheffield that's what we do is there's a bit more sophisticated
i mean and some orientation sensitivity is constant it is about what
and then the output of those filters we can again construct histograms and sort of
county through the same idea
but this
works in very very limited settings
and it took us a little while to figure out what we did we have
figured out to give us credit for that
and there is no slogan which multimedia community really
fond of using it's called the semantic gap
so the semantic gap is the first generation CBIR systems were based on colour and
and these do not capture what users
i'm interested in so they are interested in pictures
monkees our kids are paris hilton what were not interested in picture which seventy percent
twenty two percent three
that's not what really is about
we we have a lot of evidence from human perception of art
what are the queues for categorisation and that most important cues shape
but this is ignored in all this work because we addiction
so what happened is that
the kind of these two facts if you look at the ACM multimedia conference is
by large their conclusion from this is OK this is hopeless the simple approach don't
let's go off and try to develop good annotation tools of people we can bring
the user in the loop and produced tonnes
that's kind of what you
caricaturing of it but that's what the
multimedia community is sort of
push forward
are in the computer vision community this kind has been
we are trying to fight the good fight
will try to solve the
the fundamental problem of recognition based on shape
and now the question is what have we delivered in the last five to ten
and i will argue that we have made substantial progress
and it's not anywhere near human performance
but it's good enough that it useful for some and the derivatives
so this is the promissory notes
so let's let's get some so here's the research
so essentially we want to take images and analyse them
and automatically generate annotations corresponding to object labels that activities in video
if if you can automatically generate those annotations
then of course these can be combined with other metadata and then these become the
the signal to be used for searching
because we believe that at at runtime analyzing analyzing images is very expensive so you
don't want to be analyzing a billion images but if you you have more
the content of the image into some
something that you precomputed then at runtime things can go pretty fast
that's surprising
OK so let's start with some context what
we know from
human vision
another constant cutting apache
so then we look at the con straints all kinds of people give you very
strange all kinds of constraints we found there are four kinds of constraints
you actually can push quite deep
to use it in very effectively
while we call
pattern search space means having constraints we can cut another data search space cut the
the pattern while we we categorize into this peening spam pattern antimonotonicity
OK so we have strong pattern and another fuzzy and week one
we also for the search space because they had been monotonicity we have pattern inseparable
and pattern inseparable
what we can push so i give example you're c
actually quite easy once you see the example OK
for example i give you a constant say
i one the pattern to be a sick
i mean i wouldn't mind this chemical compound of finals basically patterns
those form like rings or something and one
if you say this
very interesting thing is this one grow the pattern suppose you grow up and finally
find this one's been benzene rings OK so this by arranging the pattern from this
pairing you want to grow
forget it because you got a ring
you grow anything longer bigger and can still contain the strain you're never
satisfied this basically
there have so the whole pattern away without growing from there
OK so that's the one we call strong
what is a weak one
i give you this constant k the consensus
the density ratio of pattern suppose it should be greater than zero point one i
list i give you the definition what is what do i mean the density ratio
the ratio is the within for this pattern the number of edges
divided by
come possible combination of the that these are the vertices possibly come to construct all
the possible edges
so this is it
available at this is the path branch OK so if the possible edge
and available edges almost the same so it's almost one there is very that's
otherwise is sparse like we
assume we want density ratios that's OK
this one interesting thing is
it's not
everywhere you grow
back from here from here
they were touch the wall again
but the interesting thing you can see for this week
antimonotonicity constraints is if you want a bigger
graph satisfy this
there's an interesting property is you can find a least award
smaller one smaller means
i have one vertices that's smaller want a least one is also that's if this
you can not find any subset which stands
there's no way of grow growing still can be that's OK that one that one
we can prove it if you
you carefully we can prove this one with this well with this property we can
see this constraint actually is weak partial funds means you're not saying from here is
useless but i find all the possible integral OK if they none of them
can satisfy this
this ratio
and this one were dropped because we know further growth we never said this rich
OK so this kind of constraints we call week one
then our view the data and monotonicity constraints to see why this one is very
useful in case for example you may have the constants like this the number of
discrete or equal ten
or the pattern contains vendor k
suppose we look at this conference number of discrete and that
at the very beginning we grow this monograph
OK of course the number number of edges is not over ten
you're not drop it
OK why don't drop it because you see i grew further eager would be
you know
would be more than ten
i still like to grow
OK that's fine the perfect but the interesting thing is
you go back to look looking dataset you suppose i grow
i look in my graph in the middle
i found this frequent pattern grow to understand the remaining part of graph actually were
not even have more than ten years if i add them together so was this
one size is five the remaining one
without growing part size should be at least five if this one small
this dataset is useless you can cut
right so that's the idea
cut any graph line integral find the remaining part has no way to satisfy it
you cut
then you may you may ask one question is why do cut it from the
very beginning you cut it why have the weight entry here in the middle
i can then
the format of the
regional groups so here in this case
this data is just plain
we some
variance applied to it
and this is the recovered
great so it's actually denoised this manifold very well it's really easy example PCA we
do it as well
but there you go so he's got connectivity
what we do is building activity matrix between all these points then we compute interpoint
distances then we embed those distances and that's the embedding using the colours here match
the colors it so it's been rotated ninety degrees
the swiss roll
so that's the swiss roll
and then here's the uncovered embedding dennis
it's got some slight flaws but it's basically a plane
this is the trefoil three four o
no not
here's the data
and here is is
recovered in that
so it's obviously can't split it's called to parliament topological constraint has been circles
and there's there's another issue with this method
is embedding in euclidean space what happens if the original character is you're trying to
embed say someone walking which is somewhat periodic it's it's not really euclidean space some
sort of a cylindrical space what they tend to do is not make use of
them in the one dimensional structure basically living in two d space is really circle
of political issue that has to do that
so i'm not going to make sweeping statements about all of the spectral methods
so from the covariance interpretation we think of the similarity matrix is a covariance
each element of the covariance is a function of two data points
it isn't isomap but in general it is we just going to specify the covariance
matrix by similarity measure
now another option is to specify the inverse covariance
if we specify the inverse covariance
if the inverse covariance between two points is zero those points are independent given all
other points in not independent
in the true sense
the only independent if we observed all other points
if you look at the covariance how they cope very they won't be independent
now i'm not going to talk in detail about this but i just want him
to this
laplacian i can maps and LLE
can be seen
as specifying the inverse covariance
in particular ways i'm not going to talk about
by giving particular weights on the inverse covariance so the giving connectivity structure
now that means when you look at the covariance the covariance each two points of
the covariance depends on the entire dataset because it's the inverse covariance that specified only
between two points in a pairwise manner
so that's the way i wanted to i don't have time to prepare that's really
the way i wanted to cover these guys the from the perspective of you specify
the graph structure
and they often it's called the plastic
which is why it's called last item at is best inverse covariance now
comment for both of these techniques see you create
a structure
and then you extract the smallest igon value
so the largest actually discard the smallest i value and then you extract the second
this complete within this framework
it makes complete sense you're doing that because the largest eigen value of the covariance
matrix is the smallest i value of the inverse covariance matrix
with one little flying ointment they discard the smallest i can value the covariance matrix
because it's all once well
there's also an interpretation for that which comes back to centre in which i didn't
talk about
in detail
if you send a command if you don't send a covariance matrix
the first igon value will be all once
so for example if you you've got data and you seem a zero mean
and then you compute the covariance you confuse me computers covariance the first thing you
get is like vector of ones
o point what you're gonna get better ones which is associated with the fact you
have removed the me
so that the removal of the smallest igon vector has an interpretation as entering the
when you're moving the smallest like vector from the inverse covariance so both these things
make complete sense the of specifying an inverse covariance and extracting the largest eigen value
of the covariance or the smallest value of the inverse square
and they were quite nicely just to show you the early results for those things
that really isn't quite nice as isomap i didn't spend a lot of time playing
with parameters it's not really matters that i looked at the third dimension i would
find it probably went along the line there
it also shows you know they don't always work i just used seven neighbours you
can go into my code and play with settings if you want to see how
quickly can recover the thing
it does something we're not here i'm not sure maybe even a bargain like in
right so the final sort of thing
what i
i want to briefly talk about is more closely related to my research and i
actually credit card for these slides because
i work together with karl and his sort of illustrating some of the points here
so everything we talked about so far is spectral methods distance matching let's trying to
reconstruct distances in the latent space to match distances in the data space
well the final thing i want to see is what happens if you do things
in a slightly different way you try and say well
all this going on is that i have functional mapping from a latent space to
annotate space from x to y
the model predicts
so this is sort of what your data tells you and this was what your
model tells you
and in this special case it's very simple to tell you to do moment matching
it says
choose your model parameters
change the status of the these guys end up matching what your data tells you
so it's very intuitive in this this special case that's not always true for maximum
likelihood but but here it is
so there are many ways that you could imagine trying to solve these equations
the naive way this is what i would suggest in practice but just just to
give intuition the most naive way would just be gradient descent you would start with
your current parameter and the way you update is by
adding to that parameter you add the difference in the gradients in this sort of
thing you think about this is the training error it's it's telling you
this is what your data says
this is what your model says and this is the difference it's the sort of
air that your model this is currently making sort of pushing that to make the
predict the data is special case
this is the way that i would suggest solving it but what i would like
to emphasise this is important
remember i said that you can't escape this this inference problem this inference problem comes
up again and what you want to think about this expectation is an expectation of
an indicator function
so if you sort of break this down analytically
and what you find is it's like marginalization operation
to do this you have to run something like the elimination or the junction tree
algorithm to do exactly
so there's a bit of what you might call the chicken and egg problem or
of cart and horse problems to be able to estimate the parameters you have to
be able to compute marginals
computing marginals is tricky so it's
the of circular larity here the
both problems get wrapped up in one another because of this
nice into the form of the updates
let me now talk in detail about this because sam spoke about this the IPS
cells this is slightly different algorithm it's not gradient ascent per say
it's actually what's known as the coordinate ascent algorithm you sort of fixing all the
other coordinates in ascending on one
i won't go into details of this sort of key thing is it again you
get quantities that involve the data what the data tells you and what your model
tells you again you need need to do inference to be able to compute those
those quantities
again let me skip this because sam went into this is the issue of data
augmentation and the algorithm which is sort of a very nice
general purpose technique for solving problems which can be formulated in terms of exhilarating functions
OK so
in the last sort of twenty minutes i just want start on part two
just again i think probably people are getting tired so try and stay high level
this for the next fifteen or twenty minutes actually before i jump just any questions
about issues of parameter estimation and model selection
things like this
so what
for instance if
going back to the simple example where i had an image model on a lattice
had pairwise connections
we wanted to estimate these four numbers here
so for instance if if this was a very big relative to this it would
be telling me that the image is quite smooth
so i'd be sort of trying to figure out what the values of these numbers
in that special case those would be the parameters
more generally might functions over bigger cliques you'd have more parameters but it's the same
kind of principle
maybe one other comment the model selection problem is is is pretty tricky in general
there are sort of sure-fire methods to do it there's some interesting theory
in particular things like AIC BIC can be used to some extent to do selection
but i
a lot of these methods are computationally intractable
so the current state of the art is that there are many methods that no
theoretically are quite well understood
one when i when i plug all cases in their own right
so basically if i have a data point i what this is saying is when
now compute the posterior probability for this data point was that what was the probability
that it belongs to all the ten thousand that i have
well it's just some numbers for each but they better add up to one right
because the guy has to belong to someone after all right
OK but that's easy because that's what i do is i simply make some here
over j of all possible
so this would be i j and then
i j OK
it's not you see the magic happens and actually
i could i could
i could
change of the name and i could
dig out this good all responsibilities and we had earlier right
so what is this responsibility said to us earlier they said to us
zero or one and the there were one if i is the i th data
point belongs to cluster k right and here these guys are soft their numbers between
zero and one OK
and the posterior probabilities that a given y is going to belong to a given
and because are defined like that quite trivially you can see that if i add
them up
over k then i should get one
so now we have one missing thing to do is we need to compute derivatives
with respect to the prior case right that's the that's missing thing we have
so now what we need to do is we take the objective function we had
and now
we add a lagrange multiplier that enforces
the fact that the prior probabilities need to add up to one as well
so what implication does have
i need to take derivatives now
and make them to zero with respect to the parameters themselves
but also with respect to the grande multipliers OK
taking derivatives of the original
cost function with respect to pi k
is not very difficult and it's done in very similar fashion to what we did
before right
so now let me just go straight to the results so what is it that
the pie case should be
well interestingly
it's sort of a very intuitive
it's sort of the very intuitive equation OK
remember earlier for k means
what was the sum if a fixed k and i added overall
and i added over all the points so far if i just had this thing
here right
that was the number of points that belong to the given class right
so now
i get the same thing except because it has to be a probability i divide
need to divide by an right
so this gives me it's sort of a very very intuitive equation right
so what is what is the sum over all these guys as one one
that's correct
so when you implement mixtures of gaussians one thing you can keep is
you can keep
you can keep track of of of big matrix are
that is of size k
and right sort of contains for all data points how are they distributed among the
classes right so if you were to plug to sort of do e major c
with nice colors and stuff like that you would sort of c
the different data points distributing themselves among classes
OK so now i have to make a tough decision
if they were a little bit
we behind
and we have this pattern so it is marked here is already or not
actual OK this just
you know give me a sign when you think it should be
should be something
the actual
OK so in this slide here we only took we only took generic derivatives with
respect to the parameters theta right but actually we want it to be the mean
and the covariance so what we need to do is simply to come in here
and now we know how to update the prior case we've just in it and
now we just replace this thing but the actual derivative with respect to the mean
so let's start
i heard you had an exhaustive
evening but
i don't know what we can do
we have quite a bit of things today
so if i want to cover everything that i have to go a little bit
faster than last time
i hope that will be OK with here
you know the last time we are talking about and the peace and then choose
the basic
constructions which just the basic framework
and you're talking about
stuff like the the existence of optimal policies what does it mean
to be policy are
what does it mean to be an optimal policy
was the optimal value function
given ultimate value function you can find an optimal policy in all you have to
agree five suspected that the value function
then introduced
the action value functions and then the optimal action value function concluded that
given ultimate action value function
you don't have to be much computation just
if your
the given state you optimize respectively action to optimize the optimal action value function
and you've got an optimal policy say
this whole topic is
board learning value functions like OK this
in some approaches people
try to avoid that and i don't know if you have time to cover that
if the dog then
please come to me and the breaks are
two million excursion i'm very happy to talk about those approaches
so in the MDP is there are three
basic problems the planning problem the learning problem and and learning fast
so five e manitoba structure things like
you know this existence things how to construct the optimal policies how to think about
other things
and so today i'm going to talk more about
like in the first part i am going to talk about planning and then we
the learning an optimal learning stops
so why is planning interesting on the first hand
it's interesting because you could have this model of these approaches by your learning and
and given the more than you want to find out an optimal policy right so
then that's that's the planning problem you're given the model
what was the optimal policy or how can i compute
and efficient manner
policy that's good enough
OK so
we left after this first present station
at the end somewhere here after introducing action value functions
so let me just briefly very briefly finish
this mentioning
me mentioning several variations of the basic team
so first of all
when you're doing this iterative computation of the optimal value function you don't have to
be all the states at all times that
and there are advantages of not doing that
and there are many are giddens they're trying to organize this competition in such a
they don't waste time on updating states which are very important
depending on the context
that you could have target and slightly lower is that are
so there's deterministic ontoprise real time dynamic programming
our good model to broken saying
so that's the idea is that you want to
make decisions faster and you are actually interacting with the environment
and by interacting with the money you have the time constraints you don't have much
time to sing
and yet you want to learn
good enough value functions so how do you do that
on the other side is that
as you go along the class
c or x you're acting as well as you can see your knowledge here agree
fine with respect to what you
and as you do that
you know you're travelling along the past maybe two hours ago
and then you're visiting the states and the question is that once these you want
to have a
the idea here is that you want to update all of those things that you
are visiting
why because well may be optimal policies for is going to focus on a pretty
small part of the state space
and then there is no value of learning of all the values of the state
of those part of the building never visited by the optimal policy so the idea
is is pretty simple
and the implementation is is is also pretty simple
and evaluation of the idea is that well if you don't you're not in this
real-time time situations
but you're in a situation where you really want to
have the value function pretty much everywhere
so you know and i stress are
you of the thing from the go backwards
and it makes alot of sense because
OK so i have to mention the by source target and is just a special
case of a patient
if you think about it
and so they are out there think from the goal
backwards and that makes a lot of sense because you are basically propagating information back
first from the got see are propagating discourse to go information back from the war
and if you do the synchronous value iteration so are
during the iteration stuff on all state synchronously at all time steps
i don't need to waste a lot of time thinking states
that of course are not or the the value function is not going to change
so if you have a chain of states
i have to go from this state started to go state
computing a value function so these may be i finite graphs unsinkable defined i
graph like a change
and i use value iteration and not every time step on come i'm doing updated
every little state
room temp the fraction
the fraction in the conduction band
is about ten to the minus nineteen because so few of them you can give
each of them name so there's almost no conduction
silicon at room temperature is an insulator so if we want to get some conductivity
we got heater computers have to such a high temperature i don't think so so
we need some other way
populating the conduction band and we're going to do
one other mode of promotion we look for work citations like citation in the third
mode is kemal
he mo x citation
what we're going to do is we're going to get carrier
the carrier injection
introducing impurities
by introducing empirical and i know you're sitting there thinking he is crazy we just
spent all this time and money making silicon six nine purity
and now we're going to start throwing impurities in anyway
well there's two kinds of impurities in this world
two kinds of impurities
there are good impurities and beneficiaries
all right the good impurities are called dopants
these are the ones that are their desire
OK so dopants are good guys and then there are other ones that are called
contaminants and these are undesirable and purity
so we don't want contaminants so we're going to look at
opens and this is a really important lesson right now
i'm teaching when i'm showing you for the first time in three nine one is
how we can use chemistry to alter the performance of the material i want to
take a plane
high purity silicon which is an insulator room temperature and by operating on its chemical
composition give it properties that it cannot possess otherwise so this is the paradox is
the paradigm for solid state chemistry you want something has got a higher yield strength
will change its composition
you want somebody going to higher conductivity will change its composition
that's different
OK so this is an engineered materials
this will be engineered materials and is it engineered engineered material what we're getting is
via chemical change
biochemical change purposeful chemical change
so we're getting if you like
tailored composition
the composition to give targeted properties
and this is the
this is what underlies material science
you don't see which you like
make it
how do you make it by understanding the relationship between electronic structure
bonding and ultimately properties
so here's what the gamma designed to talk only about elemental semiconductors so in the
case of
in case of
and romania it just never do restricted data silicon germanium that's that's not such a
bad restrictions since we're in the silicon age all your micro devices contain silica
so this is pretty good so here's the game but you introduce a little village
in puri
introduce a little vaillant
what i mean daily of a one
a always the same as the latin word for alias
so we are going to introduce impurities that have different valence from silicon and germanium
silicon and germanium are group four or fourteen if you want to use you pack
notation so what want to do is introduce something else
give you an example so
and the purpose of introducing a covalent impurities is to cause
because electron
electron consumption
and how they're going to work well you see best in action so here's a
simple example lets put phosphorus in silicon phosphorus is you know is group
fifteen or group five
so it's
good five valence electrons let's first look at
cartesian world so here's silicon sp three hybridized
and it forms a diamond like
diamond like solid right
diamond like solid
so it's crystal in its regular race
silicon is
at all the corners of the tetrahedra
on and on it goes give about three of these
so what happens if i introduce phosphorus introduce phosphorus the phosphorus actually goes in
and substitutes for silicon solar phosphorus
phosphorus substitutes it doesn't go and sit in some void space actually substituted
substitutes for silicon graphics going to substitute for silicon has the form bonds agreed you
can just sit there is no passive observer here if you want to play you
gotta bond so fast comes in with five valence electrons so it goes one two
three four this form of its valence electrons are born to the four adjacent silicon
is what happens to the fifth valence electrons of phosphorus there's no empty orbital in
that if the electron can sit
seven of the electron sitting here kind of
tapping his foot wondering what is going to do
let's go over the energy level diagram
here's the energy level diagram this is silica
elemental silicon downstairs valence band upstairs the conduction band when we put the phosphorus into
the silicon where in energy space whereas the only place that fifty electron can go
and this is slightly more complex to bound but again it's very
sort of each step is actually quite
so here we have it the
expectation over the sigma of the soup
of the
over the function class of this correlation
the thing here
this function now is a linear function
so we can think of the
you know this is w com o five x
but some of sigma i of a linear function
we can move the some inside the
and we get w com
all of this gubbins inside
some of sigma i phi i five x i
and therefore
how is this maximized what is maximized if w is actually parallel to this
o thing exactly
is equal to be
and so we actually end up with just the norm of this quantity
the spectre here
and we can take all the constant sound so to be over and come out
so we actually get
you see that i mean if you want to maximize this over w
you just choose w
parallel to this thing
and of norm b and c get be times the norm of this thing
so actually that isn't even an inequality here
OK and now
there's a little bit of trade
what you have to do is to
make this an inner product
with itself and take the square root
OK so this is the norm it's the inner product with itself to describe so
that's just an inequality
and now you move the square root
through the expectation so jensen's inequality
and if you do that so
what's happening is your sort of
rather than taking the expectation of the square root values
square root values
you're taking expectation here and then taking the square root and you can imagine what
you get is bigger
so this is actually bigger because you take expectation first here
the input and then takes credit because the square root is concave
you actually get bigger value
so it's just jensen's inequality so now what do you do well you've got an
expectation here
of the sum
and so you can take expectation inside
the sum
and the expectation of sigma i sigma j
where i and j are different
is is zero because they cancel each other
out again
plus one
with probability half minus one probability half so they cancel
so all of the cross terms here cancelled
and you end up with just the diagonal terms and on the diagonal you get
sigma i squared which is always one
and so you end up with the sum of the diagonal terms in this
kernel evaluation
so that's just the trace of the kernel matrix
square root of that times to be
OK so this is the empirical rademacher complexity
and therefore you know you can handle your case with the norms growing
you just actually measure the norms on the sample
and that's how you get actually that
OK so that's the the rademacher complexity for
a set of functions
sorry for the
so of functions empirical rademacher complexity on a particular sample
of linear functions with norm at most b in in a kernel defined feature space
OK so now applying that to ESPN's
OK so there's a few steps here i've slightly read jaguar the SVM
definition here to explicitly make an optimisation ghalib it's entirely equivalent to the standard method
slide just slightly formulation with the norm
if w squared constrained to be one
and these are the slack variables
what we need to do
is to bound this
expectation of the loss and this is the heaviside function here so zero and one
of minus y
g x so this is going to be plus one if there's an error and
zero or minus one if it's correctly classified or negative
and by the heaviside will be therefore zero every size just the function because zero
and zero goes
jumps to one
so this is just the way of expressing the probability of misclassification as an expectation
which is what we need
to apply the
and now
the trick is to approach upper bound that h
that function that we were looking at by
a hinge loss function which just basically starts zero
and then goes up to one
with a gradient of one and gamma
between zero and
minus gamma so it's sort of the
it's sort of
goes the other way round it starts at one
so that's right for a greater than zero is one
and then it goes down to zero at minus gamma
so that will be upper bounding the heaviside function which is zero all the way to
zero and then jumps to one
so we can take this function here
and and upper bounded by this one
i've added the minus one for technical reasons
and now we apply the rademacher theorem this is the empirical value of that this
is the rademacher complexity
and this is the extra term
so to plug-and-play here
and now we need to bound the rademacher complexity this quantity here
the well so first of all let's look at the empirical value of this
quantity and that is just the sum of the slack variables divided by gamma
so we actually getting the exactly the one norm
of the slack variables that you optimize in the
in the in the support vector
you have this empirical rademacher complexity
and this extra term
and we have the final step is to bound this
this empirical rademacher complexity in terms of
the rademacher complexity that we've already computed of the underlying
linear functions so this is this composition
with the loss function which is now hinge loss
OK now there's the a detailed which i'm going to skip the proof of the
this basically results in a multiplication by the lipschitz cont constant of this
loss function
and there's the detailed proof of that which
is quite involved nothing very serious but it just is a bit involves i'm going
to skip over it
the basic
the result is that you get two times the lipschitz constant
what is x values should be distributed according to some pdf f of x that
you're interested in
now you have access just a scalar quantity but in general text could be could
be not a single number perhaps a collection of numbers x could be a vector
but for the examples that show now of only consider x being a scalar quantity
so the next step the third step is to use these x values two
estimate some property of the pdf
f of x that you're interested in
a simple example would be that if you consider simply too
fixed values from a to b
and you simply calculate the fraction of
the fraction of these x values that fall between a and b
and that would give you what is that's an estimate of the probability for x
to be
between a and b and we know that simply the integral
from a to b
of the pdf
so that that's a way of estimating this particular quantity and that is then given
by the integral and that's generally what you find is the monte carlo calculations it
is formally is equivalent to doing an integral
you don't have to do it that way in fact sometimes we simply regard the
jet generated data is generated sequence of points as simulated data
rather than generating according to this algorithm we could actually do the experiment and these
x values might actually
refer to the outcomes of our measurements
so we can use these generated values simulated data and use them for testing our
statistical procedures or otherwise calibrating the measurement procedures that we would eventually then carry out
with with real data
OK so now we say a few words about each of the three steps are
the first step was to generate this sequence of random numbers
the followed a uniform distribution
right now you can imagine how would you do that you're going to represent a
in a computer
say with a certain number of bits suppose to use thirty two bit to represent
a number that would go from say zero up to some maximum value
and then i could take that number and divide
by the maximum possible value that would give me a number somewhere between zero and
now how can i generate a number that would be random when you could simply
say well for every bit i'm going to toss the coin
and if it had so i don't know one and it's zero
head tail tales right down to zero
and then after thirty two point tosses i'll have generated random numbers
and that would work
actually and people have
i tried to use physical processes to
form the basis of random number generators and for certain very
specialized applications that may be something
the people want to do but is generally too much trouble and has its own
host of suite of problems and so on what we do is is we use
a deterministic computer algorithms
to generate these random numbers
now these algorithms have
the property that if you run them again you get exactly the same sequence of
random numbers so you can't really regarding this truly random sometimes called
pseudo random numbers
but for all
purposes that we use them for they are effectively as good as true random numbers
in fact better
because it can very often be very useful to be able to reproduce again the
exact same sequence of random numbers sometimes you see above your programmer see some unexpected
behavior and you would like to be able to reproduce that was true random numbers
you could
i guess never do that with this deterministic algorithm you can reproduce the sequence if
you desire
right so there there are a number of algorithms
but one can use and i want to describe very simple but quite effective algorithm
just to give you an idea of how they work and this is what's called
the multiplicative linear congruence rules
generator or g
and the idea behind this algorithm is the following is that you start with an
initial value and zero which is called the seed
and then i need to supply also
two constant values among supplier a and the modulus
and what this algorithm does it specifies the rule that tells you how to to
update this
value and so here's the rule that tells you how to go from its value
to the i plus one value
and i plus one
it is equal to the multiplier times and i modulo
and this model
the modulus operator says if you take the remainder when you take the the guide
to the left divided by the guide to the right and then you take the
remainder so for example twenty seven mod five would mean that you take twenty seven
divided by five
which then has
the remainder of two
right so twenty seven mod five would be two
so it's the remainder after integer division
OK so that's the rule it's a very simple rule
to program up in a computer
and it has a number of interesting properties
the most striking properties is the sequence of numbers that produces is periodic
that sounds crazy this post is supposed to look like random numbers that sort of
certainly there there are periodic
they could not regarded this as representing random quantities now the idea is that you
need to make this period very very long
and you're you're only allowed to use the sequence well within a single period if
this thing actually starts to repeat then there no good as random values
so here is just an example to illustrate how this periodicity can arise suppose we
were to take
a value for the multiplier of three in the model s seven
and we take as the initial value the seed one
this is crazy by the way the value the picture modulus is typically close to
the largest possible value that you could store in a computer with the number of
bits that you will allocate but just to illustrate this periodic feature i've chosen the
fairly low value for
the modulus this is actually an example from the book by plant that i mentioned
OK so let's see how it works and zero is one
and one is therefore the multiplier three times one month seven so let's see three
months seven that's three
so four and two
it is three times three that's nine months seven is too much
and so forth down the line and here i find finally in six is three
times and five fifteen months seven
is one
but that's where i started
OK so the sequence simply repeats
now you may think that was only a very simple algorithm how about some of
these more complicated algorithms they all repeatedly that a common feature of every
algorithms that i know
that is in use they all have some sort of periods
and in practice what you do is you try to make that period extremely long
we all
let me know how in
two or more
when we look
is this
you are
the model
well all
almost like about
so you can
one of
my work
the only
so the
little girl
but she would
if they no
at the end
no because
data where
one two
two men one
you smoke you're going to die early enough
but you won't drawing social security
and therefore the government actually saves money by smoking
because by the time they add up how much they get on the stick tobacco
and how much they earn by you're not living long enough to draw attention
it's much better it's much more money than how much it's going to cost
take care to wire died from emphysema
or bladder cancer or lung cancer or
heart disease
many more people die from heart attacks due to smoking then died from lung cancer
in fact so think about this
think about this if you smoke it's probably a good time to stop because if
you continue your age especially for women
which is for some reason women have a hard time stopping them and i can
see why it's probably some physiological things if you if you continue now you're it
will be almost impossible to stop
if you lived with smokers
ask them to leave
if you live in a home with your parents and they smoke
tell them it's time for them to leave
from house
smoke second-hand smoking killed probably between sixty and eighty thousand people last year in this
second smoke and by the way
if you want to see an interesting phenomenon goal veterinary hospital because there
they was great frequently frequency treat dogs with lung cancer
and why do they have lung cancer
in nineteen ninety nine percent of the cases in one hundred percent of the cases
these dogs
with all to smoke and average tobacco smoke goes through six or eight dogs in
his or her lifetime
it's absolutely true
so if you if you think the dogs
if that's the fact for the for the for the is to think about what's
happening to the inside of your lungs
so i'm going to take back what i said before before i told you that
the most important thing for you to do in this course
is to learn how to think clearly and to assess the still conceptual complexity of
there's actually one more thing that even more important to get out of this course
if you do
and that is
to stop smoking
if you do that
it will be vastly more important for the rest of your life but anything you
learn here
so write that down vastly more important
you may think it's glamorous you may think it's exciting but keep in mind
people to stop smoking
vastly greater effect on reducing the morbidity and mortality
in this country
anything the cancer researchers can do
keep that in mind
and if you start smoking now
and you think that somehow the cancer research is to be able to come up
with some miracle cure by this time you start quite coughing and starts spitting up
don't be so certain
they may not be able to save the ball you're fat out of the fire
so i don't know whether i get this message in a very subtle way or
a picture of
but i think i think about that
now never going to focus on one cancer with focus on cancer because it's one
of the consequences of cigarette smoking but it's a disease we want to talk about
both this time next time and we want to relate here to the cell cycle
and how the growth of cell proliferation occurs
i told you last time the human tumor is roughly speaking about the human body
roughly carries three times ten to the thirteenth cells
so that's quite a few cells
that somebody cells are in the human body plus or minus
human tumor of one let's say one cubic centimeter
is roughly ten to the ninth cells
would quickly make a scan over the sky
five minutes that's all they had
and i joined the group of george clark
which come at MIT
he was doing actually astronomy from very high flying balloons
very close to the top of the atmosphere
and the advantage of balloons was that you could observe the sky for many many
hours if you're lucky sometimes even today or more
but on the other hand
since there is always a little bit of atmosphere left above you even though very
little there's still some left
he actually is i absorbs almost all
x-rays below
twenty killer that controls would be absorbed and we wouldn't be able to see them
but of course
compensation was that we could look at this guy
for many many many hours
nowadays no one is doing balloon observations anymore
no more rocket observations everything is done of course
from satellites
so when i came to MIT together with george clark i developed
new x-ray detectors for these balloon observations
many graduate students were involved
many undergraduates
will take about two years to build
give you a rough idea will take
million dollars
in terms of nineteen
sixty six
dollars and
the weight of such a telescope will be roughly
one thousand kilograms
the belongs in those days cost about two hundred thousand dollars
gets up to these high altitudes
and we would need about eighty thousand dollars of helium
you will see some slides of that
we have to go to an altitude of about two hundred forty
a thousand feet
really huge problems for that
you'll see one
they have diameters of about six
a hundred feet
and the material
extremely thin to make them light weight so that they can go i
the thickness of that polyethylene
was about half of one thousands of an inch which is then
then the surrender at that you have in the kitchen
it is thinner than cigarette paper
very risky business to fly these balloons
no guarantee of course they will work
you pay your money if they work that's great if they don't work that just
tough luck
there's a good chance that you have a failure when you want the balloon
very fragile
could be damaged right at the launch
but even if they make it up in the atmosphere they have to go through
the trouble course
one hundred thousand feet very very cold
balloons get brittle
and then they can burst
that of course
would be and then of the balloon flights
and that could also be the end of a phd thesis because all these
flights of course we're connected with research
and therefore his phd work
sort attention during these
early phases of the ones always
extremely high sometimes even unbearable
so now i would like to show you
some slides
which will give you
good idea of what
these expeditions
we're like
i am a classic problems
now it work
all right so if i can have the first slide
you see here
and that's who at the time were undergraduates they both phd
and they're working they're very tedious work trying to
putting electronics together
you may think that
science is not very romantic
but i can assure you it is they fell in love with a married to
have kids
that's the way it sometimes goes in life
here you see the plant in texas where these huge balloons were made
a lot support again sort of like
the way to the tangerine is put together
the surface see these of the balloon
and the ceiling of the gore through
make up the balloon with
only done by women only women were allowed to work there
nothing to do with sex discrimination of any kind
i just found out that
women were more patients they were better
make way fewer mistakes than men
that's the way it goes sometimes in life
you see people coming out of the box nicely techniques
plastic cover
we also have a year
well only
on the graph because of something
so only that
but the graph norms
this was not my
we were there was something wrong with them
can so
concerning the was holding the balloons
the whole is nothing more than that because the whole is almost always through many
many many of which are looking at all the layers that form together
that's my
story was never nice
if you see fail
now there
right heart failure
now you get a pretty good idea what it's like
you see them on
telescope is there
there you see it's enormously big blue or is and he is now in most
of these will stay empty
this is the role
which holds this
part down this the only part that will be inflated
you see the newly in proc
see inflation tubes
we will have the men from both sides
which will then gradually begin to feel this part
of the building
the role of arm detail armies very important
because when this part of the balloon is being filtered wants to lift wants to
go up
and of course you have to keep it down you have to keep it under
so these are all arm in this
his car
it's loaded down with
concrete is very heavy and then
just before the launch this role arms by command is flipped over and then as
you will see later that the balloon will
make it up
you see the early part of the inflation
it comes in from both sides
so we we fly these balloons almost always only morning because then the winds are
you need extremely
reliable winds you need to know the direction very well
and the wind should be
no more than something like three or four miles per hour if there stronger
louis blues CUDA cores that i mentioned earlier
the sun is behind
the balloon
here the bubble is nearly fully inflated now
still going on
still going on inflation would be very close
the end of inflation here the role
and then
in this direction here
five hundred feet or so down is the
the road which cross
we know very close to launch was still in alice springs this is one of
my graduate student jeff mcclintock at the time now
doctor mcclintock
you see radar reflectors which allows us to follow the
assume that's already been done so we're gonna look for the argmax of W
of this quantity here this outer product so this is the primal representation it's
equivalent to maximizing this Raleigh quotient which is just the ratio of that quantity divided
by the norm squared and this actually just picks the first principal component that W
what you would then do if you wanted to go for the second was orthogonalize
the data to that direction and look for now again for this maximum
where this direction has somehow been excluded from the data and then you get
the second and so on so now this actually just putting in Lagrange multipliers
for optimizing this quotient you end up with this quantity and if you take the
derivative of this vector W you get this equation which is an eigenvalue equation for the
covariance matrix X primed X so essentially the eigen the directions are the eigenvectors of
the covariance matrix and the ones that you want to choose are the ones corresponding to the
largest eigen values because if you look at this eigen value and compute W
primed X primed X W actually see is equal to lambda and so lambda measures the
variance in that particular eigen direction so the eigen values is actually are measuring the quality
if you like of the projection so clearly you want to pick the top eigen values and
choose those directions as your directions in which there is most variance and those are
the corrections you project into okay so so that's the primal principal components a very classical method
of data reduction of dimension notice that the there' this very nice property that the
amount of variance that you capture if you pick K eigenvectors are the sum of
the eigen values first K eigen values the total variance which is also the
trace of the kernel matrix is the sum of the norm squares
of the training data and that it is equal to the sum of the eigen
values so you can see a few eigen values start big and go down you can see
very clearly what you're losing by truncating at a particular point you're losing
the sum of the residual eigenvalues that you didn't choose and you're getting
the variance of the sum of the eigenvalues that you did choose so it's a very
nice way of reading of what's happening so what about kernel PCA okay well we
want to find a dual representation of those principle eigenvectors that's all there is to
it it's it's a very simple problem and the the trick that shows us
that we can do it is the following if we have a an eigen value
sorry eigenvector eigenvalue pair of that covariance matrix then it turns out
that if we take X W and lambda the same lamda but just multiply X
pre-multiply W by X then it actually turns out that that is an eigen
vector eigen value pair for the kernel matrix so here we are X X primed
the kernel matrix times X W that's X primed X just by changing the order of
the multiplication times W which of course is now lambda times W and so we
actually show that X W times X X primed is lambda times X W so this
is now and eigenvector of this matrix and vice versa if we take an eigen vector
which I'm now denoting suspiciously as alpha look and eigen
value lambda of the kernel matrix then I claim X primed alpha lambda is a
kernel is an eigen vector and eigen value of this covariance matrix and again
same computation shows us that very simply X primed X times X primed alpha change
the order X X primed times alpha that's the kernel matrix times alpha is lambda alpha and so we
end up with this vector being an eigenvector of the covariance matrix so there's a one-to-one correspondence
between the eigenvectors of the covariance matrix with non zero lambda and the eigenvectors of
the kernel matrix with nonzero alpha and indeed we can get between one and the
other by this multiplication and in particular if we have an Eigen vector of the
kernel matrix bingo we have a dual representation of the eigenvector of the covariance matrix
is X primed alpha that looks really familiar that is actually our way of expressing
a vector in a dual way it's a linear combination of the training data which
are in this as columns of this transpose matrix X so so here we
are all we need to know is what the norm of this thing is in
order to get the normalization right if we assume that we've normalized alpha to
be one which is the normal way you would if you applied a standard eigen
value routine to your kernel matrix you get back eigenvectors with norm one so
what is the norm of this thing well just multiply it out and you you find
it's lambda and so we just need to normalize by that one over the square
root of the lambda in order to make sure that this dual vector that we
sorry that the the vector that we get when we use the dual representation
is normalized correctly and so this is now the dual representation of the ith eigenvector
of the covariance matrix and it involves just the eigenvector the kernel matrix and divided
by one over the square root of the corresponding eigenvalue okay so it's as
simple as that it's a very very sort of natural thing again because we're measuring variance
and we're maximizing variances absolutely natural that the weight vectors in the in the in the
feature space will not have any component orthogonal to the span of the training data
there's no point in putting in a weight vector with some orthogonal component because you're
just wasting your varianceon a on a direction that has no no variance at all
this tube
and the sound comes out
on the other side of the two
and that sound is as of t
so you have to use the exhibition the puffs of air blow into the two
minutes of t is the sound the sound of the stu makes both u of
t and s of functions they live in some function spaces
let's assume for simplicity that these are actually periodic functions
so they have fully years series expansions still live little l two
and let's play the following game
every day you come to me
and collect the sound
that i make for you on that particular day
you don't know what i'm doing and just generating sounds for you every day you
come to me
and collect the sound the sound we just discussed lives in little tools of the
sound lives in an infinite dimension space so every day you go back with an
infinite dimensional data datapoints
but what i'm doing from day to day
OK unknown to you
is i'm actually changing one degree of freedom freedom in the physical system that is
generating the data for you
what i'm doing is i'm just changing the length l of the steel
so how do we reason about this
you would actually try to understand what is the set of all the sounds the
physical system can generate
where there is only one degree of freedom in the physical system and to understand
this you would actually have
to do something like this
so the equations of air flow in this deal
and these are the equations the complications leading to what is called the webster hall
equation ultimately v
p of x commodity is the pressure
as a function of time
t is time
x is location
in in this in the horizontal axis
so in other words sft
the sound is tube generate this still makes is really the pressure wave
had when x is equal to l
u of
is the pressure wave
when x is equal to zero at the other end of the two
so sort of this
and you get a nice closed form on so far how of is related to
s of
and if you have t looks like this it's a periodic function has a four-year
series expansion it lives in a little to the fourier coefficients of the alpha ends
so every sound you represent by computing its fourier coefficients and then it's the point
in this for years space
and because of the fourier coefficients of the s is and what i've plotted is
the set of all sounds in the space spanned by beta one
b three and b just seven for particular simulation
so basically the set of all sounds
generated by this deal with just one degree of freedom would lie on
a one-dimensional curve
in little l two
and this picture
looks more or less exactly like the picture
that i made out
a few slides ago
you might think even this is artificial when does
you know when we
in the situation where analyzing just single tubes
but actually there is a long tradition and some of you who
come from BT's in acoustics and its application to speech analysis would be aware of
there's a long tradition in modelling the book the set of speech sounds as those
by a non uniform tube
the vocal tract
as this nonuniform two was excited by puffs of air
that you blow into this tube
by moving along
and that's how you speak
and this is essentially the acoustic model of speech production which is the classical model
developed in the
the fifties and sixties and seventies and
sort of elaborated over the last thirty or forty years
and so if you take this view
he would say that look at all the speech sounds that are being generated generated
biophysical systems
and the degrees of freedom in the physical system are not that many
you cannot move your vocal tract in arbitrary ways
you cannot generate any sound
any desired sound by
moving vocal tract you can only generate the set of speech sounds that are naturally
generated by vocal tract so it's a physical system with few degrees of freedom and
the set of all speech sounds with therefore
in some low dimensional subset
of the ambient space
of all signals
in which this is embedded
so that's an example from acoustic so let me give an example from images
so what's an image
an image more or less is something like this
a function from our tool to zero one
well any x y
f of x y
is just the
intensity of that image at that location
so every image is therefore
lives trivially
in some function space again just like acoustic signals live trivially in some function space
and now i wanted to consider the following class of images is very simple
class of images almost trivial class of images
these are images of of vertical bar on the translation
these are pictures of vertical bars
as i said
this is the set script if
so every element of this set script f
it is a particular function that corresponds to a particular image of vertical bar
and the way the set is generated is by taking a particular vertical bar which
we call the
that's the image of a particular vertical bar and keep translating this vertical bars so
water molecules
in a solution of water of all things
and the fact of the matter is if let's say we grow one hydrogen
one water molecule down here and one water water molecule down here
what will happen is that this
oxygen atom over here by virtue of its electronegativity
will have a certain
appalling this hydrogen atom
taught itself and in fact what actually happens in real life whatever that is at
the molecular level
is it this hydrogen atom may actually be bouncing back and forth between these two
oxygen is it may be rapidly interchange between them
this interchange
cause a strong association between two neighbouring water molecules
and indeed represents the reason why water does not vaporize at room temperature because the
water molecules have a strong affinity or or nobility from one another
and therefore just take some illustrations of the book
this is the way it illustrated in in the book
probably good to have
a screen down and here you can see the way the water molecules are actually
it in water this is the the lower illustration here
just to indicate to you that the hydrogen atoms are not really the
the possession
the ownership of one molecule of water that is constantly being exchanged back and forth
and this back-and-forth exchange the sharing of the hydrogen atom
it is what enables the hydrogen bond over roughly five killer calories
of energy per per mole
to hold things together by killer calories
it's not much
it's only one order of magnitude above point six rather than being two orders of
magnitude and therefore if one raises the temperature to the level of boiling one the
temperature is high enough the thermal energy is high enough to rip apart these kinds
of associations
now if we were to go back here to look at this carbonyl atom
we would find the following sort of situation
here we have this unequal sharing of electoral positive electronegative
o bonds let's put in the city group like this this is a carboxylic acid
right here
here we see two
a carbon bound to hydroxyl here and by the this oxygen atom
here once again we have an electronegative atom
and in fact if we talk about an ionized
as it normally in the absence of ionisation there will be a net zero charge
right here
but at neutral ph it may well be the case
that the association for various reasons between this oxygen in this hydrogen
i will
will allow the hydrogen or or rather the protons the nucleus of the hydrogen atom
to just wander away
and therefore we can imagine there could be a net negative charge here
a whole
this is has one full electron electrical negative charge and the charge of one electron
and this proton will have ionized will have left the carboxylic group
in which it originated and now we have an ionized to citigroup group
either before or even after this ionisation there's a strong affinity of the carboxyl group
with the water around it because let's let's look about what happened
let's look at what happened before the innovation occurred
this carboxy carbamoyl here is strong unicom electronegative
and therefore it will participate in hydrogen bonding to the water
solvent here
i e this proton will be shared between the oxygen of the water molecules and
the oxygen right here
similarly here this oxygen will be slightly next electronegative this for the reasons i just
described in here once again there may be some weak hydrogen bonding going on
although not as effective as over here where we have a double bond we have
a lot of concentration of a cloud of
electrons are pulled towards the oxygen atom
and this begins to give us clues
as to why certain molecules are solvable soluble in water and others are insoluble
for example if we look at aliphatic compounds let's look at a compound that structured
like this
i guess
most people would call this
and we can
called that
and this has no electronegativity are positively by virtually equal affinities of these two of
these two kinds of atoms that is the hydrocarbons
four electrons
and as a consequence
this will not be able to form any hydrogen bonds with the solvent around if
the solvent happens to be water
there's there's not good bonding here
and this will in fact also if one puts this in in a solution of
water this will cause all the water molecules to line up in a certain way
almost quasi crystals
the aliphatic molecules
will be ordered certainly around the elephant molecule without being able to form any strong
hydrogen bonds with them
and this ordering represents a loss of chaos a loss of
entropy is chaos it's disorder it's what happens let's say
nine ten fifty five and we'll leave the room the sudden order becomes
chaotic and here before
before this lining up occurred the water molecules were chaotically arranged throughout the solvent after
this lining up occurred there was a lot of entropy there was a lot of
and thermodynamics tells us
generally the ordering of molecules is disfavored
and consequently we now have two reasons why this molecule doesn't like to be in
the midst of water first of all it's unable to form hydrogen bonds with the
and second of all
there's a decrease in the entropy in the chaos that occurs when this molecule directly
i'm not used to being half an hour behind before you can start by all
try and try and get slightly back on schedule so
it's my job to give you an introduction to
the whole idea of machine learning
and and then to try and introduce one of the many different important theoretical
foundations of machine learning which is the probabilistic approach so
i think is this microphone just for the camera
OK so you use two microphones
thanks that's so i want to emphasise four-star that the probabilistic approach is one of
the core
the ideas in machine learning but it's not the only approach in your life or
during the rest of
the lectures about other approaches but whether or not use probabilistic approach in any particular
problem it's important to note that because it's very influential in how our ideas about
how you think it is often an important technique you should be using in your
problem is not the only ones
i want to start by showing you a video if i can find
and then be you
thinking about
although structure is
this is
produced by of you was microsoft research in seattle
it's easy if you look at the video for humans to figure out what what's
happening in this video right what's happening is the computers box around the base that
and this video is impressive for several reasons one is that you can actually run
this system in real time on laptop so it's not likely to be
and they computed on for six days and made this video actually
and the other thing that's impressive although you could argue that because system is busy
during analysis each frame
it's not taking advantage of the fact that french sequential circuits a single
performance would actually be
so the question that i want to try and get you to think about is
if you had to write computer program like this
let's assume don't know about village on
face detectors about how would you go about doing it
OK that's really
kind of core problem
machine is a task which is relatively well defined like detecting faces in images
and you need to write a programme but it's not really at all clear how
you should start writing the program so
the fact that i'm going to discourage you from taking is the approach trying to
just say well i'm smarter than the world
i know what this is the face has two eyes nose and mouth and i'm
just going to write to i detectors was attacked
detectors going around the money
image and then i'm going to you know specify my quote exactly what needs to
be highlighted something around the table
and that's going to work
what you should convince yourself before you do do anything in machine learning that is
never going to work
the world is too complicated for
the essential
approach two
two building intelligent systems which is codified in machine learning is the idea of using
examples from the real world to train systems which are then given as one
for example if you want to train system to do face identification to go cover
picture like this to named then again hand programming is not really possible here so
what's the solution the solution is to get the computer to program itself at some
level by showing examples of the kind of behaviour one
so in the face problem we would show the computer alot of images and say
these images have faces
and then we to computer what images and so these images don't have faces and
then we trying to automatically from data set learned what is about to face OK
so this is the learning approach the and i think that
you know it's very easy to make a very strong argument this approach essentially dominates
intelligent systems
in in the modern day
there were older approach is based on rules
they were coming back and expert systems and stuff but those have almost universally been
eclipsed by learning machines in huge range of application so we should think about this
it's not really that computers programming itself completely really what you're doing is you're writing
a program
that has thousands or millions or tens of millions of undefined constants
so imagine you know those or c programmers imagine you literally wrote program but at
the top of of the CAE program there were a number of define constant one
comes their like
a hundred thousand or million years ago and the only one way of studying those
constants but cost to control the degree program for setting of the concerts different program
runs how do you set the concept that's really what the game of machine learning
about tweaking the real numbers inside a computer program your road to make the computer
program behave the way you want so geometrically you can think of this as any
particular program you write with undefined constants defines a space of possible
executables right if a million parameters in new
based on the goal machine learning is to put you in the right spot that
knowledge dimensional space to solve your problem face detection spam email or what it is
our goal in life is to estimate
internal parameters of computer program structure is specified by using an existing set
and that is that somehow captures correct behavior we want
so you can think of statistical machine learning models as probabilistic databases so
traditional database technology can really answer any query about items were never look into the
dataset and the idea of a probabilistic model for statistical models of talk about for
the next two lectures is that they can build
probabilistic any query about the about the
OK so
the these models also a lot of other advantages they allow you to make decisions
given partial information by taking into account the uncertainty or an observability of one
i don't know they count for noisy sensors actuators because what measurements taken in world
are not accurate for physical reasons
they can explain things that are part of the model
explicitly because they allow for certain stochastic behaviour and so
to get a classification so you can't just go above the
threshold by small amount above by quite a bit and the the
amount in the so it's very analogous to the mention of and a light I don't wanna that each other's it gets to the
legacy and I don't think it's very very instructive um and
particularly the corresponding of proof that 2 Saleh's so given that you know all the fracturing
to mention is you want a computer about the demographic function in the
way that some was lemma computer bound on the growth
function in terms of the the EC dimension that is in the paper by at long at al long choose a banque
you have aren't somebody who can be found in and and that it is absolutely problem and that is a really
very tricky very tricky in the article monitorial and I certainly wouldn't want to you don't have to reproduce or even in the present and so on so I I I don't want to go into
those but I just want to highlight exist and uh you know there's a machine are if
you like the bounding fracturing dimensions of various
function classes you can do it for the new classes and for
other function all of his theory works in general see
doesn't just apply to the functions of socio metallic so
very general results from the full all be bound it is
somewhat similar to those hours that most some of the major
global of the of the uh the growth function you get in this I was lemma cases the d you Lord here and nobody if you remember
that in the of alone italicus you get died most where so there's a an
extra log factor comes in the but you know a lot of work to
between learning there is used in lot of problem on so that it it all work through e 1 but I think I uh but I would like to indicate that this is
a more direct route and I think it's quite a nice a little of the idea that you can use to get covering numbers for
linear functions and I going to restrict down to looking at
the case of linear functions that says the answer and I'm going to look at how we can actually bound those
covering numbers for linear functions in a direct way of
this will be the last thing that we have to talk about and
actually I'm going to uh up suggest you might look at the details of this is an
exercise overnights and will have some reward points around so I'll talk about that at the end but it's a
difficult time in the of 1st are indicated you know at a
sort of the brush programmable how I think this mean how
this should be done on uh and uh uh that you know that in the book and the
details of what the hell you purchases and so on so we doing this week and
the this is a problem of up essentially remember 1 it's
trying to we have some function as a more going to try and
make sure that we're going to find a elements in the cover that is how this similar performance to add on the training set so on all
the training points its outputs should be willing gamma of
the output of the function of the start of on the training set on the trial make sure that this function comes from some
simple small said that a couple of things so that we don't
think of it is not converting that problem of finding that
approximately function to learning problem a classification problems that on and we're going to do
that by effectively making in each of those approximation so for each training point we can think of book are which is the output of the functions that I got I want to make sure that the output of the functioning my
cover is going to be with a gun and Denmark over of that
value so I get out So imagine putting a threshold or a sort
of a type of a universal threshold act gamma and I'm going
to say that this a function is correct shall correctly classified it is on
the right side of the threshold and you don't think that
making that in to a classification problems by effectively
adding 1 extra dimension in which is the output value of
the function of that so you can make it to the
classification function in fact it has 2 in the training points all if you go and you're trying
to cover and points because you you have to have 1 and classification problems was
saying I want to be a no warbling gamma above the output
value of the function and given and I need another 1 was saying I'm not woman gamma below soberer to sort of classification is that you have to make it but you can help by doing this extra to mention convert that been to
essentially a a yes no classification answer and furthermore of the actual weight vector that you start
it where the actual functioning started with satisfies
there's constraints clearly because its output actually is buried in the centre of that it's not you know it's it's it's the value that was not gamma bubble gum Belloso it's going in the
centre and it has a large in which is gonna paying so we have a situation group of a learning problem
and we've got a solution which has a large Indiana on that
many problems that thing know we should we would do apply the perceptron algorithm to find a classifier to solve that learning problem out I
know who is not familiar with the perceptron algorithm in 1
more the of the of the of the project we so should spends a
very brief it's a very simple algorithm and all just
which features are important for your problem
and so
in the remainder of the talk and going to bridge should tell you
what of the tools to discover is called the relationship
let me first define what i mean by a local feature relevance
shares a rather complex graph itself
when the allies completely but like to hear the sounds of all the things that
can happen is relatively elaborate in some cases
imagine that what you want to predict is like cancer
and there are some variables that might be causing lung cancer
for example smoking some genetic factors and some variables that may be a consequence of
cancer like of alive having test is or some other
symptoms that people some sometimes call you know biomarkers
now there be indicted causes like anxiety might be causing smoking
and they might be also consequences of causes
that are called in the jargon confounding factors like other cancers
there may be hidden variables
for example it may be that like tar lines that are
more that causes lung smoking
lung cancer but unfortunately you have access to them
then maybe also
hidden confounders so for example
imagine that has been you know a recurrent theme in the tobacco settlement problem in
the united states
there has been an by now a lot of health policies not to smoke in
public places and restrictions on selling cigarettes and tobacco companies have been heavily complaining that
there is no real evidence that smoking causes lung cancer that only correlation has been
observed and that so far there hasn't been any real prove that there is no
genetic factor
that would both cause cramping smoking
and cancer
imagining that there is such a genetic factor
then the school out the hypothesis that smoking causes lung cancer
there are other interesting things happening
imagine that you would like to predict what counts on the basis of coffee
indeed the coughing might be a predictor cancer but imagine that you have another cause
of casting molecular biology
if you don't know about our cheap then coffee becomes very poor predictor of lung
cancer for example if you are during the hay fever season
and becomes virtually useless to monitor coughing to predict cancer
and you know i have shown you other cases you know is the story of
the systematic knowledge this is the example i gave you with the baseline problem
all in all you have you know all these different cases here
and people working on causal future discovery
of playing this game of trying to find those variables that are closest to the
in the sense that this shield
the target from all the other variables and that's what people call the markov blanket
the markov blanket is the set of variables that are now in the
o shaded area
such that when you
you consider these variables then
the variables outside the shaded area become independent
of the target
and as you can see this is not as simple as it may look
at least as the people working markov blanket telling because if you have a hidden
variables or
those may be the ones that are really in the markov blanket
and in particular in the case of systematic knowledge is
the nice maybe the thing that is really in the markov blanket but you don't
know about it
and you may be thinking that you know certain biomarker
is relevant for example this sort position in my mass spectra you may think it's
a well it's relevant but in reality it's not relevant
the nice was what's was what
nevertheless i think these tools of
of causal discovery of very useful because they allow you to in some of the
arts instead of just detecting correlations you can detect causality
and that might become very important particularly if you want to
the grass
between random variables
we're dependencies are presented by edges and
the graph allows you to compute various distributions between subsets of variables
what is given is the probability of a given variable given its parents and from
you can compute the joint probability of all the variables and all sorts of
marginals that are using subsets of the virus
the fraction in the original vision entries have no meaning but in causal bayesian networks
they indicate causality
so here's an example of causal discovery algorithm
bias to send clear more and giving this example
not hoping that he will memorize it immediately but to show you that it's not
that complicated
let's consider a b and c
random variables that belong to the set x
and be a subset of x initialize with a fully connected un oriented graph representing
the causal relationships between the variables
then find an oriented edges
by using the criterion that variable a shares the dark ages bartleby
if and only if no subset
of all the variables we can render them conditionally independent so this is what is
written a conditionally independent of b
given the
so all these algorithms for detecting causal dependencies rely heavily upon
tests of conditional independence between variables
and then the orient edges in so-called colliders of triplets of collider is
is that when two arrows
o point
to a given variable
they collide on to c
so your ages and this is colored using the criterion that if there is a
dark age between a and c
and between c and b
but not between a and b
you have this
the pattern of connections
if and only if there is no such containing c such that independent given given
OK so just to say that you need to know to do another another test
of conditional independence to determine
and then there are some heuristic to further orient edges
these algorithms are
expensive computationally and also statistically so they are very data hungry and take a lot
of time
so usually people resort to simplify them
and compromised for example by
abandoning the estimation of the full graph but caring only about those links that between
the target variable and the
other variables
or abandoning the idea of fully oriented to orient in the graph or anything only
a subset of the edges
i'll be talking to the political
algorithm for discovering the markov blankets
which is the case in which you care only about the given target
and you want to find those variable that shield
the target from all the other variables
so what you do first is to identify the the parents and children
in the following way
that's the first iteration you add
and even though let's call it a
the second iteration you add another one that's colin b
and then the third iteration
you will be looking at conditional independence so if a is conditionally independent of y
given b
then remove then you don't need a
and keep only