the different and discount factor is a side effect
that's a
it in effect is not the goal
the goal is to be able to express knowledge
of actions that these very different time scales
that's the goal
because it allows us to then planned more efficiently and that few medical reason where
by planning can be out converge faster is that we in fact get
people look ahead
is one way of saying it
saying it is we get a bigger discount
because this kind of the point where we can always discount
more mean s
this county on the goal is in effect
i hope i answered that i hope that made sense that makes sense
you can ask the question you have to be
you have to accept the answer can
you can challenge and
he said there is that the main difference is actually the a one to
that's that's the critical difference the effect of
is a big attraction
but i think that was
one want is the ability to represent actually different time scales
have yes i do believe that
so we should do
you understand the reason is not
you are
max q is always interesting
structure and extraction
you start with your comments about that we want to talk about that here so
you can also ask you must skeptical of here is different from
a different perspective this landscape hierarchies is is that
it's a very anthropomorphic way
or language use
so we think
if the was we have
like the country to see i have yet to see any reason to need
very little promotion yes
that is
so profound was
all is if
the intuition that
we just to quickly apparent is really asking
one of my
nine OK i don't spend enough come back you so only a few minutes left
a do
is to see an example
with that
the goal of holistic education now
he goes on holiday to the state of the
so what happens often and preventive actions
the evaluation first people that intuition this now hold a state
i always say that you know
i you can you get by with so it's not constraint has caused a lot
of people
the target state one of goals the options yes
OK very
very much so i should say this
this is sufficient so
if we plan
with both primitive actions and options and the choice is based on the value of
the change because of the actions which is
if we plan only after the total weight of the actions
it depends on how much how
what range of choices the option
make of it
right so
so if you keep the action choice assessed
the expanded accidental by adding options then of course that policies
we can probably not be able to find the space the on policy in the
space of four by just
i think it's a hoax was a hoax
is that i've been talking about optimal control have been talking about what you get
first course
that's just a prince
it's not really expected it is that the behaviour of
that's the principle
i call it common misconception reinforcement learning is in his house
some people dismiss people
this firm by conjugate prior
but i'm assuming exponential families
so you could do all this
without the exponential families that's fine
but the thing is as soon as you go to some linear function class
in the exponent of four you hammersley clifford theorem
well this is actually this exponential family notation is a very convenient way of writing
but of course you can play with this norm
so i mean
there are lots of ways how to generalize this to make it much more complicated
just trying to convey the simple case
and it's very easy to
make it more general more complicated and fill up the slide the equations but
all right
to recap
this in the product between of x and y so you explain it to you
for the y and y plus one
and well
similar expression here
we want to compute in approach between a given four x y x t y
and the expectation
then this is just
the expectation here over the kernel function
given x
and expectation go like t
so that's why we can get away with
a rather simple terms even though the overall expression might look a little bit daunting
it was
one line
is that he
x y yes
and the subscript x y min
this one
no that shouldn't be subscript that's just the joint feature map
but then
if i look
into that specific model that had on the previous slide
let's go back one more
to that model
we had
phi x y
and phi y phi x six but just picked up on that very same notation
i mean to be more specific my father x and y
it looks as
so this
one big long vector
of phi
x y
of x i
while i
x y
x plus one
why i plus one
after the end of the sequence and then we have some more terms
why why
why i
why i plus one
and then we have
one why
of y r plus one
why are plus two
and so on and so on
and if they want to compute the conditional expectation
of the big east here
then i can do that
now componentwise the problem is actually easy
it is this component only depends on the y i love this one
this one only depends on the well
so only need the marginal probabilities
even though the overall expression here
involves the entire sequence
so that means that i'm bringing the computation down from something that could be exponential
this is an exponential number of flies
something to fling it
does that answer question
and now
we get
the subspace representer theorem
and the subspaces the representer theorem is the
expansion equivalent
i'm not going to touch those but i was emphasizing that
that it's there
that's moving is there and and actually i have
well i have us
the problem too
about maybe i'll mention this about smoothing
the only been mentioned
can i say this about smoothing
which is
and then i'll come back to the heart of the subject which is here
so smoothing involves also
you know going back up
and probably most people don't have to pay a lot of attention to it
so i get
things about problems in matrices
often from the
from sort of area of people who work in linear algebra
well the problem appeared
that i'll stay here and i'll put it on into the lecture notes
for this
and the right away offer prize for solution
because when i saw the problem
so was put in by a friend of mine from berkeley
i don't know where he came up with it
but i realize it's gotta be intimately connected to the kalman filter
OK i thought
well these guys the readers of this this journal or like experts in in linear
algebra they'll solve this problem
twenty ways
but that didn't happen
the problem one month after month unsolved until
the idea that the copy i have here of the problem
it is said would somebody please send an answer
and for me that was so striking a an example
in real
time so to speak of the of the
cut the the separation between so much of linear algebra and what we're doing here
course it's not totally separated the people in numerical linear algebra no efficient ways to
do this and let me remark
well on one
he's general comments
that as always
we have a choice with this system what's our choice here
and how to solve that system
we have a choice of solving it by elimination
or by
you are my orthogonalisation
you know if you remember that choice
and that choice in this world is called this is the square root filters
this is a here we got a square
so the formulas i'm writing down are the classical formulas that involve
things about eight times a day
but for super stability and sometimes for speed or sometimes you lose speed
those are those are the crucial issues probably gain little stability and lose a little
speed if you change this
if if you
express a
i'm just going to put it up here do nothing with it
a as hugh
and of course you to compute q are recursively
new rows are added to a
new things are computed here
so this would be this would this would give the square root filters
it was like a bombshell in in the commons
common world
as an alternative
and i'm not the
it at all
able to report on
the current state of that battle
now i was going to
i tell you this
so this is this is the problem
so i have a try diagonal matrix
i tried a google matrix let me what what can i call it here t
four try diag
and it
factors into
yes a lower
the usual lower lower with ones on the diagonal
pavements and upper and one of the what's the information about the we have about
l has to die this has three diagonal
l has two diagonals
he has diagonal you has
dial above and i'm not going to assume in this problem that the matrix is
symmetric positive definite
just try diagonals all
there's no all for all objects z
the robot is an holdings in that situation so that first feature since the robot
find the robot
and the object x is not heavy
and the robot is next to
the object so i can sort of
so that's the preconditioned action rama can pick the thing up
if it's not holding anything if things that to
and it's next to it
now all the terms he like for instance you see are SSL not qualified they
implicitly universally quantified but since there was implicitly all implicitly universally quantified we drop the
so this is this is true for all this
it's true for all that for all x
OK now let's look at what the actions do normally we distinguish two types of
fixed positive effects
the negative effects
like the lecture from from the fact that
OK so the first one says is the positive effect and it says that if
x is fragile
then it's going to be broken after the robot drops
and negative effects might be that well it becomes not broken if the robot does
the repair action on the object
you perfect so their preconditions for the repair action and maybe you can only do
it if if it's not broken you might want to do that probably would want
to do that but in some cases you might just learn do it and no
change in the state situation
that's that's a really good question
other domain constraints cetera we're not really going to talk to much about the main
constraints but let's look at some possibilities
so the first one in blue this is excess on the table if and only
if it's notable
so the main constraints religious put some restrictions on the domain usually they make the
reasoning a little bit easier
in the situation calculus usually don't have domain constraints
i just put it there because in a lot in some of the formalism you
do have these constraints
uh huh
now the idea here is going to be the following
what we're going to do is we're going to take all this stuff so we're
going to take
the axioms that say something about what's true
initially it is zero
this is called series stuff
plus we're going to
the prospect seems to say what's possible
plus we're gonna the effect that seems both negative and positive
hopefully that will allow us to answer the question
you know is some flaw f
so there is some flaw if true
at the the situation
OK so basically when we read this from right to left we're going to do
a one and a two three four all the way to you
and what i want to be able to reason about is whether some properties true
after i do all these actions
and obviously if i do that for all of the ones that i have i
can work at exactly what's true in this
now the question is well if i just take my initially
my position the state initially
if i take the
the facts about my
actions so
the preconditions
and their effects
at the beginning of the lecture we sort of agree that was enough
so now i should have enough enough material
to be able to answer this question whether it's true or false
so one happy so that
just look at the end
i can now
then we come up to this now going to come to the sort of point
i want to try and make which is about this thing called the frame problem
many of
that particular if you don't
any i sort of classes
all the things that we've described so far
in the initial state the
preconditions effects
all they do is they describe what changes they tell us when actions can be
applied and they tell us what those actions do
so they tell us about the things that change
what they don't tell us anything about is the things that don't change
and you would think that that's right
i don't have to write stuff dan about what doesn't change i just want to
have to write
down stuff about things change
and the problem is that if we don't say anything about what doesn't change
then we can reason about
so he is one example
going to come down to the colours
suppose i have
cold colours
and it tells me that the color of an object x is c
so this might be a y block for instance
in situation s
if i picked this subject up
well if we go back a couple of slides
and we have a look at the african i this precondition
four pickups
so it tells me that i can pick it up got nothing to do with
the color
and presumably also the effect of picking up means that is now in my hand
these antibiotics
how close
relate to those nature they what you will find that the index and the approximation
OK then you can grab some
something from nature then you try to
to train and in some way you probably can find new antibiotics because that's the
but the trick is what he wants is the search
so this one is a huge nature in some kind of a german
they want to find this antibiotics whether it contains something very similar structure in nature
that's what they what they say they want search rather my
but search everybody knows search
you probably want to have index just thinking about will go if if you google
no index how do search the web there's no way you can search the web
google using indexes in ranking so index is the most important thing for anything to
search large
but if we think about this the
graphs how to search the graph database
OK even this one is not mining your findings very charming
the reason is the structure
you need of course you may have the subgraph isomorphism test which is NP hard
cases but the the major bad news is that it is so huge graph could
be big
and you go there you fetch everyone do this i some testing is not
it's not really working because it's so slow
so the important thing is indexed there are a few indexing structure available because even
here yesterday mention about this they like to stay light the graphs graph was done
by dennis shasha publishing parts
and there are several
things but the interesting thing is all these once they are not really using graph
the sea they do graph indexing they're using packs
using the longest pass to the index of course why they don't use graph you
pretend to stand because the possibly enumeration of the subgraph easy explanation OK you can
not index explanation search space
OK that's the reason they use class
now we think about
for the
for the query graph the whole process to try to find similar structures this eugenia
query graph
this is my
chemical compounds i go to the nature
i want to find something similar of course not exactly the whole thing
is you find the subset we say the subgraph
you want to find this one compaign this up somehow get
OK so
you need to construct index if you have index on this one
you probably OK but the problem is how many such subgraphs you get if you
get a big graph this one union one of them is exponential
so if we think about the whole search space
we were saying
first we can swap index on the structures that then we do query processing we
take this structure we enumerate
there we
check those force possibly cut that we find the core the matching OK
but the problem we were looking at is we know
if we want to index all things it's impossible
but oh well we can look at the cost with you where is the problem
why we do this graph indexing could be very expensive
the first thing is
of course if you have index entry this entry serves may have cost ireland CPU
but then you take the index to coincide
you may find some candidates
this is your candidate set
then you may find for each candidate whom effect the real graph
and they you do have some of the testing whether it's real graph is the
one you need
but the key part if you want to reduce the cost he parties make this
one small
thinking about this a in davis here we know there's one car mike stonebraker quite
often using this once example of
mike stonebraker is the one who invented the first relational database system called in greece
he was a professor at UC berkeley
there are two ways to index one the index mike another is index still break
which one do you prefer
i think everybody was index will break around the index mark
the reason a is if you index mike you go to the your phone book
how many might have never have hundreds of thousands of might and so if you
take kind of south
this set this candidate that would be really huge they you have to search every
page of the form book to see whether this mike is mike stonebraker this might
is not like stonebraker
so that that's too costly but it gets stonebraker
the set is much smaller
you do this
the remaining task even it may still take some cost was only could have better
than that
so if we know this
we probably do the same thing
so the interesting thing is previous people also think about this they don't index everything
they say i pick up graphs
pick up the parks take up the longest pass i want to index some so
then i'm i'm OK
the previous approach including the commercial daylight what they do is they say
search the longest pass lens one installing three you enumerate all these passing index you
can do the search
but the problem i can give you one simple example you see this past may
not really work OK
i give you this core group they find in the chemical
compon database try to find something campaign the structure
so you think i for this point two longest pass was the longest part i
can get
it's carbon carbon carbon carbon get for commons of lands three
go to the database suppose these are the three databases
do get all of them
are they get what you need
OK so c
this last fall have also the stuff has four commons former team
to get everybody is more like a user might
to search mike stonebraker is basically get everybody out
OK that's not effective and efficient
it's but if you use the structure
if you use the whole structure OK they go inside if you see there is
only one answer that one you're taking up so very obviously you want to use
bigger structures rather than just the longest pass
now we give you the example
the interesting thing is
what is the structure you want to use if you want to use all the
substructures is explanation so that's the interesting thing happens is way too frequent substructure mining
that means what we really want to find the general philosophy is first identify frequent
substructure using the frequent graph might
the interesting thing another interesting thing is we say we don't want to use all
the frequent substructure is because it's is exponential
and we want to use discriminant substructures what's discriminant discriminant means it's my structure
is rather different from yours
mine would be the candidate if we have very similar
like you are not sure
that's the independent in our philosophy
so if you think about this philosophy
what if god is a originally about the whole structure is all structure can be
doing index you get millions of them they use only one to find frequent one
i can reduce the least one automatically it if i say i want to find
so this is
written in
the sense for
for the first life form organism being so these are the types of nodes in
in this structure you can see
we have
almost hundred thousand nouns spend thousands of workers twenty thousand adjectives in almost five thousand
so this would be
well type of structure which would that will be so let's see if we have
a sense for words but
and then we would be
so was
he said but so it's vital for
but are
hall could be again
you say you know he's a relationship to and then having is relationship part of
so i think is part of the boat and
i mean can be also part of airplane for instance and so on so these
are the relationships so all the senses so each node is one sentence and all
the senses are connected to it
with the edges and he'd each edge is labeled which is type of relationship
we have twenty six relationships and now if we look at a couple of them
one is hypernym
this would be his from lower to higher concepts like breakfast meal
i mean would be hypernym of
breakfast hypernym is from concept to subordinates meal lunch so just
has member so this is one of the important type of relationship so from groups
to their members faculty professor in this kind of relationship or member of
opposite was it called
from members to their groups so copilot crew
o has parts so they lack or
we saw bird bird being called same
and so the opposite course meal antonym would be opposites leader follower so
two opposite concepts and we have twenty six such relationship so
in that sense this is
quite reach reach database which is used quite often
in text analytics are mainly for this indication of text or even for so
some other tasks
OK so this would be
simple lexical relationships now we go to little bit more sophisticated ones which syntactic
representations were made stop here in this vector space model
are maybe a little bit less relevant
so vector space model is
the most popular in representation in text mining physically most of the algorithms most of
the tasks use this presentation
basically a
what's behind this vector space model so
it takes a document and transform it into sparse american actor and spice american actor
means that it's in a big vector of all possible words which can appear in
the document but its nonzero components non-zero elements of this vector
just for the words which
which actually appear in documents this would be kind of short explanation
and why is this interesting because having such representation we can use
you are
japan operation so we can do
well kind of metrics and vector operations on top of this which more or less
correspond to what text mining
in the most cases
having this kind of representation
it means that the completely forget about the linguistic structure within the text but since
the text has a lot of redundancy is a good in itself this does doesn't
just watch
so another
kind of synonym for this vector space model which is used in
text mining or information to its better first presentation because it's really back of
a difficult task would be
classification clustering visualisation and so on which seems to be
so how does look like
looks like so it's we have documented evidence simply
into vector
prices for this particular
documents because the elements listed journal appears three times and then the right number three
in front of the driver and so on this
having such a vector then we perform linear algebra operations and this works quite well
again i want to to go too much into the details here actually d and
we don't have just these numbers frequency numbers but some other numbers which we call
TFIDF which
tell a little bit more is very simple formula which
calculates this weights and is a little bit more efficient
o and
in the end we have something like this so
if this is original text original document which we get that after this
formation we get
vector like this but
some numbers which
scores and with this vector then we go in the algorithms
for learning clustering cancer
OK skip this
language more this is another representation of text which is quite popular for certain tasks
like machine translation and so on but again i was keep this so busy basically
here the whole intuition is that we are able to predict the next words from
the previous words so this is the whole the whole idea and having this
statistical models which is able to predict the next word means that we may be
able to solve certain tasks like speech recognition would be
uh would benefit out of this mess out of this statistical model or
OCR optical character recognition again handwriting recognition machine translation and spelling correction so
so this is
type of bike of approach which which is used for
modeling the text
full parsing missed another level
so the algorithms are
but we can do in polynomial time using linear programming we can also use value
iteration policy iteration which tend to be more efficient but these algorithms are polynomial time
in the number of states and actions
and that's not really
so good
unless you're domain where you can really engineer the problem to have a small number
of states so so it's nice result but
for this talk is going to be interested in the case where the states space
is exponentially large in terms of the problem encoding size so
in the real world has
very very many states and we're going to try to get algorithms that work in
the real world right so you can't apply these directly
so what can you do if you have a large world
one approach would be what are called the model based approach
there's a lot of work on this and what you do is you the final
language that can compact the bribe very large mdps now there there are several ways
you can do this but one way would be to use a dynamic bayesian network
you don't have to know the details of this or probabilistic strips to describe the
transition and reward functions so so these languages can be used to describe MDP is
it exponentially larger than their their encoding size in terms of the language
then you have to design a planning algorithm that can deal with that language in
a lot of you here know how hard that can be for example with DB
ends are probabilistic strips so of
so this is what i'm going to call the other
model based approach and there are some problems with this i don't want to kill
research in this area because it's very interesting
and useful but but one problem is if you take a random application that you
care about and try to encode it in one of these languages is always going
to be some feature of the usually an important feature that you can't quite
fit in the language and that there could be a couple of reasons for that
it could be because
problem size in the encoding will blow up for some reason to give you an
example of that in a moment or it could be there's some fundamental representational shortcomings
of these models for example you want to exaggerate his events like nine one one
calls but these languages cannot handle them nicely so
so this is the problem when you are faced with an application and there are
some planners out here that the all these languages but you can't use them because
your problem isn't described nicely in those languages so so that's where monte-carlo the monte
carlo approach comes and goes as opposed to the model based approach so so in
these cases when when you can't this
problem i
compactly in language that exists
you can often write a simulator for that domain so you can you can use
your language could be the c programming language and you could write simulator that takes
an action
interstate and spits out the next state and reward
so you can evaluate you can do this for
pretty much anything you can imagine if you spend enough time
a couple of examples if you try to encode
the simple
well seemingly simple problem of klondike solitaire
probabilistic PDDL you'll find ways i can't find a compact way to do it so
that you can use the existing planners and you could model is is is upon
DP partially observable MDP but those planners don't really scale
when we were interested in trying to solve this problem we were sort of stuff
but it is really easy to write a simulator for klondike solitaire you have a
particular situation you take an action you distill card same thing with another application i
was involved with fire and emergency response here we interested in sort of routing multiple
vehicles around town
placing them in places to be ready for emergencies in response to nine one one
calls it emerge and this is a very exciting this domain its arginase events in
terms of traffic patterns and the nine one one calls the comment hard to model
if not
what was it
andy then they can be of why
that is summerbee events you get a teaching post at the first you get the end
of at
for finding out is the question mark or something else
with probability one minus something else
and then you get the entropy
all finding out whether it's zero one given that you know that it's not a question mark
and the probability is zero or one if you know it's not a question mark this come out
it is just the same as and peay the same
ratio so the at
it should not
so that's
in any textbook as well if you want to read up front
clarify what i just told you
you can make life easy four yourself by
being smart about how compute entries so this is looking harry but it's not too
hairy when we do not way
so we have become very useful information
it is equal to
this loss which is eight
plus one minus the
you know
minus this thing
we have a grand cancellation innovator who's over s
and left woman suffrage to be not as we had before when you maximize that's the capacity
this is actually set capacity
one was at
so we found the capacity
i want to go back to this diagram everything we talk about the noisy channel coding said
let's imagine we got a noisy channel
we're going to slap clathrin coated on the front that adds redundancy
well good at the club decoder doesn't
inference to infer what the input was
how fast can we communicate and we were actually solve the noisy channel coding theorem
all this particular family answer is you can communicate at a rate
one minus with essentially zero errors
that's achievable
that's what we had introduced a completely different topic
noisy channel coding with feedback so i'm gonna changes diagram now ongoing imagine a completely different diagram
where everything that comes out the channel
gets back
and is available
the encoder
a different diagram
it's got an extra communication link
back from the end of the channel to the encoder encoder knows exactly what's going on
so if the encoder
stands for example
one zero one zero one
and what comes out the shower
i have some
question marks in one
there question mark
one question mark
what the answer to the question how fast can communicate over this channel given that
you've got feedback available to them i completely changed the game right
because the sort of encoding trick you could now uses you could just say well i'm gonna listen
my output whenever the question mark
i will retransmit the thing was just lost
because i know that they didn't receive anything
so i'll just retransmit so you wouldn't
this story can you if you had a question mark trying to send one around
what you would send would be
this is the original
and then the transmission
would be assuming that a question mark happened at these or ann bomb
what we transmit transmit
zero zero one minute friends and one again because the question what happens then you keep on going zero one
and then
think in the next one is a one
but i guess
lost is not a question mark there
say transmit again
i think that's stating words clearer one hundred on the ball
you keep on
transmitting a symbol until it is correctly received
what's the rate you're gonna be able to achieve with clever skin making use this feedback
habitat geneva
what rate can you communicate at
if you reduce the red feedback link
on average
you just imagine how much time you spend successfully communicating its whenever the wrong question
marks you've got a little bit over the channel
there's a question mark
coming out
you want achieving reliable communication at all
and the fraction of time are question marks is at
so the rate at which you're communicating using the feedback link
one minus
any questions anyone
not clear on this
this is the case i mean the discrete time domain
the discrete time
all minus two
minus one all
major undertaking the
sampling period to be one for
so i've samples at all integer times
and i act on those with this filter h which in
which is
which advises ax of zero by
h of zero
these of course we everybody says
i mean i even highlighted with yellow this fact that
we've got k two indices at this one
it's a convolution
it's time linear time invariant i could try to put all this down
this is an phi are it's also
and linear time in well i'm squeezing
facts but
there are all evident here
OK i just want to complete this
so why have zero nature
writes of zero
h one n nodes
it's going to be lower triangular
and templates
as well anticipate what's coming
on that
hmm zero
multiplies acts of and
when when k is zero agent zero mode the next event
h one multiplies x of n minus one
features are also on the main diagonal line
x of tutor give the wives to contribute to why two
but then they will be in each of one
on this diagonal
as you see that
eight one multiplying eq some minus one into y of zero
h one multiplying eq severo contributes to y one
h one x o one contribute to y two
the matrix is tough but
and we can understand
and the matrix is completely
but let's quit
that's quite well read that too
suppose suppose suppose i just have to tap agent zero
h one
let's take short
crude felt
what could be achieved
two tap filter
so so so so that felt so right now to for a while and
agent zero active and
class h one n one
x n minus one and that's all we're doing
so there's two tap
and therefore just
two diagonals in the matrix
how should we understand the action of such
convolution that is the convolution
as the convolution of something that only has two components a
was something that has
doubly infinite
but what does it do
what does it do for example let's just take examples
suppose both equal have
eight people are killed components are both
so so
so why have and
a is one half x and
and one half of x one three percent
are running average
can we just
consider that
example because it's really very useful one concern
actually look at that
its natural as
i can hardly
avoid going into the fourier in the fourier domain looking to see
because it's constant coefficients
looking to see what it does to exponentials
can i do that
well first of all what did what does it do to
zero frequency to the DCG terms suppose the input
oppose the input
it is
x all one
has DCG input
what's the output
the same thing
i'm saying this as a low pass filter because this is this is
well maybe equals zero
with no
no corruption
o making
o zero on
introduce omega properly but
zero frequency certainly corresponds to that
tell me the other extreme
what input
it would be
wiped out by this filter
alternating one input so the second input of
special interest
is that all
one minus one one minus one
that leads to y
what's the
output for that
of course that continues forever
so it doesn't spoil our duty
o why comes out as
OK and what frequency
now let's
allow that word frequency to be in the sneak in
even more
this to me is the frequency on me pi
and that's the fastest oscillation the highest frequency i can have
i fourier transforms
or also
it's also
those two are identical
in other words
i'm using the
the discrete time fourier transform
that takes
well let's just so is the discrete time
so in the frequency domain
i use capital ex
for the transform
of the input little axe
up to the end of august
and then there was this
big turns so the crossover and then the sentiment
remained negative
throughout the rest of the year
and the important thing
notice here is that
the sentiment crossover
happens actually before this
price lunch
this was like the first nice thing to see when we
plotted this chart and then we went on to computing
causality tests so basically we wanted to see whether the sentiment
helps predicting the price are the price
basically helps predicting the sentiment
the preliminary results but they are all very polluted preliminary they showed that actually the did the sentiment
would predict would help predicting the price and not vice versa
so but before r
before we all get very rich
by selling your this technology because we don't want to play with our money on the stock market
we of course need to do
some more
large scale tests
if this is true
currently what we believe is that
in some
cases this is true so we can actually
predicting the price by looking at the sentiment
about which cases these are
this is not completely clear right now
okay so i will conclude here
so what
i will just recap what i was
talking about right now so
on twitter people are definitely expressing opinions about stocks extensively right
we acquire these tweets
and we analyze the vocabulary to see whether it's positive or negative
and then we can display the results along the timeline
and observe sentiment trends through time
and yet our preliminary because all the tests are
that's it
thank you for your attention
i just wanted to understand whether this platform
is aimed is being rolled out on various languages because you're saying that you only taking into account in english
which is certainly the most spoken in this but most spoken language in the world
but i planning to include also let's say spanish are offered in french or german
yeah the technology that we are currently using is based on statistics
and statistics with this kind of methods how it helps to have
a lot of data right
when we
go far uist stocks and for english we kind of get
quite a lot of data
which is not the case
if we go for some other markets
i would expect debt we wouldn't
this so successful
researching this week with other markets but it's definitely something that we could try
because in the end the technology that we employ is
quite language independent so it's not a problem to process spanish-language are italian language and
it's not a problem the problem is just in the amount of data
end having
something that we call the training set the training base which means a lot of tweets
in a particular language
already in manually are somehow
incredibly labelled as positive and negative
so for english we have all these things
use technology like these
flow to me should stay in opinion of the obvious social community about the company
doing needed to have somebody in a company in my company
to teach
the technology about slayings
and the
how we humans
uses all humans communicate
the short toward the
want to uh
for this
i think in this particular case that the technology that was
employed here
it is based on machine learning
which means that you don't need somebody to more
the vocabulary or are
you know the
binomial distribution around you
very good
if you look at the binomial distribution
andits it's got me
all end times he where he hear is at
at its covariance event q
here is other thing is one minus
all right so you can look at and then you know what variance means
how they relate to well roughly plus and minus you know thousands of minus what
so this is the mean it's ten thousand five point one two thousand
the variances nine hundred
but what does that mean the meaning and the variance is the square of the standard deviation
so this is
the square and the standard deviation
you take the square root of it
which is
the tree
and tells you roughly how many bits in the way
you reflect okay
now the binomial distribution is pretty much the only bidder mathematics you need to know
for this course and i do encourage you to
review the binomial distribution and get good at working with it because we are going to use it
over and over
this topic in other topics in information theory as well
so we have an answer
thousand plus and minus thirty
thanks to
mister binomially and inter
the distribution that that's his name
we've got this drive
we launched the company
are we going have a happy customer and reseller the first
this right
any opinions
know why
it is slightly too many flips isn't it
if someone storing important information
so the question take
you have a salable described
very little
one giga bytes
this right
if it were disk-drive
this a binary symmetric channel how small would have to be for you to be
able to make a successful business
how small
the flip probability
to be
these into neighbour
and have a chat about this question
answers has all they need your after have a salable this drive
a viable company
ten to minus thirty
another answers
and the minus five
that's true
many people
need twenty about despite these lecture notes are about three years old so
put a little star had to say
independent things like this
you you can test whether this is true right so given the graph on the
the exponentially many
of these kinds of independence statements through
the the the the the the the semantics of the graph right so we did
a prose kind of
the first to do is establish these
very strong correspondences between
writing these kind of statements their equations
and what do they mean in terms of graphs and what is the crisp on
between statements and graphs
OK so we're going to get too deep into that but i would want to
undirected graphical models which i call them arrives early in the talk
they are the the undirected can because the way they define distributions is not true
conditional probabilities but was called
potential functions so let's
i worry about the same set of variables alarm burglars earthquakes
now we want to define say the same kind of distribution over these five variables
it turns out we can define you know
for any business we can define a distribution
well something very similar in this network using this this this kind of presentation so
instead of these kinds of tables we just
factors that called or potentials that specify a nonnegative values
for each
you know the assignment of the variables came here
for each possible
joint defended this
normalisation factor make sure that this whole thing sums to one
just the some or all the variables of the product
it is called partition function normalisation function a other things and
this is the thing that's actually hard right to this one of major difference between
business and market networks is in a basin that if somebody asked what's the probability
of this observation and it gives you all
say a five
values i just look at our multiplied together number
if you think question mark network it's much harder question because you don't know
this one risi i mean you can look at this part
but one was is the hard part
and for some classes of graphical models we can do this efficiently we can compute
this ze efficiently so
now used to
used to do nasty a
roughly something like this in hmm
when things become grids
i've been doing vision
the partition function
intractable so even if we had just very simple connections the graph is this thing
this right it turns out that
coupling the partition function is intractable
OK so
that the potentials do not mean the same thing as
conditional distributions which right so there
in some ways harder to interpret in harder to get from people right there are
sort of these kind of compatibility functions you can think of a fair
if there over several variables the number for each of those things is that the
sum to anything it's kind of hard to interpret and people are very good at
interpreting conditional probabilities when they have to do with causal causes and effects right what's
probability of me having already knows if i have the flu
actually it's much harder to say the other way around what's the probability of of
flu right
because you need to
you need to incorporate other possible
explanations for conservatives
right so so
the prose interpretation of each local factor is not there for us
but it is actually much more flexibility and it's used in
for example in models and it's very hard to try to find some kind of
conditional distributions and the great right to do
pixels of whatever it's very hard to make it directed in the direction of the
that you still have the same
so that's why
one the framework is very convenient and
in a way
you don't lose anything by making these assumptions because you get the same results if
you don't make it
so that's why it's it's fine to keep working in this setting
of course it would be nice to understand their
and that's not
the case of the moment to understand better the relationship between the idea sitting in
this setting
OK now back to the bounds
that real things
one thing is that
it's all of the case that these bounds are
very far
the actual error that we make
so if you compute these quantities
i mean one function is
it won't be too bad and that's what i shown you with this curve these
bernoulli distribution and you have the the bound it's OK it's not very close but
it's not too far
now when you introduce these
covering numbers or all these geometric quantities than the bound become very big very fast
and often they go
much higher than one so may often
the bound your thing when you put here the covering numbers
four you set of functions
if you set the function is not
completely simple
then the bot will be much larger than one engine
whereas this
you know
it is less than one
it's a bit annoying to have completely trivial bound in the sense that it it
doesn't tell you anything
well it's still tell you something because it tells you that with enough data
the band goes to zero so that's already
not too bad but for any reasonable sample size the bound will be
maybe a hundred
so OK
together so the point is
in the course of the writing these bounds we have done something non-trivial
and what was nontrivial was not
the holding or been bernstein party it's the geometric sink
so how to use
these bounds so if if value
is non sense
what can we do with it so here i am i mean there are other
ways to use but i give you here three
i call that's three levels of the of using the bounds
one is the quantitative level which is what i just said using it to estimate
the error
and it's not possible because most often
at least so far the bonds that exist so far
are very large and do not give you any meaningful information about what is really
there that you make the second
level is to use them
to do model selection
so you don't care about the value you care only about the relative value so
you compare to algorithms you compute the bound for one algorithm and the bound for
another reason
and if one is smaller than the other even if they are one hundred and
two hundred you would still prefer
the one that is one hundred
and the last one is
not to worry at all about the values that your thing when you compute these
bounds but rather try to understand
what you can do with this geometry
so kids of the first level
as i said
the problem is these are
a a little bit messy mathematics right binomial there is there are not very easy
to control or two
to get a nice expressions of of it these geometry
again it's hard to really capture well and there was also this problem that we
have the supremum but most often the the algorithm does not that been the supreme
so all these reason make the bounds not very short
and if we want to have
better bounds it was we would have
expressions that cannot be computed or that complete that are completely unreadable so
there is no point in trying to use the value of the bond directly and
the best
mister use cross validation if you really want to estimate the air
a guys
now for the second level so
doing model selection
the only thing you need to know what is that
the minimum of the bound
it is located at the right place
if you have an algorithm that depends on the song parameter c alpha
and you compute the bound that
correspond to each value of this parameter and you get something like this
even if this
is c one hundred whereas the so that's the bound
and the jury something like
like this
where this is at most one even if you have such a picture
what matters is that the minimum here is smallest at the same place as the
minimum here
and that's that would be fine if you if you get this kind of behavior
for you about
you perfectly happy because you can select
you're parameter alpha
from the bone itself and you don't need extra validation
but OK
i would say in general
it doesn't work that's nicely
so again
i would recommend not to use it
so then comes the last
the last hope for you making and use of these bounds which is the quantitative
and again it's very
difficult to actually make use of it because you can very easily make very easily
misled but by what you think
OK so the goal is somehow to use what's
appears in the bound
to get in spirit inspiration for making new algorithm or for modifying your i mean
the way such that it
performs better
but in general it won't give you
the optimal value for the alpha was things like this
it will only
somehow tell you
how the
OK where the complexity comes from or where
is it that your class of function
miss may overfit
why is it that your cluster function may overfit and it will explain
this in terms of what is the relevance structure of this class that
it controls the complexity and the overfitting behaviour so for example
if you take
function class that does that is parametrized by center number of parameter you would say
well let's not use too many parameters because maybe it becomes too complex and i
i might overfit but then when you compute
these geometry quantities for this
function class it may very well up on that
after some number of parameters the complexity does not grow very much if you add
someone got behind will alter hit a metal pipe
strong pi allowed set
a little over began to associate
that sounds like noise with the appearance of
the white rabbit
well white rat is not even fear
but what about the sound from the part that scary
yes a lot all this part of natural for a very long was there was
allowed and that room all of this would be great of which only somewhere here
in that district
however as well
and so the the
exposure to this once
produced a few reactions our because it coincided with the appearance of the white rat
that studio substitution
i began to her and so the experience of a rat
began to
you both that the response in the lower so we just like to how what
happiness to the substitution three so that you take away the
take away a lot of noise
three the white rat
what happens
we started
you can start your brain
because john watts
has shown
that he and producer
an emotional reaction conditions little baby
two theory
or be delighted any object that we wish
to history ability
we've talked about stimulus generalization wasn't simply white rat produced reaction by
watson found the
fear generalize to other
so stimuli such as
rabbi dog for club for
in the same cluster that if you see in that video
john what his beer
five if you're thinking about same one
i see
he has appeared on the scene allow this
really afraid
is acquired
here the prior to both
like that
in two that with the part
and the possible for just the second series
questions have come to rest
during world
the in cident so you know said yes so that's the case
exactly right so the question is is this a case stimulus generalization it is because
he was condition with white rat in that
conditioning generalize to
objects that in some way or similar to what they white wine
so same the reaction
was generated
we it our
OK so that's why
watson was simply interested in
making these from
i mean my life
he was interested also in the in the philosophical importance of what he was doing
to him the experimental album said something
you know what i said was that
really human beings are
pretty mountain
to produce
when we try to understand ourselves in
why we are where we are personalities
our behavior our emotions and so on
we often wonder you know is
is our biology articles
has our experience for us
to be who we are
or the way we talk about that
the phone content is provided by MIT opencourseware under a creative commons license
additional information about relations and MIT opencourseware in general is available OCW MIT you
last time we were talking about the valence bond model for describing the bonding in
particular the binding
between the atoms in the polyatomic molecules
and we saw that the key
after this description
was allowing the
i wavefunctions individual wavefunctions
and after
two constructively
interfere themselves
form some hybrid wave functions or some hybrid orbitals
and then it goes hybrid wave functions
that overlap with the wave functions of another atom to form a chemical bond
and in particular what we treated last time
is this at e three
wave functions
there were centered on carbon
percent nitrogen that was centered on oxygen
and we saw that
he says the three functions for this linear combination or this destructive and constructive between
the best way function
and the three
two the wave functions form these as the three functions correspondingly these as three states
and as i said we saw the carbon we saw the nitrogen so that are
and those with functions
and being appointed
to the corner to the vertex of the factor graph worthy at all
i was at the centre that that would drawn so in the case of nothing
you find the hydrogen to each one of those
sp three hybrid wavefunctions what you get is
a tetrahedral geometry around the harbour
if you hear nitrogen
where does
as the freeway functions around new find to three hydrogens
and you've got trick and all
pyramid and the geometry of the ammonia molecule with those two long hair sticking out
at the end another per vertex of the factor in front but remember we talked
about the shape of the molecule
it has being described by the positions of the atoms and not the positions of
and we talked about water water sp three hybridized
we have two hydrogens to what we want to find the plane then
and then we have two long here electron sticking out of the oxygen those going
to play a big role
in some binding we're going to look at the end of the lecture today
right so
we've got to move on and we got to talking about another kind of hybridization
which we started to talk about their time which is the s
two hybridisation we talked about for i
and we saw the PSP two
and being in the plane
which in the case of four we then bonded hydrogen to those at two wavefunctions
functions we got plane molecule or on h three
carbon can also undergo
there is sp two hybridization
so let's take a look at it now
right so i
in the case of carbon we have to do this electron promotion that we talked
about also in the case of the sp three hybridization
and then we let now
one of the two s wave functions in two of the two p wave functions
hybridize constructively in
destructively interfere
and the result is three
the two wavefunctions or three SP two stay
one electron in each one of them
and then
one of those p orbitals are those p wave functions and the carbon is sometimes
that's just the atomic wave function the atomic orbital on carbon
and if we if we look at the
picture of all of those wavefunctions functions here it is
this is the two as on the current easy to see why
what we do is we let these three for example
these three constructively and destructively interfere to form these three sp two hybrid orbitals
or hybrid functions
the result is that they look like this
the result is they all have
a large positive
and then to the constructive interference
and they all have a small negative role
and all the rest of the pictures that we're going to draw we're not going
to draw that small negative or is it just makes it hard to draw
but the bottom line is that these three low-flying plane
and then of course we still have that PY atomic wavefunctions centered on the carbon
that is designed for
right now i'm going to do
i'm going to put all of these three wave function and
same plant
since they all have the same origin
so on
that's what i'm doing right there
here it is for the carbon
it's clear that the brain uses unlabeled data in quite quite effective
well we
with things that effective in any case
OK so
now what does this have to do is john
there are two assumptions which can be made
which one of them is completely in line
what we discussed in the other one is
quite a bit
in line with maybe
more broadly of the manifold as having a geometric structure in the data so the
manifold assumption basically if as
for data
so it comes
from the manifold
and the distance along the manifold is the natural
a measure of how close
the point
i'll i'll discuss and the cluster assumption is basically saying that there are some clusters
in the data in
arguably the clusters also geometric objects
let's look at the intuition though if i just give you two to label point
this is read by the way it's not a black ink
looks black but we know that red doesn't exist
so there is red points and there is
the point
this still a labelled points right if we just have those two points
that presumably
the natural way would be to
i have the bound which is like this
most of us would agree probably now here's the question well if i have already
pointed out well this is not the black point is are at points and the
blue point here but i tell you well all my data leaves on the manifold
which is a union of two circles which is a one-dimensional manifold
well bound doesn't seem natural anymore
something like this seems far better
so basically
what does it say there's a the geometry of the data changes our notion of
you know where the boundary should be at which point similar from our think before
we thought that basically it's all based on the distance in the euclidean space
the only thing that basically are all based on the fact that this
two circles
i have well effectively clusters right this is classed the middle
class there is a small circle and the fact that there are two connected component
if you wish
here is is something similar but in a slightly different set
so you have to read point black point and blue points
and there is an unknown point of this is the question mark point OK
this is really an anti-communist
that bad
it's so
how would you classify this point well if you don't have any information radio classifier
is blue
presumably well it's kind of cool to to the blue points and if you have
a linear separator is probably somewhere like in the middle between those reported to the
blue points out if i tell you about all the data lies on this manifold
suddenly it seems more natural to classify this point as belonging to one of those
two points right
the point here
probably one of those because this is the proximity on the manifold that itself so
we kind of saying that the proximity on the manifold probably gives us about the
idea that the euclidean proximity so euclidean proximity would be the distance between this point
and this is clearly the smallest distance but somehow breaking
so the outer space doesn't seem to be the right thing to do and this
is the intuition that may be completely wrong it may actually be that this is
the correct thing to do in this curve is completely irrelevant we don't know this
this the
this event both intuition and to some degree an empirical fact
that this actually is the right thing to do to go along the
OK so the sort of implies that this is an empirical fact this is
what you do if you just used so
imagine i have
digits the ones i showed you and they live in the seven hundred basically each
picture has seven hundred something pixels
and really when this several hundred dimensional space now i can do two things
i can feel the classifier so i have a bunch of labelled examples
like if i get maybe thirty for each pixel and i just think the nearest
for new point four new in which i just think the nearest distance is based
on the pixels represents and
i look
then cheque whether this distance is you know what is the class of the point
which is closest to that point
so if it's a seven labelled this seven right nearest neighbour classifier is a simple
one of the simplest possible classifiers
that's one thing that alternative to that is the geodesic nearest neighbours when i take
a bunch unlabeled points
i construct the graph
and i look for the shortest distance on this graph
so i constructed graph using my unlabelled data for the first one nearest neighbour only
uses labelled data the second one on the users
uses both labeled and unlabeled so the second basically tells me that well instead of
looking for distances and the euclidean space we will look for distances on the ground
well what happens
it turns out that if you do this basically use unlabelled data to construct a
better notion of distance
the error rate so misclassification rate goes down
quite significantly
not quite effective tool but
close to that
so by just incorporating this unlabelled data into the equation
you can sometimes get a lot of improvement and
in classifier and
and if i said so i i be
so this constraint is essentially saying that everything is correctly classified in fact this right
hand side is equal to zero that means every point was correctly classified if it
is equal to one that means every point is correctly classified this margin one
and so i the slack variables where you don't want every single point to be
correctly classified with this margin
OK so that's i i is actually exactly the hinge loss
measured at every data point x i
then one can show
that the optimal solution w star for this
well actually have an expansion in terms of the data points exercise
summation and phi x i
there are many ways to see this
we will see this using the property of reproducing kernel hilbert spaces and using the
so-called represented here
so then you can go to what is called the dual setting where you see
the w star does this thing replace this over there and you have this whole
entire optimisation in terms of alpha first and then solve the optimisation of around us
is actually a good point
say something
minimum norm
so what you are trying to do with support vector machines is actually minimize the
norm of the function www
this last
the of the blue
so this corresponds directly more or less
regularized least squares
where we have replaced the least squares loss by the hinge loss
is that a correspondence to the minimum norm solution
you might ask
this is how the standard development of support vector machines goals
the problem is that you have a bunch of data points like this
you are data points
and some of them are labeled plus some of them are labeled minus
and you want to come up with a linear classifier that separates the data right
support such a linear classifier exists that means there is w which would correctly classify
all your data points correctly
obviously if there is one w there are many w because you can move the
w just a little bit and you would still get correct classification
so then you can solve the following problem minimize
doctor w
subject to
why i times
w dot x i
plus b
greater than or equal to one
this is often called
this thing is often called
the support vector machine for the separable case
OK so you say
as assume have a finite number of data points and assume these data points are
separable i want to find the linear classifier that separates my data there are too
many linear classifiers separate my data
the solution space is not unique because doesn't have a single element
and so let me take the minimum norm solution
so let me minimize www subject to these constraints
particular problem seems to have a geometric
interpretation in terms of something called the margins
the margin being the distance
each w which is a candidate classifier the distance to the nearest point
so in some sense this is really like taking the minimum norm solution
you again in the usual setting in our and if you do that points live
in rk
you know that very soon
well not be achievable
because data points going to be linearly separable if you have lots of data point
so is this feasible set will become empty very soon
and so
what people suggested for example that makes that them that's what a slack variable xi
and this i i
so that
if this is you know that means the point is correctly classified as this is
nonzero the point may be misclassified as so trying to minimise this surprise trying to
minimize the number of classification
and this is of course to the north
if you look at the presentation in many places the way this is justified
is the following
they were first tell you
the right thing to do
use the maximum margin classifier
if data is separable
it's a well defined problem there the maximum margin classifier which corresponds to the minimum
norm solution
but we live in a world where data may not be separable or at least
linearly separable so let's do something about it let's add slack variables and converted into
this problem this seems
and this is the algorithm that then gets used
now what is pathological
this is a lecture five in linear algebra
it will complete
this chapter of the book
so the last section of this chapter is two point seven
talks about permutations
which finished
the previous lecture
and transposase which also came in the previous lecture
there's a little more to do with those guys
permutations and transposase
but then the heart of the lecture will be
the beginning of what you could say is the beginning of linear algebra
the beginning of real linear algebra which is
seeing a bigger picture with vector spaces not just vectors but the basis vectors
and subspaces of those spaces
so we're
a little ahead of the syllabus
which is good because we're coming to the place where
there's a lot to do
to begin with permutation
can i just
so the permutations
the matrices b
and they execute
croix state
we may need them we may have a perfectly good matrix of perfect matrix a
that is invertible that we can solve a x equal b
but to do it
i've got
to allow myself that extra freedom that ever zero shows up in the pivot position
i move it away
i get a non zero
i get a proper pivot there
exchanging from the row below
and you've seen that already
and i just want to collect the ideas together
and in in
principle i could even have have to do that two times or more times
so i have to allow
to complete the
the theory
the possibility that i take my matrix a
i start elimination i find out that i need ro exchanges
and i do it and continue i finish
i want to do is say
and i will make a big project out of this
what happens to a parallel u
so a typical value
l u
this was
matrix al with ones on the diagonal and zeros above and
multipliers below and this we you know we know
with zero down here
that's only possible that that description of elimination assumes that we don't have p
we don't have any rho exchange
and now
i just want to say OK
how to account for o exchanges because that does
the p
in this
factorisation is the identity matrix
the rows are in good order we left them there
maybe i just add a little moment of
reality two
how matlab actually does elimination
matlab not only checks whether that payment is not zero as has every human would
it checks for is that big enough because it doesn't like very very small payments
events close to zero are
numerically bad
so actually if we ask matlab to solve the system it will do some elimination
some some rho exchanges
which we don't think it's necessary algebra doesn't say the necessary but
numerical accuracy says they are
well we're doing algebra
here we will say well what would
what the row exchanges do but we won't do them unless we have to
but we may have to
and there
the result is
it's hiding here
it's the
the main factor
this is the description of elimination with rho exchanges
so a equal value becomes
this act so that p is a matrix that does the row exchanges and actually
it does them
it gets the rose into the right order
in the good order where payments will not
one zero one appear in the pivot position where l
and you
we'll come out right as as a appear
so that's the that's the point
actually i don't want to labour the point
a permutation matrix
a is just ordered
which is very nice and traditionally the relations are specified in advance for us they
discovered automatically and that results in the output traditionally is relation specific whereas stress the
output is a relation independent
so textrunner which we actually unveiled back in its k seven is the first one
was the first web scale open a system by now it's extracted easily over a
billion distinct extractions at its peak it achieves about point nine precision which is quite
good but that's very low levels of recall
it definitely has a challenge in terms of recall and then when you when you're
dealing with the web you might allow us
some latitude in saying OK i didn't extracted from this sentence at this page how
about getting it from the next page
right so
but that is one of the trade offs in in text so how does textrunner
work well it uses fairly simple heuristics to identify
what the
proper nouns are what the entities are in the sentence the really hard part and
the real innovation is how do we get the
relation and so if we have tim berners-lee and the web
and we have a number of intervening words the the question is which of those
denote the relation is that the entire set of words is just the verb invented
and how do we do this in general right that's that's the technical question here
how do we figure out what the relation is and the mechanism textrunner use actually
was original paper use naivebayes but more recently we've shifted to
using a conditional random field CRF the basic idea is to view this problem as
a sequence labeling task we go
we start with the entity on the left in berners-lee and then we go word
by word in this era tells us OK this word is not part of the
relation this one is not this one is not the relation starts here
and then ends with the second entity so
this the CRF is learned and general
relation independent level and the reason this works is because it turns out that our
are relation independent close to tell us how people express relations in english
so this is what the system looks like we actually used distant supervision techniques i
won't go into that to automatically generate a hundred and eighty thousand training examples we
fed those to the CRF it learns an extractor and then we feed into web
corpus it produces it uses rather the learned model of relations that avoids any specific
nouns or verbs and that outputs a set of rock samples of this form
we then count the topples identify synonyms and index that output in lucene which in
turn allows us to do a set of of relational queries and i'll show you
a demo in a few minutes i just want to tell you first about what
happened after we came up with with textrunner
well first of all we we're excited that the system worked at all but it
certainly had plenty of errors so let me talk about two types of extraction errors
the first one is let's say we encounter the sentence al gore invented the internet
textrunner happily extract invented al gore internet and so we call this a sound correction
of a sound extraction rather of an incorrect facts right garbage in garbage out there's
a lot of incorrect information over on the web in textrunner happily extracts these incorrect
facts or or opinions
another kind of error that we see is actually an unsound extractions of if the
sentence is the cost of the war against iraq has risen above five hundred dollars
there i five hundred billion dollars five hundred trillion dollars then above the iraq five
hundred billion dollars is is really not sound extraction and our work is focused on
unsound extractions of this challenge is interesting as well
how do you filter unsound extractions one of the key idea is that we used
which is the one i want to highlight is using redundancy
over a massive corpus like the web it turns out that the more redundancy you
the more distinct clues you're able to find like barcelona mayor and downtown barcelona the
more distinct clues i have it's effectively like co training right i'm getting clues from
different angles leading me to be more and more confident than in fact extraction is
is sound and the other thing we can do is we can look at the
proportion of clues are among the mentions of the word so we can ask what
fraction of the times that i've seen barcelona say do i see clues that suggest
not to wild oats
it is a means of separating the data points to clusters which might be still
in and overlapping here
perfect is i mean in the ideal case it is perfectly if separated in this
part here it's simply means to
improve are
to work out the structure of the clustering structure but it's it's not i mean
could see how this
works in the next slides but it's not obvious
one thing which i already mentioned here we will see that later on
more closely is that in this case like the example we had it contains three
very clear clusters
now plot the i values of here
of the graph laplacian what will happen is so what plot here is that you
have hundred data points probably so and so
my matrix contains one hundred i values
that all of them next to each other
so what we see
you probably can see very low but
it is in fact he what he sees we have three i can which are
very very close to zero
there's a huge gap and then they are all the other ones
actually one can use that
at least in theory to predict the number of clusters so you you just look
at the i values and show look at how many small line happened and we
have gap and then it's OK mister clusters but that's just
i mean people do it but it doesn't work that way well
OK so i try to before the break just try to get the first interpretation
by spectral clustering works
that's my favorite one actually there are spectral clustering it's actually not new i mean
people have done it
already in the model in the seventies actually but nobody really noticed it and it
became really very
well spread like many people use it seems like two thousand one two thousand two
there not to have lots of papers but it is it's nothing new so there
are very many different ways of could derive
why spectral clustering works but i think this is the what the one
which i find most interesting
that's the we have all the data graph
we set clustering is something which
make sure the points which are in the same cluster similar to each other
points which are in different clusters are not so similar to each other
OK we need to i mean if you want to to
seven other to do that is someone to do or the easiest way is to
derive a mathematical criterion
which tells you
but you can optimize i mean
OK that's what people usually
so the idea of what spectral clustering
or what you want to look at this we say OK what we want is
we forget about the this within clusters we just look at distances between clusters and
we say
we want that
two clusters of things where the connections between the two clusters are very powerful and
very low weight
so we want to and then we define the things we say
the cut between two groups of points a and b
it's just so we sum over the points in the different clusters are similarities so
we say we define what the cut between those two groups this is actually a
the sum of this in the search
like the weights of those two images
it was a great we already done we minimize cut we
we have an objective criteria we use it for clustering
OK and actually for
i mean for minimising cut it can even be done in more or less efficient
way it's surprisingly not NP hard but it's there's this min cut max flow theorem
many maybe some people know it so you can really do that
but now there's a problem
and this problem is
shows up if you look at this
the vertex here so what happens very often is
you have one out there that point
and then you just to minimize cut and say OK great if i want to
have to tools in this graph just cut here
because you just cut one that interest to cut two inches
the problem is not of course that this is not what you wanted clustering so
i mean somehow we
we don't want to identify outliers i mean that's sounds something would like to do
but that's not what we want to do we want to find
groups in the data and those groups should be more or less reasonable size
and that's why people came up with different objective functions which try to incorporate the
size of the state of the different clusters
and essentially there are two different ways
which are two something very similar so ratiocut what it does
we say OK so in general what we do is we want to define a
balanced cut that is
we say we
we have two objectives we want to minimize the cut but we also want to
make sure that the rules are more or less
if the same size
that's ratiocut that's so
so we're going to minimize later on so
we have term which incorporates cut
but have also
which incorporates the
the balance between the two clusters
and what's actually going on there
it's very simple to see
so this term
one over a
one the so remember the absolute value of a is just the number of points
the number of vertices in a if know
so just look like negative charges of we say for example a and b if
they are both
the same size
and this term will be just one or
and half plus one and half years
four over and
which is pretty small if ten is large then if we have another case for
example is an outlier and just contains one point
and the content the other and minus one point we have something like one of
one plus one or
and minus one
which is which is i mean roughly one so here we have something in the
order of one or and here we have something in the order of one so
it shows that if you manage to
get hoops smallest having the ecosystem this term will be much smaller
so that's so now what we do is we just take the product of those
two terms
it's a pretty arbitrary way of doing it but
that's how we start
there's another way of doing it so that's called ratiocut this is called normalized cuts
so very something instead of taking the number of points and it's will you take
the volume which was the way to each school
but with the same reasons
so how
and are
a bit OK i mean that's where we're going to talk about that so that's
the problem of course i mean aim
OK so so far we just define our objective function now we want to minimize
the course it's very difficult problem that's exactly the point so we can just look