not use your brain and just use the computer
gives you much work this
so what you can do is you can just pick a random pair x and
x prime from the training data
look at the distribution of the squared distances
and i think the point one point five point nine one
you pick those as values to sigma square
the knowledge that produce the problem of
finding the right kind with the one of choosing among maybe three different kernel with
they're all going to be in the right order of magnitude
at least for my experiment so far i've seen that
this never performed significantly worse than really
during the optimal value
so therefore it immediately end up
with a SVM classifier
we get the kernel with right we get the scale right
consider well fiddling around with c
and you get something that will work fairly recently spread out of the box without
being too much validation
and you can see the incredible exactly
to make it
i think it's a good time out
basically question then break and will break for ten minutes and i'm supposed to tell
you that you're not supposed to be at the of
OK a question
but how that will reconvene at twelve thirty
i failed and it's just me but but
this is going to be
a little bit more
challenging in terms of mass
and also contains a bit more challenging
what people here now is also going to help you
four other pictures that may have a graphical models
and during this week next week
it's going to be useful
but what we will do is now take a sharp deviation from what you might
have seen until now namely essentially problems of regression and classification
which deal with very simple scalar values
random variables
and this is something that happened over
over the past five years
and that's i think we're at the moment the most exciting part is the current
at some point
given that i probably don't have enough time to recover both have to ask you
what you prefer namely
the prefer
the page ranking for sequence annotation
OK well i can
talk about twice as fast
and you will probably understand very little of all other but prefers web pages
and like sequence annotation that being well basically i have some binary sequence i want
annotated with certain properties of prince's nineteen tagging about that
now none the wiser was i think the numbers are about even
well let's see
maybe i'll briefly cover the sequence then look at the web pages
are not
without the first though i look at multiple
the reason for that being that actually these are the things we fancy version of
the multiclass
but what the best all love know well you should be able full graph
optimal separating hyperplane
i'm just going to nominate it looks breakfast out of the multiclass condition
so what i'm going to do is i'm going to say
well remember what we had one being one
i have i can also imposed a condition that looks as follows excited of w
it's great for a then one but it i thought one of the right
why markets what i can do the same thing
up after bit
but what i can actually do is i can say well this is an instance
of multiclass classification problem
if i know one thing here
the these are called
so what do we get
in the perspective
so on this
can be visualized like this
in the matrix times
cross channel and then you will see very nice well the differences
in time
and how they are distributed in
across the channel
then we can
so he had to manually but of course you can also have some some algorithms
to make sure
based on the matrix
appropriate interval
here which was done manually
these in
these values and when value for each gender
it shows these various
so let see here
differences for this
bishop p one component thank you for the
visual and one
p three component
so this
gives an
idea what individuals are good too
OK and so this is that for first first step is is just to use
one with purely for
special features features one way each each end
and if we train on such features
classifiers the nice thing is that
this classifier
is the spatial filters
so we have a a for example is a linear classifier training on purely spatial
we get a bit vector
that is
and the length of the
it became clear to pick up for this
so maybe
just about anything
OK so this is not very very important that because the classifier that that was
trained on this purely spatial features is spatial filtering so you can apply it to
the EEG signal
and then the the weights to different channels and we get
filtered signals that
emphasizes the difference between
the conditions and the nice thing is that we can visualize this filters as the
so there
the classifiers to theatre is one
great value for each channel so we can
displayed is a map and c
what is machine learning and and that learn from from the data and what's the
discrimination is based on
so in this case for the p three hundred component spatial filters if focused centrally
recipes round has evolved and tests
also as weights
and if if we use this
simple classification of separately for for each interval of components that we
detect again this interesting components we get the following error rate this is indicated here
before each component we get different error rate
ranging from o
twelve two
here we already see that
visual components
good for discrimination you
but also this
give some contributions
so and then of course we will not
to stop here we want to integrate this
information from
different temporal intervals so the next step is that we
extract spatiotemporal features
and that's again very
very simple it's just the same as before but now we do it for different
interviews so we have different intervals self-interest
the calculate in each gender
the average value in each of these intervals
and now we get to the
long feature vector in large feature vector
because we get
not only one value for each gender but as many as we have the
so we can
those features
map of the
as a matter of
series of scott
o we cannot allow us to think of it as a as matrix of course
so we have to two dimensions
shannon space and
so but
then these features
already quite high dimensional space here
fifty nine EEG channels in example seven time in terms of interest
dimensionality is fun searching
now it
this is a before and now i added classification
ordinary LDA on the spatial temporal features
and so this is of course
disappointing for years they resided
twenty five percent so it's was
the best thing into
so we
and all the information together
on this concatenated feature vectors classification because
became worse so
i think most of you know what the problem is that if you have a
high dimensional data and some some overfitting
i don't have enough training centers
the good singing
in this situation is that it's not
overfitting on miss estimation but this systematic bias and that one can do something about
and so therefore
we need some formulas these linear classifiers based on the estimation of the mean and
so we have
so here we assume that we have some vectors drawn from a gaussian distribution
and in classification we need to estimate the mean
and the covariance
and and he says
basic formulas to estimate mean and covariance
and the observation is that if we have a high dimensional data not
so many samples then this is a systematic bias in their
the empirical covariance matrix and the system that because of the large i value
of the estimated
the range too large and small i'm not too small
so this is misinformation and then of course it a
which is
simply this formula the difference of the mean
weighted by the inverse covariance matrix
it's not
very good
this covariance matrix is badly estimated
so what does this mean
i can value
so this is
cut to one we have
data distribution of the data were generated talk
some distribution on the true distribution is indicated by the black ellipsoid
and we could draw some samples from the distribution is as shown in blue
and from based on this template
the empirical covariance matrix is calculated and
this is the structure like the red the sort
i value
of the latter diagnosis
disconnected body that's your like very far away articles
given the sensitivity
we found these things to be quite stable actually because once you're
because the way we are doing it is some kind of sequential greedy way
we find sort of go we we use the same node multiple times so that
are actually not so many competitors so there are not too many different places
and because you are just asking sort of
we keep high degree connected nodes speaking and then you do many bands go through
them or they just go separately and that doesn't mean that there are multiple separate
that's because there is just one pattern
they don't make much difference in the in the graph itself
this work
good so
i think we can find elements of machine learning
here for like fitting estimation right
i think
he so
here the difference is that instead of comparing statistics you you can call you are
now comparing likelihoods so it's again sort of
initial statistic
so yeah i would say i would say most here
may be here but this is more like application
i would say that works
if i have to
a show
it's similarly minds
would like send you you know this is the state so they have this sort
of time points when they and it's not time it's more like
what level
a lot of this is a
that's good
even though
it's very different it's like many different networks right so now we say that we
don't see as the network gets larger so we say as the same editor gets
larger diameter gets more but you don't say
you know they can any network of hundred nodes and now take some of the
network of ten million nodes that one of ten million times smaller than the
one of the four hundred
so i think we are talking about two different networks
of course who talks to whom and writing messenger for example what is even surprising
maybe like we have because in africa writing in in
after africa or you know like you see people using internet like the coast of
africa central africa is missing so you like the question is how well does this
six point six correspond to real world because in one sense you could say oh
you have these holes in africa so we have to go around that the concept
of getting through
so you could say you know i mean that i would like to find reasons
both for the same in the real world there should be a bit higher singular
which should be a bit long but i think what is interesting is that you
know taking four million times more data like six orders of magnitude more data
u q
around them
it is
sure that was that was debated but they were using different measure right i mean
the question is whether you blocked what kind of measure plot there and how do
you find out how do find it and the depression is also home getting from
your plastic quite right and the difference that was also that i think that it
was done by bisection here we're not cutting away using realistic the full network and
say the best part of the size and i don't think the full network and
so was the best part of this so we never got anything going
because that was made this so we be sections so it's not clear whether small
pieces where do they come from whether they come from because the when you do
that half
o point guard
like artificially creating this more pieces because you're cutting some dancing to me
and and region and its grounds for sure
maybe i
i mean we should do they can definitely good good it's about tries
a desirable way so for example if we have some kind of statistical significance more
significant pattern is maybe that's what you want to keep them less significant once you
can you can throw them away
but it is in these contrast could be a huge number
you know they could you know potentially they can be
exponential in terms of
the features
so for example how we can use contrast data mining so for example we can
in domain understanding so for example let's say
in a medical context one could say young children with diabetes
have a greater risk of hospital admission
compared to the rest of the population
so this could be
just an observation that say you take all the datasets from children
you know and then if you find the ones who
generally come to the hospital more often
could be the one from
i don't like diabetes
so therefore you conclude that
if the child is that the take the chance of the child to come to
the hospital is much higher compared to a child who is
and of course it could be much more
nine of sophisticated than those kinds of simple rules
they could be used for building classifiers so for example if you do this contrast
they're like like like some kind of fingerprints so if you see
these these signatures several times then you can easily said that i get this
object has all these patterns that i've seen that belong to to this particular class
and therefore there's a good chance that it belongs to
so i'm going to cover several examples how to build
robert classifiers using these techniques
and we also
showed that
you can also see what the distances so for example
when you when you look at now you know that it's coming in
sometimes the datasets that even though the individuals do some kind of classification earlier you
know when collect the doctor it is quite probable some of them were misclassified or
they're not as accurate because some
that parts were not measured properly
and you know like for example
let's say somebody collected several
diagnostics for an individual
medical experts sees is part of the data and comes to conclusion
and some are not seen in the other part of the data
and then simply said OK this patient must this particular
i know this is all
all or some some
some problems
but this
as you see
more of information that could be wrong and generally people also say that
the more you know typically
we are actually this is fired
i was making in one of his keynote speeches
in the NASA
just to tackle these that's all
people who look at the skies take the pictures and then they want to know
about exist are already below or a galaxy
apparently you know ten or fifteen years ago
they would have huge numbers scientists to go to these images and this this is
a galaxy the this is an nebula of this is the start this is how
they work
and the reason that only a few of them could do that is the number
of dimensions for each object you know the look the spectral components the look at
you know
the location of the space
and they may be you know lots of dimension data
like them
and humans are not good to see you know more than the dimensions to two
to classify these things
so so therefore the more information you like
the experts can actually make more mistakes
now we we not without looking at large complex information and interrelationships between these
these kinds of things
so later when they started playing in the machine
they found that their grandfather these
physicists who are employed to just to the identification of these
these objects that's taken from these
optical telescopes all radio telescopes and so forth
so so you can see that in the US as the dimensions go
the you know some kind of classification
automated way of doing is more important and people do make mistakes in which case
you should be able to correct
those kind of corrections could be done by giving some kind of weighting so for
an instance is classified as lexical class one supposed to be class three let's say
then instead of using you know zero one kind of assignment you might use some
kind of probabilities to statistics things or some weights to them saying that the chance
of this belonging to the classes point seven minutes to the other classes point three
when you have these kinds of waiting then you can do much better analysis and
you can build but similar class for so what we found is that using this
contrast patterns you can actually do the waiting to these things so for example
let's say we collected two datasets
we somehow found the patterns
in each of these things and not dominant in the other
and then you have a take an instance and then you look at how many
of these patterns is that it has so for example that in this particular instance
here is a
let this be
the resonance
frequency omega zero
i'll make it a little straighter
so you start at very low frequency this is zero you start here was have
zero divided by k
we all agreed that was obvious
and then the amplitude will build up
go through maximum
goes down
and ultimately
goes to zero
and this value omega zero
this value is q
times have zero
divided by k
now for those of you
you look very carefully
you may have noticed
that the maximum you that i have drawn
it is not
at omega equals omega zero which may go against your instinct
this maximum
or curse at a frequency which we will call omega max
which is always a little bit below omega zero but for high IQ systems
as i will show you shortly
it is effectively the same
i will come back to this
the face
as a function of omega
this is why
and this is by over two
and if this is omega zero
that delta will change in the following way
it's really hard to imagine then that what he's doing
you are in face at very low frequencies
and resonance precisely omega zero you the by over two
ninety degrees out of phase
and at very high frequencies
you will see that the two out of phase
and i will be able to demonstrate that to you
coming back to this
mysterious maximum not so mysterious actually
where is this what frequency do we have really the maximum amplitude
well to calculate that
you would have to take the derivative of that monster equation
you will have to take the eighty omega
if you go you have to have to be zero
so that's when the maximum occurs
and i'll leave you with that exercise may take you few minutes to do that
you will find them
that omega max
so the real maximum
it is located the maximum in terms of amplitude
is omega zero squared
is gone muskrat over two not for the two
to the power
not so intuitive that it is there
and if you like to write that in terms of q which is often done
omega max
so that is the frequency at which the amplitude
reaches a maximum
is omega zero
times one minus one over two
q squared
and then
the square root of the whole thing
and the reason why this is nice you can immediately if you know q
you can immediately evaluate
but the differences
percentage-wise between omega max
and omega zero
if you want to know
what the maximum amplitude itself is
so what a maxis
so that's really this value
it must be very close to q times have zero overkill but is a little
you can write that
in the following four
that just a matter of algebraic manipulations
you get to q here
you expect
and then downstairs
you get something like this one minus
over four and then you get q squared to the power half
so now let's
but in some numbers that you get some feeling for
the answer is that we have
suppose we have
an example of IQ equals
some of value for q
pendulums that we have q way higher than five take among number before q
if i go to this equation here
two squares twenty five
two ten twenty five fifty
that's two percent but i have to take the square root so there's only one
percent of
so omega zero
omega max
divided by omega zero
is o point
nine nine only one percent lower
there's only one percent below omega zero
and then if you want to know now what a max
so you would think that a max is very close
two q
times have zero over k
it is not
two times it is a little larger
and so
if we quite a max divided by a zero
a zero now
it's meant to be
the amplitude when omega equals zero then is the shorthand notation this number is not
a little higher is now five point oh three
you can see if q is higher
then of course
these numbers
become even closer than omega
max becomes even closer to omega zero
and then this maximum eight becomes even closer to queue times
i have zero for k
rarely ever will be
the body too much was the fact
of data
and we're going to have a set of policies which is the current version space
is the set of
but is that we might eventually converge to
and we're going to return
the max over the centre meaning passes
and possible labels
of the difference in losses
so this is a generalisation
four essentially arbitrary loss functions as long as
is there and
so these were imagining of these losses are made between zero and one
so this is the view what you care about an example in proportion to
so the the difference in losses which could be achieved amongst the remaining plausible boxes
OK so
the previous safety guarantee
doesn't quite hold for this
because sometimes its value could be zero
so you need to
to prove
this is also say if it's a for exactly the same reason that a squared
is safe
what's past this is not the
best possible predictor it will never be the best possible predictor went on to prove
this is not the best thing or may not the best in good
this now we want to prove some speedups
and if we want to do with arbitrary loss functions it seems like we need
to do to go a little beyond the disagreement coefficient
so we need to define a new quantity
which is the so symmetry
that you are this obvious symmetry
is so we have two predictions
xeons prime
we have different possible label
which which could be the truth
we don't know which which those are
so interested in
what is the maximum ratio between
the losses
a single label
and the minimum
the difference in losses for single label
this turns out to be
the right easily you analyse the label complexity
OK so
when you think a little bit about what supersymmetry means so for zero one loss
elysian prime agree
in which case
the losses will be the same
in iteration define zero zero is one
or they disagree in which case
this difference is always one in service of the symmetry is one
four hinge loss where you just have hand starting at one
and going up to minus one
this also into our to zero
because you want to be minus one
that's going to be one
for logistic loss turned out to be something of more complex one place you be
inverse for square loss to to be
it may be worthwhile to think about so this is the difference of losses
is the function of
xeon see prime right so this is the thing like a derivative to generalization of
so if you look at logistic loss it look something like this
on a fixed interval
you can
you have some
derivative magnitude here
the sum of
ninety it from this new into a
the ratio of these two start ups to compute
the symmetry
so this also tells you what i squared loss as an infinite so symmetry because
it go to zero
you have to make sure the zero is not the domain and then it would
and i guess
in applications of square loss that i've seen typically one only the zero inside of
OK so we're almost so
we also need to generalize disagreement coefficient just very slightly so this is the definition
of this coalition before
and the claims that you can rewrite is the probability is really an expectation of
an indicator function
and i can
right out
this is there exists h and h prime
in my set
about these which the degree
and now
now becomes there no units attached to it
so so this is dimensionless
all right now how actually do I change the variable in the equation
0 watch this is
utterly trivial idea and utterly important but don't slog around doing it this way trying
to stuff and
lifers 1st instead do the inverse of the words right it instead as t equals
M T 1
the reason being that it's the that's facing you in that equation and the 1481
a substitute for so let's do it the new equation will be what well the
since this is a constant the left hand side becomes DT was
times M
equals k
times 10 to the 4
minus end to the 4th T 1 to the 4th so I'm going to factor
out that the 4th and make it 1 minus T 1 to the 4th of
now I can divide through by and get rid of 1 of those and so
the new equation now is
the T 1 take the time of is equal to
now I have K cubed out front here I'm going to just give that a
new name k 1
but but but but but the
essentially is the same equation is no harder to solve normal
and no easier to solve than the original 1
but it's been simplify study for what looks better it looks better lets us all
right to compare the 2 but this 1 up and green and this 1 agreeing
to just images the same with indicate that has the same equations
notice so t 1 has been rendered is now dimensionless so I don't have to
even ask when I solve this equation of please tell me what the units of
temperature are what kind of LU measuring temperature it makes no difference to this equation
k 1 still has units what units doesn't have a it's it's been simplified because
it now has the units of blood
of since this is dimensionless and this is dimensionless the units of inverse lines so
K. 1 words that units involving both degrees and seconds before but now it's inverse
as its units
and were like this 1 less constant so that 1 less constant in the equation
it just looks better
short of
this business so I think you know
that k 1 the process of forming k 1 out of k 1
out of a K and Q
it is called lumping constant so I think that use the standard terminology in physics
and engineering courses
and triangular constants together like this and then you make and you want them there
they are a lot for you and then you just wanted do
so as an example scaling of watch out for when you can use it for
example they would have probably been a good thing to use on the 1st problem
set when you're handling this problem of drug elimination and hormone elimination production side of
things but you could lump constants and as was done to some extent on the
solutions to work
get needle looking answer 1 without somebody constants
OK now let's now go to serious stuff where we're actually going to make changes
of variables which we hope will render
unsolvable equations suddenly solvable now I'm going to make the thereby making substitutions but
it's quite a quite important to watch out there 2 kinds of substitutions direct substitutions
but that's where you introduce a new variable I don't know how to write this
on the board of just scheme so the new it's it's 1 which says that
the new variable
is equal to some combination of the old variables
the other kind of substitution is inverse is just the reverse here you say that
the old variables
or some combination of the new of all the you'll have to
stake in the fuel variables to with the basic it's what's appears on the left-hand
side of
it is it a new variable that appears on the left-hand side by itself or
is it the old variable that appears
on the left hand side now right here we have an example
if I did it as a direct substitution I would've written t 1 equals to
that's the way I defined the new variable which of course you have to do
if you're introducing it but what I actually did this substitution I did the inverse
substitution namely I used t equals t 1 of m times t 1
and the reason for doing that was because it was the capital T. is that
zero as a function of the original parameters and are vector of lagrange multipliers
and then
we take derivatives of this thing
with respect to theta kl
a particular element here and if we take the derivative what we get
so we get n k l
divided by
OK now
all right
and now if we set this equal zero
and so theta kl
we get
that i get this wrong
for all k start
solve this by setting it equal to zero we get that data
OK kl
it is
we have one minus lambda k times the theta KL and then we divide by
OK so we get
so essentially is proportional to
and k l
with some
the grande multiplier here what we want is probably cale's two
some to one when we some two l
because that's the constraint that we get when we take derivatives with respect to lambda
so this becomes
the maximum likelihood estimate is in a ball
over some
time of k
l products
a really happy with that
i think this is sort of a gory detail and i apologize for people who
think it's really trivial just because i want to demystify there there's a very mechanical
way of doing this
we have a model
we write down the likelihood function we may have to consider constraints in the likelihood
function and then we take derivatives and we try to solve and sometimes in these
simple cases we can analytically solved for
the parameter values
and the beauty of this is that the answer we get is really really simple
an obvious
so if we want to learn the maximum likelihood parameters for data to the parameters
are really
x two to the parent x one
then we take the counts that we observe four different configurations of x one x
and we take those counts really renormalize the rows sum to one
and that's what we get here in this tiny corner here
now do you guys think this is reasonable
is this a good
a way of estimating things
well that's that's a good
observation so for this particular configuration of the parent and child we didn't observe
that's occurring in our data set of
fifteen data points we have fifteen any big n equals fifteen data points to generate
matrix of frequencies and so on
our maximum likelihood estimate was zero for that element
and that seems uncomfortable if we think of the model is the way of predicting
things about
feature data because essentially what that saying is just because i didn't observe this particular
configuration i think it's impossible in all future data
so that was it for maximum likelihood estimation discrete graphs with
fully observed data
now let's move on to slightly more interesting set right questions the press conferences
is quite reasonable
you could say
but but i mean the the question was philosophically you can say anything exists if
you never observed it but if you take that point
then actually can do any machine learning because if you have the data set
then you've never observed in n plus first data point so you could say that
could possibly exist and so the only thing that you could predict is the stuff
that you have already observed
so i couldn't for example predict tomorrow
the sun will rise because i haven't observed that you
so i think philosophically philosophically
you may be able to argue that but your life would be very difficult
he would agonize lot which is related to the philosophers to do that
now let's consider a slightly more interesting problem let's imagine we have a graphical model
but now
only some of our variables are observed in the rest of the variables are hidden
now will be use interchangeably
the terms hidin
and missing in latent people often use these
the terms interchangeably so let's just call these axes here
and the y observed and now i'm going to ask us to
the parameters of this model
just from observations of y
you might think well that's a little fishy right you want me to learn the
relationship between x one and x three
given by this parameter theta three when the only thing i observed is why
i mean i'm going to say yes but try to do
where you know where machine learning researchers and statisticians we can boldly go into problems
that other people might think of fish
let's apply the same principle we did before
which is to maximize the parameter log likelihood given the observed data that's perfectly reasonable
o thing to start out with
so we can write down our log likelihood is a function of our parameters
and this is the probability of the observed data given the parameters
now the only thing
weird about this function is that to compute the probability of the observed data given
the parameters
it's hard to do that directly from this because we don't know the values of
all of these hidden variables
our graphical model gives us
a joint distribution over all of these x and y variables
so if we just put it
different possible values over the next variables and we some of those out
we get by the basic marginalization rule of probability the probability of the observed data
given the parameters is the sum over all possible settings of the hidden variables of
the joint probability of the observed hidden variables given the parameters
so now in the same kind of ballpark as we were before
we have a lot like function to try to maximize it
and here's a nice trick to pull up our sleeves
and that's the algorithm
we as well as grande multipliers and i'm going to ask about the EM algorithm
raise your hand if you know what the algorithm is
raise your hand if you don't know what the EM is
OK a small number of people
which is reasonable given the
we have a very diverse set of backgrounds people here
here's what we're gonna do we're going to maximize the parameter log likelihood given the
observed variables and the EM algorithm is in a very intuitive sort of
now I set ahomework question yesterday andthe answer was is the same yes it's amazing yes
isn't it so just arecapyou you draw a you choose an unknowrandom you you
you draw ball from that random earnings it'sblue andyou really want a red ball and so
you have asecond draw and youhave a choice of sticking with the sameearn or switching
sticking or switching and most of you preparedpreferdswitching Ithink what you're seeing
is something like this you're you're you'rethinking wellif itif it was a blue
the first time is much more likely to be this earnwasdrawing from
and there aren'tmanyred balls in thereso I better switchbutactuallywhen you do the numbers
it is exactly equaleleven totwelvetheodds are against youboth ways by exactly
the same amountI think it's quite curiousthis I chose this example completely at
random whatever that means I and Ithought I've made amistake when I found that
and it's notit' not generallytrueabsolutely not generally true itjust happens to
be true of this particular numbers of balls and and try to understand why intuitively that's
notthe right answer I think it has something to do with the fact that intuitively we we are
too certain about our initial inference it is more likely to be the the the
right end you've drawn frombut only by a factor of abouttwo to one but
I think mentally we kind of downweight the possibility that it couldbe the other earn
when youwhen thethe laws of probability get at rightthey properly propagate
that uncertaintythrough into the season stage andit really doesn't matter whether youstick or switch
really you're stuffed anywayokay today we there's gonna beslightly higher
content to concept ratio andI'm gonnabe talking about some practical issuesa little bit
about bayesian computation you've had a verydetailed look atsampling methods
from from from I know I'm not going to say very much in this
sectionI'm gonna say quitea bit about questioning models sothis is model-based inference
wherethe models come from we talked aboutthat a bitlast timebut you know you're
never quite sure andwhat can wethisisgonna be a
paintheyou can can you use data to criticize
your model and to choose choose between modelsthat's themain point of today's talk and
then there's a a few small items at the end and then after coffee I'm
going to talk about some recent applicationsI've been involved with and trying to go
through themand picking out the lessonsyeah the lessons learned in thefirst two
tutorials see where they where where those ideas come into the to to themodeling
and analysis that I've doneokaythe key point about bayesian computation is
whichever whatever methodyou used to dois that we're talking about integration and not optimization so that's
quite a bit different from any other paradigms this is rather weaktag line
not due to mewe are integratingand being greatrather than optimizing and
being wise and the fact that there is an integral therewell it'sintegrals therein almost
everything we do with withwith probability models essentially because you marginalizing out variables
and not the not concern at a particular time so there's an integral in thedenominator
in the posterior probability andwhen youdo prediction this integrals top and bottom if you
want to estimatedthe expectation of a function in this and another is an
integral there as well so we'realways we're always integrating and that's not just a sort
of numerical computation point is because bayesian inference is essentially about integratingout uncertainty you know
I've used the word integratenot as it were sequentially making the best decision at
each stage and is quite crucial to the Bayesian way of thinking that that's that's the
way it works sonumerical integration very wellunderstood subject as a huge
literaturebut but it seems thatquite a lot of the mainstream
literatureand numerical integration isn't terribly relevant and there's several reasons for thatfirst of all
we're almost always concerned with pretty high-dimensional problems and classical methods of numerical integration
as an example but i'll tell you exactly how we do it
and for discovering powerful in distinguishing features between datasets like example i give you
like the other patterns composed of conjunctive combination of elements basically we're saying this feature
values this feature value and this feature value
can also capture patterns support change over time you can do that so for example
you know it's a very first example i gave you
papers published in this period were papers published in the year you can you can
tell you know i mean are they you know you have to do some kind
of feature
mapping for these things and then you can ask questions what's happening
so as i said the you know the cancer cells
was the was the front cover the people appear
the patterns have been applied in medical applications for diagnosis of
acute lymphoblastic expressive so now let's look at the the space of these so
so one of the ways we can look at is that
think of this where there the the two classes two datasets we have two types
d one and d two
it's a cancer this is class one and class two
then we can have all these patterns so suppose let's say
there's an exponential combination of patterns so
so obviously you choose one pattern
and then you find
how many instances have this pattern
OK so that gives you
martin value so let's say
in the that's to you chose the next
let's assume
the pattern x here
that is the
the support at this point and then
and then you look at the data set two
and then it gives you
what is the support for that which could be zero or
four hundred percent so that gives you a point so basically what you can do
is you can learn this metrics or this box
with all these factors
OK so remember this an order of the pattern of each pattern has two values
it's supporting
in one it supported the two so now
each point has two values and you
you just drop those points
into this into the space
now the interesting part is that the lower region is the reason that we are
really interested we want to find all those patterns that
following to this
in this and similar you can grow in this side as well but just showing
the important patterns in data or this celebration
so what it says is that
if it has the probability
all support less than a i'm not interested in could be noisy
so that means you want some minimality that you're interested
and then what you want is that the problem you know the support value has
to be much greater than forty one otherwise if they just equal suppose at this
point that means all these patterns are
equally probable or have exactly the same support in all of those things that means
any any pattern that sits in the
in this forty five degree line because we're using same scale
there are interesting because they want to tell us anything because there
equally likely on both datasets so therefore we really interested in mining these so the
whole research goes is how do i find the patterns
easily from here
so all i'm given is
this slope
and given
short run these are the two values are given
and i have to find
the question is some people would ask how do i know to choose these things
you know in any
machine learning you know there is no absolute answers you know like if if anybody
thinks that
machine learning going to solve all the problems wrong
because you know the way
i would say you know you've given n points
i can find the perfect function
that goes to the end
the moment
so i have infinite functions i can give you that you've got to these
and points
i give you an plus one
infinity of then
and i go to the n plus one point
but i'm still left with infinity because that's what i start right
therefore as you can see
you will never be able to find
perfect function in that sense
you know we will never know the real more
you know like in physics
let's get going to a and
what we're talking about last time
is the discovery the piano
it was not the most basic constituents of matter
so there was the particle
that was even less massive and that is the electron
but today we're going to discover the nucleus
and so
says that nineteen eleven
this is our brother
in england
and what he was interested in doing
i was studying the emissions
the emission from these newly radioactive elements that were being discovered
so the emission from radium bromide radium for example
and so on
what he did was he got a sample
radium bromide
from his friend marie curie
and what was known
is that this radium bromide
he needed something called alpha particles
and the exact nature of the the alpha particles was not known
however what was known
was that the world heavy particles
that they were charged
and they
they energy
course today we know what these alpha particles
feeling of loss of helium with two electrons removed
all right so he got his radium bromide
alpha particles are being emitted from radium bromide
and he had some kind of detector way out here
which detected these alpha particles
what found is that at the detector
there were
one hundred thirty two thousand
alpha particles
that was the
that he was able to measure
and then because he was trying to figure out what is the nature of these
he did this experiment
he took a gold foil
gold foil
i really meaning
two times ten to the minus five inches
that towards the magnet to better than the diameter of here
i've always wondered how we handle there
that's pretty then
what that
and the whole
but how great he said
once this gold foil was placed
can operate was still
one hundred thirty two thousand alpha particles that
it appeared that
the alpha particles that were being emitted just went right through the foil
right to the detector even
seem like those alpha particles the world the same company
doesn't sound like a very interesting experiment
but at that time he was working with person name guy
post guide the same geiger is the geiger counter
and geiger wasn't too happy about the results of these experiments and in addition
tiger here and this
undergraduate student hanging around the land
his undergraduate name
morrison was really excited about doing science he just hung around there's really want to
do some
and geiger
these one my going with this guy
geiger goes rather further says i got marks and here he really wants to do
something which with
and rather for
what we have here and build a detector
can swing around
goes here
what happened to all the detector that will rotate around such that the detector can
be positioned
in this way
so that we can look
for any
alpha particles might be
cannot meaning
in the direction from which they came
geiger said i thought he was going to be out of line here
problems are at that maximize the site to build the detector the detector
and the geiger OK right let's let's try this
and so on
put the radium bromide there in this arrangement
there is there at the detector
and a year
it takes
the detectors
and they go well there must be a general background
so what they do that thing
while away
so they are presumably all the particles are going in that direction
take it away
and they listen and they here
and they put the ball way back
and they're less than a year the
alpha particles per minute
and they a
another way
what we're
same is basically the same result
they go up for others for get down in the lavatory
rather for example over their shoulder
they like
but they
there are some alpha particles coming on
not many
right look at what the probability theories
the best
we can calculate the probability
is simply the number of that nanoparticles twenty
the number to calibrate the particles twenty
over-the-counter trades
the infinite number
articles one hundred and thirty two thousand eight the probability is too
times ten to the minus four
i will describe this
right next door going to
the mathematics of this so the idea given the solution one
and you want to compute the next one
how can i reuse
the one of the first things so
recall as i said use all these things by
setting up a graph
and then
algorithm to work out what the maximum flow through this graph is that gives you
it gives you
the solution now one of the important things about this which i didn't actually state
this point
is that when you said the graph
for you to be able to solve this using this
max flow problem
must have
positive weight
you must have positive weight on the edges
the reason for this is
if you don't have positive weight on the edges
mean flow algorithm does not work
there is no such thing
on the graph with
negative edges
the thing was how much how much
four water whatever can you
pass along an edge which has in the past
the solution the question doesn't really
and so the must have positive weight
now it turns out that
does occur
a lot the problems
most problems going to have positive weight and hence you can solve using this
using this
graph cut out i should say
if you have some the edges of the graph is the graph
the the graph corresponds to
energy function
now the energy function
is represented by the graph
energy functions can have negative to right and so the question is minimizing the energy
function makes perfectly good sense
even if you have
its negative and in places in the terms of the negative in the sense that
it will become clear
so this problem makes sense
and you could think of solving it
the way we solve it is to turn into the graph and solver using the
graphical form max
it doesn't work
if you have a negative to negative edges in the graph and in fact in
that particular case
you can draw graphs negative edges and finding
max finding the
optimal cuts
the graph
with negative images in fact NP hard
if the edge positive
this flow algorithm which has polynomial time
if not the negative is an NP hard problem so you don't like
negative edges
on graphs
that that's prelude to what carbon few slides so his general idea
you gotta unfortunately have got videos here but i think it's not entirely necessary he
got the top cow
one around the field
the bottom left could represent the
in contrast terms on the edges
it's obvious contrast in the image and so you get this contrast terms
which become part of your cost function and you can segment
OK so you sigma this thing
and you get
you get this you get your you get you contrast terms your solution
and now you come up with the second problem with the cow move too much
and you
thirty the second later in different frame
very similar contrast terms
and i think that that that having to redo the whole computation
well the idea is to look at the difference and update the graphs
how does the graph get updated one of the original graph
we like correspond to the it's almost the same
in most parts of the image right
i think obviously the unary terms are unchanged from assuming certain background
nothing's changed your returns also
you will die terms and unchanged except
around the edges of the object and so the number of nodes in the graph
change is very small
that of course typically the EU returns to its history the binary to cost which
which would be
drive the complexity of this
i thing in fact but you're right if lighting changes
then you know maybe calc slightly different colours
maybe it doesn't make a lot of terms probably quite the same
and the edges of the the way of the edges
they were change to match mental potts model which is the
doesn't depend on the rules that doesn't change all
part of the function
so for instance here
yes if the if the differences between the two graphs and minor
in fact you can actually have
don't have to have the same structure in fact normal will have the same structure
the same graph with different weights
most weights will be unchanged then we'll see how this
oh well
doesn't accumulate i mean that from from
time time you see so you just comparing it with the graph
in the last time
it's a bit and you will see how this works
the unary terms in this particular case maybe dynamic
maybe life changed in
given area and so on
you can
do that
time in some of these five here another one in this particular case it's best
it's best to change
so OK let's let's get down a little bit detail here what happens
so you get more mathematics not to do this but i have the graphs formed
makes it
computing the st mincut
the of this graph
well OK so
forget about the middle
basically this this augmenting path algorithm which used to
not supposing this is this is a graph which you start with
the original graph zero those the weights on the k
so there's
one example
so this
this is the thing here called re parametrisation which i'll talk about the more the
general idea is
behind re parametrisation is
i prefer to call reweighting you're assigning different weights to the edges
in a way that
the function of the cost function represented by the graph
does not change so
there are two basic
reweighting or re parametrisation
things you can do one of them
is you can add see alpha on the right-hand branch
right hand passed down through their i've added alpha
to each of those
where alpha is any value right
and it turns out that does not change
those are the two
population definition f of x is a is the
continuous probability distribution
four x
it is
so that's different when you have continuous values you you don't have the probability that
x equals x survive because it's always zero probability that
the temperature is exactly a hundred degrees is zero because it could be a hundred
point zero zero zero zero one degrees or something else is an infinite number of
possibilities so we have instead
was called the probability density in
we have continuous random variables
not going to
we need to know a lot about this manuscript this is i want to get
the is the basic idea is that
so these are
called population measures
because they
refer to the whole population of possible outcomes and they measure
the probabilities
so it's a it's the truth
but there are also sample
it means
when you get this is
the two partner counting the leaves three
you can estimate from a sample
the population expected values
so the population
i mean
is often written x bar
if you have a sample with n observations
it's the summation i equals one
x by
divided by right that's the average
you know that formula right at you get your heart and leaves and we count
the number of leaves
well you have an branches on the tree you count the number of leaves
and some of up
one would be
there is a gift
i have a little trouble putting this into the
the two-part story but you see the idea you know the average person that's most
elementary concepts
and so you can use this
to estimate either a discrete or continuous expected value
now in finance is often reference to another kind of average which i want to
refer to an which in the jeremy siegel
there's a lot is made of this
and the other kind of average is called the geometric average
and so
we call that
i only show the sample version of it
g of x
he calls
the left parentheses
i equals one
act so by
there's one other and power
so what you see that
if you have trouble seeing that
it's different instead of summing and dividing by i multiply them all together
and take the and through of the
so this is called the geometric average
and it's used
for positive numbers
so if you have any negative numbers
you have a problem if you had one negative number in the product would be
a negative number and if you took a route of that you might get an
imaginary number so we don't want to
use it in that case
this appendix to one of the chapters in germany
siegel's board
where he says that
one of the most important applications of
this theory is to measure how successful and investors
suppose someone is managing money
have they done well
so you would say well they
investing money over a number of different years let's take the average over all the
different years OK
so i suppose someone has been investing money for an years annexed to by is
the return on investment
in a given year
what is the average performance with the natural thing to do would be the average
them up
jeremy says that maybe that's not a very good thing to do
but he says you should do instead
take the geometric average of gross returns
what does it mean the return on investment is how much you made from the
investment as a percentage of the money invested OK
the gross return is the return plus one
all right
the worst you can ever do
investing is to lose all of their investment one hundred percent
if we add one to the return you've got to number that's never negative
and we can then use geometric returns OK
and so jeremy siegel says
really in finance we should be using geometric and arithmetic
why is that well i tell you in very simple terms i think suppose someone
is investing your money
and he
i have had very good returns i have invested i produced twenty percent a year
for nine of the last ten years
and so
eighty that's great but what about the last year here
and is all i lost one hundred percent
in that year OK
so you might say all right that's good so i i i would add up
to twenty percent a year
for nine years
and then put zero
nine hundred twenty business return for nine years and put in zero for one year
and maybe that doesn't look right
think about it if you're investing your money with someone like that would you end
up with
you end up with nothing
if a one year when they lose everything doesn't matter how much they made in
the other years
so jeremy says in the in the text is that the geometric return is always
lower than the arithmetic return
unless all the numbers are the same
and so it's a less
it's a less optimistic version
and so we should use that but people
in finance resist using that
because it's a lower number when you're advertising every thirty one
the biggest possible
we also need some measure
we've been talking here about measures of central tendency only
and in finance we need as well
measures of
that's how much something very
central tendency is the manager of the center of a probability distribution of the like
central tendency is to measure
variance is a measure of how much things change
from one observation to another
so we have
they given the lecture
on text mining and information extraction
and we'll focus well we've seen in the last lecture
extract information
and yes the
application which
extract from
they don't
it the
and then because of course of information
the cast
the degree
thank you much
i think it's a very weak cue of information from
you probably know
it gives kind of the work we're we trying to
the information actually
information retrieval
the core
part of this
of information items in databases and repositories
according to
any information
i think i to do that
also during the the class
thank you for all of the information on the content more
we have no
the new material
make sure you can take a look
text audio
so on
and all the information
we are talking about
by q
typing and key words but there are other ways of
expressing information
and it's not
show great by
type of query
when you actually can live with multimedia objects in the image and you want to
find similar
you could import some music cues
and find music files
that are quite similar
according the
we use these into multimodal information needs so need
in a career that i
that can be a mixture of text
images for
well i don't think i have to tell otherwise would not be cool
but we have also for information
if you look at the success of search engine
on the web the
of course there are many different
building information systems
and i cited here you know
and i would like to information retrieval rules
as we know it
then we have
maybe i i'll get just means get points
the club information system
before the really cool
this might be words
and we also have to make few
the data structures in this
the data structure
for large collection
and read what we try to perform a kind of matching ranking
we try to find the
with the the query
we have all types of ranking functions here
they can be used
for type of and i also think about the project
and what if we could just list of relevant documents
well but is square
can be also express the by some sort of to find you will find in
the article
we used to live in a few keyword
also you have a question answering systems
where you
in the input
based in natural language which you a question but it can also be seen in
natural language
but you have other forms so is a question answering system
you really is a question of natural language
and in our life
in my what's
currently in question answering systems
in the
then you're
question is not compared to complete that
but the first sentence of the paragraph so small snippets of the document
these are are the observed variables
then you have a hidden variable y
which could be state variables so for instance this could be a secondary structure and
in particular structure could be that some of all the she walked walk while
so and then they can be relationship between the hidden variables and all of the
here x i y i
you can also have a relationship between one in very well with the next one
this is relation
then the rest is assumed to be independent and it is this probability model
like that before it
OK so and they begin fight
the estimation what to fit these
find the parameters of before
so now the question is once you have this property model so can you point
the label sequence the state sequence of both are the most likely state
this is the
the log of probability everything coupled with the product and then you get
some of these elements one with the emission probability one with
and this is is
the likelihood what one state
so what
problem the problem is even sequence you would like to find the label sequence y
y such that the probability of p x and y
for that we use dynamic programming
you and i wanted it
the idea is that for every position in sequence
so we consider all cases private position in sequence for every possible label that he
consider all cases where we could come
then you maximizing of all people tried
and since then we have this independent
we have independent here
we can compute these quantities efficiently so we can prove in the end that we
we can iteratively
extend the optimal path
so maybe
i mean i think you don't know you every time in the end i think
so that's the generalisation of this which is called the generalized hidden markov models
we don't assume
then we have lot transition every
every time step at every position
but we might if you be might switch
we might want to say so
you would like to
identify segments where certain
every transition is not a single letter is consumed but several letters you know so
the image one letter at time when he had made several levels
and we have the markov property on the second level
and we have within the segment we can have non markovian
o point depending on the length of the sequence
this is important for modelling segment segment length three points in the secondary structure k
known why some properties which
there are some
the things to which depend on the length of the segment
OK and there's also a dynamic programming algorithm for finding the most likely
so in case of hidden markov models we assume independent of of position from one
actually the independence of the
one position from the wise up with
and we had to do this in order to be able to compute the probability
in this way
OK so there's an extension of this which is called conditional random fields and here
in very might depend on any
input variables x
and what we're doing here and
you have i x and y
the internet which in the x and y
thank you for compute your w vectors
and you
the conditional probability in this case the difference is that they not modelling
the probability of p x p of x and y but the problem what in
the probability of x
y given x
but this can handle non independent features and this can also be extended to all
the markov condition
so what i'm going to talk about the a bit more
the other i
and i with which is called max margin structured output learning and here
i would like to know function
y given x
it is going to segmentation patients y for sequence x
so if you would like to
what didn't function why we can find the patient by maximizing the function by
so the training to be an n input output pairs of input
input and labels
and now we would like to add such that has a large margin between any
true segmentation and approximate to consider this as a two class classification problem any
true segmentation
so for example any wrong segmentations is negative
so we can write this stuff
f y ten if x minus
OK so it actually log exp function so you know it's convex but it's actually
very complicated log exp function he probably talked about the easy to compute this is
log x function that has an exponential number of extra terms so it's not easy
to compute so if you want to compute the likelihood that's that's what you're up
OK but based on what we did before
it's very natural to think of the same thing
right this likelihood the summation is a hard problem
on the general graph
but if i had a tree it's an easy problem i can compute the likelihood
is very fast on any tree using the sum product algorithm
right so the same idea what
with the different function what i just do the exact same thing not just a
convex combinations of trees as before
right so this is the example we looked at before i was taking my original
problem now splitting it into trees
but all this do it on this new function
so if i do that then i immediately get an upper bound on the log
likelihood of the data
and so the
this is the log likelihood on your original problem and what it's saying is it's
a convex combination
this is the log likelihood on treaty and that's whatever weight you put on that
so this is the same thing we can efficiently evaluate as long as we don't
have too many trees you can always compute that upper bound
and then the question is what is the best upper bound
i would like to find the
split into trees that gives you the tightest possible upper bound on the log likelihood
so let me let me show you
what this is doing
so let me just write a little bit here if you don't mind
what i'm going to show you in a minute is that the best possible upper
related to something known as the bay entropy
in this case because we're doing convex combinations is related to what's known as the
reweighted entropy
so let me let me define that for you
OK almost down
so many people know what an entropy is
and entropy sort of the way of
measuring the uncertainty that's that's implicit in the distribution
and they sort of pop up a lot
in physics there's this sort of a reason physical reason why you would get entropy
something known as the gibbs variational principle but we don't need to know that that
right now
what's important for us is the following
if you remember the things that were used optimizing or from this morning used optimizing
over things that are the marginal distributions at node c of the vector at every
and if you have the vector every node you can define
it's the probability distribution you compute you can compute its entropy
its entropy is just the average of the
of one over the distribution or it's minus the average of the log sort think
it's and it's a measure of
its maximal uniform distribution it's zero if you have a distribution puts all its mass
and one point
right so that's
that's actually a
concave function if you play around with a little bit it's concave is a function
of the vector the marginal vector the note
if you remember we had a matrix that was sitting on every edge
i member from this morning you had matrices that we're sitting on the edge and
we are putting constraints on those you other matrix you can use it to compute
something called the mutual information
o continued to drop
OK this is what you would expect from from the previous bond because somehow we
would expect that the complexity goes down the complexity increases when you use more iterations
so therefore this is high potential for doing so we we
we would expect that
with this with a simple hypothesis the generalized but what was found that the generalisation
goes down so this was
something else what we would have expected from the band
the question is is occam's razor
that is that simple things perform better
is the wrong in this case
so just i mean it turned out just need to be explanation
and that came in nineteen ninety eight by p finding the point about the only
and they came up with a different bound so they were able to show that
expected error of a function
it is bounded by the
the empirical margin error
OK this quantity to you
so the classification of the margin plus something which again depends on the VC dimension
of the basic policies class but it somehow divided by p day and this is
in march i mean this empirical margin
and then again sometimes which depends on it
so no that we don't have it depends on t anymore
so previously had depends on
on the complexity of this combined hypothesis class so he is only
the VC dimension of of the single
of the basic says class k but on the other hand we have this depends
on the day
so if you could somehow lucky
that peter large and on the same the same time disappear commodity small then this
bone is going to be small
but if somehow for for some reasonably large theta
this is not very large
then we can't i mean the response
what is largely
i mean the the
essentially could say even given a certain number of examples of the sea the different
classes fixed simply to logan over chemistry iterations i mean combinations of songs i mean
this number of iterations of selecting from the basic forces classes t convex hull right
so this function classes fixed
i mean in the
OK so
it's it's true so i mean many more examples then this becomes more complex
i mean you could say it is fixed class then OK only works for certain
OK so
so we have this bound if if they have a large theta so then this
i mean if you if you're lucky so then the empirical margin small so this
term is small and on the other hand this system small
so then then we are lacking but if you do we consider small theta then
the empirical margin error is just as large as points in the training error
OK this is large so
and then we have the somehow
then you could also easily the other part
this is just like
i think it was not generalize to real
but i haven't seen as result
maybe should be free to get so
and I changed t-minus say that
now have changed the wisely way to say it is I changed teams
because the team is always there t 2 t plus a you get this by
applied t plus to get the right hand side
I replace this by t plus a and that this into team and that's the
end of the
that's a universal rule for doing it OK now I'm going to use that same
rules for transforming U of T minus a
I find that the the the the problem is now I function like t square
assigned t which is written in terms of T minus
and I don't know what to do with
the answer is by brute force
right in terms of T minus what is approved for
reinforces the following
and put it to you might say the children T TV minus
so that is there analyticity by a of it was
OK and now what's the rule I just following with the same
what's the sauce for the goose is sauce for the gander minus x
plus transform of f of you know what I ideas
where I C a T I change the t plus said OK here I C
a T
all change that at t plus a
well I got
the plus a minus a
plus a smoking taking account what is
16 plus a of the
by pieces passive understanding OK let's calculate systems of examples and suddenly you breathe a
sigh of relief that this all is doable anywhere along with what's happening
but when that covering up any crucial I OK and covering up the things but
you know that
a let's see which we calculate for about what I discovered let's calculate will plus
transform of
you of the
OK 2nd well 1st of all right out what it is in terms of the
unit step function
and that formula
yeah you see it now you don't love
so it's all plus transform is going to be
well plus transform T minus say that follows that a special case here where the
function this function is 1
whatever that was what it doesn't either 1 makes a difference so it simply going
to be
will plus transform of what's he would have been would have been which is
signal plus transform you have to be this 1 that 1 restaurant
because as the function 1
and we don't care about the fact that it's zero for negative values of the
so that's my events and so I multiply it by e to the minus state
s times 1 over a
I'm using this formula you the minus AS times will plus transform the unit step
function which is 1 over and about the translation that was taken care of by
the exponential
and minus because this is minus the same thing with be
so this is will plus transform of the the box
in the beginning the system doesn't like
hence me
it fights me it doesn't like that omega it wants to do something different which
is part of next
weak selection
and you will see that in the beginning
so we have to be a little patient
before my real
so five
ready for that
so i'm going to start now
to drive assistance
at the frequency which is below resonance
i want you to see two things that they go hand in hand
and i want you to see
that the
you're going to
very low frequency
i'll give you the amplitude this is twice the amplitude of the driver
now it is here spring
now spring is here
so there's only this much is
to add to zero
at the zero isn't small no more than three-quarters of an inch
and now we're going to
that that's object
the expos
to this
given a little bit of time
to recognise me
it takes a little bit of time to reach the steady state solution
and next time we will
how much time it actually takes
so if you want to be a little bit patient
and you will see
if we give it
too much then being too little and then of course it starts to
get stuck
are we close
we're close will be close enough now look at it
because going both to the left for me
both right for me
for you to go in both to right
you going boasted left
both the right
and both to the
and both to the left
this was the amplitude
twice the amplitude of the driver
may you look carefully you it's less
it is that the zero to the
this gentleman
immediately noticed because we have two strings
so you see here
apart from the factor of two
you see the delta zero
and you see that the amplitude indeed
is half of
the amplitude of the driver because of the two springs now we're going to residents
omega zero
nasty things may happen
you may break
we have to give it time
see what's funny things it's doing
well the study stated
have to wait
just a little patience
with more time
notice also that the remember this is only moving this much
newcomers this is moving
i'm a even be exactly address and we can only
do the best we can here
may not be exactly of resonance
boy close to resonance now all you have
only look at that too
my and resonance
i think i got it you see
in phase no out of phase
now we see the ninety degrees and look at this teeny-weeny little displacement here and
look with this man is doing
that is resonance
and this is
basically what we're going to be talking about and this this lecture
now in the UK
well certainly in in london
we are very proud that the olympic games are coming to the UK in two
thousand twelve
the scots are quite pleased as well but i think probably more so but
so it struck me that
the book is the the gambling shops will probably be taking
lots of dates for the
and the
the time that wins the gold medal in a hundred metres or in this case
the distance and the the long jump right so what is the the distance to
the wins the gold medal in the long jump
as i said what we do is we try and use some very basic machine
lamb a trajectory
of what the
gold medal distance is going to be in the long jump
once you've done that
we can make a prediction and then we can go into some money and bit
of what distance will be
what do we do
we've got some data
quick chat
corresponds to the winning distance
and the year
the games took place
now of course there are lots of other attributes
then we could have the columns form of all the top athletes that potentially maybe
competing what the weather may well be light can and so forth
and clearly if we're really going to put any money down and making a bet
as to what the actual distance would be
then we would want to use as much information as we possibly could so we
would we would gather as
as many attributes as possible as many indicators of what the the likely winning distance
would be
but some are just from our the perspective here from from the book perspective what
we want to do is we'll see what sort of predictions we can make
if all the we take into account is the amount of time that has elapsed
from the very first modern olympic games
so in many ways discounting a lot of valuable information but we'll use time
our last time as a surrogate
all of that information
that potentially could be available
and also on clutters it doesn't clutter the the
what i'm going to develop here
so as one of the speakers said last we can always look at your data
let's just do that let's look at the data that we have
andrew plot to be
gold medal winning distance
against the time so the amount of time elapsed from the start of the first
modern games i'm not going to use this laser pointer too much because you can
see that all shaking hand because
the video was thinking last night was about stronger than anticipated
OK so let's let's look at the data and see what information that is so
the first question is our tribute which is the
the time elapsed from the first modern games and the winning distance as a functional
relationship between the
it the last time
i predict
all distance
someone showed please
yes and no
you might have to look at it and you can see there is a relationship
OK so it
there's a number of things so those of you who are really keen on all
the long jump well of course the games uninterrupted during the the two wars and
you can see this little
this thing he was of course bow beam in nineteen sixty nine games held in
OK but anyway there there's certainly a functional relationship they want to make this
sort of objective visually we can see the something
so the for a formal perspective what we want to do
as you want to find a class of functions which will map
our attributes which in this case i are integers
want to the real line was electrified onto the
the positive half of the real line so we're looking for some function
and given what we observed it would seem sort of reasonable
that a linear relationship exists
so we could say that the class of functional that we have is is going
to be from the linear class which is parameterized
by an intercept value w not and
some slope value w one
so here's a model
the sort of thing that we
land in second year
high school
linear models
so the W's other free parameters of our model with this linear functional class
now what we have to do is we have to identify
the model parameters
one way of doing this
is by considering what's called a loss function and i think someone may be talking
about more detail and more depth of about loss functions and classes of loss functions
but in essence what we're going to do is we which is going to define
the loss function
which will enumerate miss much
between what the model predicts
and the data that we have actually observed which is our target value t
the distance
clearly have lost should be
over all possible observations
so we would take up an expectation but he was going to take an empirical
expectation so we define our laws
for all of the available
input output on attribute target example peers