four members of
because of
this is intended to be
the action
it is
he was
one is
o was
it is
how hard is o
all these
if you
first of all
through the world
the first
this something that
here is the
june cohen was all
the answer is
p people making a difference between the functionality are
of some system and the
parameters of the system but
just the same thing and we become networks just like bits in this laptop here
all parts of the functionality and of the parameters in a certain sense all the
ways in which we can network which is the general computer which can compute anything
this laptop can compute because this laptop essentially is we can work with a particular
activation function for the continent
then you don't have really this difference between functionality and parameters and what you can
do with these we can networks is that you can
use them as predictors of time series for example of histories of actions and
and sensory inputs and you can
you can
compute the difference between what an the network is predicting and what really happens and
this is what you want to minimize the cost and and then you can compute
a gradient algorithm space in progress based essentially because there is a way of changing
the voting system such that you minimize that you that you find
that you compute the first derivative of the
i wish that you have namely minimizes error with respect to the problem that is
running on the weekend which is just as its weight matrix so this very nice
you have
a space
of programs and in that space
you find another reason you find gradient which leads to a better from
now in the nineteen nineties and neural networks of this type so we can attract
they were considered by some exciting and very general but it's in practical applications they
just scale up well that was all toy problems but the situation has totally changed
has totally changed now and is just one recent example that is by the way
that's alex graves who used to be my phd student and now a poster community
and he is now beating every other algorithm and connected handwriting recognition connected handwriting recognition
is much more difficult than
single digit recognition
which we had before a couple of slides ago
because there is no teacher tells you where and does
this individual let's start here and what is it and all you have if you're
lucky you have a set of
training sequences and teacher told you what kind of
letter labels
this corresponds to but even the teacher doesn't know is that the latter here is
that part of letters that just an accident is that
is that the beginning of some letter at the end of it of another level
and so on but what you can do is we you can do
things just maximize the probability
the probability is
label sequences
which in this case for example he'll blank b
billowing blanket he old blank AG
and you you want to match the somehow to this real valued input string they
get here and you can maximize the probability of this label sequence given the input
go all the training sequences and said and it turns out that if you do
that right if you use the right type of networks you must use long short
term memory recurrent networks which don't have all the problems that the original become networks
have in particular they can deal with really long time lags between relevant events what
the traditional african networks cannot do this and this is enough to know when all
the handwriting competitions alex for example also achieve the best results and in around handwriting
recognition contest
although he doesn't speak a word of arabic
now you can use these these compression machines of these really we can networks as
prediction machines and therefore compression machines
and it's very natural for such networks and to develop various sets of neurons that
always get active when a certain type of
spatio temporal sequences active is present and then store the memory from one
because if you want to predict the next thing given the previous things the best
thing you can do is to to encode the stuff that frequently occurs again and
again by just a few things a few neurons that somehow correspond to a prototype
a prototype of this object which is that an object is just something that frequently
comes up
and so
clearly defined groups of neurons or little complex things that stand for
absolutely that stand for complex input sequences and compact call them i just a natural
byproduct of compression of this time we cannot work like that those trying to predict
data sequences is compressing all the time and the way compressing is use the same
units again and again for different but similar
input sequence
so the best thing to do
to deal with environment like ours is
just invent a couple of prototypes
that reflect what's often be occurring and then on top of it
just after tx is that you need to to describe the
special instances and that's the way you can save a lot of
and i never understood this difference between sub symbolic and symbolically
obviously you get stuff that is very much like symbolic computation just as a product
of these
of these training algorithms for we can facts and of course as you
interacting with the world as the agent that is
all kinds of events but some of them are related to the sun goes up
every single day and you have to be three times a day and all these
there is one thing of course that is that whenever the agent interacts with the
one that situation itself so it's the most natural thing to have a couple of
neurons that somehow represent this prototype of the agents of that will be something like
itself some more people often discussing consciousness and in all these things in writing books
about it it seems to me was just a very simple by-product of compression it's
just sufficient to have a couple of years dedicated for modeling the things that frequently
appear including
yourself we can take one of these we can use networks that are modelling probability
distributions over all future possible events and london and we can then
and that's why the function doesn't
doesn't exactly the data but that's actually very smooth underlying function
and the useful thing
about the marginal likelihood is
it doesn't just care about how well you fit the training data
it also cares about
how complex models
it has a very specific way
of measuring
exactly how that complexity
and that's given by
by this expression up here
which came out automatically out of the framework
that automatically this term is telling you how well fitting the data in this term
is the complexity
the complexity penalty is not lambda times the complexity the way you have to set
i think that this is the scale that you need to measure these things
and there's no knobs to tweak
so it so it's completely automatic
so here's a picture
o thing which known as occam's razor
tries to illustrate how it can be that this very useful property comes comes about
so in this plan here i have on the on this axis here have an
abstract representation of all possible data sets
normally you can order datasets let's say all this is of particular size
it's no you can order
sets of data so this is abstract in some sense
and on this axis here you have the value of the marginal likelihood
OK let's examine what happens
with when we look at different models that have different types of complexity
let's start with agreement has been was very simple models that could be that it
so let's say the regression model
and the green model corresponds to
linear model
so the linear model
can only fit
a certain subset of the data the data that agrees roughly with and what that
means that it only takes significantly nonzero values on a very limited
a number of the dataset it's only for these data sets
it models things well
i've also drawn to a more complex model here
so this this model here
four four large number of
datasets that states polynomials of degree of two hundred or something like that
can really you know model
almost any dataset you could think of
so so so that has significantly nonzero value for lots and lots of data sets
because these things are probability distributions
they have to normalize to one
that means that
the value of the of the
the marginal likelihood can get much larger for the very simple model
so if you have a data set
that that is actually well modeled by by simple model the marginal likelihood for model
with a much higher than for the very complex
so what happens in this
in this case selection scenarios that now you get a particular observations
this particular observation
doesn't fit very well into this is very simple model the marginal likelihood for model
this is low that corresponds to the rector they
the two simple model
in the other
now the
these colors don't don't match is this is this very simple model
this does this very simple ball doesn't fit very well
but the very complex models correspond to red curve almost exactly reproduce the training data
it is also not very likely
a function that flutter is that much
could have explained almost anything so we shouldn't be too surprised that also explains our
twenty data points in that case
and the exactly right model is the one which is just complex enough
to capture the data like
this but perhaps the most important slide i will talk about you can forget about
casting process if you understand
that's right
so the question the question is you know why is the complexity
penalty the determinant of this matrix
so now the the process remember is a distribution over functions right in and if
you look at the the value of those functions
at those particular locations where we have data
then you get this covariance matrix y
it's hard to think about because it lives in this very high dimensional space
but basically you can think of this
you know
that's how this listeners very high dimensional space right
and what it says here is that the penalty
depends on
on how big that ellipses like this is actually the volume of the lips i
so the determinant here
is the product of the ideas values and i can values tells you the variance
in the different directions
so this is unlikely the hyper volume
of this thing right as a half
because these variances
and you the volume of the thing is the this is the length
the product of the lengths writing it into half outside the lover so it's exactly
the volume
of the right and that tells you
how many different functions
where possible
and the more quickly the functions are the more possible functions there and this is
exactly the way you value
so it's also it's it's also completely analogous to the to the entropy of the
measuring the same thing
OK so
so it seems that there is something that something extremely nice about this this quantity
that sort of popped out of the of the framework
we might be a little bit skeptical about whether this is
but this is exactly right but it seems a little bit too good to be
so maybe i could
this way you by giving
you are much simpler example
where you would be able to say if that's exactly right
so i tried to do that
so here's an example is a different kind of question
which will shed some light on that a lot of
so let's say i give you a task
i give you a bunch of observations
and i say these observations come from a from a unit dimensional gaussians
which has a mean of zero
and you should tell me
what is the variance
OK so i give you a bunch of hundred points points
and you should tell me
and i tell you they come from gauss drawn at random from gauss and we
have zero mean
you know what is the variance
but probably pretty good idea about how to go about this let's just try to
try to make a pictorial representation of or you could try to do the other
points that were run
so let's try to entertain three different crosses one is that they came from the
gaussians with a narrow variance
OK one is that they came from gauss and with somewhat larger variance and and
now houses the camp came gas and from a very large
well scoring technique doesn't give you an intuition whatsoever
what do we mean exactly by this
from these data
we were learning
y and x
y one given x one x y y
one given x equal to
so when x is one
although here when x is one
why is one half the time when x is to
why is one half the time
i only show a data item five a lot more daylight that
i will learn that another thing that x and y are independent
the first thing you do is
you take
all the data and learn your conditional independencies
and then from the conditional independencies you learn the causal DAG
it's going press wrong thing
how much data do we need
now in one thousand assume that we know the independence it's right men but
the map is only as good as
if the dependencies how much data do we need to reliably learn anything
i'll come back to this right
but then again assume for now that we learn the conditional independencies for certain
so can an example here
i suppose
vehicles x y
these are some of the observed variables x and y
and we learned are independent
we're starting out with this knowledge
production wire independent
we cannot have the causal DAG in a and b we could attempt making the
causal faithfulness assumption x could not cause a widening like can not convex
because if i applied the markov condition to this DAG i don't get that independence
i would like to get the wise independent of x and this then y is
independent of its non descendants conditional on x
so his day doesn't say y and x are independent neither does this one
right so
there's an independency that is not
shown that that was which screws up faithfulness
so we must have the causal DAG
and c
that's kind of a no-brainer
you have to the rebels and you find independent news and they don't have an
idea what causes it
you have come to this talk figure that out it
so now the simplest example
i suppose
this is a set of conditional independencies
we have no independencies in other words the dependent
so when i say this set of conditional independencies is the empty set
i mean there are dependent
we cannot have the causal DAG in a
because if i applying the markov condition to that
its axis is independent of y
and that the dependency is not observed
so this with the causal DAG
causal markov assumption will not hold and we're assuming it does hold
so we must have the causal DAG in b or in c
x causes why why cause effect
now you may ask why why could we have a hidden common cause because before
in common cause with we correlate them with another right now i'm assuming that you
don't have common causes
so they make that assumption
which i can make you want to write
but of course i can conclude that there is a hidden common cause to assume
there is no such thing
so another if you want to have to be able to find the neck
that there are
correlated one causes the other you know which one
i suppose we have three variables now nonuniform we get things that are little more
and we know that x and y are independent
so the only independent sees the x and y are independent
there can be no edge between x and y
owing to the reason i just gave an example one of the edge from x
and y
the causal markov assumption we're not say the independent
right because
OK then example one so there can be an edge
there must be an edge between x and c and y and z owing to
the reason given an example two
once is no edge between x and y there's is no edge between x and
and the markov assumption with x the
are independent
and that's not one of our observed independencies
so the markov essentially be violated
and for girls process you can
that looks like this
if i have a picture here which is not
sorry this is not a visible
as i
yeah it should be
i hate it when people say that in talks but sorry just happened to be so
this is
i've taken this picture from from the pitch you see this option and williamson who is
was the inspiration student and what you see here is
here we have a gaussianprocess
this is a function drawn from a gaussian process
this function has the larger length scales
reproduce function by sampling from a gaussian process which has a large bandwidth parameter the
kernel parameterized have large bandwidth the functions that we draw from it oscillate slow
and this function has zero right so it it it oscillates slowly
they axis as its me
right so that would be
the function we draw from this model here
and now we plug this function into another girls process
and use that as the mean
the function of the girls in process
and we give the girls in process smaller length scales something that we sample from
the output will oscillate at a at a higher rate
but what will oscillate around not exist anymore but rather around this function
so we get something that looks like these these small weekly functions here you these
the red and green functions
so that way we can
we can model the problem where we have to timescales
something that
something that oscillates on two timescales ones
end and then larger time scale and we can split these up
now the um
the most widely used
hierarchical model and bayesian nonparametrics i suppose the hierarchical dirichlet process
the model works like this so we we remember when we sample from a dirichlet
process you this this was the formulation of the order parameter iterative process we saw
we have this parameter alpha
it was that the parameter which control
how probable it is to produce a new cluster
and then we have this
parameter gene knock here which is the distribution of these other atom locations right of the cluster parameters
we now sample
the idea is now that we sample that
the measure which controls the location of atom locations
from indirect process
can usually this is a parameter that we choose
but now is we we do this hierarchical you we
sample this measure itself from a dirichlet process
and i've drawn over here so you see
but in this picture here this is a sample from all represents a sample from
a dirichlet process are all a part of the sample
namely finally many clusters
finally many atoms
the locations here on the on the interval
these are the locations of of the atoms what i call theta yesterday right so
in this discrete random measures the location of the direct spikes
and the height
of these
of these bars here
are the weights
which correspond to the cluster sizes are the cluster probabilities
these are
locations of cluster parameters all values of cluster parameters and probabilities of the corresponding clusters
all right now we we take this discrete measure here
we plug it into a dirichlet process and we sample from there
what's create happen if we do that each time we produce a new cluster
be drawn from
the measuring given here and that is itself a discrete metric so we will always
when we produce a new class that we will always
produce a point that we have already seen in this matter
we have restricted the possible about the values of cluster parameters to these values
and so you see that
these are two different samples from there
and you see that the locations you exactly the same as up here
but what's the point that nothing changes was something changes and those are
the weights
because we we sample from this but we sample from the random
and these are not these are not the number of points that we actually see
these are the probabilities right so sample from that you get different we different weights
why would you why would you want to do something like that
and application of this is
a nonparametric
version of latent dirichlet allocation
and which is which is a topic model and i don't expect everybody you know
what they can allocation is i suppose lot people probably do but
basically what you wanted to hear is
in topic modeling
have that i guess that
the basic idea of topic modeling is
that if you want to
if you do
natural language processing you want to represent a topic
good way to do that is has a distribution over words
so that's the basic assumption of topic modeling topics are distributions over words
that means u
when you analyse a big corpus of text data
you basically extract all the words that occur in the data
and then you record how many times
does this but doesn't each word occur and that gives you a probability estimate of a probability distribution
and the idea is now that
remember yesterday we talked about this power laws
he said well in in language there are some words that occur all the time
and then there are some words which occur only rarely
and many of these terms are specialized now a few if you focus on a specific topic
right if you have some biological terms it overall in the language occur rarely but
in the in the context of biology it may be more frequent
and the idea is that you can use these frequencies to characterize
is a complete characterization of the talk
so the topic
in technical terms what does it mean the topic is a vector that represents a probability
it's a probability over all right so it's it's a very large very long vector
each entry corresponds to one possible route
but it is finite
finite length
and the entries are numbers
nonnegative numbers with which sum up to one
so it's a probability distribution over a finite number of events and these are the words
and then when you sample from that
use that has been
the parameter vector of multinomial distribution and sample from the nineteen
and now
one way that you can that you can
so in topic modeling if you want to represent
you represent then in terms of mixture models and that's
that was an idea that started
in the late nineteen nineties with the moral code
probabilistic latent semantic analysis
and that's very simply it's it's a mixture model of multinomials
and the way it works is
we first sample
the first sample the index of a topic
the topic is characterized
probability distribution over words
and then you sample the document from the probability distribution
so that's a mixture model representing documents
this more latent dirichlet allocation was introduced with based on the idea that there
using a simple mixture model is very restrictive because what is the assumption in their
this assumption that mixture model is
every data point belongs to one cluster right
people control the actions they can see
what you added
look at what i wanted to look at home in back
so if i showed confidence and at
you simply choose to ignore the focus on the one hand i'm sure
many of us have some
training and we just ignore it
now this is
almost instinctively when you look at the search results page i just social problems
and you know as sure
so in this sort of thing
even though
that has been shown to the users not making an impression users users are not
seen that
so in this sort of thing
what think well justified
will be at on
well what users actually
c had
and look at me
and understanding of get trapped products
following online advertising work when users
do not in fact
have had control
and the answer to this street before
the first part of the answer
is the massive scale at which online advertising history
it's essentially
percent to serve as the millions of users
thousands of years but as having billions of such transactions
between users as over the over the course of a month
it's essentially
destroying as many many times many many different users in the hope that something somewhere
some users are going to CBS
we have a good track record from source
so it has to work
he is a massive schemes
in in addition to have very low marginal cost
so the cost of serving any one given
one is that in one
people setting
in terms of one particular on
has to very
it has to be there
of the two thousands of minutes against showing that
plus you should not be way too much competition for
because if you spend too much effort to come up with the best possible at
for this content and the user simply chooses to ignore
and this is you have become a very low margin cost ways of showing that
and many many different actually many many different so massive scale and the marginal cost
kind of like this in this but then
this means that you cannot have human in the
it's just too costly and too slow humans
do any sort of data processing or even online
thinking of of
all of this has to be done
automatically on the fly
using very little computational effort
and the key here is to one
even a little bit even a little bit more
if we can come up with something that just barely crossed dependencies doing this can
translate into millions of dollars month
consider the massive scale which this process is that
and now there are many different ways we can think of quite one
the state of minas
one of we have
is to learn from
so typically
any any computation everything online advertising system which generate huge historical logs so lots of
the form that show this particular with this particular user who come from this particular
demographic when the user was actually looking at this point on this particular page and
so on and then
i showed this user either clicks on the not
billions of such transactions
this this this is starting to very noisy signals
it's very weak
but if we can extract some information on this
this this one based on the fact that we lot what is good at this
and this will lead us
in many games
even look
in terms of millions of dollars
just more satisfied users
and this is part of the reason why online advertising is becoming less important feasts
slowing economy is because there are lots of interesting open problems in a
and this has led to the birth of the new distance for
called computational
but computational
it's not a completely new
it's really more of an amalgam of these problems we have already seen so far
just with special add constraints so for instance
if i want to show that actually users initially and have to look at the
end of the set of all possible subsets of
text processing
maybe natural language processing and the forgotten what it's about
so the text analysis simple
i have restored is in some sense it is
so that can quickly retrieve the when it becomes the best for this
for some given content in some sense
so i to be able to do some large-scale information retrieval
have a good model of
what match what pages want ask
match the use queries and so on
so this request looking at all all sorts of historical data and coming up with
a good more
this is exactly what we do in statistical modeling machine learning models and so on
again optimisation problems become more for instance
one example would be that
instead of showing just one i want to show
two at the top of the words on the side so for that school
so how to optimize for this in a set of four hours
but these sort of according it each i want to show as diverse as possible
but also acts that individuals good so on so how to optimize for this same
set of facts i think is just picking up four
in this whole severity of
let's suppose that the result
of the measurement of each event is some collection of numbers some vector of number
that i'll call x
which with
and components but now the that the
elements of this vector can be completely different things so x one might represent the
number of neurons x two might represent the PT of of subjects x three might
be missing energy and so forth i just want to say that for each event
i measure some some vector of
now depending on what classifiers and i'm talking about
this vector x will follows some n dimensional joint pdf so if i'm if i
want to somehow
assume i'm only looking at pp goes to safety bar then x will fall some
joint pdf if i have a proton proton goes to gluino paris you will be
some different media
so for each reaction
i will get out label that some hypotheses with the hype what i mean here
by hypothesis is something that specifies the probability law
four x
so usually use sort of statisticians notation f of x given h zero
four is the null hypothesis or f of x given h one or some alternative
hypothesis those would be the terms that's a statistician would use in particle physics usually
we we say
that might be the type of event i'm interested in so i call that the
signal hypothesis
and the other events that i'm not interested in that's the background hypothesis so sort
of flip back and forth between using signal background and h zero h one
the important point being that the that specifies the probability law four
the observable
suppose you have
some data sample with two kinds of events corresponding to say two hypotheses h two
and h one
and suppose you want to select events of the type h one so you want
to somehow test h zero and rejected so as to retain
h one
here just symbolically are two dimensions of the state space x i and x j
i mean it could be many dimensions but there's just two dimensions and suppose that
the density
it is implied by
the hypothesis h zero
and that's the density that are implied by the hot hypothesis h one
right so how do you select the events
well what people usually start off by doing is just making some sort of cuts
in x space so what you mean by a cut based analysis is that
the decision boundary the the selection boundary in this space is just a set of
rectangular cut so it's it's a rectangular or in n dimensions i suppose hyper rectangular
decision boundary
but you can see that's not really necessarily optimal decision boundary here certainly not the
something similar might be a linear decision boundary you might say all right let's just
somehow try to separate them with the liner with with the hyperplanes
also in this case because this structure is kind of curves that wouldn't be the
optimal does a boundary to separate them you might want to have some sort of
a curve decision boundary
so that's the basic problem that we have to deal with in it in
event classification or more generally in setting up some kind of statistical test
now that surface that decision boundary
is some surface and in dimensional space so what kind of an equation describes the
surface in an dimensional space
if i have some scalar function
of that vector x equals the constant
that will define that defines some surface in the n dimensional space right
in that regard whatever that function is that describes the surface in question i can
i can use that function as a new random variable i call that year test
so that will be some given function
of the variables x and also a in just a few minutes some some strategies
for how to construct such functions
for the moment suppose that i've specified function
well specified function of random variables then you can work out its PDF so if
i if i know what the PDF of x is given ages
i specify that function
and i can work out the pdfs of
given h zero in the p fifty given h one
and so on
i might wind up with some pdf that look like this is something that piqued
over here
so assuming the hypothesis h one
something that's peaked over here is in the hypothesis h zero in each one
the two different things
so now this this decision boundary in this and dimensional space
has now been reduced to a single
in this one dimensional space so from the one in the one dimensional problem the
n dimensional problem somehow maps down onto a corresponding one-dimensional problem
and and this division of the x space or the t space into two parts
defines a statistical test
right so the idea is that the one half in which you would say
except the hypothesis h one and reject the hypothesis h is zero that's what's called
the critical region
the test of h there
so then you look at the data you you get your point in x space
that corresponds to a certain point the space and it falls in the region over
you would reject the hypothesis h zero in favor of the alternatives
h one
when i say that you will accept and reject different hypotheses there are certain things
you obviously don't always get the right answer
it can happen for example that the you reject the hypothesis h zero
but in fact that turned out to be the true
the hypothesis that was the real nature of the event
this is in the plane version of our algorithm or considering the local structure
only this is in the adjacent versions of our algorithm so the real whether do
one or the other is used to imply that you operations have to be added
at the end of the computation
so consequently we noticed simon and the implied edge assignment found by our algorithm
and need not necessarily correspond to the exact graph edit distance
so the crucial question is now
whether or not the accuracy of the also optimal distance that we found here remains
sufficiently accurate for pattern recognition application this is exactly what you want to find out
in our experiments
so here's the experimental setup
we use the knn classifier in conjunction with graph edit distance
so what demographics distance or exact graph edit distance and and then we address
classification problems
so we think that this classification accuracy given by the knn classifiers
is a good indicator of how good or bad our approximation of the exact graph
edit distances
so we had several meta parameter values that we have to
that we have to determine entities and we use the validation set and the results
that are reported x are applied on independent test set
so we use three other systems to compare our new algorithm with the first of
all of course we use an optimal tree search based on a star implementation in
industry search and then we have also true
suboptimal modifications of the standard tree search algorithm
which we refer to as beamsearch and pathlength sunbeam search which we are basically doing
is we're pruning the tree search and path claims we making reweighting of danger it
will pass in the tree
OK so he was the first data set is used
this is the letter dataset
which consists of graphs representing capital letter line drawings fifteen classes
so to construct these graphs we first manually
draw some prototype line drawings of each letter
and then we apply to different distortion operators on this prototype line drawings and so
we can obtain arbitrarily many
for each letter in arbitrarily high distortion levels you see we have applied quite high
distortion low so it's get it gets harder and harder to predict the real class
and finally to convert drawings into graphs we represent lines by edges and ending point
lines by not
so the results that you see here are
chief on high distortion levels
so first of all you see that our algorithms both the plain version and also
the adjacent version are very fast and they are much faster than the exact
and but they are also faster than the two suboptimal
modifications beamsearch and pathlength
so and when we are looking at the classification accuracy we see that the classification
of course is not negatively affected
so it is even increased
and it is statistically significantly better so when i first saw this we were very
surprised and thought maybe something wrong here and but we
i think we have found a good explanation for this phenomenon
so in this diagram here
you see dots and he starts represents the graph edit distance
between two graphs
so in the x axis you see
the found exact edit distance between two graphs and the y axis you see the
suboptimal distance found
between two graphs
so as you see we distinguish between entrance
distance is the blue dots and these are distances found between two graphs out of
the same class and we have interclass distance is the order of the red dots
and these dots represent distances found between graphs out of
different classes
so what we see is that the blue dots the intra class distances are low
so they are low in exact version but also the suboptimal version and what is
very important they are not increased these distances by our suboptimal version
but when we are looking at the intercluster distances they are quite high
so this is all right and they are even increased by the suboptimal version
OK so to summarise this means that the graphs in the domain of graphs i
re-arranged in respect to each other
and to simplify this we can say that in the
the classes are pulled apart from each other
and this is a welcome effect regarding the classification task so we do not claim
that this happens on every data set but it happens here
so choose to conclude the suboptimality of our algorithm here mainly leads to an increase
of inter class distances while most of the intra class distances are not strongly affected
the disease
this is a good effect
so we have tested our algorithm on two
other datasets the first the image datasets which represents which consists of graphs representing images
out of five classes
to convert these images into graphs we first segment down into regions then we eliminate
at hand if you ever complex cost function usually it's hard to optimize might have
many local minimiser good recipes from all over the world how to improve that and
in the end you are not really sure what what you should pursue an intern
in real life in this in the spectrum of of of complicated and simple models
and introspective problems with with the image interpretation one particular simple example is that you
take a cost function and it's just the some
of individual contributions from object i and this contribution this course contribution is is captured
here by the functional described by the function psi i conditioned on x y
that is actually sort of a cost function which which calculates the
clustering solution or the the segmentation solutions separately for every object and then it's up
to two
to get the course for the complete configuration
extensions incorporate neighborhood information in cluster assignments it's fairly clear that when you have a
situation like this you know these spirals there are already colour coded for you so
that you know what i mean by groups here then you want to have some
some some more refined properties which or a sort of more sophisticated more sophisticated criterion
to really define the group and it's no longer closing in the embedding space in
the two d space it sort of being being in a high density area that
high-density area is sort of a part of the spiral then you want to have
one of these arms of the spiral denoted one of them is one of the
here this this this example is is chosen to make clear that an object wise
evaluation of course is not sufficient you have to have the more sophisticated cost function
to handle a situation like this and actually we have we have proposed to model
for these for the spiral example a couple of years ago and you see there
are still some errors in here so so one of these green dots you actually
do laser into here
so one of the the green dots belongs to the spiral over there and it's
OK OK i mean this i mean this data point here you would probably say
this should be blue
it's the popularity of that model that screen but don't worry about it
so two two two two sort of set the landscape of way where we position
the segmentation problems in the classroom problems let me distinguish between two types of sort
of extreme two types of problems learning problem supervised and unsupervised problems in supervised problems
you have methods which are trained on standard of labelled examples so at least on
special cases you know what should come out you train that you have the problem
of noise in your data and then you have to make a trade of how
much you believe the examples in your in your training set and how much you
want to generalize to new cases
clustering belongs to different standing in clustering nobody tells you what the correct segments on
it depends on your application and you have to specify sort of a cost function
which which gives you a guide installed solution and this cost function h is is
is the input which distinguishes between good clustering solutions and then once in a sense
you have different cost function
for the supervised methods in the unsupervised methods and at that level of abstraction i
think one can compare and see what is really necessary in order to learn something
the problem specification what is given in data clustering i said already in classification you
partition your object space and you have these training objects from the supplies and the
key problem is how to generalize the partition to new objects so it's fairly clear
what you would like to achieve in in classification you would be you want to
make correct classification of future future examples
so in clustering
it's not so clear how you actually
how do you actually pursue these training these testing step here
you've unsupervised partitions of objects or the objects based on the quality criteria and how
often do you optimize the
cluster criterion that is sort of the challenge she but there is also a generalization
issue in unsupervised learning problems and i will come later to that now
you have these notions which are clearing classification is underfitting sort of a step in
between and is overfitting
and when i when i alluded to these notions of of of of classification then
what i basically meant is that on the training data the blue and the red
dots here this complicated boundary looks fairly OK you know none of the blues on
the wrong side and on right on the side however you you would not bet
your personal money on this classifier i'm sure otherwise let me know after that against
so so this is the overfitting situation
i make too much i extract too much information from my data and i will
be penalized on future tests of that of that classifier
and i guess it's fair to say that this is the key problem in machine
learning and it's sort of relates what i believe two of the of of the
most the issues in in computer science there is the computational complexity and involved which
has been put on the on the sort of the research landscape by people from
computer science in particular value and and and and the called community that so that
this computational learning theory on one hand and you have the statistical issues the statistical
learning theory problems how much can you say on the basis of noisy data and
how fast can you or how efficiently can you say that and the relation here
is not very well understood so far and i think this key problem in machine
learning in classification will come up also in applications like object recognition like segmentation but
it comes up in a more complex way
and we learn a lot if we start identifying what is the generalisation problem in
in vision in the oceans
OK now let me see
i have to rush little bit otherwise the seventy five not be reached the structure
is i i talked a little bit about this basic concepts and then i will
go through a number of of of clustering approaches all segmentation approaches and
i will start to say a little bit about optimisation much less than what i
presented at CVPR titterrell and i would like to spend a little bit more time
on validation of clustering solutions because i think the validation issue
GEM this is the stick breaking construction so it's the
distribution over probability vector where the first entry is gonna be drawn from a beta one
alpha and then the second entry is gonna be taking the the rest of the
probability mass and then break at some point which is drawn from a beta one alpha
and thus repeating this infinitely often what's the form stand for Griffiths Engen and McCloskey
basically the three authors actually they have kind of independently discovered this distribution and they
kind of explored it and then later on I forgot who was it like eitherAldez or Pittman
who decided to name it name this distribution after them yeah okay so in the
last little bit I'd like to tell a bit on the somewhat different
topic which is basically constructing random trees okay from basically coagulations and
fragmentations okay and trees are quite useful I guess we'll see a number
of this sort of trees in like things like hierarchical bayesian models where you have
where the model is defined on the tree okay but in in this case
what I mean is actually somewhat different is basically one where we'd like to learn
the tree structure from data that typically lives on lives on the leaves of the
tree okay so basically this is a problem of hierarchical clustering or hierarchical partitioning
and the way we're gonna do it is by using fragmentation and coagulation and
this view is quite nice and there is a quite is a unifying view for
a variety of bayesian nonparametric models for random trees okay as as we'll see
okay so let's start off by to by looking at random trees and trees
are basically so in in this context what we would like to do is to learn
to learn or to infer some tree from some data okay so in philogenetics you
might be given data on the various species and you like to learn about the
evolutionary history that relates one species to another species and we know that I
guess if you if you I presume that everybody here accepts the idea of
evolution if you accept evolution that to basically first approximation then the species
that we see nowadays as you look back into the evolutionary
history is related on this basically a philogenetic tree okay where the species
are kinda like much into the same species as you go back in time so
we have you know mammals out here and then much down to with reptiles and fish
and so forth and with other plants with plants and have very
far back in time long long time ago so this is a problem from
biology learning trees is also important for people who for psychologists who are interested in learning
how is it that we are able to construct hierarchies of categories of things like
everyday objects or of words of in general of concepts okay and so here we have concepts
which correspond to everyday objects that people might know about maybe children might know about
and we'd like to learn sums of hierarchy or a tree that that kind of
groups the different concepts together so here we might group that all the animals should
be together you know duck and chicken should be much together seal and dolphin should
be together seal and dolphin are kind of like you know sea animals here we have tiger and lion which are quite
different from the other animals because they are dangerous animals okay or these people perceive them as
being dangerous animals so they're not the same as cows and sheeps and pigs here
we have things like edible vegetables fruits you know like
various tools that people might use and and down here we have vehicles basically like
trains and jets and cars and vans and so forth okay so we would like
to understand how is that people can learn this sort of hierarchies in their head from
features of this everyday objects and again we'd like to infer this tree over this objects
there's of course been lots of ways of building these trees from
from data okay so I guess probably one of the first things that you might learn
in the introductory machine learning course would be things like the linkage algorithms where it's
basically a hierarchical clustering algorithm where you start off with every object in its
own cluster and there it iteratively find the two most similar clusters and merge
merging them together and that merging operation basically forms a tree so those are linkage
algorithms are I guess what are called algorithmic approaches basically somebody just tells you here
is an algorithm for constructing a hierarchy okay so that's really no no model behind this
and the q table
as the one rule for each state here and has one column for each action
we assume that there are only three actions in this particular example and quite a
few different states here
what happens is you
however given state and in this particular case this guy
it is in this
state is standing on the ground and the distance between the two opponents is say
three feet so that's why we're in this role here
and here are some exemplary q values for this role and
we choose the action with the highest state action value of course
well that's what happens
this guy grabs his opponent and
and now comes the reward for their reward this is the health bar of the
opponent and this is the health bar of our guys these the acting guide big
guy the other guys the victims
and you see no good i think other people's health was down quite a bit
more so quite resistant and easier the health bar went down a bit and the
rewards that of obviously translates to a positive reward for this guy here and so
now we can
observe the
next state now the distance maybe five feet in this guy's not so we're in
this role here now
now we look at in the school an example we take the best state action
value here which was the six this was the largest value of these and now
we have everything that we need for updating you need are we know our initial
state and q value
we know the new state represented by this and we know the reward
so now we can use this human learning equation
and what essentially happens is that the observation is OK in my subsequent state if
i choose the best action
that that will be worth six units
now i get an immediate reward for of ten units because i was a bit
too around the head of my opponent into the earth and so
they did this together gives ten plus six is sixteen so this is essentially evaluates
to sixteen
but this thing is starting point two so we will have an up to date
in the positive direction for this towards the sixteen
that's the whole idea of of
this update scheme
any questions about that
well don't be afraid it's
it's just a game so
what we actually did was to use the different representation of the q function
but that we first describe what kind of features we used so one thing that's
obviously important is the features the separation between the two players
because if far away then something different is a good move for
then if they are close for example when you close you might want to punch
while when you for part you may want to kick or you may want to
move closer
so another interesting feature is the previous action taken
and we probably took this also to encourage the rhythm to show some continuity
so the this is pretty much the previous action of the opponent
so then there are different modes in which you can be you can be standing
firmly on the ground you could be in the air because you just do the
fancy karate kick or you could be knocked on the floor in which case you
always has to be careful that unfair opponent may not kick you down on the
and another very interesting thing is the proximity to obstacle because in these games you
have certain world if you like a room training room and it is can be
quite unpleasant to be in the corner of the room with the back to the
corner and being punish they'd like boxing so there's definitely an interesting feature now we
selected among different actions there nineteen there were nineteen aggressive actions like kicks and punches
ten defensive actions like blocking or lunging
and there were some some neutral actions were just you know moving about stuff like
he added that
checking that when antibiotics the condition is satisfied
at the end of this process this process will end up with the maximum wage
which is not necessarily max actually
finding the maximum clique in graph is and and then you have problem
and p hard even to approximate
it's very very different
but finding a maximum clique it's the simple problem actually come from
so instead of
i really like i was taught standard algorithms for finding dominance
we follow quite different we transform
the combined total problem the purely combinatorial problem of finding dominant sets
into purely confuse optimisation
and once we done that we can exploit the full arsenal continuous optimisation technique is
available in a position to actually our problems will be a quadratic optimisation problem
and there are the zillions of algorithms for solving quadratic optimisation actually use a very
simple one is five from evolution
OK so
so now we are just seeing how can i transform
the know how can i characterize the the notion of dominance in terms of continuous
let's take an edge weighted graph g and that's
the the
the adjacency matrix of this graph
so let's consider this problem the problem of finding the maximum
of this quadratic function this is linear in
metrics for if you live
i can just say that
from ways to express a x
just so
four all
so all j
i j
x i x j
if you actually can also ride this in a different way
right this way
one of we are talking about with
i was sure this differently
later on we could go back to that
in this case it's much is symmetric canonical
with the zero that
OK so consider the problem of finding the maximum this quadratic polynomial homogeneous polynomial over
the standard simplex the standard simplex is a very simple geometric structure it's it's the
of the plane
of equation
some exciting equal to one this
it means someone will excite equal to one
so the play with that equation with the positive or of space
so we require that all x times greater than or equal to zero
this is an illustration of the stands in between and is equal to treat just
try and
consider this problem
and let me just point out that
other approaches to pairwise clustering notably
one hundred of years ago by and also by perronnin freeman ECCV
these european conference on computer vision
please do quite similar but fundamentally different quadratic optimisation
the basic idea in this approach was actually the sort of spectral class
these two
find the largest eigenvalue
and then the corresponding eigenvectors of the agency of the adjacency matrix a in this
finding the largest eigen value and the corresponding eigenvectors
they found by maximizing x transpose x
the standard simplex on the sphere
another thing is that this problem is computationally much simpler than that that problem if
of the probability function
and then we're going to introduce new variables v which is an velocities
the game to
the vectors that
like the velocity of the physical ball have affected position and then you can have
the velocity which is the speed in which is moving in the direction
and then we define
what we're going to do is find a distribution over both of these quantities
x b
i'm deliberately gonna skip through this two
quickly just to give you a flavor but i don't expect it to be able
to implement this and understand fully from this exposition say a
the joint distribution over x and b is going to be the distribution we had
multiplied by something related to the velocity which is going to be it's going to
turn out to be gas distribution
the joint distribution has the marginal
the distribution we care about and have another distribution to do with the velocity
then there's is a bunch of physics and actually is a bit subtle to see
exactly why it's valid that allows you to evolve
your position and your velocities
and the physical analogy that you want to have in your head is that you've
got a hilly landscape where low areas are areas of high probability both like to
roll downhill and go to areas of high probability
and you start the ball somewhere in the landscape and you allow it to roll
around so then it's going to want to roll down to areas of high probability
one symbols got up speed when it's going downhill will also go up to areas
of low probability again so is not an optimizer is not going to end up
just sticking made distribution
so a
this details
and i'm sorry but i want to cover all the things they
i just want you to i wanted to mention that even though i don't have
time to properly because it's very important algorithm
some of the biggest hardest problems so in the nineties there was a great advances
in bayesian neural networks which have thousands of parameters very high dimensional probability spaces with
lots of nasty ridges and multiple maintenance and using gradient information able to get very
very competitive performance of based network by using hamiltonian dynamics
using a gradient information for the toy picture of the sort of trajectories that you
might get so the pictures in lecture one doing metropolis and gibbs sampling on by
very gaussians and they all did very slow diffusions because they're constrained to me by
lengthscales the width of the gaussians
methods based on hamiltonian dynamics on a physical system are able to just
mean persistently along the distribution of made much faster progress
the disadvantages are that
you have to derive gradients you have to set various parameters to do the dynamics
of the system and it's more work and i know some of the people in
the room of use this in their research there found in a very well when
you get to work
OK so
this is just sort of an idea that is
this is something where some of the advanced research research machine and
markov chain methods is going to be you need to look at
clever ways of introducing new variables that will do different things we might make it
easier to complete your probability theory might make it easier to move quickly very different
advantages and this is where the bulk of my research has been one of the
i haven't i'm not going to talk about my research at all in this tutorial
but several of my research projects have been different ways of introducing auxiliary variables and
that allows you to do
all sorts of different things with markov chains
i'm going to take a break for
three minutes so document itself before it the question
that's the next section
that's what uncovering next after the break
so a quick break again out of my comfort viewing of conformal questions like you
OK i apologize the slightly whirlwind tour i'm really trying to give you just the
flavour for the things that are out there
the last section i'm going to spend talking about
one particular problem because
it ends up throwing up a lot of interesting issues which
i have a whole new area of MCMC research and the problem of finding normalising
constants and it's not
we call zero significance
the user has
so that
OK let's have this
prompted request
like so
she said she
or is there
it's exactly it's actually so the cross sections of the different physics processes
skate differently with centre of mass energy so for instance the higgs cross section
the blue blue express section increases by a factor of forty if you go from
tiverton to LHC
and the background only by a factor of ten
so that's for the WWD kitchen your better at the LHC is of any processes
that blue initiated you better at the LHC that the temperature on for processes like
whlch those o'clock initiated because if q q by going to w
and not only increases by a factor of ten this again related to the patton
flax for glance it increases a lot more about the lh
then for quarks
compared to the collider so
so only getting factor ten and the second but the background to wh production are
partially again
one could dominate anyway to the background are rising faster than the signal in that
case so it really depends on how
your signature changes with centre of mass energy and how your background changes and that
it is driven by the pattern flux
i have to question all
this is the
well it's
over the of
get your so called friend
that same
quantity occurs in like
bayesian approach as well yes i was doing it frequentist
if you want to say
so what
all these
she would
it's got to do
in the particular example that i think we're talking about where you're selecting events that
the hypothesis is the label which
tells you whether it was say an event of type h zero or an event
of type h one single event backgrounds and normally in the frequentist approach we don't
talk about the probability of the hypothesis you wouldn't talk about the probability that a
specific event is
signal event in the sense that you wouldn't talk about the degree of belief
that that is the single event
but notice in this case we're observing many events so this label or hypothesis is
in fact the outcome of repeatable observation so this is one very interesting example where
the same application of bayes theorem
makes sense
in both the frequentist context and in a bayesian context with only slightly subtle
in the interpretation of the results in one case if i say that the probability
that the event is a signal event is
such and such i mean if i look at many events
with similar data
and the fraction of those events that would be signal events would be
a certain amount i think it's exactly it's the same formula that i partially obscured
here but it's basically just based there
whereas bayesian would say no i have a single event in the data is fixed
now in my degree of belief that this event is the single event is given
by base there
but that's actually this is an example of events selection as is the case where
you have a perfectly frequentist application of those there
tomorrow tomorrow i'll talk about using bayes theorem in parameter estimation and then really the
distinction between the two philosophies becomes
a person
one way which
well i mentioned this OK so what i mentioned was the simple
multiplicative linear congruent shield generator and that was a very simple algorithm
you recall that the state of the generator was basically encoded by a single number
which there was just an update rule for that number
the periodicity the period of that sequence is basically close to roughly equal to the
the largest number that you can store
or law of of nature is a software program
and it valid if it if when you calculate the to the universe of the
experimental data at the time evolution of the physical system
you get exactly what you observe i mean what the reality is something the observations
are correct by the way i'm assuming there's no noise i'm assuming a deterministic world
and the thing about quantum mechanics
so the idea so in a way what you have here if you go back
to leiden it's the idea that god is the most perfect would be that here
you have the whole pattern evolution of the world
from the creation of the world until
now until you know the end of the world
the idea is that
that there is a simple program
that enables you to calculate this which would be the the beauty of the ideas
from the the idea the elegance of the idea that god used to create the
world or another way to put it would be the laws of physics
OK so the the assertion that the world is comprehensible understandable means that all of
this diversity
actually come from a small piece of software which would have the initial conditions plus
one of the laws
so then you you integrate to go forward from initial conditions calculating the time evolution
of the world in the case of the general model
to be more precise
it is i have a computer and what i explained to be a string of
zeroes and ones it will be a finite sequence of zeros and ones
and the explanation of the theory that explains these facts even if
the explanation will also be a string of bits
because you know a computer programming computer the spread of this
it was in one
let's look at this idea
that if a if a if the theory is our if laura theory can be
arbitrarily complicated than an ocean of theory becomes meaningless because there is always a lot
what this in this in this in this domain it's very
it's very clear what that means
because take a look
if you have a set of facts and you have and bits of facts
there is always
and then bit theory
there's always the trivial theory which says that these are the facts
you know it just put it just
so that's not about the theory that's not a valid explanation that is not a
law this does not have any structure
when does the facts have structure what is the pattern
it if the theory is much less than this
much less than this
much much worse than that
there's this idea of occam's razor right which is the simplest theory is best known
in this domain would say that the smallest program you measure the size of the
program the complexity of the program and that
and he would say that the most concise program the most compact program is the
best theory
that so called occam's razor
and i don't know how you spell that you know a lot of ways to
spell it
the cancer is
like it's of course knew about occam's razor but blade is saying something more crucial
what limits saying
it is
but there is always a lot of you know if you have and that there's
always a trivial theory
where is no compression where you just basically say this is it this is what
i saw
but that doesn't count because that's always that that's the way of saying
that's not a lot that's not structure that a pattern
you see
i mean something is always itself but that doesn't that doesn't but if you have
a much more so let me put it another way
another way to put this
and so the the
i'm losing you folks i can see the patient is
is dying
so let's put it another way how can we measure pattern with go back to
how can we measure
so i'm talking about
pattern in our toy environments
you folks are concerned with all kinds of patterns but i'm just going to talk
about the pattern in a string of bits OK i
a finite string
the question the way i measure patterns like this you have a computer and you
want to calculate this as the output is the result of the computation and you
ask what is the smallest program i don't care about time
i just care about the size of the program so i want the smallest program
the smallest program
that calculates that specific object that i'm interested in i what i'm
the idea is let's look at the size of the program OK so people right
that is the absolute value of p of p is the the program and i
compare that with the size in bits of the
of the bit string that i'm interested in
the question of whether this bit string has pattern or not how much pattern doesn't
have the ideas you compare these two numbers the number of bits in the most
concise program you compare that calculates that particular bit string you compare that with the
number of bits in that bit strings
the number of bits in the in the smallest program the carcass that the string
is actually much smaller than this has a lot of pattern if the number of
bits in a bit string is
essentially the same
the number of bits in this and there is no pattern
so what you the way to measure the amount of patterns
is you
subtract from the number of it in the bit string
you subtract the number of bits in the smaller
to calculate for that bit string of for that
a bit strange
and this number measured in bits the amount of pattern
so this number will be is essentially zero
the most concise program is the same size
but if
if the program is very very small
if the string can have in the in the in the extreme case as measured
in bits the amount of pattern can have
the minimum is zero and the maximum is the number of bits the and the
bit string so let me give you
two examples of this let's look at a bit string which has not out which
has maximum amount of pattern
a string of zero
you know and zeros
and then bit string consisting entirely of zero
has and bits of patterns
pretty much
because in fact
to be able to calculate this from my computer that i really only about log
two n bits telling me how many
how many there are
and if i o that's essentially very small compared with them
so the amount of patterns and minus log two n which is essentially an
which is essentially the length of the bit string so this between has a lot
of patterns
now the other extreme is you toss the coin independent also the fair coin and
you get something well here's the way let's look at intermediate cases
how about
how about a bit strange
well how about a bit string where bit is repeated
so you have you know you have one one zero zero every every
every two-bit so they have to be the same
but otherwise you have complete freedom
to immortality and it was like to get to
so neutrinos actually are happening all around us
and they are
less familiar than other particles because they are so
and reluctant to reveal themselves but it is possible
how we do that is something which we'll talk about the things that we know
about neutrinos
how do we know indeed neutrino is produced in beta decay well the answer is
that neutral state say his
beta decay
ten to proton emitting electrons going one way and the neutrino the other
and then upstream the target waiting and
neutrino hits the target
the reverse of beta decay
and turns back into
the electron
so you see that this sort of
the energy that sort disappeared
in neutrino here
reappears the balanced downstream so something has gone from here to here you can see
it directly but if you believe in the conservation of energy and momentum everything balances
that some unseen neutral object was transported from creation to
hitting something in these experiments we now know
that is not just electrons but there are two heavy versions of the electron called
the me one in the town
the same amount of electric charge
the same properties
in all other respects the best experiments we can measure
except that the me on is about two hundred times more massive than electrons and
the tower is
thousands of times more massive
the two thousand times more massive than electrons four thousand times the mass of the
problem as stated the same
the electrons
has this
neutral counterparts
called the electron type neutrino with a new subscript e the neuron has an analysis
one new subscript
the town has an analogous one new subscript ten
three times of neutrino feature which matches with the three times that
how do we know that
the question
i removed the slide to tell having that but i think now i didn't here
we know that because experiments
like the ability to get the nucleus
an electron positrons produced
the neutrino is long
and it produces electrons or positrons not neurons or towns
there are experiments for example
the primary so it can decay
into a me one
and a neutrino that neutrino hits something upstream it turns back into a mu r
and we know from experience that originates from eleven states that there are
so is much harder to detect and measure for technical reasons but otherwise pretty much
the same
where the decay of a massive particle can turn into
a tau particle neutrino tau particle neutrino and if the neutrino hits something upstream it
turns back into attack
so these neutrinos are clearly different they
how a memory of how they were born which they transport them and reveal
later on but precisely what the nature of that is we don't know
so here is the summary of where we are with the fundamental
particles of matter
the electron as it has to have versions mu and tau
there are three varieties of neutrino
one for each
and this little family we call the leptons so lepton
is a generic words
particles like the electron and neutrino
it's been half
they feel the electromagnetic and weak forces
should say that more carefully they feel the electroweak force
neutrinos which have no charge do not feel the electromagnetic they feel weak
the london towers feel the full
panoply of electromagnetic and weak
they are all called leptons
they do not feel the strong force is the
forces that originate in the color charge of quarks carry
anything which fills the strong force
which is what's been half is the clerk
the up and down movement they live inside neutrons and protons
matters we know it they have heavier versions
the one with charge positive two-thirds
has a heavy version called charm the heavier version called top
identical in all respects except mass
pretty much
the down quark with a negative charge one for also has to have versions called
strange and bottom
o strange particles that i mentioned at the end of the first lecture discovered back
in nineteen forty seven in cosmic rays we now know are strange because they contain
strange quarks together
it was not formats
talk would be
pretty much the same
down strange in boston pretty much the same electron muon tau pretty much the same
but it's mass discriminates this is the beginning of the idea that i mentioned at
the end of the first talk but it is mass
which is the
inside the present standard model of particles if it wasn't for mass
they would all be
much the same
what it is there are three varieties and not more
from source
terminal then
you don't have been looking at this
more mathematically
later on
we iterate until all the least one saturated age no more
past the remaining
up along edges which is actually
that's the match max flow
i mean come
algorithms and
the set of talk about that
more rigorously
well as i said in
incidents in nineteen sixty two also probably the least then
so the idea is to use now by boykov and kolmogorov
efficient algorithms that vision researchers and
perhaps we use because
is freely implement freely
which i'm sure you'll find a few
look for the names boykov and common graphs
and we use is typically in graph cuts off
there also this one goal which i don't know much about
parallel in power law
examples of graph cuts in vision i'm sure this is a very incomplete graph cuts
is used all over the vision
these days
a number of things that i am able to show that it's useful in
it's just the fraction
one of them is another example
we looked at just
static textures
this interesting work on
video textures
by various people and i also name
rick szeliski as one of the people who has worked on this and also
the idea being you have video
and you
videos of them
so this is just an example flame or something like that and you want to
video just goes on forever
so you
could stacks together
taken taker
a clip
it represented by
the time dimension being the horizontal dimension here
put another one and then work out where can i cut
between these
two are
if the most
the way that use these notice then you describe this as an example graph cuts
i looked
so has this he says three d generalization image cool
it is
very good
project or
result from
michael code as i mentioned before from microsoft
well which included next thing which see graph paper on this where he took a
if one of make panoramic from images right so the question is a digital camera
you put things up and make a large image what about
so he did the single video panoramas where
take a video try
things are moving around in course
and he makes
continuing the you can just look around in this panorama and they always be
something moving in that area will go on forever so for instance one example is
what i haven't got here friday show examples of wavelets beech trees
flags waving
in the harbour at to
it's very impressive the way it's done
by doing this
making cuts in two dimensions going the spatial dimension of the image also time dimensions
working at high
these things together because it can't be done
perfectly all the time you have someone walk into this room
and out again
show that to forever doesn't look persons continually walking and out of the city but
it's a continuous action like waves of trees waving you don't notice anything artificial about
the whole thing looks like
so you lose b
it may not be a very accurate approximation of classification accuracy but it is also
so it is easier to talk to
so such functions you use the gradient hypothesis or use some global optimisation techniques
so we have to use gradient this
you can somehow be
well of course you want it to be differentiable but even that is not possible
for it to be differentiable almost everywhere then you finances optimisation techniques to minimize it
but you can also use
two days but the problem is if you many parameters where it is created what
is goal of this technique actually don't need to use these functions can directly what
you just try different parameter sets and she classification accuracy
user things like genetic reasons to mutation crossover to go to the next parameter set
created in this world but source code
is usually i don't know
and although these kind of feature scaling
the reason is
if we
if we do this kind of issues scale which is more complicated kernel so so
we are going to want to spend more inference
then the situation using only one single got to know your way to work
but really we we don't know we we never where they were given that the
performance is
it just as i said earlier this morning as so in designing machine learning and
reasoning you always searching for the better than simplicity and performance so
but you know what we are doing this
we try to use the more complicated
no we will never know if it performance is going to be better for that
this is a lot more studies to which
so we have to collect a out of bag benchmark datasets and try to try
to come to see
if using only one single kernel parameters go into the surfaces seriously of
feature scaling then will
we will one using feature scale is very significant better so we have that stated
and we are sure that maybe this time you have to do it by using
only one single got universities fine form
plus you want to try it
one is not is not very easy
there's another people kernel combination
so the question is how see something like this
so we we are considering
i kernels
you may seen is
obviously this going to be you know
o which is a plus sign
the combination so you with constant here that those coefficients this is like a linear
combination of several kernels
and there are ways of of such accommodation and assimilation p one
so using such things as well if you a k one k the other kernels
that is a linear combination is still OK
then the the
i want to say that this is actually
related to parameter selection and we just discussed
you for example you can see that at the kernels with different kernel parameters here
that this is you can always
parameter gamma one
these are you could always cover with parameter gamma i try to do a a
linear combination of
well so this is like to select the common parameter is you've got what is
good then this kind of constant then
in which we identify this stewardship because one another he eyes they should be close
to zero
so that's why is it so so that's why
this kind of companies using this is somehow related to parameter selection
so the reason why they should be scrapped kernel combination technique is used to the
machine learning community quite a few people work is one of the newspapers today
the idea by forming this kind of things into a convex function with conflicts with
his earlier music
we talk about parameters actions
this functional parameters you usually can
but this
for this kind of kernel combination which they can be formulated
only function of those you want to you
it is a convex function when c is fixed so still not good as the
sequence where penalty promises based on this function is a function that says may be
easier to be minimized by
it is of course the idea
programming problem optimisation so problem is a convex problem but the computational cost is also
quite high it's not very easy problem to be solved so it is clear
this kind of approach is going to be going to be very useful in practice
i think we need more empirical studies just like what i said earlier for
to feature scale
we may to collect also so as system and there was serious comp sch this
the second is the common kernel combinations
is come to regular
just prior to selection
to the average
many more
a lot
so i think that the number of support vectors are same
well it could be done
so you only uses one another
well i don't
clear it is that you one
so it is not only k one only needed
so the percentage of instances your support vectors it is increasing use of combinations where
this is going to be up or down the i don't know and i don't
decent work in this class and most of you have the ability to do good
work and some of you have a fair chunk of you have the ability to
do excellent work but may take some work on your part to get to that
the last thing i should say about the grades is why do i do this
really i try to do it as a sign of respect
for you and that may seem like a surprising to say what it just sort
of going on my little gleeful manner but i'm going to fail all of you
i mean
it's worth i think you guys are so
you're so
you've got and sold
so far
on your ability
many of you have learned to coast
and it's not doing you any kind of service to let you continue coasting my
goal here is to be honest with you
are smart enough probably most if you pull some sort of be without a lot
of without breaking into a sweat is not of significance sweat
so be it
but it's just lying due to pretend that excellence
in philosophy
so what i want to do in this class is be honest with you and
tell you you really don't work to be extraordinarily proud of yourself
first all you've done something OK or what you've done good work admittedly it's not
great but you don't good work
that seventy five percent of the great is the papers the remaining twenty five percent
grade is based on discussion section
now that's a lot of your great to turn on discussion section and so the
first thing i need to tell you is i really mean it
if you block discussion section your grade will suffer
so it's worth knowing in a general way what you need to do
there good grade discussion section and here answer is perhaps the obvious one
you need to
you need to come to discussion sections having thought about the lectures
having done the readings having thought about the questions that they raise
and you need to calm discussion section then prepared to
this week's set of issues you need to listen to what your classmates are saying
and say
why you disagree with them and not just that you disagree with them but to
raise an objection or
why you agree with them and when somebody else attacks and said i think that
what john was saying was a good point here is how i think he should
have defended his position or what have you you need to engage in
philosophical discussion
if you're not participating in discussion section
you're not doing what this section is there for
philosophers love to talk and we love to argue and the way to get better
thinking about philosophy
it is by
talking about philosophy and so i put my money where my mouth is i'm saying
look that an important part of the class so important that it's going to be
worth twenty five percent of the great
again it doesn't mean this is slightly different from the papers it doesn't mean that
you've got to be brilliant philosophically to get in a rather you've got to be
a wonderful class citizens
to get an a for discussion sections and so they put it back that input
is when the syllabus sort of participation and here i mean sort of you know
respectful participation not hogging the limelight but the participation
you can improve your grade but will lower your grade
non-participation or not being there that will lower your participation grade in any question about
i'm sorry to have sort of along gloom-and-doom but it seems that it's only fair
to let you know what you're getting into one of the remark about the discussion
sections the way i think of it is like the conversation hour for your foreign
language class
many of you have heard of what class before
it affects you
maybe fifteen percent of maybe twenty percent in most of you have not
that's pretty normal i don't go in the discussion section thinking all i can talk
i don't have any background philosophy never done this sort of thing before that's true
for most of you
the way you get better is by
talking philosophy
next remark this this is just one last connection with god great this is the
initial philosophy class the crucial point about intro is it means first class in philosophy
does presuppose any background in philosophy doesn't necessarily mean easy
some of this material for some of you is going to be very very difficult
and although the number of pages that you'll have to read are not there's not
a lot
probably typical b fifty pages may be less
it's from anything that fight dense material and
i don't really have the fantasy that many of you will read this stuff twice
if you had the time to do it that would be a wonderful thing to
philosophy is hard stuff to read
a remark about this being into into classes is that its introductory and that the
issues that we're talking about our kind of first
run through
every single thing that we discuss here could be pursued at greater depth so for
will spend whatever it is maybe we can have talking about the nature personal identity
two weeks
but one could easily spend an entire semester thinking about that question alone so don't
come away thinking that whatever it is that we're talking about here lecture is the
last word on the subject rather it's something more like the first words
actually one of the work about what what about the readings and the lectures
of the characteristic function so well sorry and the moment generating functions
and this is this is simply due to the fact that you know the sum
the density of the sum is equal to the convolution
all of the of the densities
and now in the fourier transformations convolutions are transformed into products
so that's why in the domain of characteristic function so a moment sorry moment generating
functions is this some which implies the convolution in the density domain is simply a
and of course if we have a product then for
means that that is for the cumulant generating function we have a sample
it is the sum and because the information is simply a linear thing you do
it separately for each them into some
that's why you will see that became as the sum some
sorry commitment
the sum will be equal to the sum of the components
and the point is that in the second when n is equal to
for the second well actually well start when n any equals one
the first derivative so that this is simply to me
and when it was sold
what we get is the variance so expectation of
x squared minus
the expectation it says what it and now what happens is that if you can
equals if any course three well in that case actually so this is in if
we have
if you have a zero mean
zero mean variables and we only get the expectation of the of the pilots that
moment and now when we can equals four then we have so that's idea the
and then the fourth order cumulants equals
as written down there
but it's is all about this idea of
of characteristic functions
that the characteristic function of a sum being the product of characteristic functions so taking
organisms it's some of kind of some of the logarithms of characteristic functions and so
when you when you then you can make any kind of linear transformations and you
still have this amazing property in particular can take you can take the derivative and
evaluate them at any point
well you develop them at point zero because that's the brightly by far the simplest
thing to do if you tried to evaluate that at any other point you will
get into a lot of trouble
the reason why
one city
well in
it's just that too many distributions in practice are symmetric so it uses skewness will
not work when you when you happen to have a symmetric distribution
so we can we can we there's no problem we can we can develop a
method for ICA estimation where we play everything where i want to talk about the
kurtosis we can always replace it with skewness but the problem is that those things
those methods only work when you have non symmetric densities and we fortunately unfortunately we
have quite open symmetric densities and so we want everyone to have a general purpose
method we cannot really use skewness at least we cannot use skewness alone we could
use some kind of a combination of skewness kurtosis
so as i mentioned that his skewness because skewness is zero
so then now you might ask that's how do we know that the process is
not zero
maybe bigger well we will see later that then with we have is given as
as zero then we get into kind of then the midst where we just you
know that generates objective functions well it's just that
it's just kind of
empirical observation that most often when you have nongaussian random variables they have non zero
skewness is that every non-zero characteristic
it not necessary to show you can construct some kind of
non gaussian random variables that have exactly zero kurtosis but we just kind of hope
we don't need that kind of area
these properties here are basically true for any cumulants
well this property is true for any equivalent and then this simpler homogeneity property is
true for any component but then this exponent here will be also the
order of that commitment
OK do you have any questions on this cumulants stuff and so on
so actually much before actually is a very old concept it it has been useful
for almost perhaps perhaps even one hundred years before
the invention of ICA
one of the reasons is that it's kind of it people have used this isn't
some kind of intuitive characterization of the nongaussianity of distributions depict people talk about the
book of distributions which have positive kurtosis and negative kurtosis having kind of the typical
forms of pdf so when you if you measure the kurtosis of the distribution and
you see that it negative then you intuitively understand something about this here you have
some basic examples
so this
all this
probability density
is called the laplacian probability density but it's actually write down the
the distribution function perhaps
so it is also called the double exponential
density because it is simply the exponential density like on two different on two sides
so the pdf is given by
some normalisation constant times the exponential of a function of
the absolute value of x
and here we go well here we can have some kind of variance
variance too and this is what is that what is the scale
but the point is that this is like in the same vein gaussian case we
have square but here we have just the absolute value so that's why that's why