it's trying to do
believe this is easy
no hidden problems
maximisation using derivatives and set to zero
given that most likely set but instead there's a there are
some issues of variables
these theories are
analytic candidate closed form so we apply the expectation maximisation algorithm
which means maximize the lower bound on the log like sort of maximizing that maximise
the log likelihood that's the case the exact same problem
we apply
jensen's inequality to rewrite
this is the expected
complete likelihood
but some KL divergence between this
proposal distribution and the posterior over the hidden variables given some
so this turns out to be a lot easier to work with then this this
is a function or some proposal distribution q when he very
that i want
maximize and some say that this is a function of two variables q theta which
is always less than the original one
the data
so instead of maximizing one thousand
or the fate of the log likelihood of data maximize this
pounds which has two parameters
this proposal distribution of what my guess is the distribution of the hidden variables
that's the q and then the parameters for this
lower bound
so this looks like this
axis parallel optimisation we maximize over q
that pushes lowerbound maximization the we keep pushing upward slowly in
increase by iteratively increasing this thing
every set up here we first maximize over q
this gives us the best rescue the best fit the best universities in order
and this is easy to maximize their own easy to maximize here except
i can get stuck in local minima so we you with the standard guess
and know this
q this status this each that is the best here
the start of the place to get to the global optimum
and what's going on in the e step for maximizing this functional
distributions of hidden variables and parameters
and it turns that the most likely the highest value of this function is one
that the q distribution equal to the
posterior distribution over the hidden variable given the observed variables and current guest tomorrow
so the stakes
the lower bound
and maximize such that his log we surface
this is the right
functions as l
the capital of functions
it touches makes this were more than just the log likelihood and then we maximize
i say that these are the people or lower bound
maybe the best model
see it is that
and then you
train your model so that's all there is to be seen as and the end
of the day doesn't three he's that
you need to do no matter how hard the network gets
fundamentally maximizing this and maximizing this
and running just to show them because
we need xh given xt
and that was the marginals conditionals we got a
so that's the
all closed world that we need in terms of bayes next tools obviously there's extra
so we dynamic bayes nets will
just to keep things simple that these are just things that are unrolled in time
so of the network of static variables
you've got this
timestamp for every single variable
and this is time people zero articles one to three was three
and really was one
something is happening in time represented as a random variable you know
the probability distribution
and this can continue indefinitely
it's a really long time series
so the
two classical example of dynamic bayes nets are the hidden markov model over here
this is an yellow means
this is in state
that involve markov dynamic
so the current state depends on my pasta
once on the current state i generate an observation relating to my
current state
so imagine this somebody
we cannot directly observe the happy sad control but we can look at how much
they're smiling down here
and so to evolved from happy to neutron from trolls and jump back and forth
between extremes
and so there is some kind of
my assumption here can have evolved to be
s one s two to describe the state transition matrix given s two of how
person smiling and then as three persons
frowny surfaces are observations
but but but that's a very much
so while providing is concerned so for most of its history mathematics has been explicitly
so for example you could geometry there are two types of theorems there i mean
you know sometimes are called on to show that
geometric configuration certain properties other times are called on to construct an explicit symmetrical object
but the proofs and show you how to construct it similarly now to bring out
rules current concerned with solving equations analysis and probability you're trying to calculate passing trajectories
and probabilities and so on i was only developments in the nineteenth century that inaugurated
methods that that you know we now characterize being infinitary or abstract conceptual nonconstructive set
theoretic or predicate of and so on and whatever they do one side effect of
these methods is that they tend to suppress or sometimes completely eliminate quantitative quite computational
and i was program
again on the surface was folks questions as the consistency of the new methods but
i think it's better to view it more broadly is trying to
address these these these dramatic changes in nineteenth century mathematics and try to reconcile sort
of the abstract infantry
view of mathematics with with the feeling of mathematics should have
concrete computational content
and so you can view the program is trying to
recapture explicit computation so you want to have your cake and eat it too you
want to allow the the set theoretic
methods but
but have some kind of concrete understanding or interpretation
so it's not surprising that
that help its program in the twentieth century was largely a matter of foundational reduction
initiative in principle if you can prove something using non constructive or infantry methods you
know in principle you can reduce it to two explicit constructive reasoning
proof mining today aims to put these insights to good use so as we heard
in or call box talk so for example extracting explicit quantitative information from abstract
four infinitary nonconstructive arguments or as low as five extracting metamathematical metamathematical useful uniformities in
you can also be the program is interested in developing infinitary methods that are better
suited to
to addressing finitary combinatorial or analytic you find problems
and finally
you can also view the program what interested the programs as well as developing means
of interpreting nonconstructive developments for example in computer
commutative algebra described his talk in algorithmic and computational terms
and so along the lines of the delhi concerns that you know like to sort
of call your attention to the the the issues and big questions that are being
so harold edwards once once quipped to me that is so some that was remarkable
person who was very much influenced by nineteenth century sensibility anyone script to me that
will you wouldn't have to mine proves
if you know for these this explicit quantitative information if only we just did your
proofs in such a way that you preserve that that explicit quantitative information all along
but of course the mathematics today we don't whatever reason we we find it useful
to us
to use abstract nonconstructive methods
and so i think so for mining i think you can view it as a
way to sort of understand what is lost when we go to abstract infinitary methods
and at the same time you know what is is that we gain
from the use of those methods and finally you want to sort of minimizing losses
and maximizing game so the question is you one so even if we allow ourselves
to use infantry methods proof mining aims to see if we can recapture some of
the quantitative expose information
that's lost
so no topic on discussed briefly is formal verification and automated reasoning so the phrase
is used most broadly to describe a branch of computer science that uses formal methods
to verify correctness
and verify correctness in practice can be one of two things so one is verifying
the correctness of hardware and software to design relative to specifications to have specification you
have a description of the circuit and you want to prove or verify the circuit
does what it's supposed to do which is something that is all the more important
if the circuit is you know running a nuclear reactor flying an airplane so you
want to have some kind of formal guarantees that your designers is correct but it
can also has been taken to mean verifying the correctness of a mathematical
and so today interactive proof assistants have been developed that really do both
there's there's much more common between those two
that then you might think
and so you focus most in the mathematical side but the ideas
formal verification is not supposed to eliminate mathematical understanding or take the place of ordinary
mathematical proof or anything like that but rather you only in recent years there has
been increasing reliance on computation and mathematical arguments and there also have been i to
say getting there are there proofs rely on a good deal of very difficult and
and delicate calculations
and so you think you want to think of formal verification is a tool to
help ensure the correctness of the is as approved check
so again not science applied mathematics but but but in so far has have incorrect
arguments is important mathematics having computational systems to verify correctness is is a good thing
and the idea is what sitting in interactive proof assistants are actually constructing a formal
axiomatic proof as you go
somewhere in the bowels of the computer there's actually a data structure that you can
you unwrap and find yourself facing formal axiomatic proof
and what the computer does is also first one has to keep track of your
that is your axioms and the rules and checking applying them correctly but keep track
of what you've proved and what you in your definitions
so one line computers much as you can do that
and then and then performing detailed calculations you fully automatically but then you want to
know you i don't want to sort of way program and run it you want
to have some kind of verification program is the the calculation it's doing is is
giving you the result you think it is
and all of these i maintain require a better understanding of mathematical
language that
let me let me emphasise that technology is not ready for prime time it still
takes as suggested still takes much more work than one would like to check even
you know straightforward mathematical inferences
but i think the time will come when it will when formal verification will be
commonplace in mathematics and in the near future as i said there are arguments that
are very fiddly calculations i or arguments that rely on a good deal of kind
of computation
we're already formal verification is is starting to show
its utilities and so on so on number of interesting things have been formalized date
when i let me just mention that there are a number of interesting projects along
the way so she was going to a is is right now within a few
months certainly within the year of the verification of the feit thompson which first or
purposes was a landmark in early an important landmark step in the classification of finite
simple groups tom townhouses similarly pretty close to having full verification of this proof of
the kepler conjecture ministerial mentioned in this talk about but sky has launched an interesting
to develop new foundations for algebraic topology and perhaps beyond relying on the on the
simple idea that you can view dependent type theory as a calculus for reasoning about
topological spaces and continuous maps between them
and then you could model that we're in hmm
now in multimodal inter interactions and interfaces you in general have more than one of
such streams to model at the same time so we need another notation
so the notation here is to introduce another viable which
you have now
a set of sequences and each
a set of sequence
it is and you may have for each of them and so such so if
we take an example of one set of sequence could be this presentation regarded by
that guy he recorded the audio and video so you have two streams of information
for this
particle and then in the other room there is another one recording another event we've
also audio and video so that next to a set of training examples
and so these are the two labels here this is the evidence and this is
the kind of tree we have
audio video
that's why we need so many indices
and in the same way as for HMM GMM is we need to
to define what will be the task in past will always be basically the same
we want to compute the likelihood of our data
this is often called the inference problem
and we want to train
this model that's going to maximize
that likely would
over the training set of a set of strings
so this is the likelihood so it's going to be the product all are sequences
and these are the set of sequences
for all the
and here training is to search for the best parameters of that guy
what are the
the options that we have the simplest one
which many people use because really it's very simple is called what we call early
integration hmms so in in fact is going to be a simple HMM so we
all know how to train an HMM is very and it has been used for
twenty years we know how it works for all these reasons might be a good
choice for you
and but you need to make some assumptions
the basic assumption is that is that
you are going to assume that all
so for instance for this evident
he's regarding your doing the video
you're going to assume that you're doing the video are
i have the same frame rate how they are recorded at the same time case
but you meet you're going to need to
extract them at the same frame rate this is not often very good because we
know that the old information
it follows something much quicker than the video information but let's suppose that you agree
with that anyway then in that case you decide that you are one frame of
information contained both the audio
and the video and basically we
we call that early integration because we're going to integrate the audio and video
before using them into the model
so there we decide before when we extract the data that they are all going
come from the same model doing the video
so in that case we have a single emission distribution and the transition distribution and
we have our HMM and we work
with it
and we're happy
this is the first solution that the solution is
so called multi stream HMM
which has been used to also in speech and in many other cases in that
if we have node u in video source what you would do is that you
would train an HMM for each of your sources separately
assuming that because they are they are not related to each other during training
you're going to have to hmms
one for the old you one for the video
and separately you're going to maximize the parameters of the reduced sets of sequence and
a set of video sequences
without knowledge of each other
into this training
and while
during decoding you are now going to assume that they come from the same
hmm so you're going to create the kind of but the
we're because you
in order for this to work you need to have the same kind of insurance
so if you have a free state here going to have to restate here
and during decoding you're going to force them to go into the same state your
new information in the video information are going to go into the same state
during the decoding so that their
they are
this is very simple to train because during training you have
so you have an separate
problems which you can solve using each of them in hmm but
during training this is simply the complexity
of the normal HMA
times the number of strings you have and we know how to do that very
if you consider that you can have these two levels if you do these pure
telling OK to pure this
seven pure p three has you find these values here
when you compare with experiments it seems to be that is close to these ones
so under that the differences do due to the mixing of the river
so that's why you can say that you have a skin like that either seven
health minus
and once that's three have minus so it's not like that you have
isomers here runs state here so that means
depending on the nucleus you're you're studying you can really had different features
and that was not expected by the calculation before the experiment
so now concerning shape and fission isomers
in the eighties and nineties there were extensive search for all these shape isomers
because of two reasons because first you had a very clear signal so it was
very clear experimentally
the second point
is that you have something collective so that you can really compare with
approaches where you treat only collective motion to to really
look at this part of
of nuclear feature
and what people have observed for example in this region of mercury and lead
is that you had some bands
so exciting bands very regular
and it was interpreted in terms of these men based on the shape isomers here
and then you have a professional bands
if you calculate the deformation you really have stupid information
so that means that you have the big axes which is twice
so small axis here
you see that that's what the first picture presented in the first lecture where you
have the detected photons depending on the energy here
and you see that it is the signal is very clear you had this speaks
very intense because it's it's a collective and so you really have favored the case
in into inside these bands so you don't have to continue rates going everywhere you
really have these band that
that comes out here
you see that you can produce up to sixteen spain sixty age for so very
excited states with high speed
so this is represented like that you have a rotating nucleus excited repeating it is
that the we need some photos to go back to its ground state
fission isomer so this shape isomers that are observed in actinides many calculations have been
and what is here in the difference between the state and this one
i minus ground state here
this is bloody this difference here depending on different nuclei from w to nobility
you have only a few experimental data piece open symbols here
you have a few in uranium petroleum helium no here
the point black point are for theoretical prediction
so you can see
two things first agreement is not about here so you can think that the here
you can make reliable predictions
also you have these decrees here of the energy of the isomer when you increase
the mass number
and you see here three points where you have negative energy
so negative energy mean that the state is buildings one
so i mean that this is the ground state because the ground state is the
state that has the minimum free energy
so it mean that what you think what the eyes and there is in fact
the ground state
people were really interested in that
and that
there have calculated people have calculated the lifetime of the state because
you need to know the light and in fact it seems to be that it's
not about bound state budgets on the reason and
because if you continue sufficient barrier
courting insufficient value it goes like that are not like that
you can go here very easily so it will go through fission
so this is only a reason and and and then you can use with vision
but many many papers were published containing that point because people have made the same
calculation for very high them
z equals great hundred two hundred two
very very ABC's them and they have found this feature
and so it was very important because when people experimentally want to study and to
heavy elements what they are looking at it the alpha decay
so they do fusion and that is supposed to have populated
created a very heavy system
and then it will emit alpha alpha alpha alpha two and known
then the and then you reconstruct that and then you say OK if
created these
very ABC stem
but then
if you have a superheavy that goes from fission and of course we have then
it completes the agenda where you want to
two to study them to prove that you have created this
OK so that's why
it was really interesting
and it seems to be the same that
the states is not do not have sufficient lifetime
to be considered as ground state and the reason and even
in these superheavy nuclei
concerning these fission isomers is also very important for applications when you want to know
very precisely the cross section
so cross section
what happened to this reaction when you change for example the the energy of the
projectile this is the section for neutron induced
fission on uranium two hundred thirty eight
and you see here that you have the first when two different states here two
different isomeric well
when you have seen the the labels that correspond so that do have the same
you have structure the cross section
so that means that the process is more favored are in favour of when you
have live inside the same energy and it's really changed
the cross section
so when you want to have a evaluating data very precisely you need to know
precisely the position of these things
i going out to shape coexistence
shape coexistence is when you have
people have talked about strictly exist and when they have observed
sierra vista second requested that at almost the same energy as the ground state
it was an expected if you look only and the single particle levels so
this is all you should have quite existence of the phenomenon that you don't know
they have been discovered that when you look at the single particle levels you see
and if that's not enough
it turns out the mean is also involved in
working memory
dealing with novel situations in attention deficit hyperactive disorder and schizophrenia
in depression anything you want basically anything that people care about in the brain dopamine
is part of it
and this may
it sounds crazy but actually the brain only has
four different neuromodulators there
neurotransmitters which are ways in which are molecules by which one neuron
communicates with another neuron but the four neuromodulators are molecules are sent all over the
place and you might think if there are only four of these in the brain
they must have really really important widespread functions and effect
a lot of processing in the brain so it's maybe not so surprising the dopamine
is related to all these things but still
it makes neuroscientists really want to understand
how does what it does and how we can cure
the situations where does the wrong thing
so as there are many functions are many hypotheses or i should say as there
are many scientists there are many hypotheses
and we'll all go through all of them for lack of
only talk about the first two
but just to
put these on the board and so you know that although i'm going to tell
you that i think this one is true it doesn't mean that it
but there are others to consider
so originally in the eighties
the first part consists about dopamine will not the first
the very influential hypothesis was called the anhedonia hypothesis
and the idea is
the inability
to experience positive emotional states so usually if you eat something nice or you
i have some sort of positive experience with another person or whatever you feel good
about it and only at this stage where you don't feel good about things that
used to make you feel good
what i saw is that
neuroleptics which are drugs that are antagonists to dopamine so they stop the function of
dopamine in the brain these drugs cause anhedonia so cause people to not enjoy things
that they used to enjoy life
and so that
that was
the reason is to suggest that
i don't mean
maybe it has something to do with the dynamics are with enjoying pleasure in the
perhaps the last movie know there will be another movie later
is a movie from peter shizgal concordia here in montreal
and what you're seeing here is the rat that is less pressing but not for
food as you see there is no food magazine here whatever he presses the lover
he gets as that of
i electrical current straight to the dopamine area of his brain
and he loves it
he really really wants to
get this you can see how he doesn't want to live or to go away
he's really trying to coax it out
because every time
he gets this that in his brain it just makes you feel really good this
is called
brain self stimulation reward
and it it
was studied extensively
at the time when people realize the dopamine has something to do with reward
and till today
in general the idea was OK there are rewards in the real world you know
cake money et cetera how does the brain know
i got the reward well you might know that god rewards through this molecule through
this through dopamine dopamine scored all over the place telling the brain a good thing
now happened and that that was wise anhedonia hypothesis
and this explains well first of all it explains
electrophysiological recordings that people had
none of the time
so what you see here is
these recordings from the diplomatic neurons
a monkey
every dot here is when the neuron fires
and every row
is one trial
and every trial
sometimes faster then the monkey god it's got some two cities mouth this is the
thirsty monkey
so this is how one that the jews
and then some more time passed
what you see is this is the sum of all these that of all this
raster plot
and what you see is these the manager on fire right after reward
and then after a while ago back to baseline
so the idea is they signal to the brain that are reward happened to the
i was obtained
this of course explains why
the rat would one
that in his brain to the dopamine urticaria because that's exactly like getting real rewards
in the world
and explains why he blocked mean animals stop learning so if you give neuroleptics and
if i had to do
conditioning studies they don't learn to level press and they don't have to leverpress for
food they don't work for normally words in the same way
this story would have been simple and nice and we would have not been reinforcement
learning and the whole thing would have and except the
in the nineties schulz wolfram schultz who also
these recordings
started making his experiments little bit more complex by adding the stimulus before the reward
and what he size
when a stimulus
it shown here in the reward is obtained two seconds later this is again recordings
in monkeys the monkeys are getting
jews reward after seeing a visual stimulus on the screen
from the cluster
sure the good representation is simple algorithms like these
what works quite well
and they have been a number of
modifications to the e
thanks for heuristic which have been added to it how celibacy points
how to learn the distance metric
bisecting the sex these constraints in these to handle large amount of data but the
basic idea is essentially
the same
but not of what has gone on
after two weeks
in two thousand six two thousand seven
just looking at your machine learning conferences only ICML ECML
one hundred fifty five people
in the machine learning is this conference pointed out that
not quite limited
we the policy about fifteen people were thought the last thing to of seven long
so why might have so many different
the choice of the objective function generative models in states
and he thought
selecting one before
heuristic own preferred
preferred generative model and and you will come up with
different outcome
which may be admissible
but there is no good which is optimal
this is the knowledge
in a
but as you can expect that the starting point is poisson
point seven
the status of and by similarity matrix
there's only so much information you can extract some grouping them so it's not surprising
the complete based on some kind of entertainment
from the neighbouring distances but you know the difference
mathematical models available
the information bottleneck using information theoretic idea
matrix factorizations and recent work has been on an some of overlapping maximum margin
so i want to the
sounds to to all these different methods but i just try to
hopefully emphasise few these methods
so in spite of so many
clustering algorithm from somebody who wants to use it
data clustering algorithm for a given application
so this is is
these problems what features normalisation schemes used
i personally view this as a not a
not a problem
of the choice of listening and but the domain knowledge
you need to have some domain knowledge in order to figure out what is the
representation the features that should be like not
how to define the pairwise similarity
how many clusters
but let's think about how to choose the output
parameters and we have to that you have
needs to
and which is quite critical of the spectral out the minimum spanning tree algorithm is
a heuristic which was to specify
a particular parameter
does it you have any clustering tendency what happens if i generate random data are
uniform in five dimensions
if i applied it to the first five five five clusters if not so be
it does not have any clustering tendency so this is an important point here is
a lot of time
and clustering it doesn't really doesn't have much less tendency
i discovered clusters and partition
again it depends on what is the purpose of the last thing about the first
thing is to simply organised data
in a way of efficiently computing lets us know that doesn't really matter
but in other situations trying to learn the the structure of the data
then the list of entities that are extremely important
and how to visualize the red and brown clusters
so what is the a cluster one as i already mentioned the set of entities
which satellite
and entities from different clusters are not like that but the real problem is how
do we define the notion of light
and like
well one thing we can say is cluster can be defined as within cluster distance
that is a pair of points that fall in the same cluster distance between them
is less
the tree
most this
but it turns out there many useful clusters not satisfy certain requirements
you know the cluster like this and the looks like this perhaps will satisfy this
requirement but not necessarily all types of plants
then the clusters have been defined based on connected clusters within cluster one activity should
be people
one activity
but we we all know that an idea of cluster is compact and isolated is
within cluster distance is much smaller than between cluster distance
and again it depends on the representation of the book representation likely to have compact
what the really result of the game is going to be
the actually we don't have that
so the interesting question now is and this will be the interesting question again and
again and again is how do we represent
the state of the board whatever the state of the world and it is our
chose a representation of this new network which
in a way is
very suitable in very well crafted for neural networks but on the other hand is
primitive in
in a different point of view that makes explain so there were one hundred ninety
eight input units of the neural network
and in particular you for each color and for each of the twenty four points
on the board you four units for
neurons in your input layer before inputs so
let's fall in the number of checkers on the point then
if there were no checkers then all units would be zero for the input if
there was one checker then only the first unit with be one
there were two checkers the first and second unit with be one if there were
three checkers the first three units would be one and for more than three checkers
the force units would be set to represent essentially how many more than three there
the interesting thing is that some backgammon knowledge enters into this because these first three
i really kind of very different cases is something is empty that's very distinct case
from there being one check in particular because one checker can be hit
right and that's really weakness having one checker on the point is bad for your
game in many situations so distinguishing this is very important now in this case where
n equals two is an entirely different matter now from one check which is the
vulnerability if you add the second checkers suddenly you're controlling that point
so the opponent cannot
entry at that point or cannot go to that point anymore so suddenly this becomes
the strength and that i think that justifies another unit
this thing here represents the case we have three
three checkers on the point that can be particularly good because now you could even
move checker away and would still retain control and this extra check is referred to
as the builder because it can help you build other points to block the board
even more and so this report just represents the rest
so this is pretty clever
now in addition
we need a unit
for each color to indicate the number of pieces on the bar
so if you appears on the bar that means that your first obligation
according to the rules is to get them back into the game game so it's
very bad to have checkers on the bar in fact it can happen that you
have checkers on the bar the opponent has blocked out during the entire field in
which you may enter and then you're totally start you cannot move and whatever you
throwing dice will be wasted called dancing on the bar
so that's one thing and the other thing of course it has to be represented
as how many of you are still once you've already out
because that's the ultimate game and if this number here is the number of stones
out reaches fifteen born borne numbers on support of then you win
also we need an indicator of whose move it is
what you have essentially is the standard feedforward neural network with a sigmoidal activation function
here the weights and these are the inputs and that that was just a standard
two layer network
what i mean by well clever representations well i think he did use of that
naive knowledge if you like about backgammon to build this input representation and it was
advisable to think very hard about about which properties of the problem you can get
into your presentation because that makes life for your learning algorithm much easier
on the other hand consider this we see this board as humans and we know
there are points next to each other and they are next to each other right
we know that there are some spatial relationship
the neural network has no idea about this the input representation is a vector and
the vectors could just as well be totally scrambled it has no idea whatsoever that
we're talking about a continuous line of twenty four points here
so in that respect that's a very primitive representation but i've hardly seen any progress
in investor representations
so here's the TD learning rule that was used
the parameter vector of the neural network is updated using the standard
rule four td lambda
in particular with this pt which is the eligibility trace which is updated like this
you have this dk here you have the gradient of the value of the neural
network with regard to the parameters here but with the loss so this this of
course depends on the neural network representation of your value
you can use backprop to train that you initialise the weights with small values
how do you generate the sequence is through the state space and
quite amazingly you can do that by self play and that's probably why this whole
approach was is appears to be so elegant because you don't need any external interference
this system is good generating its own training data so far given position where you
start you find all the legal moves
to determine the subsequent positions
he use the neural network to evaluate these positions then you use
then you choose to move that leads to the position with the highest probability of
and this gets you through the game you have two of these neural networks essentially
playing against each other and after each move you make TD update
and in particular since you the dice rolls you don't even need a lot of
epsilon greedy exploitation or stuff like that exploration because the dyes give users the stochasticity
to explore the space
after three hundred thousand training games TD gammon well had the same strength as a
handcrafted not such true as this
as as the program that use supervised learning to learn backgammon and this was neural
gamini incidentally it was by the same authorities are
but i mean that country half compared against the best thing that was available at
OK so it tells you what exactly is documents
so this is informative
some can be of very different kind
they can be just as short as this
they can because it's so obvious short snippets
they can belong to scientific abstracts they can be just single answers for all its
provided keywords also standardisation
they can be
as i said earlier derived from a single documents for
document collections so the former case speaking about the transition that it is about what
there are a couple of sentences such paper all proceedings of the conference
in their content they can be very engineering so you get document you get a
summary or the summarisation the query based you provide we only
information relating to the risk factors such
it can also be used focus so that you can give me about what you
know with respect to that to get summary
in the approach that can be extracted for
so performance better extract
such extreme document this these phrases clauses sentences paragraphs or can be extracted
so the structure is that what
people usually do
percent imagine to summarise text documents and what you do is would create those documents
think about for a while
immediately right and you know what the documents
but then just right
january new
summary your understanding of the documents break
but surprisingly to you perhaps but this is not really it's station works at the
moment because there are problems with semantic so there's no
a unified approach to
the meaning of complete documents can be extracted from text
so there are some theoretical difficulties and also even for existing theories many of them
how to implement had to
applied to real world problems
what it means is that all systems especially all systems extract and extract sentences and
this is
local solution which works quite well sometimes
first it's not going to what you get out and
thanks here in summary
so this is what all systems do you get a collection of documents for example
is multiple musician those documents in
and every document is split into sentences so here i don't have anything to think
i don't have anything to point you can use it
so we to split every document sentences
green dot
and then you cluster similar sentences together
c interface inheritance after this sentences is all about the same what happened when this
is business and what a certain person set of sentences which was
consequences of the events so the clusters and what all systems to
given the clusters they bring
according to
what and so that is something like we are very interested in what happened when
not really interested in what
this doesn't set
clustering clusters
well there probably ought to and from every cluster
just one single sentence is extracted and put into the summary
so this is a very reasonable approach of course there's no guarantee that what you
get is
because you're doing something right
so for example imagine that
you have a cost of those two sentences
which are to the old i will read the first killing the syrian foreign minister
today condemned the killing of eight civilians in the u s three as an act
of criminal and terrorist aggression so this is the sentence comes out which was published
by the guardian
thanks for reminding me this is going to be based on joint work with artists
and actors
i always have pronouncing the name of probably not in a quarter and ravi kumar
which will appear in KDD two thousand eight
OK so
let me start with an introduction to social network that's what metric is a graph
that represents relationships between independent agents independent individual
and we see them every day there's every everywhere especially nowadays with the advent of
online social networks and they are making a big difference in everybody's life there are
offline social networks social networks in the real world like network of professional contacts
the been observed to make a big difference in
for example when people try to find jobs or in the salary that people receive
their location in the social networks like to make a difference
o also for example network of colleagues in
every profession for for example physicians or
there's been a lot of research on how these networks affect how people learn new
techniques for example
use of new drugs use of new agricultural techniques and so on
and also recently we've seen a lot of social networks on the web
with the advent of this notion of web two point o which is essentially
you can think about the social web
you see a lot of examples like online social networks to explicitly expressed by social
a social network for example facebook myspace orkut
instant messaging software
link in which is more
the repertoire professionals and so on
and there are also social networks that are a bit more hidden content sharing sites
like flickr delicious youtube weblogs
and finally there are social networks that are used in order to create content that
wikipedia is essentially a social collaborative system that people
so the point of this slide actually social networks are everywhere using them over there
and so it's very natural to
study the objects and try to understand them
and as i mentioned during the past few years there has been an essentially an
online revolution people are sitting more and more of their interactions social interactions online war
a lot of people are keeping track of their friends online
this is this is a lot of facts and essentially the structure of the society
and also on social science it is pushing the number of contact person can keep
track of the list and don't know exactly what the effect of this and so
on this side there's been a classical result in social essentially
look at the number of people that a person can keep track of and see
that this this number for humans apparently this is something called to a hundred and
and this has a large impact on the structure of society
for example for other primates this number is much lower than that the structure of
society is much simpler and what you see in online world is that this number
is increasing are increasing with the help of
on line
social network
and also another impact of this is that the
we're seeing the definition of the notion of privacy with the new social network
but there
and finally from the perspective of social sciences this is an ideal experiment experiment lab
it allows us to to measure and record all activities
many very large social networks
and the resulting get massive datasets in order to study and understand social dynamics of
previously traditionally in social sciences datasets that they used to work with her
very small size fifty people are so because they're all
gather using survey data
now the notion is going to be talking about this show social correlation the fact
the social high play an important role role in shaping the behavior of users online
and offline for example there there's been a lot of papers
document in different contexts there is the paper by back from and others that look
at the moment of joining a community on livejournal it's essentially blogging community
and they show that actually graph in the next slide show that the probability of
joining a community increase
with the number of friends that you have in that community
this is actually the graph from there
so you see
and in fact that this is the number of friends who already have in this
community and the y axis you see
the probability of you joining the same company i see that this problem is is
at the beginning very fast and slower but still it's increasing with the number of
from a model that that gets
elimination independent representation of face
and then recognise what what you seeing
and in particular here what you can do is you can use
prior of how images are formed
and this is the pride that comes to us from the computer graphics community
and the idea is that you know the way that images of form that is
an image albedo is a light source surface normal
it's a very very simple model of how images are formed by low so if
you're ever played computer graphics games you know these kinds of models are used for
generating the world
right and we can take this prior knowledge and embedded into these
systems in particular we can say well there's a light source is a surface normals initial beta
and effectively we multiply three of them together
and now we're gonna put as a prior the queen face
elimination interface is gonna be used would be using a divorce which in this case
we using gauss enables mission because
the face itself is real valued
we're gonna use the surface normal
we also gonna be using gauss machine is a light source that specifies the direction of the light
um is being inferred from the data you know thee
he surface normal image shall the light source so everything is being inferred from the data based on
observed images
and again inference can be done with variational inference learning can be done with stochastic
approximation because tools can be really quite
for modeling these images
and then there is a little bit of transfer learning where we have a set
of you have a set of clean faces can build a generative model that fits
you know so here's one particular example had thirty eight subjects you have forty five
images different illumination conditions twenty eight subjects for training test for them for testing
and this is what happens that's that's also show you this particular image
this is being third elimination independent representation of the image
and then you can do define things like like
second sample different lighting directions in just like the fix
and in terms of recognition
just based on a single test example
you can do fairly well in terms of recognizes compared to you know deep belief networks and such
and then once you have six or seven different images and models
like so singular value decomposition the fact that we ignore the prior
but there's an interesting task where you do put some prior knowledge into these models right
and you might want you might wonder why do sort of recognize faces and the
difference between winning condition it's kind of interesting like for example companies like samsung
interested in this kind of stuff because
you know they also speak like cameron committee so you're walking
your room
and you have a real lighting and that if you can recognize who you are
and basically you know recommend watching stuff
right or maybe like
show you and then
which is more likely
so what about dealing with occlusions or structured noise right this is another particular example let's say
you get to see observed image but there is a structured noise
covering part of the input
right and by the way what we do
everything here can be applied in a lot of different application domains there's nothing specific in these models
what you'd like to do
is you'd like to essentially build the model we have a clean face
you're recovering the shape of the quota
right so he can use against billion or dibble's mission to model the face
you actually have a binary idea modeling the mask and then you have to putting
a prior how these two different sources interact together
we actually produce the observed image
and there is a little bit of gas in noise now the details are not
important but what is important is that you basically having a model that models the
model that models the shape of the kluwer and then you combining these two together see putting some prior knowledge
about how shape
as well as the object itself should be separated
right one interesting thing about this model is that if you look at the distribution of this data
given these latent features
it turns out that this distribution has a heavy tailed distribution
right and any time you see a heavy tailed or robust
the heavy tailed distribution should sort of should bring about
right anytime you sort of try to deal with noise
you should be putting heavy tailed distributions that can capture they they're not structure
but here's
you know what the model can do
so this is what happens during the training so this is the case
and then
what you're inferring is inference phase as well as the glasses a particular shape
the shape of the inclusion and this is what happens if the test is a
test subject and this is the first phase
now obviously this is not true inference phase
this is the phase that the mobilization look like the generative process if you stimulate
more you'll probably have a slightly different face
have a whole distribution over what it should look like
the same force car
and then one interesting thing about these more by just putting this prior knowledge you can do quite well
right so for example here
you know with robust multi can get eighty percent recognition varies at the pixel level
you know you're sitting at seventy percent fifty percent right
so it's quite a dramatic increase by just putting a little bit of prior knowledge into these models
right or modeling the source of noise corruption order
missing data
the same thing goes for speech recognition that's another big application of of these models where you have
you're looking at twenty five millisecond frames new
extract phonetic labels
and this is one particular example aware
you know u u basically trying to the spoken query detection this is the case where r
you know you have a bunch of keywords
and you're trying to
detect whether you're observing this keywords when somebody box
you know you can imagine it's very useful thing for like that's your forms right
so talk on the phone and he says particular words
the system can catch it right
you know so far for these kinds of things when using these models
you can get
fairly good results compared to traditional speech recognition systems speech recognition systems that using gas mixture models
so there's a lot of
there's a pretty big discrepancies a pretty big gap from sixteen percent delta nine percent
right before the war
four using these
these models
let me now
switch gears a little bit and talk about a slightly different but related problem which
is also interesting problem in learning community people trying to look at
the idea of transfer learning one shot learning
so let just illustrate why this is an important problem
suppose i show you this handwritten characters and i tell you that that's an image as art
how many of you think this is an image as art
what about this one
do you think this is arc
yeah what about what about this one
yes what about this one
what's happening here
what's happening here is that you just seen one example
right and you're able to generalize
right what so far we've seen
is we've seen sixty thousand examples are images of tools and then the model says
finally understand what makes it to a to and i can recognise things
obviously you know same goes vision if i show you a single image overseas where
you recognise what is and can generalize
so one of the fundamental problems in machine learning is is how can we learn
new concept which is a high-dimensional statistical object from few examples
and obviously humans can do that's can we teach our machines to do that's very challenging problem
right so if you look at the traditional
OK so
before i do
junction tree which is here
the key is one of the main
algorithms for exact inference is limited notation just easier to work with so
OK so i have a vector x right it's don't know random variables the
joint probability function or density function
is some subset so if i say x of today i mean
just a subset of variables in x that are in a right so
and if i have a x one
through x and is is two
so and then it's x two and x
so x a is this
so that the examples and so
right and then
in this notation for four
it's OK so that and then we need additional so for
assignments threats to these kind of false i'm afraid so an assignment to a set
of these
very what value assigned to try
so what about the same variables and then
you know it's a with this sort of
will face kind of x is the set of all possible assignments and then we
need to do is look at kind of subset of scientific assignment to before one
through and i may be asking about what is the assignment to variable two and
sent to the same trick kind of indexing it by
this subset
sort of on the subscript means the subset of the assignment editor but right now
those things are in the
and if i do union then this is sort of a joint
or if you take the
what you says
to assign and with this assigned to get so this notation but
it's important to
you get lost so
and it so any in function of users just it's the function of the variables
OK so
just in this notation now we can can restate some things right so have the
entire set so this is a
interested in and i am interested in public particularly
so to get this i marginalise out the entire distribution so i think the
union with u where u is in x
seven skip a bar meaning to a bar is the complement of a some sort
of all possible node an extra bar x a bar means the
so the rest of the possible assign because the morals innovation
there exist
additional thing
and then you know he is this the right now like this so basically an
assignment here
this function only looks the part of the assignment cases function and just cares about
the part
that's very intuitive
OK so with that hand
the inference is that we have a vector variable that we care about this is
all the way over density that written as the product so we met business into
the formal
there is some evidence assignment that will incorporate into their
and there are some query variables denoted by x q q is a subset of
OK so we have the p of q given
all possible variables and w is the assignment to yi
how to incorporate evidence
so the probability of everything but each given e
is a commune in the end
divided by p
he said the w
which is basically the product of that
this is the full joint writing and here station is OK well i think the
part that they need from from you think about the domain from w in each
clique have some variables assigned someone not
and then divided by the probability of evidence so
we can essentially
absorb those factors into the
and calling things the prime right so he
e w goes into the prime and also
whatever is observed here i just instantiate the value and kind of collapse the potential
i just worry about things that unobserved
there is that they can sugar but basically
when do want to get evidence i think the potentials instantiate the values that of
the evidence that rings the potentials and now only a function of the subset of
the variables that are unobserved
and and then what the probability of evidence just goes into the partition function anyway
so for example for business the partition function was one right because we had everything
was normalised so
this is actually becomes exact probabilities evidence
so this is
what i said words
so now we can just reset the problem is finding
he view
people use this computer marginal the
and so this is already instantiated evidence right we to here we forgot about and
it's already
inside the inside
these guys
and so it's just what i need to do to compute this thing is to
some out everything that's not in q
with this partition function and you now is split into things that are in q
and things that are
OK so
now let's look at the
variable elimination in this
notation so as additional function i'm something out overall user
that are in the complement of q
all the different assignments and this is the
the actual private care about
so i think that the evidence that there
scotland backing what that incorporated
basically what this is what was talking about is when
so we have
evidence nodes
he said i is my evidence nodes one i
eliminate those i create new nation cliques which is all of the things that that
had that
the that peak
and then we have a q this this is the product of a potential that
only or
or q
so i mean that we're going to get you out in the but to get
these things we need to sum up
everything else it's not any the evidence and not a q
OK so
and variable elimination and we just you know because variables that we are interested in
we send them out and it was very specific to the actual
crew were asking right so once we we will be asking about probability of one
his for example so let's say we have some data points
so we're going to blue points here i don't know whether you can see that
so their points and their circles around these points what the size of the circle
is proportional to the
in proceedings of the past so this is why
y t here
OK so there are some points which are the boundary
which are very grandchildren at some points outside the chart position
this is the case without noise
let's say we use adaboost now we have a few examples where we added noise
for instance this one here
so the mislabeled example
there was here so another one here and one here
so the influence of those examples increases drastically so this is the example which has
the largest
paid so the queen is about decision boundary which is generated by adaboost
OK and he changes of quite a bit
if you know use
and drake with this definition of the inference then somehow
this example is weighted down because the artificially increase the margin therefore the influence of
the example in the next iteration goes down
it's essentially the examples was the most with the smallest margin given the most weight
so it can be artificially increase the weight of the model the example for the
weight goes down and the decision boundary is much much better
so it it doesn't have this standing here
the positive thing about this i was it really improve the classification performance of adaboost
it really helped in making the most much more robust
it was one of the first things addressing the overfitting problem in boosting
the negative thing about this article was that it was essentially modification one algorithmic level
so we couldn't you couldn't prove it
anything about this we could show that is converging to some minimum which was meaningful
something was more like modification of some quantity inside the
we couldn't show that to solve some optimisation problems
so and of course we didn't have generalization results
so and it took me a while to understand what what what i should do
that i mean i was quite happy with i wouldn't but you couldn't show anything
and essentially the idea was that we understand first what's happening in other in adaboost
i mean what optimisation problem is which is optimized and then really try to understand
the techniques of optimization then we go back to the optimisation problem changed optimisation problem
and then apply all the techniques to solve this better optimisation from this fuzzy
the best strategy
then we can use the convergence results for leveraging and apply the margin bound that's
what i'm showing you know
OK so you have seen the maximum margin problems so no
this is an extension of the maximisation problem
so the idea is that you so using maximum margin constraints the margin of the
example and should be greater than role
but now you have this additional variables science this is often to select variables
so for some of these constraints you not enforcing that this one is larger than
three allow some of those science to be positive so this constraints relaxed
and then you penalizes the some of these clients so you maximizing role
and subtracting the sum of basic science
this is soft much
so again we have the l one norm of the office equal to one and
this is very similar to the soft margin SVM
so this is the so-called new
formulation because we are using it part of it and you here
and it turns out i mean there's some results which shows that the fraction of
points which this science are not equal to zero is essentially the margin error
o is bounded by the new in some way is related to the new
so the empirical margin error is about a new service called the new to the
new trick is
the question
yes it should
maybe at this history is like
so it's not negative then
it's happening
i mean really have complementation closed closest sets rose always on it
so now we can actually with this i mean
i give you this optimisation problem might so new is essentially the maximum margin margin
now we can actually go back to the boundary which have shown you the margin
this was stating that the expected error is smaller or equal
to the margin
and this is actually related to two new
OK so this is the new parliament this was the primary of plus something
which depends essentially on the basis of set but also on the margin
OK so what what this last optimisation problem i solving was essentially try to maximize
the margin
much was founded by this new variables right so this parameter new
OK essentially
bb six this this we say you should be no larger than this
this much should not be large and this then the maximize role
what he so that means minimizing this bound
so this this optimisation problems really motivated from
from this the margin bound
OK so how do we get a regularized version of boosting
so first we have to define the optimisation problem so this might be the new
LP problem which i've just shown you
or you can also do regression i'm showing one example
and then having the optimisation problem we just have to go back and reconstructed posting
on from that so we can use essentially this leveraging technique we can use the
various technique or this current generation techniques of people's like with
so and then we have an article which rigid optimise this optimisation problem which can
solve optimisation problems using the base learner to call several times to generate constraint and
so on and so were gradient
and then you can use essentially the convergence theorems which which i've shown you to
prove convergence for for this particular i
essentially this has been done in several races so
i mean you different ways so is more the original boosting type techniques very methods
the column generation methods and essentially for linear programming classification there different versions there there
some names for the new LP classification there are some some other names of algorithms
and they're all the papers which can read
for regression this sum
for one class classification is also one
and for multiclass i think there's also some people about that
and essentially when you have some other optimization problem which some changed optimisation problem and
then you can just go take these techniques and improve you the convergence and the
director of
OK i would like to illustrate this one case
also you have also heard called models for minimal
unsatisfiability preserving seventy boxes
that's what came out of
stephan slovaks worked on the navy's from funds work which is
minimal like minimal axiom sets
so just to give you more proper definition
if we have an ontology which is really just a set of axioms
and we have some entailments
eta which is entailed by the ontology
then our justification is just a subset of the ontology
it's just a set of axioms
go is a subset of the ontology
and importantly the entailment holds in this subset of the ontology and a set of
axioms as well
and the key point is that is the minimal set so
for any proper subset that would take for justification
the subset
well it's intelligence helmet here
so one way
if we just look at this the kind of more
pictorial sense
if you imagine it to be ontology
these blocks here represent axioms
then if we have some entailment that we're interested in and we want to know
the reason why we might have a hell of a lot of axioms search you
consider something like the NCI ontology
which contains one thousand victims of matter which also contains hundreds of thousands of axioms
you could have a lot of action searches so
my justification pulls out and isolates the axioms
responsible for the entailment and these may only be a small subset of the actual
so we can focus our attention on to this
if we remove one axiom from the justification
it's no longer justification an entailment doesn't hold in this is this subset of axioms
and this is the way we go about paleontology
and now it's important to notice that the
keep something project it's important to notice that there may be more than one justification
for a given entailment
and also
these justifications can overlap so we can get actually being shared between separate justifications but
if we want to understand the reasons for entailment
and we need to look at all of these justifications and if you want to
repair the ontology
we need to move one axiom from each other justifications if if this is justification
four unsatisfiable class
then we can turn the class of fireball
by removing the axioms that define class to take one out from each of these
justifications here
so just to reiterate important points and maybe multiple justifications for an entailment
the kind of a lot and removing one axiom from each justification breaks the justifications
that entailment is no longer supported by the remaining axioms and if we do that
for all justifications for a given entailment and this is what we call the pa
and now we know what justification so we can make description of written sets for
root unsatisfiable classes slightly more formal
the class is a derived unsatisfiable class if it has a justification that's super set
of the justification for some other unsatisfiable class so we've got a set of axioms
that say what classes is unsatisfiable
and if there's some other unsatisfiable class and we have a small set contained in
the set of axioms that explain why so the classes unsatisfiable
then we know that are first class is a derived unsatisfiable class
and any unsatisfiable class that is not derived unsatisfiable class is a region satisfiable class
so this is that none of these justifications contains the justification of another unsatisfiable class
any questions up until now
we can further split down into a partially derived unsatisfiable classes in purely derived unsatisfiable
classes partially derived unsatisfiable classes
a derived unsatisfiable fireball classes for which there is at least one justification
that is not super set of justifications for other unsatisfiable classes
purely derived unsatisfiable classes unsatisfiable classes for which all of the justifications are supersets of
justifications for other unsatisfiable classes now the ramifications of this is that if we want
to repair the ontology
we can affect clusters are partially
derived unsatisfiable class
then we can start to fix it by looking at the onset satisfiable classes and
actions then
but they will will play have to do some iterations
the same justifications here that don't have axioms in the overlap with the solution size
five classes
is not active at times
here she has exactly a friend a active friends at the beginning of the times
and she becomes active in this step so this is the official FIFA and similarly
can define and a
exactly the same way except that this is the number of pairs
the user does not become active in times
if alpha and beta are given the probability that
we get
this scenario we get this data set can be given by this expression products
p eight our y
one minus the power and a therefore for for solving the maximum likelihood problem essentially
we want to maximize this objective function
find alpha beta maximize this function
and you can do this using a number offers thank you very much
also for convenience both for theoretical results and also for implementation capping the number of
active from the value or which is
o thing and
basically the point is that more than that
rarely happens anyway so
it's not going to estimate much but it's going to
help in
increasing concentration reduced the right
OK so the maximum likelihood problem one lemon it's going to be handed later on
that there is a unique solution alpha but unlike problem
this is interesting because this function this
likelihood function that we have here is NOT concave functions should when you have unique
this is because we have concavity
but even though you don't have concavity
can show that if you have two
o point for maximizing the function
there is a path between them such that the function is concave along that particular
at the the result that gives a contradiction so you can have two
and the reason that this lemma is going to be useful
in now to have gone analysis that essentially the same or some local used to
show that
the observation that we estimate from max
the problem is going to be a continuous function of these parameters why and
so now
let me get what they decide that you're using in the flickr dataset
flickr photo sharing website
this is the shell of the first
they have the data the using with for sixteen month period
and the number of users who by it
show you a graph
during this time period eventually the number of users was something like a hundred thousand
and about three hundred and forty thousand of these users have used the tagging feature
that this is going to focus on
and there's also a social network people can specify contacts in this
and the number of edges that you get the more accurate and then you get
something like two point eight million
twenty eight point five percent of them are not neutral so that a twenty eight
point five percent of your friends people that you may not friends have not named
and the size of the giant component
in this graph is something like a hundred and sixty k
so this is like being captured by profile they carry enough pictures here and
you can have all the stream and on each photo
you can that people can comment on it and also you have
feel that describe the
and usually you
specify these stacks other people can tag your photos as well but almost all of
the tags to the user specified by the person was also the form
and also
so like if you look at the prose
you know more complex have seventy five
and this is a graph showing the number of growth in the number of users
or the time period during the
and as you see the to very actually this is the number of users have
been using the tax school forty dots
to keep up with the tradition of showing paul offit for the in degree and
out degree this is thing out of the graph this is how you would expect
from an intersection
i mean if you think about the tags there are about ten thousand tags that
are used to describe photos in the dataset had and we focused on the side
of a hundred
seventeen hundred pounds or in some experiments even less than that surround is these attacks
that are used more often and there are different types of attacks there are some
of the members like keywords like halloween or katrina hurricane katrina
there are some that goal
and more small like landscape or black and white
and there are some that are periodic more
you see you get peaks at the time of the
and for each had essentially defining in action
that corresponds to using the tag for the first time noticed that we don't care
about their future plans to using the tag because the second using the tag is
probably not about social influence you want use the want that
so the act response you're using it
again back to this discussion of the maximum likelihood problem coefficient of
the run this maximum likelihood problem on a number of
Ruth Halaban, who was a pioneering AI researcher, sequencing things by hand, figured out that
C kit was a mutation that drove some small number of melanomas she did that work at
so that was nineteen ninety one
in nineteen ninety eight, excuse me,
a group run run run by Brian Druker
created a drug at the time it was called SDI four seventy one,
I believe,
a drug that was later to become gleevec
was designed to
address a particular different mutation that was called it was
a fusion gene that happened when two pieces of a chromosome broke off and came together
and created an oncogene, a gene that causes cancer. and this drug
was very effective against that fusion gene so there's nothing Ruth Halaban could do in
nineteen ninety one, there was no drug, there was nothing anyone could do in nineteen ninety
eight, there was a drug for this fusion gene called BCR ABL.
but then
two thousand
or thereabouts Druker
the same group working in a different cancer gastrointestinal stromal tumors discovered that
this drug for some reason happened to also bind to
and inhibits C kit.
well, there were still some dots to be connected because it wasn't till three years
later that a group in italy, inspired by a letter to the editor in an obscure italian
journal that no one had ever seen that said, you know, maybe we should try
gleevec on the melanomas that express C kit, he connected the few dots in his head and so that led to
the work that Stephen Hodi finally published in two thousand and eight at asco. so nearly
two decades went by to connect three dots
now this is something, if you're serendipitous enough you overhear something in that cocktail lounge or something
conference, science works this way but it is unacceptable for it to work
this way in cancer, there are too many lives at stake and it's easy enough
to connect three dots but this is the size of the knowledge base that we're
dealing with, these happen to be some of the databases that people involved in the
semantic web project are trying to connect up the ones and magenta here are the ones
specifically relevant to this project
that I'm trying to do.
and as I said just one of them, pubmed has twenty million abstracts in it
so we need some AI here.
it's not that hard to do some to to capture some low-hanging fruit here, back in
two thousand and three Alan Rappaport of who did a company called
they're on data which some of you may remember from earlier days in AI, was
a student and I had a different company called medstory,
put together a simple application for asco
in which we got people submitting abstracts in breast cancer to fill out a form
something like this, which is akin to the reference model what subtype of breast cancer
were there and there were only three subtypes back then, it wasn't very complicated but based on the
author filling this out then when a when a researcher or a doctor came in and said what trials are
relevant to my patient instead of having to thumb through four thousand pages of bible
paper, you know one page per four thousand ab each of four thousand abstracts, they could
look it up and this was we actually ran a clinical trial on whether people
would use this and ninety five percent of the authors voluntarily filled this out when
they were submitting the application and seventy percent of people
looking up trials used it because they felt it would be helpful. this was a big success
and I I'm basically building on this now
for as the human interface, the user interface for cancer commons. so if you can
imagine just adding some buttons to the side of this where you fill out whatever
it is about your patient and then click a button and be able to find
out what the treatment guidelines are and where in that big decision tree
square root of two x one time six two in x two square
these are three dimensional vector and you see that if you take the inner product
between five UN five v
this is just the inner product of these
three dimensional vector with these three dimensional vector
then you see that it's equal to OK it's maybe a bit quick but
if you do the math you compute everything you'll see that it is just
u one v one plus u two v two to the square squared
which is exactly
the inner product between u and v square
and is that the kernel that you you started with
meaning that you can you can see it like as as if i'm trying to
say that if you use this curve
then it's precisely as if you were trying to use
in formation of degree two
our if if you wanted to to use
quadratic information about your coordinates
it's very easy for instance if you use this kernel
to derive we've to derive using it for a linear algorithm to derive
this user face that are like ellipses
high probability high power
i possible
if it's
actually work
and and and things like that
and now we're back we're the very simple kernelized classifier
so the one with the average plus points in the average negative points
again we have the value of our far we have the value of b
i use
garson kernel
when you use gaussian curve you have these parameter sigma that you have to deal
i'm not going to tell you how to deal with this guy because it's
it's a pain actually
but i'm going to show you what kind of decision surface you can have using
an our RBF kernel is very simple classifier that i i showed you
on linear classification problems
so here is the training data
the blue points that are positive point
the red one there are negative points and as you can see
there is no
no lying no hyperplane that could could separate
blue points from breakpoints
i use very simple classifier that i showed you we've
v v gulshan with garson kernel of different with the in the parameters is called
the width of the of the kernel then i using missing equal to zero points
are five zero point one zero point two
and four here is zero point zero five here is the point
here's point two
why it's those pictures show
it is the value of h
given the location where it's computed
the only thing that you have to remember to see that
the red
corresponds to the blue
here the red here
it is like the rule here
and the yellow here
or even the blue here is like the right here
nice choice
i didn't realize that book it's OK
so the only thing that you have to remember is that i use a very
simple algorithm
where i can analytically compute the advice i can out analytically compute b
be the value of b
and i just place garson kernel into this very simple algorithm
i run it with these nonlinearly separable training data and i get i get
those non-linear decision surface because you can imagine that the
you can imagine i don't know if you can imagine but here
there is a
the war between the red and the yellow
these are the the location where you
you're going to say
everything that is in this part is going to be
positive and everything that is going to take that is in this part is going
to be negative
we use the very simple linear algorithm we used do we just picked
a kernel that is well known we would be the gas kernels
we used it
we switched the colors
and we had these results
they should be very happy now
are you
yes nice
a small thing about kernels
as a glimpse of what is going to happen to you in in two hours
or never because i think that time a little behind on my schedule but
here's that the graph
the gram matrix of the kernel this is given an input set as
made of and data
x one to x and the grain the gram matrix s of
of of k
four s
is just the matrix made of all the
the dot product between x i x j a g
so this is
i obviously symmetric matrix because k of x
i xj is equal to k affects excite and these is a very nice property
of positive definite kernels is that
what ever the the training set or a set s that you choose you always
have this property that
that is this property here
you take
and he said
as of x one to x and you compute the green got the gram matrix
OK with respect to s
you'll see that
you will have this property
in other words
i can values
the gram matrix are all nonnegative
as these one and
i guess i'm repeating myself before they tend to be a little bit more process
oriented so
you either have functional programming
kind of style
or they have the
style you have prove so you have derivations and then you have
distributions over there those derivations based on that
distribution so you can make inferences
ah good question so
one question was how much knowledge engineering essentially
do you have to do and how much
data cleaning do you have to do and so on and definitely i would
imagine for most of you you guys realise that when you do a machine learning
method that
ninety percent of its missile aging the data and getting it into the right format
and so on
interestingly though
i personally have found with appearance which is one that i've worked with the most
actually a lot less
something where you're building traditional statistical models so
for example one of the demands that we
i did a lot of work with was tuberculosis dataset
where the tuberculosis dataset describes the
tuberculosis patients the people that they have been in contact with and the produce
particular tuberculosis train they were infected with and we were working with doctors at stanford
medical center and they said that they had given the data to
traditional statisticians and you know after six months
the statisticians came back with a couple
statistically significant
differences between things versus we
take the PRM stuff and applied it
we're able and we to give them
first off the picture
you know what they depend on one
from that
so they were impressed
and please with that and then they could go in and they can look
at that model and basically focusing on particular dependencies and do inference is using those
and then i would say that you should then go
traditional statistical methods so
it helps you to the bottom of understanding of what depends on what what doesn't
depend on y
to understand things
so one questions knowledge engineering so
is it
therefore it is no silver bullet
one point
like initially we thought well if you have a database and has the relational schema
well you just use that relational scheme
people to sign some
really not very good relational schemas so it may well be the case that you
need to
do some
massaging with that
so the second question was scalability
i think there's
different places where the scalability
comes and so first off
this allows you to
really huge
models if you're not careful
and if you're doing inference
so the inference is one place where the scaling
be an issue
but for learning
learning actually
it's surprisingly
not as bad as i think most people think because the fact that you're getting
all this parameter sharing actually
help you
but that's kind of my experience my experience is
the the biggest
if you can get it to all fit in memory
you're OK if you're going to find out what fit in memory then there and
huge troubles so that that's
the biggest one but then there are certain kinds of steel stability issues as well
the third question was about
what places it's been applied in practice so
applied in practice so what we've done this
to regularize the status that was one of the more interesting ones we've done a
lot of things with
data as well
there's been a fair amount of work of applying this to
biological data in terms of the work that
near freeman and so on have done
but i think it's still
all right
very right very for
and that's fine up
OK so i do want to
something about
undirected approaches
i have used this definition
and i'm going to do a little bit
about frame based directed approaches and rule based on direct approach is the rule based
and direct approaches are the markov logic networks
first off
analogous to
the business
a little bit i'm going to say quickly a little bit about markov networks
how many people have
that was markov networks before
OK so there's a guest
lower percentage than the bayes nets but
the basic idea
is again it's
where the random the nodes represent random variables
and the edges represent
and here's a little example where i'm talking about the fame
four different authors
there there is not this encode search
conditional independence
these ones are ones that basically
if you look at some
set of nodes for example
a two and a three
if they separate
a one and a four
they're are conditionally independent
the parameterisation that goes along with a markov network
a set of factors the factors
are over subsets of the nodes in this case i have simple edge potential that
work in this area is the one in a thousand transactions are fraudulent
the delay in labelling talk about that and and often the classes mislabeled things label
fraud when not vice versa illustrate that
obviously the transaction times arrive according to some sort of stochastic process to arrive at
regular intervals
and this one is particularly important i think there's reactive population growth since the distributions
that we're dealing with change over the course of time
so well
illustrate all of those
here is an example of critical whenever you make credit card transactions
between seventy and eighty variables are recorded
every transaction you make
so the numbers the dimensionality is going up is not just how much is spent
when you spent
it's there's an identification number transaction type is an ATM cash withdrawal or a mobile
phone top-up or
credit card sale one
the date and time of transaction to the nearest second is the amount of the
currency local currency amount merchant category this is a categorical with around two thousand different
categories and saying what sort of merchant was the the supermarket was closed who bought
was in the betting shop whatever
tony the nature of the transaction
and there are a whole load of others
seventy to eighty
in each to each credit card transaction you make
that's just banking data in general now let's look at four days this is a
slide from
this you can stop it from the US patent office website
this is the pattern number if you're interested if you know anything about work in
this area you might well
i have an idea
what particular system it's an early version what particular system
and in the in the
in the pattern they listen these variables this doesn't look like too many but that's
what you can't see them but let's see what they are the first one says
customer usage pattern profiles representing time of day
and a week profiles and says
the the second expiration date for the credit card
the third one is a dollar amount spent in each ASIC
yes i see because american version of merchant category code set dollar amount spent in
each merchant category code
we have two thousand of those
during the current day
so potentially obviously this is sparse but potentially there are two thousand variables just for
the third one alone here
and it goes on like that was the fourth one is percentage dollars spent by
customer each ASIC much group during the current day and so on so although it
doesn't look as if there are many variables here
they blow up to high dimensional problems
as if that's not bad enough
this US pattern also says additional fraud related variables which may also be considered are
listed below
and then this these
and these
so quite high dimensional problems
i'm gonna say about unbalanced classes
on monday a very clever gave almost exactly the same example is this
i'm going to very quickly repeated because i want to refer to it later so
just to remind you what it is
suppose we got detector which identifies
ninety nine hundred legitimate transactions correctly so it gets some right and also identifies ninety
nine hundred fraudulent transactions all the legitimate gets ninety nine percent right of the fraudulent
gets ninety nine percent right
superficially it looks as if that's pretty good
but as we all know from monday
we have a problem when the priors are very different than the class sizes are
very unbalanced and i think this differs from eric grelet ongoing
i'm going to take one in a thousand transactions
i was fortunate because as i've already said that's sort of ballpark figure what goes
on in this
so we've got this is the true class legitimate fraudulent
ninety nine percent are correctly predicted as legitimate
across fraudulent ninety nine percent correctly predicted this fraudulent
so it looks pretty good
and these are the actual numbers which are legitimate and which are fraud
OK now that's what these numbers through
ninety nine percent of these that's nine hundred ninety nine fall in that cell
nine point nineteen ninety nine point nine nine of legitimate are
predictors fraudulent only one percent similar sort of things here the other way round
but now let's look at the those which are predicted as fraudulent
nine point nine nine really legitimate point nine nine four
so we're only getting nine percent correct
of those we predict to be fraudulent
for every hundred
only nine really all
ninety one percent suspected frauds are in fact just now this matters in this context
a great deal because
operational decisions could be made you want to decide whether to stop the car stopped
the can drop the cart
and good customers must be irritated
if for every
ten customers you phone and say
i think this is fraud or every ten accounts you think before you start online
of those are going to be perfectly fits perfectly
things are more subtle as i illustrated with my sort of economic imperative social implications
stuff at the beginning
in general
customers quite pleased you you you ring them up and you say
did you really make this transaction
there are often quite pleased that you're not you can probably that's what it looks
like UK europe and really
it looks as if you can
two o point
they're not going to be too pleased if
you're there often getting phone calls from you you irritating them all the time so
did you make this transaction so there's a delicate balance here
are all sorts of other
factors influencing how these sorts of systems must operate in practice it's not just simple
mathematical statistics
and i think that sort of principle
there are a lot of other issues pervades all i'm going to be talking
the next thing i want to talk about was the delay in learning class labels
because it introduces subtle distortion in the data
if and when fraud alarm is relate is raised we think a transaction is suspicious
then you quickly find out the true clustering up the account holder did you make
this transaction
yes or no you find fraudulent or not
and that number of correlations that can model
is equal to k right so you say
there's a number of correlations of their
and and indeed this you're saying and noise reason i'm going to explicitly model
and separate the noise somehow
if i now had observed
a certain certain vector in my in my thousand dimensional space
if i want to
the projected onto my twenty dimensional space let's let's make twenty
this college to has to say
two so that we
because two is sort of the number we choose all three four using PCA to
look at our data right so you could also use this to actually look at
your data right now we know
everything about
bayesian mechanics
so we know that because we have a prior on x
right we also have
we also have likelihood right if we fix x if we say here's x then
then we know what the what the distribution of y is going to be conditioned
on the right and it's simply it is a distribution and not just not just
the number because we're adding noise right
so i have a prior have likelihood
i just want to crank and and i have a posterior right
so i can so i can for any
data points
in my thousand dimensions space i can find i can find the two dimensional representation
of it right so i can sort of project my
my vectors now
i get agustin distribution which is not a surprise because of multiply the some prior
with the agustin likelihood right
but let's look at the mean i i suppose it's more intuitive to look at
the mean right so if we just wanted to look at the means of of
the posteriors so think about it again for any possible data point in my data
space i get a little girl some posterior in my in my plane right so
we get all these little only is it goes in
if you will
so what are the means if i look at the other means well you see
you know this was linear model and
the design matrix was land
and then i had the noise term so for for you
every of you that has been working with animals this sort of
it sort of looks like the normal equations somehow read this sort of the projection
i would get
let's think a little bit about this about this projection term
so two
think about it
two things
what happens
if the noise starts getting large for specific dimension
OK so remember this is a
a thousand times a thousand diagonal matrix OK and it contains it contains one noise
for each of the of the dimensions in high dimensional space
alright so i'm not saying that noise has the same amplitude for all dimensions useful
thing here is that i'm a modelling noise
independently across
individually across each dimension OK so have
i have a thousand sort of noise variances that of learning
now you can sort of see
let's let's look at the the the size of the test so as so what
sites should be to be anyone
so bitter
what times what
none of it it has to have more because if you look about it it's
it is we need to get back the mean
of x right so what size it is x is just
take it slowly
so x is k times one right it's k times one vector and we've said
k could be too if i wanted to look at the data around
what sizes is why i
the times one right OK so now we know what size beta must be right
so taste k
times the
it's k times the projection matrix that brings me my dimensional data back into my
k dimensional space
OK fair enough for enough that's fine
now we can also guess what size is lambda actually we can guess what sizes
lambda because we know that there was this relation
so lambda
lambda better timescale right
which sort of makes sense
so now
let's try to be the test would beta
it is
a call
to this
now all lambda is transposed so it's k times this OK so short-sighted and these
along one
and this gets multiply
the square matrix here OK
so far so good
the simplest thing we can do is
pretend for a moment
the land that are orthogonal
if they orthogonal they don't need to be
the reason why i'm doing this is to help us think
let's just take them to be
the other thing i want now is i want to get diagonal matrix here because
if i have a diagonal matrix here what you what you see is that the
diagonal elements what they do is they scale the columns of of of this matrix
lambda right that's what they do
and so
what i want to give you is intuition of what happens even if a certain
noise term is very large so if i sort of discovered that
you know it's a site one like
the first dimension in my thousand dimensional space has a lot of noise OK
so what happens then
what happens if this term going very large is when i take the inverse
the one one element of the inverse is going to be very close to zero
reason to be very small so what happens then what happens in is one and
multiply these guy
this element is scaling this whole column right
and what does that mean
that means that when i be the projection
when i sort of take my
my my y data datapoint has a thousand dimensions
and i want to obtain my kahlil dimensions
there are going to be a linear combination of all the thousand dimensions and what
and what this is saying is that have not a lot of noise in one
of the dimensions i'm just going to switch their one off and not going to
listen to it too much
it's nice
all right
so that's
let's think about some other aspects of factor analysis another convenient thing in factor analysis
is that
the number
so thank you very much for
for me it's a great pleasure and
the named lecture is really cool
particularly one named after the greek heroes
and worried about the
timing of the election after all the food and alcohol
and not me
and i think the system but
you may know that alcohol has a biphasic effect on your whole level is increasing
you tend to be away
and at a certain point you start thinking it tends decline fall asleep
so i recommend
and gonna the
i'm talking about
applications of behavioral economics two
public policy
titles the economist as therapist
is that the title actually comes from
a paper by two princeton economist
nearest main goal and hasn't after
OK well they're going attack first against neuroeconomics
the current be pleased about that but i sort of think neuroeconomics has yet to
making any great discoveries but i think in the future we will and the other
thing that they attack
is what could be called the new paternalism in economics and i'm actually the reason
i didn't jump to the defence of neuroeconomics when you made that comment is really
much more excited about the second much more excited about
after applying behavioral economics
public policy
and that's when talk about
in the in the halls of course kind inquiry what happened to
and i can
but is think what i would say
when i started using powerpoint
i used to make mistakes pointing at the screen
thinking that i guess it
here i guess i'm phd on the lowest level of development the discrete just imagine
the are city as well
that's like in second slides kind of important so we work here
that's the first
this time
it's going to gradually is going to gradually come into focus
anyway when i was what i was walking in the halls of my university
university and became a poster
and this is the poster you might see
very you see what's behind this picture of the statue of liberty
and the reason you copied to come incompetent to know what's best for yourself
this is if you look at the small loads from the libertarian society that you
and so they seem to think that the answer is obvious answer the question is
obvious that is that we do know know what that what's best for themselves
well every time i see this poster i get plunged into
and questions
depression because the that isn't the answer i can
but you don't have to look at my behavior
if you look at the behaviour of americans and a lot of people in the
you see that there's a lot of people don't always know what's best for themselves
and even when they do
they often have trouble getting themselves to do in health behavior
between nineteen sixty and two thousand obesity in US adults increased from thirteen percent to
thirty one percent
and of course the the worldwide trend as well
in nineteen eighty five
it was not a single US state with obesity
right about fifty percent in two thousand five there's not a single state
and the country with obesity rate that's less than fifteen percent
a lot of if you look at diseases in the united states test
about a third of the deaths in the united states are caused by
like lifestyle diseases that are caused by behave behaviors that people do like tobacco alcohol
it's also the case that many of the medications
one of the most promising medications like medications to control blood pressure cholesterol avoid strokes
in fact many of the medications that are designed to deal with the lifestyle diseases
aren't really realizing their potential because people don't take them
and so
just one of many many striking examples
half of patients who have a heart attack stop taking cholesterol medication which is an
extremely effective remedy against having a second heart attack within the first year i think
it's pretty shocking is having a heart attack after all
this is very
and if you look at spending savings of course the the US is probably worse
than this but the average u s savings rate is minus one percent
we're just saving one percent of our world each year
and the media network in the year two thousand households was
thirteen thousand dollars
it's not very much
can you tell you that
so traditional economics
i think among friends here we all enjoy the expansion of traditional economics is not
well equipped to deal with these problems
because it assumes that people know what's best for themselves and their people to act
and understanding
as a result there is little or no need for intervention beyond the problem of
externalities that is the the
problems that people cars for other people but that there's no need to intervene to
help people
protect themselves against themselves
and so most of the policy
was the types of policies that were proposed by conventional economists focus on changing prices
or providing information to people
behavioral economics is very different big focus of behavioral economics is on the mistake people
make mistakes people make often we don't know what's best for themselves and even when
we don't know we often can do it and this this motivates interventions like paternalistic
interventions interventions designed
to help people protect people against themselves
very much like you might
help the child to
you might have
protect the child like try to get the child to eat healthy food something like
this insight that behavioral economics
mode can motivate new types into interventions
has inspired a new approach to public policy
which i reverted with the blanket term light paternalism
so the paternalism
we may not policies that are intended to benefit individuals
and they promised on the idea that people cannot be relied upon to pursue self
paternalism is distinct from regulations that again attempted to attempts to deal with externalities to
protect people from other people