finally that is this
the issue what sleeping in the class
now my view is it just by
OK i know you guys need the rest
and interestingly
the best sleeper in the first couple of rules haven't met you guys is person
i have followed
some people really have to come to the first and second row
because they claim that don't hear me they cannot really go to sleep
that was true in slow but i think loose has got very good
acoustic so
structure in the back
but only of only criterion is if you talk in your sleep as a lot
of talk
next if you're going to sleep i ask you to sit between two non sleepers
so that's what happens to whole rule will pop up
we don't want the domino effect now it's going to be
captured on tape and that's going to be really bad for my
spread yourself but yourself around
other people
all right so
that's it in terms of
last in logistics and everything
i'm going to start
going into the physics proper
i will try to finish every lecture on time
but sometimes in the middle of a sentence in the middle of the derivation and
they have to go or be complimented no need to shuffle your feet then most
i i know what time it is
i also want to get out like you guys
let me finish something other based on their finish few minutes before time
that's because the ideas of physics don't fall into
seventy time in seconds and sometimes below also i'm used to teaching this course three
times a week
and i would certainly twice a week
so things that fell into nice fifty minute units are now being
there are different ways it's pretty difficult even for me some of it will be
the timing may not be just right
can anybody have any
i should tell you first of all that in this
class the taping is not enough to because the cameras can be behind your head
i mentioned to you in the website that this is not the big opportunity looking
to be a star
only the back of the scene
in some cases the back of the head could be more expressive than the front
in which case this is your opportunity and i shoe otherwise
just don't worry about it because you'll be only heard
you may not even be heard
so i've been asked that if question is not very clear i should repeat
so that people listening to the later we know what the question was
but i would ask you
make one thing very clear
that is i'm not in favor of you're talking to each other because distracting
you're stopping me any time is just fine
welcome that because i have seen this subject for god knows how many years
the only thing that makes it different from me is the questions that you people
you can stop at any time
and you shouldn't feel somehow you're stopping
the progress of the class
there is no fixed syllabus we can move things around is far more exciting for
to answer your questions that
have while i don't
don't worry about that to stop me any time you don't follow something and don't
assume that
you are falling something because
there's something wrong with your level of comprehension quite often
you guys come up with questions that never crossed my mind very interesting
things we need to be year after year after year because this sound so reasonable
suddenly sound unreasonable and some of you point out some aspect of it
that you didn't follow so it could be very interesting for all of us
i have issues to discuss in class and quite often
some questions are very common in your classmates will be grateful to you that you
brought it up
otherwise you get ten years get ten emails all the same question
OK so
when to start now
anybody have any
questions about
format midterm exams
oh you mean my office hours
no the discussion sections are tuesday
from one to two
and tuesday night from eight to ten
and the
the website has got all the details on
when and where yes
there are many many lap times and you have to to
go to the website for the land and by the way that reminds me i
got lots of suppliers
given to me by the director of the laboratories which will tell you
which lab is the right left for you
offered many times a week yes
i think it's a good idea to take the last because
in this particular class because i don't have any demonstrations
all in the other building
so this will remind you that is because of experimental science you will be able
to see
we're all the laws of physics come from
so if you're going to take you should take it at the same time
thank you
this is the calculus this class
i expect everyone to know at least the rudiments of differential calculus
what function what to do with what the second derivative of take derivatives
elementary functions
how to do elementary integrals
some time later
i will
deal with functions are more than one variable which i will briefly introduce you
because that may not be the is but certainly something you will learn
and you may use on and
but there are different ways of doing physics minus two
demonstrated over and over how little mathematics you need to get the job
others who like to show you how much mathematics you could somehow insinuate the process
OK there are different ways of
playing the game and some of his find great pride in finding the most
a simple way to understand something that's certainly my trademark that's how it all made
sense also
if you feel there's not enough mathews i guarantee you that i certainly not
eventually the snow the whole class but that's not the point i will use it
in moderation
and use it to a user talk
the best effort possible rather than use it because it is there
OK so
i don't know your mathematical background but the textbook has an appendix is reasonable measure
of how much that you should know
you've got to know you are trigonometry got know what's sign and what's the cosine
on pairs of pixels
and that one says
there's a big change in
this is a big change in intensity
between these two images
so this is the
very light
then it's quite
likely fact that they belong to different classes
so i put a small weight
on uncut
if on the other hand these two pixels
look very much the same intensity
the cost cutting
assigned different classes i put is relatively large
so this is the dark matter
in the middle
based on contrast
so you can see OK this about
unitary likelihood
is there
and you can see approximately like belongs to class one
the pairwise terms
as you can see
there is a high costs
a low cost rather along edges make cut
and the the potts models just
across the whole thing if you do that
minimize the whole cost
across the image
you get this
solution and everything
rather nice thing about this
works not only on this direction works rather well
so i mean by
this one step
the optimisation step what i mean
by this what i mean is i have each of these
things belonging
have a unitary cost
they have the binary cost
what i want
is card
and i'm getting curve
the costs
only when
phi phi kappa between the two trying to cool the cutting costs
the cost of putting these in given classes supply is given by the first time
minimises hold energy function
all assignments
and that's the result i get
other examples of it
sigma of course rather nicely
stick it
in a different setting
not sure if you are familiar with alpha mapping
formatting means in fact you don't just
o one was you signed transparency
twelve so particularly
along the
the back to the main
when you put that at the top
o thing if you do if you just say
take the pixels directly from the original input you find in fact
you get it grass along the main
in fact so you have this transparency there are some mixture of pixels
along the lines with the of mappings of
this one is actually one which being look quite a lot rather difficult
segmentation task nevertheless
people like to then put them in a different scene just to show how well
it's worked
OK ECCV is the european conference on computer vision there are three kinds computer vision
the major ones
in ECCV
european conference on computer vision
in ICCV
international conference on computer vision
and CV
p or
computer vision and pattern recognition
so once again
and so on
to get a little bit more
down into
the way this time
i said
for instance that there are
two types firms typically there are unitary terms
which just
terms relating cost
given a single pixel of single known graph and there are binary terms
which relate
so the way you do this typically
as you make a graph like this this comes down to a graph we solve
this using graphs
and the graph
draw is
the yellow dots are in one-to-one correspondence between pixels
the image this applies not only pixels with this thing to pixels
we have two other
which we
denoted in red
one of those
labelled zero and the labelled one or maybe s t
one is the case for some reason which is not apparent to me
OK you label you get take this graph and you you join
zero one or two every
one of the other
nodes in the graph
and then you assign weights
signed weights to each age
and the edge weights you assign the edges between the yellow and
no it's quite clear what the edge weights should be those related in fact equal
the energy firms
it's not quite true lyrical they're related and the way will see to the energy
terms involving pairs
blue edges
related to
the energy term of the individual pixels in fact that really need both
top and bottom edges the label on waiting list
label one
those are
that's the way you make graph this more about that later
and then the question is
how do i separate find cut in the graph which separates the top note from
the bottom right now so there's no power
through the graph
top to bottom from zero to one
and then the cost
all that time
the total
for the edges
then the height of static pressure increases by ten atmosphere
for every ten metre
is one atmosphere
canadians from the table
i know how to pronounce the name because i dutch she was the dutch inventor
is usually credited
was building
the first submarine
very early seventeenth century around sixteen twenty two
and he successfully operated the submarine
the depth of about five metres
imagine five metres
how static pressure there
half an atmosphere
ten meters one atmosphere five metres
of an atmosphere
nowadays submarines
go it's a little secret how far to go but
they've gone up to three thousand feet
which is nine hundred meters
well had of static pressure
is ninety atmospheres
on every square meter
all that submarine if it is it
nine hundred meters
there is a force of nine hundred homes nine hundred thousand
often rable submarine
it was an enormous accomplishment for the seventeenth century
that's how are you going to seal
well by the side of the vessel
is one atmosphere
that's the air that he was briefly
five metres
you know level
so the outside
pressure is one of the atmosphere
namely one atmosphere barometric pressure and have an atmosphere from the static pressure so is
an overpressure on the vessel
of half
an atmosphere
but that means
on every square centimeter that is of course pointing inwards
of half a kilogram equivalent the public kilogram weight
force is always perpendicular to the surface
and if you take two square meters of his submarine
that would be a force of ten thousand kilogram
amazing that he managed to do that and that you could actually operate
this submarine successfully
i can show you here twenty six one hundred
what kinds of forces from the labelled
dealing with
you see there in front of you
paint can
and i'm going to evaporate
not a separate ranking factor webpage
the paint can i'm going to one the air out
so here is the pain can
about twenty five centimeters by fifteen
and so it equilibrium this one atmosphere outside one of the inside thing can happen
i'm going to suck the air out
so i got on the pressure here
in other words
the pressure outside is higher than inside exactly
the problem that from label
pressure outside is high and inside you get impose
he managed to counter that build strong enough
we topicality and here
you can argue well then the overpressure is really one atmosphere the only dealt with
one atmosphere well before we reach
this we've actually believe it already implode
so the force is that we're dealing with a very comparable
what from tribal wars dealing with
when he built his submarine
so this can
will start to crumble
when we
take the air out
that's another way really seeing the atmospheric pressure
i take the pressure of the inside
you can literally squeezed
because of the
of air
it is hanging on this and is pushing down on this
it has to be properly sealed
it's always a bit of a problem
and so i have vacuum pump
the problem
you can already here
the force on the front cover alone is three hundred seventy five
square centimeters
if the pressure inside was zero
that would be a force of three hundred seventy five kilograms
i'm very happy that can
and these are the kind of force is very comparable to what from rable
i was dealing with
in the seventeenth century
and he was able to
even operate submarine under these forces without collapse
OK i think we
well i think this is a souvenir
no i can give that you have to first to take this off
you can pick it up later
that mouthpiece is quite pressures for us because we
you have use it again of course
so see what the tremendous forces at stake when you do is
barometric pressure if you go scuba diving
you go to the depth of ten metres
which is taken to open your mouth
we could go all the way to the surface
and culture brief
but there's no way
the other two
here is the water level
if this is ten meters
in that you can produce the gibbs sampler
any time
you can write down your
like that
and the reason is
you can complete
the product of the FC are
the marginal
of the product of the indicator that so omega i
between zero and if i have seat
so when you look at your distribution as a product of simpler
functions and simple we mean that you can do an inversion
of this inequality
you can write
a gibbs sampler because
of course if you integrate this
in omega on you do get f i
what is the marginal is the is the product of the ifis the same time
the omega eyes are uniform
or this interval
you have one two
here f k
so you think
it's very easy to simulate and once you have assuming make hours
your joint distribution
is a product of indicators
so as the function of theta
it's also a product of indicators
and so on on it to simulate is uniform
all the set of y
so it that i y
is bigger than omega
OK so this makes for very
give some
you just go around
OK so it's it's really
the MCMC version
the the
fundamental of simulation because
if you think it in dimension one
you still disliked from from gas
it spirals f
but if you say it
the photographs often
what you do
create random walk or subgraph and random walk
all the photographs
stationary distribution is the uniform distribution so if you keep moving at random you
formerly of the subgraph you produced
the markov chain whose stationary distribution is uniform and if you look only at x
the first component marginally you get a distribution that is
gives the size and probably just move uniformly
exact point and then you move uniformly over this interval
get there
now you move uniformly over this interval get there for instance you keep going on
that one direction at a time this of course in the case where you don't
use the product the competition
in the more general case when you can do it
in one direction you can just multiply
the uniform moves
four eight
of the if i
and are totally arbitrary up exams
the way you like you just want to pigs and so that
this is easy to invert
the king
so this makes for a general
and in addition
one depending on the shape of the factor graph
you get is a geometric ergodicity or if the subgraph is compact you get uniform
good is it says this converges fast enough
drag and the drugs that getting
may prove impossible
in some cases
this step
they require one uniform generation this step may be much harder
because you have to produce
this set
OK so far
the said that contains that's
this is not always
tourists this stochastic volatility yesterday
stochastic volatility was the problem because
in my distribution of the volatility
that is normal bit
which was nice enough
two nine sigma minus two there
and i
the observational bit which had an exponential of an exponential decay
what you can you can break
so you can just rewrite as experiments x where
press of control minus x
if we just look at the simplest
so somewhere
we say
this is
the marginal
of indicator
then omega is less than this exponential
simulated on omega
that is easy cementing the mean that we want to simulate or
actually this is the highest praise
this is not an insult
OK this is the highest praise
and i think what it means is
that other people know enough about the theory
the algorithms and implementations are so good and so reliable
the rest of us can just type a back slash p
that's most of the time and of course if you're building real time system or
or the sizes get two million or ten million unique going to be using back
obviously but that said that the boundary growing with time i mean that's the wonderful
thing about anything that has to do with computers just take a vacation for years
you know
my from my colleagues the other end of the EU actually do real things
they and all their friends around the world will make stuff like twice as fast
c just you just go away and take a vacation
you series no you go you go to the greek islands for three weeks to
come back
computers are faster so just say it's it's it's great
instead it so
i mean that and i think that's everyone being flooded by moore's law and so
on so
OK so that i mean certainly the case with with all this so when i
come back to technology and also no of course i know i'm not telling people
that this use a backslide mesh like be actually i know everyone is classes has
used a everyone here has done a back slash we probably only if you actually
know actually what did
and you look fine normal
nothing terrible has happened is not true nothing no ones
OK so
anyway when i finally do is when they get real i like to come back
to them and also to them
when they're yelling at me all say
also a whole on the back of your use TCP IP
actually sometimes believe they want to know what i'm asking that's which is even cooler
right is that all say oh don't tell me you're using these are using as
a black box you don't even know what's inside it like so
and finally some of them will say OK i do
you know because like everything is i'm even institute this if your even communications on
this on on stupid you know on your laptop between different components and
so say you know what it does
most final say
no and i look here's what you need to know if you need to know
a OK it but it is not trivial by any means
to deliver to make a reliable bit pipe
to the transfer bids from one place to another with unreliable
medium in size it is not trivial but the first thing it's no more trivial
than it is to solve this problem numerical OK it is not trivial
and here's answer all you need to know is this
very intelligent people have thought about this problem very deeply they thought about what can
go wrong deadlocks all sorts of crazy stuff and they have come up with
about which they know an incredible amount that's part one part two
other people have implemented them
to the i with and as far as you know and these are very reliable
implementations and the result is that for most of us we can just
most of us can just consider certain things to be
file transfer to be reliable bit pipes
we don't have to care about how many packets rory transmitter how the flow control
when all that kind of stuff now
likely squares
if you're doing real time control
or something like that
or or or ultra if you're doing some computing requires extreme reliability
then you know what you can't treat TCP IP as a black box
but to do so
but you might ask this is common down the answer is no this makes them
more angry
so anyway so be i i mean technology here as in praise
it's OK now when you lose will use least squares
if you just come from two sixty three use least squares OK but in fact
that at the beginning i mean we use least squares is it easy to recognise
the least squares problem i mean sometimes it comes to on a platter like somebody
walks and says i took these measurements is a linear measurement model we guess these
parameters i know something like that are you know i received signal into this channel
so what seems to be OK right so we have to treat clusters of points
and you can kind of see
the tree different modes
actually i add more data points in here
he might actually be able to see the true clusters small really
this can add lots of data points OK so we see three clusters so this
is nice and working fine stuff like OK so what happens now if we
another class right
still running going a bit slow
OK so
anybody see any problem with
this right now
that's true so this kind like it
it's not quite able to
all four cluster
how many clusters do thing is in a mixture model
obviously so you can see that we have
this financial models come going to get into trouble not because it's not
flexible enough to capture
this is a very simple devices
is a finite mixture three
and if we try to fit it to four classes we're going to see of
course that you try to
model this fall classes using tree mixture component
so so right now it's colour much does two clusters together and it does manage
have a component for each of the class for each of these two clusters
so this can work
but not quite
so what we do next is basically to take a finite mixture now and take
the number of components in this measure to infinity
so that it can do with any number of clusters that you give
so it's
a finite mixture model gibbs sampling definitional
so now we want to take k to infinity
so before we take eighteen to infinity what we do is imagine simply really large
so what happens when we have a really large number of missing components
we only have an data points and could be big c
thousand by k could be even bigger a million something like so
number of missions
mixture components k
we can imagine it to be much larger than the number of data points that
we have
and because every data
in the worst case every data point can be assigned to its own individual cluster
so that's really only
and the clusters that will be used to explain the data
out of this really large number of
we components
but this is that most of the components in the mixture was simply be empty
so they are not going to be associated with it at all
and what we
well we try to do is actually to lump it all this empty components together
so if we
the the first equation here i'm just going to take say
this thing here and copy it over here
the probability so inactive sample of the probability that
data item i is going to be assigned to cluster k
given the assignments of all the other clusters
it is going to be proportional to
again this conditional prior
but i to my i being assigned to complicate multiplied by a likelihood
of the data item
given all the other data items there's currently assigned to cluster k
and so for the
for the clusters for which
for the occupied clusters foot so for the clusters fall
i have
there are currently
they could say that currently have the title assigned to them
so in other words where this and k term is
not zero sum
all land
all the columns would be pivot columns
because three columns are telling me that there are combination of earlier columns
so this would be the case where the rank is an
this would be the case where the rain is
smaller than n
so in this case the rank is and
and the null space
of a
only the zero back
and no free variables
three very
and this is the case yes free variables
if you allow me to
great thing this language that far
that's the case where we have
combination that gives the zero columns so i'm often interested in the case when my
vectors are popped into a matrix
so the the definition over there of independence then talk about any matrix
the vectors didn't have to be
vectors in n dimensional space
and i want to give you some examples
vectors that are
what you think of immediately as vectors
but most of the time this is the we are the vectors we think of
and we can put them in the matrix
and then independence or dependence comes back to
the null space
so that's the idea of independence
can i just
let me let me go on to spending a space
what does it mean for a bunch of actors
a space
well actually we've seen it already
you remember
if if we had columns in the matrix
we took all their combinations
and that gave us the
column space
those vectors that we started with band that column space so spanning the space means
so let me move that
right up
so vectors
let me
call them to say
the one up to car use some different letters a b
i space subspace
or just the vector space i could span space
it means
the space
it consists of
one of those affected
that's exactly what we did with the column space
so now i could say in shorthand the columns of the matrix span
the column space
remember to bunch of vectors that have this property that they span a space and
if i give you a bunch of actors and say OK
let s be the space
that they span
in other words let us contain all their combinations
that space as will be the smallest space
with those vectors in right
because any space with those vectors in it
you must have all combinations of those vectors in it
and if i stop there
i've got the smaller space
and that's the space that they span
OK so i'm just
rather than needing to say take all linear combinations and put them into space
i'm i'm compressing that
into the word spam
so if i think of of the column space of a matrix
i've got i've got there so i start with the columns
i take all their combinations that gives me the column space they span the column
now are they independent
maybe yes maybe no
it depends on the particular columns that went into that matrix
obviously i'm highly interested in a set of vectors
that spans the space
and is independent
that's that means like i've got the right number of vectors
if i didn't have all of them
i wouldn't have
my whole space
if i had more than that they probably wouldn't they wouldn't be
independent so like
and that's the word that's coming
just right so here let me put what that word means a basis
four of vectors for vector space is
it is a sequence of vectors
like all of the y
b two
up to
save the
d now stopped
with that letters that
it has two properties
i mean think about very simple example you have long sequence and the patron two
three five seven eleven to the prime craft and then you make a special entity
of primes you build secretary the prince primes now because this user often then to
reconstruct data
he developed the concept of prime because it allows you to
compress your data
but they only finally many which are simpler than the data themselves
you have
i haven't told you how to find the simplest theory but i mean what to
formalise just i mean this supposed the gain numerator all theories from simpler to more
complex and look how well they are then you pick the best one of course
i mean this is
it takes a lot of time and if you do it know can a computer
do it but
nor can the universe do it but it is the gold standard which you try
to achieve with some more clever methods by
partial search clever search or whatever
OK so
but before we come to that there is one
the problem
and this is
occam's razor is not a formal mathematical objective principles of
so what is simple for one may be complex for another
so we have to
define quantitative notion of complexity first
before i do that give me another
example the famous go emerald paradox
with about that are not about that
OK not OK so
that's one of the most famous
the paradoxes in philosophy
which is still not completely
so have to policies all emeralds are green
most of you know probably there
emerald green
but you have
second hypothesis all emeralds found till two thousand ten i agree
and after the blue
so which hypothesis is more plausible
i mean both totally consistent with all observations
from this perspective the equally good
but nevertheless i guess most of you what
bet on hypothesis h one but the question is what is the justification of that
and you can invoke occam's razor here too
i mean the first hypothesis looks simpler i mean just count the number of letters
in the sentence
use your intuition
in this case
i mean you could argue are the times which in two thousand ten but i
mean that the processes for which after some time to come up with them and
then you would argue for which
well i've seen on road
what you mean have i mean you want to predict the future so
what you mean things never happen
you also never experience the hypothesis that all emeralds are green in two thousand eleven
year-old inexperienced that
i mean what you're trying to do now is huge to to generalise over i
have a class of hypothesis
yeah the continuity arguement which is not bad but there are processes
jump around and
so for instance
the sun i mean grows every day
but you wouldn't predict it's there in twenty billion years
also it has ever been there in the past five
billion years because i mean you know by physical processes that will explode from
so you would predict a discontinuity of all you have never experienced the discontinuity in
this case
this is another thing that you're maybe no no i mean this happens but this
set the eclipse happened in the past so you have some experience these happen so
so you need an example
it has not happened in the past but will happen in the future according to
i mean the continuity arguement is pretty good in many cases but not universal
OK here's another nice paradox
the black raven paradox
or confirmation paradox
i assume we go out and we observe ravens and this all to be black
so what you typically then infer all biologists who is OK probably already
so you have this hypothesis that
raven this
implies likeness
so what you do it
it's like nearly every other point depends on every every other points and so
what you what you're seeing here something called ptolemy triangulation
so basically it away just triangulating all these points and we can parameterise how these
things move in the classic nineteen this is point distribution model
you generally just do this by removing similarity from the shape so member similarity translation
scale rotation
and everything else and prolific with is the non rigid deformation and sensual there was
applied principal component analysis sought to get that variation in there and then they said
we have a model what you're saying the animation
put this again
it's essentially the principal component
that's the first principal component
that's the second principal component
and we
parameterized in exactly the same way
so you that w x p
and just making sure that the way the express my p
it follows that fundamental role that it follows an identity matrix and that it can
be can computed it can be was any information
now you know what function helped users what function with images
so now
most people know that when we actually storing image we deal with an image it's
discrete this kind of the individual pixels is not a continuous a continuous signal
the what function but the problem the what function is nearly always gives the fractional
so we have an example here
to say i i got of the line
coming for you
and this is the actual image
and i want to subsample this image there and the way i want to subsample
this image is essentially just to have this many pixels
evenly space and things so if i'm going naive saying well
on this going to turn pixels on and off based on what the values for
are here
this is what i'm going to get
and it's not really representative what i have in original images is sort of
for anyone is kind and done i suppose any math course or any kind of
thing and sigma systems and things that this is essentially anything
so you're essentially you're you're not we're we're we're we're not take into account the
you want to take into account the icing effects going on this image
one way to get around that in a kind of
had not the slightest talking about never to be
familiar with using this another example by using those who are familiar
is in the wagon wheels examples what camille nineteen
thirty some sort of
going along and they kind of the
the speed of the wheel
doesn't sink up with frame might it actually looks like it was going backwards
and this is the function of not sampling cracked right and that's very similar to
what was going on there
so what we typically do in computer vision is something called image interpolation and there's
a whole mean can become daunting if you have time to perform but if you've
got any map that it's really simple i think people drumming up too much the
compare with polymer interpolation bicubic things about all we really doing is the kind of
thinking hang on an image is an understanding of samples of an image name is
really isn't a discrete
image on this representing discreetly only do something useful with it only to come and
go back into continuous domain
and so
what i
it's essentially
if i think so i think actually visualize an image in one day phyllis to
say that is that my image being to be a commitment on one day come
what occurred
what i do when images it's really sample is that when i story of essentially
all these all these points here
and if i admin nyquist probably as long as i'm sampling at twice the highest
i this actually got a lot of information learning so find something about the human
visual system one of the things i can generally store that information
if i want to know what the images what the image value of objects is
given just these points
given not excited because i know the value of x
but the x which is the fractional values between these two values
i do something very very common things and it's basically like a power series expansion
and so
essentially just take the gradient
OK but the gradient of light based on its neighbours so you can kind of
very it's the can make it larger if you want
and i also
the time i can and in some noise
and i can get a pretty good
of what
all right the so be it should be because if i have obeyed my sampling
theory and things like that all the information is there i need the cartoon
and we have
essentially refer to this is by linear
interpolation now there are other variants human we actually can of trying
it's essentially equivalent the second order derivative but generally falling is good enough and that's
essentially what we use in all this stuff
that's good
for hopefully not going too slow this kind of starting from the beginning kind of
building it so that's how our like given that i have a wall and i
might have fractional coordinates that's how actually get
my image intensities
you can also that's all well and good
and if if
if all coming straight from machine learning which which con was when i started this
actually came from a very different direction to a lot of people when i started
working computer vision idea quite a reasonable background in pattern recognition and machine learning and
i sort came into this and so well what's the big deal i can essentially
go three this when all around
at every values
i can essentially vectorize
these are the pixel values and here the same
the maximum values between fifty five draws and essentially
how to look at every possible value in in in in a certain area so
can so that we will everything all
and then
if i if i then has from my naive perspective whatever i can't then said
my second lecture
so i want to say that this is not true because what i wanted to
present in this lecture is
overview of data structures and
our current background but how do they have
i believe that it is not doing
it's not possible in one lecture to give
a comprehensive overview of this topic
so this idea and they have to be very very simple expression or phrase
of this problem
the first problem is how to create an effect and also
this lecture is
the last
connected real information structure
lecture in the car because it's all about
company o
structure for innovation it doesn't have anything
connected with information and they will our task construction information
starring information need
four from a user
so the question is how to create an effective
very very common approach
talk briefly about modern hardware
a new in and why characterize different from what we
had ten years ago
then i need to talk a bit about compression
don't talk much more about compression tomorrow
when i describe compression and indexing
but the problem is that
i want to be sure that you have some background
this is in the compression
you can understand what is the difference from this very simple and ordinary compression or
actually i
my concern on your understanding of similarity between this
for this aberration
then i will briefly describe the structure and
what we're going to do you remember during our search engine and we need to
build a dictionary rather than going to put all work
talking about structure
solving this problem about trying to put into memory
on may be on this if you have huge dictionary
i'm going to put all work
from all documents
and here we are looking for
toy application window applications correction because
sometimes it important we need to do correction
imagine that we are getting very good documents from character recognition and want to improve
our indexing by automatic correction and then discuss how to implement analysis
and then i will give you a very brief introduction to to presentation and they
were not introduction simply
mentioning on some more and definitions in prohibition that we need to understand the inventor
talk about innovation of information they will agree
so how can create effective
o structure which searching for other
so what we need to think about to think about
data usage
however going to use these days
if that building dictionary what we're going to do with picture
usually they are going to add and we're going to show
so the picture should be
insertion if you do if if you do it in the first challenge
if going to be already
there have been this index
i don't need to optimise the search for this particular type of in the world
judge structure need to optimize the church
so first of all we need to decide
what going to do with this data structure what what what what is the main
how we will access the date
this is our first task
going to
as i said in our thinking of the structure
then we need to do some selection we need to select chorus
and select structure
actually not not two options to one
you cannot
separate stories from structure
i think that the
remember this famous book from the extra programs are very different class structure
the main point of the ball
that you cannot separate algorithms structures that together this
it's in our programs
very very and structures changing algorithm changes structures usually and the same
and the last it's a bit controversial option and to be getting so it's that
again as i said on the first lecture
if we are trying to implement good compression
maybe you don't need to implement it
because if you don't know how to implement compression maybe you have a library to
read doing the
what i'm going to say is that
the current more situation we already have a lot of libraries
and for professional developer and especially for church
it's much more important to understand how to
the right through
and how to use them
then to create the tools from scratch because it's simply not durable in many cases
what we're talking about effective data presentation
this strange situation here
and i will talk about it when i talk about
more than hardware and about all other stuff is that
data representation is representation that
we trying to optimize
complexities of our algorithm
use exact language that's the meaning of the word analysis
i think close enough whereas synthesis
has to do with reassembling signal reassembling function from its constituent parts
the signals from
its constituent parts
all right and the two things go together all right you know one one without
the other you want you want to break something up into its constituent parts and
just let it sit there
all these little parts and on the table with nothing to do
want to be able to take those parts may be modified those parts may be
see which parts are more important than other parts and then you want to put
it back together to get the to get the original signal or a new signal
and the process of doing those things the two
aspects of fourier analysis i use i use the word analysis there's sort more generic
the other thing to realize about both of these procedures analysis and synthesis is that
they are accomplished by linear operations
series and into rules are always involved here both analysis and synthesis
fourier analysis
analysis and synthesis
by linear operations
this is one of the reasons why the subject is so
so powerful because there's such a body of knowledge on and as such a deep
in advance understanding of linear operations linearity will make this a little bit more explicitly
go as we go on further but i want to point out now because i
won't always pointed out right because when i say linear operations one thing here in
real time series
e g i integral
and series
both of which are linear operations in all the sum is the sum of the
integrals in the real world of constantine's of functions of constantinople the function
and so on and similarly with some so i because of this one often says
one often things that fourier analysis is part of
the study of linear systems right in in engineering is there's there's there are courses
called linear systems and so on and sometimes fourier analysis is thought to be a
part of that because the operations involved in it are linear i don't
think of it that way and i think it somehow important enough on its own
but i think of it necessarily is subsumed in a larger subject but nevertheless the
fact that the operations are linear
r does put it in a certain context
in some in some ways in some cases the more general context that turns out
to be important for many ideas
right so often so you see
we often hear that fourier analysis
three a
analysis is part of
the subject of linear systems the study of linear systems so i don't think they
really does complete justice to for a analysis
because because the particular special things that are involved in but nevertheless you will you'll
hear that
let's get launched alright let's start with
the actual
subject of fourier series and the analysis of periodic
periodic phenomena
and for
as i said is certainly shouldn't be necessary
for me to sell the importance of periodic phenomena is something worth studying you see
it everywhere
the study phenomena is for us the mathematics and engineering or mathematics and science and
engineering of
regularly repeating phenomenon that's what always involves some pattern that repeats and repeats regularly right
so the mathematics
and engineering sciences and engineering course
out of that before science
maybe i won't even mention science mathematics and engineering of regularly repeating patterns
i'm leaving a couple of terms here i mean all these terms somewhat of a
what does it mean to be regular what does it mean repeating what is a
pattern in the first place but you know what you you know what i mean
you know it when you see it
and in fact you can mathematically analyse it is what makes the subject so useful
i think
although again
it's not ironclad she was the subject is so rich that every time i make
a statement i felt i had to qualify well it's often true but is not
completely true and sometimes not really true but most of the time it's true
that it's helpful but not always helpful but in most of the time application helpful
to classify
periodicity as either periodicity entire periodicity in space
all right you often see periodic phenomena as one type or the other type although
they can overlap see often
periodic phenomena
periodicity in in time
a pattern repeats in time over and over again you wait long enough and happens
again so for example harmonic motion so e g harmonic motion and on
o thing but on the string
harmonic motion
or periodicity is base
and every
it is the space
the city in space by now
because you have to make some approximations to solve the many body problem
so it means that you need to have an approximate inference which is adapted for
this approach is if you change your approach
we should the from that you have developed
it is OK for these new and better approach
so the different approximation i will mention tools of the show more because it was
the first approach developed for nuclear physics and the approach is based on the mean
field so they are quite different in the philosophy
so the other types like UBM interacting boson interactions like algebraic approaches
but for prediction of many many nuclear this one
to my mind the well suited
i recall you what we call because of what what are the nucleons in quantum
so they have access to discrete number of states
because they are quantum objects so there on the can have only some values of
the energy is
they are fairly and so that means that they cannot occupy the same quantum states
with all the same quantum numbers it's what we call the pauli principle
so that's why he had neutral and protons and here for example the difference in
the speed at the
so then the
historically part of the show model it was developed by get my year in nineteen
forty eight
and it's only
so what is it about for electrons in at all
so what you say during another conference in nineteen sixty three
if that in analogy with that atomic structure one may postulate that in the nucleus
the nucleons move fairly independently in individual orbits in an average potential
which we can assume to have a spherical symmetry
so what does it mean that you have the potential
that is seen by the media and so this is an example potential deduced from
experiments with this sort had this
died what's some potential return here
where you have here that some here
the range started there and air
to have an analytical solution of this potential is quite difficult so you can approximate
with this can where you are and when you later which are plotted here
so this is wrong minus fourteen anything
this is around two fairly so
you see that you have different shapes
you can say whatever of these potential that you want these three is seen in
our is so you can cannot
so that's so it's not so sensitive
two suppose should use here either what sex scale with our our facilitators
so then
you have different states
neutron on pretense of operator and you have the revision so it
hiring energy
these quantum states that characterized by
quantum numbers so principal quantum number big n
right quantum number small so
for the special expansion it really depends on the number of the beast members
azimuthal quantum number l spring
and so
feel these different
there are some rules and for example you have this relation
we introduce to
momentum which is all little argument implies the been so this is the total angular
so then
you you're single particle levels in the shell model when you start running an equation
with this potential so this is example for scareware
scott then you have these big n here and small n and l
from physics you need to introduce this binaural so
l stein is company and this is very important to find these
structure face so
and then you have all your here
and you see that you have some gaps
so these twenty eight especially his created by just been over here
but the other one created here so you have gaps for these major members
that i told you before
so you see that for example if you feel at this point here
you will have a very stable nuclides
so if you want to excited you will have to
two rules about the definitely put something here so
all these nuclear that's why they are very stable
because of these here in the energy
the historical independent body show more than has been improved a lot
because OK give very satisfying results for magic nuclei especially for the ground state
and low lying excited states where promotes nucleons
on different channels
but in fact in the nuclear you don't have only the
individual citations where only a few are promoted and two different shows you have also
corey around motion an awful lot of articles to get what we call so they
can can vibration can vibrate you can have richer nations of car and motion of
different nucleons
lots of those
and there will be some something very blurred
many of those units
as will be the result
and it's also clear that
if they are not
you know
doing the same thing and in parallel and everything then you don't see anything
with e g we can measure
at least ten thousand of the neurons are doing similar things
in parallel
and also there some geometrical issue in EEG so so if you have these little
so dipoles
we can are all of these
current dipoles then we cannot measure
things that don't have the right orientation to be measured with EEG
so you g is blind to some directions
things that are
no way
in the fold
on invisible to two
e g but
in with the MEGA measuring the magnetic field so things might be different e g
and m gene can measure
you can use it to measure so negatively
but in general images has a higher resolution
OK so
a single neuron
hands up
there are lots of neurons in parallel
add up to something mecca macroscopic the visible
and something visible with an
usually EEG device
and so
we will mostly be focusing on the somatosensory cortex which is not the red box
with some
taken tony jarrett box
so this is so to say the last stage
so you have this microscopic
electric field and you can sample the with EEG electrodes so he plays a number
of electrodes all over the place
say sixty four hundred twenty eight which is the standard
and you can measure
certain contributions of this electric field and of course you have more than one
and you see
in this picture
you see eugenia
this is the reference but you
clue and another young all but you can also
but you
you have to have one electrodes which is to say
the reference electrode with respect to which all of the electrodes measure
in fact you always have to fixate such an EEG cap
and you have the
quite uncomfortable robert thing
oppose it to you
because of the way the connection is not so good so the
the the gel electrodes essentially have an impedance of about five kilometres you do it
ten don't do it so well
or or more
and what you can typically measures are signals of the all the
five to fifty or sixty microblogging
each the two
just to give you an impression
with low impedance
so let's have
so over you
how things can be done
first of all there is the obvious thing
so you can implant sensors two brain surgeries
and place an electrode array into your brain
place areas of sensors on the brain say with electoral that the core technology
so noninvasively you could measure with e for example
and this is mostly not penetrating the skull in this sense
when you put the gel into these electrodes and occasionally scratch the skin a little
bit but that's the only invasive thing that you do with e g
but there's also other things like mhg you could use from i principle
or new years
near infrared spectroscopy
all these techniques have to have different time scales in different resolutions e g has
about it the resolution of one centimeter
image is slightly better news is even better they have a rather decent
o thing identified but this URI is the same thing is identified by a URI
so she went more discussion about the semantic service before the end of the tutorial
there are lots of property from folk which are very popular for just place data
together many people and then this
if you kind
properties which is a kind of
to sense
this with the list i compiled based on my own experience is not is not
grounds in
might have some data on that from the from the sun to spend the paper
about the precise usage from
this is really my
personally i brainstormed list stuff that people use
there are these
three properties of the bottom often kind of useful kind of glue properties just tying
stuff together and say five page to say that this the page particular page
so if you in this i was taught about we've got RDF document and then
you've got to an HTML page about the same thing you can use this property
to say in the RDF documents
the corresponding HTML page
so from the talk about second price if you're not talking on the web specify
what is
actually about you can use the property to do so and rdfs seealso is really
just the way of connecting to other related documents that state a particular user agent
might want to also
the reference and integrate with the same
same data releasing
so if we think back to the whiskey dotcom example i mean there's a number
of ways that we can type in the data and in the in the wiskii
com data set of data sets so
i i think each other distilleries to their
corresponding entries on the pedia
whiskey fans being quite quite fanatical of create lots and lots of useful information on
wikipedia about about whisky distilleries there's also information that we can link
some of the whisky distilleries independent companies owned by small families or private private individuals
some the majority by these big kind of multinational binge-drink companies so we might want
also link the individual stories to their
parent company
entries in in the period in which the company
and also onto whereabouts there actually
located you can use
you're the POG in this case to do that
we've got if her photos of these distilleries on on flickr via the flickr after
we can link together depictions of these distilleries with information whiskey
same with regions these things have representations in datasets we want to tie those those
things together and
we also
i want to be able to link
there is also potential link the brands individual brands in a data set to the
corresponding entries on wikipedia but we need to be
catholic in doing this
and the reason is because on
there there's some
whisky brands have where the brand is the name has the same name as the
and on wikipedia have differentiate between
not sure telescopes for example but the laphroaig distillery and the laphroaig brand has one
entry about both of those things so we just links to the
the laphroaig distillery and the from brands to the the frog entry on the pedia
then we basically saying that the brand and the distillery with the same thing which
is the case so this is a kind of nice generic example of how you
didn't work may careful about how you actually
the links the making understand the destination that data that the other to before you
created automatically can often come unstuck with these sorts of situations
and then want to link the brands and products intended to refute
so this is basically a schematic representation of this so is that that was look
on dataset and you can see the or
lot of potential for linking to external datasets but that's
the DP one carefully
in this particular example
the state of the art in india
link algorithms linked data is relatively basic there's lots and lots of an example based
on string matching so imagine to link book titles together there's lots of work with
just taking combinations of author name and string titles using them as the basis for
much across different datasets
things like musicbrainz are quite useful in the musicbrainz dataset for provides a bunch of
your eyes will be well basically do it which have been mapped into URI space
pretend fine artists and works contracts and so if other datasets used the same your
eyes internally because you can download the data set that is common key which can
be easily used for
merging expands another example the same there is a slight issue with lifespans in that
sometimes they been
OK that zero waste is more than thirty minutes so everybody could go either
mister actually OK if there was our pride can you don't have to even go
into the store use scan and you know it
that's the poll station
so that in general is this OK there are lots of readers
the reader or send signals
OK they reduce signal down who you know those commodities OK they have RFID tag
there were there were really flat they would say i'm here OK they even during
the RFID
but you get into the system you can match you can do a lot of
but with this
how will be the RFID could be are ready
because if you reading so many different things
and you put into the system
you want to construct a data warehouse you want the data mining the data is
really really huge
so with this one starting in
year two thousand two
after i came back from the ice the conference that conference to the oracle
vice president hubert talks said to find petabytes and how to handle the packet but
state and his most community argument actually is RFID he says
if you go to war are just a walmart that can just claim they want
to embrace are widely acknowledged this edit war marked
they have
you know if you
i have every commodity store on the desk
you know was all the traces
very can goes rule high order had
even now
many other policies so you can verify petabytes
so then had to actually african back actor discuss with me about his phd thesis
i said what about we do this RFID data warehouse data mining that could be
quite interesting to this thesis he got
you've probably see like i see the two thousand six he got the
best student paper award
in this conference
the warehousing and analyzing RFID data sets that are a lot of research papers surrounding
in different corners of the of his thesis
my first part centuries this ceases
you know abstraction because this is so long it serves would take about two and
half hours to prevent so our not discussed every corner but our discussed several metres
things one warehousing how to warehouse RFID and another is how to use a to
the flow mining traffic mining
many other things on their minds
so the first thing i would discuss RFID data warehouse
so the first thing we should say is the data generated by RFID system can
easily reach
that's why they call the state is really enormous y
they got this
the problem is
the reader keeps reading aloud of things
and that are fed each tag is not that long query thirty six bytes or
something like this or sixty four bytes
but if you read
lots of details
and many many times you get a lot of redundant
we so many
unique acumen two petabytes
but we found actually even you claim for example warmer
so they can generate every day they can use seven terrabytes are highlighted
there are lot redundancy
and also lots of low level of abstraction
so if we want warehouse
the RFID data
what we want to do is the first thing is we say
you can have a very highly compact summary for our
you don't lose anything
but you actually can make the data much smaller
that's the first of the age
another thing is you actually can play with this RFID
in the substantial scale we call all of this online
analytical processing music and toured are up on this RFID data in the market dimensional
space in a very efficient way you get get had about state
and you also can preserve a lot of information for example you can preserve the
past structure of RFID
actually the cost is not that high
that's the whole thing we think you do data mining and data warehousing with the
petabytes state is manageable
to some extent even on your PC
using may only have two hundred one twenty megabytes gigawatts how can handle petabytes state
after that you listen to
two my tutorial profile is not that hard
let's look the whole thing just this thinking at typical examples of the whole hour
RFID life cycle
the fact
we're generating lots of commodities and they put RFID tag on it
nowadays the RFID tag is still reason expensive for example the bigger RFID may take
about a dollar of fifty cents together while RFID tag
but the price dropping dramatically OK
now i think in some RFID tag is dropped to almost like cents
the size could be very small like this year or early this year scientific american
has one interesting picture is
the user test tube
then the test tube just get half of the test tube is
on the orange juice is they have some very small thing they enlarged it you
if you do not because it's just now
it is encouraging
is given
in this happening but it
what is happening which is going to be
i wanted to know exactly what
so things may be able to out
the thing that this is just graphs
it's the
examples you extend this this is going to be location
but you know that's the first
two months
so we're talking about you know need to the to
this is to show that it
this is example should
which is exactly the same as graph structure is true
that means that
so this becomes a problem
that's why was concerned
this makes
she said you know this is the next
my just
this that structures which nations should
according to the commission
he the same
this satisfies the basic idea is that the quality of given that it is and
it was so satisfied distribution
this is a structured list
so for example this is about the difference between infinity
this question is max
the question is
none of the max
so according to which is
this is the most likely sequence of states
to demonstrate the exact same semantics exact results right so he
according to his agent comes
exact same thing
right so what happens next
is that
here in the US and chinese x
we see the positive
max max c
it is sometimes a max
right so you've seen
that he so impressed essentially the same arguments
students so that
but if
that's the same thing you accuse them
so you have to be specified rights of this image is
just to see if it is positive
is it a max because he said exact information through
it's not see
web pages right so they created a graph it
and everything else is to be made you know how what they did to the
east everyone collective classification is another example where
link information knowing that things are not independent but actually quite connected helps us a
so many network they or many they actually can be represented very naturally as the
network rights social networks are the most obvious example we know that people in connections
and friendships or some kind of interaction between people collaboration networks
for example from the feeling that you can extract from from archive and the other
another different example where he connect to scientists if they call for the paper
in systems biology that a lot of networks
from gene regulatory networks and things like the web graph as i said and citation
networks are different example now i have papers in web pages as my knowledge and
connections that citations or hyperbolic internet meaning how
let's say help this one another in communication networks meaning email things like that here
know are people in the connection is if one person sentiment to the
so that's basically what we do
and what is interesting looking at the other this line that would be because somehow
it's it's a collective action of many orders of sort of many independent nodes in
some sense so we get we get to see some kind of merging phenomenon noticed
there are some kind of design that artifacts was somebody would sit down and say
this is how i want be but we think of networks of some kind some
kind of being organic some kind of they arise naturally out of out of these
local elections of the
so the question is what do we hope to get from analyse such network they
analysing such metadata data and so the first thing that just i want to show
you what how how we go about this is i'm blocking you hear the degree
distribution of and just simply means what is the number of connections to particular notepad
and the probability of seeing an another such connections and the point is if i
claudius on log log scales
i get this straight line so it means that the whole thing follows this power
law relationship of being the slope of this thing and what does this tell us
about the network it tells me that i should think of networks like that right
where every node has about the same degree i should think about them like this
right there scale free of species is called the right have
a lot of these
high degree copyright right you have so basically and they have these little nodes connecting
through the heart so
real networks are like they are not like right so for example this is one
the other point with that the data is that it spans many orders of magnitude
so here i just showing you
you know over the last you know here's span of five years how you know
networks of let's say five hundred nodes up to two hundred forty million six orders
of magnitude larger networks were examined in in a short period of a few years
and these are all you know
online communication for online social networks and here is the scale and the largest that
so far is two hundred forty million nodes
who talks to whom i would
is the message graph
people are the users and connections mean that one person but
and similarly as you can ask what is the structure of
let's static networks you can ask how does how the
statistics are global properties of networks change for work on the scale as the network
and the two examples here are the first one is the following one it's called
the densification power law with were what i'm showing you here is the size of
the network over
so this is the number of nodes in particular point in time
and the y axis is the number of edges that particular point in time so
every dot here is is the network of some particular snapshot or at some particular
and what is the point here is that the point first this is on the
the second point is that the slope of this line
is one point six which basically means that the number of edges
growth of number of nodes some of and this non so it may be greater
than one meaning that everybody is increasing over time and so for example this is
this is the case where i have my network and i'm asking what is going
on some the global statistics of the network as the network
another simple statistics that also has quite surprising behavior is that they are so some
some notion of what is the longest or every shortest path length in the networks
which how many pubs
this debate from their from around the world some other
here the x axis by this is the citation network from physics so basically what
eleven years and this is how the diameter what so basically the idea is that
even though my network grew from that for more than four orders of magnitude my
diameter actually show so basically i have this object is getting bigger but internally it's
getting smaller something and this is another example of how the some nepotistic scale with
the size of
the question then is OK why am i doing this what i want to do
really the output that you want to generate
how do you go about use
you know standard machine learning technology to solve these problems right most of the literature
is probably all binary classification or regression or or perhaps multiclass classification but a lot
of problems out there you have more complicated prediction problems the second class of problems
is where the outputs are not
structures in the strict sense of
a tree of graph sequence
but where you have multiple classification problems that are coupled together so we will also
see many examples of those
we're really there are multiple response variables
and the response variables are all interdependent k so you don't want to just predict
right for each example would the document or be an image or what it is
right you don't want to be independently predict the label but really you have a
large set of labels that are that all coupled some
and so then the question is right how can we extend machine learning techniques to
with this collective classification problem in the way that we are better than just independently
predicting individual
response right
so here are some
motivating example to start this so you get an idea of what types of problems
you will be able to tackle with these methods so we're not going to talk
about how we the full application here that's what stand but this is more the
motivation of the types of things i'm i'm talking about so
if you do things like for instance part of speech tagging
right then what you want to do is you want to take a sentence like
this sentence up their profits soared at at boeing blah blah blah
so this should be input acts
and what you would like to do is to annotate every
word in that
sentence here
with a particular label
from a set of part of speech tags so and would be on the would
be over he would be proposition against possessive adjectives and so on and so forth
so you see
output is the red hard here right is the augmented import by these attacks
why is this useful it's often useful for instance as the first step in the
syntactic analysis of the sentence when you know maybe at some point you want to
pass sentence often part of speech tagging is the first thing to do
to get there OK so you can see
you know why why is it not simply a multiclass to binary classification problem because
these things will become forthright right so for instance with u u label
you know certain things here let's say as nouns or verbs might have an impact
on what neighboring labels should be right because maybe certain sequences of labels are more
likely certain you know annotations on the whole sentence level are more likely
than others right so so you would like to take that into account
right and how can you do that
the second problem is related but is a bit different so i'm mentioning here independently
is the problem known as information extraction where this is really only
like a broader title for for a whole set of different problems
so the idea here is that we're not so much interested in tax for individual
words about what they are part of speech rule is but would be interested in
is really
to mark up
the document with named entities that are mentioned in the text and also to classify
these mentionings according to a particular you know set of types of entities that you
might that you might want to define so for instance an organisation country a person
and various other you know entities that types that you might want to define timidly
what you would like to get it is if if i have a paragraph like
this right i want to know that the WTO friends and an organisation of the
united states our country
richard aboulafia is the person name
and so on and so forth right and what i want to do is really
i want to add let's say one way of encoding this right i want to
add tags that identify segments of consecutive tokens
and give them a label that this is the personal name of this is an
organisation in right like like senior
and again in doing that right
things will not be completely independent in particular if you if you look at neighbouring
things and you know the segmentation senses the segmentation problem if you like for sequence
of words
you need to look at the overall segmentation
as a whole
in order to to do this already
sort of you know to identify as segment of rivaling right goes beyond like a
the independent classification
OK so the challenges here to predict the segmentation
OK and then taking it a step further in terms of complexity of structures and
also the type of
the problems we might want to look at is here's an example from natural language
parsing where
one of the input is again the sentence what symbols here
and what you want to predict is apostrophe like this so let's say you might
be given a context free grammar of some sort right that tells you about you
know what the types of constituents are that you can you can find here so
any difference that there are things like noun phrase and verb phrases and you're given
a little bit about
you know how
the set of production rules basically and how these nonterminals can be translated into other
sequences of nonterminals and then ultimately into the sequence of terminals which will be or
sentence but basically what you want to do is you
parse the sentence and identify
correct and among the usually you know large number of possible parse trees identify the
most likely the most plausible one that gives the correct interpretation to this set of
english it's right so and the question here is of course traditionally
if you look at this rate in in the nineties people have started using probabilistic
hi little t
this time the star
right so so high
OK so this is the sort of these two policies are only three running around
policy one
is this high which is going to be learned policy
all capital t time steps
policy to
is the optimal policy
for all cattle t time steps
and then this definition
is kind of it's it's mixing to policies
this kind of
hybrid policy so we have a set of hybrid policies
we act according to
pi for a little while
and then we are going to pakistan for a little while afterwards
i guess the index t
defines how long they according to pi how long x four and five star
so it is defined by
x according to h one the first time step back engaged with the same time
step and so forth
OK so this is actually
a very simple proof
other questions about this this is the
if you saw because it's the classification problems well
the any of reinforcement learning
it doesn't tell you how to solve question because the classification problems
because getting extreme to do that is pretty tricky but says that
these exist
which is maybe reassuring
so the proof is essentially just telescoping arguement
so you start with this difference
you write out the meaning
of the value of the optimal policy
and the value
of some of the policy pi
and then let's see
and the claim is
you can break down the difference
in two
a difference
and a bunch of
intermediate steps
so we have this
think about moment
so let's say that pi star is the same as pi
he said that one particular time step
and that it behaves differently
then it it's in this particular time step is just keep right
the difference in these two values
the difference between
it by serenaded by
is going to be the difference
that is incurred
those at that particular time step t prime
i mean no we think about this
this is
a particular
there's particular quantity
and i can
insert in between
these two quantities you could add subtract
this quantity
you could do that for all the two primes between
so i'm not explaining this well
OK so
about the thing to do
if you have something like the form a minus b is to make it a
minor secrecy must be
right because you just abstract c
this will be
and i have the same
i also have a d which correspond to different t prime
in general for all the difference between
one in t
all have
term that i put into the sun
right and the difference between these terms just how often we are going to high
and then how are you according to pi star
and then we can rewrite this
two where i have terms of the form minus the
i guess
or predicting which people are going to get to
well this the the five years before they got
and so on
we see that one-to-one interactions don't exist
but the patterns are informative
and there are
patterns and sub patterns that marked the individual states and their common
state patterns that are shared
in in health and disease so there
there's something that cuts across
individuality in the immune system part of the were born with part of that we
if we happen to share a particular diseases or propensities
a systems approach
the body
we can look at we can mine information from the immune system of the immune
system is mind from the body and we can get some
hints about going explaining this for therapy
a mention two kinds of
please developed again in my laboratory
in fact
as of today there should be
the announcement of the results of the double blind placebo-controlled trial in the united states
for something called t cell vaccination
in multiple sclerosis is the idea here
is that instead of trying to suppress
the systems attack against the brain multiple sclerosis is an autoimmune disease where the immune
system is attacking the brain instead of giving me in individual
immunosuppressant cortisone things that
damage the immune system
in t cell vaccination we vaccinate the patient
against the disease-causing cells
we use the elements of the system to
regulator system so that the t cells that cause the autoimmune disease in this case
it's an equivalent amount of in rats these dead rats
have t cells that
attack there have used their brains we can isolate those cells the cells that cause
the disease the paralysis that the rats
and vaccinate
these these of course
and brother are identical twins so we can vaccinate against the disease by taking the
and stimulating
of of regulation
in in the world and make them
resistant to the disease and as i said there are now studies
showing that this also works in humans these publications up until now not been got
blinded placebo-controlled the placebo controlled studies are coming out
this week
another type of
the activation of this system with new information is something we've developed peptide therapy diabetes
the microarrays
we can
in mice
resistance to diabetes from animals that are susceptible to diabetes and identify a peptide
two weeks reactivity is beneficial the of the month
that of neural activity this but it will not come down with the this and
this peptide is now
in phase three trials
in human beings and i in phase two
it appears
individuals who have been
treated with this peptide that the system itself is looking for
can maintain their a data cells to maintain the cells that produce
insulin and the individuals given the placebo treatment lose their activity
i think that
it it
it is one of the two