if i were to say that
g like two like sport
you look as though you really like something like cricket
you know like cricket rugby
is there any point
in continuing talking about cricket
o point what's the point in time so so the first thing you need to
do is find some sort of common ground
something that the other person has mutually interested and what you do
then you can be very clever about the way you communicate with people if you
can pick up certain things about their their representational
channels and incidentally before i go into the body language stuff how can you tell
if i'm talking to you
how do we know
what preference you've whether your visual auditory organizers
how do i find this out
because you probably don't know yourself
some feedback what sort of either
OK so so if they start to get interested what else should i do what
else can i do to find your
listen to
what using
because whatever you are you're probably going to start using the word
and this works in your own respective languages as well
so the best ways to listen
to what's coming about the words are they using how to express themselves
with the what's another thing you
so you can you can
storytelling and you can try different stories to see which one
the person latches onto
absolutely another thing you can you can try and be very careful with this
research suggests that depending on whether your visual auditory can aesthetic your eyes move in
different directions
so visual thinkers so to those of you chose number one
house number one your eyes tend to do this when you're thinking
if you look up
because wider visual people tend to look up
the picturing them imagining the picture if they carry on looking down this too much
noise so they look up to to imagine the picture you know when you're in
school and the teachers asking you to spell a word
and you do this and the teacher will my teaches they it's the answer not
there you know
well actually the visual thinkers it is
that's exactly what the answer is because they need to look up to to imagine
the word to visual look thinkers
have a look at people's eyes when you're talking to them do they often do
this when they thinking
and the probably visual auditory thinkers tend to look straight ahead
when they thinking
so have all the other is going to pull down the straight ahead there could
be auditory
and can static thinkers guess where they look
to get in touch with their feelings
they can assess it tends to look down when that when they're thinking so now
you can take this to the next level
this research also suggests that your eyes go left or right
depending on
when what you're thinking about in terms of time
most people
not everyone most people
when you are looking to the past
your eyes tend to go to your
so if you think about the past
your eyes tend to go to the left
because when you when you're looking this way
that's the past and that's the future
and most people when they are thinking about the future tend to look to the
this is quite interesting because if you're asking someone let's say you're in an interview
and you're interviewing a person and on their
they've put
they've experienced building business in ten million dollar business
ask them questions
but also how did you do this
and see whether i if their eyes go to the left
maybe true because the thinking remembering
if they go to the right
because of
the talking about the past and yet the riser going forward into in time this
is where the term is more of an american expression
the american expression is that a downright lie
or you're a downright lie
down right
you get in touch with feelings and you get a very creative you line
that's where the phrase comes from so but don't don't take this as red it's
not true just because someone is looking to the right of the line it's just
a generalization that people tend to look to the right when they're thinking in the
the temple st
if i had to
if i had to say yes or no
for this picture i would say yes
they're in rapport if i had to
but there are a few things are a little bit worrying still the facial expressions
on exactly and he does look a little bit concerned but you can have rapport
talking about something very serious
you can have rapport talking about someone you know is
basically dynamic you can still have rapport
you don't have to be laughing
OK so
a number of ways we can do this we have really mentioned vocal yet we've
mentioned the verbal
we mention visual you can start looking
people who are not post
the start looking like each other which is very interesting
you can have rapport
when you match the other person's voice
people are pulling someone's talking slowly
the other person tends to talk slowly
if someone's quiet
the other person tends to be quiet as well
if they've got that connection and that report
can is that it's an interesting one
can aesthetic rapport
you can even have rapport in terms of breathing
one when people are really
in synchronization with each other
they start breeding at the same rate
as well
i i didn't experiments
ten years ago i didn't experiment at the time i had a nephews about six
six seven eight months old
names of irony
and i was looking after doing a bit of babysitting for my sister and he
wouldn't stop crying
and i remember this thing that read somewhere about breathing levels and how you can
essentially what we end up in learning
he is this problem probabilities for the topics
and now
we can do recognition using the model we have learned we give
a novel image
we represented
we represented as a bag of words
and then we take these models we have learned and select
the most probable topic which corresponds to the category in the PLSA case
in LDA case we actually to select the most probable category marginalized likelihood for the
viable so in any case this is the overall structure system of these
algorithms of course we have to from of visual object categorisation point of view we
have to go back and think about some of the issues we we talked about
in the beginning such issues are scale and rotation we don't have explicit scale and
rotation in in in the model models what we have it is implicit so the
just detectors and descriptors we know how do we take of inclusion i believe this
is actually quite relatively robust model for occlusion because it uses these broken down broken
down patches it doesn't really force you to have the entire image as long as
it has enough enough
enough patches to represent your object category that's fine and also in theory we can
think about actually built in this knowledge into the different latent themes or topics
how do we encode translation while that of words model
i don't have translation issue at all
but there are people who have
i attempted to deal with translation by adding a reference
and then we
how do we deal with viewpoint variations again
its implicit in the descriptor and detector but again you can think of in theory
it's nobody has tested this yet but in theory you can put this into the
latent topics and
so what is the properties of this bag of words model was very intuitive it's
analogous to documents and
it's actually very
and very nice way of
of setting up the problem so that we can use a lot of these useful
generative models and and it's very convenient a because ten the power of generative models
some of the some of the power is you can use it for unsupervised training
or weakly supervised training you could incorporate prior information
you can just
i have a lot of expressive power for your data space and then
the learning and recognition is relatively fast compared to many other methods
but what some of the weaknesses of the model the one of the really most
salient weakness is the lack of geometric information
we really ought to think about how do we feel that information in test whether
how much it adds to the to the model and then it's so far the
models are not tested extensively for all these invariances and of course
if you believe in understanding image include
after segmentation then this model is not clear yet how we can use that as
of now to do segmentation
this is actually the first point
no rigorous geometric information brings us to the second
and the last model i'm going to talk about today which is part based model
so we've seen in the bag of words model here bag of words model is
basically we represent images like this but you know i think it's really a face
here the images truly like this
the bag of words model was say yes there is a face
it's really not phases of scrambled phase which is not realistic instead
if we see
this dispatches
right arranged like let's in the image we have the better believe stronger believe that
and this is the y direction
and this is the next
and i'm going to
every wave coming in from the left
it's called the incident rays
and so i will give
moving in this direction
and then
there will be a reflection
which i call are
something may come back
this direction
of the one
and then something is being transmitted
into the second medium get that structure
we are
and that
it's going into media number two
and that's what i want to evaluate
i have boundary conditions that actually call zero i told you earlier
all of the three things together wave equations and boundary conditions
that's true
the boundary condition is that x equals zero
why we must be two
the string breaks
why right here
must be the same as the y right there otherwise there will be a break
of the string
but not only that
y one
it must also be
the y two dx
if that were not the case
that would be kink
in the
role at the
his attention here
there tension here which would be a net force down
but the
the junction itself has zero mass
so to give an infinite acceleration so you can never have king
in a strange not even when it is connected like this was not history
so it must be something that is always
here that
could be like that cannot be like this
and so that's on the condition that the
the relative the spatial derivative from the left must be the same as on the
right side
for a start
with an incident wave
comes from the left
so why why one
why i
i incident
some amplitude a of identity and the incident one
times science
i'm going to write is now we can write it in many different ways right
there's only one
e one x
that's clearly traveling wave that moves in the plus direction
because the signs are different
now i have
we have
it's a reflected
times the size
the same frequency
now i got a plus
OK one
what is the difference in size
this one is going this way
this one is coming back
amplitudes i different
but the case and the same
because the wavelength in medium one is the same
case two pi overlap
that wavelength is is not going to change for this wave as it is for
this one
so now i get to transmit one
its amplitude
times the size
of the same omega
because if this junction
she looks up and down with frequency omega that's the same for both media
so omega is given you can change omega can omega is different from the right
side of this for the left side
in other words
omega one
is the one time scale
but it is also
times k to disable maker
so i get here
x goes into the second medium the minus sign indicates there's going in this direction
that the k two is different
because the speed
is different
because the two is different from v one so with the same frequency i get
a different value
so now i go to my boundary conditions by one equals y two
what you see here
then i get there that
a of y
a of i
x equals zero
any moment in time
i must know that condition so a of i
as a or
must be
you are
if not then the string
or break
i can now take the derivative of my function
the y one b x
this is the case
of these one not small
you find
now also here
more like it's a lot
i don't know to can
the correct this is the last version of the time with
on the side
and now for something because you might want to what
what can i do with this information extraction
the book you want
but if you look at the relationship between two entities
if you think it could be that like the example i did yesterday that
companies merging with another company you want to find
relationship or you might want to find other relationship like this example of
the of stories published here two thousand four
so you want to find one
the entities through
and the other secret
in one of the form
you might be full kind of movement
so we can build upon from
this event
r from the centre of things
you see the
note the words in the past and each one
it is described by a number of features
and you have all the the parts of the relationship you far more than the
i have a dependence
so were
each is easy part of speech can be used the
twenty four value which means that
the bank
so far features that now
proper nouns
you might use is maybe a bit of a new champion you
well it when you have a part of speech tags to a few words of
a sentence
general will lie group of would gather
like the
so if you
the log
the large land the city of new york
ten is the large map of the the city of new york so the three
not sure
so think of words
if you take the word
to get point
but there is no no dependency when you show
there are no bad
i recommend you
it's just that you
the sentence in set b
here is the time
a person
also the geo-political and
so i also think it entity
so you
it's supposed that you have to be
that gives
this kind of information
or you might think
in the classification
well you would need to accomplish
also the entity
so now can be a like to create
it can be
just announce like two
it can be of what could be
some of
and then also the argument that all schools are where the degree of
so here you've read the
it is actually
the acts
what people are the and the
another second arguement is not affected by
an argument with this
so you can
you have
a more accurate representation of
your data
you don't have to let back to new york city and each node of the
thing that you can define also the values
and then
when you're actually willing to compare
the similarity of three
if you have a
the support vector machine when you
so you will compare the similarity to
between each pair of j
but also when you will find you
you will that will come similarity of q of you use with the model
the model
the support vectors that you have
so what is really computer
the old
by criminals
the actual text i think you to
which is defined in the u
good morning
so i see we have
a lot of parents here how many parents we got here
welcome to the parents
how many of the parents have done the reading
so good design work on the parents to
will see that
we've talked about
this diagram i keep coming back to if you want to study biological function the
two traditional ways to do that we're looking genetics
world biochemistry genetics the study of an organism with one broken components those components being
genes biochemistry
the study of the purification of individual components from an organism away from the organism
particularly the most important such components being proteins what they have to do to each
other the unification
in molecular biology that occurred in the middle of the century from nineteen fifties and
the sixties and really up to nineteen seventy or so we came to a conceptual
understanding that
genes encode proteins and therefore these different ways of looking at the organism organism minus
component components mine organisms were complementary point of view and in theory you could go
from the gene sequence protein sequence and protein sequence back to gene sequence you could
go for gene sequences functions functions with protein
except for one tiny detail
this was all just conceptual
conceptually we understood
by the nineteen seventy that the
DNA may RNA made the protein the protein carried out the function
but as of then
you couldn't
individually work with our purify
the DNA corresponding to any particular gene
all the inferences indirect inferences indirect inferences from bacterial genetics better regulation or missiles small
experiments in all sorts of interesting indirect ways working at the genetic code but the
o thing
this is the problem
some people in the late nineteen sixties said great molecular biology is over we understand
the principle how life works now let's go understand how the brain works
and there was an exodus of some people from molecular biology and neurobiology to now
go the brain figured out fewer than ten years or so but in fact
people began to focus on how you can get to work with individuals specific genes
now what's so hard about that mean it's not very hard to crack open red
blood cell and purify different proteins purified hemoglobin you can provide even enzymes chemistry allows
you to purify different components from each other want fine enzyme let's crack open the
separate proteins over some column that separates them based on their size and their charge
money pure inter fractions all or as a traction to see which one has the
enzymatic activity but they use the physical chemical properties of the protein to separate them
into different pockets why not do that would say
human DNA and purify out the gene for beta globin codes
he would the beta component hemoglobin
what would be the problem of just using physical chemical purification to purify one human
gene from another
is one very big molecule
well i could be sure that may be able to break it up
now let's purified beta globin containing part
it looks the same it's just the
it's one chemical palmer was pretty boring properties
and they're not very different any particular DNA sequence in any other DNA sequence basically
about the same molecular weights and charges there's nothing to separate by how you gonna
purify better
that was the problem
that's where all coming in DNA came in which were common DNA was a remarkable
and totally different way of purifying individual components
and the basis of it was this notion of cloning
if i want to purify out from the human genome having human genome
human genomes about
three billion bases long
if i want to purify particular gene what's a beta globin or some other gene
typical gene
might be
on the order of
thirty thousand letters long
this is one part in ten to fifteen
purification of go to achieve
any given gene is only one part in ten to the fifth of the human
genome and then what about a typical mutation
maybe the mutation that causes
the chemical that causes sickle-cell anaemia by changing a single nucleotide beta globin well that's
one base pair
so that means
the surface built by decision tree
you can think of it as a constant these
estimated cost and so that means in the region he had
and this is the indicator function if ec if your input is in this region
so m
it's someone else to zero and multiplied by the constant in the tree model
can be thought of as the sum of all these regions
so these regions are defined by different levels
and they're hyperrectangles
the trees allow for
different scoring criteria the two most famous the two most used are square
where there is the ideal constant is the mean
and the absolute there were no constant is the median of the population
so one of these two loss functions that is averaged over the data and they
share your risk
so you want to find the tree with the lowest prediction risk
so you searching over the space of these constants in regions too
minimize squared error
for instance
this is a tree model
and to do this in unrestricted way
it's extraordinarily difficult
universal technique is to restrict the regions to be
disjoint to cover the space to be simple in some way so here's one we
can define a region in an ordered way and so another region behind
we would show up but the typical way is to
is too
provide splits
their independence and conditional previous
justice with stepwise linear regression which is the greedy iterative procedure for deciding which inputs
to use regression format
that's the the typical way that decision trees down
so you start with all the data
we check each each possible split value and
define a score function that tells how the quality of the split
how much you reduce the variance using square
how much should use the
the least absolute deviation
if is an absolutely
so you choose the input and the split that improve the fit the most you
again greatly the single that improves the most with no regard to what's going to
happen subsequently and then you replace here
original regions with these two new regions into it recursively again
so the big question is when should we stop and if you go to tree
talks and support people argue about whether we should use case going to stop or
if we should overfitting then used car sales
carter technique for instance overfits intensely and then decide how far back to prove
and to reabsorbed cuts and so forth so
this simple algorithm can probably could i one i could up to my first tree
algorithm is one or two pages of seeker is all it takes but of course
to handle real data and category data missing values and so forth
would take hundreds and sometimes thousands of lines
some of the great strengths that can deal with irrelevant inputs
input is shows up in the tree or does so naturally does variable selection
and you can you can do anything you can measure you can use it can
is categorical variables ordinal variables and numeric support
and you you get a an important school
better tree algorithms will tell you how useful variables were
monotonic transformations won't affect
so you don't have have problems with outliers
if the value is three point one four or three thousand one hundred it's greater
than three so the questions being asked are insensitive to outliers in your in your
input there's not much output
they're very fast compared to
other iterative techniques
missing values can be handled the cup of different ways either
in circuit split is hell cart doesn't work comes up with substitute split in case
the first variables unknown what variables will best replicated this the splitting of the data
that you might know so sort of a stack of questions you ask any state
very clever way handling missing data other techniques other
algorithms creating new class called missing
but maybe it may not be missing man random there may be information in its
missing this and so that this might be a good way to split
off the shelf the future and will parameters you can use and within minutes of
learning about them
if you have a single tree it's very interpretable this too few levels you can
say the state of the question which is very useful when you're doing consulting to
be able to interpret required where
the problems are coming from or where the
the best clients are
so four
now they have severe limitations
if you're trying to fit a trend piecewise constant served very
four way to do that so you also need a lot of data it exponentially
each through your data by splitting
splitting data
so in high dimensions especially data is already very sparse
if there is little interaction in your underlying another small river trent then
a and b can the thing then this have a very hard time finding a
plane where regression is very good
you can already see an idea here where aggression is terrible trees are good maybe
we should combine in some way
if there dependent on many variables
also have trouble
also because the greedy search strategy there's high variance you can change one data point
in your dataset get a completely different tree i've seen that happen and so that
can be can look like a completely different route may have very very similar performance
but typically in your data
real data you variables are very correlated anyway
so the fact that split on
agents instead of high
i might have been just barely
the a second best and therefore when you change one data point it changes and
that's sort of the butterfly effect thing happens here propagate
then the whole tree looks different now in the
in the estimated values may not be as different as the apparent difference by looking
so those are my names for
heads and tails
and so we have a and its
the discrete distribution
so it's a probability mass function
as opposed to probability density function
so the probability of x equals x
he calls so here is the random variable x
and here's it's possible outcomes which either zero or one
can somebody tell me what's the formal way of
the probability of the different outcomes for the new institution with parameter theta
OK so as i say that if x equals one and one minus the data
if x equals zero so you could put it the other way around but this
is what's in my notes
and so now already going to do the trick
i'm going to write this as
stated to the power x times one minus data to the power one minus x
this is really just saying the same thing is this it's just that this says
that in the notation it's going to be more convenient for future use
if x equals one
then stated to the power one is data
and one minus stated to the power zero
it is one
so this is stated times one if x six x equals one and if x
equals zero
then here we go one times one minus state so this is the same thing
as this
it's just a notational
the trick
so now let's suppose we have a training set
training set
x one
two x and
and h
x y
is either zero
i want to maximize the likelihood function so i need to write it down
the likelihood of the data given x one to x
it is
what cycle function
this is the likelihood of the log likelihood
tell me the formula for the like
so that's the survivors so
the dark definition of likelihood if the examples independent is the product of the probabilities
so product of data to the power x
one minus stated to the power one minus x i
and then this is
stated to the power
times one minus dataset
to the power and
times one minus data to the power
minus h
where h
it is the sum of the exercise
so what
c four
so there are three
there are three things in here this stated the power oxide is one minus stated
to the power one and this one minus stated to power minus x
when i take
all those products in there
again each of those three things and times so one minus stated power one
and times i get one minus stated to the power and
and here
these exercise
some of them equal one in which case they get the status of them equal
zero in which case i get is just
a one in the product so
what i end up with this data to the power of the some of the
and similarly here is one minus the power minus the sum of the exercise
so now
data that is the argmax
this thing which is stated to the power age
and one minus data
to the power n minus h
we have zero
is this thing to say to let it go one
this is
a little bit of an awkwardness of so the parameters theta
it's not allowed to be any real number it has to be a real number
between zero and one and so this maximisation problem it's not an unconstrained optimization problems
are constrained optimization problems
and generally speaking constrained optimization problems are hard to
you have to introduce multipliers or other technicalities to solve this particular problem can be
solved rather directly but still whenever you whenever you doing maximum likelihood one thing you
need to pay attention to is whether it's an unconstrained optimisation problem constrained
what's the
simplest possible
the way of solving mathematical optimisation problems
that you typically learn as a freshman
take the derivative and then y
and so does it
you strategy it doesn't always work but it's a good
first attempt
and since
i'm talking about machine learning which i view as being part of computer science and
go into as opposed to part of mathematics and going to call this algorithm
and here we will present accuracy as a function of the number of genes
and some people in the cadres of asked me
do you see an optimum when you feel you vary the number of genes
here the authors have tried in a number of strategies on how to build the
multiclass classifier and so some of them so this is the one of the top
is the support vector machine using all being which is one versus the other a
multiclass classification and you various other possibilities
and as you can see on this graph when you vary the number of genes
sometimes you also an optimum
and sometimes
you actually level off or or you keep increasing the accuracy as you increase the
number of features or genes
so we'll have to find a way of determining
what is the optimal number of genes
of features
for some practical purpose sometimes even though using all the features gives you the best
you might want to use fewer features because only at the expense of say ten
percent irritation of performance you can have a hundred thousand times less
and this may mean you know more efficacy or
easier explanation of data
on this example we're looking now the problem of drug discovery
in this case
people have been screening compounds for their ability to bind to a target site which
is trom being sick key receptor in blood clotting
and the training set consisted of a number of compounds that were active in the
number of inactive compounds
and we had to predict for the test set which compounds were going to be
binding the features
used were some very low level three-dimensional properties of the molecule
the president's you know the group movement which is oriented in a certain way and
and in that case again
you can see as we vary the number of features
then the success rate of prediction go through an optimum
and in fact you know of these
hundreds of thousands of features here the axis you know he's got that one hundred
but it goes up to one hundred thousand
you have a fuse on the twenty or so you have the optimum already
here's another example of feature selection in completely different domain it's index filtering
the answers using some non-core from the rioters
got newswire the twenty news group
and the data set of web pages
in a very simple representation of data which is called the bag of word perform
these experiments
so what that word means is that you're representing the document
the features that are frequencies of words in the document
so here you have about you know a hundred thousand features two hundred thousand words
were retained
and of course it's very sparse representation because many of the words never
occur in some documents
by performing feature selection the things some of the interesting results here for these are
for the news groups so in the news group alt it is the most representative
features autism at this in more morality
the other three first ones know for conduct graphics
and you can see that for space on that also makes sense you have space
now signed orbit
religion god church and saying politics of the middle east you have these are armenian
turkish and and for you know this this other news group which is slightly different
from this one has
keywords but
this allows you to
o to characterize groups of texts in terms of the most prominent keywords
here's another application of face recognition
the authors of
of the paper
try to apply to different feature selection algorithms to determine in the image what other
parts that are
the most useful to recognise faces and here it was the discrimination simply between male
and female
with the relief over the if they used a hundred features they found this part
of the next most you know important with five hundred features they started having some
part of the i and with features you see that there is you know more
there are more details that are being picked up by the algorithm
for life is an algorithm that
does not
filter redundancy
in the feature set
so as you can notice that features are selected on both sides of the face
even though
they might be redundant because the face is symmetric
so they propose another algorithm called simba
which eliminates redundancy and so that algorithm picks up features only on half of the
face and does not repeat them on the other
so let's now dive into not to reviewed some of the examples of feature selection
to dive into the reason themselves
and the first so introduce some nomenclature
so we first so that there is
the simplest method is also called univariate methods
and they consider one variable at a time and see where that variable is predictive
of the target
on the contrary multivariate methods considers subsets of variables that together
predict well the target
people in this field also make a distinction between filter methods and wrapper methods
filter methods rank features or subsets of features independently of the predictor of the classifier
have criteria
that's work on their own
whereas wrapper methods used the classifier of the learning machine to assess
the features of the feature subsets
so first
we're going to review some very simple univariate filter methods
so what is individual feature relevance
so again
you know in in an example four of
disease diagnosis you may have features characterizing patient he's with his age number of kids
medical history in some measurements made in blood
and let's say that we have here one feature
that is the age of
and we want to discriminate between patients who are at risk of heart disease or
patients for a healthy
well if we if it turns out that we have the distribution of the two
patients which are completely related
then we going to say that that feature is useless we can't make a separation
between the two populations of interest based on that feature so there is all reason
to discard it
if the joint probability
of the
the variable of interest and the target viable
is equal
to the probability of the individual variables then there is independence between the variables in
the target
or equivalently
thing vanishes
so we're left with the first part
we can see here is the result will be independent of the orthogonal parts this
of of overall cost of the objective function will not be affected by f perpendicular
how what the second part
how would this be affected by a perpendicular
in any idea
it would increase exactly so the first part i will not be affected by a
particular the second part turns out since
i think i strictly positive strictly monotonically increasing you can only increase
if we add in particular part so therefore it is cheapest frost to just take
f which lies in the span of the training points anything off from that we
might want to add it can only increase this thing over here
that's already the proof
so therefore there for the minimum
can be expressed in terms of the training points
so you should ask you should also get the point here
my point
which was what you need
because the show shorthand
so someone said yes they actually should be getting two points because he saw the
first problem is to some extent that's true that was particularly courageous
but then his his post of already sinking which he has an advantage to begin
with intellectual advantage so
i think we should take away one
so long
this represented theorem gives me a nice way of showing you what's the support vector
machine without spending much time when it a support vector machine is simply the special
we are
all labels of plus minus one so support vector classifier lim sup plus minus one
and we use this particular cost function
it's a cost function that only depends on the point through
the function and
it's this is something called the soft margin cost function and
maybe i shouldn't spend too much time when it's not but that particular case and
then the solution by the representer theorem can be written in this way and it's
this of course support vector expansion
and these points that have the ones that have non-zero far they are the support
so that's one application you can also have other examples one bayesian maximum a posteriori
in that case
you can interpret these terms as likelihood of the data and prior over the set
of functions
you can also write kernel PCA
as one example of an algorithm with the representer theorem applies
it's kind of interesting because in that case you need a cost function that jointly
depends on
the training points
maybe just just briefly so you've seen that pieces of the idea and kernel PCA
is you
like can support vector machines you maps or in any comments on your map the
training points
two a feature space in the feature space into something linear irony i in this
case you look for directions of large variance and if you do that
that i was going to show you
just so it is also seen a support vector machine in action so this is
a little video ones made of the solution of support vector machine as you change
the nonlinearity so here i am starting with the relatively small nonlinearity this is almost
a separating hyperplane
and as i so i mean in fact this is a gaussian kernel again like
in most examples is gaussian income that's quite broad it turns out you can prove
that in the limit when they brought with the incoming becomes infinite it's the same
as using a linear code and you turn on the nonlinearities we make the kernel
this brought you see the solution becoming
more nonlinear
and i was asked leave before in the break something about gaussian kernels someone asked
actually for that was the queen what was the question
because it was you here
right question can there is good because in kernel better than the other comes and
cannot always separate i cannot separate all datasets and the answer is in principle yes
goes income can separate all datasets and the reason we've seen yesterday the day before
with today
it was probably today
well it seems to some extent in both cases the reason is that goes in
kernel induces a strictly always induces is strictly positive definite matrix
so i'm i'm making the assumption that points are pairwise distinct or in fact crucial
assumption is there's no point of the positive set which is on top of point
the negative set
in that case of course you cannot separate the data sets you have conflicting labels
but that's not the case all even say all the points of different
then the gaussian kernel will always mapped them into a feature space where all points
are linearly independent
so in a way that if we have m points you mapped into an n
dimensional subspaces and dimensional space in that space you will always be able to separate
them but of course in support vector machines if you have a cost function that
i showed you before
chromosomes the paired up with each other homologous chromosomes
and big g
little g
were carried on a different pair of homologous chromosomes in my meiosis pictures
if that was the case
when these chromosomes segregated
the first meiosis step meiosis one it might be the big are indeed you are
on the left side ninety big our little jewel of side it might be that
that little are one one side centre
because these different chromosomes they could have chosen to line up and in different ways
that's all cool so many goals law of independent assortment is consistent
with the chromosomal theory
he pointed out last time except
big are in big g
we're on
the same chromosome
then we have some explaining to do
maybe medals was just lucky
and big are in big g
happen to be on different chromosomes
what takes the third trait
maybe the reason you got once once one for those traits was it was also
on different chromosomes fourth-straight city-state how many traits
seven traits
if they all gave once once once one assortment
they all have to be on different chromosomes
how many chromosomes the peas have how many pairs of chromosomes the PS have
very interesting he might have just got lucky
in fact he did
we know that there are different chromosomes
makes you wonder whether maybe hadn't if trade that something funny decided
not to put it in this paper i don't know it's interesting
i guess it's choice involved in what you want to report it at what point
here so suppose we instead
i had
big are
and being g
are little g happen to have been on the same chromosome then they would have
been inherited from common from the common parents here it's a from here into the
f one f one
would look like this
there are different from some sort of like this from the same chromosome would look
like this and now
let's make a little scorecard what's gonna get passed on to the next generation
we've got the possibility that it will pass on
this one could pass on
o let's let's keep score big are big she could get passed on little are
little she passed on big are little g could be passed on and little or
big g could be passed on
and if they are on
different chromosomes
we expect water
water water
but if they are on the same chromosome
what we expect
what will come out of this
even if you're going to get this one in which case you get both the
garden g or you're going to get this one in which case little are little
g have a half zero zero
all that's very different
what does mendoza of independent assortment say
it favors this
but mendoza law of independent assortment can't possibly be right
if we see this
so many people didn't observe this
but if we really believe this chromosomal theory we'd expect to see it eventually
so who is going to be right
mendel or chromosomal here
if you vote for both
i and even for mental
i mean the chromosomal theory
how for
how you have both the data to be contradictory how to have a vote for
OK fine
so we have very different predictions
notice that these
i the parental types of chromosomes
they the ones that went into the cross in the first place big are big
g these are the non parental types
of chromosomes
they're the ones there combinations of bigger and bigger didn't match either of the two
parents would have that new combination
it took a while before folks sorted this out
and it was eventually sorted out
in fruit flies
it is of course
the case
neither mendel
nor district prediction from the chromosomal theory turns out to be correct
members law of independent assortment does not hold
and if none of them raise their hands
you can minimize more
have any information
OK so that's one against all
and then
if you go and you analyse the mathematics of this
what you discover is that this failure mode
significantly less severe than this value
because you still have an even chance of picking the right guy in this kind
but that they can cannot go on this happens there
much worse one k
so you can take advantage of that you can create instead of reducing two
binary classification you can reduce to
importance weighted classification
so the importance
the reason your hand is supposed to is larger than otherwise
and you set about classification
we compare these two methods
it turns out that
this week one against all
always better
this is the accuracy so things above the line
irwin's for weighted one is
is bunch of different
learning algorithms and i wanted different datasets in
i guess one town slightly worse
but every time
the better is attempting to deliver
to the some other race in terms of working
another motivation is sort code wise
reduction to sort of inhaling larger
what we do not keep the insight into the workings of learning our them so
we do not need it yes
only one is reduction the reduction is from multiclass classification to binary classification
so in a sense
so we were editing from multiclass to binary
you can do it directly with this one against all
or you can go from multiclass two
importance weighted binary then to binary
so i was comparing
the the
the important of binary is an intriguing for its environment that
other taxes and talking about a black box productions
he even apply them to any classification our them
and you can apply them
just were given some standard interface to all classification there are no special prior things
or anything like that
i was comparing this direct approach
we're doing one
verses are
verses of
compose with
so we'll talk about later which is this
so one thing which is important is the
reductions in not competing with themselves right
these are two different productions
the one versus on the way to one versus all those discussing
but what you really want to compare with
is the weighted multiclass classification right because you want is the best way
the comparison is not done right here
it's time for some of the other things are present later
so modularity
no parameter tweaking
we're just thinking about the classification of the sum of the particular type
or just using it as you would use things that type would actually
dealing with any primaries the classification error
you can reuse your old learning algorithms
the these reductions
right so
that from
now having to think so much viewpoint
in particular
i think there may be
it is fifty classification algorithms have been invented
it is pretty impressive because
mrna fifty cover datasets
if you can
former reduction to classification
you fifty are supplied whatever
one problem you have
it takes awhile fifty hours
and then
you can actually in addition to using the learning outcomes because entirely black box you
distinguished guests participants of the
bled forum on europe
this year with the debate
about culture and its relation to knowledge society
it is my honor and the real pleasure to introduce slavoj zizek
who will give us a view
radical thinking about the future of europe
mister slower
i think the
i think the negation we are
what's know i going on to engage in peace
in which we can take
the man who is a chance
those of you
the years is
this is
this is nice
in eight
so i mean that
we can
there are
so use
it it
you know
he is a
instead of
and you use
in the US
there is
he is
eight of
we should
the problem is
is are
this list
so rich
this is
more and more
so this
well the
of course all these
what we
one of the
this it's
he is
you of many
there you know
this is
a few
are you
that is
this is all
he not
here also
all this was this
the main
both of these
o o
one is
well he is
it means
it it's
i think
the crucial for the production of that it's no longer just so it can see
reasons for the changes
the place precise about the facts
so let's first
the first split you see one
for you use black star i can't message do not
four of the country
so tried to live until
all of you not about what the image
the first is
look over
for the right
you can forget about the problem of good
so the problem
i think it's going to be very to the point of view
stochastic if they can be a number of possible states given by some distribution
episodic versus sequential episodic means
it's literally just one episode and finished the whole thing repeated again for example you
could have
a camera that's on the production line
looking at it affects the coming past might have defects
on the other side is
the artifact arrives in front of the camera the camera looks at it
besides with this effect not makes simple decision yes or no
the numbers on this forgotten you start all over again
so in a sense it's pretty simple situation
one action time
and in this one is not connected one before
a more typical situation sequential way
you're trying to achieve something it takes the number of actions to achieve and then
you anybody
continue on to something else
static versus dynamic
for static environment
while you're what to do next
doesn't change
and dynamic
if while deliberating
the environment can change
so in
in chess
it's essentially static except for
one case
is when
you play the clock
could not dead
but otherwise i suppose also rules that have been first forty moves something in
can roughly speaking it is static
but typically
environment the dynamics of things are happening all the time when you rating and that
may be very important set playing football
try to get the ball trying to sell what to do well
can't wait for long
discrete versus continuous
this is
reference to with this discrete
or there's some sort of continuity sites and some sort of measurement with the real
if you've
well chess stresses
is discrete event street
this could be board sixty four squares
and the pieces and so on
continuous case with the
and i this
it's driving a taxi
OK so you you know we've got autonomous vehicles vehicles that can drive around the
how is afraid doesn't get back to that
the finishing line
and maybe now they can drive through the environment is that the grand challenge
but imagine
taxi driver that
not only can do all that they can they can talk to the passengers negotiate
phase in all sorts of other things
well there's lots of lots of continuous things there it's been continuous and
breaking precious continuous and lots of things are continuous
single agent versus multi agent
in some sense situation is just a single agent environment that's it
but typically we're multiagent situation and the two basic kinds of things that can be
one of them is the other agents can be your friends
and you're trying to achieve something
so notice that in the space missions that
the the talking about
instead of building one
the robot robots going to go off and do something
lots of small and just let the
and if you lose someone idealism that's fine but they
communicating that together in order to achieve some task
and also military applications like that
where there are swarms of
you have these all other other artifacts
performing some mission
the other kind of thing that can happen is that the other agency registries
so for example during the war and you got the rights on the other side
or your
in some kind of action trying to
you could be doing something
now the other agents are trying to get more cheaply
good instead of you
so typically one is in multi agent situation
so i guess i jumped ahead of them
right so the sum of because the first part
so this in words at the bottom there that come up in the islands community
so you can
talk about whether right so i was cooperating with one another
i will get exponentially more confident
this is great
he would think well
problem is solved and we can just write this corollary
we've done
and that's pretty much what we thought at the beginning and we implemented it
and it didn't work
or shall we say it only works for a lot of data
and i mean this is what people typically two
uniform convergence reasoning
so if you read any
recent paper and uniform convergence theory and distribution free bounds and all that
that's basically what will happen
and this in a lot of alarm bells ringing because i mean have also been
doing that for the past eight to nine years
and i guess i was for the first time where we actually sat down and
tried it out and realize how how awful it was
not say
examples of that
but i cannot first focus on the good things
the good thing is well
if you solve this for epsilon so if you fix some probability
level delta news sources for epsilon it just means that
so i will behave like one of was square in
so we can show that our estimator is consistent so this is usually the holy
grail and so
you know
should be just fine and we should be able to finish here
we can also use this as a taste
and we just say well
we observe a certain deviation epsilon
what does that mean in terms of the confidence level so we just like that
if someone in here
and compute this quantity
if this quantity is
very very small
we know
that well
it's very likely
that people's q
it's very large
it's quite likely that is not able to keep
really nice things affecting about
fifteen years before he proved that found improved another result
say proved
that for also those who statistics
this quantity here that we compute is asymptotically normal
and the variance can very easily computed
as you can
to an improved
computational that
so what's really happening here is here taking the expectation of the second term
here taking it both so this is like the standard way i'll compute the variance
just here we have two random variables but
not so much different
you can really do that easily with the fall of
so what you can do is to estimate the variance from the top and it
turns out that the convergence for the estimate of the variance itself is very fast
and then
since we know
the distribution
often means
is going to behave like this
four people's q
normal distribution we know that variance
now all we need to do is we just need to integrate over the mass
but since that's the normal distribution we can just look it up
we don't even have to do any work select tricks always to avoid doing the
and then
this is exactly the kind of distribution here
this orbital delta and that gives us the taste
so basically
that will give us the little outputs of every delta we can solve for now
for you
and this will be artists
and that works amazingly well
and even more amazing thing is already works amazingly well if five six observations
we compare
two the asymptotic to the uniform convergence reasoning
and it turned out that we need about one hundred times as many observations for
the uniform convergence reasoning as we needed for the asymptotic tests
that story
this was all of the theory are going to here for the rest of this
and i can lean back and enjoy
all the applications
let's start with something very simple dot integration
so that's like
get the data from various sources and we want to know whether we can combine
we compare and compare compare a couple of methods
the only the
yes some in two unfortunately
because the reason for that is because you know learning within
how well that's going to be hard because even have to solve these other problems
as well as vision problems speech understanding problems and motor control as well as the
understanding part which are actually interested in so we're just gonna look kind of
the simplest thing we can hear a text adventure game type situation
taken the atomic actions in the game might get move give shoot and the physical
in the game like character one key one key two
now here's a different instances of the key
p one and key two they have different labels and we we can then just
treat these symbols as the
so why are we going to represent the world and this you can see as
a pre processed versions of the visual signal learner situated in this world might have
sirin is going to be easier for us
so with that in mind we can then
define what we call the concept labeling task so the task is to map any
natural language sentence x to its labeling in terms of concepts y that's going to
be like this concept straight on the previous slide
so and to train it we can be given training triples
x while URI to excise the sentence y is the concepts in this URI call
it the universe it's the current state of the world that you know and it's
going to be the set of
of concepts that you know about and their relations and their relations are just a
pairwise relations on concepts so
this picture
maybe explains it more clearly here's a typical training triple OK so you put the
sentence he cooks the rice
this is the
output y that we actually
want to learn how to map
the that's the concept labeling so this so here
the symbol rights in the angle brackets is actually the the symbol for the
the concept the physical
o thing right in the world right so you have to actually learned this word
maps to to that concept you don't there's these labels by the way
they're just for you to understand i mean that could be
it's not like the computer knows what's the word right
and then
the universe here
is the set of all concepts so things like mark golden hat and so on
plus the relations between so here
we just got two kinds of relations
location and contained by and for example john has location kitchen and wels content rice
is contained by gene so that means gene carrying rice
so we can represent a world like that and the idea
it is
yes i mean that consider the
war over the course of the brain
i'm going to say
yes indeed i'm going to take a data set that looks like this
and it's kind of small wireless to try to do something
so indeed my data is going to look like this kind of sentences
and there's going to be ambiguity here so he can see she goes from the
bedroom to the kitchen that she should be labelled with the concert mother
so you don't have to disambiguate she
and if we go back to our example
when you're doing that disambiguation
you can use the universe to do that is because if didn't have the world
knowledge here the she
it's going to be impossible to disambiguate if you happen to have
when you're decoding this if you know that the word rights correspond to the concept
rice which is
let's go back to the all the concert rice which is located in the kitchen
and you know that he here is then cooking
the rise which is in the kitchen you might be able to disambiguate the heated
john because jones location is also the kitchen so you can see that you could
try and use this world knowledge to disambiguate
the isomorphism
going from this vector space to the direct sum of vector spaces
is usually called the fourier transform but the representation of it
the isomorphism of algebras here
that takes this
the product of
the space is this parties in cartesian product into the direct sum of full cartesian
products of smaller dimension
OK and equivalently it could take
filter matrix
and split it into a direct sum of meat dishes that means write it
that makes it corresponds to a block diagonal matrix in the four
domain to make
yes there are irreducible
can assume that there is
and the spectrum of the signal
will be just
a function that takes all these in this in this is
and essentially it will perform
what we've seen in the beginning that
polynomial violation
a corresponding to do this this isomorphism so each of these things quite belongs to
one of the
smaller vector spaces OK
give you as a running example
algebra brother corresponds to the usual fourier transform
for instance
the notion of algebras i said before is in general a vector space clustering as
an example we could have the complex numbers the polynomials and so on and so
a polynomial algebra
to define that we
choose a polynomial amount of money polynomial of degree n
and as an example
we could see this one right here
and we defined
polynomial algebra corresponding to this polynomial
as all the and the set of all polynomials with degree smaller than that
OK and the is the example we can have here
and there
the same set but actually the
all the bananas are computing more modular
x minus one
all right that dimension of this
of this
polynomial algebra as a vector space is an which is exactly the degree of the
of pn
and we could choose the basis for
such a vector space and we could choose the canonical one this is the simplest
form to choose but that's not necessarily
the only one
now the boundary condition
what should be
representation of x to the end
our vector space so
that means we need to find some coefficients corresponding to
these vectors in the basis that
o correspond to two this exit here this doesn't belong to the algebra because it's
degree is an
in the case when our polynomial is x
minus one then we see that this is exactly one which is the first
the first element in the basis so essentially
this reduces to the cyclic boundary condition
and the signal extension refers to what correspond to
o module
of x
and this is obvious that
as n grows it will simply repeat go through all these elements of the basis
OK the convolution is just the product
of a field there
and signal
you know effect so here
the algebra and module are identical and the model is called in this case regular
well this exactly correspond to secure circular convolution in the case of x minus one
and the spectral
exactly the roots
one of the and of x
and there are some and this thing and you will see why that makes sense
in a second
and just to note is that here they are the interests of unity
OK so
this is the spectrum
the fourier transform
is the isomorphism between this algebra
and our colleagues these vertical things groups
i would circle the
and i did that in my notes but the
things get really messy if you start circling this diagram is going to get really
fall just to warn you
by the end of the almost unintelligible but hey
there it is
here really
feeling bored you can draw this a few times and you can draw the how
it grows
so there are the groups political groups of five
the second step is to recurse
this is where things are a bit unusual
even more unusual
i really should have had the line in between one and two
so going to have this down
concerted here
also in step one want to find the median of each group
OK so
what i like to do is just imagine this figure each of the five elements
in each group gets reorganized so the the middle one is the median so i
call these the median of each group
o five elements of the median
right in the middle these two elements less than the median to on great in
the media
again we're all elements are distinct
OK so that they are computer how long is that take me
and over five groups each with five elements compute the median of each one
at times over five state and that's going to
the i mean you're coming comparisons which is good because definitely
the point is within each group only have to do because the number of comparisons
because of cost number of elements doesn't matter you could use randomized selects for all
i care no matter what you do can only take constant number of comparisons as
long as you don't make a person more than once
thanks so
this is easy
is any
you could sort because sort the five numbers and then look at the third one
this is only five it
so that's one of the idea already we have some elements that are sort of
vaguely in the middle
but just of the group
and we've only done when your work
doing well so far
now we get to the second step which starred core
well we curse
the next idea is well we have these four over five medians
i'm going to compute the median of those medians
so i'm imagining that i rearranged these and unfortunately it's an even number six about
but are rearranged
so this guy
from the second box is the median
these elements that these two elements are strictly less than the sky these three elements
are strictly greater than this guy
now that doesn't directly tell me anything
it would it would seem that doesn't directly tell me about and the elements that
we'll come back to that in fact does tell us about some of the elements
right now this element is just the medium of these guys each of these guys
is the median of five elements
that's all we know
do that recursively
this is going to take team event over five times
so far so good we can afford to recursion a problem of size n over
and linear work we know that works out to linear
OK but there's more promising not done yet
the next step is part axes are partition element partition there the rest of the
algorithm is just like randomise partition so we're going to define k
to be the rank of x
and this can be done i mean it's and minus are plus one or whatever
i'm not going to write how to do that because we're higher level here
but it can be done
and then we have the three way branching so if i happens to equal k
we're happy the pivot element is the element we're looking for
but more likely
i xi less than k
or it's bigger than k
and then we just make the appropriate recursive call
so here
it's like the i th smallest element
in the lower part of the year
the left of the partition element
and otherwise we recursively select the
i minus case
the smallest element
and the upper part of the era
OK so this is not writing sort of high-level because we've already seen all of
this is the same
as the last couple steps randomized select
that's the algorithm
the real question is why does it work why is this linear time
so the
first questions what the recurrence we can quite right down here
because we don't know how big these recursive subproblems could be
we're gonna the recursion the lower part of the upper part this just like before
if we're lucky we have split like zero and minus one this is going to
be a quadratic time out with the claim is this this partition element is guaranteed
to be pretty good and good enough
this will the running time of this thing will be t of something times n
we don't know what the something is
how big could it be
i could ask you but sort of indirect result of tell you we've already recursive
called here and over five
it better be
the whatever constants is going to be something
times and better be that constant is strictly less than four-fifths
if it's equal to four
then you're not splitting up the problem enough you get an organ running time
if it's strictly less than four-fifths
then you're reducing the problem by at least a constant factor
in this sense if you add up all the recursive subproblems and over five and
something times and
you get something that is a constant strictly less than one times and
that forces the work to be geometric this geometric you're going to get linear time
this intuition but it's the right thing to wish
OK so whenever an earlier time keep that in mind you want to get the
proper if you're doing divine concrete got to get the tall subproblem size to be
some constant less than one times and
that will work
we got work at this
costs in here
and we're going to use this figure
which so far looks surprisingly uncluttered
now we will make it cluttered
what i would like to do is drawn error
between two vertices
we're going to start today with the cities of lecture and nuclear physics
the basics of so it introduction it is
the appreciate to introduce you prefer so is good
she started a few years ago as a phd you
and then should become very quickly one of the difference in these things especially in
the french institute for nuclear research CA
where should we can
since two thousand
group leader of the to conduct nuclear
structural studies and also the many body problems which is now located in the need
believe it was just asked
the microphone
good morning i'm very happy to be here so
i'm working on nuclear physics so
i'm now working again which is convex and that the illness you know you'll lu
it's located in common
and so it
it's not as you just we with nuclear physics we are dealing with things that
make money
this smaller
we are dealing with MTV of energy we are dealing
with experiments
we ten or twenty people so what i'm going to
to teach you is what is nuclear physics what are the main features what are
the experiment from nowadays and what are the theoretical development
that have been undertaken
but before starting just three questions that seems to be very easy but
that are very tricky the you know what is the heaviest nucleus
in the universe
do you know how many nuclei do exist just think about one
one number
how many nuclei do exist
and what about the shapes of the nuclei
because we are dealing with the quantum system and
you will see that shape is something very
important to interpret experiments that
it in contradiction with the fact that you are
dealing with one something so
these are
tricky question also
how many nuclei do exist just to give you a flavor
this is the nuclear charge so
so you have the neutron number and put another here
so all these big cell represents one nucleus
so in yellow you see that you have two hundred ninety one stable nuclei that
do exist on earth
but there are many other nuclei that have been fantasizing laboratories here at
these are the sale or again you know you know the places to do
one thousand artificial nuclei have been found is sites that
there are many many predictions that to seven thousand bound exotic nuclei may so you
see that there are a lot of discoveries
new discoveries are made every day and there are a lot of places was the
future seven thousand exotic nuclei have to be discovered
you know one are
these are stable nuclei that are here now on earth
all these
i do that
to the lines
OK to the lines
doesn't here and all that one
other i'm going to that we are searching for now
concerning the
concerning the deformation these are some theoretical predictions
i will explain you know
course what these hartree fock bogoliubov approach
it's a theoretical approach so we are dealing with a nucleus made and made with
neutrons protons
and it's very difficult to study because it's the many body problem so many constituents
do interact
and we don't know how to solve that it's not specific at all
nuclear physics is common to all the
type of physical whatever you're starting when you have many many courses showing that do
interact you don't know how to solve that exactly
so you do some approximation for example you have the right
so you do what we call the mean field of these are prediction from these
and what is not here
what is needed here is the main information better mean deformation and you see that
they close to zero correspond to spherical shape
and you have only a few spherical nuclei
do correspond to magic numbers what we call the magic numbers
eight twenty twenty eight
fifty eighty two is the same
a kind of magic number of an atomic nucleus the value is not the same
but you have also
magic numbers when you are dealing with it from
but you see that many many nuclei are poorly so the formation of deformation in
and in the range so it means that in the intrinsic frame
they are like that or oblate here
so i mean that it's quite difficult to
to study in because you have many new components that are on different orbitals so
when you average
and when you consider the average there is the average of the the formation
then you have
something which can be very cold deform
april literally
so now the value of my lectures after this introduction
so today will be devoted to some features about the nucleus
i'm going to talk about the discovery
with the research thought experiment
and some properties radius binding energy
the interaction between nucleons
lifetime bridge activity in some application for it's in our for electricity
and energy production
so tomorrow will be devoted to modeling of the nucleus i will explain different approaches
so i macroscopic one where you are dealing with liquid you consider that and you
can easily with and then you can calculate many properties
front because cooking approaches where you really treat
nuclear one degree of freedom
that then the lecturers will be devoted to a number of recent study
concerning the discovery of these exotic nuclei
the isomers isomers are metastable states that do exist
in different nuclei so metastable states excited states which means that you can produce images
in an excited state that state it will stay
so if you construct your own kernels
and you want to show that is a valid kernel to do that is
everything is valid actually if you want to show that is a positive definite kernel
or if you want to or in other words you want to say two to
show that it fulfills mercer's property you just have to show that
give rise to a gram matrices that have no negative i can values
it's not always the the the the easier way to to prove that the kernel
is is a mercer kernel but
these away
and these input contains a few results that can be used if you want to
construct kernels from kernels
if you take the power for kernel
imagine that k one and k two are two mercer kernels them
OK want to the is also a mercer kernel and if you take the positive
combination of two kernel
it's still look mercer kernel issued take them to the if you take k one
times k two it's also
mercer kernels
so this is usually long and exercise that give when i teach
kernel methods and this is usually an exercise that nobody is able to do
so we're not going to do it
so here is a partial conclusion
so the kernel trick
there is this the first thing that you have to to to remember
it is the kernel trick you pick your favourite linear learn classifiers
and you could analyse it
and you you end up with a nonlinear classifier against criminalizing
linear or even just consists in replacing all dot products by kernel
and you're done
then we talked to beat about the mercer's condition
mercer's condition is is is the thing on the positive and negative organ values and
it's are i'd like to to stress so that it means that if you have
a kernel that feels mercer's condition that means that it's
there exist mapping phi said that when you compute k of UV it's equal to
the dot product between phi of u and five feet
there are a few
existing kernels so
that i showed you
actually there again one that is the two that are very popular the RBF kernels
and polynomial kernels
and a very important thing
uh that i'm going to talk about more later on is that
doing classification with structured data such as trees graphs sequences
is made possible
by the idea of kernel
in kernel methods mean that
the only the only thing that you have to worry about is to define
the proper kernel if you want to classify
you just have to define
mercer kernel on graphs
and you can use these very silly
dumb algorithm that i showed you and you can do classification graphs
if you want to do classification sequences you just have to derive
a new kernel sequences and then use any linear classic algorithm that you know for
instance the perceptron algorithm that you can show due monday
can use it you can customize it and you will end up with a nonlinear
with the a classifier for
the the the important thing that is that we the kernel method
trying to two
tackle problems were that involve structured data is is a model to the problem of
of finding a good kernel
exists there's no no no no need to worry about algorithms the the questions that
go with with the kernel trick is
and i'm not going to answer these because
i don't exactly know how to
two and
it is how you choose the right kind
because it's difficult
how you can combine kernels so there are a lot of works that
i'd read the problem of combining kernels usually the combination of kernels made as a
convex combination that is it's almost like the combination i talk to you about
these communication here
we've that we there
convex constraint on the
the coefficients
then there's the question of building kernels for structured data
and there's another question i don't if it's a question or something that i didn't
say much about is what kind of algorithm that you can use or you can
use us as the kernel algorithm so she here here's a list of very
of some other in
so it's ridge regression the kernel ridge regression and if you know what is regression
it's just the square regression where you want to
to predict a real value from x
four from some input data x
and you use square
the least square method and you do you have you add some regularisation and gives
you a ridge regression
and you can catalyze these you can two very closely related
algorithm which is a kernel fisher discriminant
you can do to kernel PCA
so it's principal component analysis it's an unsupervised method that you can use and you
can do as the
there is support vector machines
and this is the topic of the next the
the next
fifty minutes
how good
OK so it's a multi asked me asks me if if if you you have
some kind of knowledge
as how the chosen kernel is going to to make your data
so the problem that
can i say except that if you work in specific domains
usually if you know that the the kernel that you derive is
it is
it makes sense for for the experts of of the domain then
you have good chance
more probable that you can have separation but otherwise you cannot say that's why i
say that the truth in the right kernel is an issue
it is very difficult and you can not even know
with a good to the directional regions the very totally wrong kernel so there is
no answers
thank you
you'll see that there's usually there's just one section of the paper
that describe the bulk of the the and the strategy they used to compute everything
usually it's really nice it's really really elegant
it's there's it's there's just one part of it is that is
not new but very very
so for the mismatch string kernel
the only difference we've we've
with the previous kernel the spectrum kernel is that you low
low four four
this matches
that is that if two subsequences are not precisely equal you want to say that
they are totally different you want to say that the value of the similarity of
the subsequence is is equal to zero you will
and of course
down weight there are similarities
but you're not going to say that is zero
and again it's too if you write down and if you think a moment of
on on the problem you may think that
allowing for mismatches may
you imply a lot of different
algorithmic problems but they were able to two two two two
to use the same suffix tree structure to efficiently compute the mismatch string kernel again
just go see the papers he there nice
and then using this kernel
there were
able to two
two up if a performed the result that the results that they have in the
spectrum kernel and and they compared favorably to several state of the
our method using svms
so the the thing that is very important here is that
leslie and her coauthors only focused on the on
the design of the kernel they didn't really care about what kind of algorithm that
they were going to use
they were just worried about having good kernel
and and is very important because for all all or other kinds of methods like
neural networks and
bayes networks some sometimes everything is
you have both the outgoing
the modelling and inference everything is entangled is is very very hard to to see
the difference between
part and the algorithm part in and everything
four kernels you just kernel methods usually for specific promise you have to design a
kernel and then once you the current you can use
what you want
and fisher kernels
this is something that
is interesting is it's not i don't think it's very easy to to implement because
because of the remarks that i may make here but the idea is is is
the following imagine that you're you have classification problem
and you consider all the classification problem on sequences
and you have to be positive sequences for instance x one to x and and
watch the first the first thing to do
you do is to model the probability distribution of the sequences
in order to do that you can use a hidden markov models or can any
kind of models that silly talk to you about yesterday
that is appropriate to model
it is something very special is that you're going to compute the feature vector u
x for some value x as
he is famous for
you have a moral these forces and HMM an HMM is defined by parameters
and it defines a probability distribution and you can a
differentiation differentiate with respect to all the parameters
and this is what you do you compute the gradient with respect to all the
printer that you define your your model european local model for instance and then you
take the gradient and you see what i what what is its value at at
at the precise x that you consider
is the meaning of that
and you have the vector
so the size of the vectors is precisely the size of the number of these
is the number of parameters that you have the define the define your in the
define your your model the thing that you use to define the to model the
probability distribution on your data
there are many question actually if you were can be done on on fisher kernels
you can and you you want to tackle some specific applications i i UU your
capitol of reaching very good results but there are a few questions that see that
that are very difficult to handle when you do official kernels like
how you choose the adequate model for p
there is that the dish the how you're going to
estimate the probability distributions of your data
so these are these problems
there's another problem that is a which is that you're going to do two steps
of learning the first step is to learn
these models
and the second step is the the learning that the class
learning of the classification function and so it's usually very difficult to do it's not
it's not recommended due to do
tasks if you want to do one thousand
if you want to do classification just to classification
sometimes you cannot avoid to avoid doing so another task but if you can spare
the the the
the the learning of of something else did of doing density estimation then you should
do that because the problem that you have for classification
all classifications you have them for density estimation so you have
two problems and you have a kind of a pipeline and it's very difficult to
deal with this is despite by my
and so there's there's
there are the the things about modern marginalized kernels and sequences these
OK now i want to enter into the details but if you want to derive
another view of
the fisher kernels and to
actually they make just they make a connection between their kind of of kernels which