including the amplitude a including the phase angle phi
that first calculate omega
that is the square root of k over n
that will be ten radiance per second
the period t
which is two pi divided by omega
it would be roughly
six point
two eight seconds
and the frequency f
would be about
o point one six
just to get
some numbers
one point six sort
this is not my
they this is o point
six to eight
and this is one point
six words
two pi
divided omega you can see
this is then six divided by ten is about o point six
all right so now
i know that equals zero
x equals zero
so i see my solution right there
right here
i put it equal zero
and in order to access zero
so i get zero
he calls eight
times the cosine
o five
a is zero
if i really the thing at equilibrium and i give the velocity of three meters
per second is going to oscillate so a is not zero
so the only solution is the cosine phi is zero
so that leaves me with
five by over two
three by
o five three by over
the only two possibilities
now i go to my next
initial condition that the velocities minus three
here you see equation for the velocity
this is my three
people zero
so my story
mine is a in use
we don't know yet
i is a
and there we have only just created
omega story which is ten
he is zero
i get the sign of phi
if i by over two
the sign of phi is one
so you find immediately that a course plus o point three
so the solution now
which includes now a
is that x
he calls plus o point three
the cosine
which is ten t
plus y
over two
so you see that the
initial conditions
but the conditions i t people zero they determine my age and it's human my
face angle
if you had chosen
this as the phase angle three by over two
that would be fine
you would have found a minus sign here and that's exactly the same
so you would have found
i want to demonstrate to you that the
period of oscillations nonintuitive as that may be
is independent
of the
amplitude that i give the object
and i want to do that here was this track
i have a an object here
this object has a mass
one hundred eighty
six plus or minus one gram
court and one
i'm going to also made it
every going to measure the period
but instead of measuring long period i'm going to measure ten periods because that gives
me a smaller
uncertainty is small relative error in my measurements
i'm going to do it as an amplitude
which is fifteen centimetres let's make twenty
so i get ten t
get a certain number
and i get an error which is my reaction error
which is about a tenth of a second
that's about the reaction that we all have roughly then i'll do it forty centimeters
we get ten t
and we get again
plus and minus one point o point one second
and we'll see
how much they differ
they should be the same if this is an ideal spring
within the uncertainty of my measurements
we see defining there
i'm going to give it a twenty centimeter offset which is
and then i will started when it comes back here so i will allow it
one oscillation first
it's easier for me to see it stands still
when i started
there we go
what we see
fifteen point one six
o point one six and by the way you can derive the spring constant from
this now
because you know to mass
you know the time
not going to give you the displacement amplitude which is twice as high
so i think it forty centimeters
but ten
forty centimeters huge displacement
fifteen forty one three
fantastic agreement within the uncertainty of my measurements
there three hundred and the second
of course if you tried many times you will always get that close because my
reaction time is really not much better than the tenth of the second
i'll show you something else
which is quite interesting and that is
the behaviour of the period is
on the
on the mass of the object
i have here another car
which weighs roughly the same
i'm going to add the two together
and so we get an two
it's about three hundred seventy two
one minus one grand plus and minus one comes in because our scale is no
more accurate than one gram so we put them both on the scale
and we find this to be
the uncertainty
so no
i'm going to measure the ten periods
of this
keep moving an equal and opposite directions because of the conservation of momentum
other leptons the mu on and time you want or talent and i tell
and that happens roughly half the time
or roughly one percent of that have
something else happens
namely you have
the electron and positron
or the new unknown at time yuan or the talent and i tell accompanied by
photon another bit of radiation
that's the body and soul of quantum electrodynamics you see charged particles
the things that photons respond to
photons respond to them they get radiated
and by consistent application just knowing the basic interaction
that basic act of radiation
and by consistently applying the rules of quantum mechanics and special relativity
you can build up all of quantum electrodynamics
and you can test that you've got it right
by looking to see that the number of photons radiated at different energies that the
angular distribution the antenna pattern has to study many many events is consistently described by
the fundamental
vertex that you get from the symmetry and structure of quantum electrodynamics
the other half the time when you don't see electrons and photons what you see
is more like this
that is you see sprays of particles
now actually
more common than these
events we see three sprays are events where you see two sprays
going in opposite directions
those occur roughly half the time but ten percent of that half roughly you see
instead three sprays
well this sounds like a story very much like the story i just told you
about quantum electrodynamics but now instead of having a
single particles and particles that are
leptons and photons you see sprays of particles and these sprays when you look into
them consists of strongly interacting particles like
protons neutrons which we're trying to get at
rho mesons other mesons and their antiparticles all these strongly interacting particles that are
produced abundantly
that accelerators
just looking at these patterns
you be tempted to make a direct analogy between
this is the well known structures of quantum electrodynamics and the structures that you're seeing
in the strong in this class of events that are strongly interacting particles
if you squint a little or if you're of a certain age and just take
off his glasses you would have a hard time distinguishing them
and so
one would be tempted
and it turns out to be
consistency cheque which i mentioned in the moment
one would be tempted to identify
jets if you knew about quantum electrodynamics as the quarks and gluons
of course they can be literally identified with the quarks and gluons because for one
thing the not single particles
but we can if we are willing to compromise a little bit and say
it's not the quarks and gluons but it has the energy and momentum of quarks
and gluons
then we have a testable hypothesis
because then we can test which is similar to the two in electrodynamics whether the
antenna patterns as a function of energy is a function of angle
we can also see events with four jet occasionally ten percent of the ten percent
we have even an extra
radiation event four
we can test and all details the basic fundamental interaction between quarks and gluons which
from which the whole theory can be built up
so it's in that sense that i said so we see the body of
the body of
but qcd
we see the quarks and gluons and
their joint so to speak the limbs and joints because we can also see how
they interact and that's sufficient to
build up the entire theory in principle just using quantum mechanics and special relativity
consistency checks work the distribution is right the number of particles is function of energy
is right
as dictated by that thought
there's the missing ingredient was all the profane here that is identifying the energy and
carried by these conglomerates of particles with
energy and momentum of some underlying structure that you don't actually see
the quarks and gluons how can you justify that if they really if the quarks
and gluons shopping energy why don't they show up as individual particles why they choose
to show up in this peculiar way
and that's where the soul of QCD comes in
so this is the body but there's also the sole which is how you breathe
from quarks breathe life into these many jets
many particles that make up jets and that's where this property of asymptotic freedom that
mark so kindly explained comes in
asymptotic freedom directly in the phenomenon
is simply the fact
radiation events
involved only small transfers of energy and momentum so don't disturb the overall flow of
energy momentum are quite common
radiation events like this radiation of an extra gluon in substantially different directions which involves
transfers of energy and momentum are rare
then we have our cake and eat it too namely we can see
why there are
occasionally what we can see that there are radiation events that are discernible only have
large disturbances of the flow of energy momentum
and yet
each time we have such a thing
the individual quarks and gluons
radiate softly that is how radiation events that don't change the overall flow of energy
and that produces
that is the way you go from a single particle to the observed pattern of
many particles in the jet
that is calculable that property of asymptotic freedom is calculable property
of the fundamental theory of QCD it involves calculating the action of
the of what we call empty space the virtual particles and reacting to charge and
charge the talk about that little bit more detail later
since the calculable quantity we can calculate exactly how it
turns on that is how the effective charge the
the ability of particles to radiate gets smaller and smaller as the amount of energy
momentum that has to be is conveyed in the radiation gets larger and larger
by literally by studying such jet events one can start to trace out
so for every
covariate acts i input actually going to have a vector of outputs vector of responses
that's multivariate regression
OK we're going to formulate this problem as the second order cone problem an SOCP
compare that to the last which is just l one shrinkage l one regression
done independently on every one of the response components
see if we can get any benefits from them
the SOCP which cost more computationally we also compare a couple of different procedures get
cheap method
and then a computationally more expensive method sitting in difference in rates here
OK so this is just the classical set up of the last so
how many other kind of procedures
dancing selector and so on and so forth gives you neither aggression there's the design
matrix is the parameter vector noise perhaps
and you know if you need to the usual approach is the regularized least squares
problem quadratic programme
they have a square error term and they have a regularizer
and l two regularizer is called ridge regression l one
is is l one l zero which is the count of the number of
components which are nonzero that leads to an NP hard problem
and then there's also no attempts to look at sort of convex nonconvex problems where
the exponent is between zero and one might say the l one has been focused
almost all the attention because there's surprisingly strong results available for l one it acts
kind of like zero in certain situations
now there is a huge literature on this and it's important to kind of divided
the literature and what the goals are installed at all session theoretic there's different choices
of loss functions
so some people are interested in squared error is the regression after all it wouldn't
be too surprising but the eastern square for the predictions right about the parameter estimates
OK so you you might get you might use user plugin or something but you
get the parameters to me plug that any make a prediction
and you compare that to the new data you might get and you take on
your loss to be
than expected air
OK so that's the loss function has an expectation there
now look at that loss over multiple repeated datasets and that would be the frequentist
risk you would be calculating there
OK so that's prediction a lot of people have been looking that
the more classical in is just look at the squared error in terms of parameter
if you really care about the parameters which you do in any situation he might
carry the one will focus on is what's called support recovery which is the indices
in which you have nonzero parameterized case i'm going to make an estimate
and some of those slots the indices will be have non zero values and i'll
i'll return support as my estimate after i've done that i could parameter estimates just
restricted to my support and that would be a way to actually do parameter estimation
is the two stage procedure
OK so you'd like to hear your risk now will be the probability that you
don't get the right support
so the different risk functional than the one in the first two cases
OK so now let's talk about this multivariate regression problem
OK so a little bit different so now
the y
is a matrix further and data points but every row of this thing is a
whole vector
so for every x
you get a you know every x rho here you get to y rho as
well so it's of x y pairs are both vectors
therefore the b may be is no longer vector b is the whole matrix
right and you can think of each column of this thing
as all the coefficients appropriate too
one of the y components
OK now you might hope to be able to do a good regression in this
situation when
these regression to have something to do with each other related regressions
so regression for component why one might be related to one for y two in
particular might share their support
i e there might be some relevant features
relevant axes which are relevant across multiple regression you might get more power by doing
the regression simultaneously in that situation
so that the intuition
and you can now go on sort of bayesian story if i put on bayesian
had kind of a hierarchical bayesian model of some kind to try to capture that
we're not going get this talk be frequentists org have developed some kind of loss
function which captures that
i'll get ready some tree shrinkage of parameters which we hope might be related towards
each other and not distributive everything towards its for zero or towards a mean which
is what the last so node
OK so we're going to have design matrix
matrix operations and we're going to look at all these parameters going to infinity and
try to say something theoretical situation
OK so our first but it worked on this is ue obozinski young's work started
with block regularisation second order cone problems so here's could be a regularisation problem we've
censorship in various ways
so this a really nice example of what happened to me
and after that i must say stopped working with this company was that was not
the first time that something stupid let me tell you a story
so this company
some device wanted to figure out
based on some
information about the blood status
old main have prostate cancer
so that it's apparently fairly easy to get started from sick old man who had
prostate cancer
the reason being that usually when people get sick they will say OK you should
take blood and it is actually interested that while other people will be diagnosed what
is actually and will quickly and bits and whatever you should do it
six people are usually very willing to give you that
healthy people aren't
so that this big stack of
data from sick pay will see goldman
and that's the problem OK we have a little bit of data from healthy people
but we don't have enough
that's that's so they got at the had this really brilliant idea
they went of
because this is a this company was to start up on campus
this so OK well you know
who's going to give us the bloodless easily while students of course that you give
money to give blood
and so they went off and got all the blood samples from healthy young active
probably slightly drunk male students
and came to be me and said alex can classify
so i told him well i guess i'll probably be able to build the wonderful
estimated it'll probably separated two classes but it will be no good
and so they wondered why
well the point is quite simply that of course it would take all sorts of
things probably the hormonal status will be different from the the amount of activity would
be different
demand of media they probably drink would be different so there's a lot of things
that will be very different
that probably wouldn't pick up on the prostate cancer center in feature
so we need to make sure
you capture the bias
problems otherwise
you'll get really
bad example
there's another example that happened to the US army in the seventies was
but i think late seventies when the network started getting popular
so they wanted to
build the system which can detect with tanks in the forest
so they decide to do the right thing and do actually experiments
so i went off and draft attacks into the forest
and the flow of the forest the
with the plane with the camera to pictures
and that
the tax drove them out of the forest
for the first game
build a classifier
they worked flawlessly
what went wrong
has anybody got an idea
you're pretty close
so the phrase
pretty much what happened is that draft attacks into the forest
and this was in the morning when the taxman before so that long shadows
by the time the tax that the first it was high
there were no shadows
so what the classifier actually do this it did take the chalice was munchausen did
that really well simple problem
and they spent a lot of money on it
if you do machine learning problem here one
you really really really need to make sure that you about to explain
if it isn't there are ways how to
fix things if they are not too bad if they have some amount of wire
so this goes under the moniker of covariate shift correction
i mean that tools
to deal with this
at least to some extent but you need to be very careful
and if you just naively run it
o thing you'll be screwed
another example
a bit more recently on netflix
if you look at the ratings
i think about two or three years ago the ratings changed
the average ratings
jumped up by half a point
so what happened well
when you basically gone whether
how much you like the move you're not and this is the initial scale went
from i hated it to i loved it
after that time the scale went from i didn't like its two i loved it
so all the some the ratings changed
travis intend in in the competition we had to figure that out on you
let's just stop a little bit what we had in terms of stuff
well we could encounter vectors
all strings like from takes the biological sequences
structured documents
graph like internet
gene regulatory networks
you might have some tertiary structure in your proteins themselves
and well
what can happen well you could have incomplete doctor
data may actually come from different sources
as in the same information in different places like you have three labs actually cooperating
on some large scale micro study
the doctor may happen to be biased
so that's
OK case
or it may actually be ill-defined
so this is what happens to you actually quite frequently if you talk to somebody
in the in practice
so they will tell you that they will have some idea of what you should
be able to extract
but it may not actually be very close to what really helps them this so
some the very maybe actually to tease out what really solve the problem
or even what the problem is
this is a particularly nasty one
environment may actually react to what you're doing
and reinforcement learning deals with that
so for instance
people at some point started designing butterfly portfolios
so the idea was well you pick some good combination of stocks that
when one goes up the other one goes down
he picked on those well
why would you bet on something that was value is essentially constant well you buy
low sell high right
trouble is as soon as people figure out what you're betting on they will be
against you
so that arbitrage opportunities appears
so at some point as butterfly portfolios are not so useful anymore
then people went to france in france in fancy ones
so this is why
a lot of traders wouldn't really tell you what the strategy is
it's going to compete against them
any questions about that
the next thing is a little bit what can we actually do with start
and i'm
roughly distinguishing between unsupervised supervised learning
with lines at different heights
and then at each level for you know
how many correct components are about like how many peaks at above that line
and the biggest cluster
so for example if i hope you will see one peak two
three four five
but if the threshold lower like here
i may seem to be
which means that at this level that are all in one place here i have
i love this place the
and at this level here
i have only one left
and so that could produce is not just one clustering but basically all possible clusterings
when you move this line from zero to
one the the highest peak distribution
o thing because this is a very good question in fact i don't know if
you look at the bottom of the page this doesn't work so used you want
to this the
this is why this this
can't really work in high dimensions
and one of them is that actually kernel density estimation
it doesn't work in high dimensions two
basically for several reasons so this will work in
and the second problem so everything that in green is
are difficult in this so
first of all it's hard to get a higher current density estimation in high dimensions
can you see why
because typically in high dimensions
let's say in any impediment secure
break every direction into two you have about to the tens of thousands
little q
we should just break the dimension to left and right
and so if you want to have a data point in each of these you
need a thousand points
of course if the data is clustered and it will not be spread so basically
a lot of data to fill the space most of the space is empty and
lots of point very far apart
and so was is on top of the points this not overlap very much on
the data is really what
and so it's very hard to construct
to adjust the size of the crawler to construct
so these are just
the growth and so there are some to like we actually put but serious
the cover several
several things but not
so both desire as far as they understood understood that the just it's not understood
what the asymptotic properties that doesn't come the that
like you you're doing this it estimation statisticians want to know it converges and so
on this
they are
four and a
o because the because then you want see peaks
if you think about once and then what you see the cluster sensation yes you
can think basically have to make the bomb almost this last letters all the data
in one dimension
also there is another reason when the data in high dimensions very often
there are two dimensions of the dimension of the space so they lie along strings
in this space in order to lie along lower dimensional curved manifolds and so you
can you puts here's the sphere contains
a lot of empty space
so that's another reason why
kernel density estimation in this in this
that was almost certainly don't work in
you have actually put the bombs
make them very elongated in the direction of the data line
this simple kernel density estimation doesn't go far enough in the and also kind of
finding level features like these if you are in more than
in one dimension
in two dimensions there are
if you go for level set in three and four and five images you see
that it's much harder the actually this can be fixed
and you about actually looking only at the values of
so the more
that's like for its
show you
and they say they believe that and also show you
more than
so is
one of the key reason is that
the thing
four classes
well structure real
so i'm sitting here in the
and by matrix
and you will see some examples in a minute
and basically with these large typically very sparse matrices all kinds of problems i mean
there are two large data complicated missing entries the noisy entries
and this in general we feel there might be some underlying structure which we don't
see on the surface but just looking at these matrices
what be looking for some then is a simple way in the sense to explain
these entries entries in the matrix
by using a model
and then also uncover what you might call latent structure
of the day
this is the general goal here
and in particular the types of methods that i will talk about
are closely related to a matrix decomposition to what i call matrix decomposition here is
simply a factorisation of the matrix
so we have a matrix a we want to approximate it by some matrix had
which can be written as a product of two matrices are and these two
matrices are
typically constrained to be things so you know if a is an m by n
you know how much has been owned by q so you know very thin matrix
and then we might have our and we might have a diagonal matrix in between
and the idea is
right to find these types of factorizations of matrices and and i'll try to explain
how that relates to something like latent structure
it's just a brief introduction we're going
OK so let me now talk a little bit about a particular application information retrieval
and this technique called latent semantic indexing which was developed in the late nineties
so first of all
you know
try to convince you that information so is important well we all know that right
in order to access information the most popular way of doing that is
to use box like that you know the box button
and then you know we have all the knowledge of the world out there and
certainly somehow magically you know we will get access to the knowledge and indeed
you know there some magic other names here like google and if you look you
know on the web there's no website basically that doesn't have such functionality right to
go to CNN or medlineplus you wherever you go everywhere is basically search box like
apparently it's it's an interesting problem so we would be good if we could somehow
improve search right so that's just in terms of the relevance of the problem
but really
some of course we all know that and we also with particular we know that
because very often things don't work out the way we expect them to work out
you know it's really this idea that we can identify relevant documents based on you
know very short ambiguous and incomplete query
it's a bit of
you know we have very high expectations here
and are
but but nevertheless in a very popular have the numbers you know how many people
use it and we all know that and we certainly use
i would assume
search on the web for instance every day
and more and more people use it in their professional and personal
OK now let me
try to show how
a matrix comes into play here to connect with what i said for my first
OK so the the typical matrix we're talking about here is called the document term
matrix or term document matrix depending on which way transpose the matrix
so we have a document here have term
and then what we what we typically do many other information retrieval applications we reduce
the data to
this matrix which
as an entry has just frequency count of how often a particular word occurred in
the talk
so then we can take a particular row of this matrix
and then we can use that basically is the representation of a particular stock so
if we have many terms so we have tens of thousands of terms it will
be very high dimensional representation for each document
and of course
you know there will be lots of zeros and so on and so forth and
a lot of information retrieval techniques are based on these document representation just by hundred
sixty right
and and the reason why it works at least to some extent is that indeed
in the the words that occur in the document are good indicators in some sense
right of whether document to be relevant to a particular query
so that a lot of the deeper maybe you know syntactic analysis and linguistic analysis
is very often not necessary on on
service level to find out whether document could be relevant or not because that depends
what you want you want question answering systems and you need to look more into
the structure of sentences
and in practice what people often do is they are they multiply these entries by
some smart term weighting like you you know the idea of waiting and then you
as TFIDF and things like that
and this is the foreground star but everything else background galaxies and as you see
these objects are
much more disturbing any irregular from the one that they show you before but remember
you have seen this object you are looking so far away that you've seen this
object when the universe was only a fraction of its age
so you see in the universe actually forming galaxies
that's why they are disturbed ball
so cosmology is fortunately or unfortunately depending on your point of view not only pretty
so nature is written in the mathematical language this come from my countrymen galileo and
so what we're saying here we can study the laws of physics here on earth
and that's them and then apply them to describe the entire universe this is an
anonymous extrapolation of scale remember
the first one of the first transparency is a show you
and so we are doing an enormous extrapolation here right we are testing the laws
of physics and scales of
you know
kilometres of in this case of the local solar system and then extrapolating those low
tense order of magnitude of so
what physical you know that you can extrapolate that many of the of money to
then it works without weakening
so this is not a step we are taking it as an assumption
and also we assume that the universe is comprehensible by as and you need physics
and mathematics is sometimes called physical cosmology and these deep from links to fundamental physics
so the kind of fundamental physics so low that database studied under your feet here
at cern
at the same kind of physicality and testing by looking up at the universe and
this has become clear in the past to say five or ten years basically
astronomy cosmology and particle physicist as start asking exactly the same question but they're trying
to find the answer from two different approaches in some people go underground and some
people of telescopes
but you know the the question is the same and well the answer ought to
be the same if we understand you know the entire no physical picture behind
this this is in cosmology are very difficult to measure
so in the the graph before i told you know that mentioned that was going
out that way was the distance and then they will see in a second distances
in cosmology are very difficult to measure you can't go with the ruler in all
the way
to the next galaxy already had enough to measure the distance to the nearby stars
but the velocity is easy
and thank you to edwin hubble
that's edwin hubble was of in a small with some telescope and here's morgan described
then we can make a connection
between velocities and distances and that's what allows us to measure distances out to basically
the edge of the so
how does it work
i mean i'm sure you're all familiar with the effect of light bank shifted the
blue shift
if you have a light source the moves away from you
wavelength is going to be redshifted while if the light source go moves towards you
these wavelengths is going to be blue shifted
so velocity relatively easy to measure in cosmology because you just have to measure the
light come from one object to recognise the song featuring its spectrum and then compare
that to build the wavelength that feature we we've learned that you measure on earth
when the object is at rest
so this is how
so cosmology talk about redshift and we'll see what the blue shift and we see
why nominator but let's just use the nomenclature for now that is called fresh
we define relationship with the latter the that these days
a set of wavelengths minus the emitted wavelength divided by the emitted wavelengths or one
plus the
this set of wavelet divided by the to the women and this is some
artistically reinterpreting the picture of what happened to us back to this is the spectrum
you see there is some continues that the wavelet changes from violet to the red
and this black line here represent as ocean sometimes the absorption lines spectrum and saw
well this may be when the object moves away from you then this feature ends
up there are this feature and there so the whole spectrum has been shift
and so if you've seen relativity you know that they can be very ten in
this standard form and four smaller velocity because will always be feeling
almost always be dealing with philosophy that are much smaller than the speed of light
and then you can do the approximation that actually fits basically the velocity along the
line of sight divided by the speed of light but in reality the actual expression
these when you rejected your velocity in the direction along the line of sight
what say
two years
i was right
the rose
in fact there are
well i don't know know
they were
these are
part of
i have here
one is the only thing
i don't think
i mean i
each person
five times that
i was thinking
and now
to be the
there are are
there are two
one they were
you are
so in
eight years of
the point here
the they
or three five one
all right
all right here saying
what is more
he teaches
on you
you might think that one
is the one which
you know
generative model we say
it is it to
what you
trying to
just to the math
is that they do
we've seen
this is
so that
a few simple terms
so what we do
yes you will be able to
she would you like
one year
this film
every nine months
as as in the nine months before
much more aggressive growth
then we love
the man is exploding every business today is essentially a business well it knows it
or not
which means as a corollary every business generating humungous amounts of data
towards the end of the day
a bit about which is an extreme that
science in science scientific instrumentation has been exploring
so scientists can now easily together
one side of the scientists can get
automated more the decade
this is also government security applications
politics et cetera
the internet
and the ubiquity of the web have actually
been a huge contributor to data driven approach to business especially in the marketing side
of it on was talk about that on tuesday
finally the most important part of the talent shortage we can
but rather actually has this kind of number of phds versus amount of storage
he shows again this
increasing dramatically every year
so what i mean by mining
is finding interesting structure in data
structure structure refers to
statistical patterns predictive models and in relationships
difficulty in this definition we can define everything fairly accurately except for interest
we don't know
still to this day i believe
how to define what's interesting obviously machine continue many many many more patterns of data
so the problem is three
and pretty important from an algorithmic perspective seems to discover
you really want them to have some common sense as to what is interesting patterns
and what is now in one
i believe should be maybe
pointers to that
it beyond just simple data about scaling the analysis to very large data bases because
humans can go there
it's about automated search machines are trying a different
models instead of people type hypothesizing
one his understandable models that we can figure out what they're saying to us this
is just the machine
guessing what is going on predicting blindly
and scaling highdimensional data
my i dimensions is a huge huge challenge
theoretically and practically
it doesn't mean it's impossible
in fact you can explain a lot about the data to do something and hopefully
which was an example examples of that
that's where databases the real problem here
many queries
very valid state
i would like to say
which was represent fraudulent transactions
which is what like to refer this product
what's a good customers is my database
the problem is
database contains information but we don't know how to state is the language of databases
today which is why
when data mining licences
which hopefully you know all of this i just wanted to get one page
so in data mining and
right this was an early three maybe you know
ten fifteen years ago
you know you come up some browsers
in the morning is sort of ask what's new
what's interesting or predict something more
we are very very far from this although some interesting instances coming close to having
a like this we actually have this kind of interface to a database
and establish more applications and plug them in
but that is
one of the grand vision of what we want to be
now i would argue is still very very
sure having this calling in a general sense
so what's missing
companies have built up some large and impressive data warehousing
the mining is visible nowadays
large corporations not to do it
two is an application to discover information enterprise data
the truth is
in most organizations data shambles
most data mining efforts end up not benefiting from existing infrastructure all those are famous
o operations carried out the DNA
are obsessed with customer behavior understanding and they talk a lot about it
but very very few
actually end up doing
very very few end up being data
and the successful efforts typically one of not like we can take the form of
an application
that's a real problem for us there is a huge
issue for me we will not become serious engineering field figure
to this i have to about the battle of success
and i'm thinking across organization
i used to live
actually maybe it nine years ago and jim gray invited to speak at the national
research council he said to me
try to explain to these folks
what sustainability today
so the way i it is
our data navigation exploration and exploitation technology is very very
and then i came
you know we have this huge data storage was are right on this to one
i determine mean every together
so to me that's basically
is that the tools
and then i started these ancient right we know how to build a very fancy
a lot of companies dragging my we're bigger than yours
but we really haven't figured out how to really put it to use and that's
a huge challenge for us what it mean that distance falls today even though i
actually you know you think it uses along
so shift over time
is my story
my personal side of here
started out in pure research as a professional students wanted to be use for
and although i was in algorithms
and taking summer jobs once in while
this was sort of my presentation of the world
the world is really about algorithms and theory is
there something in the background of the database
and systems in some way you have to worry about
that was
well years
is that as you become a practitioner era view changes
right there's something important to the customer and what they need
not really about the algorithm
so moving to the side becoming smaller importance
systems and integration this you become huge
this is becoming something really worry about a lot more
right as you practice
if you're all the way on the business side
i'd rather than zero
OK it should be imprisoned
systems and there is an important
but you know is a big worry about dollars and how feasible this is and
can you make it work itself
now this is shift is very important to keep in our minds right
because it really helps us figure
how to that
attention to the right problems to solve the problem
if you spend more time worrying about this tags
data mining and you don't worry about the systems databases
you're what's really going on with the very light field
you know also need to work
it was not
one might think that are being in
has the highest objective score with respect to our users selected objective
so we
the resort to this kind of mining problem so instead of generate the complete pattern
we aimed at generating
optimal graph patterns with respect to
objective function
and that this mining framework is very
very useful and it is very general and we hope this mining framework is
not specific to one objective score
or one objective function. it should be available to
all kinds of objective functions
and once this mining framework is developed to same we can extend them to do
a lot of other interesting pattern mining tasks
for example top k optimal graph pattern mining
redundancy aware graph pattern mining
it's going to
patterns for classification
so here is mining framework we would like to propose. we would like to directly
mine those optimal graph patterns from the raw
graph database
and at the same time we do not want to set any minimal
frequency threshold because it's very hard to justify
so this is our goal to
to propose directed pattern mining framework
so we recognise that
OK also these objective functions are not N-term monotonic to frequency measure
but we can derive an upper bound function which
is monotonic and monotonic
to the frequency and monotonic to the graph size, and monotonic to the frequency let's take
G-test score as an example
here G-test score can be write as a function of
p and q where p and q
are the frequency of the graph pattern in the positive dataset and
negative dataset. we can write the G-test score as this formula
here i omit some constant function, constant value
and and then we can calculate the derivative of gt with respect to p
and with respect to q
and then with some simple calculation we can make as the following conclusion
if p is greater than q then the derivative of t with respect to p
is greater than zero
the derivative of gt with respect to q is less than zero and vice versa
for the case if
p is less than q
this conclusion is not only valid four to G-test score if we check all
the other objective functions i mentioned including information gain and Fischer score
you will find that this conclusion is always valid for these objective functions
so actually there is a hidden rule behind these
that means if the frequency difference
of a graph pattern in the positive dataset and the negative dataset increases
the pattern becomes more interesting
so using this rule actually we can derive the upper bound function
of an objective function
and this upper bound function is monotonic to p
and is monotonically to q
and because they are monotonic to the frequencies
that means we can reuse
the existing
frequent graph pattern mining algorithm
to generate these
graph patterns with respect to other objective functions that is we can recycle
existing graph mining algorithms
to accommodate
non monotonic functions
let me use one slide to illustrate the detail
here is a search tree a pattern search tree we enumerate the patterns from small
size to larger size
and each node
represents a graph pattern
and the child nodes contains a supergraph of its parent node
during the enumeration you will find that OK
the frequency of this pattern decreases
and the upper bound value of this pattern decreases if to some
point we find that so upper bound function score
is less than the best pattern we discovered so far so basically we can
the whole branch
above that pattern. that branch becomes homeless because it were not to generate an
any graph pattern that is
that has objective score
greater than the best pattern discovered so far so we call this method would
vertical pruning
with a careful examination we find that we actually can do these pruning more radically
by introducing a horizontal pruning
again this is part of the search tree
and suppose we have two patterns g prime and g double prime
both of them share the same graph pattern g
and if the structure g-prime and g-double-prime
is similar to each other then likely
the objective score of g prime and g double prime will be similar to each other
if we find that
in this branch
none of
g primes children
can generate best objective score
there likely
this branch
will not
have the opportunity to generate the best possible score
what does this mean this means
as long as we finished this search tree search branch g prime it is not
necessary to search the
like g double prime
so we can cut to the search
branch to g double prime
as you can see that it is a horizontal pruning
so this is a major method that we propose in our past disagreement was
on the order paper propose master which can do not only are vertical pruning but
also it can do horizontal pruning
and we applied our method to
a set of chemical compounds in a sense
try to see its performance in comparison with the origin of graph frequent pattern mining algorithms
and vertical pruning methods
and we collected
eleven chemical compound datasets from NCI website
and this is the data sets containing each of them contain
more than solvents chemical compounds
if you are interested you can contact me later and and we have all these
datasets clean
and here's the performance comparison between our method BB means vertical pruning and leap means vertical
pruning plus horizontal pruning remember that
this vertical pruning is already better than the traditional frequent graph pattern mining algorithm
here is the different dataset. here is
a runtime comparison
equivalent the very obvious reason that the relations between a highly non linear
if it's principle
gene ontology
the attempt to as catalogue
what all the genes are doing will fail without higher level insight there are close
programs in existence to annotate the gene the them the most famous is the gene
ontology project g that by michael ashton in cambridge is very interesting to have a
look at the gene ontology website
you will find
that they exclude all forms of higher level
even to the extent of excluding the idea
but you can label certain genes oncogenes as cancer genes the gene ontology project there
are no cancer genes and very simple and correct point but surely that's not why
those genes are selected in the first place
and as they put it on their website cancer is not so
a selected function g
there also
on the website
an interesting list of exclusions
virtually the whole of physiology is excluded
and actually the whole of the evolutionary biology is excluded and the reason for that
i think they're right to exclusivity is the reason for that is that while it
is possible to annotate the genome in terms of safe which proteins are coded for
which genes and what the biochemical functions as those proteins might be will be they
enzyme or structural or whatever it's extremely difficult as those who try to reconstruct the
complexity of biological systems no
to go much further beyond their from the genome information itself the gene if is
not the book of life
or it is a book
then it's about because it was such a huge gaps in it you can't read
but i think it's better to get rid of that metaphore
and replace it with the idea that the gene is simply a database
six principle it follows from what i've said that it was a nice metaphor when
it was introduced by
mono and yet
way back in the sixties there is there are no genetic programs
chairman refers to the fact that i did simulation
of rhythm and the hard way back in nineteen sixty
and in those days you know you have to use
valve computer to do the reconstruction and a very very slow
and had feed paper tape
and later on
these cards your program course was a set of instructions on that page protection
that's the model
the monomaniacal putting nine because they were introducing the concept of the genetic program way
back in the sixties the idea that is some separate k
for program then determines what living organism does there is no separate
and there's a lovely quote here sorry moving on too quickly and just go back
OK beautiful book in big companies plant geneticist and his his book the art of
genes is an absolute delight worth reading organisms are not simply manufactured according to a
set of instructions there's no easy way to separate instructions press carrying out to distinguish
plan from execution
just a pacemaker them again as an example
the only thing that
that could conceivably be regarded as the program is the set of interactions to include
in the computer model between the genes coding for proteins that interact with the cell
potential to produce pacemaker is
but that interaction is the system itself is not appropriate for the system
the concept of the program is completely redundant and you can do the same with
nearly all of the biological functions try to think of about biological function for which
it is the case that there is a separate program code for that is not
the function itself
i'm going to show one two
simulations at a higher level to illustrate the point i made earlier on about multi
level functionality
OK hailed
so i will
talk some more
sometime about ontology design practices
this is also war that is made in the context of the new products and
so i have to thank the members of my newly found the semantic technology lab
and in particular valentina
so outline of talk briefly about the world of ontology design
and then the relation between design our logical layers are assumed
to operate in wind
representing ontologies
ontology design patterns
some simple issues and unit test that can be applied for use in design jointly
with evaluation
so the partisans were we use some examples that were recommended by me by john
last year about the semantic web community ontology was used is have been using also
this is the only last year
still still in this series and operating in this conference looking
so until as the world include requirements of course
so for example i want to attend my ideal talk k so what ontology it
is stable
two which can be used for knowledge base joined the knowledge base that can answer
my greedy
to be logical constructs like subclass of restriction as you've seen from shows tutorial
and the bunch of existing ontologies like friend of a friend the cause the semantic
web community ontology or
the foundation reusable ontologies like
and the informal knowledge resources like citeseer or this topic catalogue there not exactly ontologies
in the sense of being explained today about
they can be used as ontology this is the
part of the current practices
and a lot of conventions and practices for example how to name elements or to
make your eyes to to work in the semantic web of
how to make it was joined cowering in
you know or how to verify
relations that cannot be expressed in within this pursuit of all of a how to
things like a transitive part of the or not as the ones or relations between
roles and tasks or these conventions and practices belong to different areas of design and
will be treated separately and examples presented in this book and of course the tools
so i those reasons translators probably most of you have already been faced with many
interfaces the many function that are contained in current semantic web and web of data
talking about this i will talk about good practices are best practices and of course
is a very old question about holt is a well designed ontology pragmatically speaking i
think that after so many years of a
incredibly long discussions with people from all areas interdisciplinary contest and that
basic things could be singled out and should be true anyway so
given that you want to do
develop an ontology within a large organisation with a team of developers or you want
to develop it in anybody can like for example recently and was this launch of
and no campaign which can be used as backup but develop vocabularies or and they
want to develop by alone on the on the peak of the mountain OK i
think that this can questions should be anyway take into account so what are we
talking about why do we want to talk about it and where to find reusable
knowledge to talk about
and also maybe do we have the resources to maintain it so sometimes the sustainability
is an issue
so these were also the images that we have singled out in ontology social work
years ago
so this was wise words constitute the
it's called the problem space of an ontology project
and the designers need to find solutions from a solution space
after prime x
like crime
the derivatives
inside here
again is just wj prime
so the derivative with respect to
this song
it's going to be fj prime
for the and we just pick out whichever j we're talking about
x y prime
it's actually
a lot
no it can't because
what i can do is bring dizzy inside the cell
but i can't but i don't think i can
cancel it out
of my
this is
i'm going to write it like this some
of the life crime
the cell
the premises here like this
so i'm going to write
j x and y prime
just moving this first and then i'm going to move disease
and act
some of the j prime
wj prime j prime x
why prime
here i just
swap the order of these two things in the summer move dizzy inside
comes the
the interesting part
so i can
i can recognise this is being something well known
what is
we've seen
it's a p of why prime given x
why prime given x
and also
but the w is not important now
so now if i go back to here
divided every j log p
s j
x y
the expected value so this is an expectation
why prime
why prime follows the distribution p of y prime given x
and w
see this this is
the definition of an expectation is a weighted average of the FJ values for all
y crimes
with each why prime weighted by the probability that white pride so its expected value
f j x and y prime
what it's saying
is that
the observed value of f x y
for the
training example x y
has to equal
the expected value of the same feature functions where the white crimes all possible labels
and now i have three different microphones each of which is a different setting
no matter where i stand in the room we will either have feedback shadows
that until these guys fix it we hope that will get taken care of
and i'm hoping of course they will cut that out of the
webcasts will say
every every time we've done this either here or several of the times at the
summer school itself
i have had the privilege to be the person who give the talk which is
the introduction to
the semantic web tutorial
i guess
i used to think it was very flattering entire high-rise was just that i was
the oldest one had been doing it the longest so they figure get him up
front quickly
the way
this thing we've been calling the semantic web
has various different aspects comes
back and forth at various times
he has
is that set
you have to talk to him today
and this is the same
is this same slide you have in your hand
i sent john two or three different things i want to make sure we all
around using the same stack
they can't tell
second one and
the only difference between this slide back and what you've been handed out this one
should have the title introduction to the introduction to
and you should all just a introduction to
if i if i start showing slides
anyone who is trying to follow that has and i made worried by the fact
that john said you all have copies of the slide
and everyone not it but when i ask if this was the same size no
one has responded do you have copies of our slide
you electronic once again
there's is anyone actually had them opened
are you reading email
well then then it will matter because then you won't be able to tell if
i give you the same ones are not so then i'm fine
we we tend to teach this course
from the point of view something called ontologies which we will get into
a little bit in this talk
a lot in some later talks
and what i want to do is start to set up a little bit of
the the picture of how these things are being used on the web
because there really are several different ways things are being used and it's important to
understand some of that
the the talk i gave that i started talking about this was called
the the fellowship of the semantic web the two towers and i call it the
two towers
and you will see in the talk why
that is but it's essentially so there's really
if if we're careful there are many different views of ontology but you will see
things that really arise from two
two different views of the same technology and it's important sometimes to understand views
so that when the presenters show you things you can try to
make sure you are seeing it from the right point of view
the way i like to describe this slightly
it is that we have this very funny
ontological conundrum is a college
which is that
one of the things that has her adoption of the semantic web for while it's
not going quite well is also used but one of the things that was the
problem was two different viewpoint so what would happen if somebody would here talking say
oh i get it this is what i need for my company
and then they go to different talk to
and here's something was said
no no everything you learned that other talk was wrong you need this other thing
and they say wait wait wait now i'm confused
and very often that was hurting peoples adoption
and what started to change now is is becoming easier to find schools
and techniques
and tutorials
but still pretty much anyone you take will be from one point of view or
another and this one you will get to that you actually can see both points
of view as we go along
and part of the reason this is important is that both of these
are ways that people are using this technology
one which looks more like a traditional AI technology and one which looks more like
a traditional web technology so it's not so much surprising that technology that wants to
really come from the perspective of
artificial intelligence on the web
is going to have tension between those two very different things
so one of the
towers i talk about
is the tower of expressive ontology and some of the talks you'll here today are
about ontology engineering
and getting your ontology right
and i like to think of that surrounds tower from lord of the rings
the tremendous amount of power
but you got to have a lot of or works around the outside garden because
if a little hobbit cats
you know you can drop your wedding ring in the crack of doom and the
whole thing could collapse i'm assuming you know the story but now if you don't
know the story i don't know where you been living in the past
twenty years but roughly speaking
right very very powerful but
you need a lot of control and in reality
there lots of views of ontologies
i can actually put a number of different names out there
but that come from this point of view which says we want to make the
very very explicit very very carefully engineered using some very powerful tools
we have to also make sure that the information
is correct and this is the technical sense of correct
inconsistencies coming into logic based system
unless they are carefully controlled
can destroy the logic in traditional logic system that
was just if we tried to use pure logic
to do almost any kind of reasoning if one if you have a way you
can prove that
and you have a way you can prove the inverse of that
then you have a rule that says anything that causes you to believe x and
not x must be wrong
so given that
if i was to go out on the web and say hey this website once
obama to win the presidency on this website wants mccain to win the presidency in
the US
the fact is that those are not the same person
there is a contradiction in a sense if one of the more or less safe
as he will be the next president and he will be the next president of
both cannot be true
so it follows from that inconsistency
that you owe me a lot of money
right so first of all i feel free to put it in box by the
door as you leave today i'll happily take your contributions but
clearly as humans you would say
something is very broken in the system
graphical models
i hope most of you
i don't know a a lot about it because if not going to to be
what i'm doing
it's not too easy
i will first give a quick overview
what traffic among our standard i will present
directed graphical models
a specific kind of customers
we talk a bit about
conditional independence
so what are produced
graphical models the name of graphic
there are diagrams for representing the probability distribution over a set of random variables
is it's generic name for several kind of of
directed graphical models which are also called bayesian networks
the and directed graphical mothers
which are also called markov random fields
and the factor graph so that the directed graph can easily be transformed into
and directed graph so it's all
make it a different way of representing this probability distribution
nodes and links
and factor graph that was directed and undirected graphs
can be represented as a factor graph
so what are these are a graphical representation for
in fact there a way of
decomposing graphically to traffic
topographic view
on how to decompose the joint probability distribution
into product of factors
it's depending in the subset
of variables
having that is useful to understand how the variables are connected
to each other
that's work
usually called conditional independence
having this decomposition of course you see that it will simplify computations
inference and learning
and it's it's in fact the way of generalizing
this simplification this way of understanding
different mothers
new mothers you do we use this
they agrams
the first let's come back to their easy example
query remember
we have two boxes and experiment is selected
one block one box then pick fruit in the box and then replace different
and so we have these two random variables which are
the identity of the box and the
the identity of the foot feet
i have two ways of writing
of the composing the
joint probability of one books and one foot
or i can see as the probability of the books times the probability of different
given the box
i can see it
as the probability of the four times the probability of the
books given different
however this first one
it's much much more natural in the way
the experiment is his career
it's also the kind of of
we have this going this
this conditional distribution of y
this one we could compute them but
it's not what we have in the first place
so that
we give this kind of graphical models in which we have
one not for the book for the identity of the books one
note for the the eighteenth of different
link is a direct link between
these two
kind of representing
that the the fruits are a product of the box that
let's take a more dramatic example
let's say
male one female one friend one can
family member so full people in each other three main circles fifteen fifty eight hundred
fifty and right in this way
the key things that interest here is the more things to sharing common the top graph
the more emotionally close to filter somebody and indeed people in they close layers to share more
traits with these types
you also more altruistic towards and here's a very simple one would you donate a
kidney to them irrespective layer the more try to sharing common more willing you want
to to to
be altruistic towards them
it turns out there are six key sector interesting on these
or personality traits
they're all things that are culturally determined and therefore change with time
and that's probably explains why friendships
gradually drift apart because over time you don't see each other ure interest change their things like
sharing the same language coming from the same place showing the same hobbies
and interest having the same
will view the same political views same religion those kinds things
there's one more and then i forgot what it
it is for the moment but the key thing the six one is human and
shared humour turns out to be the most important
these six core
dimensions a french if you like
and just to show you how important that is we then
what is collections one hundred best jokes
we have various people rate them
we took be twenty
jokes that people disagreed about most
am then had a large sample on the internet rate them before
ah their preference and do like this joke or not simple yes no
about two weeks later we went back to them
and said oh by the way we've got somebody here with their and his
that's your job profile profile is his their joke profile
you know who are would you be interested in
meeting them with a kind person you'd you'd be happy to go
you spend an evening with all or what have you
what they didn't know was that the joke profile being given back was actually the
rather but in a place that i the shared to activating
jokes or after sixteen activating jokes the same as the
you can see
the more jokes the most similar your attack profiles are
the more
you are likely to feel like person and indeed the more altruistic you say would
be towards them if you asked me
altruistic toward
okay so what actually makes relationships work
the model we work on this one derive from primates
primate social relationships appear to be able to
process mechanism they depend partly on an emotionally intense component which is
produced by grooming
explain one-minute and then a cognitive component which is where the brain size comes into
play so essentially what is happening is
you have grooming producing estimation intense component
which provides a kind of psychological platform
of which you can build a combative relationship a relationship trust and and obligations so
looking into
very quickly
cognitive that first what we understand about the cognitive component is this kind of stuff
so call mind-reading or mentalizing ability to understand what somebody else is thinking and how they're seeing the world
and this sort of forms a natural hierarchy
reflexive hierarchy
where jack here on the left is in first order intentionality as is known
he believes that something is the case being a general
philosophical term four mind-states belief states as were
including things like intentions like second order she believes that at least some case jackson
third automatically believes you will is actually
something's gotta principle this goes on forever
the second order
level here
the above jill
is known as the mind it's when he finally start to understand somebody else's mind is different to yours
that's say they may see the world in a different way children go through the benchmark about page five
that's the point at which they finally learn how to lie convincingly
because they understand how information they feed u
will affect your behavior prior to that i don't understand why you behave the way you do
so when we fast people
these are normally done little vignettes
little stories about people trying to make a date or negotiate something
and then you can ask you know about these stories about questions about the mind
states as individuals involved in the story when you do that
find typically at a small models have an upper limit out this order intentionality
three orders about what five olds can do
that's quite complicated
but more interestingly when you're also of the same people
did to list out there
in a core clique size
he finds a nice if messy correlation between the two we replicated this several times now so it's quite robust
the later on messy it's highly significant it's messy
it's messy because
sex difference
women are better unintentional these and these social
cognitive abilities
mind-reading abilities they also tend to have slightly bigger clique sizes as a result
there are also personality differences and this extroverts
tend be
have bigger clique sizes
than introverts
we knew what people high on neuroticism scale have smaller clique sizes than those who have
school level on the neuroticism scale
but the point is
is a nice correlation between the two and essentially what you've got here
is on the one access bitter behavior on the x axis
a bit software
let's say cognition
correlation between cognition
in the software
and the behavior yet what
have my friends enemies my so i would put the miners right and so on
and i could labels
what do i think about what kind of time with for each of these sixteen
different cases
OK and if i do this and then ask okay how often does do what
does this theory make correct predictions it makes a correct predictions made out of sixteen
cases and for example it's interesting that in this first case where i have pluses
so i have four months of the form where i have to process and the
predictive class this is how people behave in this case but in this case where
you have the same network structure just adjust their directions of people in the was
their actions and science of class because they don't to point to them to put
the minus here which is which is something that is in contradiction with what structure
that's so what they want to
say is you know is that a better explanation and as can see that fuel
that this provides a much better explanation about how people can create signed edges in
in this media sites so that's that's the that's the that's the plan so now
what i want to show you how to establish the yes studios that this is
a better explanation
OK so here is here is our experimental settings so the way to do this
is i will assume that links are directed and created over time
i have the status theory with which the the way i believe what is say
a user plus to someone of higher status and a gives the minus to someone
of lower status
and as a said before the two the two theories can give different predictions
the way i think about this now is to say i had a is about
to evaluate the
this is how do edge a b is embedded in the network that they may
maybe this common for indexing and this is the fraction of edges and science of
edges towards x how
hi what happened to this page
right so
so to be able to establish is there there are two things that they need
to formalize the first link the first thing to formalize that sort of realised that
links so these red links that i'm interested in are embedded in the network right
so they are embedded in this kind of try trying to write so every common
neighbors between a and b create some kind of embedding of that link in the
network so the first thing i want to know is how this people's behavior change
depending on if i know how the structure of the of this context is well
justified nor the context OK so i want to say this is my based behavior
when i don't really care what are the directions and size of these links and
i say what what is a doing in this case one says if i conditioned
on the context OK i conditioning what is the directions and signs of of the
edges towards a common friend between
so so that the first thing so try triads provide context for the region is
at science created and the second thing is that users are considered genius in the
early evening became what i mean by that is that some people are are just
overall more positive and some people are overall more negative so i want to sort
of instead of saying what people do i want to see how the behavior change
from the baseline behavior OK
first about context as i said before there are sixteen different contexts in which a
sort can appear either sixteen different labelled directed private lives in which i think i
don't think can appear
and this is basically out tells made there sort sort of sixteen different ways on
which i can condition my behaviour i can sort of ignore the context and there
are sixteen different ways in which
the link between a and b that you are interested in x
and now
so sort of the second thing is how do i address the originating the behavior
of users so the point is that some users are more positive and some users
are less positive and some users are more popular some users are less popular so
i will call these baselines and scenario
introduce a notion of generative baseline which is like how what fraction of all the
edges are created plus and i will also introduce generic also the receptive baseline which
is what is what fraction of all users receive a plus right so generative is
you're you're positive out of reflection in receptive is what fraction of
of edges that you received positive right so one is what you create and the
other one is what you see hot so i have this so now i want
to say OK how do different link contexts cause users to deviate from these baselines
right so what you want to say is if i don't know what is what
is the context in which
in which is something appears
what's the matter was the probability of a giving up blast and was the probability
of receiving a plus one says if i know
that this edge will be created
it is embedded in the network in this kind of structure what happens to a
giving up giving a positive evaluation
and what happens to be receiving a positive evaluation so this is what i would
like to like to call a sort of capture is that basically this that because
of links appear in the context this makes nodes a and b deviates from the
generative and receptive baseline right so eight gen deviate from its generative baselines and the
we deviate from its receptive baseline OK so that's so here are two two basic
examples right so how would i expect people to deviate here so for example if
this is something that happens in status theory is right there before my prediction was
that this one minus right so it would never to x x points negative one
so i would imagine that a good evaluation may be negatively so i would imagine
that the deviation of a would be the generative deviation of would be negative likely
to be more negative than what he usually is right from his baseline and also
is now receiving the negative and so we would expect the
deviations in receptive baseline of is also negative right and gives us some sort of
similar example where again i would expect deviations
of a big negative deviation of the right so here it would be more likely
to give the miners then what the ring comparing to his very long baseline and
they would also be more likely to receive minus minus compared to talk is based
OK so now how do i say that something is how do i make predictions
based resource that is still sort of this was implicit throughout the talk so far
so i will just make it more it's more precise right so the way i
mean this is a hard i've been assigned status of zero to x now i
say based on the directions in science of researchers assigned stepsister and here that has
led to that the zero he puts positive points positive weight so he has higher
standards than x so that's a plus one x points negatively to to to be
which means
x because negative status minus one so my prediction here would be the the direction
of the the sign of this actually being write his high status because
right now i would say that
the probability one two
it's only one possible outcome that would be one six
and then i have to divide by the probability of n being even
so that's that's three six about it then the conditional probability to all three given
that and is even would be one thirty
OK well actually do quite a bit with conditional probability
in the in the next four days
OK closely related property
it is the property of independence
two subsets are said to be independent
if the probability that the outcome is in a and in b so the intersection
factorizes into the probability for a time the probability for b
by this time thinking oh i all these definitions what what does that have to
do with independence
and you can see somehow that's related to the idea of independence if you look
at the conditional probability
for a given the
now if a and b are independent
that means that was
o thing in the numerator
factorizes into the probability of a times the probability of b
and the probability of the councils
and i simply get back the probability of a so what that means is that
the condition of b
i had no influence on the probability for a so that you can kind of
see that this word independence makes sense and you can easily show that it works
better as well as the probability of b given a would simply be the probability
of b
imposing the condition would make no difference if the two subsets are independent
so don't confuse that with independence with disjoint is the difference it's that's not the
same thing as having two disjoint subsets that means that the intersection doesn't overlap
the intersections and also
OK let's keep going
now up to now there has been relatively abstract definition i haven't insisted on what
elements of the subspace sample space have to represent and i haven't even specified
in this sort of prescription for assigning numerical values
to the probabilities in order to do that you have to say something about the
probability means how you interpret it
and here is more than one school of thought there are more than one way
of interpreting probability and the two
important ways
and those are
roughly speaking calls frequentist probability subjective probability
and and those are the basis of two in many ways compete competing schools statistical
and will spend some time talking about each
so let me introduce these two
interpretations when data interpret the probability is to say that the elements of the sample
space are the outcomes of a repeatable experiment
and in
limit i repeat the experiment a very large number of times the fraction of times
that the outcome is in the sense that a
is that's what i mean by the probability of a
now what
mathematicians look at this limits
here i think that's
that has nothing to do with the proper mathematical limit how can you repeat
an experiment an infinite number of times
but as this is the basic idea of probability that we have in mind for
example in quantum mechanics in the ordinary copenhagen interpretation of quantum mechanics and certainly natural
in particle physics because we had this idea
but you can
collide together
as many times as you want it doesn't appear to be any natural limit to
the number of times that you could repeat such an experiment or similarly with radioactive
decay if you have a very very large number of radio of of nuclear
and then repeating observation many times seems very natural
there other situations however in which
being able to repeat observation seems highly contrived
the probability
it's going to rain tomorrow
the probability that what i just read
what is the probability that the first person to go to mars will come back
he he or she is will about and you can repeat that somehow
it is natural under certain circumstances to define what is called subjective probability
in this game the elements of the sample space of hypotheses and here we have
a hypothesis i simply mean a statement that is either true
or false
and then sometimes in the sample space in this context is called the hypothesis space
and the probability of a certain subset is simply
interpreted as the degree of belief
that hypothesis is true
now both interpretations are consistent
with the kolmogorov axioms so there are legitimate uses of probability
and i think it's fair to say that in particle physics the frequency interpretation is
is most often used
but subjective probability can nevertheless
provide a more natural interpretation for for many things are for for systematic uncertainties for
the things like what is the probability that the higgs boson exists would either does
or doesn't no repetition of of any experiment will change that
last week i was at a meeting
of of cosmologists who were interested in in statistical matters and then it was interesting
that although
particle physicists more often use the frequency interpretation apparently for cosmologists seek is the exact
opposite that they are more often use subjective probability in fact if one universal work
with i think that's the basis
OK now regardless of which interpretation
you use anything called the probability has to obey
an important theorem
called bayes there
and is there is very easy to derive so let's just do it
we have from the definition of conditional probability is the conditional probability of a given
i see is one bigger less than three it smaller so i put it over
when i insert eight that's bigger than three to get some relief over here
and the answer to that it's between one and three so it would fall off
the right child of one i had two there
beginning three less than eight
it's here
bigger than three less than a bigger than six
so it goes here
it's in between three and five
three insects rather
so that's the binary search tree that i get
then i run in order to reversal
which will present one two three
five six seven
can run that quickly my head because i've got a big stack a little bit
careful because you should check that they come out in sort of one two
three five six seven
and if you have the big stack you can go and buy one
i was useful
memory costs are going up these days are going down there should be because of
price fixing
the question is what's the running time of this algorithm and there's no
we here this is one of those answers where it depends
the parts is easy to through
analyzer well initialisation
the inorder tree walk columns that take
order and the walk
the initialisation constant
the question is how long does it take me to do and entry into service
anyone want to guess any kind of answer to that question
other than it depends on
so on the thunder there
big omega log and that's good it's at least and again
right so you give two reasons the first one is because of the
decision tree lower bound that doesn't actually
proof of this
a bit careful this is the claim that something and again
in every all the time
it's certainly again like in the worst case returning every comparison based learning how some
again like in the worst case
it's also and again every single time i may and again
because of the second reason gave
which is the best case the best thing that can happen is we have a
perfectly balanced tree
this is the thing that i have drawn the most
on blackboard my life perfect three on
fifteen nodes i guess
so if we're lucky we have this and if you add up all the depths
of the nodes here which gives you the
the search for cost in particular
these and other two nodes in the bottom each have high
each have depth log n
and therefore you're going to have to pay at least an organ for those
and if you're less balance is going to be even worse that takes improving but
it's true
so it's actually make it and log and all the time
you see that are some cases like if you know that the elements are almost
already in order you can do it in linear linear number comparisons
here you can
any other
guess is that
and the answer to this question
go and square
right we're doing and things and each node has depth most and so the number
of comparisons are making per element we insert is the most and so that's
most and square
any other answers
is it possible for this to take m squared times
is it are the instances where it takes a fair and square
it's already sorted out pretty bad
sorry sorry no offense reverse sorted
during about shape
because then you get a tree like this this sort of case
and your computer so that the total cost the time in general is going to
the sum of the depths of the nodes
for each node x three
and in this case is one pos two pos three pos for this arithmetic series
is and of
so this is the and were like this one over two
that's bad news some the worst case running time of this algorithm is
is an square
so familiar at all
algorithm worst case running time and in particular already sort case
but if we're lucky
the lucky case to be the
as we said it's already a balanced tree
the mapping or anything
with omega log n high
will give us a sorting out from
in my again
so lucky case where n log n
and in the unlikely case where square
and what he is
sort it
mind you many algorithm we've seen before
clicks are
it turns out
the running time of this algorithm is the same as the running time of quicksort
in a very strong sense
turns out the comparisons that this algorithm makes
are exactly the same comparisons
quicksort makes makes them in a different order
but it's really the same algorithm
in disguise
that's the
surprise here