to create value by doing a structured and unstructured dance
now here's the game for example and going give you real travel allow what I
really it is like I love travel 1 I also love knowledge collective not so
I wonder below thing that you know we we wanna go on a trip somewhere
you ask your friends even in there will so the say let's do that on
the scale of earth specialist at acidity just anyone in the world has ever been
to any place in the world you want to go out and get the best
knowledge of all local hotels places to go things to do and so on so
simple concept but it's interesting pommel for collect analysis there's just a quick screenshot newcomer
Carey most of these words but this is the bits a blog sites essentially a
vertical blog sites where we collect when people come write their blogs they share their
stories just like you shirt photos of the creature stories with that would look like
a magazine articles of it out pretty anyway and they're all connected together so here's
a bunch this is the Bangkok Bank of Thailand is a bunch of blogs about
Bangkok along all rank ordered by user redeems the fault
now what's interesting about this is why does the blogger a writer and will 1
is that we give them a better place like showed flier but you know what
I gallery era of we give among space of free free host space to publish
and we have really nice designs and so on so that it looks Mitchell and
making sure their friends and family but as a second-order effects which is now while
that of my photos and flicker likable among Kodak Gallery of flickers a community and
part of a larger community connect with other people along interest lines so that's part
of the game for the blogger now we can give them all the other blogs
in Bangkok although blogs around the same time the all the other blogs and by
you know all kinds of dimensions and other photos of the same place that you
were at the same time the other side this is weird to give the reader
something to do here that and the readers in fact really all they care about
is given a destination what can I do that so we basically take this bloggers
daily which is basically it was left to was own be these isolated murals although
universe aggregating together and index here
so this a technology technique that's familiar themselves share but now it's something co-opted advised
browsing arises where you can't have it along we picture again you can pivot like
you go down to the Bangkok you can go up to Thailand over 2 photos
down the hotel reviews by some blogger like fold-out blogger down at threat then pick
up another thing and destination of England somewhere else and so what is it just
like you do want inflicted serious indeed or even wikipedia lost not hypertext there but
flickers actually indexical where hypertext sort of normal data but in this case third dimension
you like these tag dimensions time dimensions redeem dimensions but you can serve now what's
the backbone of this it wouldn't have worked if I just Sony's into a big
search engine the only way the real opposes off is because we have a very
strong backing structure which is the destination hierarchy and turns that's as our problem there
that millions of needed in cities like things in the world and is a big
number and make their in always languages and there's tons of redundancy and it's a
really nasty hierarchy and just try to be England right we have to roll things
the UK as a country half-dozen doesn't England's and is not you know it's crazy
and the CIA has a database out there but it's been it's a full blood
and tests and budgeted for waste anyway it's a problem so I'll get back to
what that kind of thing but once we got the destination there's sort of hammered
into shape
but you don't want to amount of work on the data mining data management and
then we do program we got now if use the structured data as a backup
to all kinds inferential services so this is not very deep inference but if I
have a blog about Bangkok guess what it's also about Thailand an inference users something
that we use just put it in the Bangkok spots and you can also say
by the way if I have a photos in a blog about Bangkok it's also
photo about Thailand's so I can circle of opposing in Thailand and so on all
by the way I can also look up the Geo coordinators and popular and so
cool map or indeed whole rout out all this stuff follows from the structured background
on away from the play other players ecosystem like advertisers they like to target based
on where you're going how do you say we're going the strange I mean yes
it's true to say PARIS they're probably disintegrated to be PARIS France and so Hurst
Texas but you know sometimes they go wrong and they don't like in arms across
the money anyway is sort what it might look like in this case the photos
you might see if typed in Thailand for photos nobody organized these photos by Thailand
before Connecticut the photo and you can serve through all of in Thailand nobody organized
into that group emerged from a combination of people stick in a blogs in a
little piece of the treated they live in Bangkok residents and all the everything else
inherited down is 1 of a piece of this sort of multidimensional proposal which is
testament to play
now we do that people act and to be honest with you with the common
is mixed success it turns out that like all things in this world the social
world people only do things for enlightened self-interest and most of the time and tagging
world the self-interest is kind of bizarre kind of me depends on where in some
cases like people like analyze canister Dyson chases photos and flicker and there's this sort
of obsessive-compulsive woman comes in mind tags off with 4 is a symbiotic relationship and
they have different motives and so it tagging is often different know who knows why
this case at any a real compelling reason the accurately side of things so people
mostly down but some of them do but what we did is we say look
it good Taggart all we're going to use statistics to tell you which are the
most useful wants to use the words and so it's a example we call snap
to grid said they would destinations you start typing if you as a destination police
on the destination in this was likely to be completing the watching match so snaps
you into the grid of structured data not tags early structure but the discrete now
it turns out have all these tags running around and this is somewhat of a
controlled vocabularies suggested cannibal warmly controlled softly controlled vocabulary then you have this nice combination
of structure construction indices so grass example of you could back entirely new you go
here all the tags about Thailand notice they organized by Medicare worries that wasn't users
doing that that was us doing that but we didn't take us long plywood ties
people care about and of course it to snap into the grid and you not
and you know pluralization all kind of stuff is not we still have the folk
song we still we have things organizers and the weights and I can go as
a mother well you know there's the beach tag what's there the beach tag and
for example
each segment type
has the typical length
for example wall segments tend to be longer than four segments each segment type has
the typical dept
relative to the newest line
one of them to be close to that have
dorset to be deep
here's another neighboring segments
there are aligned
the line basically means that the angle is below some threshold and neighbouring means that
you know the distance it wasn't actually tend to be of the same type
notice that this is this is a collective inference rule like this is what propagates
labels between neighboring nodes
and here's another one it says that if the segment has no previous line segment
in this part of the line then it's the start of the line
this makes sense
if think is the start of the line then the x y coordinates are the
if you think start of line then it's starting point should be the starting point
of the line but again it's not exactly the starting point because when i the
line it couldn't manage exactly the borders allows is girl some slack right this
this equation is we've got slack so i'm going to try to make them the
same but not too much
and now he is the key rule is the one that says the following
if the segment is part of the line then the slope of the segment should
be the same as the flow
the line
from the starting point of the line to the starting point of the same
but there should be no in between
and i have the same rules for ending segments and so what this rule is
going to do
is this collective you know is this inference
we're and simultaneously trying to find the best fit line to all the segments and
trying to decide which segments belong to the one in which don't
so if this sentence works well what's going to happen is that the door segments
are going to be excluded
and i'm going i'm gonna wind up averaging only
the line only the wall segments to the side walls
and we've done this
and it works well
and it's another successful joint inference because what happens is even if even you know
the originally like for example this paper by
link it kind of
all i was trying to do was labelled the segments
no we don't we doing this during inference between the segments and figuring out what
the lines are
and doing this in addition to telling us more also there's labeling of the segments
trying to figure out what the lines are jointly with leaving the segments of this
label the segments that
OK so
let me mention i could use in milan's for things like planning
well classical planning is easy to write because you can formulate as the satisfiability problem
and solve in the usual way
satisfiability is the state-of-the-art methods for solving planning problems and we've done that with things
like the blocks world and as i mentioned earlier you know we can scale to
much larger problems than before
but now you know what happens
when actions have certain effects right this is the kind of thing that we know
want to be able to do well
all we need to do to have certain effects for the actions is
given finite which the action axioms
x x that things like if the block is on the table and then i
pick it up in the block is in my hand
in classical planning this is deterministic
in real planning sometimes you know the block slips
so what i need to do is only to give that of finite weights
and that allows me to have action on certain actions with uncertain effects i can
also has sensing actions which again can be noisy what i need to do is
i need to add clauses relating sensor states to the sensor readings to world states
and again i for the world state in perfectly from the sensors using probabilistic inference
how might i relational markov decision processes this is a very active area of research
these days trying to combine classical planning with mdps and people have proposed many approaches
one that we haven't tried but you know are going to try shortly is
again using markov logic this is very straightforward we can do is we can add
to the weights to the clauses
with the following semantics is this clause true
then i have to switch to my two
that would give us a hundred thousand
and then this would be sort of like the fourier sine series of the wind
but if i choose
that if i make that is that a good choice
the take those functions sin x sin to accept assign a hundred that's what i'm
going to do then i going up like this
into the
the point that into the minimum things and minimize
but we minimize i've only got
these are my unknowns now
the weight
the unknown
and unknown
i've got one hundred and no
i'm not too crazy about the choice of sin x sin to accept assigned one
hundred x one not
because the calculations would take a long time
i have to
be able to do it to compute this integral for functions like SIN one hundred
and then minimize over this hundred dimensional space
and the idea of finite elements was the better choice
instead of using sines and cosines
what's what's said better choice
of trial function
you could say OK
like those guys in
but still you have these integrals
show when galerkin
suggested this idea
well the computer of course didn't exist
and and was three
probably too
in other words so galerkin
what i spent a lot of time
trying to get because he's only choosing to functions he would try to get to
functions that were pretty
close to the right to the real when
course the real winner is unknown but he would he would work hard to try
to find functions are close to it
what if we
if we deal with the fourier series and we take a hundred or a thousand
terms well we don't have to worry or we could have we got a good
approximation we can expect yes we probably have
if if our
if we're taking a thousand for eight terms
and we find the best
thousand weights we can probably come down close to the true value
that but my complaint about the fourier choice was the cost of
all right so let me let's invent the finite element method here
give me a suggest some other functions
so that i could take the functions one x x squared xq about x to
the ninety nine
that would be their myspace would be all the polynomials of degree ninety nine
that hundred dimensional space
i could minimize
OK you it's OK so
of with with that polynomial what do you think
is that is that a good choice
i think
not the best OK so you have another
so you're going to take functions
now you are going the right direction OK so you're going to take functions that
i this the kind of function you're putting in
OK so this is what waltz
so this is the wall street
sorry that somebody
well will add your name also walls why are OK
are but this you're you're absolutely right can i am i allowed function
the derivative is the problem
you're you caught me out actually
i said any function
but i really overdid it
because that because the step function
have the derivative is the delta and here we squaring the darned thing and we
would get infinite
so i really should have
requiring that the function that i need the thing to state finite
now you're all year
take one more step and you've invented by
so instead of piecewise constant
whichever jump
and the derivative is
is delta which was really blows us up
what should i take now
p fries and you
these piecewise
so now
switch to
linear finite elements they people piecewise linear
linear pieces linear elements
that's where the word elements coming in
OK so my my functions are
the functions i'm allowing manner or any piecewise linear
right so
and now
everybody sees
that we made our life
much easier as far as calculating these intervals
as we got a pretty darn simple functions which we can integrate
a piece of the time
b given that we know the value of c
and finally
there's the computational reason why graphical models are very exciting
allow us to define
general message passing algorithms
to implement probabilistic inference efficiently
so if we want to answer a question like what is the probability distribution over
a given that we know very c takes on some value little c
we can do this by sending messages on the graph so when we implement things
on the computer we can do kind of object oriented implementation where each node sends
messages to its neighbors and after a bunch of messages get past we can compute
all the right probabilities that we're interested in
so graphical models really combined ideas from statistics from graph theory and computer science
even if you even if you don't use these message passing algorithms you'll find the
graphical models all over papers in machine learning and pattern recognition these this is important
to know what exactly they mean
OK so fundamentally graphical models represent conditional independence and we going to use the following
no conditional independence this as access is
are independent of y
and what that means is that the probability distribution over x
given y and v
is equal to the probability distribution over x given v
you know in other words why
it doesn't really affect the distribution of x once we know the value of v
and this is just the technical conditions so that these things are well defined these
probabilities are well defined
another way of thinking about this is x is independent of y given v
if the joint distribution of x and y given v factors into this tradition of
x given b and the distribution of y given t
and we can think of conditional independence between sets of variables in a completely analogous
a bunch of variables x and bunch variables y are going to be conditionally independent
given v if the
joint distribution factors in this way and the more traditional notion of independence which is
marginal independence we can write like this
it just says x is independent of y
or in other words x is independent of y given the empty set of variables
if you want to write in this conditional independence form that just says the joint
distribution of x and y factors into the distribution of x the distribution of y
OK so
you know we can think of a bunch of examples in the real world where
you might have conditional or marginal independence
for example
the amount of speeding fine that you get a
should be independent of the type of car you are driving given the speed that
your car driving
otherwise it wouldn't seem very fair
you know whether you have lung cancer
it is independent of whether you have teeth
yellow teeth sorry
given that you're smoking although smoking can cause both lung cancer in your teeth to
turn yellow
etcetera so you know we can we can imagine lots of different examples of marginal
and conditional independence
and i will go through all of them but it's it's a little subtle to
think about these things because sometimes things can be marginally independent like for example if
you have two teams playing each other with players chosen at random from a lot
of a large pool players then the ability of team a the ability of team
b might be marginally independent
variables by
given that you know the outcome of the game versus a versus b then these
are no longer marginally independent so for example if we know that a b b
then you would infer that the ability of team a is more is likely to
greater than the ability of team b
right there
no longer remain independent
OK so graphical models are way of representing conditional and marginal independence
and i'm going to start just by talking about factor graphs
in fact graphs you have
the notes only have two types of nodes circles represent random variables and these all
filled dots represent factors in the joint distribution
so for example this factor graph here
represents the fact that the probability distribution over
a through e factors into the product of a function of
a and c that's this represented by this not here a function of b c
and d represented by this and the function of c d and e and this
one over z is simply a normalisation constant
this factor graph here on this side represents this factorisation of the joint distribution
and the normalisation constant is simply the sum over all the possible settings of all
the variables of the products of the factors
it's just what you need so that the probabilities sum to one
what these graphs represent is that
is a family of probability distributions so
this graph here represents all probability distributions over
five variables
that can be written in this form
and it
in the graph we can talk about things
like neighborhood relationships between nodes and these are going to be important to figure out
what the independence relationships are between the random variables so two nodes are neighbors in
a factor graph if they share a common factor so a and c are neighbours
but a and d are not neighbors
this is just a recap
what i said on the previous slide
and now we can talk about how these graphs
so i'll give you five minutes
so we know time of the solution or
most people who work
how many of the people have solved the problem already
then they give it another two minutes
two q one to solve
i'm not used
so i can knew the solution the whiteboard but
maybe someone is considered he has found the right solution she is on the right
solution and i would like to to present
i should say we will have a prior for the people who find the most
it's a very rare item
one day in the future command high prices if you sell it on ebay
we know is when we printed these teachers you have this little girl
there here
one of the teachers upside down
i don't know why
but we believe mean something so we have to do do something with this tissue
so i will have occasional a little exercise like this in my lectures and
whoever solves most of them
get the t-shirt maybe also some problems in the election
because you have to prove that use of
not enough you tell us you will have to do it here
now help you
if you want
to convince anyone
maybe not in the very first lecture
she so many signs
OK i'll do it
so we have courageous volunteer
direct everything within
i just want to be true
c four
OK in particular
like just
he sits on the one you
so you get something like this
but with the opposite sign
with the opposite sign you can use instead of writing in terms of
in terms of the dot product between two
the point is you go OK just show us right
do you want the microphone
can you can you hear him without microphone
the values
first of all way it to
this formulation is just
people that one slide
so here we have
the one sided between
my c
so what
right is
this is
to see why
my da my
like this
doesn't seem like
see my
so it's really hard to be here today in two
there should be some of the changes taking place in the world to talk about
a fundamental shift is happening in the world of advertising
also advertising
so when this
i spent some time period
imagine the second order
this hundreds of millions of dollars spent every
and the statistics back
providing such decisions about how to effectively space
it's actually the content was missing for
first produced
it's essentially consumers get messages to talk about
the size of the data
in fact
it's beginning to rapidly replaced traditional forms that size it introduces
the complete paradigm shift in terms of
they have to be interpreted and analyzed and speed which that analysis needs to take
place the advertising to be effective
in some sort of shared experience in terms of
organisation scientists try
it allows them to develop new models
to assess those models together models into production
without having to worry continuously about the underlying deficit necessary to manage petabytes of data
and and you know these runtime environments in operation worldwide basis
i'd also like to use today to introduce a visiting scholar program talk about what
more about that at the end of the day
so i'm going to touch upon the business of internet advertising just provided a brief
primer on on how it works and ultimately
the data that generates one of the things about digital advertising compared to sort traditional
broadcast print advertising is the very process of delivering the advertising creates data record
in fact enormous quantities of data produced every day and this data contains rich consumer
experience that we can start to mine to understand patterns and build predictive models
ultimately these models are about understanding consumers that understanding the interesting affinities consumers so we
can ensure they receive more relevant content lasted until a little bit about how we
organised company the way we solve these problems of of making sort of science is
effective when there's lots of other things to take care as well
we're in the midst of the biggest shift in the history of media
media is transitioning from a one-size-fits-all model of broadcast model
so the dynamic real-time environment where consumers can choose whatever they want anytime and content
can be selected for now
media has historically always been about broadcast what that means is that everyone who consumed
everyone who receive the magazine or watching television show would see the same content the
same same media content and the same advertising content
and in those environments everything we did was about to understand the audience and that
we need to understand every individual is reading a magazine which is that to understand
aggregate what was the characteristics of the entire population of people to read the magazine
anyone in tune into the television show we see the same advertisement
but our computers are digital devices and mobile phones are i had
these are effectively blank slide nothing is broadcast them brothers delivered individually to them based
on request that we can in turn out browsers may
and the way it works is when we go to a particular website a request
is made about websites of potentially many services
content is returned it is rendered
by browser
and of course that content could be the same for everyone
you know the server may be set up with a simple set of rules to
return the same content to everyone
but in fact that server can decide based on whatever logic our algorithms are present
in any data that has available
to provide a different message has the has the power to actually serve different communications
to each individual and everything that takes place
behind your browser
is the online advertising ecosystem
all of the different parties that enable
buyers and sellers media
two interact that enable content to be distributed to
two and machines enable us to respond all sit the next cloud behind computers
that ecosystem
fundamentally changes the way we need to think about making decisions
because the geometric expansion the number decisions need to be made we move away from
whole audiences
and to individuals
we're we're not making decisions about an entire website but rather making decisions about individual
on top of that we have fragmentation of media consumption we can watch the same
across many different screens at different times
from different places
and all of these additional considerations in terms of what content may be relevant
now alongside this massive expansion and the amount of data we have enormous compression at
the time frames that are available for us to make decisions
you know when making a decision about which advertisement which magazine to advertise a product
we might spend many weeks making that decision
we have one insertion order
and every single copy of the magazine shows the same advertisement
well the internet because in real time
and the time that the service had to make a decision to consumers experience isn't
isn't degraded is measured in milliseconds
an enormous exponential number increasing in the amount of decisions huge compression in the time
we have available to them
these problems can only be solved algorithmically
this is a big shift in terms of the way
media media buying occurred and it's the shift that we that is difficult for the
industry to move through because they have such established processes but ultimately a significant portion
you know i would wager majority proportion
of all advertising dollars will actually be decided in real time algorithmically
just to give you a feel for the online advertising ecosystem will start with the
he entities
all of the
all of the inventory all of the audiences
are created by publishers media companies that produce content and make their content available on
their website typically the content is made available free of charge and the way in
which these
media companies are able to produce that content is of course by selling advertising their
businesses that support
all of the model
in the advertising ecosystem flows from advertising markets people that have products they want to
his out of work that it's just a question of time and more lost
and it's it will happen so i think it's over really for human computer go
but i like i'm trying to be strong to bear
you can ask them to
david about that
OK so let's go to the last idea bootstrapping
so bootstrapping i mean things like the bellman equation like temporal difference learning relating the
value of state to state that falls may just when you thought i would start
with i think it is a key a key idea so let's let's look at
a little bit
so we can basically think that is an alternative way of defining value
so we can define value as i did before
we call this extensive definition i don't know what to call this i want to
contrast it with the sort of the bellman equation bootstrapping definition
so this is the bellman equations says the values state should in expectation because the
value the first reward
because the discounted value for the next state OK that's the bellman equation and just
and just think from all this is really a definition
of what VE is
this definition is a definition two of course same
the same if we have them exactly solved but if we're going to approximate that
they're not going to say
and in everything about approximation we don't have to take this is the truth value
we could take this is the true
it's not really sense which one is true and the other is not true
and but which one would be better
and what will happen we think about which which might be better what might that
we would be better to think of things of bootstrapping sensor earning extensive roll-out sense
so one can see right away that the bootstrapping
one way in which the bootstrapping things better
it is if you can make an argument going to work with in in time
it's better
because to do this
if you don't worry about learning
but let's just worry about it verifying
we have we have a theory about what the values how can we tell if
that value that serious corrective our values are correct and just look at it over
time so you think that the state has some number
and now to see if it's correct you have to see the rewards that come
and you have to see all of them out you know the still discount is
so it's all incoming because you getting a different estimate every time you get all
these estimates for every time you making them and then you for all those you
have to look at all the future awards and scans make sure they line up
it's it's awkward it's inconvenient
was this thing you have you estimate the state u a one one step you
see the reward you see next guess the same they're not the same
and you done then you can you you repeat
the news the new state it's much more convenient so that's one way of bootstrapping
is better OK now let's look at a couple other things the other things happened
with you know approximations
it's also why
one might values be approximately might be approximate because you've got the metadata
there might be approximate because you have limited function approximation you only have so many
parameters function approximation of course that's really going to happen all the time both is
going to happen all the time axis state space the state space is
unimaginably huge going to solve the potentiality not by getting the right value at every
state because
the state space is exponential
but we're going to do it by by doing well without OK so let's look
at these two first we might have to approximate because we have limited data so
here's the classic reason why bootstrapping might be better
it's an example i think this is game looking back at minor or we have
stayed here which we think is good because we have lots of experience with that
and ninety percent of the time in which that state go on to win
and sometimes from we reach that state would going to last but most of the
we go on to win
so that's our past experience and we see a new state
and we want to ask what value should it have well our experience with this
new state is it goes on to the good state and then goes on this
time to los
what should we could conclude well
excuse me
j and
once OK what value should the unknown state be given
and we can use to our two things
extensive approximation bootstrapping approx extensive approximation says OK unknown state i end up losing it
returns were zero
one minus one
OK bad state
bootstrapping definition says i saw the state took me to a good state by chance
they this time i lost from that could stay but it needs that state basically
it should be good
so these are are different and i think we can imagine we can we can
imagine cases where each each one of these answers would be would be
would be better than one of these might be better
but it in particular there are cases of the world's markov where this is
this is the right conclusion bootstrapping is the right conclusion
so that's why
that's why we might want to approximate what that might be better
bootstrapping definition so here's some empirical results this is old stuff but
we have four different problems and we are varying the degree of bootstrapping this simple
lambda parameter lambda is the books that were just applying size lambda
the the y axis is a performance measure lower is better these are kind of
like steps perhaps open mountain car
what is the cost per episode in cardiff also in our case one to be
low in all cases the right most data point the red data points
islamic is one which has no bootstrapping so that's an extensive
so the notion of accuracy and the leftmost endpoint is full bootstrapping
and in between is in between so the striking thing and then this is users
a different kind to different kinds of traits but so just look at one of
these is is typical that we get a that's a good performance at what we
for bootstrapping
and there's there's an intermediate place where
the the best degree bootstrap and but what happens if we go to one
a full extensive definition with no bootstrapping is perform skits gets
rapidly much worse
much worse
can't paul it can even have data point because it just doesn't happen it's too
now this is these are all small problems but i think the representative of what
what we think
is the correct conclusion that bootstrapping in practice
helps we to bootstrap at least a little bit
so i think is the key idea reinforced
OK second
the reason we might want to approximate because we have limited function approximation
so you don't have flexibility parameters can get exactly right all states this is we
should consider this to be the normal case and so again we have to answer
the question if we can get exact
you know that
usually computers pretty fast they
operated by
and variable white
is example such calls
and the idea is extremely simple
and everybody
you use one beat
to indicate is the last byte of this number of this is not last but
in this number
so for example if you want to encode fifteen
so we are using
one by
and they put zero in the last beat of this by to indicate that we
in court everything in one
in this in this number
ft into into one but you use two bytes and videos topped
largest paedophiles quite indicating that
the next byte is also in use
and the same situation is if you want to include the next night
and this causes so-called
then i actually went in court in ordinary text collection
compression is very very
close to what we can get with these the most optimise i never called or
rice golomb code
it's very very close the first
second implementation is extremely
you can write it in any programming language in one
one hour is the bargaining unit testing and know stuff
and it wasn't a lot of experiments that showed that the results of compression and
file in this this very simple approach
is maybe only a number of course and different from any types of wire compression
that using beats
so it's very good calls
and i recommend you if you are developing search engines you this called because it
satisfies all our demands
and actually all open source project that we discuss not only most of them
i using variable byte this and different material things yes
it's very good call
but sometimes
in pretoria situations we need to compress better
and actually we can do it we can compress better than all the previous calls
but usually the loss performance
i want to
described this because this is interesting topic that you cannot read in most of books
about information retrieval index
so the idea is that
we assume that we can compress better than all calls that we described before
and the intuition behind this is
if you have this forced
posts ideas in this post this have ideas of documents
in our previous approach to compression
the was look if we're looking only on the previous number and called the
maybe a better idea is to look not not only on the previous number
but maybe we can take a block of numbers
and if you have a lot of numbers
we have we can we can get more statistics about this number
number and based on the statistics can create better compression
because we can look into
into the future can compress better
actually if you are talking about the idea of compression
blog called it
so block compression is a big area
text it's well known
for example
but easy easy to run on unix compress that implementing this algorithm
this rigorous and they the same so if you have a block of data we
can look here can take stock uses from all these block and we can compress
the for but
so how we can use the according to here
first of all we divide our least into some blog
and then we can encode every block independently
and for every this everyblock going to
you use of questions will combine them together
and how we can divide course there are two approach first approach we can simply
get all always some fixed number of points for example we
i can say that
two hundred fifty five forcing is one block
and become president
it's usually better it's better approach implementing implementing compression
OK you already have that
OK small
for all zeros for instance and long for a ridiculous things
this definition is
nearly independent of the choice
yes that's right
OK the sense
the sense in which it is
complex it
it is normally not easy to find from the data the random number generator
i won't go into that
there are versions time bond versus common more complexity to take into account
so that one there one of the great take into account complexity is to generate
the sequence and there's one which takes into account how complex is fine
the shortest
because you here on the foundations you know i will
mostly ignore computational issues so if you know computational issues of student more
sequence is very simple i mean to figure out to number generator and then you
the program
but there is very little information
OK it's nearly independent of the choice of u
the first thing i could write a program in c or price programming lists
and they get different answers
if i have my short program written in c
and i one of the list program what they can do is just right in
enlist c interpreter or compiler
and then append c programs so the novelist program
which computes my sequence and the length of this program
it's just the c program plus a little bit of overhead which is the compiler
the overhead is independent of complex along the string is and this is what i
mean nearly independent
i think everything from
so what you have is the k of you have access
user compare two
new prime
so different universal language
it is bounded by a constant that depends on the new york times
what is independent of x
normally what you write is
then because additive constants appear everywhere discuss them
very and a little bit
right is equal to and you put plus
that means equal apart from some constant
these concepts are annoying
some believe that because of this constant the whole series crash
probably don't have time but in my book and in the book of leviticus standard
of chemical complexity they find arguments for why you can live with the consequences of
all they not
many ships in many cases
another thing is so k satisfies most properties informationmeasures satisfy in particular
the shannon entropy which probably about
which also makes the information content in
in in in sequences
and it's actually closely related so many of the theorems
probably most theorems in shannon entropy have
barry on a lot in common complexity
but the kolmogorov complexity is superior to shannon entropy
in various ways for instance shannon entropy will never catch
the regularity in the data is of high
OK that was the greatest i mean one of the bodies of kolmogorov complexity that
all regularities well effective regulators
the major disadvantage is that it's not computable
but the purely theoretical concepts
you can prove nice theorems
but if you want to do something in practice you have to proximity somehow
and ever come to that later
OK i should mention i mean there are many mathematical constructs which is so high
in the arithmetical hierarchy that this sort of you know
you know
anything reasonable
but this is actually quite low i mean this list and sigma one so you
can compute computed from above approximate from about future is the number of programmes let
them run this one as some programs stops to look for the compute right answer
and if yes progress of mankind a bit shorter than the previous one to keep
it can approximate this function from above
unfortunately if you do it and there's no way you can also show that the
convergence is
you write on any anything
computable functions
which is supposed to be the convergence rate and then you can show that convergence
slower than the function so so it's not not a very good way to approximate
OK that was the one slide
introduction to come work complexity
the summary is that it is an excellent universal complexity measure and if you come
across the country
OK so
i can't compute it i can plot a graph of it
expected graph sketch of this function
so first what you have is i mean your x
and i identify you natural numbers with
the strings
a natural number x
i can cope with log x bits
you all know that
and kolmogorov complexity the shortest code
so it can't be larger than log
it is a little bit larger because they have to talk about the coat i
don't want to go into that so you can show that is bounded by log
explores two log log x sort of marking the end of the of the bits
OK so it's always smaller than that
and then OK so
asymptotic killing you can also show that must be larger than log x foremost text
it's roughly because you cannot have i mean
if you have a class things not all of these things can have short called
most of them need to have long long called
so there's a lot about you
but occasionally function drop down if x is very simple
so for instance if x is
in talking about numbers now is two to the power to to the power of
a large number but has a very simple description was brought down
so then in these cases kolmogorov complexity dogs
well that's roughly how it looks like
you can even prove some solo
continuity for this common complexity which is quite interesting so it is in a certain
sense are continuous functions
apart from additive constants
so there's a lot of
very beautiful theorems and useful theorems onto
and at least one i will
exploit later
so now we have quantified complexity
four strings and we have some coding for other objects
what we need now
we started this hypothesis and i want a prior over the set policies occam's razor
tells me that the price depends on of the complexity of this is
so the complexity of this hypothesis that can measure commonwealth complexity so remember these are
probability distributions so these functions
but the kolmogorov complexity of function is simply i mean the shortest programme which computes
this function
and what you can show is the right way to define the prior is now
as a tool to the mines the kolmogorov complexity
so what does it mean if you have a policies which is very simple so
probability distribution is extremely simple in the short program
let's compute
you know the probabilities of samples from this distribution
so this would be a small number two to the miners came to be a
this like technology triggers
so here we have everything from
quantum computing to allthe mosthype stuff apparently these days would be
cloud augmentedreality which is going out social analytics and so on so big data
is coming according to gartner going up
what's interesting so here we have also different signals symbols
the triangles which are
like ten years to the markets
are ten yearstothe sort of maturity but
that's a big data
has a circle so it's
only two to five so it's really
upcoming technologies so which will have an impact pretty soon not as much as
maybe some other
again this is just another view
putting big data in the context of other technologies which are
out there
okay what are
key enablers
for big data
all three i guess are obvious but still
let's mention them
so one is increase of storage capacities
increaseofprocessing power and availability of data so without
anyofthese three bigdatawouldn'tbe possible in such a form
as we are discussing these days
ok,let's check each of those and
so here we are in
1986 basically
back then there's almost no data
we didn't have capacity really
but now this just exploded in the last ten years
is going up
another view
it's more like relative
comparing analog versus digital data
see back in 1986 it was
ninety nine percent everything was still analog so we had just this tiny
little disks so two hundred
fifty K
those guys remember
and then this was
growing growing growing and now
nowadays analog
part is
definitely ways smaller and everything isdigitalso this certainly is one
important enabler
exponential curve
almost nothing back then this
so called we didn't even usesupercomputers back then but this huge
server rooms are
even the word server was not there
back then so
thesehuge computersare
were as powerful as mobile phones nowadays
and now this went up
now it's interesting if
we check distribution of computing power
different types of devices so we have
pocket calculator calculators whichwerewell based on the amount of them
backthen they are pretty significant
servers mobile phones video games and personal computers and see how these proportions are
changing so
personal computers are
pretty big still
but obviously there are in decline
so this would be
clouds Iguess
mobile is moving
ormaybeI misssome of the colours basically these distributions are changing and
it's important somehow to
to to be aware that
this is growing can also types are types of machinery which we're using nowadays are
data availability was the search enabler
here's an interesting graph
soall these graphs I amtakenfrommckinsey report whichI willreferencewhichyou can
get for free from the uh web
so these are
industry sectors
so this is
and the estimated stored data in 2009 in
petabytes per
sector so
see we have
manufacturing government
communication media and so on banking would be here
and is dropping down
what's interesting
how much data
is stored per company
percompany with more than thousand employees
in 2009 you see that
it's not unusual to have
most of the companies would have somewhere in the
so unless there's other questions on move on to the second part
well we treat the two projects pretty independently and then that should be
more men
that we we do them completely independently we take the method and we get data
from the medical setting and we
learn the policy estimation the errors for that setting and completely separately we do
estimation method is the same but otherwise the models and estimation are completely separate
OK so the search for the second part
is a little bit different
we're going to complicate things into is
the first one that we assume that we don't have the state labels
this is a lot more realistic
and the second one
is that we're going to assume we have control over how the data is collected
a lot of robotics domain this is perfectly fine in the medical domain this is
not fine
in terms of certainly no one is offering to let me run randomized clinical trial
anytime soon and even in the epilepsy case i'm not going to collect data on
humans but as i mentioned for epilepsy we have a nice rat model where we
have collaborators which allow us to come in with our time DP based decision maker
and plug it into the rat brain and let us collect these there however we
want and then we doing this sort of on a bi-weekly basis so we have
this kind of set up right now where we don't have the state labels we
really don't know what's the state of the neurons any time in point or even
some indicators of epilepsy
but we do get control over how the data is collected this is both
a blessing and a curse it's great that we have to control but we need
to use it wisely we need to take action to make sense otherwise
the point of having that control
the online case
well also going to add up to bayesian framework in this case rather than frequentist
framework and the
general bayesian framework is
i'm sure familiar to everyone here
we assume we have some prior distribution over are unknown parameters
so we still assume that the model of the transitions in the observation is not
known a priori but we have some notion of what might be good parameters
we're going to be the posterior via bayes rule as experience is acquired and the
more interesting part is
how do we pick our actions with respect to the posterior
so standard bayesian framework but in the probably be setting
and the advantage from our perspective is that it gives us a nice way to
include prior knowledge explicitly
the epilepsy domain we really have very little prior knowledge so we pick fairy agnostic
priors in the dialogue management problem we have better priors we have some sense of
when the robot says something the person is going to reply something specific but there's
some noise factor but we still have some sense of what the model might look
so this framework lets us include that knowledge
it lets us perform learning as necessary because when the online setting where we get
to pick actions so we get the advantage of that in the last point which
is one that i think is useful really allows us to explicitly consider the uncertainty
during planning to take actions
yes that will give us good foreward
and yes i will try to figure out what the state of the system is
but in particular that will trade-off between when i need to learn more about my
model one they need to be pretty confident about what i know and pick the
strategies which i think are good
so just a quick recall for those of you with a short memory post food
induced coma about the problem the model the same set up as before
and the question here is really how should we choose actions if parameters
t and o are uncertain
we assume for the purpose of today's talk about the reward function is known
i did that for the first half i'm doing that again
techniques can be generalized quite easily to the case where the reward is not
known but it keeps things cleaner and simpler for today and so on
this notion of bayesian learning has been explored in the MDP set up in the
case where you know the state of the system
but after a lot of work in france
and that set up the idea is quite simple it's a little bit like the
frequentist idea you can the number of times
but you transition from state s to s five upon taking action a
so you just counting as we did before but you start from some prior
and that prior you can think about imagined experiences that i'm pretty sure that transition
is going to happen it would be like seeing it ten times and then also
counting how many more times i see it
so these counts define the dirichlet distribution
over the transition model assumes that people are familiar with the dirichlet distribution
the good thing is that the nice closed
closed form update for upon seeing the information and so these counts
are sufficient statistics for defining the dirichlet
posterior so it's easy to update and now all we need to do is planned
these counts
so you can formulate a new MDP model
the state space is defined as the original physical state
and the information state meaning or count vectors
and now the probability depends on both being in state having a certain count
seeing a certain action will take you to a new state and set of counts
so the count the count part
is deterministic and the state to state part
can be probabilistic
so once you've set up this extended MDP
can solve it just to standard MDP accounts discrete here stated discrete you can run
your favourite MDP solver and things are all well and good
in finite pomdps
we can extend the same framework
instead of having only counts over transition
now we need the help over transition
i wrote the third chapter of the book and the book that was you going
it was written by somebody else
basically because we are trying to understand it and then to construct my bit
but initially we try to get over what the
basic ideas and statistics are
have statisticians approach data analysis problems
and then we look in the second half in chapter three it will be
about specific techniques that statisticians use specific models use specific approaches
so so first is more
theoretical and the second will be more
what people do
figure four
the point is
she is
well we have
one of the
section numbers here you find the section numbers don't make sense in terms of
the individual the talk section was taken from the book
so if i missed the section of the book out then that section
in this slide
OK so
a quick skim over what had introducing what was introduced and was one of the
basic statistical ideas the details of this are in the book basically and that's what
i'm assuming you have access to some stage
so i would take
the fundamental idea is statistics is that we think of uncertainty
as based on a probability problems but if you can explain in terms of exactly
how it works
we will
think of it as
it's just random chance so probability is an integral
element statistics because what we're doing
in statistics is well we did probability say this is how the world is what
should happen if i do such and such a thing to do was some sort
what would you statistics go the other way and say
this is what i did this is one of the data i got what does
that mean about the world so so one is what is called induction and is
what i called the deduction
right so source the simplest thing about probability is
was called the random experiment or statistical experiment and it's
as a trial so we do something
and the result is random so we've got examples here but you must see before
rolling the die
and what's wrong with this case
so rolling the die is one thing of course so in this case and i
got six possible outcomes are possible results and
the random editor
the problem
we're going to stand
so so one of the world's largest an example we're rolling the die
and you've got six
possibilities and they're all equally likely and the result you don't know what the results
going to be is randomly determined we don't know
if you have a a lot of physics and you could observe the di very
very closely
you might be able to work out was going to happen but that we're assuming
that we haven't got that sort of information and it's pure chance that turns it
is the same tossing the columns you've got two comes to a head or tail
and again it's totally determined
statisticians use a bit further from that this is the origin of probability statistics that
gambling games basically people
employed people mathematicians statisticians to
i will have rowed in the game against richmond who wanted to gamble pays people
like me to work out the probabilities of various things happening a long time ago
but statisticians take this further take it will be on the government going to say
something like that
this example here which you see what chosen an example later but
if you
so something biological you plant a field turnips
you find the turnips will grow differently
and you find if you do the same thing with the turnips on two different
occasions you get different results so there's a random element to that as well so
so the yield
the weight of the term it comes that will move
and the results looking yet we about the call those outcomes or events sometimes and
this just a
in some notation all probability this is one
there very few politicians one view probability based on the frequentist view
you do lots of these trials
in fact
you do
and trials
and we have an outcome results of the results of this event the here a
it might be something like the score on the die is even
for example for trivial example of so what's the probability that happening well
we can work out it's just half but in
and on not the
and this indicates once again that somehow one's exposure to infectious agent historical exposure has
a dramatic effect on one subsequent susceptibility to the
the two a virus and in the case of polio virus we're dealing here with
an agent
which is much simpler than the retroviruses we talked about last time like RSV poliovirus
also has a single stranded RNA genome
and that encapsulated in a protein asia's cold
which is made up of only of viral proteins so it's very simple single stranded
protein h is called the single stranded RNA
it is actually polyadenylation at the three prime and so it can serve as a
messenger RNA
it's all the same polarity that is it has a plus polarity which means that
it can be translated immediately
i'm distinguishing that from the other flavors single stranded RNA which could be of the
complementary strand which could exist because one can make double stranded RNA which obviously cannot
be translated so this can serve as a messenger RNA and just as an aside
the way the polio virus replicates is totally different from that of retroviruses what happens
is the polio virus makes its own plimer is you go from single stranded RNA
two double stranded RNA
i e the complementary copy is is made and that in turn is used as
a template for making more single stranded RNA
progeny RNA
and note here that there is no DNA and all involved in fact poliovirus can
grow inside the cell that has been deprived of its nucleus moreover if one stops
nuclear RNA nuclear DNA dependent transcription that has no effect on this
but you'll you'll notice correctly
the these these kind of steps here
involved RNA dependent RNA polymerase is
and in the normal physiology cells
that such a plumber such an enzyme never operates and therefore poliovirus must make among
its other proteins and RNA dependent RNA polymerase that can mediate the steps making a
complimentary copy of this strand get to get to the complementary strand in the making
progeny plus strand RNA is
again it has a very simple capsid of several viral proteins which rapid
now if one wants to assess
the potency of poliovirus RNA one can grow in a petri dish
one way of figuring out how much poliovirus RNA is in the solution is to
make a monolayer of cells like this
and then take various di lutions of virus document one talks about a virus type
one talks about a solution of virus particles one can really see them and even
if one could see the money electron microscope one wouldn't really know
what fraction of the ones who were seeing were actually biologically competent
but most interestingly you can take poliovirus solution of poliovirus particles place on a monolayer
of cells here
which can be infected by polio virus
in contrast to what i told you last time about
we're infected cell can tolerate the continued presence of the viral infection without dying
poliovirus is a highly psychopathic virus and by that i mean it replicated inside cells
and it kills them during the course of replicating inside the cells
so here what one has the polio virus will infect the cell here
and then
it will begin to infer spread from that cell to neighbouring cells in the
in the surroundings
and in so doing
it will create it we wrote a whole
right here
in the model layer
whose presence a so-called black signifies
the fact that there was initially infecting virus particle there it spreads intrinsically that spread
outward from the initially infected cells
in detail if you want to do this experiment really nicely what you do have
few affect the initial monolayer cells which i show here and in section is you
put on a layer of
the other rows or something above the infected monolayer and that ensured so that if
there's any viral spread it will be from cell to cell spread in a certain
neighborhood random virus particles getting into solution and swimming around all over the place infecting
cells helter-skelter
so here we might want to infect initial cell right here the monolayer and now
this grows will confine the the subsequent spread of progeny virus two adjacent cells in
with a ternary numeral
and what might happen in the real arithmetic the real numbers the ticket not the
actual numbers
so we have these these particular constants
and we have particular functions and successor function
and that sort of thing
this allows us to build up a little algebra inside of formal logic of times
inside terms these are all still have formal
mechanisms therefore methods
we still have
some predicates and variables but we now everybody in terms
here are the successors zero
successor's successor of zero
which often enough issue or not
have created to that kind of thing
sometimes in whatever in the future
these things would be called numerals
and the underlying thing at the neural spines to represent is the number
so this is supposed to represent two
but it's not it's this isn't just in your
referring to two we had in in a good model
the distinction between the natural model
in which
in which the the term zero prime prime
actually does refer to two
from some of the models
so this is kind of relevant to this kind of exercise because we trying to
build up
very complicated terms
build up with numbers
with the idea that there's this mapping to form
in the next couple of pages show you two ways that this was done
this is not a great import these days because people tend to believe that can
be done
they i have to be too big a deal about
it certainly is important as the first you cannot proceed unless you can show that
the model that the mapping is unique and so on
cutting method is going to assign the close to
the variables x and y
that can be
this kind of thing in principle
in our official notation
and that
it's going to be related to a formula in the language
so we call it and conventionally this thing
we all use that notation yesterday the standard description machine for instance
this is the same idea
now it's time to use more formally
so this is supposed to be
a particular terminal language two
formula five
and we need to see a couple of ways in which we do that
not only that
what girls
considered more than other people have found
easier or more or less
difficult anyway ways to a number of things is not just formulas derivations
after all the derivation
informal logic is supposed to be
a sequence of
the formulas
each formula which is either an axiom or follows from the preceding ones by the
rules that kind
and it's supposed to be
the last thing in the sequence
that's one
that same the introducing the concept of the derivation
we can cut that is the number
by just giving a certain number comma
we can decide that
this thing here
can be
as well as
telling the formulas
these axes
zero successor any other
function symbols or predicate symbols quantify whatever are around
because it allows up into this thing we can also
and so we can express their relations that way
so we could and we might get to that so much in the beginning but
we assign a closed term to each derivation which after sequence
now if the language in question
is the language of formalised arithmetic which is what i've talking about here
because will be in your
it will be like this
big formulas
just keep going here i guess i'll just show you the
the cleaning e
this is sorry the bill as jeffrey approach
in the bill of jeffrey
scheme for doing this sort of stuff
this is not the my golden goal
we started out just like this one both else on board
let's bring this is going to get the number one
rockets get the number two
the ampersand the wage
i think the logical conjunction
gets number three
exists gets four
the first
variable whatever it is gets five
this scheme for extending
if we assign five to the exterior
wilson five nine
x one sin five nine nine to x two
and so on
for the function symbols if there are any we'll use the six series
so function symbol
the zero function was
zero arguments
is so these constants get sick so
six years can extend to is k
we've got six o six nine six nine nine
in the course excited states
that's now it and logical symbols
we've done constants and function symbols
now it is predicate symbols
so the predicate symbols get the seven series
we've just associated with each particular predicate symbol in the language whatever it might be
seven seven i seven i had a section
that's a little example
which issues discussed so far completely mechanical
that course was an important point for these guys
for lexicons x
x equals x is coded by this scheme two
let me say wastrel
it's forty nine case
we start with forty nine that we have to have a left parenthesis
by the time of the state
i have
so that should be for nine
one five on sorry for nine five years sorry then left prints several x four
ninety five
four nine
references one
and so on
that's the mapping
so if i gave you formulate certainly produce the number by
phone around
what what what
is more complicated but
we need to proof is
if i give you my number
can you figure out the formula
if i give you the number
nine by itself
that number there is no formula correspond to
which touches x x five x six hundred thirty three
please we saw here in between these separator potentials
that connect and containing the variables so x one x two x three
shares x three with this week so we have the junction tree
and now we can run the junction tree algorithm
and the junction
basically contains a
the public distribution and send messages around which everybody is consistent
and we might consist is
i want to very tables in the junction tree
so each one of these please
we saw earlier as a function of its variables and nobody's these articles so functional
registered to the functional groups one x two x three i want all these functions
to on the variables they share
OK if i asked this function
what is the likely value for x two
next week
true or false
well this one like extra is true but this one like sixteen false and i'm
going to be
structure out the
you just all the
by sending messages from each clean to its neighboring saying this is what i think
then marginalize over the shared variable
so a b will send a message to saying if i some of my two
dimensional table entries over the
here's what i think should be
and then you get that message then update stable so it was about see you
table from b
so basically get invited to the two one dimensional
two by one table two by two table and some will stable give you the
same value something on the table
over c
so that's what i mean by message passing and so that's ever gets updated many
up typically with this message be the same for the first method the ball potentials
are really
we have a consistent distribution
there's something very valuable about that because once the judge in other that consistency and
we have a marginal distributions are
and how to treat the junction tree algorithm is guaranteed
it was two steps you initialise all you need to feel
and separate potentials you pull messages up towards the roof
everybody updates
that's upstream like it's in this room everybody is their tables and the reluctant to
send messages back downstream of individually
he's done some these
it's sum product messages
also called the sum product algorithm because it
at the very end when you read three tables your potential tables
you separate tables they all become potentials they become marginals conditionals over the hidden variables
given the data
so that's what we want for inference of each one of these
clearly now becomes the probability of the variables
it's describing given all the observed variables that you've actually observed before started the junction
so we have all these marginals telling you what configurations are like for the hidden
variable here this invaluable in the parent variables
as a two dimensional table
and also the normalized every potential functions is the likelihood of the data
the problem is that there were some of the hidden variable
so for basically one one
very efficient algorithm on it reaches the collective distributed
we have
all these interesting marginals conditionals over hidden variables given the data then the likelihood of
the data given the model
OK so that steps one two that we would like to do with
with that bayes net
and then another step is maximizing like so i can evaluate that like but i
also want to increase by
we only some parameters
i just think my tables
or just some jealousy means and covariances
so we'd like to maximize the likelihood
by summing over the hidden variables
basically the probability that the XV given the data
these are rights age disappears
so that's what that's like
able to learn from the data the worst-case predictions from learning theory would would apply
but in practice they don't because real data is correlated like this is a simple
correlation and we're gonna talk about this correlation first how you fit models that assume
this correlation
that's not invalid lesson doesn't mean that you don't have to worry about the curse
dimensionality because it actually associated with your model not your data
we were sampling from model had this independence characteristic if you make such a model
that has this independence characteristic your model is covering a vast space data can be
difficult to extract information from the data so there's something wrong with models like back
i think it's endemic in machine learning and statistics to claim that this is a
characteristic of the space is a characteristic of the model plus the space yet it
gives the worst case thing that can happen in the space and then if someone
brought to the data
which has after characteristic you really wanna be asking them what rubbish if you just
give me there's no information in this data because there really is and that's what
these lessons are about
um if this information is regularity in the data that you can extract those things will be true okay so
one thing i to do is put somebody
i mean because
i mean i just think it's in a larger sense is a myth a lot
of the people think people extract from it but not touched on earlier saying you
should expand things in the dimensions that's what the statistics say
because it's a bad idea
by making a feature size and infinity that's always gonna problems no no it's not
because the structure the model because the capacity control that's the way but talking about
yeah i'm saying the same thing is about what you know about your you'll
dataset size is a very bizarre thing if you think about it for someone to come to you
you're going be model and someone's bought u on you know his your client he's
walk into a room and he says that the data set
i found out hundred things about these fifty people
please can you fit your model
thank you think it that's difficult because
the zpi is large and in a smallish
but are trying to model and the guy goes all just i can tell you
one hundred more things about those people would you like to know
and then you should know don't tell me because then you have an even larger peak
i don't know anymore because it will mess with me the data as well as
how can that be true because it's not true
those hundred things will not be independent the previous hundred things you'll get richer model
the person so and so on so on
okay to be more stuff about that later on
okay so
where does this low rank abundance come from it comes from a low dimensional approximation
for the dataset that's the connection with dimensionality reduction simple low dimensional approximation linear low
dimensional approximation
if we made this e w w transpose dusty i made indeed sigma squared i before
then i would be known as factor analysis on the former used is known as probabilistic piece here
probabilistic principal component analysis and is a linear mapping from q-dimensional latent space
because i'm to build probabilistic models i think the low dimensional thing as latent variables unobserved things to appeal dimensional
data space
and then we can mappings we do a linear mapping from the then we corrupted
by independent gaussian noise noise is high-dimensional that's something we can't i mean that's almost
like this one way of thinking about noise if the nasty difficult stuff that we
can extract information from the people who define noise were people like the class and
gauss who looking a planetary motions through
the atmosphere and telescope and they said these things like on account four
let's assume independent random things being added to each other observation
arm bands
they're unstructured something they can't deal with the structure structure noise is very interesting but
it's not something we're assuming hit
and then what we do is we marginalize these latent variables using against him prior
that's how we do probabilistic piece you so
just remind on the notation so
two dimensional latent space pure dimensional data space and the number of data points why
is data in this end by p
matrix that's important because
it turns out if i write why why transpose that's an inner product matrix
center data is like data with the mean subtracted of so that's something we use
a lot and the latent variables are x and then we can use this mapping
matrix which maps repeat dimension to q-dimensional
data space so in fact when i go from
measure the similarity between the patterns
and if you're interested you can check our KDD that was on the
file page we describe these two cases
OK so far i just discussed as techniques to interpret
those discovered patterns
i haven't touched the second problem
if we set the threshold the low likely we would generate an exponential
set of patterns
and in some cases it is really time consuming so
researchers propose ideas for example closed graph patterns
and the maximum graph pattern to generate those graph patterns that are not redundant
so here is the concept
of closed frequent patterns
and the maximal frequent patterns
so let me show you some examples of closed frequent patterns
a graph pattern g
is closed if there exists no supergraph of g that carries the same support.
of which is obvious if some of G's subgraphs have the same support then it
is not necessary to output G subgraph. G-subgraph is just redundant subgraph
if we compare them with G.
and here is the definition of maximal frequent graph pattern
a frequent graph pattern g is maximal if there exists no supergraph of g is that
is frequent
so basically suppose we have a large set of frequent patterns we would like to
pick maximum
maximum patterns and output patterns to the user
so by doing this too
actually we can afford to shrink the size of frequent pattern set
here is
number comparison between frequent graph pattern and the closed frequent graph patterns
here is the axis is the minimum support threshold is the y axis
is the number of patterns
so as you can see that the number of closed frequent graph patterns
is significantly less than the number of frequent graph patterns
here i do not show the
number of maximal frequent graph patterns actually will be
much small than this number
and and you want to find those call graph patterns we developed some new
method which enabled which is able to find these patterns efficiently so we do not
want to develop some algorithm. OK in in the first step we generate all of the frequent patterns
and the second step is then we just do the for
post-process to generate those close closed graph patterns. this is not a
we would like to propose some pattern mining algorithm which can further speed up the mining
process without generating is intermediate
frequent graph patterns so here is our method the intuition
so suppose we extend a new pattern candidate from the previously discovered patterns
with k edge
and we would like to find some conditions that we can stop the search of
all the super
so here is a condition
if we have two graphs g and g prime and both of them are frequent
g is a subgraph of g prime
if in any
part of the one tgraph in the dataset
where g occurs
g-prime prime also occurs
then we actually need not grow g any-more since none of G's subgraph will
be closed except those of g prime
so this is very intuitive basically we can skip some search space
however there is a very tricky cases we should pay attention to in the graph
pattern mining here is example suppose we have two graphs
in the database
and we find that
edge a and edge b
always are coupled together
OK then we can find that's OK
with our
early termination condition we may need to expand patterns that contains
edge a and b together
however we recognise that
this part and this is part and actually this one across at least in both
of these graphs
but this part can not be generated by
this pattern a and b that means we have to design some specific
heuristicus to avoid the generation of such cases
so in our closed graph minimg algorithms we develop some mechanism to do this
so so far i have discussed
techniques about frequent graph pattern mining which is just related with the frequency criteria actually
many application scenarios
there as an interesting objective function so that we can use
for example let's take a second problem setting is example suppose we have two sets
of graphs with positive label and the negative labels
there are many interesting
objective functions
popularly used in data mining and machine learning society for example contrast ratio
let p and q be the frequency of subgraph g in the positive
dataset and the negative dataset so we can derive contrast ratio
we all can derive G-test scores
to measure the significance of this graph part and we can measure information gain of
these graph pattern we can do the cosine measure etcetera
unfortunately except as the frequency management as we
have seen before that frequency measurement actually is anti-monotonic
to the size of the graph pattern
here i should use the value change of these objective functions with respect to the graph
size of all supergraphs of a given graph pattern
as you can see that
the frequency
this measure actually always goes start with the growing of the graph size
however all of the other three
objective functions i listed here
i encourage you G-test score, cosine, the information gain all of them are not correlated with
the size of graph
what this means
this means that you if you want to find the graph patterns
have the
objective scores
you have to enumerate all of the possible subgraph in the database and then check
their objective score one by one to find those acquired patterns with a high
certainly it is not
good solution because it's not affordable in many applications
so researchers resort to some intermediate approximate solutions
here is
frequent pattern based mining framework
OK in this framework in the first step we can first generate those frequent
graph patterns and in the second step
so we can check their objective score go one by one try to find
those graph patterns with the highest objective score
however this mining
pipeline is approximate and also it has its own bottleneck
in the first step sometimes we might generate millions or even billions of patterns
here's the reason if we use that to the minimum support threshold too high
likely you will miss some important patterns
if you use that as the minimum support threshold is very low
likely the mining process will be stuck in the first step
and the second is has no guarantee of the quality because there is no correlation
between this objective functions with frequency
so we recognise this problem so rather than actually generating the complete set of frequent patterns
we are thinking that it could be more appealing to generate graph patterns
that has
in our work well with the case of lot marketing when we had the recommendations
between people and the other one is blogs have citations between blog posts
OK and the questions we ask in this part was
what kind of cascades arise in real life so so basically we would like to
see what are the common
the shapes of the cascades what got what the graph that commonly occur in the
network right so could be out of three stars and so on the question is
what is the distribution of this over this cascades and then
in case of fire marketing you could also go and just ask
how how what is your probability of going and buying a product if somebody makes
a recommendation in the more recommendations you get more likely to buy
if you do get tired of communications and just
develop some kind of resistance to that particular problem
so the first
case is from the
like marketing
well the idea is that we have descendants centers and followers of recommendations and they
all all get discount there is some kind of incentive for people to do to
do good recommendations and here's what's going on so we have a person does the
by the book
was the what when they are checking out they get an option to send recommendations
two to friends you may
so let's say
the person decided to send the recommendation now this this the the receiver gets a
two to buy the book
the same product and they get ten percent discount because they react upon the recommendation
and the centre also gets ten percent credit
because they they made good recommendation right and everyone is happy
and the process continues
and the data we were using is from are large
four vep store that the case that was doing this they have a big so
that our readers at least three million people sixteen million recommendations on half a million
products and we had like four categories of products sold books dvds music and videos
and the questions here is how hot what can we say about the propagation of
these conditions over the network so here's here's an example of the product recommendation network
so i think this is the product recommendation network for some movie
the blue nodes people that just like bot purchase the product without any external or
without any influence that we know of and then once once the blown-out purchases the
product it makes recommendations right it makes recommendations to all the black nodes
some of the black nodes
hard to say
the to the recombination and go go by the product so this would be to
read and write and also when of the cases where the accommodation was successful the
person went to purchase the item and the think propagate and you can see that
a lot of a lot of the graphs just a very small but then we
have this slide
there is a connected graph where you can find some red nodes
when they were recommendations recommendation sexually propagate
right in the first question to ask is
however this propagation that's how the cascades in real life and what you can find
you can find many many times there are just starts right somebody buys recommends and
nothing happens
nobody follows
then what also
happens is that people have common friends so two to people so first person buys
makes accommodation and somebody else buys and makes recommendations to the same set of people
like here or largest subset of in the other case that i know what the
the crossing from this one is when this person buys makes all the recommendation and
then one of the people
after the combination again
make it makes recommendations for
so this is for example what what we can see and this makes alot of
sense if you think of people have friends and friends of friends and so on
and then the second thing that we can go and examine is what are the
cascade the sizes right so how big this propagations of recommendations so basically we can
go how many people participate in one one cascade and you can plot the distribution
and again i'm showing the
cascade size so the number of people people in the propagation graph which is the
and i blocked on log log scales
so this means it follows a power law that has a very steep drop-off
so basically most of the cascades are very small radius stand
while while there are a few that are very large
so this would mean that that was the propagation of recommendations were like hundred people
it follows that
and what what is interesting from this is that if you would have some kind
of a simple branching process than this
it wouldn't generate URI
distribution like this
what i was promising before is we can go and just as query simply what
is the probability of buying a product as one gets more and more recommendations
and so we are putting than the number of incoming recommendations which is the probability
of buying
four books and four dvds separately
and for books you can see that after recommendations people
don't don't want to buy anymore while for dvds which are to be different
the common the probability or the
the likelihood of purchasing saturates at around
ten to twenty recommendations
and this
make some implications for viral marketing practitioners to on deciding which people to target and
how much how much spent send to them
and see if we can do similar things on the blogosphere now we are observing
blogs that what you will know slashdot and blogs like that right so the idea
is look these websites where people can post their diet is of course and so
on so basically the idea is you have this website that is composed of posts
in each post is time stamped and it's i
so hypertext because hyperlinks to other interesting things on the web
other post and so on
so this is how we can be represented as a graph
we have a huge box represents a blog
each blogs has a set of time stamped posts
posts and his posts just like
to be embedded
the difference being that the algorithm that it's going to guide your search going to
tell you which
feature to try next
so one particular example of that is the backward elimination
algorithm are the that was designed for support vector machines
it is very simple you start with all features then you're trying to learning machine
on the current subset of features by minimizing a given risk functional
then for each of the remaining features
you estimate that you've used select the feature
in the results in the least increase of the cost function or other decrease of
the cost function
so use these degraded or to improve
your your performance
as as measured by your cost function
and then you remove that features
that improves on is degree j
and to start over again
you try again with the remaining features and it right
this kind of embedded methods of work for the full kernel methods and for neural
instead of abruptly removing features in these degrees or or or adding features in this
research methods
what you can do for embedded methods is to use scaling factors in this opens
you the door to a wide variety of algorithm for feature selections
that combined with training
so before you know you know enormous space of all feature subsets we had one
for selecting the feature and zero for not selecting it
this corresponds to this vector of sigma
there is one for each feature one or present presence of the future and zero
absence of the future
so these are discrete indicators so you can replace the discrete indicators by
continuous scaling factors
that are now between zero and one instead of belonging to just zero one
sorry this
type here so that this is meant to be between zero and one
so the advantage of doing that
is that now we can perform a gradient descent on the scaling factors
sources do it we take a break in the middle so
so i think this would be a good time to break to make you present
in it and and the remaining part of the talk showing you how you can
design your own
algorithm for feature selection with your own training methods
using the scaling factors and then we'll be talking about causality
so in general
if you only care
to make predictions we don't care to know whether the variables cause the target or
the consequences of the target so
it's force predicted for disease to find genes that are
that have mutated and causing or disease or to find proteins that was concentration varies
in serum as a consequence of the this is like for example immune reactions
in some cases we will see when we care about
performing actions on the system
and c
what is going to be the results of our actions like for example delivering drugs
to a patient with respect to q and in that case we care about causality
and with the features are not closely related to the target so we'll talk to
but both of these problems in the second part of the presentation
a five minute break
so will come back and thank you for coming back after the test the the
first r
first like you to take questions if you have some questions on the first part
i've taken some questions offline
welcome to you know
as the more here
yes that's great one twenty
to details but i briefly spoke about the problem of multiple testing and the bonferroni
correction but a few
go the way of estimating the false discovery this becomes you whatever you can only
was the whole discovery
i didn't also give you know many details about this problem as the
the difference with the using
tabulated distributions
but there are some
delicate aspects about this whole mess and
in some experiments performed we not get always the same results in estimating the false
discovery rate is the probability distribution of the four methods
because in the sense the null distribution that you assume
this presentation is delivered by the stanford center for professional development
we are on the air
welcome one and all
and as i said on the TV when you're walking in but just to make
sure everybody knows this is to sixty one three transform and its applications
really transforms at all
and my name is brett good
circulating around are two
documents that give you information about the class there's a general description of the class
course information how we're going to proceed some basic bookkeeping
items out a little bit more about than just the second and also it's still
business schedule analysis a bit more about that in a second let me introduce our
partners in crime in this course
we have three courses fence
thomas john thomas was standard
this time serial regime aggarwal is that right
rushing enough
and the communities
OK so far
and correct
that's what i mean is everybody
thank you are now
and we will be setting up a time so the review sessions and so on
are also that will be that will be forthcoming we have a web page for
the course some of you may have already visited that but let me give the
and it's the addresses on the one that she one of the sheet is being
passed around but let me right now so you can be sure to visit and
register for the class because it is on the web page that you will find
a course handouts course information i will email people v of the web page or
have to be registered
i five to seven announcement of the class
post announcements in an email then that will be done through the web page and
you have to be registered on the web page in order to get those emails
i won't be doing it through access rights so it is at like many of
the other class http slash slash you were calling go
are there
class but stanford edu you can find it very easily
he knew slash each sixty one OK
go there if you have not already and registers of the class
right now let say little about the information that you have one is a little
bit more about the mechanics of talk more about the content and just the second
the little bit about the soldiers and schedule and the course through the syllabus is
as i said on the on the top in outline what we're going to be
doing a fairly accurately awarded we're going to be doing but it's not a contract
right so
there will be a natural inflow of the course as well as things go along
and when we get particular material or what we cover in order to do this
is more less say accurate but it is not written in stone
what you should use it for however is to play your reading so i things
will be much better for all of us if you
read along with the material as the syllabuses scheduled basically outlines are because there's there
are times when i want want to skip around little bit there are times and
i'm going to derive things there are times when i'm not going to derive things
and you'll get much more out of a lecture our time together if you've read
the material thoroughly before you come to class so that's one thing i ask you
to do we have two exams scheduled we have midterm exam and finally exam i'm
going to get the midterm asymmetry sami's is already actually on here
at least tentatively sort of toward the end of october
we'll have outside of class where that is will be down regular exam
but i want to do it for ninety minutes rather than fifteen fifteen minutes just
too short of time for class for material like this so it be nineteen examine
all schedule at several sessions outside class this is way usually that has many problem
has worked out or if everybody so have an alternate times and so on and
the final exam is scheduled by the registrar's office do not come to me right
before the final exam saying all i scheduled trip out of town i hope that
sort of problem
right you know what the dates are ahead of time
but also regular problem sets none of these things i'm saying should be new you've
been through the drill many times the first part of the problem sets are going
to be i i had of startling innovation last out of course
where i had about the problem set on monday and had to do the following
wednesday actually had like we can have to do the problem sets and there is
overlap between the two and people thought that was just a brilliant idea
so we can do that again this year except for the first problem so i
decided was not good policy to handle the very first problems at the very first
day of class
so i'll hand out on wednesday and post that also really suppose sure handed out
it will be available on wednesday and will be the following wednesday and again these
sorts of things are pretty routine for you and i'm sure even through many times
it will be practice
r although again not necessarily every time
without fail to have matlab problems on the homework one or two malapropism problems in
the homework so i'm going to the assumption that people have some experience with using
matlab that doesn't have to be terribly advanced and also accessed using matlab so if
you don't have experience using matlab and you have access to to matlab get some
experience and get some access
will be hard
we sell soul little bit about some things this is the course reader for the
course it's available at the bookstore
and also available on the course website doesn't have the problems and it has the
material that going to be covering class now
this is basically as it together set of lecture notes that have been using for
a number of years in the class nice tinker with it
every time i teach the class
but because it is stitched together set of lecture notes there the organisation sometimes a
little bit odd like you have an appendix in the middle of the chapter
and what that means is it was used to be an appendix to set to
particular lecture that went on that particular day
and there never got moved to anywhere else right so the organisation can be a
little bit funny you can help on this sorry that is if you find typos
if you find errors if you find things that are less than clear in their
in their wording if you want to if you if you have some other ideas
for example there are other explanations please tell me i'm all i'm working on this
i have to say that the whole because these these are written in this election
these are meant to be a good and i hope helpful companion for the class
that is they're meant to be read and they're meant to be used so i
you can help as generations of students in the past have helped try to refine
these and turn them into something that's really good accompaniment to the classes we go
one other thing that special this quarter is
the class is as always taped to an election the lectures are going to be
available to everybody but this time for the first time which is going to be
available to the world
i stanford is assigned an experimental bases which are competing with MIT here i think
to try to make some classes some of the materials for some classes available to
the world war i so the election is going to be everything's gonna be done
through the website
but instead of being stanford i d two
view the tape lectures i think anybody in the world can do these lectures of
the daunting have to watch my language
address well