you guys probably sit here talk about how to kind of noxious title from my
original research i talk where i was going to talk about
several problems and how inference in these models can solve all your problems but
actually don't really need this
OK but i decided that i decided that
first of all we still don't have enough also decided let's just talk about something
very very simple because the end of the day and i know john i really
tired because he really really so i about something so simple
it's incredibly simple
once you get the basic idea it's like very easy to understand really this talk
should take ten minutes and it will probably take actually twenty minutes but hopefully will
you sure happen
here it is
scan of paper i wrote a whole
which is about
almost fifteen years ago
from this
just an observation that very very simple classifiers perform annoyingly well on the problems so
basically just a little
medium scale experimental study where he majored a whole bunch
classification algorithms on all the different problems and he concluded that
if you don't know what the problem is before hand and ask you to bet
on the classifier
you're probably better off spending on a really simple classifier
and for any in any given problem these classifiers are never at the top of
the list but
they consistently performs surprisingly
i want focus today on the simplest possible classifiers which is k nearest neighbour so
k nearest neighbour kind has a bad reputation across the country classifiers are usually uses
k nearest neighbour is like you know the
think that i'm going to show you my algorithm is now going to beat but
actually k nearest neighbour has many kind of healing properties right so it's very simple
but surprisingly effective classification procedure the decision surfaces
automatically nonlinear it's nonparametric so it has very high capacity but you don't need to
do anything to training
i the quality of predictions improves
automatically as you some very strong theoretical result this and on the face only a
single parameter k which
you can easily achieve by cross validation so
he was actually an pretty pretty exciting part
idea and so what's the problem here
there's at least
at least three problems
one is
what is the nearest mean
so i told you k nearest neighbour
the videos
the nearest neighbour
classifier they take the point
you find the k nearest training examples to the test and in the majority vote
of their labels
we need to define what you're saying that requires a scientist very important for
so this is where things get a little bit and we will usually be just
say well you know normalized features some kind of way that my cousin told me
it's good idea and then i'm going to the euclidean distance in that space and
time to pretend that everything will be OK but seems a little bit unsatisfying summary
principles just arbitrary defines distance anyway even if you have
it could just be another problem which is
i do actually find the k nearest neighbors
the difficulty is that you know that people are using our huge hundreds of thousands
of the training examples and so you really need search through all of these examples
test site
and furthermore is really going to carry them around in your suitcase with you when
you deploy your classifier is OK
he said my classifier but you
x your hard drive has the training because of problem class
well there's also a very good idea so i would like to improve on these
things you like to somehow
dance in the middle
the first years
and it's very sparse on the outside and that's in that region
of the
visual cortex v one
like that in a way that makes this
sprints the central region that comprises the outside regions also noted is half circle here
affect the left right halves of two eyes are mapped to the left to right
and left halves your brain so they separated
so you actually first-half field in each of the brain
so the effect that if you look at this this image here which just to
zoom and has an idea there is that you see
this kind of mapping
so very very high central reservation
that's a much lower resolution outside
the effect that if you focus on the dot here
you should be able to have approximately the same ability to read and they all
of the letters
OK so that same year resolution near the centre
is much higher than your resolution outside is probably depends a little bit on distance
much of work for here the other thing is so that's the sound spatial sampling
density and the other thing is that there's multiscale in terms of precision in terms
of frequency
in the brain so you frequency response to spatial frequency is depends on something you
should see the kind of harm here
possibly it's amazing stuff that you could ignore
your i has a peak
spatial frequency
around here with the spirit of about three octaves so just don't see spatial frequencies
the outside that too low
they get removed by the system to to i don't know the resolution see
and then finally
some stuff about how
we kind of construct picture of visual world
OK so
you might think OK which take an image and then interpret the image does not
really like that human vision is very much driven by cycad so your eyes are
continually flipping from one part of the same to another analyzing it for a few
milliseconds and and the thing to another part of the same so
and that's used to together with very nonuniform spatial resolution of the i to get
a kind of zoom in on particular points of the scene with some kind of
context around it
so what you do is you construct your mental picture out of the series of
which you very piecewise kind of representation we don't have that impression when you're walking
around the world you don't have to stop and think oh gosh need to look
somewhere else you just have the impression of surrounding seen this this kind of uniform
and well-defined but you're your eyes not like that
OK have ha
right but first we have here this account course driven by ten to mechanisms they
tend to focus on things that are important in the scene
another thing that's actually took a the people want to understand is that even when
your eye is fixed on
o point
it's never stationary this ways doing a little bit of juggling
article microsd cards
that allows
the right to do better spatial resolution
typically if she in terms of images you can resolve out of pixel
but if you stop moving your camera a little that you can resolve maybe ten
pixel if you move it off by averaging
signals of the spatial positions so this gives you the factor of maybe five or
spatial acuity the otherwise would have
and it happens all the time is something something around actually does
so all of that requires some kind of temporal persistence and model what's going on
you can of integrate the of space to make into this model secondly i love
you that what you see is
basically driven by subconscious processes so stuff that you don't see like grouping together and
relevant elements completing contours removing shadows all this kind of thing gets done by your
and you just you just don't see that happens nevertheless
so you don't notice all these things
this just some examples cont conclusion conclusion is classic things so you'll see a nice
white triangle here
even though in fact there is no context given the triangle is just that they've
got some pieces of content here your brain completes to make these things here you'll
see there's actually two illusions here one
is that you will see that the cube can be very very easily was not
completed here the second cube so if you look at it for a few seconds
to find it tends to that
either this one will be at the front and this one will be back with
so your your brain simply accommodating to that signal
and when it gets used to it and decides going to flip because it needs
to find a different interpretation of something similar figure ground segmentations very dependent on the
exact context it's just the white and black transitions and changes your interpretation of what's
figure and ground here
again the level context is
but is about one point four one
so only
and i got only four
so i get sixty degrees
can only be approximated again by about one point seven
omega zero
and then i have only got five which is the last
so i get signed
seventy five degrees
that becomes
three point seven three
one point nine three
what i want to concentrate on because that's part of the demonstration
it's not so much on the meaning of omega zero
to some arbitrary
they i called
omega zero
but i want to concentrate his u
on the ratios of the higher frequencies below lower one
so i called the lowest one
omega one
simply called is omega what
if that one is only one
then the next one is one point nine three o one
not exactly
it is this one divided by four five one
the ratio now
the of the tree
and if i think this one divided by the one that i get to point
seven three
we've got one that i think the next one
i get three point three five
and the last one then
if three point seven three
so the bottom line is
that the ratio of these frequencies
not all very nice numbers as you may have expected
but the ratios are quite bizarre
o point nine three times higher than the lowest one two point seven three times
higher three point three five times higher than three point seven three
so the general
two that system
is the linear superposition of all these normal modes
the general solution
you give them very modest amplitudes
and you can choose
the amplitude of each one of them
that's effective let's say you're using c one c two c three c four c
and you also can give the initial velocities if you want to sort equals zero
they do not have to stand still
you have the choice to of course
so we can change the relative face
three to five
different modes
what i will do
it is i will to make life simple
i will generate all five normal modes for you
and i will start them off all at zero speed when i
so you the simulation
the the first one that i'm going to show you that is number one
now i'm going to show you number two
i want you to appreciate that if i showed you the superposition of one and
so i
also made in this mode in this mode
i started off at a certain position of these particles
and they start to oscillate in this mode and that money
the shape that i have never
become the same as it was
time zero
why is that
this letter also maybe you can write a hundred billion years you will never see
the station
i start with a certain shape
and will never ever
ever come back to that you why that
right at the site of fifty degrees is the killer
that's not the ratio
of two integers and therefore you will never get it back to the same position
made of approximately
but you never get it back
this demonstration is going to be
cocktail between
what do you see red because there's only one coming from this part
you bring red
well you see green here the only green because your brain
the green because there's no article caller coming
if i rotate it that this very fact
your brain will get so confused because they will see the caller coming from one
location all colors simultaneously
you see white light again
so that's what i
i will do next
and the first we get some light on that
this no make dark
the rooms not completely dark with almost dark
nelson then that very fast
and you will see that you have a new idea of colors going to fade
i'm going to call us anymore
which proves my point if you see colours from the same direction of the color
your brain
the brain state
white light
see that
this is not part of polarisation
this has nothing to do with polarisation
but i want you to understand
a lot of trouble
is a little bit
president except
that it doesn't have this shape
it is
he has this shape
different shapes
you can make the colors
separate articles can be composed columns and that's what's happening
with rain
so now
what i will do for you
i will make for use something like
it's not exactly right
like ring
and i will do it was one one
because if i made of reindeer twenty six one
you will never come back
we can do
so we have one one there are these
the glass sphere
and we're going to shine an enormous amount of light
right in your face
it's this one of
i will some of it will reflect on the back and we'll come back
you will see here
we ran on the outside
inside you will thank you see
it is indeed very similar
i can't
chinese light into your face
so i have to
the cover over it otherwise
will not come back either
and the the hospital
the light on this
screen will be extremely faint
what do you expect to use on one one
and that's face how much did you pay for this line
right can you can which forever
so it's going to be extremely faint
but it will be poor
and i will show you the four
along the arc
you can use your own arises
because once the light here
it comes back to you it loses the election
vision maybe not for one the percent all more
i'll give you thirty seconds for your eyes to get used to be
i don't do that you won't see anything because it's very thing
and then
i will
show you with my parameters
you are cured i can rotate around
and i can
just in the right direction killed light
of the art
related through
right so the first thing
your eyes have to get used to the dark
one is like there
two and off
give it a little bit of time
i for the video
it is
there is you're park
you see it
just so you can see here
so the x's are locations where i measure
namely the members of the
OK would be the covariance matrix and what you would assume is that you have
nonzero terms in the covariance
parts that actually share an edge
so let me just put another hot in here to make things will be easier
what you will get is that
in the covariance matrix and k
i would have nonzero term for the internet say that two and three
one two three four
five six
and so my covariance matrix so will have a nonzero terms between one and three
one between two and three one between three and four and so on
they can translate this directly into the matrix and do inference
people doing this often talk about cars gauss markov random fields
they write entire books about it
as if it were something very special and very different from everything else
which is that
so don't be scared somebody talks about it
all this does is it just means for many cases you can actually
get away with matrix inversion where otherwise you would have to the something expensive
so this is where my covariance matrix come from
so these these would be the voltage is that majoring here
but since my voltmeter is unreliable
so i go with my multimeter here
played in there and then i see
maybe this
two hundred and
fifteen volts
what i'm really observing
maybe next played in here i will get the difference
so why is this
he will be that
these locations will be there exists
the mean of y would be t
sorry sir sorry
of course
stewart was
paying attention to the told me that before the break
OK so
what is basic and
he actually would have a pretty good
the reason to assume some u
i could for instance assume that this is uniform at least if i have a
good network
and i would assume that this is just before the voltage
you can find in australia which i think at the moment is like two hundred
thirty watts
basically the victim you
what be just two hundred thirteen
two thirty
and so on and so on
maybe a slightly better assumption would be if this is where i think connect two
actually my
a power supply
well i could assume that maybe the will to a little bit lower they wouldn't
pick exactly to thirty but maybe over there have pick something like two twenty five
but again the surprise so you can always learn
but this is why you will get the covariance matrix
which has a nonzero terms all the way along the edges
so if you don't observe those variables
you look at the remaining covariance matrix this will actually make things correlate
because what happens is
we have basically
x well sorry
t minus mu
OK inverse
he wants me
so if you take a sparse matrix in inverted you will get things
so you get things feelings
which actually tells you
that you will get correlation between longer range ranges
now the nice thing of this piece here is
those of you who have fundamental analysis
you will know
the matrix with that sparse structure is very easy to solve
because you can basically to variable elimination by going for this is that these two
variables and you can eliminate for this it just pile of things that the aliens
as you go along
you can use exactly the same procedure two
deal with the inverse of this matrix
never even
in that case if you have such beautiful representation
right OK inverse explicitly
always deal with k inverse
through the implementation of an algorithm
because in this case actually solving
OK inverse times t minus mu
is an order of in of operation because the tree
whereas writing out that matrix explicitly will be in order for in square operations
so you're completely screwed if you actually in right that matrix out
never do that people will run out of memory for reasonable problems
there is a corollary to that in graphical models
and then you would have message passing so you will see exactly the same structure
game messages going all the way around
but the very same ideas
that you would get four
gauss in markov random fields he would have in general
except that the theme
variable elimination isn't quite that easy anymore because it's not all quadratic
that's really the only difference
the for instance win and was talking about message passing today
and particle filtering
i'll push on
with the case and notation reminder
we're gonna be using all
some of these guys now so
as well as what we used last time
we've got
the similarity
now came for me
it is three things it's a similarity matrix is a covariance matrix and its the kernel matrix
ages the what i
felt have the slides on this time last time i
i found them in this deck
they were in the wrong place so all
go through the centering matrix idea a little bit
and then the key thing is the sentence similarity
or kernel or covariance be used beef about follows a model you can baby's notation
and then we get at some point need the
the graph laplacian so will use alpha that's
so today is more about them
spectral approaches to dimensionality reduction we gonna pick up
where we left off last time
so just the
the slides i was missing where
these ones considered the matrix form the squared distance
so if you've got a few computing distances in data space
this is how you might write them in a matrix form
the diagonal the inner product matrix
as a vector that's what operation is a poster indicate
times the
the vector ones
minus two times in a product plus one times the diagonal any other way so this is
they from this part you get the centre while i transpose why i hear you
get the minus two why i transpose why jay
and here you get plus why jay transpose why jay
in your matrix
i don't know i know i think i've spoken to about not about this before
and then he feels like matrix things the less clear and i feel able clear
there you go
it's certainly much easier to do derivations on
and one other derivations which is the one i showed you last time
what happens when you send the distance matrix
so this centering operation the centering matrix has this form which we talked about last time
what this if you multiply this by on
the matrix why
you get why minus one overran times
why times one why times one just sums otherwise together
and then this one transposed maps back out again so just means you've got eight
why minus vector see this in matlab right you do this regret matter operation this
evil operation in matlab to send your data copy the mean down a hundred times
to avoid using a loop is matlab disgusting language on
hands this is the main affect the matrix where writing down this isn't how you should compute these things
obviously but it's a nice convenient way of writing nothing you're doing in matlab if
you subtracting the mean from the data and its
denoted in statistics age is called the centering matrix and when you multiply age
he decided these guys eliminates these two terms and just gives u
this why have why had transpose
so the centre square distance matrix is is closely related to the sentence similarity or kernel
so i want to use an example
so might think what all this distance is going about his a classic statistical example
when you're given distances and how you project them so
we redraw a road map a map from road distances
so what we're gonna have is using distances across europe and all we know is
city names and what the distance between
those different cities is yeah
so that we can guess squared distance matrix
we've got the distance between london and edinburgh
a number in paris
and in terms of road distance traveled
and you can
i've got some data
and then you could also know the actual location of these things so what you
can try and do it well you can visualize these distances and ideally they should
look something similar to the map of europe
what we do is we enter all road distances in the distance matrix we square directly using squared distances
and we convert to this similarity matrix a can told you about the convergence interpretation
but the outcome of the moment we converted the similarity matrix using this operation on
the distances
and then you have two times by minus two
and then you do the i can decomposition because we know that minimizes this entrywise
one number b
three for each
nine these seventy were seldom like much
and i can
work with those numbers and never made another function
but so that's really the
the idea is that the
everything now is seen in terms of those coefficients
and actually
it's that c
how would i
what is the relation between
what i produce
function one out of this function to give you an example so you where you
have some numbers
i suppose my function in one
a specific function
on tried
so suppose i want to come to take off just one interval
so all the time
also to one
one of the box
square wave here
like to produce
so would
one zero one suppose i would like to produce
there are one
how much
of the box
this where we should put it
to produce five
four of his
four is
one of the
right so you have no trouble to do that my point is
these numbers for what you could have
what you should could and should have done
to take the five three
send it through
you're from last time
so through this lowpass filter
it's not filter
so this one
one filter
and when have come out a member of those filters
well it's a very short signal we really really all zeros until
all zeros after
well four
so do you remember what
this is a very good
o thing to do
remember what comes out you know what's filter again for four
OK so i send signals through
and what what's in the
get out
the averaging filter takes so this filter takes half of the current
plus half of the previous
OK so outcome
i can mean always zero
and it'll keep everything was wrong
the first time it sees five averaging with this guy before so i guess what
we want to know more about this
that's it
the average three with five
for the we really want
however it is zero with three because one
so and then it's series of that so it's all
eighty five four that we really like three we really don't want to know this
is zero
but then you remember what the filter i did
downsample it to every other one
so it takes
pick the right one
throwaway way he
now down here of course is the difference in filter
take five minus over two
minus award two
you see
probably one minus one
three minus five or
so o
why am i getting
now let's assume the other case
with the constraint here is satisfied with the street
so this means
you back here
this means we have a point which is somewhere inside the correct area
and not even on the boundary
so it could be like this point here so its corresponding constraint is satisfied as
a strict inequality
and what i'm going to say now is that in this case the corresponding like
multiply it has to be zero
because otherwise the same arguments before
so this thing is positive and and
here we have minus but at the same time for i want to maximize
then the value that maximizes l is actually phi zero everything else would be suboptimal
so these points that lie
inside the allowed regions
they have to have a value of five which is zero
so this is
stuff like intuitive proof or intuitive argument
what's known as the KKT conditions kowalczyk and tucker conditions so that certain conditions about
these logos multipliers that hold true at the optimal solution
so the next step and
i hope you have you believe me that doing this thing here is a good
idea to maximize the respective wnb minimizing sorry minimizing with respect to WP maximizing with
respect to the other five
the next thing that people usually
two is a derived what's called the dual problem
eliminating the primal variables
in the way you can do this is that at the extremum
the derivative with respect to the primal variables vanish
this gives us two conditions
and we can use these conditions to eliminate the problem variables
so let's compute the derivative of l with respect to be
so this will give us some time depending on how to find and y i
y i multiplies be also
she gives us this equation here
likewise will take the derivative with respect to w gradient user vector
if we do this we get something here linear term in w and here we
get something with phi y i x i this is the product
so when you go through this he find this expression
so we substitute both of these things into the
like loss function
before i show you the result of this substitution let's take a little closer look
at the second equation from the last slide
is this equation actually tells us
not only how to eliminate w
from the
primal objective function
it also tells us all the solution of look like
so terms of the solution will be an expansion in terms of training points
multiplying with these not what multipliers and the training labels so this was plus one
minus one depending on the two classes this is a nonnegative numbers so
so we know already know the solution of the problem we we find one
is such that it's a linear combination of the training points
where the points of the positive class of nonnegative weights in the training points of
the negative class have on positive weight
because the weights could be zero and we also know when the weights are zero
remember from this argument here was saying if there a constraint which is trivially satisfied
strict inequalities of point which is easy which is inside the respective class then the
corresponding phi has to be zero so this means all the points that
my inside here at this point is this point of these points here
we'll have to wait zero in the solution
which makes sense if you think about it because
geometrically so we said we want to find a hyperplane that leads to the largest
margin of separation and i guess you can imagine that this point back here does
not carry any information about the position of this hyperplane so if we remove this
point from the training set solution wouldn't change so it doesn't contain information about the
solution therefore it also doesn't appear in the expansion of the solution
it's reassuring that this intuition is recovered by the
started in november and developing in nineteen ninety six and
it is a programme for analysis and visualisation of large networks
this is really important thing
that large networks can be analyzed with it because it does not support the algorithms
that are really time consuming because that what they would run too long
and the latest version of course it can be accessed
freely at this
this is just the set of real numbers
and they the same
OK so
large networks this means several thousands to several million years of vertices
what kind of networks that are usually analyzed pike are the
these are usually sparse networks that been that the
number of all lines is a lot less than
number of
what is the square
and what they are typically of that order are
of order and
times longer of
and these are just some of the networks that can be also accessed from
into from internet page of buying so there already in format and if i just
briefly go through so you know what these networks are about whether the smallest one
has almost three thousand vertices so we start this small
it's this one is the dictionary of
on what it is an online dictionary of library and information science
here the vertices are presented by
war and the lines between two words means that one word can use
is explained by the other by also by the other work
so we're in the explaination of the first word there is
this second work including
then there are some citation networks for example this one is the situation of
self organizing maps of the people who are who are working on self organizing maps
than the other citation would be from computational geometry and this one from US patents
well i can i can explain this one a bit more what does this mean
this means that we have four vertex vertices we have patterns and art between two
patterns well are between two patterns mean that the first what excites the other one
then we have class
so the vertices would be atoms then english words for example
we can can different words and links between them would be if they are synonyms
of each other or something like that
then internet of course here the vertices would be removed routers
and for world wide web the more distant vertices would be
would be
websites and of course the
links would be
here are links
and then this one is almost the same but this is the largest one slovenian
internet and this was used by
gregor petritsch also in his work in his doctoral dissertation
so it's
he also collected the whole network
OK so what kind of data types the despite support are despite
one has well
by then
like operations are performed are the first one with the network of course if there
if there's we're we're talking about network analysis and the second one the partition the
partition east what we mean by that is
we can divide the
but this is of the network on subsets that excludes
on on different subset
none of
each vertex
only in just in one of the subset
then we have vectors
this would be the
vertex properties
so each
can has can have
number attached to it
then cluster will be just
a part of the partition so
or maybe one or maybe made
more of these subnetworks the permutation
it will be just
that every vertex has of of course again
number attached to it but there are these numbers are all different so the permutation
is normally used when we want some kind of sorting out of vertices
so each one has its
and how hierarchy is rarely used but is used for example when we do hierarchy
sorry hierarchical clustering
and the something more about five
well i'm going to also show how this help i looks like
this is
it looks
so here
we have the network and this is the list accumulator where all the networks with
that we have here we don't have any network selected of course but if we
had the some that was selected they would appear here in this list
and here the partition permutation cluster hierarchy and vector so
it's of the data set that i described before
and of course IT operations are also
are also here will depression can be used on different types of this
data types and of course there are there are
which is a conducting
it closed
the cut
you see open it just
allow you to look inside but it is
close all
and there are some negative charges here
and positive charges in the foreground which you don't see the red field lines
come from positive charges and up on the box
and the negative field lines go from the box
two the negative charge
there is clear polarisation
the box itself is neutral i started his neutral box
because of this electric field they get polarization i end up with negative charge on
the box here
only on the outside
the positive charge on the box here only on the outside
electric field is zero
no charge
due to this crazy electric fields
the free moving charges in the conductor
i will rearrange themselves
in such a way that the electric field is zero everywhere in the conductor
it is zero inside
the cavity
and that the close
the integral of of e dot tl is zero everywhere
if these are
static fields
and this
clearly impossible for us
however calculate
how to charge configuration at the surface will have to be in order to meet
all those conditions
can do this
and it can do it extremely fast will being all the laws of physics
it could very quickly passed starts here and minus charge there
make sure there is no charge on the inside of the surface
make sure that the electric field is everywhere zero inside and in the box
and also make sure that the integral you don't you have a zero everywhere in
and therefore the box and everything inside becomes an equipotential so it also arranges matters
sort of the field lines never intersect with the box always perpendicular to
all of that is down
in almost no time at all
by nature
it's an amazing thing
this happens and something that as i said it would be impossible for us
calculate because the field configurations
are extraordinarily difficult
so if you're inside his metal box
no matter what happens on the outside
you would be electrically isolated
from the outside world you wouldn't notice that there is a strong electric field outside
know what you notice that people are trying to
charge up your house
recall that
electrostatic shielding
and we give them the name
that house use would be called a
faraday cage called after the great
physicist fire they will learn a lot more about him during this course
before i demonstrate this
i want to address the issue
which is related to the problem two one
which is your next assign
and i want to urge you
make myself no solution but i want to urge you to start working on that
assignment this weekend not next week this assignment and not
just baby sign these MIT assignments are you going to put in a lot of
to do them so please start this weekend not to do me a favor but
do yourself a favor
let's talk about problem to one know i will help you with that problem
to one
i said several times
that is not possible to get the electric field inside the hollow conductor
i suppose i go inside the conductor
i go inside there
and i put sneakily chart in my pocket
and i sit inside the new clothes
there's the charge inside nothing you can do
and it is the charge inside
is electric field
so now we have a situation
since it is post
valentine's day my heart has evolved into a sphere again
now we take a spherical
this is solid material
and somehow i'm sitting inside here
with a charge
plus q
make it mine is if you want to that's exactly the problem to one is
now clearly
there is positive charge inside
so clearly there has to be an election
but the electric field inside the conductor
these electric field anywhere year
must be zero
it is not zero electrons will keep moving until it is
sort of conducting material itself has no electric fields
what does that mean now
with respect to any charts on the inside surface
now they must be charged only insights
because now
if i made this my gaussian surface
which is now a spherical surface closed surface
miss the girl says
that the closed surface integral of e dot the age of this surface must be
zero because the electric field is zero anywhere
that's the same as all of the charge inside divided by actually non-zero
so does charge inside must be zero
and it can be no charges in the conductor itself
the negative charge must know
on the inside of that
so that the net charge inside
this surface is zero
now we do get
charge on the inside and how much charge you get on the inside exactly minus
q sort of the sum of the two is zero
now this conductor
originally was neutral
it had no net charge
on the surface of the conductor
we must now seek charged prosecuted
because the minus charge on the inside
came from the inductor itself
so the sum must be zero
so now you get a curious situation that the prosecution charged insights
which creates in field inside
creates negative charge on the inside the same
the magnitude and opposite in sign
and plus q charge
on the outside
and the electric fields they're very complicated
electric fields
i to put him in
i would imagine that this charge q is closer to this world and this will
that the negative charge here
will be larger in density than there
really an induction effect
the negative charge wants to go to this place that's really what's happening
and so since this charge is close to this wall
that will it will be able to attract more electrons
one question to ask ourselves
it is what is engineering
how do define now what is engineering
the definition of to use is one put forward by steve centre you are one
of our professors who now what attire
he defined engineering to be purposeful use of science
right so then
what is external to about
so six
this course in engineering
and i like to use it level two
the gainful employment of maxwell's equations
many of you have seen maxwell's equations before most of you should have
and their hearts
six two is all about teaching you how to simplify our lives make things simple
so we can gainfully employed maxwell's equations gainfully employed
the facts of nature to build very interesting systems
so let me show you how the transition is made
so while the world around us
so we make some observations in nature we make measurements and we can write down
a large tables of measurements
so for example
we can take objects and
measure the voltage across the
and look at the resulting current through the element so we may end up getting
a bunch of values such as
so start of life making measurements on what exists
i mean but the tables
we could directly these tables
and based on the observation these tables you could go ahead and very interesting
engineer interesting systems that help us out in day-to-day life but i think it will
be hard to imagine having to
resort a set of tables to
do any kind of useful work
so what we do is engineers
is the first there
eleven of abstract
we look at all the data and so how
an abstraction
such that we can simplify or much more succinctly put
in a simple equation a simple statement what these numbers are telling us
OK so for example a physics laws
so laws of physics for example
or simply abstractions abstractions
so these sets of numbers can be quantified by law for example
these equal to i what this current
relates to the resistance of the object
so the musical i is a law
succinctly described the sort of experiments
OK a and places a large number of tables with a very simple
you could call this lot
you could call it an abstraction
because i see a lot of physics
call the mass fractions of physics if you like
there are maxwell's equations
and so on and so forth
so this is what it is
OK this is out there
OK and along an abstraction describe
well the properties of nature the see it in some succinct form
if you want to go and build a useful things
we could take the abstractions of text my maxwell's equations and going about things
but it's hard it's really really hard
and what you learned in
this place is all about simplifying things a complicated things believe that fraction simplified things
so that we can build useful system
OK even in six table two restart life by
making a huge leap from maxwell's equations
very popular very very simple laws
again we show that lead to make today
so the full set of
the first fraction we layer is called the lumped circuit abstraction
and once again abstraction
what we do is
because of simplifications that allows us to view a set of objects
the discrete or lumped elements so we may have to define now
water sources
well defined resistors defined
capacitors and so on
and i'm going make the jump and show you how to make the jump in
a few minutes
so no
on that sort of abstractions within the layer another abstract layer and we call that
the amplifier abstraction
OK to remember
if you actually down and dirty the sitting probe measuring objects and billiards stables
the abstract things in the simple laws and life for the better
then we show you can abstract things further out and the discrete objects
and and then you can build an even more interesting components all amplifiers
and the playing on the amplifiers fires
so these little red rose
they choose
all that we have some
when corresponds
this strategy
like squared
there that's were
it's not for
so is
so you can
seems like
so w
this means
also we
you can see the difference between
they're all
a lot of them
the reason for
we have
so what
the need
o ratio
well so much the ricci flow
you some
he he
one of
all of us
this is the
you want
let me
all of the walls
you think of it as well
all the
thirty keep
i think she is
so what
but in this distribution was
it is the or
is it the place
you want see the
is easy to
it is
so the initial
and for
so you are in this range and the
i don't know
what is the expectation of the vision
the first one
he was the
this is the
i see
that's what lost
what you get
as non proper nouns
i mean cocaine
so i started some cook
how to
you can also use cope with a lower case e
to mean
like something called
four serving of such drink
as the sun
that's OK
so that's how the notation works
OK so
the notation works for single words
but what about phrases
like clinton joke or joke about clinton
when you have something like that you use either multiwordstring are compound
string depending on whether the head of the phrase
his initial or final
so if the
head of the phrase is
at the end
which normally is an english
you use multiwordstring
and if had this at the beginning
then use compoundstring
clinton joke
the head
he is joe
rather than clinton
and you can tell that
by thinking about
how how to make the plural
of this
plural clinton joke is clinton jokes clintons
so that
head of the
well i joke about clinton you would add the as to choke
so that means the joke is the head of the phrase
takes a list of
here but it's just a list of strings and
a lexical words
which is going to be the head
and part of speech for the word
the meaning
clinton joke is represented with multiwordstring
first arguement is the list
the string
followed by jokes the were
this is the head of the phrase
we want the company
version of just the word
and denotes joke about find bill clinton
you could
potentially infer this lexical entries
it happens to be stated
so right because
the plural is clinton jokes we know that
joke is the head of the phrase
compoundstring is
very similar to multiwordstring but for convenience
the word which is the head comes first
and then
the second argument is the list of string
again but now
because i'm on that side the thing i need to plug in the other forms
nine six two
and that's going to give us two
that the left and right limits and this is one little tiny subtlety and almost
the only thing that i needed to really pay attention to a little bit right
is is that this
we did not need
you need x equals zero
in fact i never even told you what f of zero was
if we stick it in
we could stick in OK let's say we stick it in
on one
on this side let's let's make it b
that it's on this site so that means that this point is in
this point
his out
so that's a typical notation
this little
open circle this close dot
for when you
include the so so in that case
the value of f of x happens to be the same as its right hand
namely the value is one
and not too
so that's the the
the first kind of example questions
so now
our next job
introduce the definition of continuity
so that was the other topic here
so we're going to find
at x is zero mean
that the limit
of f of x
as x tends to
is equal to that
so the reason why i spend all this time
paying attention to the left and the right and so on and so forth focusing
is that i i want you to pay attention from one moment to what the
content of this
of this definition is
what it's saying
is the following so
it has has at various ingredients here so the first one is the limit
it the
and what that means is
that there's an honest limiting value both from the left and right
and they also have to be the same
right so that's
that's what's going on here in the second
property is that after that zero
well defined so i can be in one of these situations where i but i
haven't even specified what the big zero is
and there are equal
so that's the situation
again let me emphasise
a tricky part of the definition of the limit
this side the left hand side
is completely independent is evaluated by a procedure which does not involve the right hand
side these are separate things
this one is to evaluate it
you always
the limit point
so that if you like a paradox because it's exactly the question is is it
that if you plug in a zero you get the same answer as if you
move in the limit
that's the issue that we're we're considering we have to make that distinction in order
to say that these are two
other otherwise this is just tautological makes it's very little it doesn't have any meaning
but in fact it does happening because one thing is evaluated separately with reference to
all the other points
and the other is evaluated right
but the the point in question and indeed
what these things are
are exactly the easy linear
that's exactly what we're talking about here they are the ones
you can evaluate this way
so we have to make a distinction in the these other ones are going to
be the ones which we can't
these are the
the nice ones and that's why we care about and why we have a whole
definition associated with
all right
so now so now what's next twelve
i need to
give you a
a little too or very brief tour of the zoo of
what are known as discontinuous functions
so sort of everything else that's not continue
the first example here
but let me just write down here is is jump
so what jump discontinuity b well we actually already seen
the jump discontinuity
is the example that we had right there this is when the limit
from the left
left and right
OK so that's
that's the
as in the example
right in this example
the two limits one of them was one
one of them was too
so that the jump discontinuity
this kind of issue
whether something is continuous or not is
may seem a little bit technical but
but it is true
that that people have worried about a lot the
palmer who was a professor at MIT when he
did his work for the nobel prize in economics
i was interested in this very issue
of whether stock prices of various kinds are continuous from the left right in a
certain model
and that was a very serious issue
in developing the model that
priced things that are hedge funds use all the time now
left and right really
can mean something very different
i in this case left is the past
and right is the future
and it makes a big difference whether things are continuous from the left and continues
from the right
right is the true that the point is here here somewhere in the middle somewhere
that's a serious issue
the next example
that i want to give you is a little bit more subtle
it's what's known as the removable
and i want to update that number
in the light of
the data of collected so i will the data and then c
what does that tell me about theta it update what i believe that the college
this is the posterior distribution center given the data
it turns out
this idea is very closely related to the likelihood of idea
so it's that we wait the likelihood by this but subjective
probability distribution
so that's the way we actually do that way we get from the
initial belief
the belief after the the data is multiplied by the likelihood and then rescale to
make sure that
the probability that one
the proportions add up to one side and the way that you do that is
you just integrate
the constant
and the reason i wanted to mention this is as well as being
because the rest of the talk about i will come back to this but people
will come back to it later in the course
but but this this is important because this gives you away
to think about automated data collection
many of these systems are out there
to for a statistical model to the data take
i haven't got time to
i use method that requires you to
he refitting the model over and over again
this however
gives a mechanism for saying
this is what i think is going on about the in the model of the
world and then i got some data
and that updates
my belief that the world would come to an automated data collection
then if i've got a model that the next there something to data comes in
i can apply this procedure i don't have to do this just once i can
i guess data update my original belief to this
well i got that if i get some of something about that
i can you have some more data
i can apply this procedure so this is what i think now
the database we now think this
so then
this page goes back into their and it's more data do this trick again and
again and again and again
whereas if you say something like
a classification trees oates
what was called induction trees i think in the book
in that situation and it's very difficult if somebody if you in models thing that's
so if you some more data
it's not that easy so they can model
what you have to what tend to have to do is to incorporate the data
in back into the main dataset and rebuild the model from scratch was saying here
as we have no way of
holding on to model and then i'd least basically we have an automated
update method
or so not a dating is built into the whole idea here that's that's what
we're doing is saying
that's what i think i remember all that that belief based on some more like
i get some data
so that's appealing if we've got an automated data collection so that's what the reason
why things should be in here because i think in the long run this is
where a lot of data mining might end up if it's using any statistical is
the model
because this is going to make it feasible
OK and the last little bit don't to
so shown here is
the primary use that we're going be
making a living out of thought that mining is
the statistics is we build model we try to make predictions from it
OK so
and let's say that is build models to describe some function that we don't know
that's what estimate this function f and we have
well first of all the
i had so we build the model
and these are predictions as heart to the prediction of fx
if we want to know how good the model is
that we would look at what's the difference between
the truth
and the model's prediction of what happened
however we don't really know the truth best known for exercise all i want to
know is
we can look at what's the difference square to make it always positive and then
look at what is the average of that that will become the mean squared error
and we might want to use the mean squared error to try
work out what's going on with the models
if this is one of the things that the early days of say no networks
where problem because
what you find is very bright star
it makes sense to two bits one is called by us and that's the difference
how far you ask
systematically with this
and the variance is supposed
the natural variability
well into the model is that the variance is
the bias is
government the bias is how wrong he model
that's not what put it
so if if the behaviour between two variables should be quadratic curve and if a
straight line so it then you have a bias in your model because the model
is wrong
but they also have variance because even when you get to say that the quadratic
curve is what you put in there you find the data doesn't say that onto
the quadratic actually very very lucky
so the variance to be taking account of the
basic variability in the data
and the bias is that you've got the model wrong and both measures of how
far fewer
so so this was the city's main square is based on
the message here
what's the matter
if you think about the bias
but if the bias is
how do you model if you you're potential lots of models very flexible
you're going to manage to reduce the bias
because if
even if you say you have a quadratic is the chance relationship if you it's
a a tenth degree polynomial
and the answer is no so in fact i wasn't assuming normalisation of this
i was only assuming that that fight times q not i was normalizable i never
had to assume that if i was normalizable
nor that i have to send after lives was normalizable
that's right
so if you look at all my equations i never have to and never compute
the moments of just firefighter by itself
i always compute products of things
which by construction will be will be normalized
so of course initially from reviewers right
here's here's more detailed comparison
well i'm showing the
computation time versus the air
of different approximation for the clutter problem here one then is a picture of john
twenty points from the model
and here i drew
on the right-hand side to two hundred points from
and the the the real mean was two
the way you read these curves is
each iteration of the p gives you an estimate so i can always stop BP
after say one iteration two iteration to get an estimate and so the blue EP
curve there is showing what you get after every after every iteration
and similarly we get a curve out of the past method variational bayes because again
you could stop them early and get a good answer
i'm also showing the result from importance sampling gibbs sampling
again were after every sample you look at what is the quality of the answer
and so on the left curve showing how well you estimate posterior mean as you
saw before he has a much better result interestingly enough also get a very fast
circuit the compare amount time as competing plants that are very short bounds
on the third iteration gets it gets closer to the posterior mean but in practice
often moves back away from the posterior
that can certainly happen right is just an iterative fixpoint algorithm similarly gives sometimes gets
closer to the posterior mean moves is away taking samples and averaging
i have and i have an average the results over many problems which is so
usually you see averages over many many problems you see these nice smooth curves here
i'm showing it for one particular instances all the noise inherent in it
OK so right that that's just the the dynamics of the of the procedure if
it goes towards the towards the correct answer and then maybe overshoots considered to get
OK so
so what i'm comparing two years the exact
posterior mean not not the target value the album is trying to get out which
is which will be different each of the able cases
right so interesting thing to notice on this plot is that as they go from
twenty point two hundred points
the deterministic methods possibly being EP suddenly get very good i mean that the accuracy
is very high
i the right to the people
vertical scales the things of the these these methods have suddenly become practically p is
not the time minor sixth whereas the sampling methods are essentially the same air
as it did in twenty one case
and the reason for that
is that when you have more data the posterior becomes more and more gas sincere
assumption makes more and more sense so all of the these deterministic methods get better
that sort of a nice property all deterministic inference methods which is something that is
don't have so if you think about it the something that is generally don't benefit
from the fact that you're posteriors
is especially calcium
i mean the benefit from there being one more than two
but if you have one mil which is becoming more and more gas your something
that isn't going to suddenly become that the
it very very well that's right here
these were
well that gas property would be the same
even in our dimensions
here we like
that to
this is goal
so four
what we get
the results the
all will be so first of all these results are not really based on the
dimension of the problem so you you get results like this even if you make
even if you make the clutter from high dimensional so i have a version of
the core problem which is we have
OK dimensional gaussians which is observed with noise and so on and you can run
all these organs on new music exact same curves out when you're on the k
dimensional very it really the the difference in performance comes down to
the shape of the posterior
really what it comes down to so if you have a multivariate gaussian posterior
then deterministic i'm going to work very well
compared to sample one
that's that's really what it comes down to
this is
you know you user
in the evening when he
yes in fact variational bounds even more flavor
yes that appears that clear
why did i mean expectation propagation
why because there because it extends belief propagation
minus one so the question is how do you find these weights so you've got
this setup and you've got a linear algorithm where you're multiplying two in the inner
product to find the answer and then you thresholding it too
give an answer as to what the class the data point is so his algorithm
i'm not sure about initialisation perceptrons how people do that but i just came up
with the initialisation of my
there is an algorithm for finding the weights
so select random data points you've got some data set of points you just choose
one data point around
and they use you ensure that point is correctly classified by setting these weights
two whatever the label is
times x
whatever the input was
OK so why does that insurance classified because that ensures correctly classified because basically
thing is the sign of w transpose x which if we substitute values for w
in why then that this gives us the sign why i find x transpose x
i now that is always going to be positive x transpose x i
so basically this is just the sign why i so it's the late so that's
the way of ensuring some kind an algorithm and the way i'm inventing algorithms i'm
well i that this
i'm trying to go through a process of inventing is if i'm inventing it and
initialisation ensuring the initialisation sets a random data point classifiers that the point correctly
now i'm going to iterate because other points on classified correctly and what i'm going
to reiterate its
a misclassified point for getting growing k i remove that they to move that section
so taken new misclassified point right
so now we've got some other misclassified points and what we do is we had
so this thing we set to here we add some portion of this to our
existing weight
so we basically train existing weight and then this is the portion we call this
the learning rate
and then some proportion of this y i x we add it now
the point in doing this is if they this argument here still holds this number
is large enough
what will happen is will be back to this situation this term will dominate if
this learning rate is large enough yet so there's obviously if we make a really
large learning rate will classify the new data point correctly
now we we
we don't want to go
just classify the new data point correctly and ignore the old one so we find
some balance where we reduce this learning rate is level so we got some combination
of the data points
and by doing that this be this new data point might be correctly classified all
the decision boundary will move towards that and then we'll repeat this until there's no
misspecified points are going to little demo of that
if i can see it correctly
iteration one with a simple dataset
and what we're going do is we select a data point for initialisation and then
what we do is
we for the first iteration assume that these are initialised first iterations we say the
way they we set the weight vector to that data point
multiply by one and this is the positive this is the positive class this is
the negative class so what that means is that actually we say that weight vector
to exactly the data point and this is a common way of showing decision boundaries
you show the line of decision and then the weight vector is always a normal
direction to that line in this case pointing at the data point we selected so
that they point will now be correctly classified by guaranteed by the initialisation of the
other thing is of course it is also correctly classified bunch other points because in
the simulation but there's things incorrectly despite all these are now being said to be
positive and all these are being sent to be negative in fact only these data
points positive so we now find
incorrectly classified data points
we've got a current weights
but incorrect classification we adjust the weight vector with the new data points we add
that proportional
of the new data point now because if you look at where the vector is
from the origin so i purposely chose the decision boundary to go through the origin
so this works you can see the vector this data point here basically is a
vector pointing in this direction from the origin so when we had that that new
data point we can add some components of that that
to this point here
and so we'll see a new decision boundary points in this direction
so actually flips around and now
there was
partial components that
original that being added here we're now pointing in this direction OK so the you
incorrectly classified data points i think there is green one it should be i can't
see from this angle
so one of the negative data points is is now
the incorrectly classified data points on the positive side of the decision boundary to be
the same thing again but this time we're gonna be subtracting because the sign of
the data point is negative
so this sign of this fifty eight data point is negative sort subtracting that vector
component of only a little bit of it and now all the data is correctly
classified so we don't
that's actually a remarkably fast classification algorithm for data sets of this type
it is true that the perceptron algorithm does tend to converge very quickly if the
data is fully separated and not going to talk about what happens if the data
is separated but basically this proves about
if you set up your learning rate if you reduce your learning rate
at a certain what value you will converge towards something in the limit of large
data which is the optimal
decision boundary so i think the really nice thing about this algorithm is the
i mean i think rosenblatt book in nineteen sixty three but he was using in
the fifties and he was head of course on how the brain works where he
used to sit on
good question
not what want not really equipped to ask answer that i had this diagram in
so it's the threshold like that
one of the things in machine learning that one of the things in
and it's community that we knew
is that if you could draw your algorithm with the circle
and a bunch of interconnecting lines
that meant it was like the brain
the idea was that you had
you're in
x one x two x three
w one w two
w three
and then you have this was input from another neuron
or cents so in this case it's obviously this is
i mean we did multi-layered perceptrons as well and they were quite effective algorithms but
this in this case you have to think of it some sort of a same
if i have a a set of entries that has been corrected
at random locations of positive fraction of entries have been corrupted
random locations and i solve this problem with lambda equals one of the square root
of the dimension so is no cross validation or anything of this nature i just
take long that equals one of the code of the dimension
then the theorem says
that with very high probability and the probability is over the distribution
of the locations of the errors then this solution is exact that is i recover
the lower income one exactly and recovers sparse company exactly this is something that when
i look at it i almost find impossible
i prepare low rank matrix i give it to you you look at a lot
of entries
you corrupt them
you give it back to me
well not to meet somebody else because we already know what prepared
use of this optimisation problem depends on nothing so use so nuclear norm plus one
of his code of dimension times one of the
and you will find exactly what you did
all the entries you've touch how you touch them and so so you recover the
low rank structure and it's an exact recovery that has nothing to do
the exact amount of what the magnitude of the loan companies and no matter what
the magnitude of the sparse there is no tuning parameter is in this thing just
just the way it is
so we seem to
one way have missing data the other one is more complicated because now we have
corruption so in the missing data world is good because
what you've got is you've got an entry and then you have to predict missing
entries but you know these entries including the corrupted world you never know when you
look at the data point to good data point about data point you have to
it for those of you know about cutting theories like you have erasures here and
errors here and it's much harder to correct errors than to deal with the rangers
OK so
it's information theoretically harder so if you look at this so what we've done is
we've run the algorithms what you see on the right hand side is uses the
rank of the low rank component divided by the dimension
and on the white ox y axis uses the sparsity
that is the number of the fraction of entries have been corrected
then each pixel on these images lot of experiment a great example is the experiment
which method works half the time
a white pixels one hundred percent of the time a black pixel it works zero
percent of the time what you see here is used in a very sharp phase
transition between the regime was the algorithm is perfect and the regime in which it
fails miserably
OK but the regime in which person is very interesting so let's be in his
white region for example is the rank is the total dimension divided by
ten so and over ten what this plot indicates that can corrupt thirty percent of
the entries
and it's harmless
k is the rank decreases two
five percent and over twenty
i can corrupt almost half of the entries in is to harmless
OK in the matrix completion world the region where things go better is much larger
because it's here now this is the fraction of missing entries so the right region
is much larger because it's much easier to deal with missing entries and was corrupted
so i'm writing a bit of time because i want to show you some numerical
i want to mention this very important paper by alan willsky and his colleagues introducing
deterministic results of very beautiful piece of work and just like as matrix completion is
this robust PCA generates a lot of interest and since then a lot of people
in machine learning and statistics have been able to even improve on these results
that's a lot of activity at the moment by several teams around the world getting
better and better results
OK in fact the last result i want mentioned but i don't want to take
too much of your time says well you could tie them together you could have
both missing and corrupted entries and you run the optimisation algorithm and you
back out the
this is one source of variance the p three is different in each
and another strong source of variance is a vision for
from the visual areas
and so this is not
and important
on the then
what what is noise does and how it has to be
the accounted for the classifier
so i
this is artificially generated from
not so much the better
so we have
two electrodes have CP set in the two conditions target and nontarget
so the very nicely separated because there
quite clean
but we have seen that one source of noise for example comes from the
i've written from from all that
no i added some
to this
q data some
the result from all that this two different factors
so this is neurons effect of fuzzy set the
if c two
and then we get this plot
while the classification linear classification and fifteen percent of their on the the second case
thirty seven percent of our own
in this case you know the source of
the noise
so if we had this disturbing channel
o that
that's introduces noise and weak classifier
in this region then again we have zero
sixteen percent
and so it is important message here is that we need is always that channel
centre-forward classification also
in itself has no
discriminative information
so the the mean for the two conditions and all that is the same for
both classes
nevertheless we needed for classification so therefore you see that
in this case got my first one where we only use the difference between the
two means that the classifiers
this does not account for for this this noise
so this
the difference of the mean whatever the weight zero for the channel of that and
would not make use of only if e
i have to log gamma
we account for the noise and therefore
from the topography maybe you would like more this small theatres
but i hope i convinced you that is more complicated
important to account for the noise
only this page you can cancel out
noise from other anecdotes
here see the error rates and you see
in this case the law come about non-zero gamma
what is it
the best
now i hope hopefully
convinced that it
the shrinkage is the
the nice thing about
so far is problem that this the selection is time consuming this first validation but
recently there was an analytical way to calculate optimum government was published and we pointed
to this technique
because i am a part of
you don't
so this is the setting is again we
feature vectors estimate of the mean
and this
covariance matrix and we want to
five best shrinkage
to get improved covariance matrix
and so
use something that is
quite using the which is the hinge loss
so now
so we should relax our goal
and we
is that of
OK so let's look at this
graph here we have a marginal
or some
classified u
on some example YX
so what we know
is that
there's a mistake one imagine walking scholars
there's a mistake when the when the function is when imagining negative by definition
a mistake here
my mistake here
this is a lot of being a
the mistake indicator function on the margin
and now we want to use something which is a convex linear piecewise linear approximation
of it
which is the hinge loss
which is a bit
so this is i call it
this is the graph of
the graph of the function
between zero and one minus y
keep in the same year
new acts
we take also did not we
one minus one u
he plus the math which i also did not there
difficult if i love
three keys to score the guy against which comparing
using this hinge loss is that of the
of the mistake indicator function
and being these conflicts
you have you seen this is an upper bound
this is a convex upper bound on the step function this is going to be
if score my you with this means a lot
and grateful
penalized more
the guy on the right side my competitor
that's why you that is not the way to be able to prove things
indeed this is pretty much in
and nothing important to not if you score
was of classifier with the hinge loss then the length of your matter
the length of humans so let's look at a little bit more to the first
of all you know they're not just that being gay when the margin
is smaller than one and opinion
and now so
you could be have zero into laws should never mind in at least one of
each example
so for is that now
suppose that
assume that this is a sphere is
and that so you have unit norm x seven hundred
if you want
and you have some unique or x
which part of the data
so you don't
with positive label
it is classified correctly but it's not enough for the about to be zero
you you have to be long enough so they
this is enough
so that the projection of u onto way it's little like this one
fine but if you take x like these
and then the
tangent here you see the who was who was trying to learn more
a lot more so that the projection onto the effect will have my mac imagine
so that the projection of x this one
so now we need to continue you
so too
so to make it achieve margin of the