very strong levels of urgency
this is the time when was
for forty years and rediscovered in the twentieth century but dropped by team us around
the world and people resources with the same genetic analyses on the fly that they
want make the end of the cold fathers opportunities so what they do is basically
the these flies and they
this the definition
the future b
it how they
and they also what makes them
some to general be
trees of this analysis
it is think of him as got the call of the eyes and you can
see that when you lies like is most likely true
so this is the only thing i was basically assume that the organisms not just
five years
and then
constraints we're going to go deeper
one of the those
so twenty four nineteen forty four
someone called ivory
with the second game show here
in fact the instances of you
link that is there is what is the support of
apparently so this is a list about the DNA molecule with
this is
because of microscopic cancer cells so you can see that was able to prove that
this morning
this information is presented long duration
and the information to to make something work
then in nineteen eighty three
so need more than these point
the main goal is is really more like this is this is greater than fifty
the guys this is one of the best teacher and then back to the old
the vic what's discovery data
and the structure of the article called DNA these are all the same as the
police and was big big news because need to solve the mystery of the whole
but not really clear what it was and we knew it was communication us here
was made and it became more information it would start with money who sequence
and i think we be
it this is a particular
the discovery binary called the genetic code so this explains
we will show going later i would like to extend our information DNA
it is used to make something because we knew that you know what is in
store information transmitted generation to derive and the goal was to keep the article
that your teacher to contact information
these things called genes
in seventy seven the centre was really good because you can is the number of
discovery i mean crystallinity of sequencing sequencing is who used which is
which refers to the
the information given
and it contains information
but can be written sequence
and sequencing is really
discover the there something to use it to read the DNA of
OK for
short strands of DNA and computer started to twenty get because as early as nineteen
eighty two that have been created to go to bed was created this this was
pretty store
the sequences of DNA that we query these sequencing technologies so the beginning it was
a small database contains few
hundreds of thousands of sequences in between
in nineteen eighty in today
the technologies to improve the and the number
sequences dramatically improved increases
so i don't know the that contains something right
on the other fifty million sequences for all
fifty billion
that is used to increase pensions is increasing this is a
one of the
o point where countries are starting to to play a role in the so that
we we could distort information
it turns out
books anymore
then the way the
the case of the twentieth century so you this
one the sequencing of the human genome so what is that
well we we knew that all organisms contain DNA contains some information to make the
organisms and in the nineteen eighties there was a big part of saying well let's
try to look at our own to sell to look at
how you manage what human it's paid off to reserve units in
and it was a big technical challenges because a lot of money but it was
in two thousand three there was the addition of the human genome
at some point this must be and his
long period because you know since the beginning people discover that there is lots of
charity there was some information in DNA and so know we we you can download
neural letter
the sequence of the human which is supposed to be so it was supposed to
be installed all the energy in some sense if you have a single
vision of as you like DNA is the programme and then
this is a computer
parameter something because of was that
i received five course but you want to be the program director enough you
so of course for is not so simple
we have the program but was that everything is not written in the programming was
computer is not so simple
but these things because we have everything we wanted but you know we need to
analyse it and this is where
the mathematics computer science of the role to play because now there is one of
the two sequences
well it's not just what some some empirical knowledge is organising
so today one thousand six i would say that the transition shop of course we
are at the beginning of boston meteorite where you're right where we need to to
analyse the data in which there are many more coming from this which is project
OK so i want to make sure that some of you might not know about
the DNA proteins genes know very little about the
molecular biology
just to give you a more precise picture of what these concepts are
what is what one of the things that
so i will start with very things first the first thing here that everything was
be alright but only things he is very dangerous
no relation
i'm not
there you know
there are
a lot too
and is
and we're all this
our goal is
of the
and there
is that easy
same this is
all of these
for moment
i mean field
yes you
in the
we well
i think is
five points
in the end
why not
you need make sure that
it is we should not
and a
well known
prior work
because you want to do this estimation that's what you want to do it sequentially
in time on this important for many applications in particle filtering like this kind of
talk in public
each time you and your acceleration of trying to approximate
according to the net playing each time you have new measurements you want to add
a new knowledge about
position the time you don't want
you're not interested in estimating
according for the target for what
except of acceleration you start giving you know if you want to take your knowledge
about about
so not mathematically also there's no problem
well essentially there very simple
relation between
the distribution of it in price at time n minus one
of the distribution of input by
this is again given by the very
very important to share the joint distribution of time and it's going to short time
and and minus one
times y
of the state i and even my book
but i like your salvation
basically what i and divided by the predictive
of your television while you posted nothing complex about
all in parties
i will often write in the following slide this fallacious photos we
basically this
which is independent of x and together with a set of first time
is simply the proportional to the first time i just want
but i do
so is that these things
where well i was going to do it is very simple
a letter at the end of
you're right really is to use the right thing penalty do which is that there
not a call to a divided by b
it not difficult then you know that
he of the and it is the eighth divided by p of
you that the numerator and the denominator
is very simple
then you remember that these guys the joint distribution of the state of water and
on television while more than one
is the
you are kind likely
they are these food
well this but it's alright still
because the the simple physical assumption about x y or
these guys were
that simply
followed by that i don't think the only way get that this is simple expression
this is the expression
we're going to use all the time
this guy is
if you look at the literature
the lead character of the
it is very disturbing that that maybe ninety percent of the paper
there is
show you the recursion not for the joint distribution of the whole set x time
one two but they always establishes the office every they look at the
recursion saying well the joint distribution of x
the marginal distributions story of x then given y one y
you can do
they decompose this
basically the
if the distribution of this thing is that they understand what that
this is a direct consequence of the notion of train on the joint distribution you
just need to integrate all
latent bible x one select x minus one or what i'm saying is that you
should think about all the particle method i'm going to describe
you should anything
two that you should be able to make the
on the mountain all this now this is
this the numerical methods are made to approximate the the joint distribution
the state xk one one four
but because
there are many applications
machine is probably fine
and so the the idea of thing to do in many respects it is the
print message saying thank
but things happen seems to be okay we're going to carry on
but to find the body
what you really want crash is machine horror
because then they would bother to report
so this is tricky conflict and try to do the right thing
we also want to check so
nowadays if you've got this running
pretty cheap to run fusion gets stuck in a kind of doing something
he will actually use that trace back
you're watching the stuff is where we started
then sort you know where you go aged how long to wait a while
and we have page ownership jackets for the memory management
which again designed for cases where memory management
so we try to put all of these things in
to find bugs
without going through the the traditional practices of the user reporting
my machine crashed i don't know why
we have scaling challenge
it's fairly obvious that we had problems already with a large number of users
but is not going to work
incredibly large number of users
so if we we suddenly beat microsoft on the desktop we're going to need a
new bug reporting
we should probably right it before the user right fist
together they get to be screaming in stressed anyway the point with we need to
get a nice friendly and without any problem
statistical debugging
we really need to do more
as you get more and more users
statistical statistical data becomes more and more violence
so the distributions of shipping tools like small with that track your work on these
and then you got
a unique identifier the change
i designed just to say this is this this machine specification
this is my magic number not to contain a personal right
again the conflict between
personal privacy
and knowing the order of machine note to go
so the distribution tend to say
do you want me to register your machine to encourage people to do
don't do it automatically when possible to install but
it's also getting more interconnected
use the case that
kind of this is space
there you go
he looked bargain kind of like that is by
more and more these things are interlinked
so today
you take memory card your PC non-technical user
and it doesn't work
we get about what the kernel bugs acceleration just something like
i'd it's memory stick for my calendar from my camera nothing happens
could be a kind of
could be about something like you which manages the
kind of the low level operations device files and devices
could be a bugging in device which handles getting it into the desktop
could be back in the desktop software which i do
it's not KB
far manager
one of the wind
could the use of mister think it may be tick box they don't do that
there's no much harder to figure out who's but something
which again pulls facts with the bugs alan davies
i can't look you can argue but still not enough
and klein transferred to now
we have
drawing links between the kernel and the actor in the system
because video video card used to be done entirely in user space
very simple devices fans
then video cards started to grow acceleration
o very easy
then they started to DM
which made parallel
today's video cards sort of memory and the memory management system
they interact in a very complicated ways the rest of the logic of support
there's a lot of media management support
got got it because it you know
one of the good sides that it should finally be able to report things like
expected using graph
so if your machine is an aircraft that crashes
have to tell you why
currently you get two red flashing lights value
we have pack if you can read most tell you messages
that's the most human value rather serious
people have used
i have had the report can be read journals
there very very rare
so we have three d graphics that also has this
and we can all think is always somebody complained
we still support the commodore amiga
and that's the be using the people who will get upset we delete commodore amiga
it would be cheaper to buy them both the new PC but apparently they consider
their media is so important
and we dropped three eight six four six all these
questions we after answer
that's the end of the
bayesian learning or my fact
might just represent some penalized likelihood if you're taking the more frequent this kind of
and there are many ways to augment the the likelihood you can use cross validation
approaches really fully bayesian estimators in which you try to to integrate over the parameters
these asymptotic approximations like BIC AIC akaike information criterion but we're not going to cover
those are now going to cover the maximum likelihood learning in the full knowledge that
it's naive and dangerous but with the
excuse that you have to crawl before you can want something like that
let's now
just see
how maximum likelihood learning plays so you guys on this yesterday the IID assumption
independent and identically distributed means that the likelihood of all of the data
it's just a product over each individual deity because we see in the independent that's
what makes products and identically distributed so they all from the same function
i mean
the belong likelihood maximizing the likelihood in the log likelihood are equivalent so we maximize
the likelihood is turned into a song
so this leads to the standard maximum likelihood estimator which just as think of the
likelihood function now the black box there's some parameters which are not
and that box is conditioned on fixing data set d
which is the data that we actually have in front of the training data and
we wanted turn the nob to maximize likely
so this is a very commonly used in statistics and often leads to the sort
of intuitive or appealing estimate maximum likelihood but you shouldn't be lulled into complacency by
a beautiful test right
just because something looks natural doesn't mean that it's the right thing to do
and then we'll we'll see how that can cause problems in the second in particular
we give some examples of the kind of estimators markets was was talking
OK so let's let's just have a very simple example which is flipping coins OK
so let's see how point which is biased
this is an example that comes up all the time and statistics and nobody i
has ever actually seen by course but just imagine for a moment that you have
pointed by saying i don't exactly know how you build a course the idea is
that when you look at some probability of coming up heads might be different than
some probability of one minus
and we want to estimate the bias and the way we estimate the by bias
is by
observing some coin heads heads tails heads heads and we take those conflicts
the maximum likelihood estimate
this may seem very pedantic but it's like you know your morning medicine good for
you go through this because in more complicated situations exactly what you're doing equations apply
everywhere and you be very concerned about your remember it's just like according to work
so what do you write down the likelihood function as the log likelihood which is
just start
over the terms of the individual
and you take the derivative of that with respect to the parameters here there's only
one parameter which is the probability of coming an end AUC to zero
and maximize
that sounds easy right there are several things happening here
in particular using the algebraic true
which is to put the value of the observations in the exponent
and to use all the value of the observation and one minus the value to
select the terms that we want
so you see what i've done that here right
written this is a very weird way
i've said this is to be at x is the observation either heads or tails
wonders you
at times one minus stated one minus x but it seems like kind of a
ridiculous way to write
you know but what i write this way because obviously only one of these terms
is ever going to be
operations if x is zero then this term is just one and this is the
term active in one then this terms stated this is it's just one but i
that way so that when you take a look
you get this nice form here
OK so this is a very common trick
the right things in this weird notation with exponent so that when you take what
you get these
nice find
OK so now
thing to remember here
this is the right
we said this derivative is zero
we get this problem estimated the maximum likelihood estimate of the bias the coil is
the number had over the total number of clicks which is number sports number
does anyone see a problem with this
in particular i give you going to tell you this going by some bias away
and if one
you see i have
what is the maximum likelihood estimate value the probability of heads
one right
but that you would be infinitely surprised if you look again starting with you bet
one dollar an infinite odds that the next be itself
obviously not because you know there in small numbers of samples you're bound to see
some variation just because the number of samples is small in particular sample size of
one you can do anything except all heads or all tails so
the maximum likelihood estimator is clearly junk and should never be used under any circumstances
but i just developed here to show the development of the maximum likelihood estimation of
course you should really use something like markets talked about like look last like the
number of hands
you know over
number had five hundred miles
plus one
something like this right sometimes estimated that some smoothing
and the smoothing estimators like assuming that before you even started
you start
you know have a conflict of heads and half according to
just to get you started before you can take any data that helps you avoid
but that's idea of maximum likelihood estimation
and you do the same thing with a multinomial distribution
which is just about you
i don't know that termites the distribution on instead of two and from zero one
k possible outcomes of like rolling a die
a biased
and again the same thing this model
you write down the likelihood you take the derivative but now
this slide is here to remind you in a second important features during maximum likelihood
hidden variables
so i i will describe the math that you probably know most of them as
you need to know to to be able to do that and i'll just show
you the results of an experiment that we did recently for this where we gave
different these different patterns and they had to judge on a scale of zero to
ten so here the judgments again we don't think of the absolute values have being
particularly meaningful and we're going to take the model predictions are normalized to have the
same minimax
so but but but the key thing is that we we first of all we
give people a pretty small number of events so this is these are all weak
signals to a traditional statistical analysis but people give you some meaningfully different answers that
depend on the function of for example how many events we give them or in
this case or varying is the ratio of the number of events that look like
they in a tight cluster to those which are so here you've got this
five time
tightly clustered events here for three
two you can barely notice it and one or the zero heroes doesn't mean anything
if the clusters one but people across again across a large number of subjects they
show very systematic effect here increasing the the judgement that there is a hidden cars
as you go
this way and similarly for some of these other things you lose your i mean
here we wanted to see how much detail yet so this is a very very
weak effect but there is a statistically significant effect of just bringing
one of those dots over here anyway the model makes the same basic predictions again
just showing that these these intuitions people have although there we can by any normal
statistical standard you know shouldn't count as evidence in a court of law but they're
all actually very sensible intuitions under a sensible bayesian model selection analysis given pretty sensible
hypothesis space of possible hidden causes
they were shown the plots and they were shown them in different random orders
the visual system it doesn't interfere
it means and so so
know that's a very good question in that what one of the so
one of the things you might think are you might question might ask is is
this really kind generous more of perceptual judgement
for this kind of thing i know i don't think it you can draw a
principled line that in other work we've actually been interested in what we call much
more perceptual judgments like you know modeling things like perceptual organisation using bayesian principles and
that seems to work well too but it's a good it's a good question i
mean here
in other experiments that we did
and you can you can see this paper
i think there's a reference to hear this cognition two thousand seven paper we did
versions of this kind of thing but we also did a number of more cognitive
things were for example you know the famous birthday problem like how many people you
have to have in the room such that the probability is greater than fifty percent
that two of them have to have the same birthday it's not it's much less
than the number we have here i think it's twenty three or something is our
i recently heard a version of this work it says how many do you have
to have in the room so that the probability is greater than fifty percent but
two of them have a birthday in the same week
i think it is and you know the answer to that is
within seven days of each other
i think it's six so
you're right so the class the classic result is supposed to be very counterintuitive and
it probably will maybe for the first time i heard about it was but but
our sense was actually people are pretty well calibrated to how big six you know
that the relative magnitude of these coincidences so it's obviously a big coincidence to have
brought the same day than to be within seven days of each other and in
the experiment we did is this before i heard about this other problem but what
we do is we actually gay people patterns birthday so it was just like this
but we said well suppose you go to a party and you meet people with
the following birthday's how
but the coincidences we just how you how strong acquaintances and
not all the birthdays had pattern to them but there was some of the network
you know they could be strong pattern like three people on the same day or
week pattern like four people kind of within a month of each other and you
get exactly the same kind of thing because you have to have a different hypothesis
space of hidden causes their hidden causes are basically proximity in in space
six million time and other kinds of things like you know the same day of
the month but basically it's a space of alternative regularities and the bayes factor does
just as well it's a good job of predicting judgments that so i think this
is a general inability to detect hidden causes the coincidences in in
continuous data whether it's spatial or temporal is something that the brain does
all over the place and computational neuroscientists have proposed that is what learning in the
brain is it's coincidence detection i i i think that goes way too far to
say that's all there is to learning in the brain that sort of the whole
point of the rest of these lectures is all the things that go beyond finding
coincidences but it is the case that the patterns of coincidence in co occurrence in
in data are
you know what are good cues to hidden causal structure and i think across cognition
and perception were good picking that
here's one other example
again this is this is maybe a little less familiar but this is this is
actually a textbook problem from bayesian statistics if you you've heard of the taxicab problem
how people heard that anyone
i think that the probably the classic version this is written up in
the task is to estimate the transition matrix perhaps its stationary distribution pi
and perhaps test different data
is a markov chain predicts predict the next day usually things that we do in
statistics in the face of this kind of problems so that's the set up next
i'd like to go back one step talk about i think there are still people
probability seriously and i just think of it as some mathematical tools in in this
how can you tell if for sequences markov chain so this is definitely a markov
chains kind of classical part of flat
philosophy if you write so
suppose we observe a process x are taking that surround them up to
and i want
how can i tell if it's a markov chain or not
the notion of exchangeable which is invariant under permutations is a generalization of exchangeability called
partial exchangeability in
it's an insult to switching blocks and think you can see
definition just one example of a strong
three states
once in terms
and you can see the the fact that first block
it begins with what it does with this
doctor right different size but that's okay begins with one and ends with two
it's first
this block is the same as well before the second block and lots of after
the first rock is the same as what after the second rock
OK so because you can make history by switching those two blocks put that one
to the beginning of that one two one two
that's the story
stochastic process is partially exchangeable if it's in the kinds of blocks which transformations OK
this set presentation can which blocks the over the size of its
and then this could partially exchangeable indefinitely through a which was first by the french
version of ten is out of service the following
if you have a stochastic process in action on occurs infinitely often sorry that technical
but it's first without a
partially exchangeable for you if it's a mixture of markov chains that is nothing if
not prior distribution on the transition matrices DP
p is one of the transition matrices is the prior and
the chance of observing the string x not x one up to xk
it should be
the bayesian average of the
classical chance of observing that strange string averaging over the past so different
for markov chains and they can you don't have to say that the transition state
probability you can say well from partially exchangeable
if you can cite that we try do
get to work
i am i like the next transparency place
if you do computation
and it's the curr
is this best part of complicated group to have conjugate priors conjugate prior analysis for
the calculations for markov chains is what kind of not
so bad just say what it is so got this
transition state matrix system in by in matrix i'm the priors on these matrices the
conjugate prior is the following each
is independent and there was light that's that that's the conjugate prior so we are
with in the parameters alpha
by the one j et cetera okay the dirichlet priors probably most people in this
audience and its parameters have a useful interpretation there's sort of problem that's the the
vector meson alpha and there some kind of indication of the notion about tightly people
are the actually has the familiar property of being closed under sampling if you have
if you go to sleep
and if you see the markov chain
the posterior distribution is easy to compute it's just the dirichlet a with the parameters
are changed for i j is augmented by the number of times for cross them
i j
very nice if you like this problem but some prior can approximate any prior as
a mixture of slice of makes use of greece loans are dense in the space
of all priors and
that's often not looking for this and is that the output of fifty fifty mixture
two there no
characterisation i find still surprising and this is what i call these kinds of things
that the johnson type theorems and it
also outside point transparency spam some
stochastic processes the markov nothing about anything just to stochastic process
i see the process
i have for predicting
the next day
and that's allowed to depend on and in the past
suppose i conditional probability of the next day given the past so my rules
the probability that the next day doesn't xn plus one the whole past
it depends on the past
the number of transitions from
xn to little n plus one
the function should depend on
what happened in the past but this time the past and i come times i
from one to just one hundred function of that cell to go to
it's necessary and sufficient
to be a conjugate mixture of markov chains to to have your prediction of that
type so
that's right these conjugate priors two
and that's because i didn't say markov chain
capturing that matches the it says
predicting that way if and only if the act as
you're watching the markov the conjugate priors quite a striking and pleasing
theorem this is is a theorem of seven it is about to the next
transparency please disregard
i have my of my in this line of work
if you use a conjugate prior the predictive future
having seen in the past is fine
in the past that is the expected value
the transition matrix p
he is
a convex combination of the prior distribution of class
empirical maximum likelihood estimate of p just the transition counts normalized so that was a
conjugate prior to predict the future is a a convex combination of original prior and
and and usually empirical estimate in weighted by the elephants and that way
and that is
the converse holds that is predicted
you know we can write like this
you know the q
if the you weren't there
right it's basically what we had before
only slightly different representation we had count here and now we have this other way
of indexing we could just write the this q variables in here right they would
cancel out
but now we can appliances inequality we can say well we can all the average
this part
inside the log or outside right now we just you know exploit the concavity of
and you know it then we know that be that we get of story is
lower bound
if we pull out the log here
now what what's nice about this
is that
now we have the this farm outside of the logarithms and that makes things easier
but anyway what you should know what that shows is basically that this expression here
right for any q
you know
for every observation you can choose one of these
q distributions
for any choice of these q distributions we will get a lower bound
on the likelihood
OK now what we actually do in the model and that's also then the way
to derive it is to say well look
you know if we have the q parametrized family of bounds
you know course ultimately we would like to have this tightest possible right so we
could say well before the current parameters that we have what is the best bond
as you know what this value for q that gives us the best part so
we could just treat theta pi is being fixed to compute the gradient with respect
rq subject to the
constraints i nonnegativity being normalized and so on and so forth
and if we do that
we basically just get
that the optimal choice for these q distributions is just posterior probabilities because if we
plug in the
posterior probabilities
right well over here
then we get the optimal
but actually the optimal
the problem
and that's exactly what we do in the east step case so one way to
think about the e step is to come up with the best
i know about and then we can also see that if we treat the
these q dispute is fixed and we compute the gradient with respect to theta pi
but then you know what we get is nothing else but the m step equations
in the model because so
so basically you know we augment the likelihood function by
you know we have the parameters
and then we have this lower bound where they also these additional auxiliary parameters q
and then we optimize with respect to both
in an alternating fashion
right and since the same function
that we have
maximizing every time
right it's actually fairly easy to you know to use these types of arguments to
be with convergence
and and things like that
OK so
and i don't know i think chris bishop to t
he gives the tutorial on latent variable models right i'm not sure
whether he
all right so
you know is the machinery so again you know if you if you look at the
you know
they are actually
you know fairly easy
fairly easy to implement and
and also
four for moderate size documents collection this is can all be done quite efficiently so
let's look at
an example of
you know what we extract here right
one of the numbers here
if you could just ignore the numbers on this slide i ix say something about
the numbers on the other side basically what was done here is we took a
couple of ten thousand news stories from AP news
and then we
learn to model with a hundred concepts OK just fixing that number one hundred right
was just we have to
you know
we have to specify some how many concept we would like to extract case can
also in clustering right we're often you need to specify a
how many concepts you want to look for and then we we actually ordered
the terms
according to their probability of expressing this particular concept right so the terms that have
very high probability the p of w given that's large
you know they come to the top and of small you know what the answer
this is the top
the the twenty years of
so if we look at you know cities concept number two
we see that the township has a very high probability but we we also see
that there are a lot of the
sort of synonyms special types of ships you see here tankers and fairy and then
you see morphological variations also these would look at all
i have also have high probability
in this concept you also see that you know related terms like c important that
are not synonyms of ships anyway
you also find here right so you can make
you know he seaports
you know that with someone tell you that it's likely then also in the context
defined the term ship and vice versa so
and you can also see the very specific
o thing going on that have to do with the document collection for instance there
was the
this oil spill vx about this
and you know that was just you know very dominant in the news so you
also pick that has been seen in this concept
OK and you can look at the other concept here so you know you look
at these things
you know they have
they often make sense let's put it that way kept is another example
here the the numbers are actually the real
expression probabilities p w d t
and you can see here things like in sequence sequences genome DNA genes chromosome regions
you know
we're here male female
reproductive offspring sex sexual exercise was we can see
you know that semantically related words are
you know
grouped together if you like although this is not really a good thing but
and now if you in the right if you're in for instance here that the
document deals with this
concept right they might be terms like DNA
and gino might be explicitly in the document right then also terms like chromosomes and
genes and so on and so forth will also get the relatively high probability that
they could occur in the document right and so i call this method actually semantic
c one
and maybe this is interesting through the one that i haven't seen before
but this is correct so it's proof and it also generalizes to any points
could as well have used in point if you want to so the way i
usually do is just take one point but it's perfectly fine
it's perfectly fine to use two points
so if you so just for convenience if you take only one point because here
OK these individuals but if you go back to the definition
just as any set of training points so i can also choose the set of
one point you chose one of two point is just one point
and i also choose the coefficients to be one
and it's another possible
OK so
it's great so we've done saying one that's another one
which one
you can approach
OK the first one
so we have
the the
that's so because because you we say
it's not into the product space so this thing is that the product and we
know that the products are positive definite and that's exactly what you are using so
if you take a point with itself
the result will be nonnegative so i think you have to
so what's your name
and maybe for those who can read the funds
looks a bit like when i'm having latex problems such as it is very tiny
OK so he's just moving the coefficients and the sums
so sum of ion coefficient AI
he moved into the first arguement and some of a coefficient a change the second
arguement and it looks like that
OK so
how about the third one
the fourth one OK
four one
o the fourth one should be done after the first one because it
but maybe if someone else does the third one
if you want you can
it was one of those over there
commission decisions joking has to be understood
we need to
all of these a
you know the image
this is a graph should this to be was
so it is too was
don't mention
it is
well there will be a because is too busy doing
so one way to argue is determined as the product of the i values
so so the that three his requiring minimal knowledge of some senior
i brought back one thing that is a positive definite matrix of positive semidefinite in
not a terminology has nonnegative values
hence the product of the i value is also non negative and the product is
the determinant
just use it
this is just one
everybody every see that you wanted to work on the data may be right on
the bottom and
just so people see it
this is just
thank you
BC and then it was the me
OK thank you i mean
any questions for me
OK so now
fourth one
we have
you know if you want to find you have to come up here
OK so the the square of all elements is zero
therefore they have to be zero is is bounded from above by zero
in the squares also known from below by zero instances where so it has to
be equal to zero
the element has to be zero
and this argument works for any x x prime
OK thank you
OK so we have to use all these properties
and we can approve in
all remaining time and maybe will finish tomorrow
how to construct feature space so basically we prove the opposite direction of this one
proved given positive come out constructive feature space
maybe maybe will manage to
to prove it so it's it's like very strict half past the
a few minutes so let's see if maybe i can do it with the humans
model was will continue will finish it tomorrow so
we have one two
five slides
OK so
the feature map will be defined as follows
given input point we map it to a point two of function
in this space are to the power x but this simply means functions mapping x
two are
and the mapping was such that
the point x is assigned to the function that we get
if we substitute x
in two
the second arguement of the kernel
could also be the first one doesn't matter and leave the first arguement open so
this is the function of the first arguement
which given a point x then we substitute in here gives us the real number
so for instance if we had a gaussian kernel function then
o point x would be mapped into a gaussian centered on x
o point prime will be mapped into those instead ex-prime
so what we have to do is we have to turn this into a linear
ignore the sum from moment the error times this the basis set
the stochastic approximation
is what we were actually using the stochastic approximation is to say
to do that
and to keep doing that so you could expand this summer out and you be
subtracting one of those each time you have a massive some overall your data going
out there but what we're going do instead of doing that whole expanded thing is
just to this thing
and then when we need to include the other term we do this thing again
so we take the first data point for example then we take second data point
for data points and apply this rule the difference between the two is that you're
dating this parameters that every time step now it turns out the
this algorithm
i will follow approximately
the gradient
all the previous algorithms are going in the same direction using more iterations because each
iteration look to one data point but for large data this turned out to be
much faster what's interesting is that we can't make it out in this region here
it's a diffusing around all over the place because it keeps on making small adjustments
in the wrong direction it is quite fast
if very large datasets with small data it will typically be slow and in fact
if you've got a quadratic error service like this you can just jump straight to
the minimum by solving the quadratic programme
but the reason i wanted talk about this is the same although
learning rules that we
i talked about before they all have
some underlying error function and one should think more about the error function potentially if
you study the learning rule what you want the error function to be the about
learning rule itself
in particular as i said before this goes into direction so
i think it took us away perhaps to work this out machine learning this is
of historical perspective what i think the mindset was but once we want to do
with was split in machine learning one one is to think that the error function
has a probabilistic interpretation right and what you really doing it
maximizing the likelihood or minimizing the negative log likelihood i mean that's what all the
talk about more
my next session but say other researchers would take the point of view this is
an actual loss function so this is the cost you will pay
for making the wrong decision
and then
this error function
minimizing the error function is known as empirical risk minimization and there's lots of theory
around well whether you should be measured minimizing the empirical risk or whether should minimize
another is or how you can regularize that to ensure you avoid things like overfitting
so these interpretations probability in optimisation theory become really important and they become increasingly important
over the last
fifteen years so much so that as i say you know i wouldn't be qualified
to start machine learning phd today
if i have the same qualifications i had when i did started in nineteen ninety
much of the last fifteen years of machine learning research i think has focused on
supervised learning
and even supervised learning has focus on probabilistic interpretations of these algorithms working them out
or clever relaxations the difficult objective functions so the problem with the objective function approaches
often you write down the thing you really want to optimize but it turned out
to be NP hard to optimize CPU relaxing from san l zero norm two and
l one norm and you can maybe per things about how close country after that's
not really my area but that's sort of
i would say you can categorize a large amounts of machine learning work into one
of those two areas dealing with probabilistic problems the probabilistic interpretation for us all dealing
with the relaxation
so things that haven't talked about which is really important in in this area for
optimisation of things like second order methods for optimizing which are very important for quicker
those include examples like conjugate gradient causing newton and newton
effective heuristics such as momentum i algorithms this does this momentum idea which basically says
when you're doing this
you should always take your next partially in the direction you took your last step
and that gets around some this diffusing around here really speeds up the solutions these
these algorithms are coming back in a big way for large data sets and a
day using things like momentum let's say we are for some large datasets fitting
the next thing the last thing i want to talk about a little bit is
sort of unsupervised learning
we would like these
converge to
the best possible error
which is that
he star
so this is
the best possible error can reach the function g bar is the function that minimizes
the expected error
that's what is called usually the bayes classifier
kind of confusing because they use a completely different meaning that
but let's say this is
you know
basically the
the classifier that
as you the right thing
this area not always zero
it can be zero if for a given x there is a unique body label
but maybe for a given x there can be several different levels because there are
some errors in the measurement or things like that
so when there is some error in the measurement is going to be zero
but it can because you say
so in general is not zero
and ideally we want our algorithm to be as good as the best one
these convergence here usually studied
in the context of
increasing sample size
as we get more and more data more observations
we would like our error
conversely the best there
the notion here when this convergence of offers
we say that our algorithm is consistent
because ultimately with enough data we will have identified the best although in the way
or the right although we would have
learn the problem
so the question is whether it is is possible and under which conditions
this will wheelock is consistent with orca
there is this notion of
universally consistent algorithm so universally consistent boundaries and is one of the reasons that
no matter
what is the underlying distribution here
we have this property that
ultimately was enough data it will
with the red the writing
the question is whether this is possible at all can we always learn
no matter what the based on how the data is generated
it turns out that it's possible
and it's kind of it's quite easy actually
it is all these or other questions
so the question is what do i mean by x generated uniformly here
i mean OK this is just an example of one possible way to generate the
instances x
uniformly here i meant to say consider q in a d dimensional space you with
the uniform distribution and you say well the
the probability of something each x from q is really
that's one possible way
because basically
you know
i have to assume that my data comes from somewhere
so i can say well
so maybe our data is some measurements about people
like you know the height and the
the weight
and i brought pressure and so on so the height is between zero and maybe
two meters
and what parameters between you know something is something
and so on
i want find some kind of q
i might assume that
any possible viewing this cube is equally likely
it's a phi don't know anything about how people are distributed then i can say
just assume that
this is uniform
or i can have you know more knowledge and i say well people or activities
and based on the
hi scales
and maybe on the blood pressure can scale is like this so i would find
some kind of multidimensional
distribution here and say OK let's assume that this is the right
and combinatorics graph theory everything comes here
and this is the one of the main objective of this course is to show
you how these things are connected
maybe we can stop here and
the next
lecture continuing to twenty minutes that OK
as of now there is ideological
so before we
start with the next
let me sign some homework for you
this will be
h four
eight five
that's six
so you have to write down
the configuration table for the mechanical configuration
then you have to write down the configuration table for a configuration defined by the
set of vertices and faces of the cube
show that the tables from h
four and aged five are equivalent
this means that
you have to also
think about this page one
what it means that two
these are the structure are isomorphic or when the two tables define the same configuration
maybe just the words about age five
if you have a h five what is the configuration table
for the configuration defined by a set of vertices and faces of the cube
this means that we have here
you have to think about q
so it has eight
it has
six faces
four around one on top and bottom
for instance one face let me again this first phase here
that that may the phase one
and five
then you have some other faces
here for instance one
vertex one
is incident with this
first phase
and the this text five and six
well the other four but this is not in the first phase
there was a question right
OK so for instance here
we have eight candidates and for instance they are one and two minutes
and one of eight minutes
and one in seven minutes and so on
so for instance here you can see that one
and five
they do not meet
because there is no line
that passed through one and five so the question is
how many pairs
never meet
i suggest that we
the graph of this
configuration the leading graph and i would write for you
this graph
has name
it's called
maybe it's kind of graph because
configurations itself is called country configurations
and this graph
is also
it belongs to the family of a generalized petersen graphs so this is a graph
if we have now
so that we can number one number two
number four
and then
and the rest are
TV debates so that everyone TV debates
second TV debate
thirty five eight
so now if we look at the
pairs of
candidates that meet
we see that
for instance this candidate here
meets with this
because here
in this step two
and then it needs
this guy also
and this guy
and this guy but it never miss this guy here
so there are two
there is exactly one
opposite to this one
and since we have eight candidates and because of the symmetry
we see that there are four pairs
candidates that never mind
this year
we have
seven candidates
four seven candidates
if they would ever want to
design the same thing
then this would be
the appropriate solution
and in this case each pair
of candidates
i it's exactly once
which has this property
so symmetry configuration with this property is then
equivalent to
thank you
so now we can move to the other part
mutations we will be meeting permutations everywhere so let's review a little bit limitations so
as we all know permutations bijective mapping from
given set to itself
and permutations may be multiplied and therefore
the symmetric group
called seem of a or s subway a
we all know that symmetry group has two elements were and
optimal value function and then extract the optimal policy out of this this is very
important because of the low
reinforcement learning problem solutions which is the value function algorithms examples of those are the
sorts of q learning and value iteration
the other class is are called the policy search algorithms in which we directly search
in the space of policies in order to find the best policy so there is
an overlap between these two methods called the actor critic algorithms in which
you directed search in the space of policy but at the same time you maintain
the value function
so good examples of
actor critic is the algorithm by starting bit by condon to cyclists by on peters
and new algorithm by sultan bodnar myself and i know what is policy gradient algorithms
policy gradient algorithms the subset
policy search algorithms in which we use the gradient
in order to find the optimal policy we're going to explain it in detail whole
basically the gradient of what and how it works but they there is a gradient
involved in finding the optimal policy
and mean you may ask what is the policy search algorithm which is not policy
gradient basically any policies the algorithm research directly in the space of policies without maintaining
a gradient examples are let's say pegasos algorithm and green or genetic algorithms or anything
which doesn't each certain state policy without using value function
you are using gradient
so now let's look at different learning more
we have offline learning
h in which learning
we learned while interacting with a simulator not really more
so in that case you don't worry about the samples basically infinite number of samples
is provided for you we don't evaluate human trafficking environment we just after this sometimes
OK now give me your answer given a good policy
but the other one which is more interesting is online learning when we learn when
we interact with the environment in that case we are not free to have an
infinite number of samples or just van wander around anymore
so in the learning just
summarize attracted to simulate or reward and cost basically your evaluation when you're interacting with
the environment is not important computational time between actions is not critical and you don't
worry about the number of samples and the main challenge is just how to minimize
time to converge to optimal policy because after some time people ask you to give
me an answer
but in online learning you're directly interacting with the environment you receive reward and cost
so basically you being evaluated in traffic environment so here the meaning of exploration and
exploitation trade-off which passed scholars going to talk about it comes to the picture which
means how much you trust whatever i have learned so far just follow that or
just give a little bit and explorer in order to
o point something may be something better
and also the rear end time execution of actions important and also
the number of samples because you don't have infinite number of of samples
OK now let's look at bayesian learning and what is the bayesian approach that was
a very brief summary of reinforcement learning
what is bayesian approach
so in the bayesian approach you have the process is even which is
and you have process y
which you can observe
so let's say this is the physical
quantity and this is the measurement of this
right so this is what you observe
what is normal you're going to be fair
the heating process from the measurements
you observe process
and what is known to you
is the statistical dependence between
the he then
and the observable which is there
the conditional distribution of y given z
let's hope bayesian
attacks this problem or approaches this problem you place prior over z over your he
which is which reflects your uncertainty about this
then you observe samples from europe observable are valuable and then compute the posterior of
the heat and given the measurements of your observable using bayes rule
that's the bayesian approach
so the main learning has this present can't so
the problems are it it looks at onset thinking of a principled way
conceptually simple it's just you need to understand these rules
it's a new overfitting because of prior plays the role of regularisation here
or a lion regularizer here
fighter than the others but we doing any heavy proving
for very much
here in
i would like to do some
this is some more sort of overview
i'll tell you but other substructural long before i do that the job that he
or she can do this sort embarrassing he did remind me and didn't find in
germany start talking about the rules i remember in fact these women congress still systems
that are on
work translated his work in this paper called general logic which is for
i think the mid nineteen
actually the the day my head right now i think it was nineteen eighty nine
of in the early
in the australasian what he comes up with this as well look you know
the people that say don't understand the true for logic is a nice way of
looking at the moment he develops the so sequence to hide and seek
natural deduction system that was really quite good is very very nice paper and greg
restall work greg is drawn credit but i should have as well
OK now
back around nineteen eighty was here a lot of mine
you may have met barbara the first part can appear
of those to johnson is momentous post-doc i was here is the first after job
of in our paper for conference
the conference was sort of research
the conference was
logics with reduced structural rules which was kind of an ugly
one of its organizers
costa doesn't mention is serbian who found all of this work he
renamed trouble or what does that mean it means that
you give a list of the usual structure rules all sets
religious are ones that reject what are these rules
so since k
in particular a rule larger sets the average xk it's substructural substructural logics
OK and some of them are weaker than we that that's what are relevant implication
why do we care what we saw the relatlon
this idea
so i mean case particularly bad for because
it's not just a
the problem of having
these paradoxes of implication should but just general found
now k was problem or just arrested because it says you can always add in
to present
what comes you want or premises
two and you still have valid and this is how can we can in premises
in the they might be irrelevant to the conclusions
we don't know why i had the number system feature that we have
that subscripts system i we share we had this
the fitch style system
so that's why it was rejected
we can
but larger role of text
another model logical systems
or for other reasons
or for those reasons plus other reasons
the turn of the twentieth century
thank you
ninety two ninety three
a few logicians that bertrand russell gets credit for that
russell's paradox
um earned similar to resume set there in discovered almost exactly the same time
discovering paradoxes box
some of you have seen before
so the
that suppose we can
what started as a general comprehension scheme
so on
this is wrong i can
for any formula a
there are some
here on this side we have a much more direct use we're actually learning the
thing we really want but the learning is much more indirect because we don't get
exact training examples from the environment on this side the learning itself is very direct
every time we take a step environment another training example but to use it now
requires a lot of grinding away in computation
depending on the kind of problem that you're working on where you fit on this
what is the appropriate method use it varies so in a lot of the robot
stuff that we've done computation is much faster than the robot getting from point a
to point b robot is very slow in the world
o had twice the world purple come in purple box there go so
apparently purple races were my context
right so in the robot examples data is really expensive it takes a very long
time for the robot to actually make it across the room but compared to that
computation is relatively cheap so a lot of our the stuff that we've done in
my lab
has focused on model based approaches on this i don't really great talk recently i
think it was microsoft guy two
and what he was working on was
low level architectural decisions in this in the circuit of computer
the memory circuit like deciding which
memory accesses to do at which time when you've got multi threaded architecture i say
something like that and what was in his case he had absolutely no computation time
and all every every learning every piece of learning had to happen at clock speed
right so you have no time but on the other hand in you know in
three seconds you get two million training examples or something like that right so tons
and tons of data data is basically free computations expensive not surprisingly he ended up
using a mix it wasn't even a policy search here the using of value function
based methods so he was able to do this max fast enough and he was
able to to back propagation information train fast enough and and we asked him questions
like well you know what happens if you when you retrain is like we don't
retrain it just constantly retraining itself because the data just flowing in such an incredible
rate so i don't believe anybody with depression that i'm here to bash
any methods on this side but i'm going to focus on methods on that site
because they are interesting
all right so
i'm going to tell you about two learning which is kind of the classic prototypical
method in the middle column value face function value function
based because it for two reasons one is it's almost hard not to go out
and try this because this is the algorithm is already on the two lines of
the slide
and it really does some some remarkable things it just it's very slow to learn
so how does this work
what's happening is we've got an aging etc etc at some state chooses an action
it finds itself in some next state with some rewards so we have that SARS
a piece of data and now the question is what do we do
well what the q learning algorithm does is it keeps the table or keep some
kind of function that maps states the q function maps states and actions to future
work and it's going to update that function in the face of this new
as follows as i have this sort of cartoon version of q because there's the
real q that i defined before that's the true if you actually knew what the
environment was that's the real key function this is some kind of approximation of some
cartoon and so on
we're going to update that by taking
the it's all value and adding a little bit learning rate amount of it too
what we have to it is the immediate reward plus the discounted approximation of what
the value the next state is stated plus one
minus with the old value so this is the difference in
if you look at is the concept of the temporal difference as how old is
my prediction
now differ from what is
it would be one step later
right so remember the value as the as a value the earliest at time t
as a value should be equal to the expected value of the reward plus the
discounted value of the future states so
what we're doing here is is trying to bring those two things back in line
with each other
so on that's the whole thing right that's the whole algorithm you just keep doing
that over and over and over and over again if it's the case that we
visit all states and actions infinitely often and we decay learning rate according to the
standard rules of decaying learning rates then this cartoon value version of q
actually converges to
the real q function
it solves the whole MDP the only way that we notice of mdps in polynomial
time is using linear programming to to fairly sophisticated computational procedure but really you can
get the exact same answer in the limit by just doing is located here
so it's kind of neat
so so one thing one thing that one affected that had because it's so easy
to implement there's
when i guess this continues to be a lot of people who just implement this
some of the
actually i
why you come
which have all kinds of one so strong non
not relevant at all
just one person
nine also have all kinds of
but at least the
i agree
so here we have example station that everyone
considers which is relevant at all
on market
well this is one of the
you should be the person who
they might
and is
had such distribution marks
so should
right as they
i mention
so the weight
so we the participants in the experiment
so we should
these just
strong grounds for
o two
you have
all this thing
mention the relevant says we
it is
he wasn't happy to participate
and we have to where
and here are some numbers
because one
so that that's just too much
i mean there's
we have this week
participants on the bottom
and in
mark this by these opposite suppose we have one
so i want
i have had
the band
which came to an end
so we want to do
on those
which might
like that
all right
the question how to compare these things because
people use
like the rest is just one
during the number man's which
even if you have one
also we have
ninety percent probability to win
at the end
this one
all right
women have much lower position because they use another one
i also related
the second thing is that we have also very
big difference i would like to call
people so some of the participants
i don't think it was just
two persons
you know
there you just right
and there was the was equal to zero
the image is marked as not well
the same
like what
using one
so the
actually already just
above zero
here's one
so that the
so it also
depends very much
so i
these guys
there there
this might be a problem
if you have one
the last
talk about
a lot
it's clear from ten books
there will again
without it they would be
but what i mentioned
and the about the
she has
so just to remind you why
in the
which is to have
for all feature extraction algorithms have been featured it could be several feature vectors which
are usually high dimensional
two index
somehow this one does
i mean you have no images and what they did
hundreds of not
and to compare
o two three
you want someone to work
this the way that was the same over the whole thing
the same
each of us and we need to come with to the site to compare
you never know
and they have one hundred
now are going to mention of course the
and the structures which
poor monte carlo representation of the density
so your estimates could be unreliable would be unreliable
so resampling kind fixes that no resampling bit
conceptual problem in
particle filtering you know the theorists have done analysis of this resampling thing then under
certain circumstances to find out how the errors accumulate over time
and the stuff you can do it you can do not for every type of
sampling scheme but it's a bit of black how widely it and how it works
indeed some people is rapidly you'll hear this
which radford had has had a long running debate about whether you should use resampling
or not in this type of these type of sequential importance sampling schemes because they
do in fact introduce monte carlo are nevertheless over time there absolutely essential for reducing
the accumulation of error
more about that later
but recently what is it actually it's basically
instead of proceeding through time with weights accumulating as you go
through time we can take the monte carlo search and resample it so they have
uniform weights and the way you do that is to take is to is very
in times square and the number of particles if i could have it and it
in the end times but some large number of times you simply choose for a
new particle ecstatic
to be equal to the previous any of the previous particles of i with probability
equal to their weight so to sampling with replacement from a multinomial distribution having weights
w having done that
released in the limit as the number of particles is very large you've got an
equivalent representation of n particles with weights set to one over the idea being that
any particles very tiny weights never or hardly ever get get chosen in this resampling
stage but any with high weight so presumably very important for the representation they get
selected the very often so you end up with a replenished set of samples that's
good for
propagating to the next time step
which you wouldn't have had otherwise with other resampling
we wouldn't want to do this every time step because it does introduce unwanted color
of its basically wait until the samples have become the impoverished
and degenerate but then you resample
so i think that's just text that summarizes
what i said
this is the this is the standard multinomial resampling schemes are much better ways you
can do this to give you a slightly better performance using ideas from monte carlo
stratification and so on
OK so we have a general scheme here for approximating the filtering density over time
would also expectations
but it doesn't quite work and in the sequential
context because we can't get calculate the importance weights so to get the importance weights
we needed
direct access to the filtering density to evaluate the weight
we may well be about evaluate here the proposal will almost certainly won't be able
to evaluate p the target filtering density thirty one more
step in here
and this takes then to the sequential monte carlo filter or the particle filter so
the generic solution to this involves the repeated importance sampling resampling sequentially through time
and it mimics the filtering recursions in monte carlo fashion so does exactly the same
thing as the colony cells of using monte carlo version
the filter
of the of the of the steps
so to outline the broader principle
behind it
suppose we have a collection of samples
again we solve the problem at times
take so we have an much says that means we've got a collection of samples
x i have to be drawn from the correct filtering distribution px t
given all the data up to t
again we can write that in terms of unweighted dirac functions if we like his
i switch notation i'm afraid to a different definition of the function centred upon
x y
the function of x
we substitute that into the prediction equation
so drops out
so we've got
this is what we needed to do for the first step
of the filtering
equations for the first step
involved taking the filtering distribution from the previous timestep which we've now got gotten monte
carlo representation for that
well the state transition density
and integrating out the previous state activity
we simply take this
the previous
times approximation to the filtering density
like so
these are samples obtained at the previous time
a t
and then do the integral using the sifting property again so we are not just
in the not like with the normal monte carlo integral
with arithmetic mean
of all the transition densities f evaluated with the previous samples locations
xt y
so want to specify to some
some precision
number of bits required to specify
it's going to be
that square
so the number of bits
quite by
the actual markov decision process
is order as per day
and then interaction we need with the world
are the behaviour optimally
it's only of SA
so the the tell here means the system
sometimes depend upon log of that's a
so this is is that we can
interact with the world and the amount
which is
less than the description of the world
in order to behave near optimal way
if this is most interesting to me because there have been debates in reinforcement learning
about what that it was necessary
ten our them which in turn build model of the world
this seven doesn't
and can because the amount of experience that uses
is less than that required
to actually build an accurate internal model
right to the overloading here
so the lower case s is the state
he there
the number of states like here
or the set of states
so this is the number of states
number of actions
so this is in our state times actions
first it
so i guess thing to which you can realise that this algorithm is is significantly
different from
and the hugh durrant because
this is strategy of trying to build a model of the world
can work with that same complexity
these are seven positive results
and then i want to go through a short section or
saw talk about
the limitations of simplicity approached reinforcement learning
and what people have done to try to address these limitations
so our first limitation is given to you a lower bound
so the claim is that
the rhythm a
which satisfies the statement
must use at least
t s a
actions to explore
so we have to allow ourselves
to markov at least ESA actions in order to
to get any cube like statement
and the somewhat stronger lower bounds which actually involves the on but we'll worry about
because this is sufficient in the the proof is actually very simple
the proof is just
here's an MDP here his family of mdps
the claim is you need TSA
actions have to learn to behave near optimally
one thing to do is here i have to agree with demonstrating this
so here we have
so for the pathway
the pathway kind of goes right
if i
behave if they behave
well in addition to
so we have to look at the way
and we have
maybe two actions
per state right
so we have a one and a two
o twenty three
yes very good reactions state
a one a two and a three
and i think about a family market decision processes
the action which leads to the next in the
is randomized it just independently
learning how to behave well here goes nothing about how to be will here so
maybe section eight two
the next to hear the sine one and section eight three in affectionate
markov decision process in this
in this family
know how to be a few does nothing about how be a few
and then all actions just take you back to the beginning
i think that we have to do in order to
figure out how to get the in the past
and receive the rewards
so in every state
you have to execute
about half the actions
in order to figure out which ones to to the next state
and every time you execute the wrong action you go back to the beginning
in every state the second half the action to test times a you go back
to the beginning which is where the team comes in
you can do better than TSA is distressing
the reason distressing because the real world the number of actions going talk to physicists
and you ask him how he states
well you know
maybe you can
you can kind of these things which
the same after that the playing scale just like the minus thirty four meters
the number of states
which specify your location with this room
is larger
and the memory of any computer
then we can ever hope to make
and this says that
you know
for general MDP
you can depend upon the number of states
that's a bit of a problem right
so lower bounds is it really big problems are not going to be solvable
but if you are
and then we have a sort of conundrum because
we know the problems that we want to solve a solvable because reinforcement learning
it is going to mathematical description of life you are an agent one thing in
the world
use all of your exploration exploitation problems every day
so somehow the method is failing to capture
what is actually do
so what that means mathematically is that we need to make more different assumptions
they have been several attempts to make more assumptions
use a jeep modeling context
also gives opportunity to draw an interesting connection between
between lesbians and engine piece
here's the cheapy
joint right so we would be
we look that they
joint distribution pty enough
i mean take the the minus log there
and what you see is
is this term here
so you get this term here here's the prior
and here's here's the data likelihood
if we look at the standard has been lost
four r
for linear spam
right then you have this
which is the
regularization term
and you've got this which is a taylor series so this is
the soft margin right so you've got this you've got the soft margin parameter see
now it's often done in a as you can you can you can kernelized this
so instead of having a linear function you can have
you can have some basis some kernel basis here
with at least two and this this this is this is this is standard stuff is
you get this
you can write you can write your your has been lost
that's false assertions should change that's
what this allows us to do is is rather nice connection when we look at this between
the minus log joint from a cheap e
andy has fear and loss
you see that you've got the same
data fit term here
and then you've got a penalty term
so what this allows to see is that both
and yes em
regularize on your prior in this certain way these are not the same function and
are not doing the same thing but what they both do is they try to
fit the data
and the regularized at
with with the prior
and so there's there's
there's there's there's
quite interesting that a work here one papers like really is is is one and
is wrote on the relationship between cheap easiness fans
and he and he talks about supplies as well
all right so
where do we stand
we've talked about
how to
change the kernel we talked about how change the likelihood
those the two objects that i think are are of most interest
i wanna talk briefly about
the shortcomings of cheapy
i think at this point it's it's it's it's very easy thing that cheap is
this all-purpose regression tool that can do
effectively anything we want
in some ways that's true
and we talked about some of the strengths and this so so well i think
that one of the weaknesses cheapy
grow out of the strengths
so we talked about how
everything is happily galaxy and how that's a really great thing about two pieces that
once everybody living inside this nice galcians framework it's all kind of easy
the weakness of course that
that's that's exactly true is that when things are guassian then we have this trouble
we have to bring in if we have a non normal likelihood like we did
the jeep classification case we have to bring in approximate inference technologies
when we're dealing with model selection it's
doing model selection over a number these hyperparameters
can be can be of the tricky because it's it's nongaussian so you have to
decide should i optimizes model parameters should i try to integrate over these model parameters
should properly integrate over the model parameters
that's it
that doesn't quite fit into this simple cheap e
simple gas modeling context
another great strength of gas processes are the nonparametric flexibility this
right so we talked about how you don't get some fixed parametric set but rather
your model grows with the complexity of the data
the downside of course is that we have to compute on all the data so here's this term
we've looked at a whole bunch of times
we look into the set of examples here
and here
if all the examples in this subset belong to the same class
we label this
with the class name and stop
decision tree
in this subset there are still examples of different classes
like soft hard not we would still continue splitting
and we which is the most informative that built at this point
which turns out to be astigmatism
we again split the set into two subsets
we can split the set into two subsets and that's how the algorithm basically works
at each
of the decision tree it has to decide
attribute is the most informative
and put it
two it names
here and then it's it's according to the value of that most informative after that
and then it also at each point it has to decide whether the algorithm should
continue splitting or it should stop
building the decision tree by simply labeling the leaf with the class names
so this will become a bit more clear in a minute
OK so we have automatically induced the decision tree out of twenty four training examples
and this decision tree is now a model
of all the data which we had available
it was automatically produced one from twenty four training examples and it can be read
as follows if the production is reduced then
the patient should be prescribed in contact lenses
which seems to be a reasonable so
you should have a normative production in order to get to the lenses subscribed and
and then the next
so if the two productions normal and you the patient does have astigmatism then
the patient may be prescribed soft lenses otherwise if the patient has astigmatism then decision
still depends on spectacle prescription if the person is myopic
he would typically be prescribed car glances if he's hypertrophic he wouldn't get any lenses
at least this was the case in the training examples available you should note is
that this rule
represents the
second is a condensed representation of this
decision table here
so let's now look cool weather
indeed let's say if their production is reduced
leads us to to a set of examples which are all labeled with the class
label none
tear production reduced
reduced number reduced to reduce the number reduced reduced NONE OK so
with this
this value
after production attribute which turned out to be the most informative directly leads us
the director describes the group of patients for which no let no lenses were prescribed
and so on
so if you would to transform a decision tree into a set of rules you
could say
the patient will not be prescribed card lenses will not be prescribed any lenses in
the two productions reduced
it will also not be prescribed lenses if
the TM productions normal
there is astigmatism and the patient is hypertrophic so we
we have to
if then rules for not
we have one rule for soft lenses
so will be prescribed if the production is normal and there is no astigmatism and
the patient will be prescribed hard lenses if the production is normal there is astigmatism
and the patient is myopic
another example we have customers
now the age of the customer
o is represented by the actual age
one of the customer will looking at customers who spend a lot in the shop
we could
i did look at how much they spend or we could to
also label them with the by the binary class value whether a person is the
big spender yes or no
so now we could have different sorts of tasks if we have a binary classification
problem describing the patients which are big spenders or not we can induce simple decision
trees and we would again have the most informative activity in the nodes of the
decision tree when we have
values which are numeric
learning algorithm will split we find will find the best splitting points to to split
the set of
customers into those which are big spenders and on expanders