we would have to find that confirmation for the hypothesis can be obtained if we
observe black ravens
because that's something that happens
that's how science works right we make observations and from these observations we try to
conclude general statements and if we observe hundreds of thousands of ravens and were all
black and we have the inclination to think that all ravens may be black
on the other hand
the resolution of the paradox would require that we would have very little or no
confirmation fight for this hypothesis if we observe non non-black non ravens this orange or
red chairs
and finally i would think that the degree of confirmation obtained depends on what we
already know
on on on
on on our beliefs so to speak
i'm not going to present
one way of how a bayesian probabilistic may approach this problem and and possibly resolved
we represent the degree of belief in our hypothesis by p of page
and as i said james would have put p of page given x
because it would be all believe in the prophecies given
they the other knowledge that we have all about the world
and now
we just define this quantity of page given evidence so the proof of the confirmation
that the evidence gives us about this hypothesis by this racial here so we say
that the probability
after the process is given the evidence over the probability e
of the hypothesis without knowing about the evidence that this is our measure of confirmation
this will be a greater one
if our belief in this hypothesis has been has been strengthened by observing the evidence
and if nothing has happened will remain close to one or one
now i you can use base
through now
and exp on this thing and what you find is that this quantity here is
equal to this quantity here i don't want to go through the steps but it
turns out that the crucial evidence dependent quantity here
it is the probability of the evidence given the negation of the the hypothesis over
the probability of the evidence given that the hypothesis is true
so we're going to analyse this
this expression here
by the way is there anyone here who would consider himself a bayesian
half life half bayesian
is there anyone who considers non bayesian
or anti bayesian possibly it's going to be i think it's great that you find
much stronger opinions in other surrounding i think so people can really have a lot
of conflict about this
well anyway so this is the racial we're going to analyse
and let's analyse this racial for evidence type one evidence type one is the evidence
we observe black raven so
this is the racial we're looking at and our observation is an object a which
is the raven and which is black
right so i've just plug in
raven and black here for for e one and here for you want sources here
and here
now i just use the one of these basic rules of probability and right
are a and b
the probability of our and b is the probability of b given are times the
probability of are
and i do the same thing here in the denominator
so now this is the expression we want analyse
so what we have here is
we in this particular expression we assume that the hypothesis is true
the hypothesis that all ravens are black
so the probability that something is black or that a is black given that it
is a raven and the hypothesis is true
a is true is one of course because given that the opposite is true
i think you know
o five that you see when you
so you
right to differentiate
and the that
so now the fact he
when this is true
and if you
particular distribution of foreground background before
we can calculate that an optimal threshold
well one of which is
o thing
color with different coloured all
this of all
by the patient
and the
so i think illustration the book and i was also from the book
this the black and white
picture but major the color and
try to
and this the right
is the segmentation by a
but just to play
of the eight
those who were
so what i
fine partition
the image that just like
that one right
all levels equal to each other
four them
and our
there are six of the one show
and if we
we have all the image
and our original standard
so we have
this is because the initial
and this one pixel
and i try to
o range
like the right
in the brain
changes in the level because some
so we
range of people
i have had
so the goal
to all the children in the qualitative difference between the two
not to
so we we have
this is of the one direction and called the the direction and
why this procedure all pixels of the image
so here know
the result growing
boundaries by segment
i actually
on the top of the original image
and we want to
when tried
we have
there are few
so first of all
one thing
and that not believe
so we
the what
and will you out there is still holds a partition
if it is true
yes is quite a lot of things
if there is no
he was
and the police
four average
in this
good prediction
then we saw
it's not going to partition
and we also
because there are connected range
two decades of
examples like but the
in this way
the predicate is true
you get a big screen TV turned on your high-definition channel you watching a great
movie during the ads
you'll also you'll see
you'll see ads for
you know maybe it's for blind you consider couch with or maybe it's for new
cleaning product review from nineteen again next one three
the reason using those as you're not seeing brand which typically pay higher CPM cost
per thousand
it is because there is no data about the audience you know the the
the fragmentation media is actually samples may only have one person who watch the show
maybe no people and therefore there is no information available to the media by justify
the expense where someone who has product way where they are in they are in
same thing you did call now
they have quantification
the value that advertising because they're receiving phone calls
for someone is building the brand for product you can buy in the store offer
car they don't know they're reaching and they can't justify the expenditure
you know this situation
seems really strange to myself my co-founder concourse four years ago when we were looking
at forming the company and the
reason the thing that really surprised this is the sample based techniques to develop broadcast
they have been applied to the internet
and yet the internet is isn't broadcast
every piece of content is delivered individually do your browsers based on the requests that
you've instructed your browser to make those and those delivery processes actually create records
and so when we launched comcast goal was to
enable addressable advertising scale
was to provide a framework technology analytics framework that would enable third parties
media companies and marketers to participate in two
configure themselves real-time decision making based on models that are pertinent to their objectives
but before you get we had to fix audience measurement
and the way we did this was the launch free service not based on sample
based approaches based on direct measurement media consumption and what we did was use machine
learning to infer the audience characteristics so to understand this direct measurement we just take
a step back
and look at the process of online advertising all fragments case online delivery any piece
of content
whatever content is displayed it's received from server and all measurements this actually use piece
of HTML code instructions to the browser to request the browser also ask for measurement
tag from comcast so anyone can sign up for the service in place comcast measurement
tag within the digital media assets
whatever that tag is fine
individuals browser makes requested as server we send a message back saying we've got your
request and we're able to record
the fact that request occurred and what information they recording is basically weblog http protocol
recording the URL to the actual page the consumer was on recording the time the
request was made by the IP addresses recorded systems needs to know what's in the
content back we know
you know whether they're running mac or PC with a request came from from and
i found this very basic web log data now importantly
we're not collecting personal information such as names addresses and telephone numbers social security numbers
in fact there's nothing in terms of these weblogs actually tell us anything about who
those people are
actually before we launched cost was that obviously this should enable you to count much
more accurately
you know how many times people requested content from a particular site the hypothesis was
that by organizing the data properly and applying machine learning techniques
it will be possible to actually also start to automatically infer
the characteristics of the audience
and we conducted some experiments in in two thousand six to two thousand six convinced
ourselves it possible
but i really need to get more horsepower into our team
we're not where there was there was over there was the reason that
most of the academic papers are written whenever except in places like this and so
we decided to get some way to get some people who can really take take
these core concepts and develop much more comprehensively and we're fortunate were able to recruit
a really fantastic team of scientists at san francisco were based was also very handy
the standard just down the road and were able to persuade trevor hasty jerry friedman
to join our advisory board may be an active participant in our african development for
the past
for the past four years
what they want us to do
it's not just count page views
and and the number of visits to website but actually start to infer and understand
unique audience characteristics is certain things are fairly straightforward
it's reasonably straightforward to geo locate individuals and understand the basis of an IP address
where they're located and therefore understand audiences from a particular area
but we can go way beyond that we can actually start to understand
whether they
people are consuming the content from work well how i would go so far as
to understand the demographics
and for that matter any arbitrary set of audience characteristics for which we can get
key reference points into almost touch on that one
but this approach was was really quite quite revolutionary in the market because it meant
the a web publisher of any size
and typically with with sample based solutions website had have tens or hundreds of thousands
of people for any measurement can be made in the audience with this approach we
could make measurements of audiences all sub audiences which sometimes just the few hundred people
and what it meant is lots of people started to participate in the service was
completely free there's no complex contracts and payments people had to make it come to
our site they could sign up get measurement and what is meant is that over
the last
four years
data volumes have grown dramatically and our entire modeling approach
gets better with more data that has
and you can see over the last three years
this is a hierarchical clustering results you get
it's very nice it's like minimum spanning tree except that you have two components
and then if you do majority vote
well since there is only one labelled data points in each cluster you get this
very nice prediction
corresponds to our notion
but if you do
if you happened to pick something else for example complete linkage
that's the cluster you get
and because our label points are here and here
majority vote with be confused and if you have the rule of breaking the ties
randomly that would be the classification get and which looks terrible
this is just another case to show you that be careful with the assumption that
you make
church so it's not that
it's not that the either but just didn't get you there
and this is an of course this is the artificial example just to show you
what happened
all right
so let's move on to
a very different kind of
so my supervised learning models
co training and multiview learning
so let's
use the example of
named entity
for classification
and it's very simplified the task here so this is a task in natural language
processing in particular when you were some companies crawl the web page they want to
automatically processed texts and identify the person location organisation et cetera in the in the
text and they want to do it using a classifier that scott named entity recognition
named entity is
a phrase which is the name and you want to say oh it's name is
this person or is this name is is the place or is an organisation to
so let's consider the simplified version where we have
person and location
one example would be mister washington
that we know it's a person and then at washington state with the location
being this task
here's what's making it special
beyond the named entity itself
we actually know what's the text surrounding it
so in this case so we have the instance one that is the text surrounding
it in text is headquartered in and i use on the score for this context
and they have the name entity itself and in in the second instance we have
mister washington the vice president could
so this is the a case where you
first of all let's assume you know where are the named entity but secondly also
know what's the next it
because of this we can represent each object in this case each object is named
by a feature vector that consists of two parts
or we will call it two views
so this is my notation but these two views the first few years
the word is often named entity itself
the second view is the words surrounding it in the context
so i divide my feature vector into two parts
now why it useful forward we will see that it
but let's first two and a little exercise
if i give you is an instance one
an instance two
and i label them for you so that you know being states in location and
this p there means it's a person
and i ask you
that's your training that you have to label data points
to classify
those two points
how can we do that
what can we do that
o well
i didn't expect that i but that's a very good guess although i suspect that
will not work too well on the whole corpus
of course we know english so we know what the correct classification of this but
pretend you don't know english so that it's not possible to do that
now my claim is actually if you have more unlabelled data then that might actually
help let's see
so now you have three four five has more unlabelled data points
let's try to do this
i know headquartered in washington state and that its location so by instances three although
i know nothing about it i see the same context
now you have to make the assumption you make this assumption that you have
know saying you know don't those should match the data distribution
but unfortunately this time he is difficult to compute
because there are exponentially many configurations right
and we'll see some ways of doing doing that
you know if you look at markov random fields with latent variables
that becomes even more challenging and that's the challenge when we start looking at deep learning models
here these acts is composed both with something called visible
variable select pixels and images speech signal words in a document
as well as latent variables
and these latent variables you know
i can tell us something about you know you the topics the semantic meaning of of of the data
you can specify the probability in exactly the same way
but the problem is again you have this
normalizing constant but even more problematic to have this summation over the latent variables
so if you try to do inference in these models you basically want say well
what's the distribution of the latent variables that i'm trying to infer
and the parameter learning becomes very very challenging task so a lot of work and
i'll show you some of the worker
in the deep learning communities factor basically figure out how can you do with the
intractability and as i go through the door are gonna make it will be more
more precise
so let me move
in two
a class of models called the stick boss missions
and these kinds of models that are very useful for learning low-level features
these are kinds of
a model sometimes they called
undirected graphical model is a bipartite you have a bipartite structure
in the simplest model you have stochastic binary visible variables again think of them as pixels in your images
and you have stochastic binary hidden variables we can think of them as feature detectors
so feature detectors you know that can tell us something about maybe semantic
representation of documents or some kind of
a little high-level features that you see in the data
right you can specify the energy
of this configuration in the simplest way of specifying the energy is just using air
it's just a linear combination here
what this term is effectively during is it's basically saying well what's the correlation structure between each pixel
as well as each
we can variable
and the parameters theta i just the parameters w as well as these biased and
so these offset terms a common
think you have now you can specify the probability of the joint distribution using a
very standard definition right it's just a
e to the negative of the energy or r if you write it explicitly
you're essentially have
this time where you have a pairwise sometimes is called pairwise potentials
but again just modeling correlations between pixels or latent variables and you have a normalizing constant
and these sometimes called you know if you've heard terms like markov random fields boltzmann
machines log linear models this this
correspond to the same basically the same model just different names
now why these models are called restricted
the reason why they call this that this is because there is no
connections between these hidden variables
and then has an advantage and disadvantage
the key advantage
is that it turns out that computing the distribution
over the latent variables can be done in closed form
and this is a very useful thing to have
in particular you know if i show you a new image i can quickly tell
you what features make up image
well if i show you a document i can quickly tell you what topics make up at the document
right so it's easy to compute
and the same way the conditional probability of observing the image is again has a closed form solution
right so
if you apply this model to you know
handwritten characters again this is the kind of structure that was a very closely related despite scoring model
the one that we see it sort of tax will edges
and then you can say well if i show you a new image
well this new image can be written as a combination of these
and it turns out to be you know useful thing to have because you can
represent a lot of different images just using a subset of of of these bases
so it's kind of like it natural is very simple basically tries to find
this composition of of of these images
most hidden variables are gonna be of these numbers are given like these numbers are
given by the conditional probability of a particular feature being on
and obviously can see for this image you not observing a feature like this
will have a very very small probability
one which
OK so
got kind of life she might have that initial belief
then he comes the data someone actually gives you the labels she
for these guys
OK so now you have a label
that ties the blue thing to hide the the
measurement model
and why there's noise will because you burn so there's the ship of there
and you kind of look over industries and crossing of figure out which
the ship is
and enough instances showing and you know you have a good prior your parents think
start output going on about
and so
you had prior shape you have your observation that brings in data
the data being the tag shape and with that you know get posterior which is
you know kind of nice
i will be using a lot of graphical models which will hear more about the
next week in way to represent this model
the probabilistic models with this graph had a brief introduction to to this yesterday
so no that is unshaded this
something we want to learn
the arrow indicates the conditional probability p of the given age
and not by itself that and say that this is the marginal probability p of
and the this whole thing denotes the joint
of the of the comic
this is the graphical way of representing this
you some examples of the sort of thing
and this one more thing i needed to say that
this also
the trick is
to do this integral
you need to the normalisation to another distribution
so if you have many hypotheses many of current hypothesis could be huge
and this is usually combinatorial integral
a very high dimensional
continues to grow
full bayesian inference there is no optimisation
it's all about computing the center
it's an integration from the optimisation problem
here's another example that i got from kevin murphy
the language model
probability of words in the language
you have the likelihood that indicates how sounds produced given the words and we know
how to the speech synthesis the synthesis pretty well and computers
we have good models of that
given sound we try to infer works for speech recognition
recognise speech
rex features a nudist beach in vancouver
just wondering why kevin murphy came
here's another example computer vision
you have believe beliefs about the world the properties of the world and on how
light comes theorize how it gets replaced an object and so on
maybe some properties of objects
pixels is not fixed
contours and so on
and you also know
this computer graphics that tells you given the model you generate high you render images
so you have an observation model
and then from that observation model you try to do computer vision
decide what the world is about
given an image of the world
again and integration problem
in this sort of perhaps setting
but now it's not only about learning and abstraction it's about
you should learn an abstraction
with the purpose in mind like markers mentioned yesterday
and this is the sort of and it's not all people with actually believe this
this is utilitarian view philosophy
we do everything with you until it in my
let's look at another example was so one yesterday but just a recap
i assume that
we first learn the population model
and we do it this is very trivial density estimate like
we saw yesterday you basically just count how many people healthy how many people have
cancer in the population
and that is that kind of a way of learning
to describe the population
in general this will be a more complex model but the methodology is the same
once you have that you also can learn reward model
a reward
model actually csaba you're going to talk about that
want to be the new
now how do you pronounce it
job you can talk about inverse
now again
but if you need to know more about this talk to him
learning the rewards is a very tough problems
you know usually we have an objective function to optimize objective function come from
that in itself is quite challenging problem
but let's assume we have learned that you're saying tell latest this algorithm that is
not going to talk about
and we know that if a patient is healthy and this might also be decided
by a bunch of people doing policy-making
you know you're the politicians in current government
might decide that if you are healthy
and you receive no treatment then there's no cost
the nation
if you're happy cancer and you receive no treatment then when you die
and that's kind of a lot of resources
to the nation
if you are healthy and you receive treatment
you lose your hair
and the minus thirty cost
and if you have cancer
and you do receive treatment
well you survive but still
you know it's going through this
the principle of expected utility
which is not the axiom is not here
expected utility i don't have time to go into it but
it comes from
actually the work of one nine
the four is game
and it's about
choice if something comes from choice theory
and about combining individual preferences
how to come up with the voting
that makes everyone happy
you know the obvious things in preferences if you prefer it should be
and you prefer b to c then you should prefer a c
and then there are five more
four more axioms
we seem to have been an saleable
and then you try to find the function that a social choice function
that satisfies all the axioms and what arises is this thing
called the expected data
so it's rational in that sense
if you gonna play
the game like in game theory and unit to
arrive at the nash equilibrium
o what nash proved this is the chief you maximize this quantity each player maximizes
how dimensions
there are no complex numbers in high dimensions
ah i thought for some time and maybe he will still be possible that missing
dimension for it can be done with quaternion which is sort of the generalisation of
complex numbers to dimension four but the problem with quaternion son why doesn't work is
that the key property is that both in the mission one and mission two multiplication
of numbers is community
and multiplication what turns is not
and so
are you can no longer
have these nice property
that allows all the
roots and all these business to go through and even even multiplication was community of
how do you compute groups
of polynomial singletons
it is not so trivial as competing with the polynomials in the complex plane
essentially the problem is that being as is based on just with polynomials can be
generalized to more than two dimensions
of course that technique but it doesn't necessarily need to work is just project your
data into dimension one dimension two and then you apply the algorithm
so that that would be a quick way around
OK even though this is very simple and straightforward it actually solves
one of the segmentation problems in vision which is segmentation based on intensities here one
is given an image for instance this image of the penguin here and roughly speaking
let's say there three groups here groups are defined by intensity so why it would
be one group
black would be another group and great would be another groups so here there three
every pixel in the image has an intensity value so it's just a real number
and therefore
you can precisely apply the clustering technique based on
just data believes in one so have to do is to fit a polynomial
o p
image intensities
this is the number of data points here is the number of pixels
and you find the roots of the problem is the problem in one variable
of degree three
and i will give you the
cluster centres which in this case is going to be almost zero for black almost
one for whites and almost point five from great
these are the results of rhyme these onto this image
these results with k means
these results him and these results were disputed by technique and as you can see
there's pretty much no difference in the results
except that the k means any and take a lot longer because they need to
iterate in order to find the solution
while this thing gives solution right away
these are cases in which actually k means and failed to find the right segmentation
this is the case of the penguins
this is supposed to be one group then we go back to the to the
penguin image
remember so white is mostly the bottom and the front of the dependence
so that's what you get here so that group is mostly fine but the second
group is mostly getting the borders of a much which is not one of the
group's you're looking for
and the same thing happens with him
however if you just apply this purely algebraic technique you get a solution that is
reasonably good enough
to start with and use that to initialize both gains in the and they now
converge to the right
so this this example is just to show
that indeed he m and k means can converge
to the wrong place if they are not properly initialize and this quick technique of
just fitting a polynomial in one variable to their points can be of help to
do in the innovation
these are just make comparison this can also be done
four texture calculation segmentation
the problem here is a lot a lot more difficult
basically how
in the world you're going to say that the entire tiger
just one group
based purely on
either intensity or color information there are stripes there's a lot of variability the head
has a lot of white parts
the ten is completely different
so segmenting this from the images is very very hard problem so we have to
do is to come up with some sort of textual description which is in some
sense a measure of the probability distributions of intensities or the colours in the neighborhood
of every pixel in the underlying idea is that
points that belong to the same group would have smaller less the same probability distribution
these results on the bottom here are results from human segmentation
so we can do the task quite well
but we don't quite agree completely bizarre results from about one thousand humans and then
the right in the segmentation in means that everybody agreed that that was a border
in between images so here the tiger
not every it's not perfectly not not everybody agrees but there is mostly in agreement
and then some people separate the water some others don't touch
so this result you can get by applying this polynomial technique
and as you can see there are errors
but it does a reasonably good job to to start with
the water is separated here in three groups there is a big change of intensity
here because this partisan these parties under the shadow similar here and then most of
the body of the tiger is segmented properly but there are some errors here close
to legs is a little bit lighter
the head of course comes out differently because white
and it's impossible to get detailed because you have to be the probability distribution in
the neighborhood and so you pick a neighborhood that is too small
it's very hard to do but if you pick an image that is too large
then you need very fine textures such as the case of the tail here also
the case of the bushes which is very
high-frequency textures
and this is just more examples on on how
incredibly simple technique of just fitting polynomials in one
and one variable can be applied to very complicated problems in vision
such as segmentation based on text
OK so now i'm going to move so that that was just a matter of
now i'm going to move the problem but i want to talk about which is
we're going to ask
after we take alpha hydroxy rear
we're gonna put in coal cement
why do we want to do that
what we really want to do is to ask after the cells have reached have
gone through s phase
how soon does the label cell
move from s phase
all the way
in the face
how long does it take how long history two
and so all is the following we take away the hydroxy urea this allows all
these cells to begin to move out is this a fully synchronous culture
well actually no because some of these cells are over here
there's a whole bunch over here these are synchronous but the rest of the ones
there it is scattered out so there's going to be some pioneers over here moving
of the phalanx and there will be some stragglers and then going to be a
big slide of these cells that are moving as the rear guard ahead
now what we're going to do work after we take away the structure we at
our old friend calls him
and call summit
tried to start right this time
because it is going to block cells as we obviously said before
right over here
and then we're going do is the following
we're going to look every hour to take some cells and put them in coal
image or believe them because some of the whole time and every i'll take cells
out of the petri dish
which of it calls that since they were released in here and we're going to
look at the matter face cells
and how we look at the interface cells will here's amanda a cell
it will be its chromosomes
obviously the chromatic to this point
under the microscope
and they start accumulating up here
and each and every hour take some of these men face cells
will take them out of the petri dish
and after we've put them in the that or will we live the petri dish
if you want a book and after the there and they've they come over here
will fix them onto the plate
i will add some alcohol or something which caused him to stick to the plate
they can swim array and then after that we already had some radioactive emulsion so
here's let's imagine his itself the bottom of the plate metaphor is we're going to
add some photographic emulsion on top of that
like that and then what we're going to see is
how soon we can detect radioactive metastases chromosomes
how can we do that because each time
an electron leaves the treaty is signed d
each time a beta particle leaves it's going to cause a grain of the emulsion
of silver to form
in the
in the photographic emulsion that we've layer above
the cell
so this rate this photo emulsion is only not we're detecting light but we're detecting
when they're whenever this radioactivity in it this being emitted
and what we're going to look for
are grains silver grains that are located above
the chromosomes in the microscope
we can look down through this play through the emulsion on the chromosomes we can
see them clearly i've shown you that before
and we're going to ask ourselves the question
when can we begin to associate silver grains with the chromosomes
because those silver grains must have been incorporated into the chromosomes during
to pay some attention to the possible differences between the training and test this and
then path of was the first one to propose that support vector machines are tailor-made
to to do this task in order to generalise from the training data test database
here are some of the results on you train
if you train a support vector machine to detect for example onset of solar and
see if it can it does it does the job with eighty six percent accuracy
on task four chances fifty percent to detect the onset of the cost and it
does that was seventy percent accuracy and so on
are a certain way in which discriminative classifiers can be pushed a little bit is
to is to combine dynamics and
and sparse data
so for example if the
the landmark detectors have to be trained using small datasets that we need but we
need some kind of information about the dynamics over time
in order to do correct classifications and then it's hard to do that using purely
discriminative methods
in fact the only way that there are there are there are very few methods
developed recently to this discriminatively but it's extremely computationally intensive and we get much
more reasonable methods using using bayesian inference and so let me introduce
bayesian inference
the other
sort of superclass of machine learning methods are the set of bayesian methods that is
to say
the methods in which the methods in which the function is being estimated by the
universal approximator must be correctly normalised probability density it cannot be simply an arbitrary function
it must estimate the likelihood of the label variable y
given the observation x and
that that that
that function estimation problem then naturally gives you any other function estimation problem if you
can correctly estimate the probability density of y given x then you can minimize the
probability of error by just using the maximum of posterior probability
the value of y if you can correctly to estimate the probability density of y
given x then you can choose the minimum mean square error value of
why is your output in a real valued tracking regression problem so if you can
do good function estimation for the probability density itself then you've solved every other problem
the disadvantage of course is that learning the probability density is usually harder than learning
the function that you want to the first place
usually require more data and usually with the same size database you're you're subject to
a larger amount of error in estimating the probability density then you would be simply
estimating y is equal to its effects directly the big advantage is that with correct
normalization you can string together a whole sequence
one of these latent variables in order to
in order to build relatively complex models
so here's perhaps the most
well at least in speed the most famous example of a bayesian system hidden markov
model is a system in which the the label at each time depends on the
labels that all the previous times as well as depending on the acoustic observations
that is to say we we suppose that that your speech articulation system is some
set of
moving tongue and lips and so on and some some sort of intentions in the
vocal folds that where the vocal folds approximate in the vocal folds separate and that
in fact there's only a discrete finite number of settings of all that apparatus that
matters so we move through this space of finite state is the discrete space of
state variables and in a particular state
the this speaker produces a particular set of acoustic spectra
so that in effect the probability of a particular set of acoustic spectra given a
particular set of other words
is the is the probability of the current word given the previous work
times the probability that the speaker's lips and tongue and gods and so on transition
from the state they were in time t minus one to state the time time
t given the world that you're in
times the probability of getting a particular acoustic spectrum given that the lips and tongue
and glottis and soft palate and so on or in a particular state
these things are is this is this is the usual decomposition is used in speech
recognition and hidden markov models i think you've seen in karen's talk on tuesday that
we can decompose it further in order to bring more information to their but the
usual decomposition is to is to talk about the language model which is a lookup
table the pronunciation model which is a lookup table linear acoustic model which is itself
some kind of universal approximator like like a mixture of gaussians
learning and bayesian system is usually some variation of maximum likelihood learning and as in
discriminative system if you have fewer than a thousand tokens you need to do some
kind of regularization the usual to two of the common kinds of regularisation our maximum
posterior probability estimation where instead of maximizing the probability of the data sets we maximize
the probability of the parameters that is we maximize the probability of the log prior
and other ten
if we had a calcium prior
would be that
so it looks like an l two
regularized version of maximum likelihood
this method which was inspired by trying to do bayesian thing trying to do
sensible probabilistic inference turns out to look just like sort of the regularisation schemes that
we cooked up before so that tells us that there is a sensible thing to
what we tried to do before was optimise the negative log probability lost that's how
i introduced logistic regression
here we're just trying to do inference in a probabilistic model
we're not tied to particular loss function say
in a decision rule
we can pick the loss function
in practice
we might do better logprob loss than other losses because it does look a bit
like fitting in
when we made that connection and then
answers questions we ask for like how to set lambda
OK a
in the bayesian framework any question that you might want to ask about how do
i said something given the data is
look at the probability then you do something
sensible which is completely determined by
the rules of probability
what we wanted to do was find the label that optimizes this criterion the expected
loss under model
and this posterior distribution over the weights actually depends on lambda
but we don't know lambda so what we do is we say
well if we did know lambda we know what the posterior distribution is
and we average over
what we think lambda is now we've seen the data
so this integral turns out to be the correct thing to do
do in order to work out this distribution if you don't know lambda
it won't be obvious right now exactly how you compute all these terms but it's
basically applying bayes rule and applying standard probability calculus manipulation
we have a method which is completely defined if we put a prior distribution over
lambda then
we don't need to set lambda i that we can
just average over everything that we don't know
we consider all possible and is in all possible weights simultaneously
something else we could do is optimized lambda so now
as we approximated integral before by optimizing we could say well
maybe this average is dominated by
the best possible and selects just optimize the posterior probability of lambda given the data
and use that one lambda in order to construct a distribution over way to that
thing is used a lot in
it is roughly called empirical bayes or type two maximum likelihood
this framework gives you ways of setting the three parameters without using validation set which
is nice
i would always use validation set as well just to check it maybe maybe this
gives you always setting lots of different lambda simultaneously and then you can use the
validation set right at the end to check your final performance
the main reason i put this slide up as i can tell you guys what
i actually do so now we've got the bit of the party where i can
tell you when my research center
integrals that i've written up once you've been given a bit of practice
very mechanical easy to do
we write down the model is very obvious what the correct bayesian answer should be
but it turns out that the required integrals
quite formidable
the high dimensional integrals the aren't analytically tractable and very difficult to compute numerically
that isn't a reason necessarily not to use
bayesian method but what it does mean is that you need to approximate the integrals
and because this area is seen as important it's the huge research effort in approximate
inference which basically means
the integrals to this form expectations and the probability distributions
how can i
do something which will work well
so again people try and come up with objective functions
the algorithms can optimize so they variational method say
you can reconstruct on moments of the random variable
and if you recall
you may or may not not not not to you know that this
this thing here this exponential thing is is actually a universal kernels
this experience the exponential kernel we can show this is a so-called conformal modification of
gaussian kernel
which is also universal so it's
if the space is dense in the set of continuous functions
it satisfies the conditions of this result here
everything that i said before holds true for this kind of thing but we can
also plug other universal kernels in here
now before i have shown you several times how to convert
such a difference vectors into quantities like this which suggests that we can also handle
them using the methods of statistical learning theory
indeed if you take here the difference vector between
and the sample from the distribution you can rewrite it like this
you know it's an expectation of function here we have the mean of the same
over some function class this is exactly
kind of a
quantities that are studied by VC theory
PAC theory
and one can combined this kind of quality using uniform convergence methods one it's certain
to be more complicated but if basically for idea
of the unit ball
with a given distribution well behaved in this thing will go to like one of
the square
OK so
it's not not talk about some
of before i talk about applications may be just one word about one more word
about this what does it mean if this thing goes to zero
it's not quite the same as saying we are estimating measure because and it's certainly
not saying that we can estimate measuring the general setting independent of the problem because
that's an impossible problem so what this is one this is just saying is that
if we look at this problem
through the unit ball of RKHS then at some point we can detect differences anymore
so all you people
which we have to choose ourselves we have choose the RKHS
by specifying what kind of differences we are interested in at some point maybe that
uniform will not
contain functions that are sufficiently nonsmooth such as to be able to detect differences between
this anymore
and the thing is a little bit similar to
the public's conception of weak convergence of risks so remember in the BC bones you
don't study convert the convergence of the empirical measure
to the true measure
you start the convergence of risks
so we have to risk which depends on the empirical measure and the to measure
you you prove that this kind of risk is zero but that's a weaker condition
the actual measures conventions
OK so let's look at some applications of this kind of stuff
and probably i don't have time to go through all of them and i want
to collaborate leads to fewer than one of them is the two sample problem and
some of you
you might have seen this because of the great and gave a talk about some
of this NIPS last year but we just spent two minutes a little bit about
so we in this case we assume we have two samples x and y are
drawn from distributions p and q respectively and based on these samples we want to
decide whether p is equal to q or not
so if we were CART this difference vectors we can
working on in terms of kernels an expression is only dependent kernels this these three
so all three expectations which we can write a single expectations over this quantity here
which is by the way also positive definite kernel but also it's the kernel of
the so-called you statistics but don't worry about that is this quantity with which does
this kind of pairwise comparisons
and in terms of this thing we can write all difference
and actually will we call it the square of this difference we can write it
as the
expectation over this
colonel h
and we can give an estimate of
d had sample based estimator which is summing over these ages
and excluding the times y is equal to j
in order to avoid the bias and one can prove that this is an unbiased
estimator of this discrepancy between the two
and one of the nice things if you look at this formula because this is
one actually has to compute to perform
such a two sample test it's just it's trivial to implement this just double for
so we can do is relatively fast and also one can do it
basically for any kind of data where one can define counts so one can also
do it for strings in graphs and other kind of stuff
this thing can be shown
so these empirical estimate it can be shown to converge to the true quantity in
probability with a relatively fast rate
so this is again a uniform convergence time bond
one could use this as the basis for a test
but actually it doesn't work very well
which is because as most of us know uniform convergence bounds often very loose pessimistic
so in practice i have to admit that actually classical statistics works better in this
case if we study the asymptotic distribution of this
quantity here so this discrepancy between the estimated difference in the means and the true
difference in the means then one can study what this converges to
both in the case p non equal to q
and in the case p equal to q
in one case we get it goes in the other case we get something more
and i don't want to go into details on it
but based on this one can
device test
test users another hypothesis that p is equal to q
so just to give you an idea so p is equal to queue then this
thing would be zero that's on the hypothesis if we then observe based on the
we have a relatively large sample
and we noticed that the had is significantly different from zero and we know something
about the distribution of t hat that we can sort of see how unlikely it
but in fact the
null hypothesis was all likely it is that the null hypothesis was true or one
likely it was rejected and building that one contesting
that getting rid of letters at the beginning and at the end of the word
and what is left after
same thing is what i did before i was counting how many times with an
individual letter pianist string i can also count how many times does the substring appear
in history
so i'm going to host i denotes with w
bars subscript you the number of times you is inside w so it's really the
number of left different left bates i can get rid of and still find my
w in my of my you inside the
so i just amplification my notation to go just one little bit for
so if i had the word for substring well i've got another word which is
so subsequences the same substring everything is instead of just getting rid of letters at
the beginning and at the end of the word i can get rid of them
in any position
OK so sub sequence is also used in math just to say that i can
take the first the fourth seventh and the eighth letter
so that makes me have a subsequence instead of substrate
and got little recursive definitions to say that obviously a string is a subsequence of
itself and that if i take off one letter then i obtain a subsequence cycle
repeat recursively and through the third rule which is saying that if x is a
subsequence of y and y is itself subsequences z then x is a subsequence of
so it's a little bit of combinatorics
now why am i talking about combinatorics because they will be involved in the algorithms
OK i need to know how to count to be able to then when i'm
going to want to do things like extracting features which we saw earlier on was
important i would want to count how many times does an individual substring or individual
subsequence appear to be able to do that well i need to be able to
wikileaks how many there are in the inferior so if i'm talking about prefixes so
prefixes all substrings which what comes before is the empty string is really the beginnings
of words the luckily the
luckily the semantics likely the words where it used to define the concept defined the
mathematics of these things are pretty of speaking so they correspond to what we'd like
to do
so how many prefixes string have well the string being of length n can have
n plus one different prefixes y plus one count the MT one and the string
so is a prefix of length zero one of length one of things to up
to length
how we substrings can you have well this time the combinatorics correspondence choosing one individual
starting position one individual finishing position your string
OK i think we'll cross each other so that we know that the mathematics if
it is to give you an multiply by n plus one divided by two if
i'm not wrong
it might be a plus one by plus two divided by two to check and
now it's it's quadratic OK the number of substrings is quadratic so it's not something
to be something we can do if we want to actually go through all the
different substrings of the string to be able to compare with something else that's something
we can actually do
now the numbers of sequences of string that's that's not quadratic that's not polynomial as
exponential because basically to be able to obtain a subsequence from a sequence what you
do is you just take the first letter and decided what i wanted to and
do i not wanted to choices look at the second letter do i want to
do i not want two choices third lead two choices and so on till the
end of two by two by two by two this means that any algorithm that
was consistent saying who
we go for each
subsequent of w do
is doomed to failure
not true if w is not very big that's all right if you're talking about
bioinformatics then that's wrong
you clearly enough be able to do anything like that
OK so you have to think about a different way of doing things
let's just look at a few of these basic algorithmic problems on strings so the
first thing is that if i have got two
looking for the maximum subsequence of the two strings we know how to do it
i mean there are different ways of doing this that can be various maximum so
that means the longest subsequence common two strings so there's many reasons to do this
i mean when you buy a set of strings you may be wanting to take
two strings the same i'm trying to find a machine is reasonably machine learning reasons
trying to find some sort of pattern that suits the strings someone trying to find
something that that corresponds OK so the problem about doing this is that it looks
nice you can do it and we're going to see how to do it but
for two it's OK we know how to do it but if given a set
of strings
right and i want to find this sort of pattern this representative string for a
set of strings which could be sort of what is in common with all the
strings then i'm going to be facing what we're going to call an NP hard
this term
it is among so many possible w and we we like to to find out
that is so that
this is the is maximized
so these so so-called editors called maximum maximum margin
and that's one spacious thing about and the whole maximum margin classifiers
finally we have a quadratic programming problem so this is the first somehow it is
the first SVM formulation we
we try to maximize these usually we like to do minimisation will maximizing something easy
because equivalent to minimizing the reciprocal so we
we can minimize the normal w divided by two but school is an increasing function
so we can remove it
therefore we get stuck w transport stop divided by two so this is the objective
function that we want to minimize the subject to certain constraints so that constance will
now we still hold two
classify all the training instances
the x i was circles they should be greater or equal to one where we
suppose feliciano unless now we don't see greater than zero we secretory CO two plus
and the
four triangles we say this or you could minus one but we don't like to
write two types of quality so we tried to come back together
so you multiply by apple's site
so remember now we have less than or equal to minus one but if we
multiply while both sides there
this minus one times minus one becomes one and they also have to change the
the inequality sign so then you get with article to one as well so those
two inequalities
they can be combined together as a single fault so we have no training services
and for each one we call it is correctly classified
this is a quadratic programming that is the source
of course it is not good
because there that may not be linearly separable
we can always use linear by this is an example that you can never use
a straight line separating the two classes of training instances
instead use non-linear kernel
so we do two things here
first we
must allow training areas
the even if you don't do that
then this is the so-called invisible optimisation problem
the idea of a constant optimisation problem is that
from from the set of candidates which satisfies all constraints that you selected one so
that the objective function is minimized but now
there's no w be satisfying all those constraints because you cannot find any straight line
forty separate all the training instances
so you you don't have any candidates to select before doing the minimization so this
is the so-called invisible optimisation problem so you need to a large training area
so here i no idea about separating all the training instances i just try to
separate and maybe some of the
but later we will say that it generally not a good idea to feed all
the training instances
with the purpose of allowing training error is not too is not only to make
this optimisation problem is feasible we also whole actually to get even better better testing
accuracy so you feel the
training data that may be the performers is good
so it was it we're going to do and then another thing is
instead of directly using certain nonlinear curves
is very difficult to model nineteen because we didn't many nonlinear curves making high school
a very smart idea is that in stead of modeling of the nucleus in the
original space we try to make the data into a higher dimensional
feature space
and that has major consequences
now the values for all five as you can imagine depend of course entirely on
the string
if you have a very thick strings
and it is very stiff it's very hard to bend of will be high
also if young's modulus of the wire is is very high
that it is extremely difficult to deform it's often will also be high
so there is no such thing as one value for all of you for all
your piano strings they all
different for all the strings
but i do want
to do calculation to give you an order of magnitude idea what effect this would
on the piano
so i choose a value for all
which is not
entirely absurd although with a higher values of of possible
and then i want to calculate is you
qualitatively what difference that would make for a particular string in the piano
and so the case that i have chosen i think of five
ten to the minus two
i think the tension which is very common for piano strings which is two hundred
and fifty newtons
i think the length of the piano strings
which is one meter
just for simplicity
and i give it a mass per unit
of ten grams
from either
i thought it would be ten to the minus two
you know as i units to the minus two kilograms
the media
and i want to explore ways you tens harmonic
of this string
he divided by u
by the way this
can be written and i will write it down again in
this is also team
provided by
k square
because of
it could afford
this is the kind of thing
but i knew
so t be divided by new
it's easy enough that is two point five times ten to the force
i have to know what
but k is well
let that ten
let the one is two meters
fixed at both ends
it's one meter
the langston lambda one this
to me it's all about ten is ten times smaller
so that's two divided by ten
so OK
which is of course by definition two pi divided by lambda ten
is then ten by
so now i have all the ingredients
to compare
this omega square this term
with that term to see by how much the frequency changes
the case where we have no dispersion
so this first now
you can check that of course for yourself level right down omega squared again
it is that terms
this deal you
and then you have to multiply by
OK square and then i find two point five times ten to the seventies
and then i can calculate of k two to four and i have all the
ingredients on the blackboard
you find that this term is ten to four
if i calculate roughly what only guys
i'm not interested in the exact value of omega you will see shortly y
you'll find that omega
is about five thousand radians per second in this case
which translates into a frequency
of about eight hundred hertz
the value itself is not so important but what is important now
as a result of this
extract number
the frequency will go up by point zero two percent
and this of course you can check immediately for yourself
which are calculated
and point o two percent increase
means in this case one six of words
but the attends harmonic
if you expected exactly eight hundred hertz this is of course not exact but i
think round the number then it will be one six of offers higher because of
the dispersion relation
but if you make of ten to the minus one which is by no means
then it will go up by one point six words
and so the bottom line hours
that for real piano string omega and is no longer and times only got one
and that's the reason that is why pianos go sharks
as musicians saying
that means that the higher harmonics the frequencies a little higher
proportional was
is an
and and that's what's called mixtape and go sharp
professor with allows
developed several years ago when he was lecturing at o three
a tory model
which uses on the computer
and the tory model has the following
the dispersion relation it is it has no direct connection with the stream
no direct connection with any physical thing but it simply use
for the purpose of demonstration
and that is the only guest grids
equals the squared
times case grid
times one
as of
OK script
and if you're not careful you may think that it is the same as this
but it's not
it's very different
the difference is
that this term here has the squaring it
and this term here does not have this these are totally different dispersion relationship
in this program
that you're going to see
bullock which flows
shows you six ways
all six have the same amplitude
but they differ the shortest wavelengths and the longest wavelength differed by twelve percent
so to neighbouring wavelengths are two-and-a-half percent part
the velocities of the individual
during the week and i think i'm going to talk about now is a graph
cut and the great thing about graph cuts
is that compared with all these other methods to the problem that i'm talking about
is actually exact
which is quite remarkable i mean normally we find the problem which can be solved
exactly you know that you've oversimplify the problem is not really any interest that this
is this is the tremendous canopy some middle ground a problem which people actually care
about you know you sort computer graphics tool that really does have this really is
solving this problem using this method the solution in this
the setting is exact
one of the reasons that turns out to be exact is because we restrict ourselves
to a binary problem where
the x's cannot take the value zero and there are many problems like the one
way you allow transparency you know what we're talking about right at the beginning you
allow the pixels be mixtures of foreground and background then immediately you need real numbers
or perhaps integers and that point this method while still extremely powerful is no longer
exact but you know something we should just take a few minutes to enjoy the
fact that we've got a problem people really care about the hard problem
that has
inexact algorithm
OK so here is the
he is the problem
this is the graphical model
for that
problem is just the same
graphical model that i wrote down algebraic algebraically earlier
it simply says that we
look at individual pixels his an observed excel
and each individual pixel
is considered to be generated from a palette
the state of this very well i the foreground or background talent and the you
know full explanation of the colour content this excel is simply that we drew at
random from the palate corresponding to foreground background
but in the graphical model we also have a link between adjacent pixels and this
was the link which was initially the easing prior that love is the penalty for
different labelings of adjacent pixels and then we
went to the modified using priors
where the prior was now polluted with data to because this graphical model is still
perfectly legal the graphical model is still perfectly correct the only thing that you can
no longer say is that these terms are associated exclusively with the prime
and that's the energy function we have now the
the graph cut trick is to take this
graphical model
and and we're intending to solve for m a p estimation which i guess i
didn't explicitly say there are many things you can do with posteriors but the thing
that we're going to do is maximized to find the most probable
posterior labeling
and this optimisation can be done by taking all the elements of this graphical model
and laying it out on the new graph
this is a different graph now which is not a probabilistic graphical model in the
same sense this is now the a network
which are going to think about actually in terms of network flow
and let's see where all the terms in the original graphical model MAP two in
this network so the network as the source and the sink so you can think
of the
of oil being pumped into the network of pipelines somewhere in siberia and
coming up
in next to tilbury docks or something up on the ten and to be distributed
around the country
you'd like to know actually
could you best route the oil for this
network and you also like to know how much oil can we get through the
network given that all of the
pipelines in this network of pipelines all the arcs of the graph have a capacity
the push oil as hard as you can to this network until you can have
saturating links everywhere and you just can't get any more
through this slightly artificial i mean it's not quite oil and pipelines it because you
know pipelines don't actually have a hard limit on how much oil can flow through
they have them more like resistors they have all the limits on the relationship between
pressure and flow but we're going to think of slightly weird kind pipeline where
there's a capacity limit and it turns out that all of the
all of the
numbers from the
graphical model get transferred into various locations on this pipeline so let's see
for example
fk the likelihood associated with this pixel has two values of k of zero in
one depending whether x is zero one and it turns out that this pixel is
associated let's say with this node in the pipeline
so actually there are as many
nodes in the network
pipes here as there are pixels in the image one of these for every pixel
in the image
this are here from the source
to the pixel
carries as its capacity limit
the likelihood value associated with background the likelihood of the background labels and similarly the
like of the foreground labeling goes on this
so that accounts for all of these vertical arcs here in all these the block
now the horizontal arcs get the
get the
using penalties
this article here
gets the penalty for this pixel being labeled differently from this pixels
and now
and we introduce the idea of the cut
so now i cut is a line in the network which completely separates the source
from the sea
and so
if i travel along the car i can register every time i cross
and every time i cross and i look up its value be FK of zero
and fk one or g value
and just sum it up so that the value of this cut is the total
of all of the values of the arcs that were crossed in separating the source
completely from the sea
so actually
there is a one-to-one correspondence now between
the value of the cut
the log posterior probability because when you
evaluate evaluated cut you're just summing up all of the energy terms in this model
visiting every term once
exactly and summing up its its energy so actually summing up all of these all
of these couplings is exactly the same as evaluating
posterior probability in this graph for particular configuration now which configuration is it
well let's see
when i cut this are
there should be great article one and all others
it should be less than or equal one
before because this there is really no
it's simply not interested in the decision function is you only to be greater than
or equal to minus one or a simple decision boundaries is what is going to
be the largest event that's why we use this as makes him to class prediction
so this is very simple
so this is for one against the rest
so from that we know it it's only
so this one is positive and all the rest
i think
well there's no
but one against one
well so far then we know
now we have
let's train occasions two binary years and each one involves all the four classes of
training data for one use
class one school the signal using his life history so one patent free and you
can find one so we have occasions two two classes
so i can give
we give simple here this is the case for
so four classes support useful means we must intrinsic six
so the first one is one of those who so for this one because what
is considered positive crystal
consider negative
so we have this is about a single one of the same year we get
six decision functions
well the next question is
how do prediction
this is also simple so there's just trying to see what is so plainly
for his
we just put it into laws policies these functions
the first one the first one is one of the reasons for it so only
thing that is because one four four three elastic something in the system so this
here is is this should be in this one little one she it was one
in all wonderful is this one and the phrases
problem then so
link is
we have a table showing the number of balls per class
so this is one of the tree
the story for you only get one vote so this one of one should be
this is a reasonable way to do
prediction so the idea behind the opposing is
if you have a nice really
not clear what they for whatever what street whatever it is full
should say this one
in a situation in perfect situation you should get minus one false
from your real class label
you should take a minus one but but you also believe is a nice place
you also within other classifiers that a street or performer
this is for the the idea is that in this situation the addition these events
is random
so the other places can attend morning k minus levels so that everyone else is
doing is
so reason for using
it's kind of the exchange
you see that this is not very reliable but they it works quite well
in some situations you may have
in some cases they have the same number of votes
we have a situation where the tree
each or
or you may do so for analysis
but this is the simplest way to radiation there also ways of using decision that
this is so i sixty series and i was always trying to
combat in order to use that to find out the win
ten really is
something that
this is a good question because of these or minus one
because of his
he he's not the initial conditions it should be always be less than or equal
to minus one
in in his relationship
well we could process one so he was still work because something could recall two
possible should be always clear all others there is article minus one so this is
a normalisation is usually not
i think i have ever done
decision by using one against the rest
these days it is useful for look some basic situation to see if really want
to have some examples this one this list does it really work
that's the beach
of the these
that's the change
it is in many practical applications this kind this is you is going to be
very embarrassed
you always have
there are a lot of difficulty
and you find first which are the the eigenvalues and then you
replace eigenvalue in here to find would which is the corresponding
eigenvector so when did the metrics a of a again we're talking
about square matrices this much is a generalization is for square
matrices when the metrics phase real-valued and symmetric
we know that our eigenvalues are also real value
and we know also that we can find a basis of eigenvector
which are all or dead which are or to allow one which other
we can force them to have norm one which is
an interesting seeing that you in fact can you know that you can
change you have a change of basis which will give you
a only being that a data metrics we is
eigen values on on that they know
and yeah so a can be rewritten like that
which which it has really interesting properties since
it favor right a
let's call it g this day and matrix t and i want to raise it to
poer for example what does that mean let's say to to be to begin
with that would be so two times this metrics
and because p it's a it's constructed with the eigenvectors
which are all or to the nile between them and with base one these
in fact end up to be identity and thus
this is only p v square the key so for and that yeah of course to
n because you which is just a and then the same seem
and so it's really easy to compute the the poer of metrics that
you have that de lies because the diagonal
to the poor our to with yeah the core n is only take the
diagonal elements the raise it to the poor
another scene is another way of seeing that also which is interesting
is that you you can fact look at the
the transform the yeah transformation of vector
x as in fact also something like that which in fact when you
give you something like he's
so at as that's what's called spectral decomposition
in which in fact you will have
which heat you will have so as you look at this
in our transformation in terms of decomposition in the eigenvectors
and how to give you intuition of that let's say
i had a really easy a metrics which is
this one ok so that we give me as eigenvector
yeah which are the normal in
the normal based noise due to the user base we take in which we
we decompose yeah ok then the user base both it
let's say i have the one one one vector
which is this transformation with this information
so i like this representation because it's very easy and very common to compute
in data point distances yeah
to do care nearest neighbors or whatever else and in fact i'm gonna base a
lot of material on computing distances like this
the dimension normalized between points are drawn from a gamma am and the means to
sigma square now the interesting thing about this the variance of this distribution is eight
sigma squared over p e
so i speedy goes high
this variance goes to zero
so only relative if you look at the
i mean divided by the square root the variance you've got this scaling up even
as you go to very high dimensions what you'll see is that all the interpoint
a good dataset
the same distance apart
in this calcium egg so any sample you take will be equidistant from every other sample
which is a
annoying characteristic if you're trying to do things like came nearest neighbors because as you change kay
find no well if you if you look at the volume and david you're considering
as you increase the
minister there may be some go from known labels to all
your points neighbours this basically says that for this density every data point is a neighborhood
over each other in high dimensions
okay so
now seems to be a bad thing about our sensation use gaussians you might think
but actually for any data where you've got independence over features
the central limit theorem applies to these farms were taking an
the same results come out they just don't come out quite nicely and analytically in the low sample area
you get exactly the same thing going on the variance about the mean scales as period one over so
distribution you sample from independently
will eat these different effect if you
one and how it differs well the guassian
in this video
it's like if you're one of the things that
one of the reasons i believe we're here is because there's large telescope here and then i'd like large telescopes
so the use of analogies as well if you're standing on the
looking out this hypersphere
okay so it's high dimensional space of these galcians samples how would look well all
the samples will be uniformly distributed across space is a bit like the stars they're
not quite uniformly distributed yet but if you're standing at the center this hypersphere
so it's a three-dimensional sphere it but it's a hypersphere
in general looking out these data points like stars distribution over space and beautiful
if you've nongaussian densities subgaussian or supergaussian
in the hypersphere the point or cluster
i e there alongside the axes are forty five degrees axes depending
on with view super subgaussian so these will be uniformly distributed over this hypersphere anymore
it would be quite pretty but the same problems will exist
this is behave very counterintuitively in high dimensions
we can compute the density squared distances analytically for the gas in case and for
nongaussian independent systems we can invoke the central limit theorem so let's see how these
apply for some real data that's what we're gonna do now is we see that
this problem and we can compute the theoretical interpoint distance between two
data and it's valid because the central limit theorem
dataset if the features are independent
so here's some example datasets well that's just test our intuition so this is sampled
from a thousand dimensional gaussians and what i'm showing is the distribution of squared distances
between each data point
and what i'm showing you there is a histogram and then bang directly is the
bit about gamma distribution we derived before
look-alikes leave the theory fits the data
um that's good
we can sample from the calcium great dataset thousand samples thousand data points so around
a million interpoint distances in this histogram
okay now i use a few examples here and if it's still going this ten
thousand interpoint distances if it's still excellent
okay so let's take at and that's applied to real data
so that we can get on its paper so we have to have a little
artificial example then a real data example
okay the real data here is a little bit artificial as well this is a famous
dataset which is the so-called oil data
it some
some oil flowing in a pipeline
and dates from bishop and james this ninety three papers is widely used as a benchmark and dimensionality reduction
it's all flowing
from well so it's got oil gas and water it
and they according to the speed
i guess reynolds number and stuff like that
mix in different ways in turbulent flow you basically get this homogeneous everything mixed together
but then there's two types and laminar flow co one is gas oil water
and many other one i think is gas oil water i hope i've got the
right way around it might be gas not must be guess who knows
like so that
now you've got twelve measuring movements which gamma ray densitometry measurements so these are measuring the density across here
this is the classics and the learning problem because although clearly if you see the
density on each these you should be able to determine which domain urine
the physics and the thing is a little bit complicated so in fact it turns
out this data simulated if you read carefully the original paper and it stimulated by
understanding the physics of these systems and what these things would really so little a
warning there
it's simulated data but it's from a realistic physical system
what you can see here is you've got i think twelve senses in total
are measuring the density
and the section these pipes
so that's well readings
if we now compare
the truth
to what we theoretically expect a happen we see that this is the theoretical curve
for thee into data point distances and this is the actual histograms
case that's not too bad is a little bit
mismatch twelve
if the predicted variance if these interpoint distances is point six six
and actual variance we've observed is is closer to
so this is a quick nap
have some other aspects of the course
will have weekly lectures it's lecturer
on intensive
in total is only thirteen lectures
will meet once a week here for lecturer
there's readings
there is voluminous readings there's readings about every topic we'll talk talk about and the
readings were specifically designed for this course i highly recommend that you become familiar with
the readings if you have a question after lecture it's probably there is probably explained
we'll do online tudor problems
we send you an email if you've pre-registered for the course so you may already
know about this the idea is going to be
that is
ways that you can prepare for the course by doing computer exercises
and we will also use those same kinds of exercises in all the class sections
we will have to kinds of lab experiences besides lecturer
the other two events that have that you have to attend are softer lab and a design pattern
that's the practice part
so i have to learn a little bit about the theory by going to a lecture by
by doing the readings and then you go to the lab and try some things out
we call the first lab software lab
it's a short lab it's an hour and few work individually try things out you write little programs that you
coursework and check the program this year if it's okay
and it primarily the exercises in the software are due
during the software lab that on occasion will be
extra things do
i dare to later
the due dates are very clearly written in the tudor exercises
once a week as a designer that's a three hour session in which you work with a partner
the reason for the partner
is that he
intent the difference between the design labs and the softer land is that the design labs
ask yourself slightly more open ended questions
the kind of question that you might
i have no clue what we're asking
open and that the kind of thing that you will be asked to do after
graduating designed the system wouldn't system
so the idea is not working with a partner will give u
i second immediate source of help
a little more confident if neither knows the solution so that you raise your hand
and say i don't have a clue what's going on here
so the idea is that's one so we we do softer lab individually what we
we do a design lab a little more open ended with partners
there's a little bit every homework
four total
not much compared other subjects mostly practice
there's an no quiz
just a help you keep pace to make sure that you don't
get too far behind
the first fifteen minutes every design lab starts with an end up with is the
native quasars are intended to be simple
if you've caught up
if you are up-to-date
so the idea is then you go to
design lab the first thing you do is a little fifteen minutes
then queries in a quiz uses a tudor much like the homework to do much like the pipeline tudor
and it's intended to be simple
but it doesn't mean
please get a designer one time
inadequacies are administered by the softwar
it starts when you hour when the design-led starts it times out fifteen minutes later
so if you come ten minutes late you'll have five minutes to do something that
we plan to give me fifteen minutes form
we will also have exams and interviews interviews are
intended to be um
a one-on-one conversation about how the labs went
and we'll have to midterms and finals
so that's kinda the logistics and the idea behind the logistics is practice theory practice
come to the labs try things out make sure you understand develop a little code
type it and see if it works
if it works your on top of things
you're ready to get the next batch
the information from the lectures and readings
okay let's go on and let's talk about the technical material in the first module the cause the software module
we kick the course of talking about software engineering
for two reasons we'd like you know about software engineering is an incredibly important part of our department
it's an incredibly important part ivy engineering absolutely any system of any modern system
but we also like you to know about it because it provides a very convenient
way to think about it a convenient language
the think about
the design issues
engineering issues in all the other parts of the class so it's a very good place to start
so it it what what i will do today is talk about some of the very simplest ideas
about abstraction and modularity
in what i think of has the lowest level granularity
how do you think about abstraction and modularity at the micro scale
at the individual lines of code scale
as i said earlier we will add we progress
look at modularity and abstraction at the higher scale
but we have to start somewhere and we're gonna start by thinking about how do
you think about abstraction and modularity at the microscale
special about programming
what we are trying to do
by supporting
by selecting examples that supports meaning analogy and self explanation
and that also provide an interface
that's one example is selected
triggers the proper behaviors and therefore maximises the learning and problem solving that you can
do by using example just to give you a brief demo of
this interface this the system is in the domain on newtonian physics so the student
can select some problems in the system knowledge base and
the system tracked student can type equation in that kind control
elements like forces acceleration vectors in the free body diagram
the system tracks all the students actions and provide feedback on whether their actions are
correct or not in this case the student draw
the direction of the force in the in the wrong direction it's turned around the
student can at any time for
an example
the system selects example to present and as you can see the example is
presented with these boxes that cover different parts of example solution
and the idea of of having the boxes is to actually try to come up
with discourage
claims copying for students within gay we tend to do so
without these tools and also allow the system to track the students doing how the
students using examples
so what
howard examples selected so i said the main form of scaffolding in this system is
to try to select an example that is the best that can increase the students
but engage in the right meta cognitive processes was on problem the way this works
just going to give you a general description of the system architecture and how
example selection happened is that the system has a problem solving model that module that
it takes as input a knowledge base that includes that has the representation of all
the physics rules relevant
solve problems in between physics takes the problem specification and generates automatically solution representation of
the solution
the specific problem that a graph representation showing how intermediate solution steps derive from physics
rules and previous steps in the solution this is done for several problems and examples
to create an example of the problem of poor
the problem is selected to is selected by the students problems loading the interface and
everything that the student does as have seen in the video
get sent to the culture model
that checks whether
individual actions are correct or incorrect using the solution graph representation and use information
two update
the system systems knowledge the rest of the models
that is the dynamic work network that represents a any given point the sisters believe
of the evolution of student knowledge and the based on
and the cognitive skills based on the solution actions that the student has generated up
to a certain point
when the students to see an example
what happens is that the system uses this to the model
to engage in what we call the example selection mechanism by
doing in expected utility calculation for each example knowledge base to see how
what is the potential of these examples to aid learning and problem-solving and the way
this not just the very high level i cannot go into details is based using
this representation of example solution of the problem solution this graph based representation the system
can compute similarity
between corresponding steps based on whether two steps have rules in common whether they are
they use it was used the same objects in the solution
and uses using this measure of similarity
the system
engages in the simulation of how
a given student the current students with specific level of knowledge of the physics rules
and specific meta cognitive skills
can you give an example
to solve the current problem
and to learn from it
OK so the simulation process generates a prediction of learning and problem solving success for
the specific student
this prediction is formalized using a multiattribute utility function that gives the expected utility of
these examples in terms of learning and problem solving success
this process is done for every example known by
in the in the course knowledge base and the
in the end the system selects the example with the maximum expected utility
so we evaluated this mechanism presented the paper
this guy two years ago
we have sixteen participants in a lab setting solving problems with coach
was within subject design that is also all students
where even to the two experimental conditions there were two experimental conditions in one condition
the students solve problems with the aid of examples they were selected by
the system using the decision theoretic approach that i just described
the second condition received as examples you problem solving example there was most similar to
a given problem
and we use this condition because the approach of selecting the most similar example is
the one that other tutoring system in the literature have used
so the result in high-level description
is that students in the conditional where these examples were selected adopted by the system
generated significant statistically significantly more self explanation and fewer copy of the students in the
condition where the examples were given the examples given were the most similar
and this led to better
and this was in no cost for problem solving so there were no difference is
not significant differences in problem solving success between the two conditions so the examples selected
by the example selected by the system were good for both learning and problem solving
what we found was that the condition the only difference is that students made on
average more errors during problem solving and took longer to solve the problems but that
makes sense that byproduct of learning if you copy from an example definitely fast and
you don't make mistakes but you also to look at
we see the result is providing very encouraging evidence that our proposed decision theoretic approach
two examples select selection can trigger learn by triggering
good meta cognitive processes
and as the future work we want to generate a more proactive adaptive interventions as
the student uses example currently there is no system intervention if the system realizes that
the students copying too much but want to try to
january that give hints discourage students from copying if you're doing it too much
and also we want to explore the use of eye tracking
instead of the masking interface to capture student reasoning and what to do that because
we believe that i tracking can give better insight on what the students doing whether
or not student self explaining away
i want to use eye tracking
our belief the possible the potential use utility of my truck is there
we have already investigated the value of eye tracking using eye tracking information
to monitor student self explanation in different learning environments