nine light situation
so is not completely dark but
so now i'm going to move the light across the two wires
you're going to see that there are locations where the potential difference is very large
because we had resonance
and therefore you'll see a lot of light
and there are locations where there are no deadlines
and you will see no light
let's first go here that's the open end
the open and is clearly where the electric field is fairly high it's like
the situation of the string which an open and
you an and i know there
we have an entire node right here
but look when i move the light a quarter wavelength goes out
i must be known new to why maybe not exactly all the node line
and now
i move another quarter wavelength and the light goes on again
now i'm going to move it back to the open end
you see the light is on
i move a quarter wavelength light goes off
i more than a quarter wavelength light goes on
i more than a a quarter wavelength light goes off
there is amazing
now i think i'm going to move within a quarter wavelength
and the light goes on again
so the amazing thing that you see in front of your eyes
spending voltage
wave between these two i
it is across the wires
along the wires
now what i'm going to do
i'm going to short is out here
when i put the light bulb right in the middle here
you could put the light bulb a quarter wavelength
now when i showed up at the end
i'm no longer residence
no longer meets the resonance condition which i mean now an open
something that you can very easily
now the moment that i no longer had resonance
i no longer have very high potential difference
at the end i nodes
which i had before when i was resonance
but for sure
the moment that i sure about these lines at the end
the locations
which i now know lines must become entire nodes
now maybe not super duper and i nodes with huge potential difference
but probably high enough for that like to go on
ready for this
now i'm going to show it is out
and as you can see
the light goes on
now it may not be as bright
as you've seen it before
this is again and i note
and the light is on
so using a remarkable
demonstration here you see the standing waves
you see the note aligned you see and the lines you also see
that depends on the boundary condition
but if you
make these open one-quarter wavelength from the open end
there's an ant i know if you have it open one-quarter wavelength from open and
is notable line and if you should short could then it becomes and n type
i have a second
which is also very interesting let me turn this off
for some of you touch those get some problems
i have another very nice demonstration which is a cable which is a hundred and
twenty seven meters long
see here
starts there
goes all the way to make you see that is really big
and then it goes back there
and in this cable
i'm going to send in a voltage pulse physical actual cable
and correctional cable
has the wire which is at the core
and then there's this in and around it
that's why it's called correctional this is conducted this conductor and in this field here
with dielectric material to insulate
the two conducting
and what we're going to do we're going to send in your
voltage pulses
which have length of one hundred nanometers
so in nano seconds
one hundred times ten to the minus nine seconds hundred nano-second length of the
in other words if you look at the wire from the side here is the
and he is the shell
just a cross-section is so you see only that show
as the voltage falls
moved in this direction
you will see locally between
the outer conductor and in conductor locally you'll see that if you
goes to zero here and that marches then
with a certain speed of light
so as the whole passes
there will be in the field like this
then there is no poles there is no field between this and so in that
sense it's sort of similar to this transmission line except that the geometry is different
he is the collection cable
now comes the
i have an option to keep this and open
so sort the line
the very of the city and the idea is completely over
and i have the option
two shortcut
and when i shorted out
comes back
now shorted out mountain comes back
as the value
when i leave it open month and comes back
two months
we're going to show you this poles at three locations
today i will be
talking about systems
but before that's
i'll try and tell you why you should care
i call the scale out beyond mapreduce because big data
it's going to be somewhat a buzzword i'm a little embarrassed
specific data but
this is work in
that has been carried out with people on my
team at microsoft
the cloud and information services lab system
the outline of this talk
it's really up to par stock
the first part
i'll tell you about the kind of applications
they gave rise to the technology be talking about
at how this is now crossing the chasm from
the web companies
these kinds of scenarios first played out
to enterprise companies ant scenarios that affect pretty much every individual
i want to give you some broad architectural
at without context and get the second part of my talk
which is
about a system called reef which we have
working on land about to open source in the next month or so
if you are interested in building the next mahood
i strongly encourage you to download from consider
building on top of it
if you want to work with what many many petabytes you may actually find this useful
of processes and i keep getting asked what as oh well applied research lab that i started at
microsoft i got there about a year and a half ago
it is
an attempt to clone the yahoo applied research model which allowed
the focus for the group this global practice platforms machine learning
i both from a practical perspective andfrom data-driven enterprise applications
we work closely with the product team
in fact we are in the product side the house
the group contains basically scientists and research software development engineers andy experiment in a balance between
publications external research at internationally-backed it in
let's go to the main topic
why should you care about big data
i think the technology secondary
you should care about it because what we do with
i give you a sense of this going forward
what we are doing with it today
is something that simply would not have been cost-effective or even feasible
five ten years ago technology trends are playing a big role in making all this
come together now
other technical challenges
and in fact i think there are significant technical advances
if you will see the coming five ten years
on the system size
but frankly i don't think there are deal breakers you
well i think there will be many difficult challenges and some really nice work
they will have good the solutions
it's also gonna need to address the social and legal issues
these frankly gonna take much longer to really understand
but i will talk about them to be
the biggest gap before
might be people
people like you
who understand how to
uses these
data analytics platforms
i numerous groups have
identified a shortage
and the national academy of engineering cats committee
of a channel part is planning the workshop full curriculum training
talking about these issues
in early
so what's the big to do about it
all start with one example drawn from a young days
the idea of the web of
concepts all the web of things
is simply this
people don't want to get back
do you want elsewhere in this section
right they think in terms of some real world concepts
and those are the terms in which they want to see the results
and you can do this
if you crawl the web do information extraction at scale
and organize the resulting data
in an entry in an entity centric manner
so when i search for say mumbai
i don't want all pages that mention by
i want everything
i want to know about the city mumbai and they expect to to recognize
but there is an entity called by
and that information is find out
here's an example
if you search
ann arbor
you'll find a map and most restaurants
quite commentary
the sort of thing here do not
this was done by classifying web pages
at restaurant web pages
inside those domains menu pages as many pages
then extracting menu items from those menu pages and associating them the entity
the rest
right that particular restaurant
and now when someone searches for all really an hour
you'll only see those restaurants that actually serve daily
a south indian dish
in the restaurant
a funny story once driving through chicago
i promised my kids those which is a south indian classical
i put out my trusty
yahoo search
and it came up with a restaurant called taj mahal
my being smart so that's not rest
you get those
as an are
and i extraction works
so went and ordered
or try to
it wasn't on the menu
so this is really embarrassing all the way out said
described systems that do that are coming up here
OK and but course as we know it we can allow features the slide all
place but we don't know
how accurate those are when done
training is this right from the very beginning this is a rather ill-defined problem
we recollect that from our discussion of quantal theory this notion that there's all these
sort of nonlinear discontinuity isn't going from production articulation to the acoustics and acoustic perception
so we know that
these articulatory distances and acoustic distances can be really nonlinear
and really there's only small regions of the acoustic space correspond to regions of high
articulatory discriminability that is that there very sort of that we can think of there
being these decision boundaries that are fairly sort of narrow things within within our space
that actually
is it is an nice
a problem for support vector machines and so we see all support vector machines being
used a lot for this problem
but more generally
i think we see a lot of examples where
people have applied
the learning algorithms support vector machines time delay neural networks multi layer perceptrons
it's really difficult to say
from from there exist from one of the problems is is all these people are
not working on a common task
and i think you could also say that it's very so it's very difficult to
compare their results but in general you find that you can
four four depending on the feature system that you can do a reasonable job get
anywhere depending for particular for this
feature system here depending on the feature you can get anywhere from say seventy five
ninety five percent accuracy in feature detection
and is that good enough
i think you certainly in experiments that we don't we see that as we do
better and better in designing the feature detectors are overall system gets better and better
in other words the system that might actually do word recognition
in a way that's driven by these features
it's not clear what is what is good enough
i think i mean it's also not clear exactly exactly how wonderful would properly define
the task to see how well you doing but
you get the given the scenarios that i described basic neural network detectors can do
reasonably well
i mentioned this issue
embedded training and allowing for asynchrony
among distinct distinctive features of was talking to minutes
about how we can use models of vocal tract dynamics to allow for describing sort
of these loosely synchronized trajectories of the articulators in that's again something as difficult to
use the internet ASR engine but we can build these kinds of miles
but for now
i think the most interesting work that's been done is in a really compelling formalism
to use here is is is bayesian networks
and we see this has been done investigated by number of people
but in general a bayesian network is a special kind of directed case asynchronous graph
that allows us to describe dependencies in in a very general way
in particular what i've taken a figure here from a paper by jill franklyn
he has
a set of dependencies in this in this graph where for example
acoustic variables which we assume are these continuous
things where they might be of feature vectors of any kind
depend on
these discrete
he hidden
distinctive feature variables which are represented here these sort of open nodes
and each of these discrete hidden variables will basically correspond to
the distinctive features
and so we see that
we can describe the dependencies amongst our observable variables and are hidden feature variables in
terms of the edges
of this graph
they basically along each edge we have the conditional probability
and so we we have away then
apriori describing the relationships amongst are distinctive features
and basically we can do that by
by establishing
the the the fourth of this graph in terms of the allowable edges here that
that are considered significant and you can see for example here or the
all the distinctive features have the dependency on the manor class
you know if if you're if you're an HMM person we could think of these
these variables is basically hidden states
these are the
observations that we have whatever they might be there might be are they might be
we can think of the dependencies between
these observable acoustic variables and these hidden states as being described by
garcia mixtures
if you like those
if you're HMM person
and we can
a bit the dependencies between the states as being very much markovian right this is
the notion of a dynamic bayesian network is one that has these time dependencies and
that's what distinguishes the bayes network from dynamic bayes network
and you're getting a hideous introduction to bayes networks is that's what you if if
if you need that night there's a lot of excellent tutorial references for bayes nets
that you could be referred to
but anyway
so we have this markovian dependency and the previous time
and we are the system designer is basically has the freedom to establish what dependencies
they think are significant between the the state variables
OK so
questions about our
for one thing i
so i good even if you don't understand efficient
quezon ship should tell you
the classi i
so the point is when i hash forty nine
should forty nine produces me some index on the table say i
OK and everything
hashes to that same location
is linked together into west
every record
any questions about what the mechanics of this i hope that most of you have
seen this
scene hashing basic action
in six one right teachers sixty institutions external one
some piercings
is to teach
so what
so i realized this
this strategy
the first two worst case
so what happens in the worst case
with passion
narrator and so i could call
all as he's
all the keys in s
i happened pick because as
where my hash function happens to match
mapped them all the same value
that would be that OK
every key
two the the same slot
so therefore if that happens
then what is actually built is a fancy linked list
keeping this structure
OK all this stuff to the table the hashing et cetera
all that matters is
i have a long link lists
then how long is an access take
i want to take me to insert something
or more importantly that for example search for something find out whether something
in the worst case
it takes or in time
because they're all just to link to someone less access take
we assume the size of this is called
the worst case twenty this doesn't work so
so attractor
will see
data structures in worst-case do very well for this problem
they don't do as good as the average case the passion
so let's analyse the average case
or in the average case
after whatever you averages one probability have to state your assumptions
have to say
selection bias doesn't hurt me
the causes i'm able to learn i can store
it was it's not like i don't make that assumption you know like something almost
to determine out doesn't hurt me
so what can we conclude here that with
if we only make embedded faithfulness assumption
and you
crosses we wanna find even if there's hidden common causes even if this selection bias
the only thing that can really confounders is
the walls at things like the finasteride DHT
so there's not too much that can confound you but there is one thing in
my case i think that's what happened
morrison myself in that study
here's causal learning with temporal information
four we probably have time for this like i something at the end of causal
learning based on two variables
but i don't think it's a good idea to ever talk to do which is
getting fatigued and
several talk a for more than an hour because they get the team
this gives us all the more time so i'm going to cover this
number a unique for variables
but if you have some temporal information
suppose i have three variables
x y and c
and that's why are independent conditional on c
number before
with embedded faithfulness assumption we can not learn any causal influences
assuming embedded faithfulness we have to have these lines
now suppose there can be no causal path from x to the
because we know that precedes the time
it is only by temporal information they you know the temporal ordering of some variables
i think that's always came before in
in any
the link between text and c must be either that in b or c effects
precedes the
every element of a property
population either they have a hidden common cause that causes the we assume
again this this body here i'm not a philosopher they've been a philosopher
o for
no philosophers
i because
five back in possibilities
many on list because such that it's only reasonable to assume that something precedes something
some time
then in the can cause acts
the causes precede the effects of these are the only possibilities
so the causal DAG must be either that in d or e
of the arguments i gave before
is an edge
this was the situation if this and went this way
with x and y are independent
that's not what we observe
if this was
there again this one this way with h and y are independent which due to
the separation these acts my independent and it's now we observed
so see if you have travel information then you can learn
data from very
three variables
actually it depends on have my two thousand four book
all the cartoon i haven't beginning but that's as an example of how this can
be and i want to get that picture but i can't find it anymore
this is the stuff of learning causes from data on two variables
so it
pressure cover the
because of the fact that people are going to see the whole concept it turns
out we can learn a little bit about causes from data on two variables almost
like a light weight and you can you can learn much but i take you
through this stuff
of taking through something and then at the end up going to let you know
that it's not of much value
do you want it
if you want to see it
so do until too
one way to learn dead structure from data i mentioned this earlier i i talked
about the constraint based method but another way
which in some sense is powerful scoring
the DAG
now the woods before i i took the data
i want conditional independencies in front of my learning
the structure here i take the data and i scored again i'm not going to
go into the ways of scoring at a simple
simple score compute the probability of the data conditional on the DAG
given this tag what's the probability of this data we sum over all values of
the parameters of the DAG
and then compute the probability
the more likely
the data given that the higher the score today arguments then you choose
right that that's the alternative way of learning structure i say it's not intuitive like
the other way but it is another way
for certain classes of models a smallest that includes the probability distribution will be chosen
when the data set is large
now what do i mean by the smallest DAG that includes the probability distribution these
two concepts here
but the concept of a small band
product concept of including the probability distribution
and i'll show you what i mean by this with
a couple of examples
we have two variables
both binary and we find that they are independent
these are two models we could have
kind on reverse here i
this is the conditional independence the but it's not something we learned from data and
i'm trying to tell you that this is what's true
all right
if you have two variables
what are
the possible the first of all binary variables you they could be
and and what parameters you need
you need the probability of axis forces value probably wise first value
so in binary
you don't need any other probabilities could probably of x two will be one minus
the next one
so those are the only two parameters you need
if you've got this DAG
you need the probability that x one
y one given x one y one given x two
need three parameters
right so these are the two possible
models there's another y going that's but that's markov equivalence
two possible their models
two binary variables
now suppose
in our data
because of the dependency
on the past values of y t
but this is not relevant because we only use
the markov chain xt
the reason why it works is is
is really
is this equation
if you write down the transition kernel
this occurs
so either you move used to you stay where you are
well this perfect symmetry
identity that is if you take full football
and you multiply the come from y
and actually on the by my support
that was because the the state i
everything is x x x x x if you move
you have y the probability of moving which is rho
the distribution that you chose to remove q of y given x one can see
that f of one row of y axis
i q i given y is exactly equal to f of x
the role of x y q y given x
so you
in x and y
in the joint distribution of the current value
and the next value
and because of this perfect symmetry which is called detailed balance your chain is reversible
that is if you look at it one way or another
it is the same
time has no direction in that in that case
and more importantly
you just have to integrate both sides of this equation
to realize that if you start from f of why you do one step at
x is again distributed as an
therefore f is really
xe stationary distribution of that ship
thank OK
now of course you have not going to change you just need to have one
more condition which is that the james be irreducible
and if you do that
and the detailed balance condition
that if you can move anywhere in a finite number of steps
that's enough
to induce positive recurrent
well your change
because they don't need much
in terms of the camels the kernel
q three q proposal
spectrum of spread that is large enough
two goals
you know have the number of steps that besides condition thank if you choose q
to be
a positive density in particular were
you don't your change is good and therefore it's always converging to a stationary distribution
so there's really universal algorithm because you just no condition
two impose on
on your parameters you going to
the point is not really important periodicity city
is just a nuisance but it's not
it's a minor nuisance
so there is a big collision friends and this say for instance to impose this
is much too strong but you can impose
that the camel
is positive everyone but if it even if it is positive in the neighborhood
which large enough diameter
that's not
and once you have that
harris recurrence and therefore you have the two theorems already yesterday basic convergence properties that
are empirical mean
two is the integral of interest or
the distribution of the change time
converges to f which is the distribution of interest
because of the whole theory of metropolis hastings algorithm in this line that's that's all
you need
two know to be convinced that it works
so that for theoretical convergence of course in practice
we get
different behaviours
depending on the choice
of q
i just go through
a few examples
to show you
how it works
or less
and i start with the first choice of q
by choosing q which is not
the conditional distribution
may well choose a decision to
that only depend on the current value to which killed y given x is q
of one
therefore i write g
in the standard simulation algorithm where i picked the wrong distribution they're correct to get
to the right distribution
so the idea that the algorithm
you just chances are good that is at any point you generate value
always from the same distribution g
and you can get from using the wrong distribution
by using the ratio
of the gene
you see that they acceptance probability is fg off the new value or
f of g
the previous value and so if
four g
you accept the new
and you stay there
it is the time that is
propositional to f
of the g
of the current value
but of course we are using a GP that produces a sequence of i eighty
that is but because we pick
and reject all others
why we reject some values we stay
the same values again sample we produce is a markov chain is not i i
strong connection with actor project as i hinted at yesterday which is that if
user gene that is
fat tails
so that ever g
is bounded
if at knowledge is bounded you get
good city
in the convergence that is your kernel
at the end
is close to
by a factor of one minus one over and to the poor and you have
geometric degrees two
that is not all depending on the starting value
OK so that's not system
of because it's related to be the same properties of facts project work in that
case but again
it we that project
the priority of acceptance in one step is one of our hands
and the first thing here is that
the problem of acceptance is larger
and one of them and you can see very easily
because when we
this primitive acceptance it's a YT he would you y
and you divide
by f of xt overdue of so f of XTO energy efficiency is less
then and
and therefore you divide by something that is smaller than n the probability to accept
is large
OK so you move faster
with this algorithm then was accepted
then we accept reject
just remark which is that
martin going to talk about
semantic web services which is a little different to the other areas
there is an acknowledgement
i won't go through them all
so what's the web service
here we're basically talking about programming so whereas
several the other presentations focused on data
here we focus on function
so it's the program programmatically accessible over the web
and we're talking about functionalities which are provided
in a distributed fashion
if you ever go to the web services presentation the first slide show is this
so we have two roles you have service consumer so some client which may be
a programmed wants to consumer service and then
some organisation that provides functionality on the web
can seem to find the appropriate service in something called the UDDI registry
which is the syntactic registry of services they have a textual description and some XML
two i was still file
but still is the syntactic description of the components of the service
basically the
types in the service and the data schema
once the
consumer has found this information they invoke service by sending an XML based message
called so
to the end point of the web service and the result comes back
the interesting thing about web services from the web services community is that they can
be a proxy for business services
which means that any organisation which sells value to customers can be transformed from a
single black box single black box monolithic entity
into a set of micro functionalities
and these marker functionalities provide some micro value
when invoked and available on the web and so you can transform the nature of
interesting things are happening in the web services world probably everyone knows about this so
through amazon
you can
potentially all seemingly
infinite computing resources
through the clouds
they have a simple storage service where you can store huge amounts of data for
only a fraction of the few cents per month
they have databases that you can invoke so through these services the argument is the
one doesn't need ninety department anymore you can outsource all the RIT infrastructure
they also have the amazon mechanical turk
service which is also called artificial artificialintelligence where they provide a framework where people can
sign up and offer tasks that only people come off and then you can invoke
these as a web service
so there's an interesting statistic in two thousand three nine billion hours
of online so was played
so now you can
view the web is a huge computing resource where the computers and people
and you can inductive the services
so this is the web services in a few slides so the problems
from web services to not really scalable
because of the task
associated with creating an application
out of web services can components have to be carried out by people
specifically by ITV personnel so if you want to find an appropriate service if you
want to put them together if they mismatches between the components if you want to
invoke service you need to phone up your department and ask a program to do
some work for you
if you imagine where at the moment there are thirty billion web resources
are out there
if you want to have services out on the web in some sort of scale
you need to have some sort of automation which will require
on semantic markup
this slide we used to present to give an overview of the vision of the
research is that you can say that is
first when
the standard web which is based in your eyes HTML and HTTP
but services bring function
so as opposed to data component then we have the semantic web where the focus
is on machine readability so you have the web for machines and semantic web services
you put the two together
canada is a very large country
was very empty
like in alberta if i'm not your percent of canada's this man
very small percentage of canada's and so most number companies
number on ground
to do that you have to have very
one more is very very clear about what percentage
forest you can create
this page seven percent if you doing clear cutting this process still seven percent
well he missus seven percent if you're talking about
sixteen thousand square kilometres
this is this is already covered this this boreal forest cover four million square kilometres
and you can't go and count between
the trouble is that the remote sensing community and the computer vision community has made
promises never really lived up to
the systems are not reliable
and not only that but not true that we reliable
and the question is how do you prove that something is working well when you
can simply sample a thousand trees
as adequate sample when you really have to count
there is a need to have some sort of technology that in some sense have
its own internal
credibility criteria
previous methods for this
one more or less OK i e in in in in plantation forests for single
space is the safest spruce
where typical models included matching building up
you can five isio would you reference cameras
OK so you know the orientation and position the cameras six parameters in over time
of day so you know the position of the sun
so you know
you can then
right what the template of
since true should be
flying the single this time of day
and many of the techniques and to cross correlation
normalized cross correlation three one cross correlation all the variations on cross correlation
and find pics can be picks but of course they they
they fall down others do that the following methods
all have not been used by industry for many reasons including that how do i
know this is correct and secondly
you change the lighting overcast you go from plantations in mixed forests and the terrible
because like this
so the ball of fire actually a mixed mixture of deciduous trees like aspen and
and conifers like spruce
these things
so you really can't have and you certainly can't assume that your from
like this so
most of the forestry done in canada
we can not use presentation for this has been very successful in scandinavian countries
where most of the first of presentation because many people argue we in australia as
well as candidates should be going to plantation not
you not using all graph
the natural forests and
the support is
so the current systems really have been very much open open loop
no learning
um no handling of public spaces
and in particular no internal mechanisms were saying
how do i know this is a list circles the evidence of the interpretation is
our approach was in this context what scepticism what can we do
so in the bayesian sense already in philosophical placing since almost we said well what's
the best thing will be good evidence for us
interpreting the same
one good evidence could be if i take pictures of scenes
and i reconstruct the forest
and then take pictures of the reconstructed it should be the same feature to the
it could be circumstantial evidence that the on on the right path is not true
the circumstantial evidence of i can reconstruct the forest
and take a picture from the pictures were taken
then they should be somehow match
the pitch is i'm going to generate a not necessarily exactly the same features that
have the same sort of statistics on the like for example top trees in these
sorts of things
so the complex system that we opened we would think we
from from a bayesian perspective is this type of system
what we do is we take images
i have a system that does annotations
region labeling
we have three d system stereo
and that nothing mysterious part is using stereo
but actually you could use light are all the top selected senses these days which
will fall by the way
these these active sources are not
and not
and then you have to combine these cells to get
to get volumes
if we treat the volumes and then you can predict images
so this talk a system we impose but this really is a hybrid system is
a complex system and you know it's very hard to get it i practical
and not just abstract formulation of how how optimize complex systems
so our approach was really a modular approach say how can we formulate it to
and we average over the training set
so this is
probably but not his covered this pretty well
so this is sort of the classical set up in machine learning
but it contains this loop over the training set
and for large sets of data that loop is inefficient
and if you believe that never ends
or it's nonstationary so as you go through the data the
the underlying statistics of the dataset change on you
right and this becomes an inappropriate formalism
so what we really need to do is stochastic approximation whereby
we just
the loss
on the current data
and the current value of these parameters
and we do some quick and dirty optimisation over that to get the next set
of parameter values
and then we iterate that
the next batch of data is going to be evaluated on the fresh parameters
so these are i gather some of these equations are missing
on slides of apologize that's the font problem
so if you want to leave those lights on a little bit longer if you
want to
to enter them
this one is fine now on the other ones don't started writing too early because
i have animated equation so they're going to change on you so so i'll tell
you when the last version is up and you can start writing a book
so now
we come to the key problem
OK sorry you were not the case
well what's
go on
may two
the key problem is that people for
centre is really
have developed these
fancy optimisation methods so this first order gradient descent i should say that i explained
to you right this is sort of
very very low level
it's almost as bad as evolutionary algorithms if you talk to anybody in the math
department does optimisation going to laugh at you
if you if you come with what everybody does is you know
second order with lots of bells and whistles and this that and the other machinery
on top right
really heavy heavy duty hardcore stuff
so actually hundreds of years of mathematical expertise have have gone into pushing things in
this direction
more and more complex machinery
to be more and more efficient at solving these problems
now the key problem that we're getting here now so everybody down
the last two years
yeah so the idea is that
at time t
it will take
the parameter values at that time
and the there
and the current data
and we're going to to change the parameter values based on that
we're going to do a little optimisation step
and then we take those new values
and that the next time step we going to measure the gradient for instance on
the new data using those new values that the new point already
so we take measurements always at the current point so far optimise the hops around
those measurements will also help around
that's that's what that's why it's sort of an approximation that's why not known exactly
to do this
so here's one here's little picture of the hierarchy of optimisation algorithms try to at
the bottom you have evolutionary algorithms which is really one of the
amateurs do that don't know anything about optimizing one level is what i'm doing
and then the real algorithm so here
and the two axis you plotted
the order of the algorithm in terms of the dimensionality of the subspace of this
sort of one or the audience with of q
it gets more and more expensive to go to the right
and on the other axis is the convergence speed
so it's kind of the inverse of how many iterations you have to run you
optimize for
until you get
good solution evolution is you have to run forever gradient descent like this forever and
here they start getting really fast
now the problem is when you do stochastic approximation which
i said you need when you deal with the large data set because otherwise the
first iteration takes too long you can wait for you just one pass through the
if you use a stochastic approximation
that approximation
it's true that all this advanced machinery here
so actually what happens is
when you go online users
with that
if you like it makes it look a little bit more like the problem is
that most people in machine learning and working on so here the the ways in
which making more complex instead of just assuming we have a single dimension of shape
we're going to allow multiple dimensions of shape and colour and texture if you like
and then what we're learning is in this sense which out of a large number
of dimensions are the right ones to pay attention to we're also going to instead
of assuming here that our training data are fully labeled
in sorted according to counter we might say well suppose the training data are more
in a semi supervised setting either on or or unsupervised they might be completely unlabeled
or we may only observe labels for a small number of examples this is the
situation where the child is in the real world where they see lots of chairs
you lots of tables lots of dogs but only a small number of them are
ever actually label
there's there's a few other
interesting ways of this model is complex but i was really problem here so this
is the the data look more like this there instead of
well the in the simulation we had
eight dimensions of which
though you may not see it here
four of them are kind of like shape so there's four dimensions along which
the categories are are coherently organised only other interesting complexity is that unlike here here
there's a perfect correlation between this one shape dimension and the category variable but here
the correlation might be imperfect so you can see what's going on more clearly if
sort these
these vectors as follows so these are just exactly the same
strings of
of digits
o and this this this this one and that one two four and so on
those are category labels so most of them are unlabelled
so now what i've done here is that sort of them and i have also
highlighted in gray the the four dimensions which happened to be the first four bits
four dimensions which are coherently co very with with category identity
and the the learning problem essentially is to go from this to this and we're
also and this is not going to tell our system learner how many categories there
are well you know the the few labels we get are somewhat informative but notice
here we didn't actually get an example of category three
labelled examples and we're going to do this by taking exactly the same dirichlet multinomial
model but now adding this extra lane variable z which
is indicator for the category and it's follows the chinese restaurant process which i guess
people have used that word but i think it has been formally introduced to write
but it's it's it's sort of the
combinatorics behind the dirichlet process and you i will tell you about that in the
second lecture but basically disease just think of it as a likely indicator variable for
a mixture of which can which mixture component and object comes from but unlike regular
finite mixture xe actually can take on any
value integers there is an infinite number of components here and the chinese restaurant process
is the distribution on on the partition of the objects or assigning integers to the
objects that tends to cluster them into a small number of groups to just like
in the dirichlet process mixture
so i mean this basically is the dirichlet process
mixture with a multinomial
model and dirichlet conjugate
prior to that
the the the twist on that is that which again is is more less people
have been doing this in machine learning and bayesian statistics for a while but what's
relatively new for cognitive science here is we're doing this we're learning in this in
this infinite mixture model but we're also going to be learning parameters of the base
distribution of of the DP if you like we're going to be learning is alpha
invaders and so that
that's going to then give us some knowledge which will transfer to new cases and
give us the second order generalizations so the second marginalisation here is to see an
object which has in this case completely novel values on all dimensions
so just it's a simple any kind of simple notion of similarity is really going
to help us here but we want to be able to learn that the first
four dimensions here are tend to be homogeneous within categories so for example this one
is more likely to be five than this one which happens to match on the
last four
and without going into too many details we we run a number of experiments with
people i think people are over here in the model is over here and we
do things like very for example whether category labels are present or absent during training
so this this was the case where a category labels are mostly absent we actually
we did one for to completely absent
he said the experiment their solutions have to sort them you know we just a
sort is in the some categories and then we show them anything any say for
this new thing it's in some category whichever one it is i mean we without
telling you but we just want to know which of these is in the same
category is that one
and both the model and the people can do almost as well when category labels
were absent during training unsupervised training as it as when they present and also both
of them to the second generalisation as well as the first authorization there are also
both affected by coherence which is just how how
how much for anyone to mention how
homogeneous is it within the category
the main interesting empirical results other than that the model and and people are the
people can do basic with the model is that people are always a bit worse
so all of these that are a little bit lower than all of these bars
and we're into we're currently exploring what might be one interesting suggestion comes from looking
when people let's say in the unsupervised case
people just sort these objects and sometimes they kind of get the right sort sometimes
they they cluster them in the same way that the model but other times they
don't and if you just look at the people who cluster them in the right
way during training and then they look almost perfect just like the model so it
seems like people might be doing some kind of
you know
it less good approximate inference which we can try to model for example by saying
well maybe they're doing gibbs sampling but with very few samples of fewer than the
model would or maybe they're doing a particle filter but only a small number of
particles in this is something which i referred to last time is kind of interesting
very interesting state-of-the-art place in computational cognitive science where people are trying to model with
ways in which the brain performs
online processing approximate inference as somehow approximate forms of approximate inference that were familiar with
the machine learning like particle filters with very few particles or gibbs sampling with very
few samples
and that we think that will produce these sort of
the difference between what we see in the people in the model here
any questions about that
so so what i what i want to do for the rest of the time
is tell you about some things which are not just
textbook models or standard things are used to seeing machine learning but most of the
things i'm going to tell you about here are models that we came up with
to try to solve some aspects of trying to make sense of some at some
kinds of learning from people solve which seem to go beyond what the problem is
that people are usually working on in machine learning and i hope some of these
ideas will also be useful to machine learning people in some cases a lot of
little do is just which motivate the problem from cognitive because basis and then show
you applications to machine learning problems try to illustrate
OK so what i decided to tell you about is about some work the talk
is going to be a bit conceptual not very technical but a bit conceptual about
some recent work about the theory of low rank modeling and so there in the
first part of the talk i'm going to talk a lot about what we have
learned through the modelling
with low rank matrices and then in the second part i will show you what
i believe are kind of exciting applications in computer vision
OK so
i would say that in my field of research is an explosion of research on
the theory of low rank modeling when i grew up to tell you the story
to start with when i grew up i worked on sparsity it was we're because
nobody was working on sparsity
now it seems that if you try to publish a paper at least in my
field was that they were sparsity in the abstract good luck
but i can see the same stuff happening now not use sparse models but using
low rank models
and that's what i would like to discuss some of the works i'm going to
present his hours and some of it is not
OK so i'm just going to talk about two very simple things one is matrix
and the other one is
ways of doing dimensionality reduction in very robust way
which i think important for people working in machine learning
OK so let's start with the first topic matrix completion if you do not know
the netflix prize check the name of this summer school again so i assume that
everybody is familiar with the netflix prize everybody knows what he's doing half people don't
know what is the netflix prize
no kidding
you're not serious are you
you're serious
so all the OK OK price is a major initiative that was launched by a
company name netflix netflix once movies out to users they have about half a million
users at the time the large surprise and they were anything about eighteen thousand titles
after you UV was mail service so what you do is you go on the
internet and you say you want to run the movie and then
netflix with a male user DVD would watch movie return to DVD would make the
next one and so on and so forth
but very quickly what they would ask users via email is what it was all
about you like the movies actually as iterate the movie you had just seen and
so users would go out and sparsely enter some entries in a huge database that
netflix was assembling database in which we have columns which are movies and about their
twenty thousand of them at the time there were about five hundred thousand users say
to you today matrix and when you see this process in this data matrix it's
a movie that this user has right of course more made data matrix is extraordinarily
is sparsely sampled because users on average round about thirty to fifty movies so instead
of having eighteen thousand ratings we have about thirty to fifty
and what netflix wants if they want to complete the netflix matrix what does this
mean that there are many entries that are not seen that have many movies that
have not been rated by users on netflix lounge to price the netflix prize where
people were to do this challenge to make predictions about the the items or entries
of the matrix you had not seen
and why wouldn't netflix wants to do such a thing i think the reason is
pretty obvious which is of course if you can predict accurately movies that people have
not yet seen and of course you can build an efficient recommender system and so
of course you can generate a lot of cost
you have lots of customers lots of happy customers and so you generate a lot
of income now of course as you can imagine there's not only netflix interested in
such things but you know facebook has the same problems apple sending music has the
same problems you everywhere you go in the online commerce people would like to change
their preferences for items based on few
so there are many such problems this is an area called collaborative filtering in statistics
we have similar problems in which we have questionnaires for example this could be questions
could be this could be questions this could be people being surveyed and some people
may not want to answer questions and you would like to know what if they
had answered the question
OK so for those of you who don't know about the netflix prize essentially netflix
offered a million dollars to whomever would be able to come up with the prediction
algorithm that was besting their own in-house of by ten percent
another problem which is not the netflix prize
what i'm going to try to show you that matrix completion occurs in many different
areas of science and engineering another thing that happens in in electrical engineering this time
is that what you've got is you've got a point in space with as xj
and what you know if you have partial information about those pairwise distances so you
have a matrix
l which records pairwise distances between pairs of points are point j
but the problem is you can only see if you have this pairwise distances perhaps
because you have a sensor nets so you have a wireless
network where
people or sensors can only construct a distance estimate is the nearest neighbors but not
too two sensors that are far away because of power constraints of you
OK so now you've got this data matrix which is very large
and what you would like to know if you'd like given pairwise local distances can
actually recoverable distances and why is it important important important because
in sensor we always want to know where stuff is so low localization of sensors
is the same as was if i can localize sensors i can compute all the
pairwise distances but it goes it's a two-way street in the sense that if you
can compute all pairwise distances and of course you know the location of the senses
up to rigid transformation
and so
the problem is from a few entries of this matrix can actually recover or global
distances so that i can locate the sensors so another problem in which we have
entries of the matrix of a very different kind obviously on the netflix data matrix
where there lots of missing entries and we'd like to interfere the value of those
missing entries
there are many other problems are a great friend of mine even is gonna talk
next week about convex optimisation perhaps issue we will show you applications of matrix completion
in control inside system identification and i have exciting applications in quantum state tomography quantum
mechanics which are fantastic due to the growth
you have problems of this kind in
signal processing of course it's a big problem in machine learning and computer vision solve
this problem of trying to be able to have partial information about the large data
matrix and try to recover in here's entire matrix is the problem that comes up
all the time
so what is the matrix completion problem is the matrix completion problem is
something like this
we've got a data matrix l which i'm going to call out we observe a
subset of its entries very few perhaps in the netflix case it's below percent and
a bound on the
performance of the support vector machines
and the important point here of course is that now
complexity depends on the margin
so we're actually able to take into account the fact that the
although the VC dimension is infinite
of the whole space the fact that we've got a particular
classifier has a margin of some value on the training set
it gives us the bound is nontrivial
so this ban will be non-trivial potentially for
four functions that
you know have a reasonable margin
this is the marginratio to the
the radius of the ball containing the data
obviously affected by the size of the training set here
and this is relatively benign log factor here
so this is sort of the bound with if you like justify
the claim that the
gamma is a measure of the the ninth of the distribution
so the
this band will not work
OK the rademacher stuff
i will work actually in that case
yes the rademacher will work i should get to that later on but this will
not work
the point that
no no you can observe it i mean that was the point i mentioned about
being structural risk minimisation over the choice of gamma you essentially have to prove the
theorem first range of values of gamma
and then use it for the value that you observe on your data
the true distribution in some sense
you know you have no idea what is gamma is your right
that said with high confidence they will be close to the gamma you observe because
the chances that you observe such a margin if there isn't one
is going to be pretty small but you don't have to worry about that exact
exactly mean that's the beauty of this that you actually measure on the training data
and infer something about the distribution
at the same time as inferring something about the function you learn so you really
doing inference on two things at once
it's it's valid
i mean it's valid OK said to make it strictly have to apply this for
a sequence of gammas
and you say you apply for
ten gammas you will have the ten factor in here or you know some sequence
some number
coming in as the delta here
and then you just use the one closest to the
gamma observed the next size down to one
from the camera so you can take the second sort of doubling sequence then you
just half the gammy observed
use that
they can
any other questions
so i think you know it's kind of a very nice to be able to
see that you're able to
combine the two inferences and and just work with empirical quantities
in in in
estimating this
so this is just to show you if you remember when we started i was
talking about you know the danger of this
tail of the distribution
being you know what you don't want this is the
the example the samples that cause you grief
and you'd like to avoid those samples
because you have no choice your from the sample you don't have a choice of
the sample you get
and you'd like to guard as best you can
against the case where
you actually have the sample is misleading you quite badly
so this is now applying the SVM
in place of what i had before the blue is the parzen window i had
for certain
set sizes this is doing exactly the same sampling of trying distribution of sorry of
training samples
repeatedly and creating a histogram
and seeing what the histogram looks like
i'm using exactly the same function space so it's it's still linear functions i'm not
using kernel here
so you know actually learning in the same feature space exactly
and the question is
you know
times x
you can think of this as the error
the neuron is currently making on an example multiplied by the input so to work
out the gradient you put each input in
if you look at the error between the output and the target then you multiply
the error by the input to get the gradient and it offered up and d
that's simple operation
which we got by differentiation is sometimes called backpropagation backpropagation is the neural networks community
the neural network communities name four
backpropagation is a particular algorithm for doing differentiation in feedforward
networks and doing it efficiently
okay so what happens if we do that we start of the neuron
with some randomly chosen weights
and the weights change so his gradient descent doing it's thing and i'm showing you
the three weight values and they
will blow up
what was happening in w one w two space looks like this the weights one
of in one direction and then one of another direction so as they went downhill
the direction downhill
what was going on well here's the data is initial weight vector that i i picked random
so it's not doing a very good job of separating
the blue from yellow
and you do gradient descent
the weights change and where the red line is changes rotates around
and then it changes rotates
around small
hand the weights are getting bigger and bigger
and after forty thousand iterations that's where the weights have got to
all right
so that's learning
and you might say well
i'm not happy
maybe i could do better and that's because
o moments ago before we got to the final optimized setting the weights with
we've managed to find a place where computer cliff that completely separates yellow points from the blue points
a moment before
when we reason halfway there
the answer looked a bit more reasonable this this this is now say okay you
win another example are classified four you and wherever arrived you say
ninety nine point nine
nine percent sure it's a blue or that is the yellow because we've got this incredibly steep cliff
and might say that's stupid
we don't like this outcome
has managed to
minimize the objective function but maybe we picked the wrong objective function
if we don't like this what we do well sensible people
change object a function
so now what we're gonna do is learning
i don't like these enormous
state sharp
changes changes in function or a neural network language we call weight decay
because you get state functions
when the weights are big
we added extra term
and these object function gets changed so it's not just gee
the new objective function of l and
about energy
plus an extra term
which says
i don't like it breaks
so the object has changed from please for the data as well as possible to
please for the data but add on a penalty for having the weights
in w
it can be defined to be
right so we do that's
now here's what happens
i've set this parameter alpha
which is the call
the regularizer if you from the statistics well
well sorry the regularisation constant
he w is called the regularizer
or if you are in neural networks alpha is called the weight decay rate
when you add on what happens to a gradient well it's just an extra turn
out and the gradient of he plus alpha y w is this lot plus
alpha times weights
so going downhill mat means you've got a minus alpha
term and
what happens when you do the minimization is shown here in terms of what the
weights do they used a blow up but now there's a whole down
and they don't
we don't have an ever steepening function
so all the way to settle down and
here's what
use the happen and we didn't have the regularizer the orange curves show everything blowing up
here's what happens in w one w two space
we go downhill downhill and sort a stop along the trajectory
effectively is what happens
so we follow almost the same trajectory in weight space but we stop
at an optimum
this new objective function this is where we used to be going after forty thousand iterations of steepest descent
now when we switch on the weight decay we go downhill and we end up in this place here
resize the looks
alright and you might look and say good that's better
because now it's not making completely unreasonable overconfident answers for example if you say
for another point arriving in this
location here
what's the chance that this in the blue grass it'll say
and about ninety percent is say i'm hundred potential
hand if you get
and no one is yellow and white it'll say fifty fifty
and i think yes that's not about answer based on
the data we've got here on apples and raisins
you might still be dissatisfied and if you are hold that thought we'll will come
back to this in a moment
now we're going to switch to
larger networks
and then we'll come back to the we the single neuron when you've got some more ideas
let me just
tell you a couple more things about the single neuron and then we'll come back to this learning
first i can give you an example of using a single neuron actually do
a real problems so i talked about pebbles and raisins or here instead is a
handwriting problem you can get yourself a data set of
handwritten digits that are being digitized in black and white dots
in two hundred fifty six dimensions so you can get yourself a few thousand
examples are twos and threes
are used the algorithm i just described
to come up with a single neuron
which has two hundred fifty six inputs has two hundred fifty seven weights
and its output can be viewed as the probability that this thing i'm looking at is a two or three
and when you do that this is what the weights
look like
andy error rate the classifier that u
i have made is about ten percent so on this database handwritten digits it gets
ninety percent of the right so it's not completely useless so even a single neuron
can be an interesting quick and dirty way to solve
some simple
inference problems
a question you could ask about a single neuron
you can view it as a communication channel
this is just a little aside and there's a whole chapter on this in the book if you interested
one way of thinking about what's going on here is
o i don't really believe that the output of the neuron is the correct probability distribution so forget the idea
but i do believe that the neuron is a helpful way to package up
the contents of the dataset
if you give me a data set
with lots and lots of examples of handwritten digits
she was
we see that
i know her
in our
and we see
the government
you have a
because property
a one
see now
it's the
the solution is
this is one
we see is
and two
this is not one one possibility would be to search
all possible entrance stop so this is this is going to be the intron and
and have to thank the interest on the to maximize of all positions
this makes more expensive
so to fill this metrics now you have these three choices here and you have
this maximisation in
they maximize into the past you try to find the start of
so and with this condition we we consider the last score and we have some
entrance score in this entrance school might depend on the link
might depend on the start of this let's spice that's what the start and spies
that's what interface
they can be kind of like this
so we have the contributions one is willing to use the lights at school at
the start of the twentieth of the end of it to be simply precompute this
by sets course for each position and then we somehow take these scores into account
and how we take this into account this is learned by the structure of
and so in the end we have
parameters which is the substitution matrix and then the function
determine how how explicit for link is contributing to the
in short squat
so this it
well you need to have the training data very you know of course
i don't need to know where the
and it it so i feel all i mean for every position there
we obvious to search the whole way back essentially this this could be as long
as the DNA maybe there is a limit on the length but still you can
do think we can take this is not going to be
it was down to if you have a
in trundling model
from this point on this quality constant and you only pay you only penalized by
the by the the point i mean by factor of how many nokia right so
it's not like can allow maybe hundred k entrance here
maybe from that point on on your in trundling model is constant and maybe
housing you pay only
so it's bit better if you don't have interlink model then you don't pay
and all for the link
OK so how can we parametrize these things so here we have a substitution matrix
this simply bipartite metrics that four letters and the deletion later so we have a
a c g t in the miners so they we have like insertion deletion
so this is essentially twenty five primary
we also have these three functions here of the length of the building and we
i mean if had a simple choice you the model them has a piecewise linear
so it's quite simple the thing about this choice is that all the time is
so we don't need cuts but we're doing this and estimate one-dimensional functions piecewise linear
functions are
but then it is
so if use think twenty or thirty
support points but piecewise linear
this just formula with
in the end we have a parameter vector which consists of these are the point
is within
and this substitution
so i for given beta can now compute an alignment score
four certain lines
so how can we optimize and how can you find these parameters
the idea again i would like to find parameters such that for non alignment good
alignment score is much larger than what we need
rather like
so and given n training examples
we have to solve this particular vision problem is that we would like to find
these parameters theta such that this will be positive of good alignment is greater than
any from alignment
first access thing out the catch even if that first access thing is
i read all the time
l are you have this sort of captures the intuition which we want which is
that something that's been accessed recently is likely to be accessed again and something that
hasn't been accessed very recently probably is less likely to be accessed again so it's
sort of captures are in our intuitive idea that we want locality of reference and
so the text talks much more carefully about these different page removal policy but any
time you see anybody talk about cache you should serve immediately as thing to ask
the question what's the page removal policy being used
so that basically does it for
our discussion of caching and performance that we started last time
what we do now is move on to this topic of of networking
thank you
so a computer network and you should all be familiar with the idea of a
computer network is its
some sort of a connection that connects multiple computers together so
why why we interested in studying computer network what is it relevant about computer network
for the purposes of this class
and there's really sort of two
the primary reasons the first one is that
computer networks are commonly
used as components of
OK so anytime we're building a big computer system is very likely that it's can
involve a computer network
so it's going to be important for us to understand what the properties of computer
networks are and how
sort of computer networks affect the design of our system if we want to use
them effectively in our systems
and fear networks have a number of uses in computer systems to do things like
the last
geographical limits
you guys are all familiar with
now the ability of the internet to allow you to check the score some sporting
game that's happening on the other side of the country
or to be able to send an email to your parents back home
so obviously
those are things that networks so so being able to sort of transmit data over
long distances is clearly a good thing for many kinds of systems
they also allow us to access remote data
this is related to the other thing to the other one but you know if
you have data that's not on your computer that you want to get hold of
you may want to contact your bank and ask them for your bank balance
and then finally
it can be used to physically separate client server
so we talked about that the last few lectures it's been awhile talking about why
the ability the fact that we can use things like threads and address spaces in
order to provide a sort of enforced modularity between models running on the same computer
but there are lots of situations in which we want to actually physically separate client
server your bank doesn't really want you to be running you know you're copy of
quicken on their server right because this notion enforced modularity we talked about isn't a
perfect separation between the client and the server whereas putting these things on really separate
machines that are only connected by this network that is controlled by this piece of
hardware that this network are sort of talks the network that's that's sort of that's
a good reason may be to separate these things from each other
and then finally the second major reason why we want to study networks
is simply that they themselves are an interesting computer system
so we talked in the first lecture about some of the interesting so the properties
that the computer systems have well you know the image is not many computer systems
are bigger than the internet right so perfect example of the giant
complex interesting system with all sorts of complicated behaviour
i will talk about some of those complicated behaviors today
as we
overview networks
OK so
the goal
the our discussion of networking in some sense is going to be to develop a
set of tools that allow us to have a universal communication
between the number of different clients
so what do i mean by that suppose i have some collection
the machines which are described little boxes
there are scattered around
and they are connected together what we want to do is to
connect these guys together
thank you
and the network system that we're going to design is going to be the interconnected
wells these guys to talk to each other
and the abstraction that what we want this network to be able to provide a
very high level
is the ability to do anything any communication
i think so
we want you know this is a and this is the
we want a to be able to send a message to be
or anybody else is in the network and that should be true for any for
any of the pairs that we can find
and so in some sense what we're going to do
over the next could cause the next couple weeks sort of see how we design
this cloud sits in between all these different computers
if you like you can think of this cloud often times the internet is represented
as the cloud is just some black box that you sort of sent messages into
with an address and on the other side the sort of message that pops out
at the other end so we're going to dive into the cloud and see what
happens inside
OK so
in order to
start to understand
some of the challenges of building this cloud
it's sort of we we should start we're going to start looking at the top
down to look at the biggest issues that we have to deal with then we're
going to break up those issues into small pieces
so what are the issues that sort of immediately pop out when you first start
for instance by computing first this vector w connecting the two class means and then
see the midpoint numbers
connection and we can compute this vector x minus c exists test point represent
in the feature space and then we simply have to check whether this vector in
this vector enclose an angle smaller than ninety degrees of larger than ninety degrees
so i to do that
we just have to
sheikh we just have to compute the dot product between these two vectors is the
dot product between the two vectors is positive
the angle is more than ninety degrees the product is negative the angle is larger
than ninety degrees so that's one simple way of doing things
and if we
go through the algebra
we just substitute everything we get
a simple solution
so we substitute everything into here
we then replace the dot products between points mapped into the feature space by kernel
so back here i have a constant which just all the time don't depend on
and then we we get this decision rules
which is now
a kernel based decision rules so it's an expansion in terms of kernels sentence here
or positive points and he is centered on the good point is some constant so
you can think of this may for the ones that didn't as before there
people who are statisticians here
that's what i forgot
OK we have
three statisticians also so for the statisticians
in some cases depending on what kind of kernel induces but for instance if we
choose a gaussian function is a kernel we normalize it
such that it has integral one so this is some kind of a given the
density model then
this is also density model we normalize by
the number of such kernels this is again it's like ipods and windows density estimate
of the positive class and this is the parzen window density is the density estimate
of the negative class
so in this case in this simple geometric classification in the feature space and so
giving us something like
a something like classifier based on
like a plug classification rule based on past windows density estimates
so it's a very simple algorithm and
this would be a good time to
take a few minutes try to everybody to derive this classifier in in a slightly
different way
so what i'd like you to try
my experience to learn a lot more if you try to make yourself also so
i'd like you to try
to derive this classification rule here
this one or something like this one maybe you have a slightly different signs somewhere
but like you to write this classification rule
simply by directing computing the distance so you compute distance between this point and this
point in the feature space
and you subtract the distance between these two points
now this is something one can compute using the products you can use the squared
distance between these two points you subtract the squared distance between these two points
and the undertaker
the the sign
of this difference to see whether you get something that's in this this one here
so let's take a few minutes and try this
everybody on his own or or means whatever
and i will try to try it myself when i say do it also
so if i don't know which slide i should be
leaving government valley this one
so how many people have
on the solution yet
to ask this not because we are in this phase transition where the last sound
level is increasing i remember i was once the talk not far from here by
stephen hawking and someone someone asked the question of the talk and then he started
preparing the answer which is difficult for him with some kind of machine that is
using so at the beginning people waiting very quietly for the answer but that it
took about ten to fifteen minutes to prepare the answer so after ten minutes gradually
there was this
increasing noise levels and after when he really answered your water it was as large
as in the train station we start answering suddenly everything was required again the answer
was just one sentence
so but how much more time to people need to know how many people have
solved it by now
i would say that's more than half business someone who would like to have more
OK so then
we can get to the solution and we can either
the research that i do it you or someone else does it and i have
to think about some kind of reward maybe i have three or four such problems
during my lectures will solve the largest number we get some kind of reward so
if you solve this one
you could you could do it here
you should
and somehow we would like to bound the loss of the imperial q of the
of the to classifier in terms
off the empirical loss
so i understand the VC bounds usually use the classification error of that period classifier
and the margin bounds use the
can margin of the current classifier OK so that is classifier that is the classification
the much
OK so i guess peter department to find i mean many others to find very
the VC dimension before you've seen the bones i just want very briefly define again
it's because i'm going to need in the next slide
OK so we need someone to define the complexity of a function class in order
to say something about this part of solar TV
a hypothesis class and functions which map from our
d two plus or minus one and the question is how complex is class
and you want to find the concept of shattering
and one says that f shatters set subset of rd if it essentially all that
cartoon is an excellent means let's say you three points and the function classes all
hyperplanes then the function class can actually achieve all different classifications of these three data
points OK so you can put you can put it here
he here and so on which all different
all eight different classification
so this is
so three points so the question is does chapter of the four point seven are
in two dimensions it is not
so the VC dimension is the size of the largest church set of x
so in two dimensions the VC dimension is three because you can check point
OK so when we have the VC dimension then we can derive such VC bounds
so the idea is that one balance the difference of the empirical error from the
expected error
that depends on the VC dimension of the function class so the larger the function
class the more the tool estimates might indicate
OK and the bound look like looks like this
so i'll have that the loss of the expected loss of n the miners help
of the the empirical loss with an example that difference is bounded by something which
depends on the VC dimension
divided by the number of examples
and something which depends on the time and the bound holds with probability at least
one minus
so if you would like to have a very
i mean you would like to have a pretty high that is known to hold
this term contributes quite a bit of the VC dimension is very high then
this bonus was
so we could interpret this as a kind of into confidence intervals
so for instance we can i mean this this holds for any function f so
for any function in the function class
so in particular for the current minimizer so that's one which is minimizing
our empirical loss
OK so we can not just plugging this and make it little simplified so then
the expected loss of incorrectly classified correctly classify is bounded by the
the best classifier plus something which depends on the VC dimension and that that comes
during the from vapnik chervonenkis and nineteen nineteen seventy one
so this is this is about so this bound becomes tight when the number of
examples increases so we have essentially this dimension is fixed then when n increases this
the terminals this term
go to infinity let's say what increase in these terms the was zero
OK and asymptotically these two terms essentially identical
OK so this is bound becomes tight with the increasing number of examples so on
the other hand if the
the complexity of increasing the VC dimension df then the empirical error becomes smaller because
we have a larger set of functions where we can choose a function from
so we have strong this year
so this is the the total this is expected error
OK on this side the complexity of the function class
OK and if you increase the function class
then the training error of course course down
because we can choose more
from the larger set of functions
on the other hand the VC dimension of the function class increases so this penalty
for the CBC dimension that's this to over here
and the bound says essentially
some of these two things up so the training error class this penalty and then
you get this bound some minimum at some point OK you can arbitrarily this country
so essentially overfitting is this this regime years training are very small and found an
independent is large
other questions for that
so how how does this apply to boost so
remember that the
function which is generated by adaboost is a linear combination of of t
t different functions
so essentially the function class of adaboost t iterations is a convex combination of functions
on this basic process at h
OK so this this this set here so that all the other ends the great
equals zero and sum to one and then we just choose t functions of the
function class
so i don't know this set by of eight so this is the convex hull
of the key elements of a
and also for this for this of course can just apply this part so
the the
expected error smaller than the empirical error plus some complexity term which depends on the
VC dimension of that
convex hull
OK now the question is how how large is the VC dimension that connects hart
so in the simplest in the simplest case compound that by simply
multiplying v
BC dimension of the basic policies class that's the VC dimension eight times t
that's the number of combined time slot t because you have some community coefficients so
that's that's a a very rough estimate so that it will be is sufficient to
show the posting results came so
we can bound the VC dimension of i have a
done in chicago a few years ago people were asked to religion
and then when asked what would happen to them when they died
most people in the sample were christian
and about ninety six percent of christians that when i die i going to go
to heaven
some of the sample was jewish that judaism is actually relation with the less than
clear story about the afterlife
most of the subjects who identify themselves as jewish said when they die they will
go to heaven
some of the sample denied having any religion at all said they have no religion
at all still
when these people were asked what would happen when they die
most of them and said i'm going to go to heaven
dualism is a it a lot rests on
but as chris points out that
the scientific consensus now is the dualism is wrong
there's no new
separable or separate
from your body
in particular there's no use separable from your brain
to put it in the way cognitive scientists and psychologists and neuroscientists like to put
the mind is what the brain does
the brain the mind reflects the workings of the brain just like computation reflects the
working of a computer
now why would you hold such an outrageous view why would you reject dualism in
favour this alternative
well a few reasons
one reason is dualism has always had problems for one thing it's a profoundly unscientific
doctrine we want to know is curious people
how children learn language
what we find attractive or unattractive what's the basis for mental illness and dualism simply
it's all non physical was part of the east
and hence fails to explain
more specifically dual is like a car
struggle to explain
how physical body
connects to an immaterial soul
what's the conduit
how this connection be made after all they knew full well
that you there is such a connection
in your body will sure commands
if you bang your toaster due feel pain
if you drink alcohol ineffectual reasoning
but he can only wave his hands as to how the physical
o thing in the world could connect to an immaterial mind
they car
when he was alive
i was reasonable enough concluding that physical objects
can not do certain things
he was reasonable concluding for instance as did that there's no way in the early
physical object could ever play a game at chess
because in that such a capacity is beyond the capacity of the physical world and
hence you have to apply
you have to extend explanation to an immaterial soul
but now
we know
we have what scientists call in existence proofs
physical objects can do complicated and interesting things we know for instance
machines can play chess
we know machines can manipulate symbols we know machines have limited capacities two
engage in mathematical and logical reasoning
to recognise things
to do various forms of computations
and this makes it at least possible
that we
are such machines
so when you can no longer say look physical things just can't do that
because we know physical thinking to align
and this opens up the possibility
that that that humans are physical things in particular that humans are brains
there is strong evidence
that the brain is involved in the light
somebody will the heller do all this view
that said that what we do and what we decide what we think and what
we want are all had nothing to do with the physical world
i would be embarrassed by the fact that the brain seems to correspond intricate and
elaborate ways to one mental y
this has been known for a long time
philosophers and psychologists new for long time getting
smacked in the head
could change the mental faculties
diseases like syphilis can make you range that
chemicals like caffeine and alcohol can affect
how things
but what's new is we can now in different ways see the direct effects of
mental life
somebody with
a severe and profound
loss of mental faculties
the deficit will be shown here
OK so
so i'm going to give you couple of examples of how to mine these patterns
and if they if it looks a bit difficult to follow don't worry because the
interest fees
basically what we're after is to find these patterns
president in one one class in the present
but want to really interested in these methods then you can go and study from
the references
so in order to start with what i'm trying to do is a concise way
of representing these patterns
is this is some kind of a convex set
the way you're going to define a convex set these by means of two
so there is a minimum in bonding said and max wants so mean balance that
is as an example here it says the mean starts with items one two that's
one set
another one starts with
items one and three
and the max one says you can go
one two three four five these are each one means a particular item just we
mapped them into one you know the moment you see one which means is a
particular item you're talking about but i to run
so so what it means is that if you're given objects of these elements
are we trying to say is everything that
so set
of these elements
and including those elements but they have to be subset of one of these things
so for example
you start with one two
the inner one two e part of that set
and anything
added to that so for example if i had
later extended this one too
one two three
this has to be subset of one of these two so in this case one
two three is a subset of that
so then i can grow
one two three four and so forth so so basically what you can see that
is that you start with one two
and you expand all these terms and you end up with with
and and similarly you can start with one three
this minimum one second in one
keep growing but whenever you grow this exercise it has to be subset of one
of those things
and what you can show is that all these elements have nice convex property
so the convex properties defined as that
it will contain all these elements
that an element y
is a superset of x but body subset of z
which means
that any element that is present in the set would would would have that property
so this is a concise way of representing all these
possible patterns
by simply using these for that
so you can do
you know quite a strong
compression you can do
by applying this kind of techniques
but of course what you can show using the worst case
it is going to be exponential
so in practice it's a very concise representation
but from a theoretical point of view still you can end up you know if
you are given a bunch of points
in to me point is one of these elements like you know one two one
two three
is a concise way can presented for given all these sets i can say i
can represent this by using these four
but of course you can always begin a set which makes this that's really large
that means you end up
a huge number here a huge number
so what we're trying to do is that if you are given two
so what you can do is you can say well my positive data sets can
be represented by
elements of this this this kind of one by
and then
the negative set is like this contrast patterns are nothing but set of all patterns
in this which is quite easy you can generate all possible patterns from from this
does it from that you remove everything that present
is the same in some sense it's a very simple definition of contrast patterns
for imaging
all it telling you is that
you know the dataset you know we just not sure there is only one data
which is feature one
taking value one let's if FT two two and so forth and what we try
to do is that there is the need set has these ones
i'm interested in all the patterns
that are
i present here
but not so for example you could say
one is
contrast pattern because one is present here
but not in this
and you can also say
i want to use present one is not and so forth that is
two three is present here
two three also present day doesn't come
so you can very concisely define
contrast patterns like this
but it could be
an exponential feminist computing
so this border differential algorithm is basically an iterative method it's minimally expands these patterns
to make sure that the patterns of
in fact
in contrast patterns so for example you start with one
and you know that immediately
if you take letter one is the taken first and immediately we know that
in one or any extended terms of one
that is a subset of this is going to be a contrast pattern because we
don't have
and then if i start with that bit too
of course two is not contrast patterns
even if i extended to three contest at the moment i find two three four
that i know that it is the contrast pattern because there is no
two three four here
OK so therefore
two three four is a subset of the set the four two three four is
context border if is basically
very cleverly expand this this sets
and the looks into the
into the negative set
if it is there
then it proves that structure and then and then go so the moment i find
it then there's no point in expanding because two three four
any other pattern will be by definition
would be a congress
the border diff can handle up to
you know
at that time and we looked at the end of PC
again the question is it you know is really interesting that
people say
we have infinite computing power
but not in infinite memory
because you know you can take any PC
run for right you've got infinite computing
so computing is not a problem memories the problem
so it's the kind of these interesting concept but of course we don't live that
long and therefore
you know we want the results to be seen so when you see these statements
like that there is an implicit notion
that i can't wait for more than an hour or a day or maybe three
months you know depending on what you do
so when you see these things let's assume there are some constraints defined so with
those constraints what we found is that
about seventy five attributes you have patients anything higher