so this would be considered a sequential mixed
this is the method with only update
so looking for an exponential family distribution with parameters
and what you're doing is you're just updating one parameter to time it just projecting
onto the i th constraint
so when we consider the sequential method
there's method called iterative scaling which is the parallel method
it it's all the parameters at the same time
and the remarkable thing about that method i'm not going to go into the theory
of that but that's also beautiful method
in a different way which is the so this particular method
in the one we saw
you update one of the data is
they update the next you know you cycle through the different sized but at each
stage you actually have a fully normalized distribution
iterative scaling
there much you don't worry about normalisation
you update all the parameters in a very intuitive it's kind of you know if
you only care about the parameter how much would you updated located in that way
so the result might not even be a probability distribution of might not lie it
might not like the simplex
so while iterative scaling is running
creating these distributions that actually you know just simply goes outside the simplex
but you can show that eventually comes back
and it reaches the
if we choose the optimal
if it is the i projection
there are many variants on iterative scaling
and one can use sort of gradient based method
i think this this
and when people suggest that these are foster
so about by just
by just talking about
a little bit about bregman divergences
so one thing we found over here is the
we found this strange connections between euclidean distance and KL divergence
on the face of it one would think that they have nothing in common with
squared euclidean distance is the most well behaved
you know it's always bounded
we dealing with bounded distributions this thing is disbanded
you know it's very familiar
kill divergence in so much more wild unbounded it's not symmetric
however these two distributions have a lot in common
both satisfy this pythagorean theorem for instance they both have a very nice notion of
so what's the commonality over here are the other distance measures
they also have these properties
and turns out that there are
there is this whole family of distributions distance measures called bregman divergences
and all of these have the same nice properties
these common properties that we observed you know just just
coincidentally between squared euclidean distance until convergence
so all these to all these distributions satisfy pythagorean theorem when it comes to projection
so what are these bregman divergences
well the way you can think about
is by returning to exponential families can that sort of explains what these things are
if you look at the gaussians
the natural distance measure for the gaussians is squared euclidean distance talk about the spherical
this is because if you look at the distribution of the spherical gaussians it lies
in these
in the spherical contours
a guassian lies and if you look at the contours of equal density for gaussians
it concentric spheres
so the actual distance measure for dls
it's just the squared euclidean distance
you can tell the density of points by measuring its squared euclidean distance from the
centre of the gaussians
you can define a similarity measure for the for other the exponential families as well
any exponential family you can see i mean look at the mean of this family
and now
let me look at the surfaces of equal density as i move away from the
the distance measure is defined by those surfaces
and that's the bregman divergence
it turns out that if you look at the multinomial distribution
you get that the KL divergence
and when you look at
and now when you vary the exponential families
exponential for exponential families are you know incredibly things they include
ah undirected graphical models of so as you have to vary the members of this
family that all these different distance measures these contours of equal density
and they're all bregman divergences
that's what bregman divergences are
and they all have these nice properties
and it turns out that once you start looking at
i i projections once you start looking at the geometry of the bregman divergences
a remarkable number machine learning tasks
the scene you know that seem to be coming from a totally different place actually
turn out to be i projections
OK so for instance
there are papers that that show that the ones you generalize
information projection to these arbitrary bregman divergences
these things like boosting iterative scaling in so this sort of
these other methods actually turn out to be
i projection operations
the simple simple algorithm for
for i projection with respect to to bregman divergences
OK and so in a sense this projection is
it's a very fundamental is a sort of central operation in machine learning
it's probably much more widespread than one imagines so
one thing that would be an interesting project would be too
just going to sit down
and c and c when can just really write down a lot of machine learning
it's just simple
as as either single projection operations
alternating projection operations to something like ian algorithm
might just be a set of alternating projection operations
and this would be really cool because them
you know you might be able to describe the whole lot in machine learning in
this sort of natural language by projections it's very simple
this very simple projections and thereby
when we talking about things to improve result in greater generality
talk about the convergence of the method instead of proving it just the same teams
in the last lecture devoted to nuclear physics and i think it's also you're legislature
for the summer student programme
i'm going to
to talk about nuclear reactions because this yesterday i gave you many examples related to
to nuclear structure
both experiment and theory
so today
will be devoted to sufficient efficient process sorry
because a lot of progress has been made recently concerning the description of this mechanism
so what is sufficient so you know that vision is the process when you had
indicators and then splits into fragments with the operation of neutron and then gamma
and as a condition of the fragments
so you have two kinds of fish
you can have spontaneous fission
when you have the nucleus
and in its ground state that will undergoes fission
are you can have induced fission so induced by
projectile which can
the neutron gamma are
in the eye and so
and i think is whatever so it then it gives some energy to the system
and then you have the component claims
that have been given an exhibition energy and then you can
undergo fission
only nineteen nuclei are known to fission spontaneously
so the difference between these two kind of nuclei are represented here
so this is the cross section depending on the energy
of the fissioning system so you see here please cite nuclei so you had to
cross section
which is
zero here even for very small and even for zero
this is to compare with this one
well you have to put some energy is still not zero energy here
then you have efficient so you have here critical point
before you can have efficient
fission on average the energy release for actinides vision is around two hundred a
so if you compare with something that you do better know which is the combination
of carbon capture and only for a for
so that means that for fission of one gram of uranium two hundred thirty five
you will have the same amount of energy than two point five tons of coal
how do you share these energy so
the main part
goes to the kinetic energy of the fission products one hundred sixty eight
then you be evaporated neutrons o five a media
and then all that what is needed because of the
fission fragments and prompt gamma eta gamma delayed bit
and then you have neutrinos so
all these can be transparent and you can have the same energy is
then in the energy from the neutrinos is lost
we cannot
take that energy
so i remind you will be important to the fission process of vertices energy predictions
of nuclear
o plant
so i hope that yesterday you were here for the talk of for the first
time they so he was not disgusting at all these nuclear power plant
and he was presenting something else something new which is so large
four plant so
i don't want to
two weeks later in more detail now doing this still but if you have any
questions concerning the
fusion and nuclear power plants and other techniques i would be happy to encourage christians
after the talk
so there are a lot of studies devoted to new fuel cycles for example based
entirely on where because you can find more italian than uranium so this is one
are they allowed to think of study is devoted to cause mutations
for this energy improved prediction
also fission is used to produce
radioactive beams so for example
there is a project at carnegie which is derived to wear
you have to tell induced fission on at night and then you can produce a
lot of
neutron rich fragments that will be accelerated the
so this is one way to produce exotic nuclei
and then you have astrophysics
why is it important for us to physics
because this is the nuclear charge proton and the neutron number you have here is
the regions
of actinides
like uranium plutonium and these are the region of fission fragments of predictions
this light masses
maybe message here neutron rich nuclei
so what the impact of that
you've got three points so first because of fish
so f process is limited
so so then the prediction of very heavy elements or even superheavy element is limited
you have also these fission cycling so you the he range and then you introduce
some structure
in the nuclear distribution because of the fission fragments of two to two fragment a
small one big one
and then you have competition
it was to be dedicated to world stability
this is why the fission process is
using application of energy production of exotic nuclei and study of astrophysics
so how to represent very basically the fission process
so first you have the nucleus
which can be excited or not and then you have the competition between reputation to
protect and
coulomb repulsion
and these attractive nuclear interaction
so you have some of the oscillation of the nucleus
and then
you lose some energy so you have to do to to give energy to the
system and then
this is then goes to very difficult point which is the critical point what we
call the saddle point
so then after this point which is the maximum of the energy then
the potential energy decreases so when you read this point then you will
got to fish you cannot go back to you we got patient
and then you have the separation of the fragments and then the fragments which are
excited when they meet some neutron and gamma to go back to the ground state
so the time scale sufficient
one is
at all
one thing
one one
how do we
it was you
what you
all right
the show you want
all we would be
i think you know
well one
one thing
and you
we be
used to work
you want to be
so why
i don't you know how
one of
in the
so this is this
and one thing so before we add the new things is so we know about
things he said
when i hit the edit it and what you can do can eat some
other things about so it knows automatically did business since it's
it was constrained from the
full of upstream to be before
so circus it's also manufacture
which is our answer to search
also allergy
which also exists
if you go to follow ups
this yielded no because
this is one the
three three
we can consult the court about
here we consider for example
cisco systems
i had to
in order to check them
so this in line but didn't
you can add some more things about her so she's
and if you check the follow-ups now
something has be appearing here
maybe not
in the conceptual the backward
this is the just telling
so one automatically asserted that it's probably
two hundred fifty thousand days old
one hundred and fifty years old
user computer scientist from it and then it kansas she's from it depends on the
and then we can have
know that she has a birthday can enter
in california number
she can right people
i have email address and she's of human beings
is a woman
because so this sort of the short in this demo was to context automatically by
concept from all the cyc
using but and using these documents together with the background knowledge from all sides
the site suggested new things that we should we could add to the knowledge base
to enrich it so the next time you will get something like this
we could extract more more facts from
what concepts from the text
i could
it is the
shelf life
so this is a allows them also
the intention was to make it like but then of course
maybe the
the score because of this i think
the things are connected anyway so the a the idea was to show
piece of
software which runs some leaves on the top of cyc which is called cyc analytic
the goal is the following so we ask the question in
natural language and the system
tries to provide us with answers to the justifications and so on and so on
that's what the difference between the cyc analytic environment compared let's say a soft first
powerset so power doesn't really understand what the question is but tries to match and
the same is semantically answers or triples which they extracted from the text
with the three troopers which appear with the pattern which appears in
in the query in the question so here in fact really tries to understand the
question and thought since it also has this huge knowledge base tries to match
it's really question which is then transferred into the of proper query with the with
the knowledge it has in
knowledge base so something is called psychoanalytic environment
so i will show two examples one is a little bit
normal one
and the second one is a little bit more advanced forms just to show you
what what has psychic
hopefully will be able to do in the in the future just a more general
so here we have a question which we normally type that we know of their
natural language
so the question here is what range capabilities are lost for the
whatever rocket launch even
world computer on the graph
it is functioning so that this kind of question
which is then with the simple
user interface and but quite effective interface
transferred into first order logic query so this this is up here
so let's say we want to integrate this function
with respect to
this particular distribution px
now in this
four compare
different ways of doing that
so what i'm showing you here is how the accuracy of the estimates in this
case i'm looking at the mean
the average squared error
well that depends on the sample size
the error will get smaller and smaller
as the as get more more samples
and is currently
good job so
the red line here is simple monte carlo simple multicolored this means that we simply
take values at random
from the
red distribution from the scouting distribution
and then we just some of the corresponding values in that forest
i that gives us the performance of here
the black line here is the optimal importance sampling
so it's the it's the best possible importance somebody you can write down
the best possible and importance sampling is you can actually compute that without knowing what
the interval is this sort of theoretical limit of how well you could possibly do
you you're always
so a little bit worse than this this is the limit of how
how well you can do
and here's the
the bayesian inference procedure
initially you're going doing is about as well as you could and then
at some point things really start to improve the logarithmic scale
things really start to improve basically because given
maybe ten samples of maybe twenty examples to and function then you have a pretty
good idea of what the function is doing
you have a very very accurate estimates of what the what that it would be
and much much faster than you would get
this is orders of magnitude less data that we need
four four
the importance of life you have to wait for the variance to be reduced
by averaging together in one of
now i'm going to talk about the regression
can do classification casting processes
yes we can
the problem is that the way to do that is to say well
we have a gas process here which lives on and on and on restricted domain
but if want to make classification probabilistic classification then we want machine to offer probabilities
so one way of doing that is to the squash gaussianprocess through some function that
limits the function to be
inside zero to one and then we can interpret the output of the
model being a probability
that sounds pretty simple but unfortunately
it messes up a lot of the nice analytic properties because now
classification galson likelihood doesn't really make a lot of sense
target values of observations always going to be zero one going to be
one of two classes but it doesn't really make any sense so the discrepancy between
the observations and the target should be carried out in distribution
i we have to choose something which is more suited to
classification and that makes our the analysis a lot harder
there are various techniques
and you can use
two to cope with problems it's slightly more detail
so again you have to know the truth of likelihood function now
which is
given by this this the cumulative
distribution function of the of the girls here there's nasty non-linear functions
the same
prior priors before
then you're
posterior distribution here will not be able to process any more it be something else
it would be something nasty
so you have to use
some clever approximation techniques to work out what you're predictive distribution which should be
and what you're much like you should be
and of course they don't have time to
tell you about what those techniques are
but let me just give you a few hints so one of the one that
you can use it as a method so human which is in the past message
this morning
you can try to find some how the the MAP estimate and then you can
try to make galveston approximation around that
and it turns out that then you can under that approximation you can get through
you can get to the calculations of the variational bound need algorithm which is called
expectation propagation
which turns out to be incredibly accurate this problem can basically get the right answer
without too much work
one last thing that i'll show you
it's related to
sparse approximations now
one thing that i've glossed over a little bit of the one of the problems
with is that you have to invert the covariance matrix is
do your analysis if you have a lot of observations the new covariance matrix is
going to be big
and you can invert the inverted thousand thousand matrix reasonably easy
you can also maybe ten thousand by ten thousand you really want to know what
if you get much higher than that then you have problems
fitting those messages into memory take a long time to them
are there any one of the ways of getting around that problem
just sketch out some ideas that i need to illustrate using
using the graphical model framework
remember the graphical model
four girls process look like this
there's even this morning with a little bit more particular about how we define gaston
graph models here at sort of mixture of his two notation might have
undirected links here and have some direct links don't worry about the details
one idea would be to say well it's hard to handle all data then just
ignore some of the
of course not very smart because in your for throwing away a lot of information
so can we do something more than we do something more clever turns out to
be whole
host of approximation techniques out there
which you get and you can understand almost all of them
so pictorially
in this nice the way
the first thing you do
is you introduce a bunch more latent variables i introduced now i want to use
and connect everything up like this
and of course the problem if you're looking at the in the graphical model here
the problem here is that there are no that no missing link
remember the missing links with the things that made things easy to compute with
they indicated these conditional independence relationships none here
between the latent variables
OK that's why it's that's why top that's why you need to invert is very
very big mistake
so first introduced a bunch a bunch of extra latent variables and i'm allowed to
do that why am i allowed to do that because of the marginalisation property marginalisation
properties as well if you have a joint process over
three variables integrate out
one of these then you're going to get
the right marginal distribution back to the things that you've written into the
OK so this is this looks like a like a progress in the wrong direction
now maybe even worse
because i have even more able to deal with and now i can come up
with an approximation
the approximation is that the
training latent variables
we can change the product into some mission go back to this point
and you can see that minimizing the like to be a that maximizes the likelihood
is equivalent to minimizing this was scale
how do we solve the squares regression problems we can
we get the expression for the gradient with respect to w zero
and get to w
by investing because i think
and this is called the least squares regression
often is not a good idea to try to that that is that it's better
for medical mission to sort of this is that system
because now
you've got a regression a
it is well known that two obviously to the top if we have that at
the time
noisy and high dimensional
i've been you will be some concept that everybody is familiar with that if you
think of what you are speaking we are doing well on our training data but
doing very poorly on our face the that so we are not able to generalise
how do we
and with this problem
since less can be seen as the matching antibodies space what we can do
and at some control overfitting is too long history
this ash
one of our hypothesis spaces in in order to reduce
tool to look for it but this is not too much complex and flexible
so we look for
ipod anybody's is based on on a low capacity
and if our training set is large enough we have
theoretical guarantee that we are doing well on similar test
this is just increase and not found any formal
so how do we control the capacity for our problem least squares regression we can
minimize loss before at the same time with the control the capacity
it means that we are restricting the section of our hypothesis spaces
by imposing that the normal follows w squares should be less than one this is
non notable about the square root system
OK again although we solve this problem and i have to introduce the background and
with constraints
i even put the the gradient you went to zero degraded
i two
to support an example i'm sorry just i have so many things to show up
in the talk but yeah i mean these are likely to that just because
so to explain i mean you you know
on knowledge function
but it
the same but i thought the idea
i don't have picture shows some sort of of business
i all the feature in the first part to give more space to the second
part because i assume
i would say
warming that
sources would be so
maybe we i can play the features
OK so
OK again we rely
matrix inversion
well we have
the matrix inversion
to solve our problems and equating the gradient w equal to zero
again we have a probabilistic interpretation of and
like for instance and they basically what we maximizes maximizing the posterior simple
four join
we always assume that
ocean prior on the vector w and you can see by the way i that
over the corpus just go sentence by sentence of over over web pages extract as
much as it it can from each sentence and then
it indexes that we put into lucene and now we have something that can answer
queries that close close interactive speeds some issues hopefully make them
will work here
over the internet and what i'm showing you here
it is accessible from my home page or just type in text runner
into your favourite search engine to find this this is publicly available you can play
with it obviously i'm going to show you a good example you know it it's
it's performance is variable but to give you a sense of the potential of this
kind of thing and this is run over about one hundred twenty million web pages
of varying quality we have wikipedia in there
we've got some pretty random pages so again
this is just the proof of concept so let's ask what kills bacteria
as a simple question processor the basically tells it OK we want kills as the
relationship bacteria as the object tell me what you find and we see a variety
of answers here and here it says one hundred seventy five more something click on
in an open up and you see the various things it found to kill bacteria
from from the obvious ones like antibiotics and if you look below we see chlorine
heat amoxicillin pasteurisation they start to get more obscure like garlic alcohol honey and if
you're not sure that you believe in it you can click on the number here
and c
the different sentences that it came from or let me do it here
so it's more visible right CC different senses you can click through and actually go
to the web pages
and then another nice thing is you see there's a lot of compression going here
and if the scene so all these different ways of referring to antibiotics world compressed
to realize is really just saying antibiotics are not swamped with a bunch of different
answers the really mean
the same thing
OK so
so good that gives you a flavour of how to textrunner works and
usually open it up but since everybody has their laptops here you can you can
play with it yourselves and again that this this prototype is not particularly optimise it
takes you know ten to thirty seconds to give you an answer we could easily
make the bailout faster with just some elbow grease there's nothing inherently slow about the
processing at
at query time right all the hard work happened at compile time the crawler so
to give you a more quantitative sense we take a sample of nine million web
pages that contain about eleven point three million triples and using samples we assessed OK
how many of these are actually any good
and we found that of the eleven point three million there are about nine point
three million with the world form relation and of those there are seven point eight
million to have both well for relations well formed and it is there are meaningful
and then what we find that all of these there were six point eight million
that contained abstract observations things like fruit contain vitamins those might be good for ontology
building various activities like that and they are on the order of a million there
were concrete facts like oppenheimer taught at berklee
and you see that the precision levels there were achieving in here are actually pretty
high rates if you type in
textrunner you gonna get a mixture of abstract facts in concrete facts but with fairly
accuracy we tend to sort them by frequency and so the ones that are more
often repeated more likely to be correct filter up to the top
OK so
so that's extraction
and now what i want to talk about is OK if you have this kind
of extraction what can you do on top of that what kind of inference you
can do because again initially we got into this and we solve these billions and
billions of sensors with great anything you could ever possibly want to know is in
there but in fact what we realize over time is a lot of the information
that you want is actually implicit in some form
and cell talk about three kinds of inferences that
we and other people have done over extraction
and those are entertained predicate resolution and this is the old problem right of the
duping has lots of different names but the basic idea is to do this kind
of compression and realize the two different sentences are actually talking about the same objects
and then i'll talk about how we assess the probability of correctness of the sentence
that's pretty important and a last they all talk about the most recent work how
what's the
what's the what the entries now this for a matrix
the things that look like this
so this is rho j
multiplying this
ck hits column k of the matrix so those are the entries of the matrix
so let us write out a few
what's the what's the first row of the
of the fourier matrix
what's right
o ones is exactly thanks because j is zero in the first row
OK so
it's all what eighty one
and the first column also why is that
because k is zero
i see i'm going to get crowded here get a by matrix and let's get
the second row and column in
or the
anyhow how we want to count that we have that is the zero maybe this
would be role one what are the entries along that row
so now j is one
so there are entries are one
right omega your w w square you
and finally set seven
there are these numbers
one right sitting around the unit circle
and to
really pin down what's an extra
j is too
so we've swearing so we have w square it
w four and the symmetric of course actually so so this this is going to
down to w seven in this way
w four w six
well it's really pin down to find the last
the last what's last number here
w know what power is sitting in in the lower corner there
forty nine
yeah seems right we're in the seventh
n minus one square right seven times seven where we're at the end of our
rope here
w forty nine but of course w forty nine is an alias for for some
smaller power w what it
what would be in that particular case
just the first power is that right w forty nine one that's interesting wlth is
w w the power is one
so w forty eight yes right forty eight hours one
and w forty nine right here is just as good
so anyway
w to the jk
know the answer
and what's the inverse
well you might say wait a minute
this is the full matrix no zeros at all
how do you expect invert find the inverse of an eight by a full matrix
o and a little thought is coming to my mind
which made him we will find the inverse
safely and of course the
it's got to be revealed by this formula because that's this is the formula goes
back from the wires connected y practices and i just throw comment here
because i like to
mention also some things that i think are not so clear as you would think
i mean the whole world is this matrix and you guys have seen it so
on if i can values
i know what it's like and values are
and we could do it we can we can see what so this digression
because the i can values of the matrix don't
don't play a big role
in the series
they all after
so it turns out the igon values it turns out that the fourth power of
this matrix
is the identity
five normalized correctly actually
i a better sort of more symmetric normalisation will put one over square and there
and one was one of them there and then that would give us one then
i i usually don't include that in in
defining the fourier matrix but we could
if we do
then we normalize this matrix so that its fourth power turns out to be identical
so that's pretty nice
on the carrying on this digression just
because some of you will
all too well the
dft formulas
what about the igon values of this matrix for is the fourth power of the
matrix is the identity
what does that tell me about it so i can values
what are the possible like values of the matrix
four person to do that without electronic help is this is not so believable
the most dramatic example
of destructive
the collapse of
the bridge
the coal mine in nineteen forty
many of you may have seen that dramatic
movie that some of you may not have seen it
and even if you have seen it
it's worth seeing it again
a little bit of wins
a little bit more wind
just likely these wind instruments you dumping all spectrums
of frequencies on two
wind instrument and it picks out the resonance frequency and this bridges you're going to
see picks out its own
resonance frequencies and the consequences are
quite dramatic
so if you can start marcos
with this movie
was nineteen forty
and it is in washington state
i have
no example
all right
destructive resonances more impressive than this one
all right so now
we've had so much fun and we have to really
get into
electromagnetic waves we turn back to
as you see them here
and maxwell
who was credited for this
structure term that the editor MP's law
the displacement current term
i was able to predict that electromagnetic waves should exist predicted
the existence of radio waves which were later
discovered by words
and that was a great victory
for the theory that i'll show you today there was another enormous victory
around the corner
electric and
magnetic fields
can move through space
and satisfy all four maxwell's equations
electric field
results from the changing
the magnetic fields
and the magnetic fields
results from the changing
electric fields one exists
at the mercy
the other and the other exists
at the mercy of one
together they propagate through space they can even propagate through
when no charges
and where there are no currents
very mysterious
i will write down
a possible solution
of an electromagnetic wave
which means all four
maxwell's equations
and this is the graphical this
play of those
weighted i'm going to write down that i will discuss the
with you in a minute
electric fields
is only in the direction of x
this is the
magnitude the largest value of the electric field
only in the direction of x
the is omega t
this is the frequency
minus sign tells you that it is travelling in the
plus z direction
the associated
magnetic field
is be zero
only in the y direction
was exactly the same
mine is only getting
if a plot this at time t equals
using this curve
right here
you see the magnetic field curve here magnetic field is only in the y direction
and the electric field is only in the x direction
and this is a package that
together moves
in the direction of
with this speech which is only god divided by k
and the wavelengths
two here
his enterprise divided by
we call them plane waves
the the reason why we call them plane wave is that
if you take a plane anywhere perpendicular to see
no matter where you are in that plane that moment in time
the b
vector are everywhere in the plane to see
think of this as a plane perpendicular
two d
axis and then this whole three passes by
so you see the electric field vector like this becomes zero like this becomes zero
like this and the magnetic field vector maximum zero in this direction and so on
that's why
they are called plane
these equations
only satisfies
maxwell's equations
on the two conditions
and one condition is
these zero
is easier zero divided by c
and the condition is only divided by k
which is the velocity
which which it
i recall that c
in vacuum we call the velocity vector like magnetic radiation
that is one
divided by the square root
absolutely zero
user if that's the case
my two
equations will satisfy
each of these paintings that were on display
now this is a piece that always interested me because the painting is very pedestrian
it's of an old polish oxcart sitting on some godforsaken road in rural russia somewhere
so how do you make that work as music how do you turn that visual
image into music
how do you turn
that into sort of live sonic sky and i should say at the outset i'm
mean prejudice you're listening here just a little bit i hear this as is me
being in the centre
and this oxcart starting to get started decide this matter everybody moves left to right
so i'm going to hear this moving left to right it comes in front of
me almost what rules over top of me
runs me down and then
this appears to my right so as we listen to this you
think about what are the techniques by which resource key creates this musical action scenes
you should be able to come up with two pretty good ideas here too pretty
good answers here we go
i slack
two minutes later
that is playing
about low brass instrument doesn't sound much like it but it's actually playing in the
higher register
the instrument and it is true that
you can have just a little bit strings come in with a counter i complementary
give me one pretty straightforward way this happen
what did he do there
as young lady out here please
OK crescendo from beginning to end
so like giant wedge so that's why it the court seems to be in front
of you and so we're talking about musical volume started very quietly it builds up
to this huge centre in which we have the bass drum pounding away there in
the snare drum coming in to give the effect of the entire surface ravelling that
particular particular point and then as it passed by the thunder passed by you and
off we went into the distance quietly into the distance
and it was will come back to that but
how did that happen we listen to the end that just one was kind of
the disintegration of the sound at the end disintegration of the sound at the end
so let's pick so that's one big one big way this happened one that's probably
the big ticket items there's another way a more subtle ways
any thoughts about that
yes the instrumentation
can you elaborate on that
right so is a kind of wedge shape with regard to the instrument to we
starts with the lowest instrument the lowest industry and then goes to the high instruments
and then back to low instruments at the end let's just review
well no we won't review this let's not review that OK we don't have time
to review that but let's go on to say the following what was resort ski
new there
it was very basic principle of acoustics and what is that principle
a big part
well to some extent i'm going to give an example of an example of that
of the train kind of going by you in the sound heading off any other
other direction to to some extent it is that way but what i was thinking
about here is this idea that the lowest sound create or the longest sound waves
and the last the longest the lowest sound create the largest sound waves and they
last longer the lowest sounds last the longest why might this be the case here
not having too much confidence in our slides this morning i went ahead and put
this one up on the board here here is one pitch here is the picture
of the string to higher so you can see it this way as you probably
know if you take the one string and
plug it it's going to take that long string a long time to past that
sort of cycle if you will just one pass through the cycle that string half
she was
i mean this is one of
you see
he is
this is what is
this is the truth
so this is
and i would say
this is
so this is
she she she
it was
he is
in the course
you you can do that
and the
i don't know
because of
and you
so this is
so far the this
constraints the Lagrange just itself and the dual would be just the minimum value the dual
function if you introduce a new variable Y and set that equal to A X
minus B then you get a more interesting dual because then the dual function would
be this objective plus this weighted sum of the constraints and then you can minimize this
over X and Y because we now have two variables X and Y the minimal over
X is very easy because this is the only term in X so the
unconstrained minimal of this over X is usually minus infinity because it's an linear function of X
and it's minus infinity except when the coefficient is zero so that's where
this constraint comes from A transpose nu is zero and then the minimum of
this over Y can be shown to be a minus infinity except
when nu the coefficient of Y here in this term is less than one in
the dual norm so then if you plug this in and write this you get the problem
of maximizing B transpose nu subject it is constraints you can get this dual problem
again with a maximization and there's also you can combine this parameter the dual and write
duality conditions optimality conditions that are equivalent that characterize primal and dual optimality and that
for example can be useful if you computed the dual solution and you want to
extract from the dual solution the primal optimal so then you can look at
the primal dual optimality conditions or the KKT conditions and given lambda try to
solve for X but maybe I can skip this so let's return then to the dual methods
so in the dual methods if we can restart with the problem at equali linear constraints the
question would be what could be the advantages of solving the dual problem using a
first order method so in general if you say I'll solve the dual problem because somehow
it's easier then that's only true if you restrict yourself to a certain class of
methods right so because it's really the same problem interpreted in different ways so the dual
problem essentially is not easier than the primal problem but they can be easier if
you want to use a certain class of methods for example first order methods and
then you see that this can be interesting for example if I don't have ek
inequalities in the primal problem and F star is differentiable then I can solve
the dual by an unconstrained method for differentiable optimization which could be easier than
dealing with this general inequalities in the primal constraints in the primal so it could be
that the dual is more interesting or easier for first order methods because it's
unconstrained or maybe it's constrained you have qualities in the primal but this is a
simple inequality and we've seen projection on this feasible set is very easy so a gradient
projection method might be a good method for the dual but not useful for the
primal because projection on this feasible set might be very complex right another reason why
people are often interested in the dual is that the dual often is gives you a problem
that can de be decomposed into smaller problems that can be solved in parallel so let's
look at we'll see that in the next slide so if you look at these dual
functions and we have to choose the first order method for solving the dual
problem then the differentiability properties of F star will be important that's the conjugate of
F so an interesting question is what does it mean for F star to be
differentiable what does that mean in terms of the original function F
use the billion triples we give you another billion triples were created by
yahoo scraping websites
it's going to lots and lots of different people with different semantic web project saying
give us the chance to start
so some of these trips some of these things and down in the graph have
complex ontologies describing them some have no ontologies describing some are very high quality data
some of very low quality data and
the challenge is very simple what can you do with this
right so
the best of the best way i've seen them sort of describing this problem there's
a a project you'll probably hear about over the next few days somewhere you run
into large
the large knowledge collider
i believe the PRI's frank van harmelen indicator pencils and by several other people
and their slogan is
reasoning systems do not scale to the requirements of their hottest applications
and that's really what it's all about is we know a lot of stuff about
reasoning and we know on about stuff that scaling the pudding those together is hard
and most of the work that's gone today and semantic web circles
focused on
a lot of data a little reasoning or logical reasoning
but not a lot of web users in other words not giving up the
the lexus control
OK if you can understand it when you have a model when you're doing expressive
there's a lot you can do so again the older AI
the slogan knowledge is power is correct
and on the web it's also the problem is if i limit the domain to
one thing that i know a lot about i know
all there is to know about this kind of drugs
you know about fifty thousand classes description of some particular cancer
that's very very powerful as long as what you care about is that particular cancer
it's not very powerful when you go to facebook
OK unless the only thing you're looking for on facebook as people have exactly that
kind of cancer and who have have somehow in their facebook profiles decided to scrap
describe at the molecular level
what their DNA is like there aren't a lot of those you will find
so again the more you know about something the more you can do with that
the last you know about something the harder it is and there's a lot of
space in the middle and think
because and so
the semantic web world you'll see a lot of different diagrams there's famous layer cake
there also things one i this is what i actually put up around two thousand
two and said you know a problem we're going to have in this field
it is
all of these different languages were playing with we call ontology languages
but they really have very different things they are doing
some of them are just modelling simple relationships
some of them are modelling very complex information
and we're going to confuse the outside world which comes to us so you come
to meeting like this and you learn about ontology engineering
and some of the people who are going to present today
are primarily going to be talking about stuff like this and
this year we had actually and talk to talk a little bit more about what's
going down down at this and i'll be given that one again later
these things are very different and it's important to understand
and this matters a lot because
if you're trying to do research in the space
if you're trying to do
you know making company in this space
they are very different things and they have different concerns so
one of these views what you're primarily
we're worried about is your ontology creation and modeling and expressivity and the other view
you'll hear a lot of talks at this conference about triple stores
about scaling about the language sparql
a way to think about it is
if you go back to the early database literature the semantic web is a lot
like the database world was
twenty five thirty years ago
clearly a very powerful technology
that clearly fits an important nash finished being the web
and a lot of people trying to figure out how to use it in different
models and so there's research
you can find that then paper is still to this day papers about
data languages and data calculi in data
reasoning as it were
and other papers about how to keep the thing fast how to make it so
it doesn't pages often
as you go around this conference as you look at the poster says you look
at the papers you will see people talking about how do i add
so i keep the system consistent if i want to have information and
you can have five fingers on the a hand but only one of them can
be thought
qualified cardinality restrictions or any other people who are saying
if you use a bit map representation
you can get
fifty million triples into a one get a one goodbye
online memory
and the reason you're seeing both those things at the same conference is coming from
the fact that
the eventual thing that puts them together
well actually here the i can in the next slide i will explain here the
the peak is constructed you can you can prove this result by constructing p on
the finite set
with finite output also because because it's
binary classification
so we can finance it is enough to get the
now for the other one
which is now strongly
he said that
so again given that
and a sequence of numbers that go to zero the end
you can construct distributions
such that the error of your ways
i will not
go to zero
faster than the sequence
so you can take an arbitrarily
slow sequence
and make constructive solutions such that is
at least as low as the sequence
the sequence as the converse is you so it can be constant but then
it doesn't look at some point
because of course you can have consistent algorithm so
you have to have
and to obtain these
so the difference between those surrounding but the first one you can do it on
the finances the second one you need a countable set
to make to construct distribution and and the idea is to the problem for which
there is no possible generalizations so essentially if you have not seen
an example you cannot predict what will be the label of this example essentially the
the function from x to y is smallest random are random in its deterministic of
course but is random in the sense that there is no relationship between the axis
and the y
and when you construct such a function
and then what happens is that so as i say eventually if you wait long
enough you what you will have seen all the samples
whether you are in a finite or countable set but it may take some time
it ended in this time can be in a finite sets
you can make it forced finite sample size as
so long as you want anyway so if you take if you're a finite set
of inputs is very big
then it will take you a long time to
to see a large proportion of this
input space
and on the countable space you can arrange such that
for each sample
size so for each n
when you sample
on average ten points
you have seen a certain number of points in your in in your comfortable space
but the point is that you have not seen yet
they have the probability mass at least in
so and on those points you always make a mistake or it has to be
to win because you you would make
fifty percent mistake so in the end you have you have this eighty and error
just the summary of these
so let's think consistency is easy in the countable case it doesn't require generalization
at least in this within this IID framework of course
when you're in the continuity continuous cases it it relies on the
in fact the he the fact that the function are measurable
and the no free lunch results they rely
the fact that
even though you may see
all the data in the end it may take time for you to to see
enough of the of the data
so now the question is how can we have this
negative results
what kind of to results can we
and in particular if we cannot prove that it's possible to generalize
we can always solution where generalisation is not possible
what can we do
so that's where
comes in the picture this
what i
call yesterday the decomposition of between estimation an approximation error
this this year and that we have seen they try to make the difference
between the error of your ways and the of the best algorithm as large as
but now this
term actually contains two contributions
you can rewrite it in this way
the first term is the difference between the loss of terrorism and
the loss of some function
in the class
so you you introduce some class of functions which
in the
regret setting i called the
reference class so you have you want to compare in the way your performance to
some class of classifiers so
you compare
the loss
of your algorithm to the best loss
in this class
and then
the best loss in this class with
best loss of world among all possible functions
so far we have not done anything is just reverting
usually these two parts these two contributions are called the so the this one is
called the approximation error so the this is
the best you can do within this class g right within this clergy the best
loss you kind of thing is this the best
the difference between the loss and the
the optimal loss is this quantity and
this is deterministic in the sense that it does not depend on the
on the sample on the training data
right so it's
it's some number that is fixed
course you you cannot compute because you don't know what is
and why you cannot even compute l in general
it should be as much as possible
the loss function
why the it
it's not it
the estimation error you
six of what is one
OK for me be so
OK so this approximation error is that i mean i think that's the important point
you can you cannot
computed because you don't know what is the star and you for example in particular
i don't know whether you start using your class g
you can assume it is there but you don't know
you can take it
OK now the estimation error
i find these as the smallest loss
that a function in g
in capital g can happen
so we have an alpha course we have the additional components to the here
what we know about the chemical potential in both parts the chemical potential has to
be equal outside and inside the container
o point
is just
a a liquid
tag pressure people want to apply
temperature t
and that has to be equal
new a point data
o point made is just in the pure liquid
so that's just
anyway a star
the liquid pressure p
and temperature t
so here's
chemical potential
o point data
here it is the point out those who have to be equal to each other
and now we're just going to use ralph lord
and what does that tell us
we have
log of x a
plus mu a star
the liquid pressure p
was on and t
so there's are
chemical potential inside the container
that's equal to mu a star
the pure liquid
o point there
so we can
just rewrite this
these are the
along x a
you a star
pressure people plus
five the
you a star
pressure p
is equal to zero
we need
pressure dependence of the chemical potential
but we
so we have an expression from that
we know that g
the t
plus the
the temperature is the same on both sides but we need to worry about what
happened different
the constant c
dg is
so now if we look at the chemical potential which is just the gibbs free
free energy
per mole
mu a
it is
the a star
right in other words the difference in the chemical potential of this changes as a
function of pressure
is going to be given by
the molar volume of a under these conditions in the pure liquid
it's just the potential the pressure dependence of
not the kind of topic i would have thought drive away a lot of people
but you never know
for the rest of you who are willing to bear with me let's let's continue
right so so
now let's just integrate we need to know the change in the USA it at
a finite jumping pressure from inside outside the container so we're just going to great
if i want
new way
pressure people plus pi
minus mu a star
the pressure p
and i just have to integrate from p
people of
the a four
and now i'm going to assume that this is only a safe assumption
but this quantity the smaller volume
isn't going to change the molar volume of today
isn't going to change significantly
going from the pressure out here to the pressure here on the grand scale of
things that small pressure change we can assume that the liquid is incompressible
over that small pressure change
which means that this is constant and so all we have then is
the the
a four
times but i
so then
back here so now we have calculated the differences
simple result so then we simply have that are the
lord XA a
but the a four star
is equal to zero
you saw last time and work through this quickly again that the long ago
x a
i can be written approximately as
minus and b
over and a
if you remember
are statistically independent knowing what the state variable
and these are unknown quantities well if you know what the state was you could
actually estimate the
now you make the assumption that the states are not observed
but they are generated by a markov chain so there's is the transition probability
let's say the state at time to the probability there is a probability to going
interstate three and so on so the joint probability of all the states is actually
the product of all these transition
probabilities and you have multiplied by the probability of the initial state
now if you want to do maximum likelihood estimation question what what's meant by maximum
likelihood estimation first of all
if this is a discrete random variable you would not want to know what are
emission probabilities this is something you don't know so
essentially all these numbers in this list are parameters so
you have a long
a series of observations and you try to estimate what are these numbers
so you have the transition probabilities as unknowns and you have the emission probabilities as
unknowns and of course if you want to do maximum likelihood with this then you
facing the problem
that the total likelihood of probability of all the observations is now
this object
because this is again
using conditional
so the conditional probability of having
the emitted
sequences the emitted symbols and the states can be written as the conditional times the
but since we don't observe the is we are marginalizing out the SS we're summing
over all
the states s
and of course i mean there's always this this this problem but you might say
if you want to do this exactly by hand you would have to
let's say if you have in the states and you would have a sequence of
length t
then there
you can sort of view this as the path so to say i go from
state one interstate three and then back so it can be it as the past
so this sum is kind of over an exponentially large
number of variables and it seems first of all of it
complicated but of course we have nice we have a nice structure so there's a
couple of nice algorithms for solving that problem in one of the algorithms has the
flavor of an ECM algorithm have been a couple of stuff is probably
he invented independently but all these algorithms for estimating parameters by maximum likelihood many of
them can be sort of put into the
family of the algorithms and that's what i want to talk about
of course is hidden markov models have have endless
applications for instance in speech
so as far as i know so in speech recognition you can have
you can try to build for instance word model
i mean if i have an expert here probably had some completely stupid because there's
i know there's fullname models says word models let's think about word models first i
think the word is sort of a sequence of different phonemes that you can speak
and so that the i mean what we actually observe is the sound
but you don't observe the phonemes they are kind of the hidden states and you
so safety events the most t nine-tenths and thus
that and clearly it's worse four and the bigger part
OK what is the solution to this recurrence
are solving recurrences so long ago what what methods should be used for solving the
the master method what k so we
so this is a case three of
so why
we're looking at and log base b a b here is ten nine so that
doesn't really matter because a is one of the log base anything on one zero
so this is an to cesarewitch which is one
and and is polynomially larger than one
this is going to be in order
which is good that's what we want linear time so far in the lucky case
unfortunately this is only intuition and what i was going to get the lucky case
we could do the same kind of analysis as we do with randomized quicksort if
you alternate between lucky and unlucky
things will still be good but let's just talk about the unlucky case
to show how bad things can get this really would be worst case analysis
in the unlikely case we get split of one two
and minus actually would have zero and minus one
because we're we're removing the partition element either way and there could be nothing less
than the partition elements
so is zero the left hand side and we have put minus one on the
right hand side
so now we get a recurrence like CNN student minus one plus linear cost
what's the solution to the recurrence
the swinish
and square this one you should just now
and square because it's an arithmetic series
that's pretty that this is much much worse than sorting and then picking the i
th element so
in the worst case this algorithm really sucks
but most of the time is going to do really well and i must you
really really like every coin flip is the wrong gives the wrong answer
you won't get this case
you'll get something more like the lucky case these that so would like to prove
and will prove that the expected running time here is linear
so it's very rare to get anything quadratic
later on i'll see how to make the worst case and here's why
it's really
really solve the problem
OK so let's
in the analysis
now you see analysis much like this before
so what do you suggest we do
in order to analyse expected time
divide and conquer algorithm so we kind of like to write down the recurrence on
resembling the running time
i don't need the answer this one was the first step
that we might have to analyse expected running time of the sound
look at different cases you exactly so
we have always possible
ways the random random partition could split could with zero to and minus one could
split in half split those
n minus one or an choices work as well so how can we break into
those cases
indicator in a very school
exactly that's what we want to do
indicator random variable suggests that what we're dealing with is not exactly
just the function t then but it's random variable this is one subtlety teevan
depends on the random choices so it's really a random variable
and then we're going to use indicator random variables get a recurrence
until then
are really
so the
running time of randomized select on an input of size n
i'm also going to write down explicitly an assumption
about the random numbers
but they should be chosen
independently from each other
so every time i call random partition it's it's generating a completely independent random number
from all the other times i call random partition that's important of course for this
analysis to work
you will see why
some point down the line and out to
so write down an equation for TV
we're going to
define the indicator random variables as suggested
and we'll call xk
this is for all k
from zero to
ten minus one
so an indicator and variables either one or zero
it's going to be one if the partition comes out OK
on the left-hand side
it's the same partition
two and minus k minus one
and it's zero otherwise
so we have and these variables between
whole point of the both of new . x we want to reduce the probability effects given the
dataset and that's approximated by saying that it is just
the the probability of a parametric model with the parameters
set to the maximum likelihood values we can think about is
the predicted distribution that's maximum likelihood the and the we can move towards a slightly more days in the U . by
introducing a private deletion of the speech that in which
case the posterior distribution is proportional to the
products of the likelihood function of the product American
we can choose a point estimates for the parameters of the
matter as the maximum posterior at which is just the same
by finding the value of things which maximizes the
posterior distribution of school the map again operated distributions obtained by just playing in
this value control parametric model as it is not really based in 1
can think of this only take the law he we get the lower
likelihood the the prior and we can just think about the process of regular right
so so this framework can be thought of In this sort of a
base in the EU but also just the support of his regularized
maximum likelihood so I tend to use the term based to mean something of a different
cultures heading Protestant regularisation but really
marginalisation the key idea in the key different things inferences when we then
integrated out of some areas make variables to the key idea in based in invisible
learning is the not so wise of the unknown parameters
Roenick point estimates so all predicted distribution to
the probability of the new data point in the training set
is just obtained from the Sun product group probability by multiplying they essentially buying making predictions for all possible values of things that the weighted by the posterior distribution so that's the exact expression just college in the summer
of the probabilities of basic inferences just a consistent
application of the some of the probability of any of the principles of as you'll see um it brings with
it a couple of the major advantages maximum likelihood and
also map of subject to use in the city of the change and examples
of this as we go through animals that they have the marginalisation correct of you that are particularly maximum likelihood but it also allows us to make a direct model comparisons
when we make these point estimates again this is not just
another instance of a good thing if we want to compare 1
model with another if we want to decide and components to have been only suggestions for example that
were forced to use all that there is a force to keep some
of the data side not used for training and compare different models all that the
validation and it is very wasteful is the from the easiest
that's very good evidence as a how to get around the fact
that the . estimates in the 1st place so immediate pop up
modularisation we have that problem a little you should more comparison and again I think that
the concept of the that have been some that are a bit late for
all of areas of the parameters of the model that has been
volatilize that they are just the variables just didn't
variables so nice thing about size is again from a
graphical . 20 years and it is therefore the Bayes perspective learning is just
infant problem soul against the are already talked about about the
inference exact inference was the 1st to that very shall
inference and amendment so basically letting adjust inference on this expanded
properties additional hidden variables which of the model
parameters so just very very simple and I in the U . so if we go back to being a simple example but attack
before which was the by the case then you remember we have the likelihood function bodies
data given the data which was the products from the point
is that so that was our likelihood function and see if we
introduce the prior at and we also 1st in the distribution
so in all the not probabilistic model we can write down the Joint probability of everything
that's the date the parameters and the few like the test . if you think about what is just the probability of the data that given to speech at quality of speech set up for the next if you think that
this is a an extract as well as know the quantity that were interested in um is the predicted
distribution which we will return on the previous you graph the effects activity to which is the next on the centre of the city of the things that so in order to make predictions we need the posterior
distribution and the posterior distribution if a given the
and there's just that you the user the you and the new
quantity which appears here that is the motto policy of the
data that sometimes called the model evidence will see why
a set of less and play a key role in the is just the integral part of speech that it was actually going to be hit with the said that the the the the the the the she said that in order to get model evidence we have 2 muscle as the things that the rules to make predictions we
have much more as a the integration is a fundamental
operation amazing inference and it and we can be all this
graphically follows withdrawal Raphael model so we have some observations X 1 up to texts capital and
in each of these the distribution for each observation is
conditioned on our parameters of speech that of this speech
that and we also have a a test points which is owned observed to make predictions apples was conditional so that's all graphical model very simple graphical model
describing the learning set up an set of introduce you to
shot of that's sort of website or if you have a sophisticated you can type
on it if you're willing to invest censuring the
and once you spend the article about bill
and of course you you type in the serial number of the dollar bill into
the computer into the website and your location
and then you spend it and if somebody finds the a dollar bill then that
this is this system he or she may go to the computer and type in
the location and the serial number in the series of the dollar bills trajectory will
be tracked from as it moves around united states
and this is actually a lot of people do in the
in the states that tens of thousands of people who actually stamping dollar bills and
many more kind of go regular look at their trajectory into spike and the serial
to the degree that
kind of about a year ago i met the gentleman who who is the champion
of that is the number one georgia's they call themselves that georgia's based on the
one the dollar bills name and that
gentlemen has actually stand more than two million dollars worth of dollar bills
and you don't have to actually do that is another each person
well it turns out that
he's a gun dealer
as you may know in the united states government dealing is not the credit card
based business
so every time somebody purchased gun it's obviously cash and stem dollar bills before he
sent it the bank or before he kind of these body back to anybody else
and this
is that thanks to the kind of individual activity of what this is all these
people who are willing to dispose george outcome
we end up having
trajectories and that when jesus from germany realize that this that set is really kind
of giving us indication how people move around because the data
small only if we moved and so therefore if you look at the chance distribution
of the consequent is fighting the dollar bills
that is somehow related to how people move
so the
statistics what is the distance between consecutive jumps and
and you know it's very well approximated by the public
essentially telling us that that this is really the flight so
the question is
is it really what does it mean
and to understand that let's look at the trajectory so what you see here is
a map of stuff and you will see kind of you know that moving around
and you know after i would actually confessed that is myself and how do we
know exactly where i was in real time well for couple of months away
that was the chip space launch and would record pretty much everything the second my
location and one thing you can see that it looks a bit like move around
but is not as random as you think it's clearly not random walk all of
us were kind of trend towards from the what would say that it's not and
if anything further you look at my trajectory more boring and repetative it becomes
so the question is really how to describe mathematically trajectory that looks much more like
that of the around the world and that this particular project it's only
and i don't know hockey stick i i the population i mean maybe the most
boring got to go to work and go home and nothing else so i may
not be typical in that respect of what everybody else does
or maybe because there's no way of knowing
so to understand how people move around we had to go beyond one person look
at more individuals
and the question is how do we do that
and and
what we actually doing is to look at how mobile phone users move around and
why we can do that well if you a mobile phone then every time you
make a phone call you of you know has to communicate with the closest power
and what you see here is kind of a region in the country and each
green dot corresponds to a cell phone tower
and the region around is really the only lattice which is approximately the reception area
of that particular tower so if you have it in that area most your forms
being connected to that particular tower
and what you see is the trajectory of an individual
and what you see is that this person about ninety six times have made calls
from this towers neighborhood about sixty seven times in course from here
and then a few times is around here and given the high density of power
in this region it indicates that this is probably is a city and its facilities
outside the city and and that's why it works here and makes up most of
his or her cause death
when you try to collect data from such a mobile phone usage issues you have
to be kind of boring around about what and of course one of them is
the privacy and this is all anonymized data so we actually just know hash code
to convert that user is
problems as well so you know we know only the tower the the user communicates
if we don't know exactly the position of the user in that particular power search
region so that the area can be ten square kilometres sometimes can be have square
kilometre so there is some uncertainty over the user actually is
so and so we know the location of the user when the user makes a
call so it technically possible to track the user but it doesn't have collected by
mobile phone companies and they will never do it for us you know because we
have to use on that they already collected the standard way
well we know essentially is that when a person makes a phone call what is
the tower he or she communicates
now this is a serious problem and the reason why this is the problem is
because the time between consecutive chords can be one second but can be ten days
and the entire time is the time between classes really very widely distributed number and
if people would call and fashion then of course that would be something like that
it will be some process especially if you have the same property to make it
clear then this is how you call that would look like it would be boring
in uniform turn
type of human activity we look at and he is actually the stuff of course
but you can look at email how people go to the library print and so
on what we find is that instead of these plants process you see these short
periods of very intensive activity like what we call first that this is like a
burst over here the subversive activities here as so one and in between them very
very long waiting times
so when you look at the human activity and this is not only form corsets
this variance in the
the direction
of largest variance
and you see in this direction which is the first principal component
the variance is large large and the estimated covariance matrix
so the
that is what was meant before the direction of the large
large i values
there are estimated to large
and the other way around in the direction of
i think was law in areas estimated to lower
so that our estimation two
the true one is more scary
and this can
easily be checked by simulation for a generated two hundred dimensional data
this is a plot of the
i'd like
one the dimensions if you do a principal component analysis
the black swan is true
and this is the color line estimated eigenspectrum
different number of sensors
if only fifty
for kind of life
feel that
the other
there is much too low
in particular the first one hundred fifty of zero
estimated for the i i various estimated two
so if we if we know
is systematic in the bias can can do something about it
this is this is called shrinkage
so we've
if we have a NPOV article that matrix estimated from the data that we have
to make it more spherical
so we have seen that it's too elongated so we we have to make it
more spherical and and therefore we use a linear
combination of the estimated covariance matrix
spherical covariance matrix which is identity
with the correct size is multiplied by the
every trying very
so now we have
nature and
an updated estimates
depending on the parameter gamma which is the linear
communication between
these two
matrices and
it's interesting observation here is of the form
to see this one takes
they decomposition of the empirical covariance matrix
like this you have
i vectors
in the matrix the underlying various the diagonal d
and you can
easily checked that the
i value decomposition of
these constraint matrix
looks like this year so we have the same
i can vectors
and just modified diagonal matrix middle
and is diagonal matrix is a linear combination of the original
diagonal matrix and
this modifies the average
so the original covariance is the empirical covariance matrix and to shrink the time i
vector so it does not turned
some of it stays in the same direction
and so extreme i values trying to extend to the average
what you can see
so they need to be counterbalanced the systematic bias
and if we look at the extreme if we set gamma to zero
then we have
originally the covariance matrix for the original a
and if we set gamma to one
in the first cancel out
so we assume that comments made very
so now we have the problem that as free parameter gamma
and that many different ways to to estimating one
easy way to use cross validation
so we do just try out different values and here in the simulation
two hundred fifty dimension data you see if you have a few training data one
fifty training data then you need
i have a program
to get
the lowest error rate and this increasing number of services in
hello i gamma or even got my pretty
if you have enough training data no shrinkage
so did
got my two
he two years ago again the formulas for in shrinkage
if you
complete shrinkage coming this one
the covariance matrix for users just skate identity for this kind of
that means that the classification
the classifier vector is just the difference of the two means
so that
the spatial filters
the difference of of the year
and on the other hand if we don't use shrinkage come i presume
he was
estimate the covariance matrix
so it
here we get the full gamut was one of the very small spatially interior
LA weekly one but this
so a continuous transition from the two extremes and to my
he followed this shrinkage lowers again tomorrow we are counting for the spatial structure of
of the noise
and to two thousand two
one more detail
a simple model assumption for event related potential is the following
what we're seeing
xk measure
linear combination of
of true
p the constant for five and noise
in these scatterplots two dimensions is the mean
of one class
this is the face of the activities of this is just the p
and the covariance matrix
that's all the rest of the nonfaces activity which is
considered noise
and to to get an idea what this noise comes from
you can make principal component analysis of this
covariance matrix
and the first two
principal components of of
the noise is
if these
so the first like like the p three hundred men
so this
it's from your
to the fact that someone assumption is not correct the p is not
constant in each five this variation
it depends on many factors that are different in each
so this