to press one thing in order to get food somewhere else is completely crazy for
active learning
and still they managed to learning
OK it's just that continue for a long time
so how is this related to reinforcement learning
so the idea is that
if animals can learn something arbitrary like this can probably learn
any the arbitrary policy
to you know some degree might take them longer and longer to learn about policy
that's really really complex but so does so so is the case for our simulations
but this policy specifically learned in order to obtain rewards and avoid punishments
in some causal way because here if the rat doesn't press the lever you won't
get food at all
and so
this is kind of the second part of reinforcement learning so we have prediction learning
learning of values and now we have a policy learning learning of actions
so so far what we have is
the world presenting animals or humans everything i said now is true also for humans
with the huge reinforcement learning problem or many maybe it's better to look at it
has many small reinforcement learning problems
and we know that animals and humans can learn both prediction and control which are
the two important ingredients to solve these problems
now the question is
now that we know that the brain does reinforcement learning can reinforcement learning help us
understand how the brain
solve this problem however realizes these algorithms
and this brings us to the biggest success story of computational neuroscience in the last
twenty years
which is the relationship between dopamine
prediction errors
so you might have heard about the mean
how many people have heard about the mean
most of you
the dopamine is or modulator
that is to create
in the brain from two
kind of in the
so an area called the midbrain
called the ventral stream mental area and the substantia nigra etc etc and all over
the place for the whole race
mostly see these hours here because these are its main targets the straighter and the
prefrontal cortex
and actually the middle as well
are the main target
from energy projections the domain basically goes everywhere even in the visual cortex there is
some dopamine
and the reason that people are really really interested in dopamine
well you've all heard about dopamine probably because of its relationship to parkinson's disease
the disease is caused by
the death of the promenade decks neurons there is less and less dopamine in the
brain at some point people developed parkinson's disease from losing these neurons
and so
this is the original theories about what don't mean doesn't the brain were very related
to this people thought well of parkinson's disease what
gets damaged it what we see is that people start behaving more darkly as they
normally did they have a problem initiating action so maybe that is the role of
dopamine in the brain helping us initiated actions in control movement
but later turned on the dopamine is also related to a host of other things
to drug addiction so virtually all addictive drugs have some influence through dopamine if not
on dopamine so cocaine amphetamine speed directly affect dopamine some affect dopamine less directly alcohols
may be the only one that does it go
we dopamine benefit
i think that some of the influence of alcohol is also through to me
gambling addictions
related to dopamine
natural rewards in general learning with natural rewards turns out to be related to dopamine
this causes people to think that
i don't mean this may be involved in reward during learning which is very different
from motor control so now we already have three different functions for dopamine
non zero wj and the gradient is smaller than
when the bridges
and this is optimal medical missions and
for the square loss is always can be specialized because the gradient can be expressed
so throughout this tutorial xnj
will essentially the design matrix corresponding to variables which are indexed by j
OK so x
data for the viable for this is just the gradient of the loss
like we saw in the
previous life as well for the square loss
OK this is one of the optimality conditions
so now this will tell you if the are similar not
and now you have to see how do we get to those two those conditions
because those cannot be inverted with the gradient then with the square loss the cool
thing is that if you write down the optimal medical missions to again brought to
the system and get a solution
his is not the case
and usually iterative algorithms are needed
so here focused for instance most of the musicians just to give you review
of existing results is sitting
so we've mainly focus on the gradient descent where you when you go from WT
two w t plus one last years going on to get
following the opposite direction of the gradient with a small primate facility
so you have a lot of strategies to do
to choose city and the one which i like the order was is to do
a line search not an exact line search is because it is kind of useless
to spend some so much time optimizing the function but line searches
stopping all the major one and also you can consider fixed diminishing step size way
which we decay in
as one of the key plus some constant so that those with those two line
searches there is a strong body of literature trying to see how fast it to
how far they converge to the global minimum of the function so here i assume
that f is convex so if there is no
there are no local minima
and if you look at the on the nice book but still have
then you can really find common interest rates for all of for these methods so
what the take-home message is that
the nice function looks the first the commanders right is the same as the k
so if it is convex and just which is so this image is
the simplest assumption we can make on on the function then you converges to to
the their value at rate one of those code of t
which is rather slow
even though you assume that you are differentiable so what people call about the smooth
with early sheets averages gradients so what were not familiar to
lynch's gradients it is it essentially means that if you function was twice differentiable it
means that the second derivative is uniformly bounded
from from above
by l
so if you assume that your
a function is differentiable you know to go faster
and if you assume moreover that the function is strongly convex so essentially means that
if you function was twice differentiable
the second derivatives of bounded from below this time then you get an exponential rate
of convergence for it goes goes a lot faster than the inverse of t
he goes as
as this
the exponential function of t so this number of health
it is exactly what people call the condition number of of the of the optimisation
essentially if this is small
and for the record is zero
the gradient descent they converge very slowly because you get back to these and of
the world or in the cloud of the world but if you find new of
n is large
then you get exponential convergence
the system is very important
because it will tell you when a simple methods i expected to work on that
and this depends on the condition number
and again if your function is twice differentiable this is just the ratio
of the minimum the value of the history over the maximum value of the of
the history
the this and this is similar types of property
and just to mention that the gradient descent is by no means the best possible
methods best possible first order methods for optimization and you have also in the nice
thing this of you have a lot of all the schemes which we obtain a
lot but the amount of coal as a
sometimes instead of nifty of methods which we achieve rates which are quicker because he
manages to go quicker
and square would have
of the over and is larger than you
so just keep in mind that the reason is not the end of the story
and now for the disease was for smooth optimisation now for nonsmooth optimization then you
have no gradients so you have this for simple method is to follow the subgradient
so i do i didn't want to define the gradient in the sense that i
have to here
the subgradient is simply
do subgradient if it is
below the function is if is if it is locally below the function so it
the just under eighty years of greater than the questioning of functions so in a
sense this is the gradient with the defamatory differentiable and it is something which is
tangent to which defines the tangent when the function is not differentiable
you have to be very careful if you replace just gradient descent by civilian dissent
you might not converge even you if you do the exact line search
so this is somewhat counter-intuitive
and there is the
countries example pundits slide i won't go one go
but this is a very important symbol methods in the context of nonsmooth optimization might
not work exactly that and so she doesn't work but far diminishing step size doesn't
converge to the global minimum so it's kind of counter-intuitive
and that the expansion y but sometimes it works like this sometimes it doesn't
also coordinate descent which is also very simple methods mine is not always converge to
the global optimum so is given for these fuzzy is a simple counterexample
so is a function of two variables vote at the level sets value one two
three four five one two three four five so the function goes in that direction
so if you want to get that if you if you start from zero
if you look
i along with the other two axes along w one
you will
you are you think you should stop
if you don't look around w to you go see things should stop
any coordinate descent algorithm would stop at that point but they the direction
direction of descent which is this one
now there are other ways to incorporate a probabilistic model inside the loss function as
the maximum likelihood or maximum security you can use for example cross validation use bayesian
estimators for large sample approximations to the business that you're not really just focus on
this year
likelihood remarks
so you get your problem you choose representation in the hypothesis class which is just
way of specifying the family of distributions graphical model and then you learn the parameters
geographical model by maximizing the likelihood of like by the maximum that's going to be
or are
so this is very simple derivation here which she IID assumption is so
so for independent and identically distributed data the probability of the entire dataset d
given the parameters is just a product over each case of the probability that it
would means to be
if so then
the probability of the event
probability and now we take the law this product it was
so you
likelihood estimation is the setting of the parameters that are most likely to have generated
and this is very convenient because each case continues at time
so we have to turn each one turn by some is to think of these
it is and vote for what i think should be
and averaging of trying to take the best
so maximum likelihood is commonly used as a baseline on statistics you should always think
of maximum likelihood simple
you know that one as priors over parameters regularisation
it these to very intuitive were queueing estimators
first the idea something that makes a lot of on
so just to give you a flavor
maximum likelihood let's talk about the
so let's say that i have quarry
and it has some unknown by probably come
this is not the
probability of the best in the country tails just one might say OK
you're going to get value
and you call and i just love the show
so going to look at scale and you want to estimate what bias
what you should do is you should according to the principle of maximum likelihood write
down the likelihood function and trying to find the values that maximize that this is
a very simple calculation want to go through
because this
right down the likelihood function
he wrote down the law
you have to do that
the likelihood function and its derivative to find values that's the same process go a
very complicated models so i'm going start by driving the estimator
but this is just to show the sketch
so here's is
data model
here's the likelihood function is the probability of the data is the product of a
long and use exponential notation true here
this is this is like this is very important because
again steer this moment
here is just all i did here is that if the head represent the slivers
of zero one
so is the point comes out to be zero
then this term is there is zero one and this one i think in the
head before
and one in the german state and this term is
one so just always selecting whether they do or one minus the writing
just as the notation
but the thing is i think a lot of this i get a very simple
expressions for the log likelihood is the number of heads
say want this and the number of tails
times or once say
so we take the derivative with respect to the data
set this to
these are the maximum likelihood estimator is never over
now you can say well i'm going to all of this a lot product in
middle of this just to get this and i could have told that you know
that was
how many have to use it was actually used to but this is important and
it is also important because i'm going to illustrate to you
why this maximum likelihood learning can be very dangerous
let's say that would require twice and it comes up heads
what is the probability that the next little details
OK if you do maximum likelihood maximum likelihood ideal case the pointwise so that two
divided by the total number two
so the maximum likelihood estimator for the probability of is
so the probability of tails is
they were very obviously maximum likelihood can be very dangerous very limited amount of time
maximum likelihood that you are very good at because you know i basically if you
have a point
perfectly valid point
probability that one was the chance that you'll see two tales of what we're all
right so in twenty five percent data size two
you'll see you have to estimate the probability of tails be so
this is why the estimators are doing now if you saw a million reflects you
can be pretty sure this estimator is the correct so if you have a lot
of data
maximum likelihood is you don't have very much data you should be able to think
about this is the laws of probability events
how much money you be willing to bet on that event occurred
you want to lose k so if you use this probability estimator and you have
to flip and you say the probability of tails is equal to zero vote lord
of zero
k is negative infinity
so that says that you would be willing to take a lots of negativeinfinity dollars
you cite fails
OK so this is a
and we don't really believe
i just another example to to give you flavor things so if you have a
guassian model to univariate normal
actually the cell is able
two lower
the the free energy state between these two and that makes it possible for the
equilibrium to be much more favoured
let's look at this this glycolysis pathway likely refers obviously glycolysis and here we start
out with glucose we're trying out flat ground the the circular structure we talked about
last time and let's look at what happens here again not because anybody wants you
to memorize this but because some of the details are in themselves very illustrative
the goal of this exercise is to create ATP for the cell
but the first step in the reaction is actually totally counterproductive
look at the first thing that happens
the first thing that happens is that the cell invest in ATP molecule to make
glucose six phosphate
i've advertised the the goal of this has been to generate ATP from ADP
then he died possibly but the first thing we go here we don't
this is an organic reaction in which the cell invest energy to create this molecule
so this doesn't make sense
what is ostensibly must make sense in one level mother because
you and i were all here and everybody in this room at least this moment
is metabolic lee active all right so we've got this molecule of glucose six phosphate
and this can i summarise
you see here is glucose six phosphate fructose six phosphate
and the fact of the matter is there is no oxidation reduction reactions here is
just an isomerisation and this molecule in this molecule are virtually in the same free
energy state
it happens to be the case that their profile looks very much like the one
i drew you before
their energy profile look like this
and one is an enzyme to lower it
but there is no energy that needs to be invested in
converting one to the other because they are very similar molecules and therefore incomparable free
energy states
now look at the next step in the next step is again an ostensibly totally
totally counter-productive way
of generating energy because once again ATP
the the gamma phosphate is in its energy is invested in creating a di phosphorylated
for fructose one six di phosphate where the numbers refer obviously the the the identities
of the carbon and now we have dive phosphorylated
fructose molecules
and so here you can actually see what the three-dimensional
what we what we imagine closer to what the three-dimensional structures of these molecules look
and we don't have to
we should focus this time with this this or this
for all practical purposes let's just focus on this pathway here
and here for the first time what we now what now happens is that this
hexose is broken down into two trials
i into two three carbon sugars
and this is the slightly actually gonna reaction yields it happens without the investment of
energy and there's an enzyme once again is required in order to catalyze
but let's be really clear now
now we have to follow the fate of two molecules
prior the first trials
and the second trials they have different names but we're not going to focus on
the names
one thing i notice about these trials is is that the rate readily inter convertible
once again we can imagine we have a situation that looks like this these are
flipping back and forth
and therefore for all practical purposes from our point of view these two are equivalent
because they can be exchanged virtually instantaneously one with the other
now so far we've actually expended energy we haven't we haven't harvested energy
but keep in mind the old economic the the
you have to invest money
to make money and that's what's going on here
the first thing happens is we have an oxidation reaction
what's an oxidation reaction we want to strip some electrons pair of electrons off of
this particular trials the three carbon sugar and by stripping off the pair of electrons
we donate
the electrons from NADH plaster NADH and here these structures are given in your book
but NADH it turns out is
the electrons are pulled away from the trials appear are used to reduce NAD to
keep in mind the oxidation reactions one molecule it's being oxidized
is deprived he's denied the pair of electrons the other molecules being reduced in this
case a
acquires a pair of electrons
and you can focus if you want about the the charge of these molecules one
of the other
but keep in mind that in these oxidation reduction reactions whether it's plus charge minus
charges here is irrelevant
the real name of the game is
the electrons
forget about the protons where there is a plus charter to the real name of
the game here is two electrons are being used to reduce this molecule to this
by the way
third mistake i forgot to tell you before
there's a double bond and one of the pavilions in the book that doesn't make
any sense
whoever finds it gets surprised but no one's feel with surprises you OK
so here i love this double bond gets reduced you see the difference between this
and this over here
and this NADH it turns out is a high energy molecules
the street value of any NADH is three ATP
i e in the mitochondria
NADH can be used to generate three ATP
and that's worth something
so NADH on its own is a high energy molecules
it can be used for that many things
but it can be pulled into the mitochondria works converted to three ATP's
so we say we're starting to make some money out of this investment because we've
made in fact
two we've made these
ATP we made his NADH is see right here
why do we say two NADH is
because each of these two trials as we're working with
and each one of the trials this gives you an NADH
so everything that's going on
after this starting from the top here
is now double because we're we're looking at the parallel behaviors of two identical three
carbon sugars so here we have so far generated in principle
six ATP
how much did we invest already up to this point
we have to what we harvested six
already was done to make a little money because i told the street value of
NADH is three a piece
on the black market OK so
what happens next
next is another good thing
each of the trials is
one can actually cause each of trials is to generate an eight eighty people to
form ATP what happens here it turns out that this phosphate over here is actually
pretty high energy state
in no small part because of electron a negative negative repulsion
and by stripping this phosphate of this high-energy phosphate
stripped off of this molecule whose name we will ignore allows us to force for
and ATP synthase two re two trials has been converted we're going to get two
so in effect now we're actually ahead
we start out investing two
we've got six back from the mediators and we're going to more back
so we've made two ATP is this is a good thing
keep in mind ATP lower energy ATP so high high energy
once again we have a an isomerisation were these two molecules are comparable states
has zero resistance
that's of course
a pretty stupid thing to do to short out the battery
but more dangerous
forty watts
i think that's the warm big deal so let's do it
so i have here
the voltage that you can see
that we measure
nine fold
duracell battery i have the better here
and you can read here
i hope the decimal point is in there but it's about nine point six vols
and now i'm going to do something stupid but again
it's not dangerous
i'm going to take my car keys and i'm going to show it out
the battery
simply connected point a with point b
and so the
voltage going to see is going maybe not go to zero exactly because mikey made
of zero resistance but it goes very low
and what you can all experience is something that i can do this but we
will get hot
this forty what
will be generated inside here it is possible that when the
betty gets hot that the internal resistance may even go up a little
remember that resistance goes up when temperature goes up in which case the power will
go down to mainly the full forty watts
but i can assure you that i can feel this thing anymore
so let me shorted out now
i'm doing this now
you read the voltage
i can see two here
is always not so easy was akin to do that
it's very low a look at some other tens of volts
and i feel this thing getting hot
really one up now
so i'm going to better
this is a terrible thing to do better is like that
but when i take
after the active resistance some of that may come back
may not be permanently damaged you see it's really a than half falls
so is no way
that you can start a car
was in nine fold
duracell battery
because you just can't get the current you need for you start
you start to motor needs a few hundred mps
if you take a car battery
that's about travel
it has a very low internal resistance
of about one fifteen
over now
so that means that the maximum current you can draw if you would circuit
it would be something like six hundred mps
and so the maximum power if you were so stupid to short-circuited
we would all be generated inside the battery
it would be something like seven kilowatts
if you ever work on your car
make sure
but you never dropped accidentally the range that you're using onto the better
because if you did
inside the battery
about six kilowatts
seven thousand joules per second are going to be
produced in terms of heat
and this all theory
as it is going to boil
the case may melt
and that's no good
not only is that
but it's also
very dangerous
so let's do it
i have here is better it
and i have here
the rams
just in case
i'm going to show that that battery
and as i do that
you will clearly see that the better doesn't like it
i would be very careful not to
hold on this range school because it would welcome to with actually can well wouldn't
stay there currently so why i
go up to six hundred and because it can well known to with and then
you can get off more
in case that happens
i walk out of here
and i advise you to do the same
you ready
OK i go now
that's what happens very high current
you do this
two often two batteries
they're not going to live very long they don't like
but i wasn't joking when i said when you work on the cart it you
so yes is the title says i'm going to talk about approximate bayesian computation
ABC is often known or likelihood free inference
now obviously in the past few days i realise that most people who are doing
approximate bayesian computation some sense so what i mean is a class of monte carlo
that i used to do inference in stochastic models
in particular they don't use when the function in the model is not available
the likelihood free inference
so i'll do i'll highlights the basic idea behind the ABC method
i don't give a couple of extensions
and illustrate them
with reference to a particular kind of problem i would on from evolutionary biology
and that while the general idea is a very generic as an extension of the
best illustrated
specific reference to problems
i should just mention this work with tavare a lot my phd in cambridge
OK so
this is two main types of statistical model that we we tend to build
the first type your prescribed models so you get your data and you decide sit
in a new division process or a normal distribution to add to or whatever
a very complicated i hierarchical cost and and so on but ultimately can write down
the likelihood function and you can calculate the likelihood function or some
like version likelihood function of the normalizing constant
so that the model that we use an implicit models
so these mechanisms to simulate observations on the model can tell you that some parameters
the future works the way it produces some sample output
the is impossible to models often give scientists much more freedom to more accurately model
the phenomena that interested in the
and until recently with the interesting thing about it was really very many ways to
do inference in in these models
so the approximate bayesian computation i went away to inference in implicit models
this is by implicit model this is a branching process
a line here in my problem represent different species of primates but it could equally
be different cell and cancer tumour
or a different human in the population
and the red dots are some kind of discrete sampling
so my problem again the primate species so the red dots represent the fossil finds
that fossils here and so on
or they could be mutations inhibited it a
so what interested in doing
it is between most today because of a where talking to machine machine learning background
that we define terminology in statistics were talking about the same thing called the time
but we don't understand each so sometimes with walking across the site
but they calibration data assimilation computing the inverse problem the manifold to build a forwards
we specify parameter values initial conditions in the output is the reverse you we want
to do
so here the representation of the primates so we've got some kind of phylogeny here
and the fossil represents the data we have available
eighteen here is too
if the depth of the trees away this route is
so it's been very flat my terminology is that the time the first primate appeared
the time the first of all you like
the divergence time
this is just notation of amazing because the the parameters that are
and it's going to be because we want to draw samples from the posterior distribution
the distribution of theta given d
and let me just say yes
for many of the tree based models appear in genetics
and grow up and will be expected the external environment and they would not be
easy stressed if she doesn't like them along
that would be covered by a neurotic now the point is that you wrote that
novel long people or who have neurotic offspring they also bring she would also not
liquor offspring this is part of the syndrome and they get that blood Lakers will
have bravely rats were confident that have that been the that date the doctors will
also make their so good you have to live images of rats which are different
in that behavioral and in there the way that their respond to stress
and that the some genetically they live in the same environment and yet there are
different and different because something happened in the history at some point a replica according
a new world order tourism
now what is interesting about this now this kind of thing has been known for
a long time but the reason that it became very interesting for people who is
that now we understand a little bit about the molecular basis of this behavior we
understand what is going on in terms of the genes that are acting in the
brain and what is happening is that
In did not linked threats this June the geology of the geology and the glucocorticoid
receptor gene is methylated wears in well electrodes it is being reflected it happens in
people follows in the bright
and it's a very persistent stage 1 it happens and the critical period sensitive period
for the is between 1 and 6 days
this is where it has to be or more click
so when we know a little bit about it and we understand that the genetic
mechanism that can be responsible for selling Americans can also be responsible for some memory
here there's no Southern heritage because here we are what we have is a reconstruction
development and reconstruction of behavior and we have all kinds of things by
which are similar we know that food preferences in rats
In my in hostess
what what the mom can influence the food preferences of her offspring and we know
a little bit also attributable about those working humans but is also suggested that what
the mother its can affect the full preferences or for office and we don't know
he the molecular mechanisms by better it will be 1 of those at the genetic
exotic can't be anything other unless we find another mechanism which is very likely and
here we have a different kind of transmission of information and this is the transmission
of some dialects in the songbirds and we know that the are members of the
belong to the same species to the saying in a kid can have different populations
and different populations can have different dialects and is Ireland's all characteristic of this population
samples to some extent not with very high fidelity transmitted from 1 generation to the
next so that's another route of transmission
here we have a picture in almost all of the various tables and very intelligent
good anymore in ways potato and Japanese and that the story is very nice it's
a story about Japanese researchers to start to look at their original started looking at
the Japanese Mikako and they in order to observe the potatoes near the whose River
was running to the seat of the wanted them to stay with the title and
1 of those said I'm a Cox a few according won't start the war should
the potatoes in the water and this behavior spread and became the norm in the
population afterward today the were all kinds of variations on the theme that developed in
this population for example they start the proportion in the seat because it's nice when
the goal
most simple
some symbols required
general has
what the
what else can be said
when you
so this is the right
all this
the people
i believe in
some all
serious misunderstanding
on the
must be involved in
small steps
one year
he takes place in the
and dance
however the
these assumptions
the answer
what was
the court
the she
emerging from certainly
one work
well of course is constant star
that's the problem
if man
historical changes not be
this should be
the reason say
from the
literature and languages
speculation about
historical change
in the technical sense of the word solution
languages don't know all
so there is no such fuels evolution by the
they change
language users of
the organisms
would like
not less
fifty thousand years scenes and
not since e
the emergence of
they model
not only before it
back and
and don't seem to be terrorists
very shortly before
well terms
language acquisition
even the first moment
r very
surrounded by the
called with james cawley
mean buzzing confusion
the infamous
extract from this confusion
there are specific for language
easy to
you try
you do that
when steering
this very recent evidence that he
what system age
this is very similar to humans
and even response to be used
so was features
it's just an undifferentiated part generated
that's true
other organisms
specific parts in
here we
nearly undetectable by humans
so there's gotta be some
additional mechanisms
that is used by
human sense that
the organism
today the very first
the something that the line
place has shown
this achievement is in part to me
that means we
can distinguish e
like his mother
i j
was spoken
it was
and it turns out
discoveries shown that
languages fall into the wrong
possible categories
when you put in
distinguish can
it was
is presiding
features rhythm
which is just a double sum over these two examples that we want to
compare with
the interesting thing is that
of course since this is
working with kernels
so this age is defined from the kernel
we can also do this fall
we can do this for all kinds of data where we can define kernels also
structured data graphs trees strings and so on
and there's a second application
which is essentially also to sample
application and that's
independence testing dependence measures
and i will actually start
and this one
one way to do it
independence testing
between two variables x and why
at is formally to say
well the question of independence is just a question whether the
joint distribution
is identical to the product of the marginal distributions
and so
if we could embed the joint distribution into a reproducing kernel hilbert space and do
the same for the product of the marginals
and then compute the difference vector the length of the difference after we have a
beautiful test statistics four four independence
in there
because we need to do this now
based on empirical data times the simplest methods not the best but it was the
first one that we work on but
the simplest methods that to obtain
empirical estimates that these two things
is feasible if we
have a sample of observations x and why
that's a sample from the joint distribution so
this is the thing that we embed over here
now given the sample
o pairs x and why
and how do we create a sample from
this factorized
distribution product the marginals
one way to do that is simply to permute all the axis
so if we permute the axis then
the relationship between so
we have to write this
so i have a set of observations that looks like this
and then sample from some distribution joint distribution over x and why
and know if i take a fixed permutation sigma
i permute
sorry one
i do this limitation
and then of course
the pairs are no longer samples from the joint distribution i have broken the dependence between the two things
but of course exercise still samples from the marginal distribution of x and the sigma of
why story
sigma of why
asked still samples from the model distribution of why so that
these are
nice samples from
there must be some the product of the marginal distributions
so that's an idea how to to independence testing and it works quite well and you can
it's a real independence testing is not just first-order is not just looking for a
zero covariance or something like that
and actually what it is will depend on the kernel that you choose so for instance if you're
take a polynomial kernel of a certain degree and to compute this kind of a test statistic here
this thing the empirical estimate is that of course he will test for independence after
a certain order but if you take a course in can with
principal before full independence
so this one i think i'm going to skip
and i want to talk about the representer theorem that maybe
now is the time to
briefly ask if you have any questions
there was one here and then here
why i
and say it
how many computations
how many permutations
well in principle you could take one computation
maybe you can do a better job i've been doing more
but in principle
already wanted to sample
you can do some
i mean
you could also some modifications but in principle you can do one
there was a second question
so can you
can you compress the data set by by doing the kernel mean embeddings as question
interesting questions so
the rationale
we're not losing information
uh by doing this mapping
and it looks like
the whole dataset represented by this one object
was which in principle it's
in three-dimensional space
so one in a sense one could say
we represent the data set by this function and if we are able to
in code this function more compactly than the data set then
we might have some
some means of compressing
the dataset
i is that a question marks one is a question mark can we compress the function
more easily than the data set
maybe that's the case
and if we can do that and
how do we know about the mappings so now we know in principle it's invisible
and we don't have an explicit form for the inversion
actually that
inverting this kind of mapping is
the general question in
support vector machines and other kernel methods
is related to what people call the preimage problem solving
support vector machines we
we typically
keep talking about this means haven't properly explain them yet
we typically end up with the
in the case of classification
we end up with a solution that looks like this
with a constant here
in the
can be the case that so the some
well i would say more about this later
it goes over all training points but
usually a large fraction of their advisors zero but nevertheless you could say that if
you have millions of training points you could still have
i don't know hundreds of thousands of
expansion points where this doesn't vanish so you you might have a very
very rich between the hilbert space now let's rewrite this a little bit
and this is actually the same as
so we have some
without some
we have some weight vector
and the dot product
we phi of x
plus being
now if we were able to
i said we're going to eliminate c one c two
he thinks one obviously two likes to be eliminated
let's call it back
look at this equation
substitutes in here
well because credit substituted omega minus
but you get an answer for c one c
what think that the answer is
what do you think the answer is
not even one plus y
so you get one of two
is possible
if you
this omega zero
you put it
you get on with zero square a minus sign
a plus sign you only get squared divided by only gets credit plus one
and now you take the second solution
and you put it
what i think you're going to find
my wife
he one
over c two
it's not mine
so what you have seen now
is that the general
comes up
frequencies comes up with the ratios of the amplitude
not with the individual amplitudes because you don't know the initial condition
comes up with the ratio of the
amplitudes and now you can write
provided that you know
the initial conditions
note initial conditions
you can also find
c one
and therefore node ratio
automatically c two
and you can find this one
i'll give a minus sign
it's a plus sign
and then you know to ratio in that model
so now you may think erroneously
and life is easy
that's far from the truth
so all you have something as simple as this
called double pendulum
there is no symmetry
one the test your intuition
one of the two modes
two normal modes low and high one because the two object
in the lowest frequency use your hands and your legs
what will this pendulum look like
all doing sort of the right thing
would look like this
what would it look like this
in other words let me make this one a little bit
let me make the difference in the larger
would look like this
what would it look like this
slightly exaggerated
it was for this one
OK that means that the ratio
c to oversee one
it's going to be a plus two
was for this one
believe it or not
c two
over c one
is going to be
the square root of two
welcome to the grindhouse
to find and i'm not exaggerating when i say thirty minutes
you have to go through the whole procedure
and then you'll find
this ratio
two point four
and i will demonstrate
the highest the
must be something like this
right because
they must be out of place
and the idea of the ratio
c one over c two
called c one
all this into any one of you any intuition
one is
well you
minus two point four
this one
be much further away than this one
any one of you want to make a guess with omega minus is anyone to
make because we only have pluses
no way on earth that you
five anyone else can look at this and say oh yes of course on minuses
one hundred
thirty minutes of calculated
and then out of that pop these
frequencies and out of that then pop the
the ratios
and now i'm going to demonstrate to you
just this case
the way and going to do that
even though we have not discussed driven coupled oscillators
in order to set it off in these normal modes normal mode
is also a resonance frequency
recall it often natural frequency
is what the system likes to do if you leave it alone
it is easy for me when i just to use a little bit excited in
the rest of the world
so therefore i am going to drive the only very briefly
and the complete
relationship is that led the prime the one that you will receive
and one minus better
cosine fade
divided by
the square root
one minus beta screen
and they
this is the
over c
c being the speed of light
so you see that if fatah
it's smaller than ninety degrees
but larger than zero
that means you are approaching each other
this stands for approaching
that means that led the prime
is then
smaller than that
so you
caught a smaller wavelengths when coming to you
and we
have a name for that
and the name for that
is blue shift
and the reason why that is called blue shift is obvious
blue shift
because blue light has a shorter wavelength than red light
so even though this
this doppler effect may not even be indivisible part of the spectrum we still call
that blue shift
so when you approach
the relative velocities approaching
you go towards shorter wavelengths we call the blue shift
now if a down
is between hundred eighty degrees
ninety degrees
so that means you are receding from each other
well and the prime is larger than life
and of course you've guessed it
that for redshift
and astronomers talk all the time about redshift and blue shift
if beta square is much much smaller than one
you can forget about the downstairs if you like that
if you take desecrated
if you take
ten percent of the speed of light which is substantial right reaches thirty thousand kilometres
per second
so the data is o point one
then they desecrated
is approximately o point o one
and so downstairs
one minus one hundred you could
reasonable approximation
it nor that
but that depends of course on the accuracy that you want
in that case you would get lambda prime
is approximately lambda
times one minus cosine
one minus
and cosine theta
and now you want to know it in terms of frequency
then f prime
is roughly f
times one plus
cosine theta
and i'll leave you with proving that this is indeed the
good approximation
doppler shift being used in sports
to measure the speed of tennis balls and
baseball's when they're being pitched
radar is sent to the object and it reflects of the object and so you
can measure this way
the speed
weather radar works the same way you can measure the speed with which
weather approaches you or goes away from you
the police can check your speed of your car
century or to you'd bounces of your car
and then it can send it sense you speed and in my problem seven in
my problems at seven i think i have a problem based on that if you're
approaching the police
so if data is zero then of course you would simply get one minus baby
one was played data can be zero of course
doesn't have to be but it can be
you can imagine how
important to role
was that displayed in astronomy
because this allows you know
to calculate the velocity of stars relative to
our solar system relative to us
because almost all stars in their respective show absorption lines
and if you know the absorption line frequency already absorption line wavelength as measured in
the following content is provided under creative commons license your support will help MIT opencourseware
continue to offer high quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
this visit MIT opencourseware OCW MIT that EDU
settle down there
this is not
some other class three online
so i have an important announcement there will be a class will be lecture next
wednesday instead of be another celebration of learning
you're going to comment going to show us
what you've learned it's going to be so
i want to make sure that we're all celebrating the same thing
i meant the patch didn't get patched i apologize so let me tell you what
it is
what we're going to look at is
lectures starting with
lecture seventeen
which was
on x-rays and halfway through that lecture was the breakpoint for the last test so
we will start with the material
beginning with bragg's law we didn't talk about diffraction
the last test the coverage
talk about generation of x-rays but not their using diffraction so starting with x-ray diffraction
up through the end of last days lecture
and the reason i'm doing this is that tomorrow is a holiday there are no
academic exercises tomorrow
and so i didn't think it made
good pedagogical sense to teachers something today
you have no recitation on thursday
you don't need again with your recitation structure until tuesday and wednesday is the test
being mindful that i'm going to start talking about solutions today none of that will
be on the test so starting with
x-ray diffraction and ending with diffusion so you
as i got up here
the suffix law's first and second laws are function all that stuff
and of course we have test a weekly quiz on tuesday
will have plenty to
to work on four wednesday so
let's leave it that way
so last day we completed the discussion of diffusion
going through analytical
presentation of fixed laws and how they are used in
quantitative measure of
of range phenomena in diffusion
today what i want to do is that
introduce another topic from the general realm of physical chemistry
and this is the topic of solutions
and for that we all the way back to the
the very first lecture three online one we looked at this
figure from the text
and what we've been doing up until now was largely working over in the lower
left corner
this taxonomy we've been looking at
the properties of elements we've looked at a few compounds but we really haven't gotten
up into here everything has been pure pretty much
but we have had to
make the odd for a we talked about glasses we got into the discussion of
solutions because we were talking about how you could modify the properties detail the properties
by changing composition of the glass so that was really in this domain of of
mixtures and we talked about doping of semiconductors and we don't the semiconductor actually put
phosphorus or boron substitution for silicon solar masses were making a solution
so that's all of them here but i am a little bit
uncomfortable with this broad definition and make sure so i've taken the liberty of refining
that someone
so what i'd prefer you recognise is that there's two types of mixtures
as homogeneous mixtures and heterogeneous mixtures
homogeneous mixtures are what we would call solutions and that gives you mixing right down
at the molecular level
whereas heterogeneous
mixtures are not mixed down to the molecular level there mixed down to the level
of clusters
so for example
if i look at something like brian
brian is
salt dissolved in water it's visually
we cannot tell that there is more than one component and its this homogeneity uniformity
that makes the solution
whereas if you look at something like milk milk is a mixture it's an aggregate
milk actually consists of two phases there's the fatty phase
which is insoluble in the aqueous phase
and what's happened is we've got to a find dispersion
the second phase in the first phase
and i find dispersion flow to the fact that is a clear and colorless
and the aqueous phase is clear and colorless but that dispersion scatters light that's where
we get the the white
in milk
and i don't like the notion that
whether it's milking or
clear and colorless in other words
coarsely next or finally makes we simply under so i'm going to be talking today
about about solutions
making sure that we understand the the underlying
so you might say well
we signed up for solid state chemistry wisely talking about solutions to give you three
three reasons first of all
we have
the systems that we're looking at are
it's very rare to use
pure substances
in engineering applications so we we need to understand solutions from that standpoint is we've
learned how to tailor the properties of glasses head to tail properties of semiconductors until
the properties of metal alloys and so on secondly main materials are processed out of
the way we make fine powders
it's not too
make little bolton castle liquid into tiny tiny little malls we make fine powders typically
by precipitation out of solution so we need to understand the laws that govern
disillusioned and x solution precipitation and thirdly what one of the major units that we're
going to cover before the end of the semester involves biochemistry
and the environment for
most of
while chemicals is the wet environment so i think its requisite that we know something
about that when far so that's
that's sort of the background preamble
that's what i want to do today is to introduce some definitions so wilburys through
some material on the handouts and ultimately get to the emissivity rules that's we really
want we want to know the admissibility rules the rules that govern when
two substances are three or more substances are going to max and for solutions so
that's what we're heading to miss ability rules
so that's summarize on this slide so first F star again was dif defined like this
we know it's a convex function from the calculus of subgradients we know how to
calculate a subgradient of the conjugate and the rule that we saw in the
when we talked about subgradient calculus is as follows so to evaluate F star
and a conjugate at a certain Y you have to find the X that
maximizes this either numerically or analytically so the value of this maximum gives you the conjugate
function value the X that maximizes it is a subgradient of this function differentiated
respect to Y so that's very easy normally if you can evaluate the conjugate
you also know which vector X maximizes this in the supremum and any maximizer will
be a subgradient if the maximizer is unique then there is a unique subgradient and that
means the function is actually differentiable at Y so when is that the case well for example
if F of X is strictly convex and this supremum is finite then
there can be only one maximizer right because F is strictly convex and in that case F
star would be differentiable and this maximizing X is not just a subgradient but also
the gradient so differentiability of the conjugate has to do with strict convexity of
the function F and then a stronger condition that's useful for these proximal gradient and
fast proximal gradient methods in the convergence analysis of the proximal gradient method to
be used we had this condition on G the differentiable part at the gradient
is Lipschitz continuous with constant L so what does that mean for the if G is the
conjugate of some convex function F well that means that the function F is
strongly convex and a strongly convex function is defined like this F is strongly convex
with parameter mu if you can subtract this quadratic function with coefficient mu from it
and the remainder is still a convex function if that's the case you call F strongly convex
with parameter mu and a nice property is that if F is strongly convex then its
conjugate is defined everywhere and the gradient of the conjugate is Lipschitz continuous with parameter one over mu
so the L in the definition of the Lipschitz continu continuity is one over mu so
we'll see why this matters but now let's look at some possible applications of dual
methods suppose so we have a simple problem with only equality constraints and we use the
we want to solve this by a dual method then we've seen the dual is
the dual function is the negative of this B transpose nu plus the conjugate
of F applied to minus A transpose nu so one method we can always apply
is the subgradient method because this is always this is a convex problem
so we know how to compute a subgradient so to compute a subgradient we compute
the we minimize or we solve the maximization problem in the definition of F star which
is this maximization over X so if you write that as the minimization problem that
means you minimize F of X plus nu transpose A X that's the maximizing the solution
of that is the maximizer in this definition of their conjugate and we know that
it's also an gradient a subgradient of the conjugate from this previous slide
so this X plus will be an the subgradient of F star and then
the subgradient of F star times will be the subgradient of F star
respect to nu and then if you multiply with A you get
the subgradient so the subgradient of minus G this convex function will be
B equal to B that's that's the gradient of this first term and the
subgradient of the second term is A times the vector X that minimizes this and this
second step is just a subgradient update for the dual variable nu it's nu
minus T times a subgradient and the subgradient was B minus A X right so this dual update is just a
subgradient update in an subgradient method the first step is how you compute
the subgradient of F star or if this has a unique maximizer or this
has a unique minimizer X then this is actually a gradient because then the subgradient is unique and
this is a gradient update is that clear so an
example of a strictly convex function that's not strongly convex would be one over X
for example over the positive X so for differentiable twice differentiable functions strong convexity
means that the smallest eigenvalue of the Hessian is greater than mu everywhere
so it's bounded away from zero by a positive mu right so one over X is strictly
convex but it's not strongly convex because its second derivative is
goes to zero so when is this interesting this dual gradient method for solving this
problem well it's interesting because the dual update is very simple and it's interesting
when this minimization is easier than the original minimization because this is unconstrained you
just added a linear term to X and minimize this and so if this is easier
than the first problem then this could be an interesting method and one reason why
this might be easier is for example if this becomes separable because F of
X is separable as a sum of separable functions each depending on only one component of
X then this entire thing is separable and you can get a decoupled problem for
this minimization so that's used in dual decomposition so this is the same idea but in
more detail just here I used inequality constraints but the idea is exactly the same so
here we have a separable objective
one term that depends on X one second term depends on the vec
variables X two but the constraints couple everything so you cannot if you didn't have constraints you
i've got enough vectors are not too many
it's a natural idea
of the basis
so basis is a bunch of vectors in this space
and it's so it's as sequence of vectors with two properties with
they are independent
and two
you know what's coming
they span the space
let me take
so time for examples of course
so i'm asking an output
definition one
the definition of independence
together with definition two
and let's look at examples because this is this combination means the set of vectors
i have it just right
and so this idea of the basis
will be central always be asking you now
four basis whenever i look at the subspace
if i ask you if you give me a basis for the subspace you've told
me what it is
you've told me everything i need to know about that subspace
those i take their combinations and i know that i need all the combination
OK so examples of the basis let me start with two dimensional space
follows the
the space a example
this space is
let's make it answering
real three-dimensional space
give me one basis one basis is
so i want
some vectors
so if by asking for basis i'm asking for vectors a little list of vectors
there should be just right so what would be a basis for three-dimensional space
well the first basis that comes to mind when we write that down
in the first place that comes to mind is
this vector
this fact
as one basis
not the only basis it's going to be my point
but let's just say yes that's the basis
why is every are those vectors independent
so that's the like the x y and zee axes so
if those are not independent we're in trouble
so that they are
take a combinations c one of this vector plus c two of this vector plus
the three of that vector and try to make it give the zero vector
what this is
if c one of that policy to that policy three of that gives me zero
zero zero then the seas are all
zero right so that the test for independence
in the language of matrices
which was
under that board
i could make those the columns of the matrix
well it would be the identity matrix
but i would ask what's the null space of the identity matrix
and you would say
it's only the zero vector
and i would say fine then the columns are independent
the only thing the identity times of vector giving zero the only that vector that
does that is zero OK
that's not the only basis far from it tell me another basis and second basis
another basis
ah give me
OK so this tree
has several properties the first thing is that it's a binary search tree
OK so you can check in order to reversal should give these numbers in sorted
order three seven eight ten eleven eighteen twenty two twenty six so it's a valid
binary search tree
we depend on these leaves with no keys and they just hanging around as those
of the null pointers each of these you can call now
they're all just
marks there wherever there is absent child
and then double circles some of the nodes
the color than red
if i didn't the black knights wouldn't
match so
to be a little bit careful
for every
note we'd like to measure
the number of black nodes from that down to any descendant leaf so for example
the new pointers there black-eyed is
zero good sources answer so these guys all had black eyed zero just
some black high school zero
OK with the black of three
zero not
because these nodes are black
so of like i was one
they right that we don't count three even though it's black
we it's not included in the count but the
leaves count
and there's only two pass here in each of the same number
black nodes as they should over here let's say eights also has like i one
even though it's red
same with eleven
same with twenty six
each of them only has two pairs each of them has each path has one
like node on it
the black i
so one good
they don't count ten that there's now four
pastor leaves each of them contains exactly one like plus the route which we don't
twenty two same thing
OK this is getting a little more interesting is one pattern here which is one
block now this other paz here which are longer but they still only had one
so if we just sort of ignore the red nodes all these patterns have the
same like
eighteen should be bigger hopefully like i did too
because each of these pairs now has black that here one black node in leaves
or one black here in one like that in the leaves
and finally the richard have
black height of
and seriously over here i guess should has two black this
same over here
so that's just hopefully these properties make sense we didn't check all of them every
node has a black parents
look at all these paths
we sort of alternating red
black most or we're just a bunch of blacks we never repeat erez in around
the root leaves are black we used
much by definition
every node is red black that's easy
this is a particular set of properties that may seem a bit arbitrary this point
they'll make sense a lot more sense as we see
what consequences they have but there are a couple of goals
they were trying to achieve here one is that these properties should force the tree
to have logarithmic height
what i like and i
and they do although that's probably not obvious at this point
it follows mainly from this press from property from all the properties three and four
are the main ones but it's pretty much all of
the other thing the other
desire we have from these properties is that there are some easy to maintain
i can create a tree in the beginning there has this property for example
i could make
have to be a little bit careful but i can make
certainly if i take a perfectly balanced
binary tree
and make all the nodes black
it will satisfy those properties
this is a red black tree
this is not too hard to make these properties hold just from the beginning
the tricky part is to maintain
when i insert nodes to the tree and we from history i want to get
i want to make it not too hard on log n time i got to
well done when you very
with row
a you create a new role
three if you want to use
with you
that for the
so the
this may
the new in
in the
maybe three million
if we see what he meant he is not
what i mean
only for the very first order
perhaps there
general assembly
how however found in the
how old
so here we are
and by
i mean very
it's all over
or are we
all of order
four weeks
what if
which we are one and
all right
we want more
women were
but more than one more
if i may need to be
the reason for doing that
so are we
and the old
well with within the right
but they
and for that will be
all of
it not known
the government
so where are
o thing here
and for role
and for all
so i wish that you get the answer
four or
the total number
it is important that we
and from one hundred and two hundred eighty one o
they were all humans on all
so that's what we have
from the
of course because i want you
i would like
we're all one hundred by one
through what you
what are you
well want
so here i just written down the likelihood function explicitly integrating out the latent variables
solely variables don't appear here yet so i can't really look at the sun and
realize how to do yet but this is you an important piece of situation which
is that
the here the likelihood distribution is actually
two the only church in which they appear here is in this as which is
the sample covariance of the data
i can see another factor analysis y unconstrained gaussians fitting has some sufficient statistics and
the sufficient statistics are just the mean which are removed and the covariance of the
data which appears here
an introduction to factor analysis is that you're trying to make the covariance which is
as big close to the model covariance which is the except that the model covariance
is kind of constraint so we can make these things exactly the same and close
he is the trace of the ratio
the trace of the of the matrix ratio
so that's really what you're trying to do in fact announces get
now the covariance to be close to the observed data covering
so here is the actual ECM algorithm
and it's exactly the same as the EM algorithm for mixture models except now the
latent variables are continuous not discrete
so the same thing e
we need to compute the distribution over the latent variables given the data and the
current parameters
and in this case the that distribution rather than just being a multinomial or we
say what's the probability of the latent variables being equal to one two three up
to k it follows distribution
so some gaussian distribution here and in the end
for exactly the same you just maximize the expected complete log likelihood where the expectation
is taken under
this continuous
so i want to make a point about inference in factor analysis remember inference looked
it's in mixture models you took the probability of the data under the particular component
you're interested in
and you divided by the probability of the data summed over all components
it was just that ratio
what's the probability of the model k divided by what's the total probability and rome
in fact the analysis
inference in principle requires you to take the ratio
the ratio between the probability of generating the data if the latent variable
the continuously variable had a particular setting x divided by
the total probability of generating the data locally that total probability
is an integral which we can do analytically closed
so you do not integral analytically and the result is the inference in factor analysis
is actually
the distribution of the variable x given the data y
is a galaxy in with some mean and in some covariance b
it turns out that new
and it's just a linear function of the data you just take the data and
you subtract the mean
and after you subtract the mean is multiplied by this magic matrix here
this matrix is just the inference matrix so inference in factor analysis which might be
might be kind of complicated operation because you have to sum over an infinite number
of possible with variable settings that could have generated the data actually because you can
do that in general closed form reduces to linear operation
so what
the covariance
of the latent variables is independent of the data
it is equal to this expression
that's very counterintuitive thing about the analysis as q
here's the point here in factor analysis
what do you think the latent variables were set when i generated the data
you can give me an answer which is in the form of gaussians distribution the
mean and covariance that means depends on the data here
the covariance doesn't
which means your uncertainty about the latent variables does not depend on the data files
that's really different than in mixture models
in mixture models if i give you the point
that's right on top of one of the gaussians and miles away from all the
other gaussians you're pretty sure from adults
and that's reflected in the entropy of the posterior as a huge spike on one
model almost zero progress in factor analysis
equally unsure about the latent variables are very much i'm sure
no matter what the data once
that's the kind of strange property factor analysis that should set alarm bells in your
head that this is a very very simple model
so this is the sort of final algorithm again i'm not hoping you'll be able
to understand these equations right now lecture i just provide into there so you can
look them up later and that this is derived in exactly the same way as
we derive the previous algorithms
factor analysis is closely related to another model which many of you may have heard
which is the principal components analysis or PCA or for those of you who come
from or engineering background the car in the left transform KLT
the same
the idea
right so in factor analysis of what we do is we assume that the
i covariance matrix we're doing constraint as model and the covariance is the product of
some long and skinny matrices plus some diagonal
and of course we said we we had to constrain this to be diagonal otherwise
we would have the same problem with number of frames that we have original
twenty minutes that's
OK good
OK so
let's consider again the barrier optimisation so let's choose very optimisation technique is a the
method of choice to optimise this method
to optimise the optimisation problem OK so this was the ideas so we define this
barrier function with this exponential area gives you
OK so i'm going to change the new LP problem so that one with new
slightly so this is equivalent formulation is to be easier to drive OK
so instead of fixing
optimizing role fixed o to one
and and then optimize adolphus and we don't fix of two of the one norm
up to one case is just equivalent formulation
OK so how can we derive very optimisation objective
so this is the optimisation now we just follow the the normal strategy for deriving
barrier function this is just taking the objective you
writing it here and then for every constraint this one here what this one here
for instance we get we get an additional term and the very up upset optimisation
and also this one
this one here leads to
this term here
the other great because you're making some people decided constraints
so we have this optimisation object
this depends on beta alpha psi
so these are the variables of this optimisation problem often cited beta this very primitive
OK so i reverted here so i just read it again so now we can
actually determine optimal exciting for us so we can just set the the derivatives with
respect to size zero so
this is the solution
clock this back into the optimisation objective and then we get this
here the structure
OK when you have a look at this
maybe this reminds you of logistic loss
so this
very similar to logistic loss
OK so we have this up par optimisation function and this is the general form
which we have considered for
according wise descent method for so we just had to optimise this kind of function
this had to form in the in the court descent and then we had some
additional time here so we can just use this leveraging scheme to solve this optimisation
problem or to just to solve this optimisation problem so once we have to solve
this optimisation problem for fixed beta can decrease peter
that's all continue optimizing
and this leads essentially
to this on some details which i great out so just details to make appropriate
but it's not important but i already
so essentially just train a weak learner you find the output hypothesis coefficient just by
minimising some loss function you update your your combined function debates in a little more
complicated manner
and then under certain conditions you decrease the speed of parameter you let it go
to zero and then you try to follow this then you can show the convergence
so this algorithm
minimizes this optimizes this linear programme with this with the soft margin
you can do the same for regression so you just have a different optimisation problem
so you here for instance that you try to find a function that is close
to the labels so it's in some excellent you just different optimisation problem we can
use the same technique so just looks the same
other questions for that
so this is a very i mean a general strategy of how to go from
an idea of the problem or of of improvement to an article with proofs of
that is what has been done several times with different versions of articles for regression
one class four four soft margins and so on
is a principle to very of correct driving on
no questions
good everything else
i have i guess i'm going to close early so
there are some applications of boosting i would like to mention but just briefly
so here's some practical issues so generally so this this posting is
like meta algorithm that can use any reasonable can so when whenever i have something
which could be a problem then you can use boosting to somehow prove it so
and essentially it has the original adaboost has only a single parameter see number of
iterations which you need to
so and it's a kind of very fast and easy
program i mean it can be very easy to implement
better evaluation than just sort of this statistics and look how similar they are and of course
if I would be taking larger matrix I would get a better fit but
but for details for that I have them in the paper here again I'll just show you briefly I
have a larger graph it's a social network of opinions that has seventy-six thousand nodes and half
a million edges again we are searching over the space of size ten to the million we
can do this in two hours and these are some properties just to show that we are getting something
that sort of matches the structure and again and it scales linearly so let me just conclude and
will be done so what I showed at least for the so for the first
first part I'll go here so what we saw is that we saw first we we went through
the statistical properties of the networks from various domains and this is basically the
key to understand how do this I know independent behavior of people or the nodes bring
this nice structure out of it right so what is nice with this is that you have
this big social network my actions are sort of are independent of the actions
of someone who's in the I know in states or in China or in somewhere far away right but as
as you compute some kind of aggregate statistics nice patterns start of emerge so this is
why this is interesting so we have this sort of independent random players doing something
but when you look at enough of them you get you patterns start of emerge so
this was the first part the second part was about the the models of
structure and growth right so the reason why I show them was that this would give
us intuitions and help us explain why do these properties emerge right how can
my local behavior lead to to some global behavior and and the last
the last part the fitting part hat I skimmed briefly was to about
understanding the structure and prediction so why would you care about these things why why
do we need them as I presented them right so here are a few possible applications right first it gives
us insight into why these things are going wrong but then you can use this
for anomaly detection for example if you want to say is this graph
normal graph is this something that I would expect or is it strange so you need a model you need to
understand what is normal for when when we need fitting we saw that using this now
we can generate larger or smaller graphs so we can use these for predictions for
example many times you you have your new I know your routing algorithm or something and you'd
like to test it on some synthetic graph and it would be nice if this synthetic graph has
the same properties as real graphs have that's is this is also the reason why we
why you want models and why you want to fit these models similar reverse from
predictions is like graph sampling right the idea would be you have a big graph it's
too big for you to handle so now you would like to have create some smaller graphs run your
algorithm on itbut then sort of make claims how your algorithm on a smaller graph would run on a bigger graph so
we want to sort of shrink your graph but maintain the properties and
one way to do this would be through this sampling scenario right you
would fit the model and now given the model you can generate bigger or smaller graphs and
run your algorithms over them and
I think this is my last slide so here I just have some questions that
I think will come in the future right so one question is how do we
systematically characterize the network structure right given a graph how do
we describe it so that all of us sort of agree this is this is this kind
of graph with this particular structures so what are the important properties we need to
measure we don't know whether the ones we have today are the ones that we really
care about or is there something that we are missing or we haven't yet thought
of another question is how do these properties relate to one another how they are interconnected what are
what are the ones we would like for example if you would like to
design a system so this should be our next one right so the question is how how could we design systems
like systems or social network of websites and so on how how could
we design them to to for example be robust to failure so to support local search
for example in case of peer to peer networks or if we want them to
evolve how how how would we stimulate I know our social networking books website to sort of evolve in a
organic way so that the network doesn't fall apart so this this is one way right so
if you look at the network I know as your little plant so how should
you be taking care of your little plant that it really grows into something nice how do you
predict the structure of the network right you'd like to do this to be able to
say what will be going on with the future to be able to say how I know the
Internet will change how do we need to scale our algorithms protocols and things like that
and I think the most basic of them all is why are the networks the way
they are right how how did this independent or non-correlated behavior of people
gave us gave rise to these patterns that we see when we are looking at a large scale properties
we eliminated all the actors below that short and for these actors
we networks in the following two cases
that is
in the triplet
if it contains a key subject key action and an object or if it contains
a subject with the key actions
but the key object we feel that this and then we create networks out of
we also try to create works out of frequent triplets but they were not really
revealing interesting relations because the frequent triplets did not have interesting actions they were like
policing something to somebody or reporters reporting something so we thought this method is much
interesting and reveals more information so we generated directed networks using cytoscape which is denoted
platform for network analysis and the networks had
subjects and objects as nodes and the verbs linking them as edges
so this is a simple network in two thousand two on the left
it shows the whole network and i have highlighted the north trees
and the interaction of this north people other nodes in the network and it was
like you could see the priest was involved in abusing and listing all the time
and you could especially it's really clear that you can see the actors like
mike cannot more is saying
blackwell james support on all these people were
victims of those crimes
and the girls and boys
or the victim so this shows
this is from this that you could see you could also see the direction
we do that all this well
if you look at the network of prosecutors you could see there were always in
warding investigating
characterizing believing answering of conducting so you could see at this in more in what
kind of what type of actions so the networks itself provides information for us
this is another network showing
the interactions between judge
and the jury and then the actors in the network so
with this network we could identify
this type of actors in more than this these kind of actions this is really
important in the field of quantitative narrative analysis because currently all these are done manually
and it takes a lot of that
a similar kind of work has been done in the humanities recently by
frank from the stanford lead to the left
so they have converted no always into to
graphs like this and then they have identified the centrality of actors but again
they do it by hand so here it is automated
once the networks that then we could analyse the topological properties of the net so
we thought of analyzing the centrality of networks using
measures like of betweenness centrality and then the indegree and outdegree and the page rank
and the hits we also apply the HITS algorithm which is by jon kleinberg which
talks about hubs and authorities and we apply to all these two all the networks
and then ran
active according to these values you could see on the right it was the the
the tracks actors according to these four betweenness centrality indegree and outdegree and here again
you could see the actors the first line shows something called long
this is quite an b this here because
the person who was involved in the sexual crime at low
that could also mean that and then archdiocese and again the same kind of factors
appear there the in degree was again showing something like in this case
allegations boys and things like that
and the degree was fairly high for the priests and judges again
the same thing would be page five
cobb and authority
so all these measures were done using cytoscape
and if he which is also in network analysis tool which is an open source
tool as well
and then
know this
actors according to this and this is shown in the table so these are the
top ten most central actors in two thousand two
according to on the punishers
and the next we've also interested in identifying spheres of interaction because it is also
common to investigate this in q and a
the spheres of interaction between this means for example communication
all i could be relation could be violent crime except run so what we did
is we classify actions into different types
and then we analyse the triplets according to that so
we classified them according to these two categories
in two thousand two which is a crime against person
and crime against property
for example actions like
here's a murder mostly it would appear in
crime against person
and crime against property it would be like slaughtered or
t or steel properties so
in two thousand two the most of the network was
the game was was about crime against person a little bit about crime against property
so once we have this
we identify what the frequent subjects and objects in the world in this
so this shows the top ten ranked subjects and objects in crime against person and
crime against property so all this is done with only the key actors and actions
that we have identified so
here you could say that dog highest-ranked subject
in crime against person was placed and then men
and then the objects which i'll go and so it is interesting to see here
that men responsible for crimes and while women and children are most often the objects
of crimes and protect the crime against property again and police and soldiers with the
subjects and the most frequent object was money and back
we also performed in time series analysis on actors
we thought it's interesting to to see the
the role of factors in a time series so we were analysing data from nineteen
eighty seven to two thousand seven in europe and so it's it's really twenty years
we did all the experiments for
all these twenty years and
for the time series analysis we considered the frequency the out degree
and they have value to plant
these at this so according to
the active archdiocese his frequency was really high in two thousand two
the out degree and hub also denotes the
his he was the key key actor in two thousand two and it's the same
for actions as well
you could see the first one is more lists which is really high in two