after ten episodes of the that function estimate and the actual true
value function for policy
what you see here tonight is lambda free flying
OK so landings one again is monte carlo
and lambda equal zero
is the temporal difference method
if i the probability of point nine
twenty five point eight
when the close to one another quite one tends to work
the best intended gases flooding you have the estimators and and
averaging estimators works often better than using just one single australia's human because one
lambda equal zero
and also of course gets around this this chain problem that we had
guys you use different step return
as long as land is not at the extremes
then you see that you going to get some value update from all possible
in step returned
thirty city lambda does not suffer from the
the slovak problem it TD zero has
so the only question here is
how do you implement
the UN
one way to think about it but not only implemented this way
you're in state st
OK is is a good diagram
this person
so this is the sort of thing looks ahead to the future rewards the feature
values OK it just said OK
i got
this estimate st plus one this is the first people see this is the first
t plus three
i know how i should wait of different customers our them together
if you get a ball in this in an algorithm
it's going to be very inefficient
so it's really quadratic into the inside the state space every state has look at
and the real estate OK so he started doing states that the complexity this happens
billions where
OK so
this is the way to think about another way you want man
OK a better way to implement it
is sort of with this
backward view
so what you get update
and st plus one you can propagate
they return that she would get from
from this date back to all previous states right because
if you recall in previous block diagram
is to start with some some some value
right so the one-to-one whatever turns you
this is one minus land
the next one sees that value times
the reward plus the nighttime lambda
for to this when you get reward plus the nighttime
and when the again
so what you want to do in the back view is
passed back
current turn
this going by gamma and lambda
at every time every every propagate value back
not sure it's so obvious
but thing better second you don't get it
so in this very nice way to implement this is called the old the eligibility
trace now a dozen neuroscience here
we are scientists
OK so the elderly trace sort of became very popular because people said this actually
looks like what neurons to the way neurons spiking way neurons are available to receive
rewards and
so the strengthening and weakening of of a certain paths
three three through neural systems
and so what happens is that you're making is this eligibility trace first state
OK this is how eligible is the state to be updated by future rewards if
you visit the state
so if you have at time t
you state doesn't call st
then you take the previous eligibility and you have to have one
for all future time step three with state is in st
you simply just discount that eligibility by
yemen times lambda
OK now the neat trick is
that he simply use this update
so i arbitrary traits revisited does and one to that state
and then when you i for states
you see the the area here
you you you just
delta which is the difference between your estimate and you current estimate the difference between
sample estimate
could i just write delta
yes multiplied delta country eligibility
if you want to see the proof that p four p and the backward view
are equivalent to look at the book but turns out that they are equivalent and
then you get this nice
this nice
view that
at this stage more often say
every time he does it state is held its is eligible to be updated increases
right they don't for while itself it is eligible is elementary decreases
OK i visited again
this tells you how much it adapts itself to wheel war sees
at the time in the future OK
as time to do this decreases the value of the last
and so on
and this was claimed to be somewhat similar to behavior observed in neural activity
so again
the summary of this is that there is a four d which is very intuitive
avatar return to get the this is this is complex the complexity of this is
is the states i square
there's backward view which is this idea of eligibility
and then just multiplies
the update
first a bite eligibility
OK this has complexity
which is just
well actually i it can be so complex that you made many doubted every state
on every
iteration correct
but it's less than than the city square
OK and these two views are equivalent
so td lambda is not only good idea into the idea of averaging returned is
i mean
well it doesn't have much
and if you go
make sure you have to do with
but you
he loved
the good one
what is known
we have
to be
and you can
so there's more
one of the right
i mean
we've got
so the
right left
thank you very much
it was
but what
well i
so what going to
is no
o the
you can
i mean
you know
you can
maybe we should try out
all of
OK a few
the press
characteristic vector max
now what i was saying about the solution is the following
in the original formulation of masking strauss
might be spurious solutions i mean
global optimisation of the objective function
which are not in the form of characteristic
so let's consider this very simple graph
and we know here there are two maximal cliques
is this one
this one
you can take the standard simplex
we know from the martin strauss theorem that
this point here
global optimisation objective function
this point here with global optimisation objective function but
that means that if they take all the points on the segment connecting
is two points all this points will be also global optimise for the object there
is infinity of of
a global
all these points here
i will not be in the form of this
of course is
so in order to avoid this problem in order to avoid solutions recently
barnes from the first n
just proposed to add a regularisation term
it's just last one of the two express that this is just the way of
normal vector
and then he proved the theorem which establishes a one-to-one correspondence between
local optimizers
of the objective function and maximal cliques
global optimisation of the objective function and maximal cliques
that shows that these are the only
o globo slash local optimum there is not a solution is
so from a computational perspective if you have to find the maximum clique or a
maximal clique in the graph just maximize this over the standard simplex
of course there's no guarantee that will find the global optimum maybe you find good
now once we have characterized
dominant sets in terms of
solutions of continuous optimisation problem how can we find well actually
it is straightforward to show that this is actually a quadratic linearly constrained optimization problems
i can take any textbook from optimisation theory it's a bombardier
i go to chapter nonlinear optimization
plenty of course the simplest one would be of sort of writing crack gradient descent
i start from the interior of the simplex and they keep following the gradient
to reach the boundary then a project
the vector gratin with already
the boundary in a just way
but instead of using this kind of algorithms
which also requires some tuning regarding
the step size is of course
when i think
the direction of the gradient to say exactly how much
along the direction
this is the parameter which is not easy to
it is the mean that we just use that
there is a whole class
are all dynamical systems
from evolutionary game theory which serves very well
this cost dynamics is called the replicator dynamics
and this is the last of the simplest dynamical systems
developing this branch of game theory
which is called evolutionary
just give you
the basic intuition behind this kind of dynamics
actually evolutionary game theory was introduced in the seven late seventies eighties actually
by john maynard smith
we try to import into biology
the notions in terms of game theory
in theory we talk about game during the first part of this talk
game theory was introduced by for nine months and was developed by john nash
in order to deal with
you know
complex situations among rational beings
namely humans
and it was the notion of rationality which was fundamental in in game theory
so the trick childminders was applied game theory
two animal behavior too general to
biological context
because we
specific problem
it's not always logarithmic is that sometimes its and it's
it's very enticing when it's true
alright so i'm going to talk about a little bit later for research stock
but today
or can talk about
markov decision process reinforcement learning and reinforcement learning
i care said this
that was in our problem
it's been something simple in RL
and you want to identify how it's important for all problem
hopefully when you do that you'll discover that somebody already studied that particular setting and
then you can use whatever approaches they developed
all right so
i started with the this is this is modern reinforced learning
so should go back to the
this modern reinforced theory
it's quite a bit of reinforcement learning theory which has happened before the seven talk
about here one talking about here
if things that make it happen last
seven years or so
so the first kind of reinforcement of the people
having been worrying about
is sample complexity in reinforcement
the sample complexity is how many times you need to interact with your environment in
order to do something interesting and useful
what is simplicity guarantee
we think about making theorem statements of the form
with high probability
given the number of samples
some guarantees going to hold
and a fill-in what that guarantees minute
we're going to be worrying about reinforcement learning in markov decision process
you should define a markov decision process defined for
so the fundamental quantity in markov decision process
is a next state
OK so we're going to have states
state something that the world imposes
women have actions
we have some distribution over the next state given the action state
there are going to have a policy
this is
and actually
so i'm curious if you can run the tests would point the camera
at the camera's output
OK so in markov decision process we have some states
the state summarizes all the information we need not to make good decisions
the kind of fundamental assumption right the you know the state summarizes everything
and then based finite state making conservatives
other questions about that
and mentioned this kind of model or briefly yesterday
in in general in the real world maybe you don't have you exactly know estate
the things like
OK so when you're sort of
physically moving around
if you
i can't see things because he blindfolded then you not the markov decision process
but other than that we are in the market decision process so whatever we see
sufficient to tell us
how to move around which is maybe true
for some reason portion of the time
OK so
the final quantities are
but the final parameters
that's absolutely the number of states
a with the number of actions per state
he's going to be horizon so when people are doing reinforcement learning
very often
that we want to be concerned not just with what happens in the next steps
well what happens to steps into the future
so that people
instead of saying i care about the next steps they say i care about
this step
some OK with the next last next little as an example of less flexible less
with they a
they quantifiable but less in terms of gamma
instead what was going to work with t because it's a bit easier mathematically but
all the results to talk about today
and the whole if you use gamma discounting
we switch from markov decision processes to ponder piece to partially observable markov decision processes
like so if if you blindfolded
and then you will wander around
you can't see anything which you can still feel and based on what you feel
you can decide what to do
and then we have a precision parameter so yes
having as a goal
learning exactly what our policy is what policy will give you the largest
some rewards is a little bit
because it can be done in recent sense
so what are goal is going to be something like we're going to try to
find a policy which is within epsilon of the optimal policy
OK so there is a specific
the result which is actually
quite interesting and i am trying to go through this result in full detail
the israelis the ECU to guarantee to each student is now our them which stands
for explicit explore exploit
so we're going to do
the is
question of what kind of information access to we have the world
and we're going to
this solution
there all the ways of looking at it as a problem namely that
the very nature of all the model the fact that it is not
a tractable model
in sense of of
a closed form density are computable density
pushes four different inferential approaches
in two to leave the standard bayesian
past four
different inferential approach that's your optimistic can be
we appreciated within
the vision real
and if you're pessimistic
that is incoherent because it's not exactly be
and the around is to see there
today that we may still be
we are dealing with different types
estimators and methodologies and again
the bright side is that's because it's too within the bayesian approach
it's a valid in and clearance
a few not at optimistic
it's merely to cases where r is not clear and because for instance
it's not
just are
a side issue that's actually relates to
two eighty see
that's more like an historical
background on these issue
connections with the introduction of maybe see between the intrusion of maybe see
some solutions that have been developed in econometrics
in as we are not always being enough attention to
i was going econometrics
although i mean that the two fields are are statistics and econometrics are
close enough
well it in
in the past fifteen
years at least
that's that's been ways to deal with this complex econometric models
pretty good
are you see an and related simulation based
techniques and so i will just mention a few here
in case you have not seen them and if you are in case
we've seen them
to make the link
with aby
so far this image method-of-moments is
such that's because you cannot compute
likelihood for instance
you produce
so observations from
you are issue model
res eight even value for the parameters theta
and you try to fit
the best senior in terms of the simulated
data when compared
with the original data
why he wrote it
one approach
don't edit it depends
a little too much on the series and so it looks at the difference between
each term in this area is an alternative is just to look at
based on the series inference and take the average of the observations minus the average
of the simulated observations and if you know it already
you can see
that it there is a perfect link that
and then are a bit broader and more ambitious is a methyl simulated moments to distinguish it from the
simulated method-of-moments
that's all
goes a bit further and uses
first statistic
okay for which
we can find an unbiased estimator of its expectation
and compare
what to observe the cave whitey
again estimated version that may be repeated in order to reduce the monte carlo valuation
and this distance
that's we again peak parameters theta
that tries to bring
what we observe
through some
prisms through some change of perspective because case and statistic is the whole vector
an approximation
based on the knowledge of the message
and then comes up i think the most interesting of the group with which is
the indirect inference approach
that was in truth about the eagerly-awaited all
namely that's
they go even further from these assumptions they have on the model
by using estimators
that's rely on a suitable model that is not necessarily true
using the
behind the picture behind the scenes
they try to
find the parameters theta that brings
estimator of the wrong model
as close as possible to an estimator based on types they are
the true model
that was no that's nonsense there is a control system that's the divides listen in
biology not some special force
we have a similar challenge now
i would suggest to you the challenges that we got a new form of reductionism
in biological sciences it is genetic determinism and i should say more about that in
this lecture but we also have a very different challenge because we now have more
facts we can handle this data explosion at all levels of biology
i'm going to be a little bit like moses coming down those two great big
stone tablets on which the ten commandments systems biology is going to be written my
first commandment is the biological functionality is multi level
genes do absolutely nothing on their i'm going to replace many of the metaphors used
in biological science over the last twenty thirty years by alternative metal force because i
think it's important we change the way we think there is no genetic programme for
genes and today the genome which they are part simply databases and the reason for
that is the physiological functions use many genes in collaboration in determining the level at
which the system
the function is integrated which i would suggest is one of the main aims of
systems biology
very simple calculation will indicate the nature of one of the problems here
we took just the equation for combinations of possibilities between large number of components taking
genomes all the way
from a hundred to thirty thousand and simply calculated the possible number of combinations of
a simple equation produces some astonishing results
let's do very simple calculation and assuming the biological function like a pacemaker activity of
the heart secreting pancreas
depended on just two genes interacting that's an absurd
this assumption course come under reasonable assumptions in the moment the total number of possible
functions using that equation would be three hundred million
incidentally that's the number
of knockout mice you would need if you wanted to investigate double knockouts in
gene twenty five thousand we never going to do that
but it's worse than that because you make much more reasonable assumptions is actually shown
moment we can reconstruct pacemaker activity in heart models representing around fifty or most around
one hundred components meaning proteins coded for by genes and if we go to
kind of a number of genes required to make a function we end up with
e three hundred two and if we want to remove all restrictions all combinations we
get an absolutely phenomenal number ten to seventy thousand
simply wouldn't be enough material
in the whole universe for nature to experimented with all those possibilities even though the
billions of years of the evolutionary process
my second principle
and transmission of information is not one way
we have been to
grossly misled
by the central dogma of biology and incidentally should never been called top of course
there are no documents in science there are many hypotheses to be tested
and the document
it is at least insufficient is even incorrect
it's only correct in the very limited sense in which create first introduced which which
is that you don't back translate protein sequences performed DNA sequences that's the only sense
in which is correct
there is downward causation
on the gene from all levels
and this leads to some very astonishing
consequences if you think it through
consequences that were even seen by one of the
i mean
it is of the reductionist approach in biology john maynard smith who incidentally inspired
together with hamilton richard dawkins concept of the selfish gene and john maynard smith a
very clever man died recently in great shape we lost him he pointed out that
landmark is it's not so obviously false as is sometimes made out of come onto
that false sentiment
so the reductionist causal chain
it would be written as genes coding for proteins forming pathways and so on all
the way up to reconstruct the whole organism what i pointed out earlier of course
is that we should never be able to do that
the complexity
that is involved in getting bottom-up trying to reconstruct the whole organism is simply way
beyond what we should ever be able to compute
this was richard statement of course they
genes created us body and mind of course they
that i'm going to bring this approach is also one of the architects of the
human genome project and distinguished molecular biologists from britain won the nobel prize just recently
his magnificent what you said i know one approach and failed to start with genes
make proteins from them and try to build things bottom
and part of the reason for that is not just the complexity that was referring
to earlier on the combinatorial explosion problem it is also that that's not how nature
does is either
the genome
it starts off in excel
but then this is much more satisfying you want to produce an algorithm put it
out there and have everybody uses it right
you know one have to solve every case study separately
i mean do we really need is a separate machine learning researchers statistician for every
problem there we don't not enough of us for that
i mean how do we build the bayesian black boxes that can we meaningfully create
bayesian black boxes
i don't know like it so what with the prior b
right if i'm going to
take a bayesian method we do this right you know some of us have some
of you guys have
guassian process code online right
well with the with the prior there
it's meant training you know you can do any regression problem right but
you know what should the prior b it should be some sort of reflection of
what different kinds of problems people are going to apply to
applied to
so we we can clearly create black boxes we put code online
but how can we advocate people blindly using them we we can write we can
advocate people
using them blindly unless we're just thinking incrementally will say well
i don't really think this calcium process
captures the correct prior
this person's application but i really think it will do better than that crappy SEM
code out there
right so maybe incrementally or providing a service
even though we're not actually
advocating you know we're not actually doing
you know
bayesian proper bayesian inference for them
so we can require practitioner to be well trained bayesian statistician so we're sort of
stuck with the sort of conundrum so on
he work with
is not
well most
problem the problem in the world
i mean the people with you want to comment on that are full of our
i would say
you want
this work
it's it's been a very
so a lot of
so i was right
so i mean the right bayesian practice i think is this case study view where
you know you you really try to understand your problem as well as possible
and development
or maybe you can like you peak at the you know you can you're allowed
to look at
whatever ten percent of your data as much as you want you come up with
the whatever prior you can from that
and then you
do your inference on the other ninety percent i think that's actually valid
i think that's perfectly valid or the right
nine years
the RBF kernel works fine for grained as the
in the first
that seems sensible right because
that would be
yeah you're basically your prior
then is a prior on the kinds of problems
your code is going to be run on
so if i put the code on line
i have some beliefs about the kind of people who are going to download
and the kind of datasets are going to run it on
and that's actually i mean i think that you know for most of us and
i know you know like for example you guys put some code on line for
the GP book bunch of you put all of us have probably put some code
generated based on the positions of trust and use the stick breaking procedure
the fact that the data generated based on the corresponding parameter space which is selected
based on the state of indicated it c
and we saw the
the next thing is also we wanted to give something in the world we give
something is like for of me yesterday is also like to sample from one just
conditioned on some data when you talk about services to the thing think you can
go through this hierarchy sent from jesus from produce some data but in the
the situation now we assume we have something to everyone to infer about the state
of that are of the probability of new
and associated with the left representation is this idea of types tempting because you sort
of simple method directly in you include the indicator variables which corresponds sort of to
the assignment of customer to table than the first of more to the chinese restaurant
restaurant process
is a
yeah i mean it's difficult to robert that he went the state of the
which that to pick
so it's like in them and then find mixture model but it's difficult to sort
of the colliding that means the data depend on both the state of c that
such essentially picks
the fact that which set out to pick which
maybe that would be able to
i don't have to think about the the the ministers played representation sometimes they they
have had this in this is sometimes but probably a that would be less confusing
if they can get
so if we know the sample
using i mean including the the measurements we have now is not too much and
is a finite dimensional model we have to add this likelihood term here on the
right because the math
and which now means that you would prefer
previous samples if they explain your own data very well now we are talking about
situation that i have data my own sister my own use my own hospital whatever
so data and if the previous sentence explain those data as well then they did
they increase the probability which makes sense
if you want to learn something things you should be sensitive to the data you
and also the term which is based on the base distribution also is affected by
the likelihood and also this is easier to understand if you want to look at
OK one one we marked here this can be written in this form which means
there is some probability you sample from the posterior of you
parameters given your own data suggest on your own model and with the
with this term the likelihood december from the already existing samples and this is sometimes
a little bit difficult to calculate but sometimes if you can explore conjugacy between
the distributions not the conjugate prior to this likelihood term it generates the data and
this can typically be written in closed form expression and its
it can be done efficiently in other cases you have to spend more for calculating
this but it's just not a very important step for now now so let's look
at this example again what happens if you choose the chinese restaurant representation so now
we have the situation that they
in the gibbs sampling you initialise everything in some smart way and then you always
resemble one of the very well
so this is sort of the state we're in now
we have table
customers and pick one of the
customers first thing is we remove this customer from the table
and then we reassignment to with him and so he could be reassigned to any
of the existing table
and the assignment is is affected by two terms servicing seen before one is the
question how well the parameters of the stable explain the data of this this custom
so you want to be sensitive now
and the second one is how many customers are sitting at the table so can
have a lot of customers sitting table this increases the probability that the sky will
be assigned to the table but only if the data
sort of the properties of explain his own data
there's the whole on that are quite well
and in some cases the customer may contact the probabilities can also open a new
table and then draw from it from the conditional distribution of the parameters given the
and since now also the
parameters that sort of decoupled from the occupancy of the tables we can occasionally also
we estimate the parameters
and this is an advantage of this the chinese restaurant process representation that these parameters
can independently be re estimated after we know which customers are reassigned to the table
in the representation this more difficult and ended on representation doesn't mix as well as
it is
i mean there's a high likelihood i mean if if there there's a strong cluster
already formed here by a lot of parameters and we take one of the guys
out that it's very likely that this guy is simply assigned to the same cluster
again it's very difficult for this cluster to move around in terms of the parameters
because there are already so many people sitting at the table it is not the
ten example see under protection so there already so many parameters decided so many data
points to decide on this parameter if you take one what the point would probably
just be reassigned to the same cluster and then it's very difficult to move around
in terms of the
the space and in the chinese restaurant process is much easier because after you have
signed customers the the table you can independently resample the set might be more
the graphic representation here this nicely discovers the couple you simply from the fact that
and then you can reset from the from disease
the factors was c it's it's more difficult to get the samples from
just because you have so many data already assigned to the status in both sports
things essentially doing the right thing is just one big suspect and the which means
that you get the correct estimates more quickly than the other so you have been
while the inclusion exclusion
principle tells us that let's look at the disjunction a or b or c
the inclusion exclusion principle tells us
that the number of such rules we can compute it by taking the number of
rows in which a is one
plus the number of rows in which b is one the number of rows in
which sees one
and taking away
he wrote a number of rules in which a and b are both one
a and c are both one is
you see i want
and the idea
the number of rows in which we use a b c are r one
so basically we can be described the frequency of this
alternating sum of frequencies
now this is the frequency of conjunction over y
over all subsets of x where x is now the disjunction
and then there is minus one to the power of the size of y plus
so this is inclusion exclusion of certain family
everybody here
so this actually generalise so if there is a boolean query i would like to
how many rows in the database satisfy the was one or
and in that case is be equals
four of
c equals one and
one zero
any boolean queries we can rewrite
as a
combination of frequencies of something some set x y and z
constant you are
for example in the aquarium
would be the a three one
and a one or two one
then the frequency of this can be described as the frequency of ninety three minus
the frequency of three one
plus the frequency of we want to
well i guess
we can verify that
so this requires a three is one
and then
either of these also we paid
frequency and paul
and i guess it holds
now what you think of inclusion exclusion
so we have frequencies of all of the y
of disjunction
all of this general form for arbitrary building query like this
we have frequencies of x y on subsets
happens now when sigma is greater than zero we don't know all the frequency
we know only the large ones
so we know the frequency of all conjunctions
there are frequent enough most of the rest you know
nothing else them
at frequencies below the thresh
well what can we do
suppose for example we have to
estimate the
the size of the disjunction a or b or c
we could take the frequency of a frequency of the first frequency c
there are some minor science music
and then it could be that we are not
we don't know
these frequencies here
we could just leave them out to think truncated inclusion exclusion so
just leave it and
there's all
actually when you do
empirical tests
this work quite nicely
but it would be nice to have a theoretical result about this the basically you
just leave out small gardens
things actually
in practice into work developed in the world
what will
it would be nice to understand why this is the case
actually there is
some but not the linear and is about fifteen years ago where they study for
a completely different
the reason they wanted to learn
they wanted to come DNF formulas or something like that
they had resolve
basically if you know
this sizes is
all frequencies
up to this level which is square within the number of all variables
then you get a very good approximation
it's extremely good approximation results
inclusion exclusion
but actually what's interesting in there is no approximation results
is that
the sum over those which you know
up to this quote level the
in the latter of subsets
the linear combination of their frequencies
but this linear combination inclusion exclusion you only helpless
plus one or minus one
some real numbers
coming into the approximation they come from to preserve polynomial so what
it's beautiful paper if somebody is interested in the theory of science
it's actually one of
you it will a very good approximation places
unfortunately for our case
we don't know
conjunctions the the frequencies until the square level
we know that the the frequencies of the line
one junctions
so we can still can have this approach that we approximate by taking the truncated
inclusion exclusion sound
open theoretical question is how large and the approximation error
there is a
a corollary
sorry conjecture
the above
subset of the
are subsets of the subset lattice
so suppose we have p is a downward closed set of subsets of a finite
and we pay
the some of minus one to the power of the subset plus one
four or
the whole of this subset
we conjecture says that this not always found
the size of the positive border
in words that the
seeing the world
i could talk about these joints as well
and there are there are various things that i can talk about with my
my individuals OK so i can assert individuals have been members of the classes i
can assert that individuals must be related individuals must similar so must be the same
or different OK so these are all again ways in which are constraining
the way in which you can interpret the vocabulary that providing you
i can
provides axioms
talking about the properties
so i can see this some proper just subproperty or to talk about the domain
and range so the that main saying that this property is used and the subject
of the property
must be in a particular class
or the object property must be in particular class then all these things simply allow
me to kind of give some
constraints some some more definition on the way in which i expect you to interpret
the vocabulary
in terms the semantics OK so i had these interpretations so interpretation takes my
atomic but vocabulary maps into my my domain and then i have the rules that
tell me how i can kind of turn the handle and produced the interpretation of
the class expressions that i had this notion of of an interpretation being a model
the ontology
essentially it respects all the axioms i provided OK so fast subclass axioms and my
ensures that the
interpretation things in the axiom kind of end up being subsets then that's being in
that's being respected and the the
interpretation is a model of the axioms
so the the actions in the ontology of kind of constraining the possible ways in
which i can interpret these
this is the main vocabulary
given not right
but provided a number of axioms k which which tell you how you should be
interpreting these things are now may be the case that in the in the allowed
interpretations there are some consequences because of the way ways in which i constrained everything
OK some properties may hold of all those interpretations are allowable and if anything if
they do hold then we can make some inferences about things so for example i
can talk about subsumptions
and i can say OK c subsumes the
with respect to some ontology if it's the case that for every model
of the ontology
interpretation of these things in a subset relationship so so what i'm getting here from
in terms of the
inference is saying OK
my axioms constrain the things that you can have a now it may be that
but three that constraints all of these models have some commonality and there are some
common things that we can deduce within a to do things like subsumption so i
can talk about satisfiability
OK so some concept description
it satisfiable
if there is a model of the axioms OK where the interpretation about to concept
the concept is nonempty
OK i can also talk about unsatisfiability or inconsistency which is one of the things
that jim cannot refer to earlier on
it's the case that there is no model where this thing ends up being on
OK so essentially in an inconsistent concept is something where
if you respect all the axioms in my ontology it's impossible for you to ever
have an instantiation interesting all the interpretations end up this thing being in this some
an inconsistent classes unsatisfiable class ten represents some over constraining or some some inconsistency in
the axioms is telling me that the
the constraints that you have applied mean i could never have one of these things
OK so talk about the consistence of the entire ontology maybe that i the axioms
that i have i have given
are contradictory or too strong and somehow there's no way i could ever build a
model of this thing and this is kind of useful information but i mean want
to know the model
so i have
i have reason this case like i can build a piece of software that make
use of this information in the ontology
based on the semantics the reason i can tell me that
some of the consequences of the knowledge that i've presented i wasn't aware of before
so for example in may tell me about inconsistencies in my my mind my model
may tell me about subsumptions now hold between things
so i have kind of ideas subsumption reasoning
the subsumption reasoning cannot tell me that is a subclass of a if it is
necessarily the case for all instances of b must be instances of a this telling
we're going to show them
more unlabelled data points
and their task
he is to decide for each of of those will point whether it is in
previous class or not
so it's
this is binary classification but you only have a single class training
now this is normally
modeled as the level set problem
so what you
well what we think the owners modelling years
to find out
the level set
in the feature space
where this probability is larger than some threshold
and then given the new point
if the new point using the levels that we classify as one otherwise it's zero
so if that's the case well i mean this is a well defined machine learning
and typically we would assume that x is fixed after training or whatever classifier you
have in mind is fixed during training
and then
the the test data shouldn't change
that classifier
if that's the case
then this psychologist study by ozaki and ostrovsky actually showed that's not the case
people would update their mental classifiers using tested as well
so here's the same
this is what people actually see
that's a pretty good acts
it consists of a square work displayed on the screen with nine dancing and the
position of those nine dots can change and that's your
that's your input so this
this a single
then what
conceptually happens is there's this feature space
and try it in one d
imagine these are all different ways that the nine dots can be considered kind can
be positioned
there is a notion of centres of there is one particular image so this image
which is the center
and then you perturb
those individual points slightly
in fact we perturb the lot
that gives you a somewhat distribution like this
and the training data all come from this distribution so you're going to show them
examples that are perturbed
like that
with this variance with this graph
so they compare two conditions
one is where
OK so sorry this is the training set so
there are two groups of subjects
but they all say the same training
this examples forty
pictures samples from this distribution right
they differ by what kind of test a c
so the test data the they have to decide
which classes which these are how the test data prepared
in condition one
test examples are pretty much sampled like calcium distribution
where you have for example assembled exactly at to this picture
and twenty examples sampled from a small
the the ring of those data points so it's
very similar to this picture then twenty more
that has a larger right
and then forty that's totally random from the whole feature space those are
the examples test examples this is of course their order is randomized
in contrast in court two
they see a similar number of test points but there are sampled from a different
in fact it's somewhat like this so basically
the mode to century disappears there's only one and two here but instead
they got a lot more example from somewhere else it's a different domain
and with a lot of examples centred around that
so that's the difference now what they want to see is for each test example
do they classified as in the class or not
now to my experiment is very noisy so what you can look at this to
aggregate information
in the end you want to see
what's the fraction
ask people
if they see
an example say exactly at you
what's the fraction of participants that classifier it
as in the class
look at all the
examples that UNC what's the fraction of people classifier
in the previous class you would imagine
everybody should so this it is in the classroom but people are noisy so
you expect some probability fraction which is close to one but not necessarily one
and then we expect this
fraction two
gradually decreased if you
look at examples sampled from say this distribution
then the fraction would decrease a little bit
if you see
estimation task is that we assume that we have the density
well over six parametrized by some parameters theta and this density is uniform density
over six
and has support only in theta and theta plus one so so theta is the
left it
borderline off of a rectangular distribution if you like so this symbol you just denotes
a uniform distribution over x in the interval a to b and of course has
to be normalized appropriately and i in
here in in future slides will indicate the indicator function which is one in the
set indicated here and zero elsewhere
so the task is to estimate the location of the parameter theta to estimate the
parameters theta given an i i d sample from this distribution here
so it's really simple one-dimensional problem and the nice thing is that then they are
not as many technicalities involved with various distributions and assumptions and approximations that we would
have to make so here's a picture of the problem
here is the density plotted and this is our ex
theta is the location parameter denoting the left border line here and this thing is
one and this thing is one is just a square density so to speak is
just the problem is we don't know whether peter is and that's what we want
to estimate
typically frequentist approach
OK we want to find an estimator theta had of x
or more maybe more interesting want to find the confidence interval where we have the
the boundary of the internal and the right boundary denoted give a theta had left
and theta have right and you see here the depends on the sample
and what we expect from this confidence interval
is that the probability that the true parameter lies in the confidence interval
the big right so that you can delta could be say five percent so we
want to ninety five percent with ninety five percent probability
over the draw of the sample
that the true parameter lies in this in terms of that we will find and
there's an interesting
the story here this is kind of a line of statistics you might say that
goes back to fisher and he was consulting
statisticians people would come to him and ask him to solve particular problems in it
was in the biological facility i think so they ask is how many
how many plants have to use here in this experiment there are to be sure
that the effect is is true and
so for him this kind of very important thing to have right he wants to
right in ninety five percent of the cases you don't care about any of the
particular case very much but he wants to have a good reputation as a consultant
here i have just chosen a simple estimator is another thing you you probably learned
in statistics you choose an estimator right you don't really derived one but people say
this is an estimator many show certain properties of estimators that's kind of the methodology
and so the estimated i'm looking at here is to just take the minimum of
all the data points
you think about that looks kind of plausible you i have this this square density
and i sample points from that and i want to estimate the leftmost
o point of the density when not take the minimum of the data points
and now we have that obviously by simple logic the true parameter
must be and must be less
then the estimator
it's not clear it must lie to the left it cannot lie to the right
because then they the the density could have could have produced a particular data point
the minimum data point so
we can also take this estimator is the right-hand boundary of our confidence interval
we know it's going to be the right-hand boundary logically so might be a good
choice would simplify things
so so the confidence interval we choose is
the the interval we choose is given for the right hand side is this theta
had right or or estimated this minimum here and the left hand side is just
the right inside minus some quantity epsilon
and the analysis is all about how big the does this epsilon have to be
in order to make sure that with high probability
the true estimator lies in the intro
that's just treat one of the very simple case epsilon greater than one
then we know for certain that our theta will lie in this confidence interval there's
it doesn't have the choice for greater one
so the regime of interest is really lying somewhere between zero and one and that's
the thing we're only going to analyse
we are interested in the probability over the draw of the sample i i d
draft simple that the true parameter is in the confidence interval and the random quantity
of course is the sample
it's easy to show that this probability is equivalent to
the probability of our estimator or right inside estimator lying between the true parameter
and the true parameter plus epsilon
that's just by changing the boundaries around so these two statements are really equivalent and
that's why the probabilities of the same
and you know how to calculate this we need the cumulative distribution function
of this estimator here evaluated this boundary of the integral and evaluated this boundary of
the intro integral and it's this
minus this here so we need to evaluate the distribution function of this estimator here
i'm going into this detail here because i want to show you that this is
really essentially logic but we're using
and that you can get quite far with the simple rules of probability and logic
the cumulative distribution function is defined as the probability over the random quantity
of this thing being less than
the value x at which is the primary here so
this statement that
that the estimator is less than x is the same as
the minimi minimum of all these data points is less than x because that's how
the following content is provided under creative commons license your support will help MIT opencourseware
continue to offer high quality educational resources for free to make a donation or view
additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses visit MIT opencourseware at OCW that MIT
that u
so last time we talked about the
the zeroth law
which is the common sense law which
it says that if you take a hot object next called out
people flow from hot to the cold in way that
is well defined
and it allows you to
define temperature
it allows you to define the concept of the thermometer
three objects
one of the thermometer two of them separated in this sense the third one and
you go from one to the other and you see whether he knows
when you touch
one object
in the middle object between those two objects
and then we talked about temperature scales we talked about
the celsius scale the fahrenheit scale
the late eighteen hundreds were booming time for temperature scales people didn't really realize how
important it was to
properly defined reference point
warm-blooded or
ninety six degrees
kramer seven point five degrees warmer because you don't want to go below zero degrees
measuring temperature outside denmark
the second so e
but there the legacy that we have today
and that's what we use
in science we use
somewhat better temperature scales and
the temperature scale that turns out to be
well defined
hands up giving us
the concept of an absolute zero
is this
it is the ideal gas thermometer
so let's talk about that
briefly today first
ideal gas
it's based on boyle's law boyle's law was an empirical law that mister boyle discovered
by doing lots of experiments
boyle's law says that the limit
the quantity
times the molar volume
this quantity pressure times more volume
as you can that pressure
it is zero
if you do this measurement measure the gas to measure the pressure in the more
the volume
and you change the pressure again you measure the pressure in the more multiply these
two together and you can do this experiment
getting the pressures on small you find that this
the limit
it turns out to be a constant
independent of the gas
doesn't care where the gases you always get to the same constant
and that cost turns out to be
the function of
the temperature
the only function it is it doesn't cover the gas is the only case where
the temperatures
all right so now we have the
we have the makings of a good thermometer and temperature scale
the substance
the substance could be
and gas
that's pretty straightforward
so now we have
so i guess
with the property
now the volume of mercury or
color of
something which is
with temperature or resistivity in this case the property
is the value
the pressure times volume and similarly that's the property
the property is
the limit as a goes to zero of pressure comes along
measuring numbers now that the property were that's going to give us
the change in temperature
i mean it's some reference point
and celsius first used the boiling point of water
boiling point
one hundred degrees
celsius and the freezing point
one water
then we need an interpolation scale
how to go from
one reference point to the other
with this property
this property
which we're going to call fifty
in many ways you can connect the dots
i draw graph
and on one axis you have this temperature idea of temperature with reference point zero
freezing point of water one hundred degrees
for the boiling point of water
and i've got
on the y axis about property of fifteen
has some value
grosse pointe equals zero
let's get some value right here
there's another value connected to this property here when t is equal to one hundred
a reference point
now there are many ways i can connect these to points
the simplest way
is to draw straight lines
linear interpolation my lies not so straight
right here
you could do a different kind of like two
what about this
i would be perfectly fine interpolation
we choose to have
about the better choice
that really stands out to be very
interesting and really important
to connect these two points together in a straight line that
has to intercept
the x axis at some point
now what does it mean to intercept the axis here it means that the value
of fifty
for this temperature
is zero
that means that at this point right here
what is it
that means the pressure and volume
because you
but i guess
here below
this temperature here
this quantity p times the
would be negative
is that possible
and we p negative
to some
because you something on this equality
and in the chamber
and now
some here
you the size
the fix it
the of the fix subspace right
which is this
now using the relation between the number of cosets
the number of cosets and the size
all of the
of the group
and the core sets
transform this you get this is using the orbit stabilizing
stabilizing relations
which gives you this right
using this relation
you get
and here it is g can
because of
depend on anything
and this
you can break this some here
which is the sum of all no x
you some these separately like for all omega that belongs to an orbit
o object
of x the big space x is composed of of orbits
and for all search and
such an orbit you some all x inside the orbit
so this thing here gives you here is the norm norm of the size of
the size of the
so this some he gives you be
and this
you just got this party and
move due to the other side
you get the
of all
of all of it
is the mean because it you go there
the size of the
one of the
fixed points
what the meaning scientific
six point for all elements of g
so that's the proof of the
the orbit counting theorem
and if you look at the shape of these
you're going to see some real some familiarity with
the expression for the part a partition function
i will show
some some more of these relationship
so what we we did here
what you can do
you can
you can number just number there ways you can you can
color cube
an element
number eight then you get k and
different ways
you can do um
refinement refinement
you can do with this is not allowing simple edge edges of this structure to
the same color
this and structural refinement
so in this case for example it's there is the the
problem of graph coloring when you cannot put up to two neighbors with the same
so this would be the proper colorings of the graph
and the answer for that for these numbers is given by a polynomial
this chromatic polynomial which looks quite or polynomial for
this case here
this is a refinement
involving symmetry which was what we did
and dances this by inside iran
remember that the leading the leading term has these order
so you can count the colorings
up to the action of g
the answer was that
you can have more can have two things together
which would be the
g or of its
the nice trajectory is structurally
strictly we find in coloring
so you would have g is an outer morphism group that structure in our case
here with the structure was cube
and the g is the group g was that the group of automorphisms automorphism is
the group that
preserves the structure
so all
our stations that that
of the cube
so this would be you know
the action of the group in in cuba where the sides
cannot have the same color
so these are more complex problem this was
so by a
cameron in two thousand six is quite recent paper
this other one here it's a
a generalisation of the chromatic
and this one is related to
a physics problems called the potts model
and it's clear
a relationship is only
it's only clear the relationship of this with the partition function of the
of the
the bottom although if you transform
to this the potts model to this fourteen cancelling representation then it's clear that the
think of this surface which is the surface for a particular to blackboard
as having the constant phase
of the way
it means that for instance that the
vector is pointing in your direction and has reached the maximum
it would also have released maximum you
so we go through one complete cycle
two pi radians from italy that's the definition of wavelength
now in one period
this wave moves from here to here
in that same amount of time
this way if you move from here to there
so i will give this year
name as i've done before
and i call that l
of c
and so it is immediately obvious
by the definition of phase velocity
that the phase velocity
in the same direction
must be lz
divided by
by lambda
i'm c
it goes from here to here
with the velocity seen
but he goes much further in the same amount of time so now
that must be
time signalled not equal see time c
for larger than c
and this by the way in that follows from the geometry
it's also came
divided by king of the time see
that is larger than the phase velocity is larger than c and i have discussed
the issue
at length before
now look at what this wave is doing the weight here
these waves hit the wall
and they don't reflect of the war
well try to
thank you see that
so they reflect off the walls
they come back this way
and then
they reflect of the wall again
and so these waves
with zigzag
she che she slowly work their way through the gap
in this direction
you can immediately see therefore that the speed with which they work their way through
the gap in this interaction must be less than c
because when they go from this point eight
all these forms
in that same amount of time
in the same direction they only go from b to d
and so the group velocity
in the z direction
is then
divided by eighty
time c
and that's
and that follows from this geometry
that equals
k of c
divided by k
i'm seeing that is less than c
that would be less than c because you can just see
how difficult it is for his wave that reflects
to work its way
through in the same direction
we discussed earlier and i explained that using the
analogy was waterways that hitting the shore
that a phase velocity larger than c has really no meanings
in fact the consequence is that the water slides on the wall
everywhere at the same moment in time
however the group velocity
what is that what did i do wrong
just me
thank you very much
thank you very much this is larger than zero
now what you
it's not my day
this what you want
thank you
all right
so notice that in this specific case
the product of group velocity and phase velocity happens to be c square
special case is not always the case
sparse signal recovery problem and and so on
you have to be able to prove it establish conditions under which the matrices that
are involved in computer vision problems how are a properties
if they don't then you're just doing in l one thing and there is no
guarantee that you will become so if i have the errors them in a particular
way that are concentrated in some places so forth we can show that are few
doesn't work on sometimes you can show property known as IP one which is slightly
weaker works out so
that is the bar
we cannot simply take the
regularisation problems that we see in computer vision and hope that it was going on
for that so that we have additional what to do in terms of
showing that the matrices involved here here have some more a kind of IP properties
in RIPRIP one and so on then you can claim that i'm really
you know getting the reconstruction so that's the
the second difference
the definition of compressive sensing problem in computer vision problem OK now we have very
very interested in looking at this paper it appeared in family but these days you
know once it is accepted can put up on the web and so on so
you get to know these
papers even before
they appear in print now
he held this this this work well i suppose you have to be a is
the at training image class and of course this paper is is
is given as the sparsity induced method for face recognition is know face recognition we
have a lot of methods PCA LDA elastic graph matching and then itself cautioned images
and and this is a whole bunch of images first two
you may insert a whole bunch of approaches but still image based face recognition problem
so this is no tax right it says if you have a
the idea is that i did the training image in the eye class then make
a matrix like this and then you write the test image you know as combination
combination of everything that you have seen before
OK so you can rewrite this in this way if you put all the images
in the article are data classes then you will see corresponding to the i in
image i mean way belongs to the i class then only those coefficients are non-zero
and everybody else zero so this kind of has the paras structure to it
OK right
then one can argue that the number of classes is high the coefficient vector is
far on the components coefficients corresponding to one class matter and everything else should be
zero therefore you go on and put it on the spot construction problem now
so what they do is they
do this and i know quite efficient construction and compute statistical error why minus this
and take the one
they use the lowest error as the i cluster is a very simple
explanation of the paper from right
berkeley and also email from university of illinois OK
now of course have shown very good results on this database it's is kind of
difficult database because it information
variations and have shown no robustness to all sorts of occlusions disguise and so forth
when you do faith signal processing and computer vision right when you go from signal
processing computer vision the first thing that hits you
it's all the things that can happen to an image
although the original images
face may be mine
but then number of images that you will see of me
and pose variations and illumination variations are given way too many
and that's the probability
and then test when we compute the mass the maximum a posteriori which is just
so all the features the conditional probability so it's very easy classifier to train it's
very fast to run test time and this is basically the classifier that is sitting
inside of all of the public domain spam engine
when you download and you know bogo filter or any of these other publicly available
spam filters are all essentially doing naive bayes
with a few bills
and even they
providers like AOL
and microsoft
we are using naive bayes inside
now they might have a huge advantage which local client doesn't
which is that they can correlate messages across
recipient right
so f eighty million people and MSN all get the same exact message
not vastly increases the probability that space but that's not something you can tell just
sitting at your desk
and actually before you all can you know microsoft is really you know
my understanding of the way they do this is just actually stand compassion
there are other reasons to be concerned about microsoft not because the filtering spam
so this is the this is the graphical model for naive bayes
and this is just the classification rule
you'll see the naive bayes surely
exponential family model
where the sufficient statistics are just the vector of
variables for
of inputs for each other
three times
and again this is just the
equations the maximum likelihood derivations that shows you
how you can estimate each of these and i just put them in the notes
not because i want to go over the net
but just to remind you that there are these things that you need to enforce
these constraints with across multiple so
this is a little exercise you can go through
later that year
i think before we have taken break here
just for remind the year is the kent equivalent of naive bayes
we don't want to naive bayes
where you have the diagonal covariance matrix for each class but there's some
subsequent building on one-dimensional gaussians to each variable
for each class
that's the continuous equivalent of the naive bayes classifier
interestingly it has a quadratic decision surface not linear decisions
so you might think the naive bayes is like the simplest assumption you could make
but geometrically it's actually more powerful
fitting model with the covariances
full covariance but i think which is linear
but this is the equivalent in this is actually very good model should try this
if you continue to classify as very good
OK so let's take a break for just a few minutes here and
i don't have very much time left in the
trying to to give you a quick overview
maximum likelihood learning three
so i just skip over the the little bit notes on the progression
but i
i had you to take a look at that and
try to give you a very quick overview of
in fully observed models that are having more complicated structure than just the simple to
models we've been studying
we're not going to be able to come very much detail but i just want
to give you a basic idea
so i to talking about models that have changed structure
so so far we've been talking about the two models
or you might be employed in the class
just regression actually is
also model whenever i talk about these
what is it with
the variables have been changed
in your home or
and later
extend this change
so it's like this are called markov models are markovian models after the russian statistician
i was interested in the statistics of
sequential characters in russian poetry
the simple idea here is that the
think little machine where the next symbol next output depends on some number of previous
inputs are symbols
and the number of samples you
look back is called the order markov model so what i did wrong here this
simplicity is the first order markov
with each
no it depends only on the previous
and you can see figure is a very kind of simple sequence small
for example imagine that you know the the most famous application unfortunately this model is
intractible rockets
so you have measurement
a rocket going to or from the sky
these time take measurements and you have some physics model which tells you how the
rocket's position to evolve
that's a simple markov models are usually used for things that have sequential structure either
in space or in time
and so
the maximum likelihood estimation for
a simple markov model on those parameters are really really easy
you just take a window
kate plus one symbols if you have keep order markov model
so for example the first order markov model you just take a window too long
in the slide across each pair of symbols is training case
and we're trying to train this model
which is
conditional model
probability of xt
given xt minus one
remember each
variable depends only on the variable previous to entire space using t here just to
give you
and this is what i'm trying to train each adjacent pair of observations this change
training is small
and if you keep the order markov model so as you know second order markov
it would be the next given xt minus one and xt minus two and each
triple would be a training
it is slightly longer sequence measuring these windows and you collect all of them together
and then you to train this model just like you train a directed
model as though we're were only contain notes or t plus one more
again here the
maximum likelihood estimators are in the discrete case just counts
so for example if these things are binary you to say how many times did
over sigma
if we knew what
these signals were well we don't know what they are
there the i values of a transpose
sigma xi the i can values of a transfer
and for the symmetric matrix was symmetric that was a square and we didn't have
we have to go up to the base word level
to get the answer
so now i'm ready
these last minutes then this is something more about the
singular value decomposition
which i sort of intended to derive but
that's probably okay that we do
so now
because these signals are the key to the signal to the singular value decomposition so
and the lecture by
writing down that decomposition
talking about what we learn from it
so the singular value decomposition says any a
and by and
can be broken up into
orthogonal i used q
shall use u
and over here
and by
usually when the transplant
orthogonal matrix and in between times
in between will come diagonal matrix
by and so it's when i say diagonal it's got these signals these numbers sigma
one sigma two on the diagonal
and as far as they are nonzero
down to one i guess it'll stop
rank of the matrix
and the rest of the
the rest of the sky will be zero so really is diagonal
that's the
that's the and it comes from a transpose
a really totally linked to transpose
the eigen values
i can values are
sigma one where sigma two square
onto however many
non-zero once they are and then maybe some zeroes
i should have said
in this condition number stuff
what if the matrix is singular
well this condition number b in that case
so also what the what do you figure with this number turn up
explode two
if the matrix a is single
it will be
it won't be defined but basically all the info so i really singular matrix
totally of condition
are somehow we don't worry so much about those it's the ones that are nearly
the are extremely rare condition that we have to deal with them
those are the ones that we have to work with
right if i was totally so it was singular you say you give up on
a single being all released square
but what do you do if it's of course
you give up on this thing and go to least squares
here's what you do if you know the singular value decomposition
if the thing is nearly singular some of these may be the last one of
the last couple
i will be extremely small
and you're better off to wipe them out completely
so that's one way of kind of
well i don't know regularizing the problem or dealing with it is
it is to move due to a singular matrix
to the nearest thing matrix and and except the thing single instead of being on
the knife-edge of singularity but we're trying to deal with
as if it's not saying
from here this formula
you are
let's see what i've when i take this form i'm certainly throwing out directions
and in this case i'm thrown out the you intervene in looking at the signal
i mean that's right exactly so if i have a zero sum sigma that means
probably not
and so to distinguish between these things the key idea in causal modeling is
you think of the notion of interventions
and something called the do calculus or manipulation think of not just random settings of
variables but what happens to variables when we manipulate them to have certain variables the
certain values
it's a different thing
to say
what's the probability of s when we've observed
a certain value for
the yellow teeth variable
first is what's the probability of as when we're manipulated the yellow teeth
very well
OK so what this is saying is that
although there might be
statistical dependence between these variables
painting your teeth white will not cause you to stop smoking in general right
so this is the distribution here
when we manipulated the variable to have a certain value is different from the distribution
we observe it in nature
whereas in the other direction
the probability of having yellow teeth
whether you
in some sort of
sample of naturally drawn
individuals or whether you're smoking in a sample of individuals that were forced to smoke
let's say
by this manipulation very believe that can have an article i guess
these probabilities are going to be the same so
the difference in the two directionality is is that a causal relationships are robust to
interventions on the parents
if you intervene on the power and the distribution of the child will still be
the same as it was before whereas
in the other direction
if you intervene on the child the distribution of the parent will be different
that's all i'm going to stay in but causality is just this one slide the
key difficulty
in learning causal relationships
that if we only have observational data
we may have a hidden common causes
make it very difficult to know whether
if there is this statistical dependencies between a and b
whether a because b
or there was just some hidden common cause for both a and b
and so
the business of causal learning is really the business of dealing with
discovering these hidden common causes are controlling for these hidden common causes by doing randomized
experiments for example things like that
i have one slide on what to do with undirected models
anything i favour undirected models also holds for factor graphs in general
the problem of parameter learning and structure learning in undirected models is just considerably
more nasty for directed models
the reason for that is remember an undirected model is represented in terms of
the product over
set of variables
i normalize
and what i've done is i've explicitly written which
components of this distribution depends on the data the parameters of the distribution
so each of the functions here has some parameters
then the normalizing constant we also have
dependency on those parameters
remember the normalizing constant is the sum over all possible settings of the variables of
the product of these functions
the problem with undirected models is that computing the normalizing constant is computationally intractable for
general undirected models so unless you're graph is the nice treaty or something like that
computing normalising constant
are grows
that may come in handy is the one that i have already there
he equals
feel free
divided by the potential difference
which in terms of the plate area
is a and actually non-zero
divided by the
times kappa
let's call this equation number three
now comes my
so thirty
in the third demonstration
i am not going to disconnect my power supply
so now number three
i started out
with fifteen hundred volts
just like we did was number one
but the power supply will stay in their throughout never taken off
we start with the
because one millimeter
just like we did an experiment one
no glass
i'm going to charge it up just like i did with number one
and of course i will say that the and
i will show discharge
search of current
now i'm going to increase the
two seven minutes
now something very different will have from what we saw in the first experiment
the reason is that
the potential difference
it's going to be fixed
because the power supply is not
this connected to the power supply stays in place
look now equation number two
so that we can all change
and i increase the by a factor of seven
now the electric field must come down by a factor of seven
so now only electric field
will come down
that's factor of seven
because i go from one millimeter
seven now electric fields
because d goes up
in case you're interested in in
the capacitance
the capacitance will also go down
a factor of seven
because if you look at this equation
kappa one
if i make the go up by a factor of seven
she goes down by a factor of seven
just look at this simple as that
so she must also go down by a factor of seven
nothing to do with dielectric
so q free
i must now also go down by a factor of seven
because if the potential different doesn't change
but if q free goes down by a factor of seven
by he goes down by a factor of seven q free must go down by
a factor of seven this goes down by factor seven this doesn't change
sort of free charge goes down by a factor of ten
and what does that mean
that means charge will flow
from the plates
away from the plates
and so my and it will not
i will tell me that charge is flowing from the plates
and so that handles
at hand there go
to the left
so as i open up
depending upon how fast i can do that
charge will flow
from the plates
the other direction is charge will flow off the plates
and that current
i will show you every time that i open it a little bit
it will
go to this direction
so let's do that first
no dielectric involved
keeping the power supply
connected so i have to go back for school
one millimeter
which is what i'm doing now
i have you this
since she to make sure that i don't short them out about one millimeter
i'm going to
connect the fifteen hundred volts
and keep it on
and as i charge and you will see d
current meter
the search to right right it always means we charge the plates
so there we go
but you see it i didn't see it because i had to concentrate
it goes like this
now charge we don't take
this connection graph connected with the power supply all the time
and now i'm going to
open up
and as i'm going to open up
potential remains the same so this voltmeter
doesn't give them it will stay exactly where is because fifteen on the ball remains
fifteen hundred novels
but now
we go as we open up we're going to take charge
the plates and so this expect to go
to the left every time
and that i give it a little tour i do it now
went to the left
good now again got two million three million four millimetres make it five millimetre
five millimeters six millimetres
and i finally end up
seven millimetres every time
that i made it large use all the
and go to the left every time i took charge of
so that
his demonstration number
why did i go to seven millimetres you've guessed it