of handwritten digits you've got a small number of digits
then we do have attributes i e pixel values
so it means that this matrix here will be right deficient
and this rank deficient then
it does not have a unique inverse
and so maximum likelihood methods are going to run into problems here on the other
there is no problem
because this overall matrix here
there's no
for right so it can be uniquely inverted and what in actual fact is happening
for those of you familiar with penalized likelihood methods are or regularisation methods is that
acts as a regularisation term
the data so that all of the information is is a is rank deficient
the overall information which also quantifies
are priors which defines the level of regularisation
there is no well defined and uniquely defined
let's just think a little bit more about this
the value of the prior variance
no clearly as the prior variance
tends to infinity
then this whole ten collapses to zero
and our
posterior predictive mean will
to the
maximum likelihood
and if you think about it
as as tends to infinity then basically what we're saying is that we have complete
so we're seeing we did no idea we have no idea of whether the coefficients
are going to be very large positively very large negatively as it with no idea
the completely ignorant
and that's the implicit assumption is made in maximum likelihood
we are only as
february plead ignorance about the
the distribution of the
the possible distribution of
model parameters
OK that's fine
no i mentioned yesterday that
the maximum likelihood estimate is an unbiased estimator
and for those of you who lost some sleep last night because you couldn't figure
out why it's an unbiased estimator graph in the laboratory this afternoon
and all of single-mindedness
but what this means then is that
the priors
right in our
posterior predictive mean
it means that we have actually introduced the bias and you have a biased estimator
no is this a good or a bad thing
well remember i mentioned two yesterday and you should always remember that all models are
right so the model that you end up developing for your PHD in which he
so lovingly spend lots of those trying to show that it makes predictions better than
anything else that's out there that model will be wrong
right the key thing is to make sure that it's useful
for the task at hand
so in that case then
it perhaps doesn't really matter that much
if you're estimator is biased
why well because you're using the wrong model so why have an unbiased estimate of
parameters of own model
what effect and does this prior half given that it will introduce some bias
on the predictive power
of the model well
let's look at this little charge here
so what i'm showing
is the likelihood of the data bytes so p of t
given x
and w
and on the bottom chart i'm showing you the predictive likelihood so that p
of t new
get the next year
along the bottom here i've got the value of alpha
so large value of alpha
corresponding to
potential unbiased maximum likelihood estimator and a small value of alpha
very biased and therefore very
so what we see
we see the data likelihood
more or less this pretty flat
as we
which our prior variance
and then of course
the data likelihood starts to drop
and of course that makes sense
i no no longer going to be getting the unbiased estimator which maximizes the likelihood
but again remember that what's important is the
the value and the goodness of predictions
so we see that as we move from the
the maximum likelihood estimator
then there comes a point for the predictive likelihood
actually is improved over the
the maximum likelihood estimators predictions and then of course it starts to decrease
and this for those of you who are familiar with regularisation well-known immediately mark this
to you know regularized loss functions where this acts as the regularizing coefficient and there's
a little sweet spot here
where your predictions are superior because of the optimal level of regularisation of your model
so this is exactly what the prime
is doing its in its
introducing a certain level
regularisation into model
so in actual fact if we were to employ
the bayesian framework then we can guarantee that is going to be some point where
our predictive likelihood will be superior to that obtained from
employ maximum likelihood
so what i've done in this lecture is introduced you to the bayesian framework which
most of you are probably familiar with
and i've shown you how to
assigning a prior distribution
on the parameters of the model
forces sitting called the assumptions of the preferences that you are you
you're making
posterior inference in the case of the linear model also falls through very nicely and
can textbook fashion
we can see that the
the loss of an unbiased estimator of n and defining the posterior actually has a
positive effect
and tens of
the quality of predictions that that we can make
right so that it was
are linear
i don't want to
introduce you to generalize model
problem more interesting one
for the relative entropy.
If we are in an euclidean space and
this are continuous distributions then we have
that representation in terms of
the density functions.
the reason why this is related to information theory, is because there is a logarithm there
and the reason why physicists like it is because it has units.
The relative entropy has units which inherits from the logarithm, from the basis of the
logarithm, and here I have listed, a bit tongue-in-cheek, some of the most famous units.
the logarithm
in information theory
you know when someone...when something is used by many many different people
who don't necessarily talk to each other, then what happens is that it ends
up having many names
and this is this is drawing from the seventeenth century with all the known names
relative entropy is not quite the same but
you know it comes close in the number of different names that it has received
over the years.
I have listed here some of them, the ones that would fit on one slide,
that you can easily read.
Now, a lot of them have the word information
and some of them of course have Kullback-Leibler. We'll
see what Kullback and Leibler have to do with this
but you can see already that there is a lot of flavour of
decisions, discrimination,
weight of evidence,
and so on.
And also there is this word 'divergence' that
happens also quite commonly. In fact
for most of my career I used to call these the divergence before converted to
relative entropy. I used to be very dogmatic, I refused to call it the relative
entropy because
Claude Shannon in 1948, in his paper,
he calls relative entropy something else. He says relative entropy (just a passing comment:
that then nobody else abided by that terminology), but he said the entropy divided by the
logarithm of the alphabet size
is the relative entropy.
But, anyway, then I converted, not too long ago, to the common
canon in information theory and I called it relative entropy. OK so the first appearance of
relative entropy is in this very important paper by Wald
where he
posed and solved the problem of
sequential hypothesis testing. The easier problem of non sequential hypothesis testing was only solved ten
years later, so he didn't actually gave it the name but you can see that
the denominator of this formula
this was the expected number of observations necessary for reaching a decision with a certain
you can see that in the denominator of that equation what we find is indeed the
relative entropy.
right about the same time
a very famous statistician came up with a symmetrized version of
relative entropy
which is now commonly referred to as Jeffreys divergence
and we would expect that
because we are kind of programmed to
think that
important quantities should be symmetric
so we are programmed to think that perhaps this is more fundamental
then the relative entropy
but in fact it's not: this is rarely useful, whereas
relative entropy in all its ugliness or asymmetricity turns out to be of
more enormous importance.
So the first formal definition and that's why it's
very frequently referred to as the Kullback-Leibler
so i think what i told you last time
he was
but that these two options for doing blind source stration
the one that uses high order statistics and the other one that uses second order
statistics and subsequent
simultaneous diagonalisation all gradient but you don't do the gradient descent
and i showed you this
this nice little cartoon
to remember ICA
allows non orthogonal projection linear projection
while i play this demo to you
i think it's fair
that you actually
you get the result of one of these i algorithms because
you know after we went through all this formulas should be able to hear the
quality of the result
so just to remind you
of what you've heard in the beginning when you
when you
try to
so the cocktail party problem there was
music instrument hidden
inside and
it was a factor of twenty smaller than the the amplitude
of the of the noise
i took this as an example because brain signals often are effective thousand smaller
the other brahmin brain signals of interest might be effective
thousand smaller than the usual things that are going on in the brain so any
any ideas
the music instrument could be
peter was one
it was from more
what about you
two guests
no i guess
any further guesses
true but that
brave one
any other brave citizens
OK so i just
clay is so so this is now with the temporal decorrelation algorithm it takes about
point one seconds with matlab
for this data
this is the result of one chance
but i think it's it's not the original signal demixing
and you see
once you like
but not quite so now you have changed the prior
i don't know with any bayesint talks later on somebody change the prior and you
can now easily here it
i OK anyway
so this is just
to read the ICA part
maybe skip you this
one of the things
but i want to report on now
joint work with with what you have another and this COI at from afar
and the idea
it is
so this is all we ask the question so
now that you have this issue of of really dozens of IC algorithm which one
should you be using
i mean in the end it's unsupervised learning so so how can you know
whether algorithm a or b does any good because you don't know the ground truth
and this is in particular important if you study things exploratory
lee so if you actually
i don't know what you're expecting
and so
so any any unsupervised learning algorithm will always give you
some answer so PCA will always give you some projections ICA saying of clustering so
but how can you actually do
SS the the
the quality of the solution that's what we're going to talk about now in the
context of ICA
maybe the the key question down here is of these
do the results that we get have any physical meaning so so we actually extracting
something that is of
of meaning
which is
difficult question and i'm certain that we haven't solved it but
is a technique that
that you can use
so what i mean by
assessing the reliability
are the quality of ICA projection i tried to make tools
so you've seen
this kind of distribution before so this is the two dimensional mixture
and you would like to find with ICA algorithms would like to find the projection
so you get this one here would like to know
what are the error bars of it
one idea
i i these results somewhat reproducible stable
so so because we don't know the ground truth we have to come up with
some criteria that that it gives us some information
that that might be useful in unsupervised learning and we take stability or reliability as
we call it as is the could here
and certainly
say if you have to if you have
a data distribution like this
i mean it's clear that any old projection will do
in this sense
four problem like this
you will find a lot of
different projections
that have very high
error bars so to say
and all of them are similarly good
there is no difference between them
and the reason is because this is the two dimensional subspace
so so so here i was talking about the one-dimensional projections but you could have
also subspaces as projections that are stable
so maybe this is
and in in this is in particular often the case in biomedical applications where you
this number
equals twenty
o point two jewels
so to kinetic energy
when down
you may say well big deal little bit of kinetic energy than one at one
point three jewels who cares about one point three jewels
it is a real big deal in physics that we tell you
and i can pretty i can make you appreciate that it is a real big
deal by doing the following
i don't change the masses
but i just going to change the direction
of the impact
here and one
and years and two
this species remain the same
the one
and this is really too
no change in the numbers except
that they go now
she had r
what is the momentum of a particle number one
well that is envy
times five is plus five remedies is increasing directional x
so the momentum is plus five
what is the other one
that is two thousand three ninety six
this is minus six
so what is the total
the total momentum of given the magnitude
equals minus one
the magnitude is one of course in the momentum
i leave this off
we will call the minus one because it's the one dimensional problem the momentum before
is in this direction it's minus one
so what now is the prime they stick together
they are
and afterwards i'm not even sure
whether they go this way or this way yes i am sure
because the momentum is in this direction
so i predict
the one primarily in this direction
so this now equals
in one class and two
time the new v one prime
well and one percent two is one plus two weeks three kilograms
so you see
the that's the one prime
equals minus one thirty meters per second
the whole system now goes off with one hundred meters per second in this direction
the kinetic energy before has not changed was twenty one and a half jules right
that is independent of how i collided with each other
what now is the kinetic energy
after afterwards
this is a great tragedy
because now you get one half
the sum of the masses which is three
times this small number square
because with these created right
and now
there is only o point
rules that
almost all can energy and kinetic energy
has been
so what you see here in front of your eyes the kinetic energy can be
the momentum cannot be destroyed in the absence of external forces
kinetic energy and momentum is appalling different things the momentum of indivisible particles that change
but the net momentum did not change
but the kinetic energy was
destroyed i can just forty kinetic energy completely if i want that i can arrange
collisions so that all kinetic energy
has been removed
suppose this particle
has amassed five
and the velocity is one that is my shorthand notation
and this particles
has amassed one
but it has a velocity
the momentum of the system is zero
plus five in this direction
five in this direction but you bet your life the kinetic energy after the collision
the children we agree that they we expect that was built on it
momentum afterwards must therefore still be zero
internal forces don't matter no matter what happens kinetic energy
so the whole system
and afterwards you have here the sum of the total mass and it just stand
because i told you
that they are going to stick together i used glue
if you have a car collision
and two cars in each other
and i compared the situation
just before the collision
with just after the collision two cars
and one has the speed in this direction other has the speed direction
and they hate each other
and they stick together the given one big clump this before
and i can give them some velocities
this is the speed of one
and this is the speed of the out of the two
afterwards you see something like this
the prime
there's a rack
impact time is so short
that the change in momentum due to friction
with the wrote
that would be an external force friction which the wrote
but that can be
ignore it is negligibly small
because it
there's a huge internal
four going on
plans on the other hand the other slams one there's even fireworks metal scrapers over
richard but that's internal friction low friction with world
so momentum is approximately conserved if we can
picture from the road during impact because the impact time is so short
so let him be
carr was mass and one
and here is the other carbon mass and two
and we'll make it the two dimensional problem because we've seen only one dimensional problems
let's make it
two dimensional problems
so this is the
direction for this car
and that's a
this is the direction in which the car was going
velocity v two
and tragedy has its
this is the place
where they're going to collide
in one direction and what will be the speed after the conditions
i only compared just a moment before it
we just a moment after the hit
what comes later is a different story
when you have four the wreck
clearly is going to slide on the road and then there is an external force
reduces friction which will slow it down
just doing impact likely
the two reasonable approximation momentum will have to be
and so on
what is the momentum
of this one
well this may be the momentum of this one may have a very small mass
small speed
and what is the momentum of this one
while this may be
the momenta of number one
and this could be the momentum
of number two
the net momentum is the vectorial some of these two
which is this
that is the total of the system that is never going to change the before
and after the collision
exactly the same
and therefore
if you notice angle theta
you know PN one and you know p two
then you can calculate
in one direction
the object
going to slides
but of course you can also calculate then
velocity after the impact
because this total momentum
must be
the sum of the total of the true colors mass of the two cars
and the prime
so you can calculate everything and that's what the police is doing when they find
rex on the road
they actually use the
the following content is provided under creative commons license
your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses visit
MIT opencourseware OCW that MIT that EDU
we're ready to begin
the fifth lecture and glad to be back thank you for
entertaining my colleague james miller
so today we're going to continue where he started
namely what you talked about was the chain rule
which is probably the most powerful technique for extending
the kinds of functions that you can differentiate
now we're going to use the chain rule in some rather clever algebraic ways
the topic for today
is what's known as implicit
implicit differentiation is the technique
that allows you to differentiate a lot of functions you didn't even
i know how to find the four
it's a technique
let's wait for a few people
sit down here
physics k
more physical
will take a break you can get those after class
all right
we're talking about implicit differentiation and i'm going to illustrated by several examples
this is one of the most important and basic formulas
we've already learned pathway
namely the derivative of x two of power
is a times x to the a minus one
now what we've done so far
we've got so far
in is the exponent zero plus or minus one plus or minus two et cetera
you did the
integer positive integer powers
on in the first lecture
and then
professor miller told you about the negative powers so what we're going to do right
it is we're going to consider the exponent which are rational numbers
ratios of integers so is m over and
and and and are integers
right so that's our goal
right now and we're going to use this method of implicit differentiation in particular
it's important to realize that this covers the case m equals one
and those are the inference so we take the one over and power
we're going to cover that right now
along with many other examples
so this is
our first example
so how do we get started well we just write down a formula for the
function the function is why
physical access to the power animals and
that's what we're trying to deal with
and now there's really only two steps
the first step
take this to the this equation to the and power
so right it as y to the end
is equal to XTM
right so that's just the same equation rewritten
and now
what we're going to do
it is we're going to differentiate
so we're going to apply
the idea x
to the question
why is it that we can apply to the second equation not the first equation
so maybe i should call these equations one two
the point is that we can apply to equation two
now the reason
that we don't know how to differentiate next over and that's something we just don't
what we do know how to differentiate integer powers
those are the things that we took care of
so now we're in shape to be able to the differentiation
so i'm going to write it out explicitly over here
without carrying it out just yet that by dx y to the end
is equal to divide the axon
access to the m
and now
you see it
this expression here requires us to do something we couldn't do before yesterday namely
this why is a function of x so we have to apply the chain rule
so this is the same as
this is by the chain rule now
d d y of y to the end
times DY
and then on the right hand side we can just carry it out you know
the formula it's an extra minus
right so this is our
our our scheme
and now you'll see in a minute why we went with this
so first of all there are two factors here one of them is unknown in
fact it's what we're looking for
but the other one is going to be unknown
quantity because we know how to differentiate why to the with respect to y
that's the same formula of the letter has been changed
so this is the same as
all right underneath here and widely and minus one
new idea
is equal to
next to BMI
if you like
the nine calculus part of the problem remember the nine calculus proc part of the
problem is always
the message you're part of the problem
so we want to figure out this formula this formula the answer over here which
which may be off-putting box now
as is expressed much more simply only in terms of x and we have to
do now is to solve for y dx using algebra and then solve in all
the way in terms of x so first of all we solve for y dx
i do that by dividing the factor on the left-hand side
so i get here
next to the minus one divided by n
y to be n minus one
and now i'm going to plug in
but this is an over and this is access to the minus one
now over here i'm going to put in for y
access to the m over n times and minus one
so now we're almost done
but unfortunately we have this mess of exponent that we have to work out
i'm going to
right it one more time so i already recognised the factor a out front
that's not going to be a problem for me and that's what i'm aiming for
here but now i have to encode all of these powers so let's just write
it out it's an minus one
and then it minus the quantity and minus one times m over
all right so that's the of exponents applied to this ratio
here and then we'll do the arithmetic
maybe just over here
in the next board
so we have here and minus one minus one minus one
over and
is equal to
this one
and if i multiply n by this i get minus m
and the second factor minus minus that's a plus
and it's less m over and
so all together
to what
don't why particular water companies had been supplying those those particular individuals
and some of them were drinking water was contaminated by cholera patients and someone else
when he completed this work and there's actually a lot of shoe leather involved he
was able to show
that the individuals who drank from one water company for more than eight times more
to get cholera and the ones who drank water from the other water company and
this was very very good quasi experiment a way of looking at observational data to
be able to identify
cause and effect
we provide a good strong evidence for
causality in general still pretty rare topic within our field
if you look at the
o work in in causal discovery that's done in general you look at knowledge discovery
and you put them together only about four percent of the papers or in that
overlapping region now it's still four percent that's pretty good actually several papers at this
have been about causality
there is a very nice paper on using a technique called doubly robust methods for
adjusting for covariance to try to identify the cause and effect there's a paper that
will be delivered to my warnings on causal discovery algorithms for linear models and a
student of mine presented a paper at the
workshop on social media analytics on quasi experimental designs for analyzing data from social media
this kind of work of identifying cause and effect
it means that we actually need to do that in the kind of more complex
representations that i've been talking about
and key factor key problem of doing this is disentangling two kinds of effects what
sociologists call social influence and homophily that is
due to people have similar attributes
because they're influencing each other
what do they become friends because they have similar attributes
and it turns out that this gets a fundamental problem of relational learning in terms
of causality in the sense that we only look at
individuals who are connected by some relationship and if the variables on those two individuals
cause that relationship then we are conditioning on a common effect and that will induce
dependence between the attributes of those two individuals
whether we like it or not because we don't look at pairs that are not
connected so is essentially a serious issue being able to determine conditional independence in almost
all work on relational learning
and this this was identified in in paper that we published recently my student march
mayor it's the first author
that was the triple in the summer
there's another issue which is has to do with feedback in these systems in causal
systems essentially all interesting social systems have feedback but feedback systems violate the key assumption
of many
causal discovery algorithms and that faithfulness that's this assumption bad weather
causal dependencies can cancel out and make variables appear to be conditionally independent when they
are actually not in most systems this didn't appear to be a problem but in
feedback systems with homeostasis system is trying to maintain some level it could be directly
making two variables have equal effects and thus we would have trouble being able to
disambiguate cause and effect the system
the talk a little bit about automated discovery about the thing that we're kind of
most about in this community
so what sort of automation that's no need starts no need for is going to
do this with these this wonderful computation available to him he needs to be able
to identify causality in highly complex systems and you'd like to learn a joint model
saying how do all these things interact with each other across space time and relations
unfortunately there's not a lot of work in this area we were as we start
to look at this in my group a little surprised and worried when we started
to work on it because it's been some relatively rough sledding for us and if
you know that
the does this that that does work and causal discovery in systems with space time
and relations please let me know about it or even just two of those those
i might have been working on algorithms to do that at least for relational data
in two thousand eight at this conference we published a technique of demonstration that it's
possible to algorithmically find quasi experimental designs
and that reply year we published a paper on relational PC with core algorithms for
causal discovery applied to relational data extended to relational data
amazing things that you have to ordinary
rational thinking
i think it's just the opposite
emotions are when you take a reasonably complex mind and turn off most of its
nice features
for example when you're angry
what's the difference between
regular thinking and angry thinking
well you're turning off your slower process is so you can react faster
you're abandoning most of your long-range plans and goals
you don't bother to be politer diplomatic in fact you don't want to be because
if you look angry enough then that's a URI better get out of here
so it's a reasonably good way to get rid of people who were annoying you
also it turns on certain features and makes you
react more quickly
the first page of the book starts with this example
of somebody who's in love so to speak
i'm in love with a wonderful person she's unbelievably perfect
centre and then if you look
all of those look like they're positive statements
but in fact every single word there
it has a negative and it's showing that you've turned off some part of your
she has the form of this character well
i can't see anything wrong
most of my mind is stopped working and so forth
of of course these things are mysterious if you don't have a high level thing
the way to think about them
OK but now let's turn it the other way
if you say emotions are simple compared to forward
here's the trouble
i think
if you
looking at the stories
you'll find several hundred words to describe emotional states
but if you
look for words for thinking
as far as i know none of our languages have a lot of words for
that and yet
that's the most important aspect of psychology
it seems to me that the main job of psychology is to notice how does
the water persons critics had they recognise what kind of problem they were facing
and then how do they think about it
and here's a
i think in the book there's about thirty ways to think about
the analogy is
making plans simplifying situation
reformulating it
one way to solve the problem is to imagine a solution and
i run the simulation in your head like second world
second life
and so forth and
and so forth so everyone has
dozens of different ways to think
and generally we don't have names for these
and we don't talk about them
and what's happened as a result is that the popular
if you is that thinking is something like logic
in fact there is a part of your brain
which watches the thinking process going on
and tries to summarize it as a very simple kind of story and make it
but as far as i can see
this is sort of after the fact
when you tell somebody had to solve the problem
you leave out all the deadlines and all the heuristics that you try to say
well clearly this is that in this is one of those in
so logic is for cleaning things up and remembering just the
correct parts of the trajectory
OK so finally
we don't just solve problems the way
let's take a good example of this stanford robot
managed to
travel four hundred miles in the desert without
breaking down or
falling into gullies are
running into things it's reacting to the physical world and it's got a great library
ways to recognise physical situations
and how true
get out of them
we're through them
and that's fine
but in human commonsense thinking
the embodiment of the
connection with the real world is really quite remote
from the processes
that go on in your reflective thinking about yourself and about your problems
and it seems to me that
at any particular moment of time
your mind is working on at least six different levels
so you've got these instinctive reactions that
you can't even control
try holding your breath for ten minutes
and you learn things
and then
there's this wonderful project deliberative thinking
where you say if i did this that would happen
and if i did this that would happen
and now you do some
you know how the astronomers discover media's
four comments
by blinking two pictures
of the sky taken at different times
and if something move you'll see it going like this whereas the other stars
the stars they
i didn't change their position
stay there
well the great thing about the visual system is it only notices change
so your retina
this has a million gadgets that only recognise when something is turning on and off
three important results
for now
about these cosmic microwave background radiation
so fanciers and wilson so only a uniform glow knowledge became so and rather than
green but there's just you no poetic interpretation of it
the temperature of around three kelvin
and now
if you say
that these must come from when the universe became transparent so on you know
that in order to became transparent to the universe must have been about the temperature
of the three thousand kelvin then you know the distribution has been shifted by about
a factor of two thousand and therefore must come from russia
o five thousand
later on
and this goes to somebody that's missing the question the other day
the doppler shift from the milky way's motion
was seen
if i now
crank up the contrast
taken out of this is zero mode then something like that was seen that these
the galaxy is moving towards the great attractor six hundred and twenty kilometres per second
so the fact that we see something like that seems that tells you that the
cosmic background to find some sort of reference frame where the universe is emerging as
an isotropic and the cosmic background is isotropic because this is obviously not isotropic this
is because we know we are moving there is a big over banks in the
united sent out also in our galaxy is falling into that and therefore also the
satellite that is you know gravitational amount of our own galaxies follow
on in nineteen ninety two
some small perturbation was seen in the uniformity of the cosmic microwave background and this
perturbation at the level of about one part in ten to define
so you have to crank up the columns strand called contrast much more in order
to see something like that and this was seen by the cobe satellite
remember that we so before we
if there are some small perturbation that they can grow under gravity and conformal galaxies
and we've seen qualitatively how that may happen where are those perturbations
well if they have at the very beginning i should see them
in the cosmic background and indeed the for ten years people kept trying to find
them and couldn't find the cause well because if you don't postulate of the existence
of dark matter remember that the perturbation in body and grow less because the body
are coupled to the photons for a very long time and when are coupled to
the photons perturbation can't grow
and they can start growing only afterwards but if there is that much of that
matter can forget about the fact that the body couple to radiation in addition to
only acoustic waves the perturbation in matter growing they can grow for a longer period
of time so they can be bigger
and by the time the body was released from the they see others that matter
over density but the fall into that matter density and so the bionic perturbation can
grow fast
and so
you can leave which is more than perturbation in the cosmic background and still form
galaxies today
if you
if you put that matter in there
that's another evidence of the fact that we need something like that matter and that
does not behave like five
in two thousand six and another prize physics so went to the to the eye
of the colby satellite one by to show
that the cosmic background is black body as it would have expected if he was
this radiation from the primordial fireball
and to the other by to show that there were perturbations and the calls are
from the properties of this perturbation we could learn a lot about the geometry fate
the cosmic background is a perfect black body in the early seventies here and less
than the width of the black body because in order for you to show you
the error but i have to show you the four hundred sigma about
so what does this perturbation come from and how is that we see the perturbation
i'm not going to go into all the equations but i'm going to try to
give you some sort of physical intuition why that
so if you have some small in each
density perturbations or you no additional potential well
then you would imagine than four tons owned by audience would accumulate
in the valley
you see that for something like that and therefore when you projected this guy is
something like that remember this is the emission from our own galaxy that this is
not primarily to cut these out what's primordial ooze out here
so it's a little bit like you know lot in the surface of the earth
and showing valley and mountains this kind of block
but we see them like temperature
because if you have a potential hill
then the four don't get the blue shifted they look after
if you have the potential well before they get redshifted and they look called
and so you can make diet combined is between the
perturbation in the gravitational potential which are given by
they over densities
to the perturbation in the temperature
so we see them like temperature and so
on a larger scale this is what happened on smaller scales things get more complicated
and this should be an admission fee
because by body for the world cup berlin photons also laid like sound waves in
the four body and soul also couple to them
and so you can see you have like something like that you have the potential
to created by all the matter and then you have the default onto a couple
of ideas and the bias represented by these two masses
and so so what
these forward with an oscillator and the effect of gravity and pressure from from the
for now
there is a time
dalton john
dalton with his breath of fresh of interest
he also
was the first individual to document color blindness in human beings
OK to call
color blindness darkness
we're getting ready for medical school already
all right
OK but
what i want you to recognise here is the best and often
i didn't actually do any of the experiments himself
although from what i know of him i think he could have done the experiments
but rather he was aware
of these seemingly disparate observations made by YPA and loyal and true
and he just said well you know
if i take those observations
and i use this framework will then i can understand them
they make sense within this framework
and this is the powerful approach inside a lot of science progresses this way it
is that there's this collection of
seemingly disparate observations and all of a sudden
somebody comes along and sees an organising principle
in all of those observations and puts forth and these postulates
that's would often did here
now of course these postulates were accepted and immediately
and rightfully so called because they were just postulate they needed further substantiation
and they further substantiation came
in terms of the work by the
this gentleman joseph gains back
the law
of combining volumes
it came by
the work of this gentleman this gentleman is more warranto romano armadale carlisle god rules
and of course
you can all read italian so you can read what i understand here right just
as well by the gas under the same conditions of temperature
lead to the the same number of molecules you know you can read italian there
and further substantiation for this idea of an
and the discreteness of matter
came from this gentleman ludwig boltzmann
gas kinetic theory who
propose that well you know pressure
there must be due to be the atoms that are moving around hitting the walls
above that's all those in
give rise to the pressure is exerted on the walls of the vessel
and then finally
it took this gentleman
ten are when it took his statesmanship
because what can is eroded and now this is the later eighteen hundreds or so
we can is outdated
is that he
got the scientific establishment at the time
and the scientific establishment at the time of course is this
a small group of pale males
but he got them
less than two dollars a time series
and then the the ensuing experiments have got
and i gave exact eccentric cetera
and finally he
got them to say yes there's something right
about the atomic theory of matter the idea being at
it was made up of discrete
particles called animals or atoms
we of course you can actually image
individual atoms or molecules
and what you see here
there are an array
of the twenty eight c molecules
and these twenty eight feel molecules are arranged
in the form of a little man
a woman
i let you figure it out but
these are
molecule sitting and flat surface
and so each one of these orange here
is a molecule
OK so i'm going to start with if you like what
how does the statistical learning community approach
what they're trying to do in
understanding learning systems
so the basic point is that this is a statistical one clearly has the
the title suggests but as with any theory the aim is to try to model
some phenomena and in this case it could be
it's part real part of official real but the data may be real but the
actual algorithms are artificial but it is the phenomena
you're trying to understand what's going on
it's the nature of science is is is is is exactly this you know you
have some phenomenon in the world and you try and write down the theory which
explains that
the behaviour of that system and the aim of course of doing that is is
in one sense just the intellectual enjoyment of having an understanding of the world but
you know more practical approach is in order that you can predict how they will
perform and hopefully get to perform that that's exploit your knowledge in terms of
actually improving the algorithm in improving whatever you're trying to do
so the series is always
to try and support practice and there's always this interleaving between theory and practice and
more active than interleaving the better i think about it
the theory and practice
i should emphasise right away statistical learning theory is just one approach to understanding these
learning systems
and the other approaches include bayesian inference that speak about the inductive inference
statistical physics to traditional statistical analysis
all of these have slightly different emphases and
different premises in the way they approach
and different strengths so i'll mention that looks like
each theory makes assumptions
about the phenomenon of of learning so if you're trying to model something your immediate
task is to abstract away from the details of the particular into the level
but you can actually
make some conclusions
and derive some results about
and that abstraction you're gonna lose something for sure
and the critical thing is to choose your
modeling at a level that captures the essential and doesn't lose critical elements of your
the the thing you study
if you abstract too far you lose you may get a beautiful theory but it
will no longer be applicable
and each theory abstracts in its own way and so
you know to say one theory is better than another is always very risky thing
to say
i think it's a case of looking at you know one theory may be more
applicable in in these type of situations because the abstraction it makes is appropriate and
captures what's going on in that situation this theory may be more appropriate in this
situation where the actual conditions slightly different
so i think you know to sort of get into turf wars about bayesian and
frequentist statistics seems to be very
short-sighted and really what we should be trying to do is understand when one works
when the other works
so on that note
i think that
you know hopefully is part of this course will begin to see what
the the modelling that statistical learning theory does
contribute and where it can be of use and i certainly don't want to make
a claim that it's the be all and end all of understanding learning by any
stretch of the imagination but hopefully something
to bring to the table of
of this
very interesting subject
so now getting into a little bit more
down into the particular approach of statistical
approach to learning
i'm going to simplify this point but i i think it's
a framework that will be
very generally applicable in this in this approach
the assumption that you typically begin with is that the data is generated by an
underlying distribution so it's sort of probabilistic assumptions about
the way the data arises
and the
the himself actually has very little access
two information about the distribution may have some prior knowledge
some but not enough
to do what i bayesian would do which is to build a model of the
so you're making the assumption that you have
very little knowledge about the way the data is generated
for instance if we are trying to classify
tissue samples to decide whether the cancer cells or not cancer cells
there there is a distribution
of the
the way the cells look
from a particular
so typical healthy cell looks in this sort of way and if you generate a
typical healthy so you get an example of that
probability distribution typical
cancerous cells
look this way and if you generate one from the
probability distribution of cancer cells you can
an example of that distribution
so this is the assumptions behind now course this is already making
maybe some
two strong steps of course this is you know as soon as you make these
assumptions you may lose something in
and that's the price you pay for making theory
but that's the that's the approach is taken
in a sense this assumption of the distribution subsumes everything
that we might hope to know about the processes of the natural artificial world study
now that's not be true in the end because we're going to make
in the way we design our learning algorithm and so on we're going to incorporate
on knowledge about
the the world problem was starting
but since the distribution contains all the
the real information
the problem in learning is precisely the fact that that distribution contains information that we
have no way of accessing directly we have no way of getting too if you
like an explicit formula for the probability density function of the distribution rather than that
we give
a rather poor
training sample
four training set which is just a sample
of points generated according to the distribution of the classical
situation the training example now i've given an example here with the input output pairing
probably going to focus mainly in this course on classification
so one would think otherwise is being
label indicating membership of the class or not
but of course in general they could be a real valued outputs or they could
vector valued outputs or they could be
it could be just no output and just a clustering problem for example where you
only have
to be an input to your system
but as an example here we have in the past you know input
it's a classification outputs x one y one two x and y
and again the assumption we're going to make it again this is already making another
assumption is that this
sample is generated independently and identically according to this distribution p
so in a sense we getting
i can do the same thing
scroll back one slide
see here
we have the summation otherwise
if i have seen orthogonal here the travel we
so only for the fairly anything interesting happens
so you can write your theta given x
and the state of
parallel given x
so what does we basically
he argued that first transistor don't depend on the orthogonal component
now for the last term
everybody knows taggers
so can somebody tell me what the northeast squared is
as expressed in terms of the power of the orthogonal
and want is
a very good
so the sum of c's apparel square
plus the total square
so what this means we get an optimisation problem in something that the pain
on the on the parallel terms
and they just plus some norm squared the orthogonal to
OK how that minimizes the the sum of all terms adjusted zero
this doesn't affect anything else
in other words
the optimal solution will be just the apparel
even though i don't know exactly what it is
i know that this is all that matters
and that's the celebrated representer theorem
well i don't know is compressed about ten pages of massive
into two minutes
it wasn't very difficult just orthogonality
why this really cool
because they say that
the cardinality of the set y
is finite
then we have a parametric optimisation problems
this is really great news here
we start with a nonparametric
as looking problem
and we realized from this era
that actually things aren't that bad at least we can write about in terms of
we don't have to hack or approximating this is exact
and then just have to optimize way
in fact also if y
is of infinite cardinality princes Y's are
then also lost
but then it will depend largely
on your sufficient statistic so will actually encounter the case for regression with this
and we can still expand things nicely
but OK then you have to use a little bit more skills
any questions on the representer theorem right now
OK then let's move on
so very simple theorem
very beautiful
OK so
what i should say this will see the has to be in the span of
the fourth example mars
so i can write it this way
well in that case the inner product between theta
and for fixing y
i can express it in terms of inner product
so i get out while i k and x y and x and y
prime actually
make prime here and has to be a prime here
and then
well it compute an all-seater
norm is just some over
while for j like prime nor that you
so you've probably seen this thing before
you've seen before and i support vector machine
it's just that there
this kernel here had a very simple form
so you've probably seen something like
why i
y j
fixed on
in some support vector optimization
now this is actually kernel
in the wise times are currently exists which is already
so this is like
some kind
in why i
and y j
and this is the very common x so this is overall some kernel
x on i
why i
and x on i xj
one j
so this is a very nice because at least it shows that some time before
comes back again
OK then look partition function
c with
figured out how to compute that is able looking at the forest
they just some of this
well defined number of ways
we know how to compute this
and one it might be computationally mace
you might have to use tricks that efficiently at least we know how we can
do this in principle
we've made a giant step here
got from very simple
unconditional models
over night for instance
ten different opinions
or from a normal distribution or some distribution of something else it's actually fairly boring
and fairly standard statistics textbook from say
the sixties
something that's really cutting edge
namely a conditional estimator
in one of the best once they can find
haven't done very much all of ten is just conditioning
it's surprising that state until now for people to realise that
well it's a bit
more to it than meets the eye so that the stick
o thing called gauss in processes
and if you
have you ever heard of agustin process basically
OK so he's really handwaving explanation what stochastic processes and it will make all the
mathematicians here cringe
basically think of noisy function in every time you evaluate it might tell a slightly
different answer
the stochastic processes
the normal distribution well what you need in order to determine what do you mean
the covariance
if you got process what you need
need the mean function and covariance function
that's all you need
in fact we make life even easy was it the mean to syria
let's just assume that state is normally drawn
i can look
there are many
so here
what is
you know
it's one of our
we call
thank you all
we are
by the
alright one
according to the law
world war
i will raise
for example
are you sure
and even
we're here
o five or p
he always
we were all
in our
i i always
well one
i e
i was right
you i can be a
o of
he he
who you
the and
applied to text documents works quite well in there might be something about text that
makes that the case
so let's spend a minute just thinking about what would be the best-case and worst-case
so i think the easiest way i know to think about this is to imagine
that we instead of having
a bag of fifty thousand different words and fifty thousand features match we just had
one feature
suppose we only look for it were kind of telford spam we only look for
the word nigeria
no other word
and we count how many times nigeria occurs
you know
OK so here's
that could be are half our feature
number of
nigeria occurances
and now suppose that i look just among positive examples of spam
and i true
but sister graham or
the probability that a randomly drawn word will be
will be nigeria
given that
let's try given that it is spam
so i may have some kind of distribution like this
because spam equals yes
and i have a different distribution maybe fewer occurrences of the word for example
in this case where spam equals no
and if that's the case
if that's the case
the naive bayes modelling assumption
is going to make this kind of one labelled data be wonderful for us
on and i don't know whether you discussed this particular fact about naive bayes when
you discuss the first time so you guys were gotta help me on
i just train a naive bayes class of fire
we no labels at all
suppose the run at the EM process but i have zero initial labels
i just make up random parameters to get started
and i have those random parameters signed labels and retrain and we estimate you know
just go back and forth the process that's a very good
in very commonly used clustering algorithm
what it tends to do is find the two finds two groups of data that
are easily distinguished
it's called mixture model clustering it's very common
method of doing clustering effective on do document clustering that's a great algorithm for doing
if we have data like this
and we were to run clustering algorithm with zero labelled data we would expect to
find these two clusters
they would just kind of happen
on especially only had this one feature
so the data is very nicely clustered even with zero labels into these two clusters
and now suppose i have old two labels one positive and one negative
but maybe i have
a doctor right over here which is positive and one right over here which is
but it's very easy
once we know what the clusters are to say oh this clusters and this clusters
positive and that's essentially what the EM process is going to do
thank you
so as long as we have a data set
would be clustered anyway into groups
that happen to correspond to the classes were interested in classifying
like in this case if this clusters into spam and not we're golden
here however
that same data set
if i were interested in some other classification function like
was this authored on tuesday or wednesday
the clusters i'm going to get out of course will still be these two clusters
that if i give one labelled data but that those two classes is simply probably
irrelevant to the classification of whether was tuesday or wednesday
thank you
so my point is this
this kind of use of one labelled data can be very helpful
you can kind of see with the nigeria spam example why
but i had this one more the clusters that'll come out from the labelled data
will be just the grouping that i want in the only thing that i'll need
labelled data for label which cluster is positive and which is negative and i don't
need many labels to do that
on the other hand if the naturally occurring clusters in the data set
don't happen to correspond to the labels that i'm interested in
the signing by my classified
some labelled stuff in stop will be downright misleading
to oversimplify a little bit
that's actually the structure of the data that this
messages let bridging off of
and so i think one interesting
so how can we test given some document set whether
it's got this kind of structure
i think the best test is to run unsupervised clustering on the documents
take a few labels that we have
and see if the clusters that come out actually
different clusters capture different labels
in if so then we know that the naturally occurring
clustering structure of that data is at least
no consistent
with this naive bayes modelling assumption
and things things had the chance of working
in fact the situation a little more pleasant than i'm suggesting because
i can maybe extreme argument that what what if we have zero labels we just
do clustering then we better see that the clusters align with the classes such a
little better than that because
if you recall the EM process actually begins with some labels not with zero labels
and so the
clusters they get formed initially
not to do any progress we need to start with some definitions
we'll just called axon
as random variables
and it's not viable can be around a vector so can be
vector of robot
this small x is the big act is more tax are particular realizations of relevant
for example reliable
can be an image
an image can be around that
a general image
and in particular realisation of
for general image available is a particular image
for example the image of car
there are a lot of is is is is is the general
nine months
it's it's not the said well i don't want to go with technical basically of
invited is the function to give you
in this case
it's not who are in
particular elements of the sample space
but essentially you need to think of a random bible is
as the range of possible outcomes
and then one possible outcome as the realization that
for example the whether the bible is the weather
and the realization is whether is that
where this would
or whether is
um and the i but
the bible can be high
particular realization can be
one point eight meters one point five
around five essentially quantity
can contain several values
and we going to contact probability distribution
the simplest way you can think of it
now this kind of thing x here
is the set of all realizations this is
the set of all position the depose sample space
think of possible crime
if you went past client
there are no reliable is quite fast
x is the particular realisation had
is one active tail x
and this kind of graphic x is the set
hands and they'll
x subscript
random vector of all variables indexed by the set it was a is a subset
of the original set the index
so for example if i'm talking about
but the my revivalist
my random vector is the weather in australia
now i want to talk specifically about the weather in new software
so the weather in new south wales is the subvector
of the entire vector of the
whether in australia
because it has many
this can be x
index a eight
this is the
notation for yourself
within this is group
x a tilde
is the rest what's not in a
it's the vector of all the other
of the weathering all the places other than yourself
the remainder initial they just carry on
so kindly graphic x a is this this
in the particular
subject to a
condition is technically the restriction of function of
the me
so you
constrained to them instead of having as domain
we can talk about arbitrary subsets of his original to me
given by the index set
yes is just to
just the same function gene into that article
p of that
c and this
so x no that x is the random violence is about can ever go
that's what we're talking so b of x can be
girls in distribution that's the probability
distribution on
one thing is run by the other thing i
so started this article is is all the
all the events in which the weather was clear
and we're interested in
this overlapping part here which is ninety percent of the time when the weather is
clear the time when paul revere also
just the over
again this vertical bars just syntactic sugar
this comic here
sorry this this work here
so i've written in english but what what it really means if you want to
formalise this is that for every point in this event space you can ask the
question you look function
clear at some the point this event space is the weather clear that one so
if you now nap this function you say what it return true
you get exactly this thing collapse the weather is clear in this section and it's
not clear over c start
and this comment here is a conjunction denotes conjunction so this is
this is common logic use common
this is what wins and the weather when paul wins and the weather is clear
picks out exactly the point
in this intersection
OK so what he's doing
is given a set of events
it's measuring the total probability like the area inside the ellipse or inside the intersection
of two surfaces that's what he does if you want to know how to do
this formally then take a formal probability course you measure theory
i don't want you to look for but i do want to do
a little bit about
what is the required properties of p
so the probability the empty set is zero
in other words something always happens you always get some of the total probability of
these rectangles the probability predicate says yes everywhere
is one
and everything else is in between so why is that because
when x is a subset of y
probability that is less than or equal to the probability one and so that means
that any set
like whether it's clear
that's that is bigger than the entities so it's got probability at least zero
and it smaller
four equal to the set of all
so it's probabilities at most one
so the curiosities what i would see if we got satellite like whether it's clear
which is a nonempty set
is its probability necessarily greater than zero
so some people think yes
the answer is actually know for technical reasons
if i throw my hand at this
at the screen this is the origin zero zero the chance that i had exactly
the origin is zero
that's not set of events there is one of the
in which i had that part of the screen but has zero probability zero probability
doesn't mean impossible
OK another example
if you have the a if you have the interval from zero to one of
the real line and throw a dart at what's the probability of a rational
it is zero because the total area
that the total length of that line taken of rational numbers is zero there is
hugely more irrational numbers rational numbers so probability zero doesn't mean impossible
that's why were i was careful right is subset of equal less than or equal
so there's just one point and not actually practical importance for most of NLP
it is probably worth mentioning on the side
OK so
this is the final thing to look at the probability that x
class probability y
a way to get probability the union of x and y provided that x and
y are destroyed
OK so
if you have some sense
and you can characterize
as a union of two disjoint sets is split into two pieces then you can
get the total probability of the whole
by adding of the probability the two
apart a small part of the simulated proton proton goes to gluino pair event by
PYTHIA and so that's what i mean when i say a simulated event is simply
a list of the momentum vectors of all these final state particles is just numbered
from one
down to four hundred thirty something right of PXPY pz
and the massive courses related to what kind of particle it is and there some
sort of code tell you whether the particles of photon and electron and so forth
so in that particular event there's many hundreds of particles produced
now those
simulated events are then used as input for other monte carlo programs which simulate the
response of the detector so that's the other main classical monte carlo program that we
deal with in particle physics that takes as input the particle list from the event
generator and simulates the response of the detector now the response of the detector is
involves random processes so that's why it has to also be
dealt with with the monte carlo method so for example you can simulate multiple coulomb
scattering of charged particle passing through the the matter of the detector and so you
would use the monte carlo method to generate the scattering angle
or if the particles are unstable you would use the same the transformation method to
generate a lifetime according to the exponential distribution and that would tell you where the
particle with k
and so forth you simulate the ionisation energy loss in the production of signals in
the electronics and so forth
the output of that monte carlo program is in sort of simulated raw data and
you can use that as
input to the reconstruction software that would then take the these these simulated raw signals
from the detector and tries to identify clusters of hits in the calorimeters and tracks
and so forth
that's of course how we designed all the LHC detectors and got them more or
less ready to run even before we actually had real data that was all based
on simulated data generated by by monte carlo
OK so i just mentioned that that's that's also a huge industry
this is something that has has been developed over many decades a and in many
other places and there's this programming package shale
which allows you to construct a monte carlo programs that simulate a wide variety of
of detector geometry and that's now use that's essentially the defacto standard for writing a
detector simulation
OK so that's basically what i wanted to say hello to yesterday two days ago
rather and
i i just want to point out here that although these are builders lectures on
statistics up to this point we only talked about probability
i have only take told you about how to somehow generate sequences that follow a
certain probability distribution i haven't actually said
suppose you had real data
what would you do with it how would you use those data to try to
make some inferences about the probabilistic model that led to to those data that's what
statistics is not is how statistics is distinct from say probability theory so that's what
i want to talk about now for the next two hours
so let me go now
two what is nominally lecture three
citing a full-screen editor
so here's some really actually this is not related to simulated
i would love it if this were real data this is somehow what we're looking
for what this
here i see an event this is at least a simulated event i see a
bunch of IP leptons and some high pt jets a lot of missing energy and
if i see something like that i would think hot that's certainly beyond the standard
model this looks like supersymmetry so this is what we're looking for this simulated supersymmetry
but now like this is never so simple
because if you see that an event with
if you see an event with a bunch of high pt leptons and jets missing
energy there's no guarantee that that's actually the type of event you're looking for
because the characteristics of the of different types of events often overlap so here's another
simulated events
but this is this is not a supersymmetric events this is the standard model process
this is simply a top anti top production
so that's one somehow main important idea that i want to drill home is that
the characteristics of the events that you're interested in
and other types of events
inevitably overlap at some level you never able to somehow make a one hundred percent
between these different classes of events so you have some overlap between signal and background
so how do we somehow
formalise that
in mathematics
what is what is going on
and then and then i want to develop models that to explain what is going
on in one site one so that's what i call from such models to achieve
but first i want this monster basically explained the the properties or whatever empirical measurements
i did in the data and i want to have i want this model to
be sort of thought of us design principles that can tell me how to better
design systems and
based on the bottom line is that i want to understand why are networks the
way they are
you know
i want to basically predict behavior what will happen in the future
so here is a prime example from sort of social sciences how analyzing social data
can help so this is very sort of very well known work from rain zakri
this is like exactly the club network at school and you know during his phd
work in seventies he observed social ties in a university karate club and then during
the course of his study that was there was some conflicts in the in the
in this kind the club and it between into the two into two new going
one one person to create new karate club was like to be influential member of
the karate club in the other person who fought for the different graphical it was
like being struck and what is sort of interesting from this or as an anecdotal
example is that you see these two groups this time you got the love of
karate clubs being formed and that division between the
the one club in the other can sort of mice could be explained but by
a minimum cut
in this in this
in this network right so the idea is that if you observe this so structure
of social ties between these between these people
you can explain so if you can predict who will go into one kind of
one club and who go into the article so basically what side people taking this
yes you make one mistake sort of you know as a as rule
yes you make one mistake but still you know you be a good job
of separating these things and that's like nice example that you know structure of sort
of social by spencer what can what happened in the world
i believe that if there is a conflict
the other
i thing that i was alluding to is that
study traditional social social network data basically that was this obstacle that you can sort
of only get two out of three things right what what you would like your
data to be is you like your data to be large scale so that you
would like to have a lot of people are a lot of nodes you'd like
it to be realistic meaning like this data to correspond to some natural thing out
and you would like to be completely that community would like to know all the
relations that are that all the all the nodes are entities that and the initially
you could sort of get only two out of three but today
as i said before because we had this you know web or online computing applications
where we have this detailed traces of human activity we can sort of get all
three of the right i can get large-scale realistic and completely mapped networks right
the other sort of a growing in
in the research is that this network they can span many orders of magnitude
right so
you know back in two thousand three people what like four hundred node networks which
was like an email exchange network HP labs
then you know what forty three thousand this is again an email network i think
was like large and you know it
columbia in new york
you know
friendships among the blogging community around four point four million sort of the largest
we got hold of was like two hundred forty million old computer and communication network
of all the users of microsoft instant messenger so we can see that sort of
the data gets larger and larger and sort of the reason why is this why
is this important is because you can observe phenomena modern phenomena that small scale this
is pretty basic feasible but you have to be careful about sort of the scale
of the data because starting massive network data in a sense gives you more in
a sense that yes you can observe what you can model things before we pretty
much a measurable on the other hand you
it gives us less in a sense that we know much less about the particular
and so the idea so some of the questions that you start asking when you're
working with large we'd like to larger data that i'm not so much about what
is the role of this particular note place in the network but are more in
and then from there you may want to move on to say something about feature
variable selection
same which of these variables have corresponding regression coefficients different from zero which of these
variables are important in that question mark
OK so he was again if it exemplifying the outline of the tutorial let's look
again at one of these
classification problems so this is actually a binary lymph node classification problem the outcome is
just the label zero or one if it's zero
it's a non tumors and if it's one the tumor sample and again the covariance
or gene expression to be more than seven thousand genes involved
it's actually a high noise problem it's a difficult problem to do the classification
and so what you can do here is just look at these linear model
and if you have a linear model in mind you know that
the target you're going for is actually the conditional mean the conditional mean of y
given x that doesn't sound like a classification but if y is the of course
this is the same as just the conditional class probability so special case otherwise binary
this is the conditional class probability
denoted by px so if i can fit my linear model if i can estimate
my linear model
i get an estimate p haptics and then i can do classification if pdx is
large in have assigned one it's below i have assigned the
then you can run some cross validation wrap cross validation around it was randomly division
into three training one three test that and then you can look at a couple
methods right here is the last so i will explain it here is posting here
other methods use an SVM method red here they do
feature selection to have built-in variable feature selection there's the methods in in black here
this is the one nearest neighbour diana and the linear discriminant analysis and so they
don't do any feature selection
OK so you can just look at these numbers and then you can argue well
from a practical point of view
if you trust in cross validation if you just want to do prediction
you done know what right it just trust to cross validation it is numbers you
don't need any theory
and then you say OK i just try out which one is the best period
so again you have to cross validation handled in your hand and you can validate
how good you are
it's pretty easy if you're just initiative prediction it's pretty easy to do
OK so however of course we want it
say something more than just stop there
the first criticism which is maybe semi convincing is that
we can have no
that cross validation is very variable so actually these numbers
or maybe not that accurate OK so maybe we still want to know a bit
more some sort of methodological and theoretical properties what different methods are doing
and if you go on beyond prediction if you go into estimation so what can
i say
how well my estimate beta had
approaches the true
underlying regression parameter now sometimes in life
presentation i you know the true parameter by data zero or beta not to make
sure that you know this is the true underlying motivations parameter to if you're interested
in that kind of norm in kind of how good we can capture the true
parameter that there's nothing like cross validation at hand i mean there's you cannot see
from cross validation how well you do in kind of a steaming the true parameter
and from there we can go on say OK case i'm interested in getting actually
the right feature if i want to know the the active set s zero these
are just the variables whose corresponding regression coefficients are different from zero
it's hard i mean you cannot run across motivation and c
which matrices for feature selection versus another one
so this is the way of the outline what i want to do
first they go in the easy task prediction then move on to estimation of a
parameter variable selection i focus on the regression and classification and once we understand that
we can move on the graphical models and that you want to say something about
intervention causal analysis
OK so in the linear model
and actually many
statistical regression type classification on
the last so l one penalisation technique is very popular and is also very useful
and i'm just going to
i mean i start from scratch so here it again what the lasso is
so in my high dimensional linear model
i want to estimate the unknown
high dimensional regression parameter beta
so what you're going to do is you minimize the residual sum of squares right
and then you have to regularize because of the high dimensional problem so without this
term here this is just ordinary least squares but that would heavily overfitting problem so
regularize and the regularisation is this by now famous l one norm regularisation penalisation p
l one norm of u high dimensional coefficient vector to some of the absolute values
and here you have the regularisation parameter lambda
but you have to choose in practice is the tuning parameters
so the advantage of doing this is this is extremely fast in computing because this
is a convex optimisation problem the squared error loss is a convex function and data
and the penalty term is convex invaders well
so this is beautiful you can compute that very efficiently very fast and so that's
so from a computational point of view this is great and now we want to
understand what is actually doing for
you're statistical
the inference problem how well can you
now is to make parameter and so on
and there are two basic properties the first one is
the last of l one regularisation technique it does variable selection or feature selection in
the sense that
the estimate here they have safer component j may be exactly zero
depending on how you choose to love and this is very different from other sorts
of rehabilitation so this kind of l one norm regularisation has what people call the
sparsity principle or the sparsity property it may be exactly zero to put some of
the coefficients exactly two zero
this is because of the l one geometry able just explain in the next slide
and more generally you can think of the data is some sort of
shrunken least squares estimate sometimes you shrink the coefficients exactly zero and sometimes not
OK so here is this one geometry of the problem
when you look at this this is how in at least recent statistics typically write
it down
this is in the long grass multiplier so here is my leg ranch terms
and so of course i can go to the other
view UN to look at what i call the primal problem i can equivalently formulated
the problem as OK let's minimise residual sum of squares under the constraint
that the solution has l one norm less or equal than some value or
OK you make constrained optimisation with respect to the l one norm and there is
a one-to-one correspondence between the lacrosse multiply land
and the parameter our unfortunately this correspondence is not i mean this depends on the
data cannot give formula for this correspondence but it always exists
i looking for
interesting sights
they want to give money to these people
so that's also the trend right trend people
of course google
they make a lot of money because of the enticement
but now if you want to find the new areas to make money
you have to find from
other channels but this is also one of of these on the
examples how you can
rich people OK because blocks fear is associated with social network
so when you reach
some of the influential people there
you can reach a lot of people
through word-of-mouth
now he blogsphere growth and growth
it grows very fast
so technorati that's one of the two companies
they are working on this this that the collected data about the blogosphere
shows that every five months
the number of
blogs doubles
very fast
here this is under the study by blocking her
thirty six million women participate in the blogosphere each week
and the fifteen million have their own blogs
i don't know what's the difference between female bloggers
and the male runners
it's very important for the advertisers
of course i didn't know this before after before i read this article OK but
what's the you know the difference
so we would like to think like when you put in place ads
against the the sum
article right so you would definitely want to find the regular of the relevant ones
OK otherwise
people want
but actually female bloggers
there different
not that big
so they are they have a variety of interests
OK so this email and the female
in this sense in this in this aspect to that if there are different
today front page new york times and the year of the political blogger has arrived
now tomorrow there will be a commission a week later they will be republican convention
OK what they do
they try to all of these both parties
i understand it needed to have greater numbers of bloggers attend
but writing these influential bloggers to attend to their commissions
you know why the reason is they really want to bring down the walls of
the convention the convention it's a huge place have you watched the news how do
they prepare this commission
it's like it's a huge place but again
very few people
percentage small parties people can actually attend right
the the story is one lady from new jersey i think she would later attend
to this tomorrow's endeavors commission
but she couldn't afford it
guess what she did
she she blog on her blog site
and in no time she got the money she watch
enough money for her to come to them
if you have a way to build traffic then you can
do something really
innovated innovated
here's some more
you only the very few people to give you some small amount of some people
to give you a small amount of money than they can afford to come to
the commission commission
it is not cheap
so crowded
you have to find the hotel all of these things
we have a good hotel here
but this is this only to a smoking room i wanted to know smoking and
they start smoking bad
right now we on this we we know that OK blogs fear
is really an interesting place to looking to
so we will briefly discuss describe like blogosphere blogsites bloggers before we
talk about the research issues OK
i think most people
i would just try to
from a or b by c
b implies c
so that sort of complicated parliament on israeli
how does it work really well developed article works
just about the same way
that something interesting happens
we have the same sort of schema
set numbers
OK so the question is could up here
for the
these two teas it
because they're just new hypotheses
we call them a a
stanford representing
arbitrary numbers numbers each time
proper k and the subscript KM b
we here
this looks kind of like but really isn't it
the formula c
you and on the basis of cities including this one right that's why union and
and we can infer also but this is the same bunch
in this period but the same hypotheses
you can
right we're
nigeria care in beta
but the unions and we remove and we just get
so the basis
beta sorry
i think alpha come in summer
three in beta is going on here
we're getting the same
i keep on going
it's a form of motorsport
remember modus ponens here or or implication of patients is gen
we have a of some premises
are some hypotheses be air base some hypothesis is on the right in the basis
of the collection about that
and that's what's happening here we just have to cases of this
the only thing we have to remember is that these need to say
hypothesis we have the same set of friends same set of hypotheses
the same subscript we could also write this as that
it is conjunction really
we've got alpha beta and then we have the conjunction of these so we have
this in some but we have a conjunction of these two and some
six editions
so we that there is a situation
in which c
so that's the way it should
this was subsequently have to be care about the subscript
now what's nice about classical logic is that we can do a lot of things
using these function in conjunction rules in particular
something that is very well us
particular rule