so now we have
a difficult optimisation problem we want to minimize this function
which is the approximation error
expectation meaning
and average over the whole of the dataset i hold data distribution and we have
this is a constrained optimisation optimisation problem because we say that w
has you need to know
so the
the information on own
do this is given here
so this was written by michael so i'm quite sure if i understand correctly myself
but so let's try to go through it may be
we can so the point is that
first we define we make a change of variables basically instead of considering the variable
we look at the orthogonal directions
well it's simple here especially because we have only sold in two dimensions so once
we define one the the dimension of w we can be
uniquely define the orthogonal direction
so now we transform this objective function
only fine
yes yes we express x
so yes we expect it express x
as the sum of the projections onto w and u
because well that is equal to x because we all have two dimensions and then
we have two orthogonal projections and then the approximation is just as given by the
idea by the definition
and so this and then these two terms cancel out and what we have is
is this kind of thing now
but just to express this no
well known of vector is the square of the normal vector is simply the transpose
of the vector times the vector itself so he was forced to that an object
vector itself the point is that is that
well first of all
well we
we try change the value change the order of these things
i wonder if this is quite quite correct well
OK so now we we
communities two terms here
and then we take the the expectation operator in here in the middle we can
do that because you is you is a constant and random quantity so then what
you get is the expectation of o x x x x transpose here in the
yes i saw
i don't like it but i i i have to fast that's correct i think
there's an error
yes some of these kinds of the i
i somehow got the impression that
OK yes so it has to go somewhere
so that this
is equal to x times
t x
and then we come in those x t
thank you
and then this thing will be
multiply by
you are ideas so now these things here cancel each other out
conductivity of air
so poor
that he will stay there
four hours
and then i will do
i will create ions in the vicinity of the electroscope
let's first put some
charge only electroscope
if you're glass rolled
outputs in charge on it
OK that's sort of charge
and the
air is quite dry
very very small
and so
b charts cannot go off through the air
the surrounding studio
now i'm going to create ions thereby meeting the
and i decided to do that
with the candle because the candle is very romantic as we all know
you have the scandal
colwell well the charges holding
here's my candle
now we're going to kendall
well maybe twenty centimetres from
we're going to look at it really going
about fifteen centimeters away
i think my can way
stops again
although affected by ionizing the air there
creating free electrons as well as i was unable to participate now
in the current and the charge can flow away from the electroscope
were because the
on the activity now is always high
but again
it's not
from the eyes how important
the temperature is
in this case
the presence
of the ions in the air
if i have a clear
distilled water
i mean clean water i don't mean the stuff that you get
let alone that i mean the stuff that is in the charles river and clean
has a ph of seven
means one out of ten to to seven
of the water molecules is iron age plus
and always mind
we call it emitted by the way
it is not the result of the free electrons
but really the result of these
eight plus
and always minds i one of the cases were by not
electrons are made major
responsibility for the current
if i have three percent of salt in terms of weight
and all that sold will ionize so you get
so to employers and cl mind
you increase the number of lines by an enormous factor
and so the conductivity will store up
by a factor of three hundred thousand
one of two million because you increase the ions by denmark
so it's no surprise that for you
that the
conductivity of
seawater is a million times higher think about a million times higher
then the conductivity
of distilled water
i would like to give you the
number four
this is distilled water
it is about two times
ten to the fifth of may use
that is the
two times than thirty
five metres
i have here a bucket of distilled water
o make drawing for you
on the blackboard there
here's the bucket
distilled water
and in there
the couple played
another couple played
was the light bulb
and this will go straight
three outlets
it on the ten
this light
eight hundred resistance when it is hot
you see the light bulb here
you can calculate what this resistance between the plates that you have all the tools
you know the distance
about twenty centimetres
are you know the surface area of the plates because remember the resistance is inversely
proportional with eight you have to take that into account
you're taking
resistivity of water into account
it's so trivial calculation
you can calculate what the resistances of this portion
and i found
this resistance here
is about two men on
millions of years
so when i put it into the wall
the current that flows extremely low because it has to go forty eight hundred homes
and the two mega
so you won't see anything like will not show any light
if five
what sort here if i really meant to put three percent weight sold in here
then this too may go home
will go down to two on
a million times
the light bulb will be happy like claiming i type because two wrongs here
forty eight hundred two insignificant
and this is what i want to
demonstrate to you know enormous importance of
increasing ions i increase ions you buy in the air
now i'm going to increase
the ions by
having sold
so the first thing that i will do
it is i will
link is here
there's a light bulb
and i make it there prediction
there you will see nothing
there we go
that amazing
close to this optimal mathematical performance in this is joint work the ruin idea was
chuck kalish who is in psychology tim rogers also psychology major issue in computer science
so the idea was to investigate human active learning in tasks that is analogous to
the one d threshold learning problem so here is the the set up we gave
we presented subjects with tags and so they see one of these things this is
an egg and these are different an x-ray area in their spikiness from real spiky
eggs too much smoother eggs and these are just geometric shapes that can be regenerated
have these these distinct characteristics of smooth this person spikiness and there's actually a single
parameter which governs how
the house spike or smooth at the object itself from zero to one
they were told that these are alien eggs and the goal was to try to
learn what the alien eggs hatch into the hatch into two different things and there
are more probably going to hatch into birds of their spike your eggs and are
more probably going to hatch into snakes
if there are smooth smoother convex and so this is what they were told but
what they were told is where exactly
does it become more probably snake versus more probably bird
so what else is some sequence of eggs and those eggs hatch and then after
some point there as to try to make a determination of where they think this
transition is built from more probably sneaked more probably bird in those eggs that seal
either just be randomly chosen eggs that presented which can hatch or they can slack
to say i like to see this character that catch so that's the difference between
the passive and active learning
so i think that's what i just said
and so they all go through some of the data in a minute but the
results are basically this that in theory we know that if you just passively seeing
A's catching your ability to localize where this value theta is is going to decay
like one over that if you the number of races are hatched the nearest to
be about one of whereas if you are able to selectively pick which makes you
want to see how it should do something like this bisection type of procedure then
you should get this exponentially to carry in your localisation of data and in fact
we see that humans at least when the noise level is too large to follow
the same trends
so here we are
the data so there are thirty three subjects and they were split up among various
conditions conditions were noise levels
so there are different noise levels we like that so i epsilon zero in this
case that means there's no noise effects once point four that means that the highest
amount of noise point five would be complete no it's just flipping point so you
ranging from what from no noise to almost
complete randomness and then we looked at three different scenarios one where they're shown random
eggs hatching
one where they can select eggs that they'd like to see how much the active
mode and then when we call machine you and this is where we took the
optimal machine learning algorithm which was this
probabilistic bisection procedure and it was choosing which ecstasy hatch and those were what were
presented to the human soul
the motivation for that was to c
if we can improve her human performance by kind of coupling them to machine that
maybe is helping to inform them about what data to select to look at
so i guess you can count so what we see here so we see that
the army traces point so in that totally random case you see that enough shows
the average person maybe you see things tending to get a little bit better but
as noise levels get higher things it more difficult for people you can see that
things are much better
at low noise levels when they can be active even here noises point one and
point two years still seem much better performance than in the past the case once
you get up to the noise of
o point four things can fall apart people can make sense of things was not
very good at managing all that uncertainty
and then the machine your case people do very well and basically they're doing well
because they're following exactly what the machine is telling them and it turns out this
machine your case isn't super interesting and i can say more about that
afterwards people are interested but we'll ignore that for the most part so
here is the here the average person or average all the subjects together and so
for example if we looked at this case right here is noise point one
the blue is the passive learning the red is the active learning and the black
is this your case which would pretty much be close to what the
machine that optimal learning algorithm we're doing so what you see is a pretty big
if people can be active that's getting close to the
the kind of performance you'd expect out machine you still see a noticeable improvement here
these are the
the bars here like confidence interval of of of ninety five percent
so it's statistically significant improvement and but once we get into this very high noise
regime things kind get all
the mixed up all the machines can still sort through all that randomness and do
better in asia said that the the this axis here is as error gave i
didn't say that before and this is the number of existing hatch
so here goes down as you see more eggs and things get more and more
difficult there's more noise so that is what we expect and here's an interesting way
to look at the story of trends of how the areas are decaying so
in the active
the the circles here are data and plotting things on a log linear scale so
the areas log in the
a number of existing patches linear and if you fit a line to those data
you see that it doesn't look unreasonable that they look fairly linear analog scale with
that sort of slope that's getting flattened flatters increase noise level
so this log linear plot with the linear kind of fit to the data suggests
that the air really is going down exponentially as we do expect and that parameter
of the exponential decay is getting worse
were slower
as you get more and more noise which is exactly what the theory would predict
if we look at passive
if you plotted on log linear scale it's not very interesting things are very flat
but if you plot them on log log scale and you fit to the data
you see you get
kind of linear fits and that's
suggesting again that you have a polynomial served decay rate in the past month so
again we see this exponential versus polynomial air decay in human learning in this particular
study any questions on that is i think just have
wrap up room most close to lunchtime the questions of human learning
so the wise your case not so interesting well what's happening is as the machine
goes large and selecting a
if we were to fight flip back to the picture of the eggs
so what will happen is the machine would
relatively quickly start
homing in on this location of x and so towards the tail end of this
learning process after ten or fifteen x so the machines just looking x-ray in this
so the outcome is one one of the six phases which may show up but
we assume that this price is not standardized and we don't know the probabilities
of a certain phase showing up
so the station is that there is a random variable theta and theta
assumes that OK
this means that the the face
the top of the dice for decades
so that came be one two three four five six
and now we do a lot of tarsus independent process
of the dies and and of them and in the end policies we observe
a certain
as i OK
and k times
so a reasonable estimate and for the
that initial we see a certain results
thing the dice is the number of observations divided by the total number of tosses
so this seems very reasonable if i observe certain face
they often
correspondingly recovers likely
if observe rarely then
probability estimate to be over
quite small
so this is something
OK now we have become a little bit more probabilistic so
in this model the issuer multinomial sampling
so we assume that is observed variables theta
my how might have different state
but i want to say there are so in the case of the the dice
was six one to six and the likelihood function is given by
probability of observing that
died showed k given the parameters in the model is
equals to the k th component of the parameter vector
so g is director of
really want to our the first
the first entry is simply one minus the other entries so why might might debated
this has are degrees are minus one degrees of freedom support and minus one free
parameters because the last one is given by the normalisation constraint anyway so we just
have a vector of
number here and
which i exactly the physical probabilities of of
observing a certain result tossing the dice
and these are numbers between a positive numbers greater than negative numbers and they should
sum up to one that exactly the probability
and these are of course point is we are interested in it we want to
the slow down
then we observe data as i said before and these are realizations of these random
variables that one is one identical and and we simply calculate the sufficient statistics which
in this case is the total number
we observed
the result so and one means the number of times we have observed that the
dicer one and are in this case which reside
it would be the number of times we have observed the six showing
so d in the following list and gerald ford's of data
then we calculate the likelihood term based on this and these assumptions and
since of the probability of observing one of those results is just gk
so will be the result of observing the OK and if we observe that and
OK times that we just to calculate due to the power of k and you
have to do that for all
results so far
throwing die so this is the likelihood function with this normalisation term in front which
is not relevant for discussion
but essentially just multiplying all the probability of observing the individual resides and officers from
in the the maximum likelihood setting with an estimate the unknown parameter by finding the
parameter values which maximise
this expression and he would end up exactly with our plausible result that
parameters which
correspond to the experimental columns
and this is fine if n is very large the number of states
in particular is much like that smaller
then and this is my give a good estimate but in cases where we don't
have so much data to be observed assessment might be quite wrong and we might
not have
observe certain classes at all and this number would be zero
which might be unreasonable in many situations so
i should also warn you that this code include some type on concepts at least
you have not yet seen
will see it briefly today
this is on purpose
is one of the things i hope you have learned to do this semester
is look up things you don't know and figure out what they do
what they mean
because we obviously cannot in any course
or even any set of course tell you everything you ever want to know in
so intentionally we've seeded some things in this program that will be unfamiliar
so during the time you're starting the program
get online look it up to figure out what they do
if you have trouble we will be having office hours
well you can go and get some help
but the tea is will expect you at least tried to figure it out yourself
final will be opened book open notes just like the quizzes
it will be the first two hours of the allotted time we want good all
three hours
so i won't be usually longer than the quiz
be a little bit longer
again very much in the same style of the quizzes
all right
let's look at this
let's assume that you have won the lottery
and have serious money
but you foolishly wish to invest in the stock market
there are two basic strategy is to choose from
you can either have what's called the indexed portfolios
or a managed portfolio
indexed portfolios
you basically say i want to own all of the stocks that there are
and if the stock market goes up by make money if the stock market goes
down i lose money
i'm not going to be thinking i'm clever and can pick winners and losers and
is betting on the market as a whole
there are attractive
in the a
they don't require a lot of thought
and b they have what's called the low expense ratio
since the are easy to implement you don't pay anyone to be brilliant implemented for
so they're very low fees
i managed portfolio
you find somebody you think is really smart
and you pay them
a fair amount of money
and in return
they assert that they will pick winners for you
and that in fact you will outperform the stock market
and it goes up six percent well you'll go up ten percent or more
and if it goes down don't worry i'm so smart your stocks will go down
there's a lot of debate
about which is the better of these two
so now we're going to try and see if we can write a simulation
it will give us some insight
as to which of these might be better or worse
all right
so that's the basic problem
as we know it
and by the way we're not going to write perfect simulation here
because we're going to try and do it forty minutes to thirty minutes
and it would take at least an hour due to perfect simulation the stock market
all right
the first thing we need to do
it have some sort of a theory
we did this spring we had this theory
of hoax law the told something and we built the simulation
some tools around that theory
now we need to think about a model of the stock market
and the model we're gonna use
is based on what's called the efficient
market hypothesis
so the moral here
again is whenever you're doing
implementation of simulation you do need to have some underlying
theory about the model
but this model asserts is that the markets are information only efficient
that's just a current prices
reflect all
publicly known information
about each stock
and therefore unbiased
the if people thought that the stock was underpriced
well people will buy more of it the price would have risen already
people thought the stock was overpriced for people to try to sell it and it
would have come down
so this is a very popular theory believed by many
famous economist today and in the past
and so it's OK
that effectively means
but the market is
OK that it doesn't matter what the price of the stock was yesterday
today its price given the best known information
equivalent in some sense
solving the overall
reinforcement learning problem
so what was the final
this quantity is start he
so this is quite is thirty is going to be
and a conditional advantage so we're going
assume that we actually get point
we can assume that we act according to our learned policy
for the first team at one time steps
in fact according to
i learned policy our new policy
for the teeth time
o act according to optimal policy afterwards right to this
this temple
is the policy for all time
first react according to
i learned policy
and then we act according to
the whole policy
and the
this is
what this expected
sum of rewards
when we
behave in this way
was expected reward someone you start acting with high
and then you want to see
incomplete without policy
so the claim is
for every
reinforcement learning problem
for every policy
the difference between the on policy
some particular policy
the sum
from two eagles won the capital t
of this
so this differences
this is how well conditioned on
what you've done up to
hello could you have done if you could optionally t
how well you did
according to
have you measurement
we learned seventeen
the teeth time steps
it's going to do
maybe a little bit worse
and that the best thing they could have worked
and this difference here
if you think about it
it's just
it's just the difference computing before right
so computing this difference here
OK so it's the difference was the other way because cost rather than rewards
but this is
this is how we could have done
in terms of number of steps
reach the next
and this is how we did
for whatever i learned
action and stop
so this is
of course since two classes
if we always act optimally
then it's intuitive copi
city start
this difference will be zero
and the policy we learn will be the optimal policy
at each step
if we mess up
the mother we mess up
increases the difference between the policy and the policy really
that was
right so so high is just act according to h one
and that's going to h two
according to its three
each four
and so on until a city minus one
rights issue
and this is same
i will experience
today i'm going to start
talking about a particular class of algorithms called greedy algorithm going to do in the
context of graphs so one review
a little bit about
about graphs
mostly you can find in the textbook
in appendix
so if you have an
reviewed appendix b recently
please sit down and review appendix b
will payoff especially during our take on quiz
so i
just a reminder digraphs
what's the digraph
was that short for
directed graph OK
directed graph equals
OK has a set of the vertices
i always get people telling me that i have one for c
the singular is not per se it is vertex
plural vertices singular is vertex it's one of those weird
english words
OK probably original like like french or something right
i don't know
OK anyway
and we have a set
which is a subset of the crosby
that's the digraph undirected graph
it contains
on ordered pairs
flag OK so probably
pretty old man english
i guess the vertex would be a little bit of
to give away maybe it wasn't french
started to be used in fifteen seventy OK
good so
OK so the number of edges
he is it whether directed undirected
he is called what
the square
and one of the conventions will have when we're dealing once we get into graphs
with you lot sets
we generally drop the
the vertical bar notation
within the rose just because it's implied it just makes it messier
so once again another abuse of notation really should be water the size of the
but it just messes up
more stuff to write down you're multiplying these things and all those vertical bars
since they don't even have a sense to the vertical bar
it gets messy so we just drop the
the vertical bars there
one is an asymptotic notation
so he is or the squared whether it's
a set of pairs because it a set of pairs its most
can choose to
it is an square miles and square over to here is the most exciting player
two hits must be square
and then another probably sometimes comes up is if g is connected we have another
implies that the size of the
is the least the size of the
minus one
so if it's connected
OK meaning what does it mean to have
graph is connected
there is a path from any vertex to any other vertex
in the graph that's what it means to be connected
so if that's the case then the number of vertices the number of edges at
least the number of vertices minus one
and so what that says so one of the things will get into
that i that i just want to remember line you is that in that case
if i look at what e
log of the number of edges
then by this is
o of log b
and by this
his omega of log b
so is equal to the data of log b
basically the number of in the case of a connected graph the number of edges
and the number of vertices are polynomially related so there
their logs are comparable
so my name is among the overlap
i work for to feel and politecnico di milano which means i'm a professor in
britain including milano and i also the is more research group in this research center
which is named chief
the purpose of sheffield is to try to realize innovation and we use these foraging
innovation which means so we with a good ideas and we try to do applied
research and bring it to the market so the rationale of why i am trying
to give this tutorial
which is about realizing a semantic web application that we dealing seven years of activities
in the semantic web many many tried
in realizing things but can be
and so
more or less this is a result which
OK so a real application but it is developers pause the real application so it
might sound as in several moments as an over because bringing software engineering texts
in the we are thinking about multiple ontologies whereas to do these very simple application
you need much much less but the point believe that following this made using this
approach you can develop real semantic web application OK so
i did this work jointly with that in which are not here but wait
the theory and is at the conference i wanted to refer you can spot around
we did it within an educational training cruise between plaintiff and we also wrote a
book about it
unfortunately in italian
i mean if is anybody that understand
good sir
the tories don't like these i basically go through the entire development cycle of the
web application
taking into consideration the equally arities of the semantics
OK so it would be really a way to to go through the entire development
cycle not just implement so you don't have really to to implement anything not available
by typing by understanding the development process that we follow in realizing this application and
i will also put some slides but gives background in particular have slides about semantic
web about RDF about how and unbiased
some of you feel that this is used to just rise
and say please keep this because we all know
and then we do so
good so
the proposal is as a said to develop together these music
so we're back
but try to do what kind tool things
are up to these days so you want to do a mash-up using database out
there on the web
you try to let them manage them and we use them anyway
but in the end you can show
to the user to the end user application through giving an edit the
in this case
what we want to do
two let to the user said this time so i want to know about all
events about folk music
and you start to
moving from one repository to not letting the information and then showing them to find
the use
the things that i will
talk about the ingredients of these two have listed here so we have technology things
like the idea of a great deal
which are things that i suppose you know it instead
partially has got many of you don't know about idea
same words about ideas about it
basic things about the now are
this is mainly due to do something about the
and then
some framework or that i really dependent on the choice that we need for instance
with gene
as application framework which means that it's a java API that allows you to manipulate
two story into repository and things like that can i will go for it in
the entire description in the end when i'm talking about implementation
d two rq is nice
those used was a database so
relational data as in the twilight RDF graph
so you have a if you have to allow access to RDF we're out to
translating it entirely which is called thing i guess
how many of you know about spike
so i mean that we also
for example
this is the query language of the semantic web so what we do this using
it to whatever is possible to access the data instead of using program to the
and then down here but other more geeky things like could to say k which
is the way in inside of
actually a sparql endpoint for anybody that wants to query the database i q which
is way
from the top program to invoke particle so it's clients
he i
we call figure nine or whether it was or for an the OWL reasoning
o thing
news show results to be is a very nice framework developed by this in my
project at MIT which is called
readings for
going back
what we have here too
as i said the going through the entire development cycle so we start from the
user needs
ways of
finding heuristics
one of the first ones positions estimating
not distances states by estimating
for every
state variable
let's say everything there
many access
so we have a knowledge to make the
even that has
one of those
and the idea have a simple example here
this the planning problem
attractor tractor
that our
convinced books
and the goal
well what the attractor can do is to
look from this location that location so its locations
and when weights in the given location with them
one of the blocks can also block in which
these are the
actually this is
also the track
the detector
it's like this one
OK so
one is the
one people these factors is
similarly we have
the case location
all of this is three
what is
this one source of what
this section
it describes the
tractor pushing something so
the project has been same location with the block
and then
attractive forces the block
what is good one
was going to be location one
and then it be location
all this is
these people
and what this table here describes the
what seems to be in the possible values of all the state variables at different
time points taking even more so
i mean it's location
factories is one
both blocks location three
what what is possible in the first one the only thing that happened is that
the tractor pushes back tractable location
o point one
these are possible
there values for p one p two
so in the initial state he wants through people who are also lot
attractor has more than what is actually seem to make it possible
in this case point saw
if the article has both values and this
the variable can also
and then we do the same again for someone look at what all the possible
actually be taken and what have you
state variable values that can be reached
the only new thing is actually
tractor will focus on three
this new
value that can be reached
only only yesterday
well you see three having value true
the o
from this point because think more interesting
tractor would be point three
location three
in could be looking three
you can
these blocks
location so that's why we get
with these actions we get the school
this is the variable values and with the other actions we get these two years
now you notice how cutting corners here what is only approximation of the reason because
i'm going to read you know saying
he could be
location to look a could be location but actually only one of these
is possible
what we have here is only an approximation of the one on the set of
reasonable states
one three
and one these trips in this
well anything about the dependencies between the variables values
one dependencies three is that it was true
then beta y equals
because only one of those of operations
and while these table here
simply ignores all dependencies can also be considered any
valuation which is compatible with these values here is you know the best course for
any of the objects can be only
and then i the last
what seems that i'm one three
tractor could be here
what would be their
the track which
below the location
same people six
and now it seems that i'm one for every possible state is reachable so
well separate users
if you have more actions you can freeze anything
everything is possible
the only using these as a lower bound estimate the number of
actually needed we think
so for example the because this is our goal
a b a one b one
heuristic value we get for this state
before the goal is that the reason the goals a one and b one
four steps
yes that we have seen ignored in
tractor needs
all three
one two
access to post all box location one
this is simply because
you have a sort of asking that can do everything simultaneously it is possible to
in this case the cost is different
some may be the cleaning is more powerful but takes longer some the cleaning is
not so powerful that is quite cost less
so the idea is to use data mining you actually character the cost estimate the
cost you can add certain level you can use the first user low cost one
you you get a rough thing then sings you want to go deeper you can
use more expensive cleaning
that's why we're not go quite deep even the slides has some more slides because
of time
another interesting thing is data flow analysis because you
look at the whole idea you know the whole saying how they flow
the interesting thing is you want to work out the rules how they really flow
along this road are lot of you know the whole supply chain so we have
roy tupels we have the stadio like this we actually can do
a lot of things to construct week or past statements means you want to register
what the
no this is a different dimensions so that the product manufacturer price
you have so many different tax this tax actually can form flowgraph
so what we do is we are from the modern dimension upon you can consider
the flow graph
so you can think for example if you want to find out why
jagger of milk goes wrong so you what you really see is you actually can
have the whole flowgraph find those of the show
so you well you really see is what's the probability you can construct it into
the whole probability distribution flow graph
OK the flowgraph what we did is using the previous data warehouse
OK based on this data warehouse you actually can go back and try to construct
the whole the whole flock
and this whole flow graphs
where were
the gender distributions like three companions and the less became simply says you try to
find where the media free chain of the of the flow of frequent patterns and
what deviate from the major parts of the free compact so you think these should
be qualified as all
so you can actually worked out the whole transition pass
based on the major flow information and then work out the all our information so
that's the one we call the flow past can we have the flowgraph construct the
flow q
then you you basically the flowcube to idea is you can think the whole saying
is according to
two those things like
you can think there are several dimensions like product category
country the price of these as dimension with this damaging you see how since the
floor where the major change where it is
you can turn on up you know just try to watch out what is the
major saying on this for example thinking about product category suppose you want to see
the digital camera video camera have so many different prime brands of producers so they
different dimensions and this damaging you see the whole seeing how they flow for each
scene for them but can only see superpower shocked something you see this friend how
they flow along the whole thing whereas the major trend was i love you can
turn on up in a very nice way of our not give you the benefit
one but you can see using this flow q
you can find a lot of regularity and regularity in your whole RFID data you
know transition and all those things
of course when you construct this remember this flow graph you construct is always
you know it's the last
compression because well you've got is frequent pattern and all are you're miss something so
what we did is using something we call iceberg cube means you find the major
above this iceberg you can see the rewrites for that and the nice part is
not so important ways to hide it because otherwise you try to get all the
details you get too much detail so that's the way the
an idea how to consider flow graphs
and of course there are
a lot of discussions for example you can
encode a lot of things like a decade have product closing our decade the whole
hierarchy became code into your stuff why study this flow graph you can have the
other encode information transfer
two your system
OK so when you started flow you
maximum get you the details of your product
the the here our is in the paper or not to give you that you
care about what you can see is you
you can be very very efficient and was to work on this flow q
i mean you basically this candidate once you can constantly q and with this cube
you can find frequent patterns frequent past
and was a frequent that you can go through one more time you can find
lots of followers
but in this process
you could also use lot of graphics out there
o thing that that that that all the stations are under represented in studies
and that you know you have the phase pictures are worth a thousand words
and essentially it's you know
i see a lot of articles where they could really have had one or more
diagrams and was really helped
thing about that with his table quantitative
and there's probably in qualitative research probably the best book
out there for four
graphics and excitations mars humans
ninety four it's more than twenty years old yet it's
twenty years of coaching and yet it's really really powerful and is probably one of
the best quality the field
she had that that's worth pursuing
transform your data qualitizing quantizes said area
b is the first step
correlating quantitative and qualitative data
i will be forced or you could consolidate
the quantity and quality data to create a new
you could compare
the different
data sources actually quality versus commentator you can integrate them
and these are
so when you have two faces
you can have
type of data consideration and type of analysis
the first two there we you have either one
type of data one type analysis that the top left that's long that's quantitative or
that's not a mixed methods study
now i was the second so there
for the third and fourth cells are mixed
the fourth one being too great degree because have two thousand eight at least
we the have two thousand that's going on
OK so those are the most
no typology we've come out with this is looking at
orientations you can have so when you do the analysis
three orientations one notation is case oriented
my do a study where you're interested
politicians lead political leaders
so you look at the case
is your real emphasis
so each case is really important in your study
you might not even want to make generalizations beyond those cases
so it's very well suited to qualitative research
but you could also be quality because you have single study designs and so forth
time series look at cases
then you have
variable oriented
so in there
your focus in our variables interest see
how to more variables relate to one another
so the case might just be incidental so you may have a large sample
the case is still important but not to the level much more what what is
much more important variables because you want to see what happens
the variables
so tend to lend of to qualitative research
we can also
the variables in qualitative research
and in the first type process experience
very very
very very pertinent political
we often interested in
processes dynamics to go on
among people nations and so forth
you know process
ten experiences
persistently socially variables and experiences the folks of people
so we come when you look at those three
in a study
one more of those may lead you to do what's called the meta inferences we
combine your inferences
and these are is the table
again you have access to this article
has is in there
if you
make it case they're able to process
and in quality and quite a few
that captures most of the of the major techniques that we we use in in
both fields
over the next couple of days
introduce some of you
to some of those qualities techniques that you may not have heard of a lot
of people have heard of
that's because comparison
a few others but this conversation analysis disqualifier that
you know as a as i do workshops a lot of people have heard of
i mean quite a silly ties analysis
it's really really exciting
most people know quantitative analysis you tend to have
in interface to this is books you have a lot of them in the same
book qualitative you often get them
you wanted to the book
but there are lots of different options you have there if you're looking at the
you might be looking at this get statistics of cluster analysis of q methodology
it's for the quantitative phase
the current FAC all the different
after that you have
this list is not exhaustive but pretty comprehensive i think
in this three-dimensional representation
again looking case
this is variable
this is process
i would argue for every single type of research pretty much
the light somewhere in that q
for example if your
if the if it's more opportunistic
interesting generalizing beyond is of interest in looking at the variables
relate to each other in the local context economy more the top n
the bottom end
when you come to the case so it it
you might be more interesting intrinsic
OK like it is cases each case really is important you chose johnny because you
want to find out out about johnny johnny's experience being unemployed
this is the instrumental
where you want to see natural phenomena
so that you which is the film being unemployed
so you choose to people because of the lot more than
that's why this doesn't always work
and what you do in that case
you find the hopefully small set of variables which if they were given their observed
would render the rest of the graph
to be singly connected
OK that's going to be what's called your cut set
but you condition on the kind of cut the multiple
has the having the graph
if you do that then we can do is
you can take those few variables and instantiate them at all the possible values
that they can take
and then for each of those instantiations run
belief propagation or factor graph propagation on the remaining signet singly connected graph
and then
compute the probability of any variable you have to
average over all of the
probability is computed for each of the ways you condition on that set
that's called cutset conditioning
it's not
it's not widely used as the standard method of of appearing
exact inference
the algorithm that is widely used as junction tree
and there are a whole bunch of other various algorithms one of them is also
called variable elimination is another way of doing exact inference some people have cleverly shown
these are all actually equivalent algorithms so we don't need to study all of these
things for different choices of cutsets are four different orders in which eliminate variables that
correspond to different ways of doing the junction tree algorithm basically
the other thing you can do
if you can
cross your fingers and you can say
i'm just going to ignore the fact that the graph is
well connected let me just run
belief propagation on the graph anyway
l initialize my
right one
and run belief propagation and
you know they'll will be loops in the graph so the messages will go around
loops but you know
it converges maybe it'll be a a good answer
OK if it doesn't converge then maybe i worry
so this sounds like a crazy idea this is called loopy belief propagation there's a
double meaning to loopy
he also been crazy
and it's also be because you're passing messages around the go around in loops forever
it sounds like a crazy idea
except that
it works incredibly well
on unlike the problems in fact
in the field of error correcting codes
which is a huge part of the you know that
the problem of coding and information theory
the standard algorithm used to decode these error correcting codes
can be
converted into
an inference problem in a book we connect the graph and the centre of and
they use is of the belief propagation
and it's the state of the art algorithms central
so given the evidence that it works incredibly well for the coding people even though
it's not provably correct
it's worth trying problem
and people have tried as an approximation algorithm and have analysed it in in great
detail there's lovely work by
you you're right
the freeman on the analysis of this algorithm
in the
but this really should follow the domain of approximate inference algorithm which i'll talk about
in in a couple of lectures
let me focus on the junction tree algorithm and this is going to be the
past this
introduction to the junction tree algorithm which is a bizarre and the
tricky algorithm that
i hope i give you least some idea if you have an encounter this out
before or why might possibly make any sense
so here's the junction tree algorithm
let's start with the directed acyclic graph if we started with an undirected graph the
first that can be
so the second step is it's called moralizing
so what we do is is we take
each node we look at the parents of the node if there are multiple parents
we married the parent
and that's called moralisation we make the graph more moral
by marrying a and b
and by marrying the in
we moralise the graph and we remove all the directions
and what this does is it results in an undirected graph with no additional conditional
independence relationships
remember the really risky thing is that we do some operation that
that induces additional conditional independence relationships and moralizing does not
so here's this sort of the last
description of the conditional independence relationships that we originally had
that step two
step three
it's called
and what that really does
you introduce additional edges
so that there is no loop of length greater than three without a chord
OK according to something that cut across the world
so let's look before we had the red edge we have the loop of length
that had no core cost cutting across the
when we introduce the edge between
we triangulate the graph
triangulation is not unique
i believe we could have triangulated as well
as that of the b
and that would result in a in a slightly different algorithm
finding a triangulation is not hard finding the optimal triangulation is NP hard
the triangulated
and the reason we triangulate it is
that this is necessary so that the final junction tree satisfies what's called the running
intersection property
it's basically you know
he the ratio of consumers to it's roughly a hundred to one
we think
you know with the promulgation of these technologies
i don't believe about one hundred percent but slide from bradley
and he is very compelling arguments why we're moving to a world where this gonna
help us is going to be a few billion publishers
and the way to think about is you know anyone the
keyboard can become and also
anyone with a camera can become a photographer and actually published images and have people
by the images and be interested in them and see them
the ipod is actually forced into very interesting dynamics in the long can
you actually becoming only that you have you have you make your own selection versus
passively listening to somebody else programming which is a shift that is very different shift
massive scale
so flickr let's talk about flickr for a couple of minutes because i
for example a few minutes later
it's site
this this is another lesson learned by the way i wanted to my thesis which
there's a lot of my own intuition
about things that may or may not work on the internet
when i first heard about the
we considering
acquiring this company
the idea was to decide lets you take photos for them share
my first reaction was
one of them
and boy
fifty million people
in less than a year in order to do that
fifty million
that's that's amazing a huge number and statistics on how many photos have been uploaded
to continued to to grow
is just incredible
what makes flickr special right this user generated content
it's not like system provides its users that actually putting it changed the world
it's actually very good you can find some amazing imagery on flickr i encourage you
to search for find photos from your friends actually
i happen to define
it's use organised like nobody
we know we use what's called the folksonomy right which is
the taxonomy just evolves
and actually in second
people tag on images search for
you look up whatever people that
right so you actually find matches
which are very hard to find otherwise it didn't
example one humans
and like this
again the images are critical
what is
you know people like promise which actually gives you a lot of knowledge about those
images come back to that human
it uses distributed
it's not through business deals or anything like that just to qualify musing ways
and use functionality because it's an open platform people actually end developing tools
to images all on the web
on the images on flickr because it's an open API and the ability to publish
these interfaces
so here's what you get
and i think the system
so think over fifty million people
he only the nineteen employees
and no more what
that is an amazing right new
that is
now we should
and as the question is this
we see this phenomenon all the web
and that's what i mean
we actually have
so if i ask questions like
you know you found something to know how do you know you can trust
you can believe that
he moved to
to which the question is compared
and from the people that you try to extract
relevant information that are more likely to your question
this is because we have little time
look at all the documents to to read all the documents that are determined by
three engines
so we would like it to be more intelligent and to find out really
two questions
question answering systems
i'm not not so successful commercially
also used to be quite easy
long query
along the
we think it if you type in keywords be intelligent enough
delete four
intelligent information
but this could change more multimodal
if speech recognizers
we can and especially when you have only
when you
access to the internet with your eyes
it would be very handy if you could drop
speaking your question
that's type in question
that would be much more
and as
in a way of life as we can
so then we get all of these types of information act
more more than
and also we do not think give around two
document collection sometimes our is not very well defined
one around her all
of the document collection
maybe visualize when see some parts of the information and you might think he is
select some parts of asia and go deeper into the ground
for information
and there are a number of the
among which information extraction so we could classify document text categorisation
we could create summary for instance of the output of
output of documents might summarise or you could you
and also in
profile of users
use of this information for that
for that are relevant computational
and also information extraction plays here so both the next generation
we might be more precise in their
i identify information of the
which is they got which by information extraction techniques
and also for the west
we refer to web
question three and class
information extraction techniques quite some important
and then i
and in general thing i also included the light
of the people who i very much
communications of the two thousand six
where he advocated access to
so as a better i just keywords
so that you know that our technology our information
they should focus
on the number of deaths that's really help you
in finding information
but not only finding information that will help you improve your problems comparing information integrating
information so more and more intelligent
agent of systems that could be built
so he spoke about look
and of course we need to think about
in fact text mining usually
now as you here on several occasions over the course semester on the philosopher what
that means is i don't really know a whole lot of facts
and so i'm about to tell you a story where i wish i knew the
facts and i don't know the facts it if it was
if if i could really do it right i don't open the door and bring
in our guest physiologist who then provide the fact that i'm what i'm about go
to measure but you know we have the physiologist coming to protect and he'd actually
tells these things
i don't know i don't know them i don't have that person but
take a look at what happens when the body dies
now i know that you can kill people a lot of different ways you can
you can poison them you can strangle them you can shoot them in the heart
causal patterns that result in death may start differently but but i presume that they
and you end up having this as a set of events take place now what
are those events this is this is exactly where i don't really know what
the details but i take it something like because of whatever the original input was
eventually the blood no longer circulating and oxygen is making its way around the body
and so the brain becomes oxygen star because of the lack of oxygen get into
the cells the cells are no longer able to carry on the various metabolic processes
because of this they can repair the various kinds of damage they need to create
the amino acids in proteins they need and so
the decay begins to set in the cell structures began to break down they don't
get repaired as they would normally do
so eventually have breakdown of the crucial cell structure boom the bodies that that's a
i don't really know
whether that's accurate below rough story editor with some story like that's probably right
and in typical philosophical fashion i draw on that story for you up here on
the board
the events that i don't really know the details of how we can just call
b one b two
b three
up through b and
so you know before b one begins you've got you know the body
working function in its bodily way respirator reproducing the cells and so forth and so
and at the end of the of the process by b and the body is
so you would be for bodily b one through bn
that's what this is a list of the death of the body is
this is a it's the sort of thing that somebody from the medical school or
biologist physiologist something could could describe for us
so here's the question then suppose we call that process
death of the body
paul what has occurred by the end of that sequence of events bodily death
now a question that we can still ask
o is it looks as though we can still ask it
my i or do all i still exist
the death of my body
might i still exist after bodily death
i don't mean to suggest in any way that we you know the answer to
that question but at least that's the question it seems as though we can coherently
raise there's no
obvious contradiction
in asking my i still exist after the death of my body
nature would turn out to be no
but at least it's not
obviously no
if the answer turns out to be no it's going to take some
some sustained argument
settled one way that answer could turn out to be yes for all we know
at this point
this was just brings us back to the thought that whether or not i could
still exist after the death of my body
looks like it should depend on what i am and so ornamented that's the question
that i'm going to turn to
but it's a bit cumbersome to constantly be asking you know my i still exist
after the death of my body
and so
no harm is done once we have clarified the question that we're trying to ask
if we
summarize that question in a bit of jargon or slogan we say instead of asking
might i survive might continue to exist after the death of my body we might
and i put it this way
i say for short
well i survived the death of my body
no harm done or
will i survive
my death
because what we just stipulating we mean when we talk about my death in the
context of this question is the death of my body no harm done we can
just say for short
you will i survive my death might i survived my death
or for that matter
no serious harm done if we ask is there
after death
as long as we understand that we're not asking about there is life of my
just another familiar way of trying to ask well i still be around after my
death will i still exist after my idea so i think is a perfectly legitimate
and that's the question we now want to turn to
now as i said it looks as though to answer the question you could i
continued to exist after the death of my body
is there life after death could i survive my death for short
to answer that question we need to get clear
about what exactly is it for something to be me
that's the question will turn to a couple of weeks
first we've got to get clear about
what am i
what kind of an entity
when i made in philosophical jargon this is of course a question from metaphysics so
last the metaphysical question what kind of thing is a person
is it seems plausible to think that whether or not
a person can survive or continue to exist after the death of his or her
body should depend on how he's built what he's made of what his or her
parts are
when the sketch for you
basic positions on this question
what is the person two basic positions
they're both i imagine a fairly familiar
you may ask me why didn't you give the error in the
diameter which ultimately of course translates into the air in the mass
the reason is that these are so precisely the way you buy them that the
uncertainty is completely negligible compared to the timing error that i make so i won't
take that into account
all right so now
we can start the
and i have to switch
two this unit here
here is this
container with the
carol sierra
it is very sticky indeed
you see that seven marks and just for my own convenience
i have put there
two black
mark so that i can easily see
the moment that i have to start my timer
and the moment that i stop it there's so many lines i may get confused
if i don't do that
and we going to time this together
and we'll see how these objects
how long it takes for them to go through
i will start with my one eight
of and in diameter
i have one here
trees are
i deleted zero
three all you can see that you should see that
three two one zero
look how beautiful it working its way through you seem to believe
so this using a knife
and but one of the top
going very slowly but just wait when it has broken through the surface
and also
one centimeter
two centimetres
three centimetres
what is that
what happened
i don't see it i wanted do another one
what i did i cleaned it i erase it
what was it
five point nine three
keep that in mind is nice to see whether they reproduce sexually
OK there goes
one centimeter
two centimetres
three centimetres
five point six six units shows you the uncertainty in my timing so we had
a five point nine three
and we have now five point six
it's not so bad five point nine five point seven
binding are tens of second my timing could be a little bit larger than the
tens of second you don't have very much time
so now we go to the
five thirty seconds
by thirty seconds
take some time to break through the surface and that funny because the thin film
has formed on the surface of the syrup
due to its exposure to air
wonderful had let's wait
patiently but now it goes
it goes now
three point eight zero
that which you have
it's going to be tougher and tougher for me
three sixteen to one inch
it's actually a good thing that it stays for a while at the surface so
that i can
get really
really that really helps us doesn't
if didn't want to go
you know even see it
here we go
now you see it's very hard for me and so i could easily
i have a substantial error two point six nine
and now we have the
a quarter inch
real big one
i have to do it again
i don't trust his at all
when it went to the surface too fast
i can do it very accurate was the first number by the way
one point
six eight
and this is one point four zero
one point six eight
and one point for zero
you see i wasn't kidding when i say that my
uncertainty could easily be
o point two now
come the acid test
and yes test this
if i'm
if the measurements were done correctly and if we really work in that regime
and if i plot
one hundred divided by the square resisting only the paper
then it should be
a straight line
all rights
he i have the plot
which i prepared
and i'm going to put these numbers in there
so first
we're going to get six points
five point lead forty five point eight seconds
for the
the smallest
ball bearings
this is the smallest one
don't be misled because this is one hundred divided by the square
but this is the smallest one
five point eight
so we are here on this line
and we are at five
o point eight somewhere here
that's it
the point is lower than you expected
the reason is the temperature went up
if the temperature went up
then the viscosity goes down and they go fast but that's okay
it doesn't worry me
the next one
three point eight o
four three point
eight o
you see that
i predicted that straight line
administrator straight-line
not a straight line
but from
OK will put in a point
o point six nine
to point
this is two point seven two point six nine
i can hardly put in the air of the time because it is not much
larger than the size of my dot
and now we have the last one
one point let's take the average
one four and five five
one point five five
is an area of about two two-tenths
the second this is an area of about two turns
of the second
all right there we go
is this a straight line
or is it not
gorgeous straight line so you see you are really working here
in the
one over
in enriching where the
terminal velocity
it is
proportional to the radius squared
OK we'll will give you the lights back
now comes the question which is relevant to this experiment
and that is how long does it take
for the
terminal speeds to be reached
the object has a certain mass
so does gravitational
the force on it
and the gravitational force equals
and g
and then there's is a resistive force
because the timings
so this this year the data matrix part and here we see here
if ten times as much data
and we need ten times
it's much computational time total time secs actually scared sublinear yourself is other stuff and
one of the actual solving the linear equation system
so that way we can
in opinion
and the results are quite quite pieces of about eighty five percent we the find
much other
he took this from from mother as it did for
and yes a support vector machine but we didn't find anything and only a bit
too much data for that
we did some comparison with other methods
these are all small datasets about things because as many fossils of cells and we
don't really think that's was there were that
small datasets the thing with this attribute views on that
but still there we
from good to bad so there's whole range is there
so what is still
o thing doing OK
could be bit better no walls
show now
some improvement recently that
what we do better didn't have redundant measurements for the classification have some regression examples
later on
we're doing much better in comparison to somerset
the reason we looked in that
the figure that we have some strange things in this of something strange assume there
is something wrong
and the
but look standard
realize the combination that actually can diverge
so this is simple problem two dimensions this function we just computed some samples
random data points
run the combination technique we have here is a realisation parameter ten to the minus
four he ten six
let's see you
it is the least square error the functional
the functional at some point afterwards
we can expect because these two terms and at some point we can't really get
close to him to be more refinement order of the same
so we can get closer to the function we would get closer to
continuous solution which is just message
the residual functional centre at some point
but what's bad if you look at times one of six original to get down
and then we said to it and then it get worse again so far higher
refinement level but we get worse results that can happen
it should have
the true rational approach
the better is the higher the refinement about better solution is
so we did
i had a bit closer look at that what essentially went down to a very
two space k so we only have two
space of
we want to be too
and joint space
we felt that because the combination technique is optimal
additive approximation methods such as additive approximation method combination that would have won one minus
one and we just OK
let's allow any c one c two c one two we could show that the
commission is optimal in the worst case sense
so only the worst case and the commissioning
i want to use
this combination technique introduced
and his son could show
skip is
was equipped contract could
thirteen optimised combination technique which goes back microsecond set in two thousand three
so the sea
norman sparse grid solution this is
combinations of
no we allow
these coefficients
this is a partial solution no we those the coefficients to vary
so we down uses coefficient before this alternating binomial coefficients but we actually computers coefficients
a simple expansion of the strongest
so we have to
one of these induce some properties of the system the system
the stem depends on the resolution but the minimum
of this
it doesn't depend on that
so we only have system that you can actually computers scalar product of
between the partial solutions
number of partial solutions
gamma distribution is the conjugate prior for it that's the one that gives an easy
sampling algorithm we lose you will we have a tougher sampling algorithm to generate if
it's if itself stable
and i just wanted to compare the fit because of use inverted gamma you end
up with the student t distribution for if you use this positive stable
and you end up with the alpha stable distributions so we found that we got
slightly better fit in the tails of the distribution using the office stable shown the
dotted line compared against the true data solid line so looked like we were reasonably
in business we're getting slightly better fit to the to the noise data using this
alpha stable model
and for symmetric stable distributions actually there's some really interesting stuff you can do for
nonsymmetric ones based on series of process
random variables something we've been looking at recently but for symmetric once we have this
basic result it says that
if you take the product of two alpha stable distributions and will take x one
to be gaussians
and x two to be a special positive stable random variable then the product of
the two
is an alpha stable random variable with the with taylor parameter tells the parameter alpha
one times offered to the individual offers
so basically as if we take
x one then to be galaxies understand the calcium standing outside you can either soak
up the scale parameter within the next two or the x one i think we
take it to be in in the x two so we take a stand calcium
for x one and multiply by perfectly skewed positive skewed stable random variable
with parameter alpha o two
then you end up with then you end up with an alpha stable random variable
for the product x one x two and that's what we need for
so given that x one is calcium next two is nongaussian
will augment the model with x one and x two at each timepoint is part
of the state vector
and then we have a conditionally gaussians model
x one conditional upon x two
linear and garcia that means we can apply the rare blackwellized particle filter to it
and then we have paper where we
it is for this type of model and it just garcia noise this is an
extension of the nongaussian case and well
a great deal to say about this is a synthetic example where we take this
sound waveform corrupted with stable noise and then reconstruct
the signal from it
works quite well sounds OK
we can construct
ninety five percent confidence intervals where the signal will be based on the filtering output
show we can just about see the dotted lines that
we can estimate the parameters of the model and see how the time varying are
parameters of the signal model very over time with quantiles on those as well
and we can also i haven't said very much about parameter estimation will also able
to make a fairly stable estimates for the constant parameter alpha was simply extended the
state space by one two of the state vector to include the alpha variable itself
and applied a time jeter on it so we that it's slightly random parameters that
there is a little bit from time to times that and we get some kernel
smooth density estimates for the posterior four alpha which says it's around about point one
one point for most of the time which seems reasonable
two us
and very little sort of time so probably skip past this example but another rare
blacklist filter example where we had some fun balls with nonlinear distortion correction so very
nonlinear observation function in this case so we basically now modelling
the the observed data
so as non-linear clipping or a non-linear clipping or quantization
the original signals and again quantization is something that get in in
audio signals when the idea you get overloaded on the digital sampler or that give
or else you get something that's too heavily quantized because the recording levels set too
low this is quite useful thing to be able to restore so
so the kind of this would be content appear quantisation function if this is your
input signal then this is what you observe the output according to the quantization step
and inverse
mapping really is one to many because for each observed y value there are many
z values signal values that could
and in terms of probability distributions we can think of a likelihood function which is
the dirac point mass centered upon the
clicked value of the unseen signal
z w that is our likelihood function for clipping
it's a deterministic
function we can still build that into the particle filter and we do exactly the
same thing with the signal process itself we assume that the underlying musical we're gonna
be clipping musical
audio signals is the time varying autoregressive process with one of these time varying evolving
parameters have to
this time
instead of using complicated nonlinear
parameterisation of the model i used precisely this i just have a galaxy in vector
random walk on the
also the in fission our written to implement
should land examples
it's actually the lambda point nine works better than lambda one
and to zero and the other ones
OK now that was the value approach to listen to the good let's look at
the source lambda which is the q value approach
again the policy is fixed
and again you still get different returns to average you still get l a way
to give you the eligibility trace
and weight update the q values
OK it's very interesting finding this you know it will take very little time
for support when
skip decides
so there is one slight problem with the eligibility trace
and that is
if you visit st lots of saying this example
estate eligibility to be updated can become greater than one
or q values
how do have typically become greater than one
so look at this example
why might be able to retrace be a bad idea
so what happens if i is in the middle stage
and i took the wrong move ten times
and then i mean that to the right to the end
effectively the ability of the of the cue value for doing state would be around
with some discounting
OK so you can see what was adopted it was they are doing wrong the
state really is the high value
in practice you do see sort of issues with the elderly trees so is simple
idea car replacing traces which is that instead of
before we the deal the of interest was it was it we just add one
to the current trace
here we just set to one so when you're like a great one
OK you find this actually leads to much better performance in practice
and you you will if you went to and you will run the problem is
that the students work on this recently and and after four days and we didn't
have the y that was working on wi-fi look at this was actually the problem
so this does happen to be did st where replacing traces
so this would probably ruin the equivalent of the four produced by in practice it
works like more efficiently
so here's replacing traces to learn a lower error
by function
so good summarize we had four to use the standard back review which is easy
to compute the equivalent
the the whole idea of this is just averaging estimators
pretty well actually
so let me cover
i've got a few slides here it just doesn't high-level issues with our own
what a great because it's actually not coffee
and then the cover function approximation which if you actually want to go out in
many evidence and in the world you can not tabulated value for every possible state
or the ivory coast in action at that you would see
trillion states just another way to do that can a hike around new approximate value
function properly the q function OK so in the world you have to use approximation
methods and then you can start to do things like this solution to a fellow
or the solution to backgammon
and what discussed briefly at the end of the day
i want to discuss that then essentially you've been through almost the entire are a
OK it's a lot of information you'll never ending tomorrow but i didn't even when
you read the book it should be like
you have to understand is already in a good book but it helps to be
if that's the information
multiple times
OK so let me quickly cover just some practical issues
now for model based in solutions i mean claim earlier there exists an awful deterministic
now i'm really curious actually that when you're doing sampling methods norelli
you cannot use that
you cannot use a drug a domestic policy
to endure recall one
and with the convergence of these evidence requires that to update every state
with non zero probability
now the problem is a deterministic policy especially if bad deterministic policy
you might not have been all states and actions
but some of his actions might actually be
the what you should take
so somehow you have to explore the whole
and explore more you you you you certainly
choose a deterministic policy some actions may not be some states so you have to
explore all options
OK so to do this we use a stochastic policy
which means that you typically stick to policy your current greedy policy with some probability
is some very small probability explore we
previous is the this earlier
then you can prove convergence starting to optimality in you can read then reduce over
time the next
of policy
and you can show that
either you read you converge to
we if i compute the gradient with respect to the pre-activation
here we can see that the loss directly only depends on all the
pre-activation computed here so then the only bit that means that
is missing is what is then gradient or they're they're a of
these intermediate results with respect to my quantity which in
in our next stage is going to be the activation of the layer below
so that is what we'll be invoking here for performing other
vations so if you want the derivative of my loss function
now which respect to the g f unit at some
hidden layer k any hidden layer k well invoke the chain rule
and by writing it as it's just going to be the sum
over the derivative of my loss function here
with respect to all pre-activation is
i for all units i at the layer above so just to the pre activation
at the layer above that's why i have to keep plus one
and multiply this by what is the derivative of
pre-activation the layer off cape one for the unit
with respect to the activation at the layer k
for the j with unit ok just applying the chain rule here
and so i'm going to assume that i've computed this already
i've shown before we all the to compute
the gradient of the pre-activation at the output layer
and now the only but that is missing is this part here what is
the derivative of my pre-activation the layer above
just picked some activation of some units
in the layer below well pre-activation is quite simple is
just a linear transformation i'm just taking a bias
loss the sum of all the way to contributions of all units in the
layer below so if i'm taking the derivative which respect to j
if unit so that there would respect to the
pre-activation wealth with respect to the bias that zero is
the biases different doesn't depend on the activation of the layer
below and i have some over all units j
of the weight times the activation
and so all these terms here the derivative respect to
specific unit is going to be zero if it's not that unit so if
this g here is not the same j as here and when it is well you get
yeah scalar times my variable with respect to which i'm taking
the derivative so i just going to be the scalar so ultimately this
will simplify where this sum goes away
and then a remove this so i get the scalar from my variable with
respect to which i'm taking the derivative
this is why this whole term here becomes just the weight between
the ai with a unit of the layer above and j are unit
at the layer k
and one other way of writing this i have some over all units i
in my layer k of the weights the weighted
partial derivative respect the pre-activation at the layer
cape loss one one thing i could do is actually
considered the whole gradients so the whole gradient of
with respect to the pre-activation layer k and multiply
that c indexing with respect to ice i'm indexing over rows
so multiplying this by the jf column
of my matrix w far too right instead i explicit some actually
write this linear algebra so i can just write this instead as
the gradient of my loss with respect to my
pre-activation that layer plus one
multiplied by the j with collen of my matrix w t plus one
so here the notation i'm using is
i'm using this dot to refer to all rose
at the column j and so because of this you can think of the slicing
matrix i'm taking all rows at the specific column so then this
would be a column vector and so to the have become a row vector that