for instance in
this is situation you see that i arranged these features these are the coordinates these
are three color channels and the gradients that
the course is symmetric and the
the vertical axis same
arm and
each each cell here represents for instance the covariance between six and the chairman
or channel and
next to this is the function
symmetric positive semidefinite so they live in be group so i can apply my the
stuff that i showed you before
the dimension of
they are symmetric about in the previous slide on several features strength
and i need only to coefficients to represent
like many
pixies on two between a coefficients i'm using color histogram which is only sixteen b
is of histogram by the way i end up with much more coefficients so he
called it
its natural way of fusing different kind of features i don't care what is called
and the other one is called the gradient i can define in my life
and then you have to rotation scale changes
and if find transformations and illumination variances
and that is an illustration
so these are my images and these is actually color-coded going metastasis corresponding to these
images kept pictures of pictures
at the same kind of
look like these so we are
kind of presenting this
just need to twenty
coefficients in this example and you know that structure the league
so one of the first example i want to show is this search on the
manifold which means that this is the points
like the pictures
o kind of like human pictures here
and i compute covariance metastasis so the spider on the manifold that i want to
kind of computable distance between them and you know how to compute the distance stars
and the multiplication in bayes about picture find these that
and i'm sure you
o is located in is here but so a computer to do this thing it
is to compute the know the whole thing
it can compute everything and search is time consuming and this is why you need
compact representations for businesses
one thing
and i think it was also this publication
we constructed multiple queries metastasis wanted to be robust to force the
conclusions so the original thing and then the like the covariance matrix for the whole
thing that down portions of the image forces here we have for the last one
right on top of and
this is how we define our little features in this case nine
the search image for
region having similar calling semantics but we do we cannot be the image copied covariance
matrix that compute the distance between the two and it's like these metal metastasis that
we are
in one case because we don't know the scale i is the application this is
just an application example of this is the kind of skin affected by scandals they
kept two towers of best match and in the second is that the the first
one was just using the whole thing and the second one using the five of
two just kind of accomplished some speedup and robustness that these are the results
so what you see nearly in the given image someone like these regions
this is about the earlier base and the flower
and this is what you end up
and these are the best images
i mean i assume that the objective is going to be in the picture but
this is my example that i can do anything and it was kind of a
that occur in space distribution systems best the result you get
the detected but
kind of like this thing is missing using this intensity different sector to enter is
different here is another example is the interface
recognition algorithm of course but you this this is it's not also structural members structure
is going to be representation again
these are the results you get four histogram features another example this about a year
and in this picture is the region it's fun and if you use histogram this
what you will get so
it is a performing then is a simple discrete but computing distances on manifold
this slide can it
about this kind of got another search application is set to the nearest neighbour because
wireless are manifold in this example we use brodatz dataset hundred twelve classes and these
in the time interval from to right to I + 1 is approximately not exactly
because the damping the dumping rate isn't even constant within this time interval
but it's approximately the dumping rate times the time
for which the dumping was taking place
that's what I mean by that
and it gets more and more accurate the small time interval
OK now here's my problem the problem is
we start dumping
at time t equals 0
at time t equals t
how much radioactive waste is in the file
no they subproblems slightly complicated is
radioactive waste OK if I put something at certain day and then go back several
months later I don't and nothing's happened in between I don't have the same amount
that I don't because all some of a fraction of the have left
answers to the problem must take account of for each piece of wastes how long
it has been in the pile because that takes account of how
long it decay and when and where it ends up there so the calculation
the central part of the calculation will be that if you have
on initial amount of substance
and it decays
at time t
this is the amount left at time t
you know there's a lot radioactive decay you knew that coming into 1803
although it's of course simple differential equation which reduces the velocities of the know the
answer OK depends on the material so I'm going to assume that the
nuclear plant dumps the same radioactive substance each time is only 1 substance calculating and
itself assume k that I don't have to change from 1 k from one material
to care for another because it's mixing of
just 1 material
OK now let's calculate here the idea all take the t axis but now I'm
going to change its name to the you actually using why the 2nd
starts at 0
I'm interested in what's happening at the time t
how much is left at time T so I'm going to divide up the interval
from 0 to t
on this time axis
into well here's you 0 0 starting point you want you to
of let's make this you want you
focuses you want
you to so on let's call this
you have
relentless about that
that the amount
the other
so I'm going to do is look at the amount that take a time interval
from you URI for URI plus 1 is the time interval delta T delta you
divided up into equal time intervals
so the amount of dumped
in the time interval from you GUI + 1 is equal to approximately half of
you dumping function there times delta you we calculate that before
that's what the meaning of the dumping rate
by trying to see how much is case
it has carried how much is left in other words
well this is the starting amount
so the answer is going to be its efforts you URI times delta you
flying this factor which tells us how
how much it decays now so
time so this is the starting amount that's fine you are
that's what it was 1st done and this is the amount of
time multiply that by e to the minus k times now what should I put
up there
I have to put the length of time that
had to decay what is the length of time that has the case was dumped
I'm looking at time t it decayed for
the time length T minus 2
of the
when the time to do that
today on
so the stuff that was dumped this time interval
when i at time t when I come to look at it this is how
much of it is less and now all I have to do is add up
that that quantity for this time the stuff that was this time interval of stuff
down then once and so on all the way up to the stuff that was
done yesterday and the answer will be there for
the answer will be the total amount
left at time t that is that is not yet the case
will be approximately you add up the amount coming from the 1st time interval was
the and coming and so on so the effort you all all say save delta
you for the n times e to the minus k minus minus I find delta
you so these 2 represent the amount and this is the case factor
and I add those up as a runs from well we start from 1
the yeah
and now let delta T goes to 0
In other words make this more like delta you go 0 make this more accurate
by taking finer and finer some analysis of looking every month to see how much
the population biology evolutionary epidemiology
the likelihood function is intractable
so we don't know likelihood function properties data given theta we can't use MCMC
he gave sample many of the monte carlo algorithms
that these and other approach
so the
basic algorithm is based upon the rejection algorithm which was first proposed by bono monopoly
back in the fifties
it's a complete what follows we pick a parameter values because of my prior distribution
on the set of parameter values with probability proportional to the likelihood
so divide by some constant here along with everything less than one
but what i find that gives is independent draws from the posterior distribution of the
parameter is that works
but what he said we don't know the likelihood function
so what david building calls the mechanical version of this
second mechanical version of based so we draw theta from prior
we simulate the data from the model
b prime and we get from the value of the simulated data the prime exactly
matches real day-to-day
is a mechanical version
but you computable to anywhere in the background producing we simulated data sets
i mean it belongs to exactly match a real dataset
now obviously see the animal very complexity here
this is just not going happen i mean if you continue data that you never
going to exactly simulate your hard to should
so other approximation comes in
so what we do instead is pick up from its the former prime
simulation data
i mean that's that the parameter if the simulated data is close to the real
and by close i mean we're going to have a metric rho and
tolerance epsilon
and this work in the following sense that the first of all this is an
approximation obviously and this is what was sampling from with this and it can make
sense in the following way
if epsilon is infinity here
we cannot accept every single
value of theta
so we're left with is prior distribution
it's island zero here we're only going to accept theta if we simulated data matches
the real data metric we get a posterior distribution
OK so
epsilon controls accuracy
the same time controls the efficiency of the computability so we not very small we
accept very few feet tall very large amounts of lots of the decision of the
trade-off represents the tension between computability and accuracy
well there is another kind of just another layer of complexity
even using the approximation this kind of model for talking about typically have a very
high dimensional output so you're talking about genocide canadian expression data they highdimensional and even
that been a good so
is it really so much data some lower dimensional space kind of summary of what
we do is compared to some of the real data with summary of the simulation
output that close to set the parameters
if s is sufficient statistic here
as i mean sufficient in the physical sense of political information about the in the
it is sufficient that this algorithm is equivalent to the previous slide
of course you say if the likelihood function is no we can never know whether
any statistic sufficient to not to find anything difficult
OK is the simplest example
so let me just say that the accuracy of these algorithms is unknown need very
near the first proposed in
ninety nine we think by it's hard to tell and then mark beaumont bolding in
two thousand one made many well-known suggested community
and at the moment is not known how the scales so for a simple example
for gas distribution data comes from a normal distribution
but then is no
i mean
we give a flat
improper prior to the mean
well the generality we assume that we observe data that has the sample mean is
zero that's real data observations
the album to follows would pick a parameter from a prior distribution
simulation data using the parameter value
well except that parameter if the simulated data is close to zero which observation
and in this case we actually calculate what the approximation is analytically
know is is that the variance of the approximation
it's the true posterior
plus epsilon spread over three can
and so this is overdispersion the approximations overdispersion and the true posterior
i mean it is true in general that the estimates are conservative dispersed
well this one should be
so here the picture you've got the solid lines if you can see this and
the true posterior
the dotted lines the approximation and we'll epsilon decreasing in the approximation gets better
have to do more work do it each time
the problem with the algorithms
and it so far
that the very inefficient
so you probably spotted with sampling repeatedly from the prior distribution
so if you got a highly multivariate promise i motivate parameter can dimensions or whatever
you're looking for a regional high probability in
a multidimensional haystack very hard to find way looking for
the idea behind MCMC of course is that by correlating successive observations we can spend
more time in regions of high likelihood
well we can't do MCMC according likelihood but there is an approximate version of it
so we have usual proposal density q we the following because theta we propose move
the prime
thank you
and then we simulation data using that parameter
if the simulated data close again
we then calculate the metropolis hastings acceptance ratio
so usually because the ratio of likelihoods in here
but that is being approximated by this acceptance step
dominance of this
two clusters actually can proceed to class
this is what i get because like construction of course the similarities is just the
usual why don't we take the euclidean distance between points
the city
the idea is called the j
the distance between two points in the similarity to this one
this the one and as i said by construction dominance that we're find complex structure
so the fine for find this dominance over sigma
data and this is no way
let's do something
captured along structure
so there is the standard
normalized got worse
and in fact it shows what happens
here is another example
of course
of course i can do i can adjust the scale we have escaped parameter here
but of course it doesn't work because the scale
just to the
the size of the class become larger get into all sorts of point for example
because consider this
we would like to extract this class
and if we ground the replicator and with k parameter we get this
c so it over segments data
and then we might
this is what it does actually
complex structured data we can increase the the scale
but then of course we get everything but of course we also have lot
so there is a simple trick to avoid this problem
and actually this is quite standard for
those are ones which which by definition
extract complex structure
the idea is to perform some operations of the similarity metrics in order to
he able to extract a chain structure in the
but we show this with a simple example just the
mentioned the basic idea
because here
the set of lines
and suppose that
calculate the similarity between by using standard approach like this one
based on euclidean distance and then i have a threshold which says well this too
are similar or not seen above the shoulders down
so we may probably that
with an unweighted graph talking about with
this problem in this way
because course these two are similar but this two are not seen in this way
now if i ran the replicator dynamics here
of course now we are the zero one case
dominant sets to coincide
with the maximal cliques
we're fine i did this maximum weight
all this maximum there's no way
you can get rid
so in which case this simple trick two
let the replicator in works well is to close
the graph
if i give you a graph
the closure of the graph is the new graph which is the same that is
p one
and the reason that between two vertices if and only if the two parties in
the original graph are connected by
this is the closure standard notion from
so if i closed this graph
it is easy to see the end up with a complete
because of course this graph is connected
if i close the graph
so this becomes a large
well actually means
so if a if a around the replicator dynamics over the closure of this i
will get
the class was
the track this is called the transitive closure
now simple observation the transitive closure of the graph
we obtain considering the powers of which is that
in general
if i give you
the adjacency matrix of the graph and
and i compute a power of
and an integer
components in the same way i j k
this number here
as you
the number of
as after of length k
connect i and j
if we
the some is our so a plus a two
so we have a way to we have actually
simple what we need to compute transitive closure
so now let's consider the way the case by analogy
one idea for closing what we call a weighted graph that we
is to consider this magic here
these are all things that live in the air and then you have to the
set of things that live on land the leopard alligator pie fun and that's one
and here's grasshopper and b she monkey gone i said what's the difference between the
two ones that live on land
like whether you would want to encounter them
in the dark jungle ali or something
these are the theories what
well if you're brave hunter course you're going out looking for the leopards alligators and
and these are the mostly harmless
so basically what i discovered is an organisation that that's in terms of the ecological
niche land air and sea
crossed with whether or not you're predator prey basically with with more data more features
and more animals we should be able to pick those apart probably pick up predator
and prey as this as as a separate orthogonal dimensions from land air and sea
but here we don't have enough data for that
and if you if you look at the features that are supported by this is
exactly the ones in this spectrum so these guys all had features like is ferocious
is dangerous is a carnivore and those are the main things distinguishing them from he's
mostly harmless levels
this is this one is in the hands free
so who was it's true i said well you should you basically just ignore that
happens to be in this dataset but there's a few
the features are just predicates you can say in language like one of the things
you can say about the monkey is that a mammal another thing you can say
is that it's formula another thing you can say is it has both there's a
small number of these features which happened to be in english the labels for these
taxonomic categories but that's i mean that's just as far as the models concerned doesn't
know that it's just you know there's no difference here
being so is a mammal is this feature
it's one that's true just the mammals not the other and here's one lays eggs
which is true of everything except the mammals as far as the models concerned those
are just you know the the inverses of each other that no one one is
no more special other just so happens in this dataset you know
as in
much of the animal kingdom mammals don't mammals give birth to live young and everything
else doesn't
so that makes sense
so if when when it when it when a child learns the words mammal right
like what what in what sense today
learn it right or if you learn the word dog right i mean you may
have somebody telling you OK this is a mammal this as you can observe this
has various other properties right i mean it's true that that the word mammal
has it has a deeper meaning in some sense in terms of how you want
to organize objects but this but children don't necessarily have to know that initially another
does this model it's just one of many things you can say about animal rights
like has the first right i mean you have a is the fact that there
are mammals and what it so if you took there's only about four five features
in here that are of that sort so there's like is a mammal
there's also there's also is a canine which actually
of these things canine
i mean it's sort of
those are basically like noise i mean
there they happened or
and basically the so the dataset has this organisation and there are a bunch of
mammals and here there are a bunch of birds there are a bunch of insects
and so on right
but the fact that there's a feature called is a mammal is irrelevant pretty much
there is that it happens to be that it's clean with respect to partition but
so are lots of others right like laying eggs is also just as clear
o point of view and
the a
which is called the importance of queensland's left yes
well they are the clean well the
well it is not
if you took them out you get the same answer
there's not very many of them there's like four
there's a hundred features
so if you look at the clean features
most of them are not is a mammal
is that the that they are you saying it's hardly surprising given that there's a
lot of features which are clean with respect to the taxonomic categories that you should
get the taxonomic categories using
so has right so
among all right
just because i mean the clean the ones which are strictly strictly clean are you
know there's probably an right so OK so the so
yes in some sense it's hardly surprising given these features but these are so i
didn't really tell you these features come from other companies asking a bunch of asking
separate subject to just name features of animals so
i mean in some sense what you're saying what applied to i guess far as
i know any unsupervised learning and if you say well your model found some clusters
and yet look there are some features which are really clean with respect to those
clusters well this sort of
if if there weren't any such features it wasn't going to learn anything
right in the middle of this
this is the
well so for example that that's what was going on here i mean again the
people who listen the features were not told why they releasing the features the
and we were pleasantly surprised and we really didn't know what was going to come
out we were pleasantly surprised that this model was able to discover a totally different
way of organizing these animals which is relevant for some of the
some of the ways we think about animals particularly for not biologists but if we
actually care about interacting with the natural world and maybe if you like
we the criticism you have is more criticism of most conventional
kinds of clustering where you're only looking for one clustering and basically it's whatever clustering
you come up with if few models doing well is going to be driven by
you have most features four like the reason why the conventional mixture model find this
clustering as opposed the other one is that most of the features you know the
majority of the features that support any clustering support that one
as a dot product and that's a little bit more complicated and we need several
elementary things along the way so so let's take another set of questions and play
with them a bit it's not embarrassing if you don't solve them but it's good
to play with the definition to learn and understand it and get a feeling for it
so I will also give you some some hints how to solve these problems
so so on the last light we started with the sorry we started with the
feature not being constructed kernels from it this time we start with kernels and
look at some properties of kernels so let's assume all the Ks on this light
are positive definite all the points are from our domain X  and the first property
to prove is that if I substitute the same element twice into the kernel function
I get a non-negative number so which means that that diagonal elements of a kernel matrix
are always non-negative okay that's the first property  I wanted to prove that this so maybe
if you haven't done so yet it would be good to copy this inequality and you
can even directly substitute this kernel in here because that's the thing that you will always
have to that you usually have to check or prove so so I'll leave it up for
a few seconds and puff okay so so now you know this equality
is true no matter what A I you choose no matter what points X you choose
so you are free to choose what you want and I want you to show that
this is a consequence of that inequality  so it follows from this definition the second
point so this is already it's a reasonably easy one even though you need a little
idea how to solve it the second one is a little bit more complicated that's
why I give you a hint so in the second  case so here we have the
simplest we have only one point if you want we have a kernel matrix with
only one element in the second case we are  effectively dealing with two points so with
the kernel matrix that's a two by two matrix so if we compute all possible
comparisons of X and X prime we we are looking at the two by two matrix
and the hints to prove this this is generalized Cauchy-Schwarz inequalities to compute
the determinant of this two by two matrix so write down the matrix compute the determinant
and then you will be able to prove this now the next one  is
a little bit more complicated but the proof is relatively easy but the statement is
more complicated so the statement says if the diagonal elements are zero so remember
we proved before that they are non-negative so here I am saying if they are zero if
all diagonal elements are zero for all X then actually the kernel is zero everywhere so
if the diagonal is zero the kernel is zero
and the hint for this one is that you should be using the Cauchy-Schwarz inequality
to prove that and finally maybe we don't have to do all of
them but prove as many as you can was there a question no prove as many
as you can so the first one is if you have a kernel K positive definite
you multiply it with a number  that's not negative you get another positive
definite kernel likewise if you have two positive definite kernels take their sum you
get another positive definite kernel
if you have a sequence of positive definite kernels you take their limits you
get another positive definite kernel provided the limit exists the next one I don't think
I don't think you'll be able to prove that here this is this is rity pretty difficult
if you take the product of two positive definite kernels you get a  positive definite kernel so you
might be aware that there's a corresponding result of positive definite matrices so if you
take two matrices that's are both positive definite and they have the same size and take
the element wise product and you get a positive definite matrix which which is quite
surprising  this is a difficult result you to show and  so I think  you in
principle you could get up to here but let's let's see let's see how far you get so
you can do them in any  sequence you like and I'll take a break and then
we'll see how it goes so this is all correct however I would like another
solution for the first one and maybe someone else can give me that
and the reason  so maybe I should first just repeat because he didn't have a microphone
so he was saying okay K's positive definite therefore we can represent it as a dot product and now
if we plug in the same vector twice  we just get a dot product if we it
itself which is non-negative the second problem he was saying that's right down the two by
two matrix of K on points X and X  prime and then we compute the determinant
determinant determinant is the product of these two minus the product of these two these
two are identical because K is symmetric with  K of X X prime is the same
of K as K X prime X so therefore we get this times this minus
the square of this  of diagonal element moreover since this is a positive definite
the second mode
we don't know
in the long after something which is useful
that needs to be some kind of
democracy like john two
you have been knowledge about the
organic beings
or at least
needs the market
the crucial thing here i know what is being debated during the winter because of
that said that if he
can made
which is now
around the world especially when the one you know expected king
the first was is open
we can that
and we are
and on the
because this was changed
before the war
it is that this is about we've
you will be about european legacy
and so on you should
because you know the image is
and so on
the model which is
it to be
to these he got for model of
well that
why is this
something genuinely you because you know
that's it
all he change three years the no example
here i don't think there is pressure democracy growing trying to get to know what
i'd call
what i think they
if the
he invented something new
which is short for us
western cape
which if anything is even more
more than five to one but
but we can fix
well that will
this is the first
i think we should be able to come
movie police of
multiplicity of the market and
proposals not
we in iraq
and to be a little
who in the sense in relation to the united states
and so on
we are
the station building and so the police
the europe want to play
we already both twenty five dollars
is there
when we can see that we leave the united states
by the end the war one i think it's going to be the first part
was when
it is a united states
it's of the three
he call his book because that could lead
the for example
we were not less than americans for
so called islam
but you know for a couple of the united states
one of the second then we can talk about
there is no
invasion of iraq but
basically we like to play so
so the which
do not think he invented
in that sense we have now
apart from the dominican republic and so on
of which i don't think we can close
travis morgan morality problem
i don't think
something new
we have two basic model
more than
american state liberal democrat
that you have many gaps in a few nuclear for example here he turned seventy
you have gaps everywhere for put all blatant paula chip so
positive and negative information
so it seems that you have the potential energy like that and you can have
stayed here
over its state and paul h paul h
so quite existence of
different shapes
so they have to form a lot of experiments folks
and especially using these exotic secondary be most people hard
again even if they had done multistep coulomb excitation so they populated meeting
different states have two eight three state
and that look at the
the different properties of this excited state for example they are found that these two
states of the first sorry
this zero posted the second european state
it has
the opposite sign for the deformation compared to the ground state so you really have
to states
the same energy almost the same energy
that have different
so this is what is compared here
you have
you have for ten seventy four
you have these experimenter is some theory
and you had with the experiment a lot of levels and with the help of
the theory we can have construct some bands and uses the grandstand and paul banned
all bled bands
and here you've got my vibration high exit
so i mean that you have a new place that can be prolate oblate and
biaxiality is how do you can go from point a to in a continuous way
so you have stayed associated with that movement here
and it seemed that this explanation
works quite well so people now do the same kind
of calculation
in selenium and so the neighbouring nuclei to see whether this phenomenon happens or not
so you can see the shape coexistence when you look at the way function
so this is the function for the different states
so here you have fallen information here is overblown information and in between these three
so you see that the first band here is mostly played
the second and is mostly oblate and that you have try xntp
for the other band
this is one way
to know whether what is information
so now
what about new structure in nuclei
so i told you about this leads him into the nucleus where they have observed
that these nucleus do have a very large
compared to the other one and rapidly polio that it's about minute so why is
because you have medium nine plus two neutrons
so if you take away one of the subsystem for example you take away these
region nine you have two neutral it's bound
if you take away when you try new medium then and it's bound
that's why these medium it is found another
neighbouring so that's why when you increase the neutron number here
you have need to mine
nothing here lead to elephant
so all these properties are understood here to see whether
what are the as the properties of the external no problems if there should be
what are the most probable quantum number they should have in order to be
hello nicky form handle so these
picture now
if if the rank are
was two
this is the this is the number of
payment variables right
because the count of the payments
so how many free variables
well you know it's true right
what is the fourier matrix that's and rows and columns and variables that means
with the rank are
how many
three variables and we got left
if you are of the variables are pivot variables we have n
in this case
four minus two
three merit
you see that
first of all
we get a night we get clean answers here
we get are
and variables so there really were are equations here
they looked like three equations but there are really only two independent equation
there were and minus or
variables that we could choose freely
and we gave them no special zero one of its values and we got the
special solution
for me we could stop at that point
that gives you a complete algorithm
all the solutions to a x equals zero
again you do elimination
going on word when the column
when when there's nothing to be done on one column you just continue
that this number are the number of that is crucial
leaves and minus are free variables
which you give values are one two
i would like to take one more step
i would like to clean up this matrix even more
so now i'm going to go to this is in its
this is in echelon form
upper triangular if you like
i want to go one more step to make it as good as it can
so now i'm going to speak about the reduced
OK so now i'm going to speak about the matrix are which is the
so what does that mean
that means i just
i can i can do work harder on you so let me start
i suppose i got as far as you
which was good
notice how the
the role of zeros appeared i didn't comment on that
but i think i should
the role of zeros appearing because
row three with a combination of rows one and two
and the elimination discovered that
when we get row of zeros that's telling us
that they are the that of the original role that was there
it was a combination of other rows
elimination not
OK so we got this far
now how can i clean it up further
i can do
elimination upwards
i can get a zero above the pivot
so this reduced row echelon form has zero
and below
the payments
so let me do that
so now subtract one of this from the robot that will leave
was zero and minus two in there
that's good
and i can clean it up even one more step i can make the payments
the payments i'm going to make it will one
because i can divide equation two
by the pivot
that will
change the solutions
so let me do that
and then i really i'm ready to stop one two
zero minus two
zero zero one two i divided
the second equation by two
because now i have all one
in the paper
zero small
this is my matrix are
i guess i'm hoping
sign of linear combination of the weak classifiers
OK so i need three pieces of notation
so you have to remember what the string three things are
number one is the matrix
in the matrix and the binary matrix all the entries are either plus one to
minus one and the matrix is going to contain all the information we need about
the weak learning algorithm and about the training data so
in our case the rural access
it's going to be the training example axis so we get sort of one
news article for each
on the column axis
we get the weak classifiers
so let me just tell you
again what i'm doing i'm taking the weak learning algorithm and everything is inside
and i'm enumerating every possible weak classifier which the weak learning algorithm can produce
so there could be a huge number of these weak classifiers
and in fact in many to actually be enumerated so i'm never going actually enumerate
this matrix in practice
but since i'm doing some theoretical work work i can now consider the the matrix
just i'm going to use the sort of tool
OK and because this matrix acts as the only input to adaboost that contains all
the information we need about the weak learning algorithm about the training data and the
entries of this matrix are plus one to minus one
the entries plus one if we classifier j
classifies training example i correctly negative one otherwise
so for example
if we have this news article right here
and it it but it contains the term actor but it's not an article about
entertainment that we missed so in my mind one so if the article does contain
the term actor and
the article really is about entertainment imagine plus one and there are two more
there are two more things that two more examples i can state
they had matrix and now i'm going to introduce the this notation dt dt are
the distribution with over the training examples at twenty third member at each iteration we
have a set of weights one week for each training examples i'm just going to
write this without the which are always nonnegative and add up to one for the
discrete probability distribution over the training examples
OK so the last thing i want to introduce is the vector lambda
and the windows are the coefficients of the weak classifiers for this linear combination
now i remember my goal here is to construct this function so that
its decision boundary
is it good you know
is a good
so the decision boundaries good decision boundary so what i'm trying to do really is
i'm trying to find these lambda so that the function f has a finite decision
OK so just to recap all the notation
so the
the matrix is this very large binary matrix which
which has all the information we need about the weak classifiers and about the training
and at each iteration
we just two things in adaboost
we just away from the training instances
and we just the coefficients on the weak classifiers to to form the combined classifier
so we iterate until the blue in the face adjusting these two quantities at every
and then the and we sped the coefficients for the final combined classifier
i'm trying to find the final combine classifiers
because know that's my goal i want to have a final classifier so you think
be interested in these lambda t
because i want to know how the entities convert to what they converge to one
whether the
the decision whether function
made from lambda final has the maximum margin solution i don't know whether whether defined
going to give me maximum margin solution
but the problem is that that entities are really really difficult
try understand the convergence properties of those lambda t is not something i want to
do because they spiral up to infinity and they just there there's a big mess
so what i found was that studying the DT's it's actually much easier
and much more
much much more elegant because they do some very nice things
so what you should expect is that i'm going to be studying the evolution of
the DT is to try to understand what is going to do
and in fact
the DT's are going to
two things like cycle around
and in the case cases where the duty cycle around the lambda is the normalized
versions of the windows are going to converge so i'm going to be able to
understand completely how my are converging by understanding the convergence of the deities
so she expected data cycle in the limit
normalized lambda to converge
OK so this one more bit of notation i want to tell you which is
the edge not going to find it for you but the edge is can be
made from DT and from and the edges the number between zero and one
so we have the candidate from from data from and told you that tells us
how well we classifiers doing in each iteration
so if the weak classifiers did particularly well at iteration t
with respect to the way the training examples
and the edges can be large otherwise it is going to be small
so the edge tells us how well we classifiers doing at each iteration
so i remember what we're trying to do we're trying to construct we're trying to
find trying to understand lambda finals because our decision function is made from a linear
you know the vector lambda final
that's because of coefficients for the linear combination we want to understand what they converge
to in fact what we want to find is whether or not at this produces
the maximum margin solution
so in other words what we want to do this one
finally in the final and we want to understand whether or not it maximizes the
margin and the margin is defined this way
i just want to tell you a a little bit about this notation system hx
this is a vector so when you multiply them together you get infected
this is the i th component that so this is just a number
so i want to find out whether or not adaboost produces the maximum lambda of
this quantity i want to know whether it maximizes the margin
OK so what i'm going to do now
i'm going to change topics and i'm going to prove this theorem for you
released give some intuition about about the truth
as i mentioned that this is difficult to analyse because the margin was increased
so what we're going to do is we're going to take the dynamical systems approach
and reduce adaboost to a dynamical system in order to understand its convergence properties and
when we analyse the dynamical system in simple cases we're going to find these remarkable
stable cycles and luckily for when we find stable cycles of the convergence properties can
be completely understood
OK so the key to answering the question was really of example
in which at this convergence properties can be completely understood that something that we just
didn't have before and this was kind of like a black box you know you
just stuff into it and then
i mean you have all these no guarantees the right told you about but as
far as the marginal goes
all bets are off
OK so here is the dynamical system that promise you
it looks like this
does that look anything like the original adaboost algorithm
is blocked by the
so that sounds a bit intuitive still we're trying to think of dependency is passing
from x to y
and if every path gets blocked by the
x and y are independent of each other
so now let's look at sea
dependency is blocked by d
a path is blocked by p
there's is a node w on the path
such that it satisfies one of two conditions
the first condition is that
w has converging arrows along the path
in other words
the path goes down to w and then from w
and then neither w nor its descendants are observed in other words are in the
set b
that will block a path
if w does not have converging arrows along the path
so you go
i right through w this way or that way
w is
in the set b
if that's the case
then the
separate x from y
the core area of this is
we can find out what the markov boundary of x is in the markov boundary
effects is
the union of the parent of x
the children of that
and the parents of the children of x
this is going to take a couple minutes how many people have encountered the separation
OK the same people who don't have a lot of good sign
so let's look at some examples of the separation
again just looking at this graph
all right
it is independent of the
it is marginally independent of b
conditioned on the being the empty set
let's look at every path between a and b
so essentially the same and is all the path between a and b are blocked
the past
is blocked by c
why is that
let's look at this
has converging arrows along the path
great eight db
and neither seen nor his descendants are observed are in the set b remember the
set that b is the empty set
that only block the path between a and b
the direct path between a and b
but now
we we really need to look at all paths between a and b so
if we examine the past eight the
a b b b
the path between a and b
along a b b is the has converging arrows
and neither d nor and foreign set b
all right
by examining these we can tell that a and b are marginally independent let's look
at another
it is not the case for this graph that
it is independent of b given c
and let's consider that well
the b
in is path between
a and b
and that path is not blocked
so therefore
between a and b
you can think of it that way in europe with
intuitively from our rain sprinkler example
if you observe
the effect
two independent causes
conditional that observation
you know
the cost become dependent on each other
here's another intuitive way of doing that
if if i tell you
i'm gonna draw
two random numbers between one and ten independently
is because most of mainstream Bayesian statistics is about variables that uncertain variables parameters
that are real valued and this this message-passing type of algorithms seem to be much more
suitable when you have discrete systems but we do use them we do know
a bit about them and we use them in a probability propagation for example in forensic
genetics so this this is one particular class of model of computations that I use quite a
bit if you have a graphical model and it's what we call decomposable
decomposable means that there are no loops of four or more vertices which don't have a caught
so this for example here is the harish one there is a half there is indeed a
circuit there or for but it's got a cord across sure cuts it such gross
very you know very conveniently handled in in message-passing type algorithms because there's a
a sort of dual graph called the the junction tree which hello yes
yes exactly yes the same thing and what this graph is by the way this graph is a
graph that encodes the conditional independences in the model I've been trying not to say
too much about graphical modeling because you're gonna get a lot about that next
week but this is dual graph essentially is is captures the structure of the
graph in a in a in a slightly abstract way in a new graph whose nodes
are subsets of vertices clicks in fact of the original graph and then on such graphs
there are nice algorithms it's sometimes called the junction tree algorithm or the Lauritzen
Spiegel halter algorithm which allow you to propagate probabilities around these graphs in discrete systems and
that's how base nets work and you got is very nice simple computations which involve marginalizing multiplying and
then the after it properly schedule the messages around the graph and you get the essentially the
exact computation in Bayesian systems where the variables are all discrete and such it
you may well of met these algorithms in a more general context and their their
their ideas like  people leave propagation and so on where algorithm
is bit like this I used in situations where they don't converge even in
the convergen of final time but but those are the methods are not mainstream in in
Bayesian statistics because of the discreteness finally I'll say a few rude things about variational
methods excuse me I'm slightly joking but the obviously variational
methods are capable of producing a powerful inferences very fast and and there are
fantastic thing to have available to us and and yeah they in any competition in
any model in which you can do both the variational calculation or an MCMC
calculation yeah we realy don't need to have a cometition it's obvious who's gonna
win but I just have a couple of concerns about it such such
methods are sometimes characterize as being approximations to the Bayesian inference and indeed well there're various
versions of these but one I mean one one one standard one is to essentially minimize
the call back liable distance between the true posterior and the best approximation in a certain
function class and that's the the classic mean-field type approximation well it's several points about that
first of all this this is indeed a best approximation but it's the best approximation in terms
of the value of the function and when we are doing inference what we're looking for is
is essentially something in the horizontal dimension of that graph and the best of
my knowledge typically that approximation results don't quantify how far away for example the
maximum is of the approximation compared to the maximum of the posterior so somehow
try to find well calibrated means but
i will say that
OK so
so much
let x one
the x and the test examples
where is
predicted probabilities
probability of
y equals one given x y
he calls the i
as the the sum of the i
of the i
let t e
the actual
y equals one cases
in the set
one day
so much so
we have
a hundred test examples
make predictions
the i three test examples
and then we
add up all those predicted probabilities
then later on we get to find out the truth about the test examples
and we find and we discovered that among these and test examples t was the
actual number of
so what can we say about the relationship between s and t
if the probabilities are well calibrated
should be
plus or minus
random noise
so the
the expected value of t
and this is
and this is something that you can only say
the probabilities are well calibrated
and so this is a big advantage of having well calibrated examples and the the
scenario that i think illustrates very well so you know
airlines always overbooked flights
and my
but then they need to make a decision of how much the overbooked flight
if a hundred seats on the plane should set one hundred ten tickets also should
use one hundred twenty tickets
and love
so in order to make that decision they really need to estimate for each flight
how many people
they're going to be no shows
so one way to do that and because they have lots of training data about
your millions of past passengers and freight sparse passenger they know whether that person
was the notion
and they know there is characteristics of these passengers in particular they no behavioral characteristics
like the passenger buys tickets the same day the previous week the previous month more
than a month earlier and so on
and so
what they can do is among
build a classifier
they can train a classifier to try and predict for each person for each flight
is this person going to be no show
and i'm sure they could train decision trees
and get some reasonable accuracy
that you know if it's a business process
and they bought their tickets
a day before
then they are more likely to be a no show
and if they bought their ticket one hour before they're less likely to be show
so you could come up with some pretty good predictions about who is going to
be you know show
then i don't really care about that
they don't really care about who know show they just care about how many no-shows
there are
this is so this is the number they really care about
and then this is the estimate they would like to get so what they really
want to do is
run the predictive model on every passenger
was booked on the plane then just add up the probably being no-shows and that's
the estimate of the total number of no-shows
which is what really matters
but they can only do this if the
classifier is
giving well calibrated probabilities you you can't add up the numerical scores you get a
support vector machine and get an estimate of the number of no-shows
so there is a fair amount of research on how to convert the output of
an SVM classifier into being well calibrated probability and the most widely used method is
take the output of the SVM
use it
a single feature so represented example by just one feature
which is actually an output and then train a one-dimensional just regression on top of
and that works some quite well in practice
yes so linear SVM the very closely related logistic regression
in fact they use the same month
sort of a linear transformation of the input examples
but then the key difference is that they actually use a different objective function for
training so for for training
with just regression with doing maximum conditional likelihood
the support vector machines are doing maximum something else
which is the loss function that involves the loss function is called the hinge loss
so actually
support vector machines are good illustration
of how
conditional likelihood maximisation i'm not the only possible induction principles
they make a lot of sense that widely used very useful
but i had an example with a mixture of two gaussians a show the conditional
maximum likelihood has pathologies and support vector machines show there is a reasonable alternative
but support vector machines don't give you well calibrated probabilities and so that you can
put it just rational top of the support vector machine
and that works well in practice the doing the just regression directly works well in
practice also
so that
i thought there was one more thing i wanted to say
so actually so
a fourth advantage of the just regression
is that it handles
unbalanced training data
there are lots of
machine learning applications where
we have the positive class the negative class
good afternoon everybody
this afternoon with and for about some aspects of group theory
in machine learning
they were sent maybe in the last two
years i have been following this time
it's a search
interest in which the algebraic methods
elements from group theory
in machine learning
i decided to to make a series of
small talks
about those recent developments
but the problem i i notice
regarding machine learning people
and these methods is that they have a certain difficulty in understanding the some some
of the notation some of the
the formalism
that's involved in this group theory was
as it as it is thought to usually
so i decided to try to make something more simple
and something a bit more based on examples
so those ideas could be
more easily grasped
so the this this connection between group theory and probability statistics is not new it's
quite maybe two decades or more
and by this has been
known for while in the statistic statistics community
but not so much in the machine learning community
and the person that developed most of the SS both papers connecting these two areas
of group theory and statistics
it's a man called the procedure icons these statisticians in
united states
and his two
phd students which became quite famous well rock more and muslin
and of course from that
you have
a whole bunch of people that do
that have
quite good work as well as suppose
it's quite important to be accessible because
the group theory that
material on group theory normals and it can be quite
counting to to start somewhere
keep in mind is named percy diaconis and this is the
the major refernce for this talk
all four
the model has to be here
OK so the outline of this talk
so the first thing a bit of group theory very basic representation
group theory it's very abstract thing
it's based on set theory
and the elements of the group it's normally abstract doesn't have
it can be you can have
different types of actions so only realise
the action of an element of the group by the finer representation for
so this is what we're going to have to deal with representation later this is
the basic
construction for of understanding and monica analysis on the group
later i'll talk about after take this
one cannot be more or less how for almost two first box
and then some applications invariant shape analysis group theory plays some role
and some things i'm doing recently
so these are the papers
that i mentioned that i followed recently
from the
flicking this this paper of the trees
from maybe
at the beginning of the nineties
so it's one of the this page is one of the
this diaconis boyd et al
this makes a markov chain with symmetry
it was in two thousand six
some applications of groups
theory in the ideas of
one of analysis
in order to x
the mixing rate of the markov chain
and the problem of finding
watching that mixes fast
this is
japanese has two papers of these one without symmetry one general another one with symmetry
his recent
paper thanks to the the seven
comparing partial ranks
o explains actly what partial ranking lists
guy lebanon nips two thousand seven
he extended the results of production flickinger to partial rankings
my is
the thing that's
that's unit in the cell
he started with a series of papers in NIPS
in one of the application of symmetric group
dealing with MOAT motor tracking of planes in airport
it was the first application in the real world applications found for
efficient computation in the
symmetry group
there are some of the papers from him as well
and presenting them as in the last NIPS there there were these
this workshop and symposium on
as you recommend
group theory in machine learning
it needs to know the name
and he is of a little bit of order this paper he was in the
it was the follow-up
that the one for NIPS two thousand six
and this two thousand seven was some improvement on the
results that we really got in two thousand six and is one here only the
thing that they do the which improves along the result
it's too
instead of dealing with
when they do the inverse transform i'll talk about which transforms into some
but here they when they invaded the inverse transform
you have to project back to the to the marginal polytope
and one thing that wasn't done before and with this project and you get much
this nation
so all those papers they are they were talking about things like this mela models
which is the probability model on this the group on the permutations
and i want to analysis on manifolds that she's
group is
what i mean by monarch analysis
of all things and when the canal is we're going to focus on fourier transform
last time i mentioned you
charge resides
at the surface of solid conductors
but that is not uniformly distributed but you remember that when that happens to be
one of the so that today
if i had a solid conductor
which they had this shape
i want to convince you convey the right here
the surface charge density will be higher than their
because the curvature
stronger than it is here
anyway i want to approach that is as follows
suppose i have here
a solid conductor a
it has radius r of a
and very very far away
maybe tens of metres away
i have a solid
conductor b
it was radius our of the
and they are connected through a conducting wire that's essential
if they are connected through the conducting wire
then this equipotential all at the same potential
i'm going to charge them up
so i can charge distribution
q a year
and i get to be there
the potential of eighteen
about the same it would be if b
we're not there
b so far away
that if i come with some charge from infinity in in my pocket
the work that i have to do to reach a
unit charge
is independent of whether these are not be as far away
tens of meters you can make it to my like you want to
and so the potential of a is in charge on a
divided by four five
actually non-zero
the radius of a but since it is only people can still because it's all
this must be also
the potential
of the sphere b and then is
the charge on b
divided by four five
actually non-zero
are these
so you see immediately
q the charge on the
divided by
the radius of the
if the charge on a divided by the radius on
we're for instance five times larger
then the radius of a
there would be five times more charge on b then there would be on a
as five times larger radius
then its surface area
is twenty five
and and since
the surface charge density sigma
it is the charge on the sphere
divided by the surface area
of often here
it is now clear that if
the radius of these five times larger than a
it's true
that the charge on the
five times the charge on
but the surface charge density on
is now only one thing
the two
charge density of a because it's area is twenty five times larger
so you have this
the highest
the surface charge density
you have
b five times higher
the surface charge density in there
and i hope that convinces you that if we have a solid conductor like this
even though
it's not ideal as we have here with these two species far apart that the
surface charge density here will be larger than their
because it has
a smaller radius is basically the same
so you expect
the high surface charge density
the curvature is the highest
the smallest radius
and that means that also the electric field will be stronger there
it follows immediately from gauss is small
if this is
the surface of the conductor
any conductor solid conductor
when the field is zero inside the conductor
and the surface charge here
what i'm going to do is i'm going to make a gaussian pillbox
this surface is parallel
good conduct
i go in the conductor
and this now is my
gaussian surface
the proportion of opponents of year essentially going to put discretizes based on
thing the points
in the right sort of the space
that's really the idea
the account is just
very clever discretisation of the space is automatically
you put point where it doesn't matter
you could send me of this the low dimensional space
well it seems that is not very relevant
instead of doing that you could do something in numerical approximations using the sum of
the masses well which would be much simpler
that have to do with the yellow
so we do in this case you could for example
in the binary you could maybe
just to get them agree with the points
at each node you the great the dimensional great OK that's what we could do
on then approximate apology density function
by the system
it on that and
we go to
plus infinity though this all consistent approximation of what that something can do know dimensional
space it doesn't make sense to do that
the problem is for us
you see that most of the point
on greater degree that you know i just knew well they have mass which is
essentially zero
so it's kind of west to find work to compute
basically the posterior distribution at this point because it's zero to deal with time
more and more importantly that
if you are not very high dimensional space
assume that you're trying to make the point on the function
in our in
i assume you're trying to do that using some kind of some kind type of
course so let's say
you're going to do
so x x x or xk belongs to are you interested in
in a meeting of the distributions the following distribution lies on our end you want
to degrade
so what i'm doing i'm opposing discretize each
the space of each state company xk
using p value
p value with you do that you discretize storyline each component but use
and you see that the
the point is that the number of points in the grid will be directly to
the and
that would actually this exponential of because i'm particularly interesting problem where n is of
all the one that you see that even if you are doing the work for
it they company by two values you we need
i like to need to deploy one on the hot that's ridiculous
this is useless so all these kind of green met when you're trying to work
supports nearly i'm unsure point distribution it's just not workable
but that's the only way we can do it
so that's why i monte the government the right things much more because we see
that automatically
don't really care about the dimension of the base that automatically putting the point where
it doesn't matter
it's not only possible and if you know if you have is that in our
again is what with you are you going to the mass of the wall are
the uniform distribution
i mean you get a lot of application you may have seen cases where you
could you could have like a significant like
the clever discretisation space
but this is what happens with happening with whatever
OK so
now because i'm telling you intuitively these these
multicolored of nations
this is just an empirical measure of distributed according to p
it makes sense
that makes sense to everything
it is just information well consider
consider that you are interested in estimating an expectation function phi
respect to
the distribution of interest
so to compute an approximation of these guys
using the monte carlo approximation of p
it's very but what is very good thing about this sort of nature
so what you do your interest approximating the i
well i've got
o point distribution here
you substitute to it the empirical
nature is the sum of the
at the sampled values are not used simply simple properties of
the that some function that is if you have
f of fire that there that you all act is equal to five x nine
it's not x OK so what using here
so you end up that you're multicolored which may be just the sort of the
best the idea is to function it may be that of course but this is
an estimate of
people have been on to slide because they want to make you deterministic approximation this
is one of the approximation the one then this coming under the distribution that these
guys are sampled values that one of
and point here
OK so now
what happens is it is it with you
this is the most part
by the law of large numbers
essentially we know
that that on the left or the right to buy
i argued
was the statesman b
of literally transforming human nature
as rousseau maintains
or is the sovereign a more or less
in the manner of the modern say
martin CEO
as for example someone like hobbes
it seems to believe all of our text that we will read the republic the
politics the prince the social contract
have different views
on the qualities of statecraft and what is not what those qualities necessary to found
and maintain states that we will we will be considering
all of this in a way
this is another way of saying or at least implying OK
that political philosophy
is an imminently
practical support practical field
its purpose is not simply contemplation
its purpose is not a reflection alone
it is advice giving
all of the people none of the none of the people we will study this
were cloistered scholars detached from the world of this is a very common
prejudice against
political philosophy it somehow
uniquely sort of pi in the sky
and detached from the world
but the great thinkers were very far
from being just so to speak detached intellectuals play-doh undertook three
long and dangerous voyages
to sicily
in order to
advise the king and ICS
aristotle famously was the tutor of alexander the great
marke valley spent a large part of his career in the foreign service
of his native flora
and wrote is an adviser to the metagene
hobbs was the tutor the royal household
who follow the king
into exile
during the english civil war
and lock
it was associated with shaftesbury circle
who also
was forced into exile
after being accused of plotting against
english came
rousseau had no
official political connections but he signed his name always
jean-jacques rousseau citizen
of geneva
and was approached to write constitutions for poland
and for the island of corsica
and total with was a member of the french national assembly
his experience of american democracy
deeply affected the way
he saw
the future of europe
so the great political thinkers were typically engaged in the politics of their times
and help in that way to provide us OK
with models
for how
we might think about
before break for refreshments
but this goes in a slightly different direction as well
not only is the study of the regime
as we've seen as just tried to indicate
rooted in
in many ways the practical experience
of the thinkers will be looking at but the study
of regime politics either implicitly or explicitly
raises a question that goes beyond
the boundary of any any given society
regime as i said constitutes a people's way of life what
they believe makes their life worth living
or to put it again slightly different what a people
i stand for
although we are most familiar
the character of the modern democratic regimes such as ours
the study of political philosophy
is in many ways a kind of immersion into what we might call today comparative
politics that is to say is it opens up towards the variety of regimes
each with its own distinctive set of claims or principles
each vying and potentially in conflict
with all the others of OK
underlying this took coffin a of regimes is the question
which of these regimes is best
what has or ought to have
on our loyalty
and rational consent
political philosophy
is always guided by the question
one of the best machine
but what is the best regime
event to raise the set of questions seems to
always insuperable
isn't that
completely subjective judgement what one thinks is the best regime how could one began
such a study
it is the best regime
as the ancients
tended to believe it aristotle and others
is there
is it in aristocratic republic
in which only the few best bitterly rule
or is the best regime as the moderns believe
democratic republic wherein principle political office
it is open to all
by virtue of their membership in society alone
well the best regime be small
closed society two generations
has made the supreme sacrifice
towards self perfection
think of that
well the best regime be of large cosmopolitan order
embracing all human beings
perhaps even a kind of universal league of nations
rest of
so this is a joint work with you know who you don't
so this is
this was some that
and we want
with the addition of ten
want to do this
that's all
so this is probably going the vision wasn't
basically because the strain
to shown
so the solution somewhat sequence
we can be reduced so that the example space
the station is going to
we had great
the first one is to do this
so that is very easy for you
points are
you can also the look as
this is the same thing
so the difference is also here for example
so to get to the
you can do is we can also be seen when we
that's one of the sequences
we know that we use for example but also give you can
actually use a prior to that she was
so what we want is one of the first system
well the world
i want to use these for about one centimeter
it is but you can just use england here is
for the square loss of people
basically because
and it's not going to be
so basically not everybody has the legal system
nowadays there are still
so this
basically we
they a simple motion
one of the following phases uses models who was
this is one
the first one to use
that's right
four so that we can the
we have
some people were
the same thing for the first
what to change
you know what you're
you must be
the club generating station
in the world
you're the decision is to be a
they are
so we see
and so what we assume is that wasn't going to let many of the original
and around twice in terms of people should
and we can use easily image space is a space
one is the density function
so we can use these as prior to say that this process is of
number one is going saying
so this is what
so you was
so to begin with
based on
but basically there are too simple too
that's the motion
well known
i believe that there is
hundreds of thousands of
and we want to track each
and you try to receive all of this
these schools
then they want to
as i said before there is a lot of things
so this is
the mission you or
this is
this suggests that the elimination of
two of the that is the
probably not
so to use
and you need to use
this is the kind of an adaptive control algorithms
and similarly if you know the the area of our web intelligence is again a
huge data of this
the kind of community people
and then you have machine learning data mining and also in the theoretical aspect of
machine learning for all of these things are fairly well connected and statistics another big
area that belongs to this area
a lot of the ice you know like you
if you're going to get
computer vision
again this a little bit of signal processing
i should celebrate a substantial about of signal processing and a lot of machine learning
data mining and in these areas
in fact all in my view one big area you're dealing with that in some
sense of course if the data has a particular properties then then you need to
know particulars set problems
so that's what you know definition of these things and and what you generally find
is if you if you do well in one area
you just go and sit in their area and between
within one hour you tend to understand it completely to some extent
i mean there will be always difficulties in terms of terms that they use but
once you understand the terminology
it's not these are very difficult to follow most of the literature very very quickly
this thing algorithms you know like in the in the in the community of information
you know that's again a huge
data mining people because they are
you can't build simple
machine learning algorithms in some sense
what you're trying to do is you trying to come up with some kind of
scoring functions
so that you can you can see
whether a document that is created
so you're trying to come up with a function that some of the
in some sense kind of the classification problem except the training data set is minuscule
don't have it all
so therefore what you're trying to do is to trying to hypothesize some mathematical modeling
this is how the
document mathematically represented
and because of that i can save my if mike really matters in terms of
the model parameters what someone matches then i see this document is like one so
you can see lots of connections and recently we've been working at nine hundred can
incorporate machine learning in two
entered into information retrieval
and you find that you
it just cannot just use machine learning because the real problem is that
we don't have
training data we have huge about you know the whole web is evolving for you
but we don't have
find that i don't think it even fits into
semi supervised learning in my view because
unsupervised parties so large
it's not going to help us in some sense
but we can do some kind of learning in incrementally learning you what you can
do that
and connects to work in inductive logic programming is holding technology program that i was
talking earlier for example
to understand the underlying
syntax of the fifth of language
that could be potentially down through inductive logic programming
and they could be there also tree based contrasts you can build
contrast that to look like tree structures
and then it those to start with nothing but
like nested if then function
so you can you can do those things and change in
changes in data streams again this is almost and this specialized area
in the data mining and frequent pattern algorithms
lots of frequent pattern algorithms that are written
so if you go to typically in ICDM conference
in a video you see some
three of four or five different kinds of
frequent pattern mining algorithms
it's quite rigorous in the mathematical sense
and i do you see some theoretical results of violence or sometimes know new definition
of a much better definition of frequent patterns
you know
putting some constraints
and and so forth so to me
the whole data mining is nothing but you know you have a model
and you're trying to either maximize or minimize
with respect to some cost
and that's what you're trying to do so
so to really do well in this space is to learn
statistics about probability rho
and also learn optimisation
as much as possible
you know convex programming is a among
and and also
in the standard of them this will give you
in know good
and much better momentum
for you to get moving to this area
and there's also connection with the granular computing and rough sets and also we don't
have to
OK so outline of my presentation is based annotations
and then
compare with a univariate contrasts
patterns and rule based contrasts
contrast pattern based classification
in contrast for a class
data sets
data cube contrasts
sequence based contrasts grow this contrast more with contrast and common themes open problems and
then i'll summarize then give you
lots of our
OK so
this the notion of contrast pattern is is quite old in some sense you know
the very feature selection
is a kind of contrast so what you're trying to do is
you know in order to do
you know the he's is a given data sets given
tell me what are the most important features of this particular dataset
you might have a data set containing let's say ten thousand features
and you know that there are too many know because of the difficulty you can't
use them
you want small subset that you know you might use some principal component analysis and
say OK
these are the
they can talk
you know
features that i can
reduce them and when i say
can it not necessarily can from these
what about ten thousand feet as i said it could be combination of them but
the reduced to
then after
kind of features the projected in
we collect all the outcome then there is
and we observe that k of these are our heads
so now the likelihood for the for the
for the entire
experiments each of the experiments are independent
from each other
because the coin
to me that the what
the outcome of the coin doesn't doesn't
it doesn't have any impact on what's going happen in the next
the experiment
now the problem here is going to be
we have k times will have property pi
and then it will have probably one minus
OK so that's the the the difference here
about whether you think of this as being an ordered set or you think of
it being an unordered set shown that
strictly only in the the number and the number of days
might be sort of like a combinatorial factor in front of it
so i'd like to believe that the way you think thinking about that particular sequence
you be that the likelihood function looks like this
that's an interesting thing that will come back to that the likelihood function
is the probability distribution over data over observations
not a problem with this is not the
the probability distribution over these things but this is not necessarily a random variable y
is just parameter
that would be about the important when we come to do
when it comes to inference
OK so let's say well how do we actually do inference in
in this model
so the class inference based on
the idea of estimators so if you want to if you want to make inference
about something and the first thing you do is you need to to invent an
and one of the
and then it was often used so-called maximum likelihood estimator
basically says well
that use an estimate of the parameter
the parameter that actually maximizes the probability
of the outcome that we actually observe
this sounds like a pretty reasonable
a part of
but notice that we could have chosen another estimate well so the maximum likelihood estimator
it one one kind of made
but in physics
people were
we're on proving
various properties of the estimated you can maybe can prove something about
a particular kind of estimator has some nice properties
and that would then be reason why this is a good estimate
that this matter although it sounds pretty reasonable it doesn't really come from anywhere i
just mentioned
like somebody thought lot about me
and this is you can find that military you can find proposal of
you know various kinds of estimators for various properties in various complicated models
what you do your classical
vision reinvent system
who thinks about the
well we different estimates for different estimator would be things like penalized maximum likelihood estimation
so you say well i want to maximize likelihood but also have some of the
constraints but i also want
or could be things like leave one out estimators you can you can estimate you
can manipulate you're your datasets are or
estimators based on resampling ideas of bootstrapping estimate somehow
you know you to manipulate the data in various ways and then you do inference
based on
on on what happened in the it
and it became something like you can you can
you can invent any kind of i can say my estimate fifty
no there no
there's no
there is no formal requirement has to be related to data like any procedure
we you can computing this is
the balance may not be might not have good properties
all right so what would happen if we actually effective by to talk to maximize
the likelihood in this case
we can we can simply you know compute the the
the maximum here we
predictive of the of the
likelihood of the log likelihood
and that they are one of the high then you get high should be
so this is a good answer
anybody have
it seems like the right you if you roll the dice
one hundred times in fifty six times comes out
or you a kind
times six times comes up heads
then the the
but think
very good
right that that's good at that
that's an important that say i flip a coin twice
and about two heads
now what's the probability
the zero
OK and zero means i'm absolutely certain that will happen
but that doesn't seem right
this something look at all about that and there are ways to fix
the properties of the system so maximum likelihood estimators are generally
if you have a very small datasets
there are are some problems there are you should you should worry about that
there are ways to fix these things conceptually
this is the kind of this kind of scheme you have to go through then
you have to think about an estimator that has
the property
one way
of of inventing the property
it's say well
let's pretend
we have
actually observe the head and tail before we start
you can sort introduces all pseudo observations
that we will
prevent this thing from ever reaching one as you you say well no matter how
many tales i observe
it could still happen but still come right in the probability if you only have
to make an observation then you have this sort of extra pseudocount then