now we have certain parameters with this algorithm that were mentioned temperature which
it is to be decreased gradually and these calibration time steps that is the number
of steps that are performed at each temperature
now more specifically
we talk about the so called a meeting schedules with the simulated annealing this is
so to say prescriptions
of how to decrease the temperature during the simulation process
just like in in the physical process if we call matter down too quickly then
the structure would probably not be regular as it should be
so it is very much the same with the simulated annealing as the search technique
if we perform in rapid rate by
decreasing the temperature probably not
find a good solution or near optimal solutions because we didn't lead the system
enough time to systematically
two two to search the space to come up with good solution
the annealing schedule actually describe how this temperature decreases and in our example we saw
a simple what we call calling plan which was multiplying the temperature in a certain
factor alpha
which is between
zero and one
and we had a certain fixed number of steps each temperature
this brings us to
parameter setting with this algorithm it is of course the question what is the appropriate
initial temperature what is the appropriate annealing schedule for each
it is
usually this is sort of experience it is everything that we need to be quite
careful cooling
this should be done rather slowly that is decreasing the temperature just a little bit
after every
metropolis procedure this will probably us toward solutions that is
even some theorem regarding this procedure this methodology saying that if we are really slowing
the temperature down
carefully very slowly then we are guaranteed to to find the optimal solution but this
is just a theoretical background which
in practice
doesn't help us doesn't help us much
because every problem is of course
specific and we need to tune this methodology
find appropriate solutions for our problem
just to briefly summarize this methodology
this was very successful in the beginning
especially in combinatorial problems
like in
circuit design and travelling salesman problem
then it was adopted as a general purpose methodology
and it does
in the literature you can find reports on different applications this mythology methodology
turned out to be successful
there was many extensions and upgrades like version of the simulated annealing court should accepting
which is
also were solutions
with a certain
not in such cautious way as in the basic procedure
then there is polarization of this algorithm
and it was also used to be
hybridisation which means combining different types of algorithms for example one such hybrid is called
thermodynamically genetic algorithms genetic algorithm is the methodology discussed later and the hybrid combination of
simulated annealing genetic algorithms is
there it is
not to be fair response but it does to the sustainment show you that in
the second so
so here's the kind of circuitry that we think may be involved again this is
hypothetical but it's sort of the working hypothesis so i told you the bayes allowed
to make the projects to the central nucleus the heaviest projections are to the medial
division and that's the part that i showed you that goes down to the brain
stem that mediate specific signs and symptoms of fear there's weak projection to the lateral
nucleus but it's not that bring the lateral division of the central has a very
heavy input to the bed nucleus and this is known to contain CRF and this
and this and this is not contain glutamate interestingly
what does have heavy projections to this part of the central nucleus is our cortical
you know what's anxiety anxiety is sort of worry it's rather cognitive and so you
know just for the fun of it i'm going to say maybe the cortical input
here which is going to drive CRF into the bed nucleus is something that mediates
something like we're because it is generally it's a critical phenomena
and so the experiments that we can do to try to test that not worry
but sustained fear of the following so we can put now
a CRF antagonists here and that should block the expression sustain fear and so this
is what we did martha of almost all do the same thing so now this
is sustained fear that is an increase in the world in a minute this is
the control condition
this is when we put the CRF antagonists into the amygdala there's no effect but
when we put it into the bed nucleus of the street from house there's a
significant decrease these are biased look awful because this was early data but david walker's
now replicated that along with the miles and this is definitely a real blockade when
you put the CRF antagonists in the bed nucleus but not the amygdala
the other way you can try to get that is to maybe look at this
and so if we put again a
a retrograde tracer into the bed nucleus we should feel cells
in two that lateral division and sure enough that's what you see
but if you were to
now make allusions
to knock out the CRF
now when you put the tracer and you should get the cells and that's exactly
what you see
and so we use the technique of cutting this pathway between the amygdala and the
bed nucleus to see whether would eliminate sustain fear
and this is just the histology from two animals so this is an not transacted
animal this is the lateral division of the central and this is the animal had
the retrograde tracer and you see a whole bunch of labeled cells that control condition
and this is the condition after we made the transition so the no cells there
so that's exactly what you expect
and sure enough again very low and
but we now replicated this once again that and the control animals show sustain fear
but when we do the transaction there's a total blockade of sustained fear
and so what we believe them
is that sustain fear is really nothing more than a continual activation of the bed
by this peptide called corticotropin releasing hormone interestingly that peptide is actually released from the
central nucleus of the amygdala and so we think and operational whale is think about
the difference between fear and anxiety is fear versus state fear and sustain theories do
to this release of zero
and this would suggest that if you
i'm interested clinically that seraphim tag should be very interesting compounds only for treating anxiety
but also for depression because there's a lot of evidence now
the bed nucleus is involved in models of depression as well as anxiety and more
generally medications that would specifically target the bed nucleus might be specifically selected were particularly
selective for treating anxiety disorders
i'm going to switch now to the end of the talk
we i substituted the bound variables because
they're doing something else the bound by quantify you can't
can't river mountain substitute arbitrary terms
that however
as it stands
is not correct
is not correct because it would allow some
inference is suppose we had suppose we're working in arithmetic
and we have
theorem that says for every number x
there's a number y
such that
why is greater than x
i assume we can prove that
in arithmetic
we don't want to be able to say oh well
why is that
is the variable
so we should be able to substitute here
right and get and
it actually consequence and we get the reason why
such that y is greater than y
by substituting y for x
no fair that
right we will
we don't want to allow that inference
the and obviously it some things
gone wrong and it sort of clear what's gone wrong this
this axis here
it was inside the scope of a quantifier here that was binding y
so when we substitute y for it that's not just some arbitrary term is that
already captured by this
quantifier we're already this special pleading
for that
that's not fair
not allowed to do that
so this axiom is subject to a restriction
the term t
should be as we say free
in a
what does that mean
the free for x in a
it means that
no variable
in two
twenty may be a variable or it may be a function thing with
variables inside it
what it means is that x
this is not free
the scope
of a quantifier
a variable that occurs in t
so in other words
when we make the substitution we're not allowed to create any bindings that were there
and that's to prevent that kind of nonsense
so what
universally true is true of any particular
provided no funny business
next and i get these in the order in which
rather than in these notes otherwise people get confused
OK well next is just clearing up junk
a implies for all x a provided x isn't doing anything
provided text doesn't doesn't care
you know a
OK if x doesn't occur free in a then for all x it doesn't say
anything other than a
because the
because it's very well doesn't find anything it's just
this allowed by the formation rules when it doesn't
doesn't mean anything that doesn't mean
everything is such that canberra's
beginning gold
but it's not the everything has got anything to do with
we just need to do that for
it's sort of for bookkeeping purposes
and then we need to be able to restrict quantify
you to apart
a is b
everything's OK
that everything's b
OK if a universal quantifier governing an implication
we can
we can restrict it to the to the arts and that's straightforward no
problems with that
and the last one
it's kind of weird looking
axiom scheme
for all x a
this is system
tanks which is exactly the same fashion
and so that's why it's creations
this is
right so
let's say that i think
nine days
this is the first fifteen years in know in the past few years
so the question is not
means in that this is which is much
o two according to doing
because you know every sequence of words and things like that
this is
right stick to discussing it is in these things
this is true
it's a few months
interesting to us
this is this approach to the topic for the last ten years
and this is what
this is
we have managed to so message passing
you i can see that in case
make sure refs and dissension
it was launched in the maximum of something like that
so this to this literature and
o which is that in the past few years which
the message passing even looking graphs so
this which i think
is that
i mentioned this belief propagation algorithm actually used
so let's see if you see
but that's not experts
so the system at risk
it's just belief propagation
in the last match instead but the crew escaped is actually in the next slides
for additional
wright's assistant that's
that's too message passing happens
this is of course for explaining that
it is and how that happens to show that this is this
and i actually
right so much what is going
so actually some concerts as games and so on and so forth so this is
statements and they do that
the applications for permission actually is essentially has to increase
once the is this and
which strategies to
coalition government
this is
this information networks
after thirty five some conclusions
especially in situations
actually it should be for you just sort of signals from year and includes you
can use this to just
and use it
so these used to process
fox try to give you some examples
that being said to the first
breakfast and
so it will break
so this is
it not to
people's significance levels and things become complicated inference methods
kernel k
because again if you have a kernel k
then in means positive terminal positive definite kernel k
it means that somewhere implicitly you have a mapping phi that comes together
so all this talk about a bit a bit more about that that
kernels must verify mercer's property i'll come back to this later
but the
what is important here the the technical details on the mercer's property are not very
important but it's just important to know that if you have a mercer kernel
it means that there exist a space h and a mapping and mapping phi such
that when you evaluate the value of k of UV then it's exactly as if
you were doing the mapping of u
two phi of u and v two phi of the and you were taking the
taking the inner product between five u and five of v
i mean that's again
all you have to do is to find a good kernel kernel that is a
mercer kernel you don't have to focus on on on on finding good mapping phi
but you have to find a good kernel k
OK so this is like to remark you you you have people that were turned
none valued non mercer kernels two two to do classification
it's possible
actually it's it's totally possible but they did it with the
algorithms that are designed to work with mercer kernels
so which is a bit weird but it's it works
and again for those of you who don't care about to mount mercer or positive
definite kernel
just think of k
as a similarity measure
here is the kernel trick recipe
first you can see the
they did
the sketch the
drawing on the upper part of the slide but the kernel trick recipe is very
first issues through your linear classification algorithm you for everyone
that is expressed in terms of dot products just as the first algorithm that i've
presented you have been of the talk
and you do have very very very simple thing and this is the kernel trick
you replace
everything everywhere every every every instances every instance of
the usual inner product
you replace it by
you don't even think about what you're doing
is OK i have an algorithm i see that they are there's a dot product
i don't care about the dot product i replacing by k
OK of if i see an approach between u and v are replaced by k
of u and v and that's it
and that's your kernel trick
and the magic behind that is that if you if you have
the kernel that is positive definite kernels
put the positive definite kernels then
you are in ensuring that there exists
a mapping phi
that is associated with
we that k
such that computing
so here's my rough plan of what i'm going to talk about today and tomorrow
today i'm going to talk about
some basic terminology
and then i will spend probably most of today's lecture talking about clustering
it's about mixture models which have been mentioned earlier
and then i will
talk a little bit about latent feature models
tomorrow i'm going to
i'm going to speak on some
a bit more advanced things so
essentially what i'm going to do is i'm going to talk about
how we can construct new bayesian nonparametric models
end i will try to use it as a vehicle to
present some of the work that has been done in the field
in the in connection with that's going to talk about something that also briefly going
to discuss today which is exchangeability
and if we have time tomorrow and i'm going to talk about asymptotics on how
you can theoretically evaluate how well your models perform
but today
mostly going to talk about clustering about directly processes scent and was related to the
good so
i have tutorial with you viete nips on bayesian nonparametrics and if any of you
have seen that a tree the first few slides things first three or four slides
are same
but after that i'm not just going to repeat that a like
okay so here's a very simple
very simple description of what we're trying to do in statistics
kind of cartoon picture of statistics
and that is we have
we have statistical model which is
the probability distribution of some
observation variable x
which describes our data
that's given parameters theta
okay and that i'm writing the fact that i'm writing that the conditional probability is already
in a way a bayesian assumption because i'm saying i'm conditioning on a random variable
you so the parameters a random variable and that's exactly the character what characterized surveys
so what i mean by this year is probability of data given some parameter
and the way i would like to think
about a parameter here is is to think about some kind of pattern
that underlies today
here's an example so this is a simple linear regression example
were be
the blue dots here
are the data
end the red line this linear trend here is a pattern
so in this case the parent would be a linear function
and his
slightly more sophisticated example which is again a regression example
and again the patterns a function but in this case it's not linear anymore
and this is the kind of thing that we can do with the girls and process for example
bayesian nonparametrics
okay so
if we
if we look at this picture here
what we're trying to do is we're trying so we are making an assumption here usually in
in bayesian statistics are generally statistics
which is in some kind of independence assumption
and that's basically what we're assuming is that
there's this underlying pattern this this is a linear trend here
and then the data that we observe
basically this pattern plus some randomness
and so the points are not exactly on the red line
they scatter around the line that some kind of randomness
but we assume that this
random deviations from the line have been independently of each other four different points
so that the assumption we're making here that the idea behind the inference is that the data is
underlying pattern plus some independent noise
and independent is
really essentially
i would ask you to
to reach this plus and a purely qualitative
passion yes that the much more noise could be multiplicative or something and just trying to say
this is a pattern and noise
all right
so in
if we're being bayesian then we assume that this pattern here
random quantity
and that is the basic characteristic of the bayesian model and the distribution of the pattern
is the prior
the prior distribution
what we try to compute is
when we have seen data we try to compute the posterior which is
the distribution of this pattern given that the data looks the way it looks
all right so
now what is a nonparametric bayesian model in a parametric model
and statistics a parametric model is a model which
first of all which has parameters of course
but it has some
fine print and fine print is the number of parameters is fixed
what the numbers at least constantly bonded with respect to sample size
so as we see more and more data
the number of parameters doesn't increase
and this is just a fixed
number of parameters
and nonparametric model
is a model which also uses parameters and so is really a misnomer
it's a model which doesn't match the fine print
yeah so nonparametric models where the number of parameters grows
with the size of the sample
if you think of the parameters you think of the number of parameters has the
degrees of freedom that the model has
and this means that the model can become more and more complicated as we see more and more data
okay so if we want to
now in
in bayesian modeling what we do is we
we treat the parameter is a random quantity
and be described by a probability distribution right so we have to take the parameter
space and we have to put a probability distribution on we call that the prior
if we want to do that here
where the number of parameters is not
and this term will disappear
that's all i'm saying is
if you could do this you'd be getting the right thing
and that's what we're trying to do we try to minimize the mean squared error
over a finite amount of data
and all those other
problems that come with
all this sort of suggesting is that we are heading in the right direction we're
trying to estimate
the conditional mean
it's actually oppose the probability
it's a property
the sum of squares error has nothing to do with the multilayer perceptron itself any
estimator you put in
i would have the same
as say this widens completely into other forms of of cost as well so in
the case of classification system we get the same
so the best we can say is that if we make mean squared error small
then the function we estimate can be
interpreted as an approximation of
the conditional mean
of the target date
which is what we would like
to be its
so we do the right thing is the message from OK it's not a silly
thing to be doing
the prose of the multilayer perceptron
because obviously we're going to have some difficulties creeping in here
the pros are its compactness
that you're capable of getting
very high
accuracy models
with very small
that was very few
processing units in
in contrast for instance to the polynomial situation where you have
this this combinatorial explosion
this whole question of compacts compactness or sparsity is here referred to in
in some of the other arenas come up during this week
it's very important
you should have more you need
many of these
OK it goes back to einstein and
occam's razor all these other things say your model should be as simple as possible
in some of the linear in the parameters type approaches that will crop up in
the way
you don't have to try to control their
size in some other way
the multilayer perceptron is is something that can
and naturally compact or sparse model
it's got a very simple training our
in its simplest sense
OK and that was very attractive back in nineteen eighty four
you know
fairly modest problem
on line PCA in those days would have taken it to full five days to
OK so take
a minute or two days one of these PC
will take some days
and you have very little RAM so you need a very simple
compactness this is this comes from a piece of rebar back in the nineties which
i must confess i never followed the proof
i just couldn't follow those
so skilfully but this is the result nobody's ever argue with it seriously
which demonstrates for
the the
situation of using polynomial bases
for increasing dimensions of
OK this is using the multilayer perceptron structure
the message here is that
the multilayer perceptron structure is capable of reducing the sum of squares error
after on normalized scalar
of the
reducing the
total sum of squares error
as a function of
the number of units is hidden layer
is not dependent on the dimensionality of the input
what we're seeing elsewhere for the series solution with this was strictly with the
polynomial is as the dimension of the
from the situation here we got the light blue line
but these equal to five
is it the ten days fifty
then what is basically showing us is the degree extreme sensitivity
so if you want to reduce your
got some squares error by a factor of ten
with a multilayer perceptron
and if we read across town to here
one ten
o point one
it says you require about
size size of about
hidden units
is relative
whereas if you've got for regardless of the input dimension whereas if you've got a
five dimensional five dimensional problems to achieve the same amount you need a kind of
a hundred hundred and fifty seven hidden units to get the same
reduction in the amount of
some squares
one easy thing to say
but certainly in practice it does seem that you can get very compact models with
these multilayer perceptron that's a big plus point
article if you want to do something in real time
on microprocessors
back propagation algorithm is essentially one line of code for each of the weights
OK is a loop
it's very very simple indeed
that is the thing that makes the weight
change over
over time and
seeks to minimize the means money showing that show you how simple it looks like
nobody is anymore
people that you know
this is great five minutes really nice successful tall people to stop producing some five
data if they know how to upload files to to serve FTP
but there's one problem and the output is not necessarily
very linked data friendly
this is the
here in the form
and when i when i generated the scientific the names of mcculloch chris and richard
this is the output becomes an artifact some of the
apologies for the quality of the rendering from the
from the project but this is basically
a few triples saying that if if i cut the top of saying that is
this person called tom heath and he knows this person called michael hausenblas
here's some details about how
a hash of his mailbox URI
and a link to where
some kind of agent can find some more information about him is basically a link
point to his foe fasting going go look this up
this is great but there's a problem in the right now without performing any kind
without doing any any inferencing then we don't really know this
michael hausenblas is the same as some make hausenblas over in some other document on
the web and even know without doing that
this is the same person as is described in his own profile
so what we need to do in this kind of scenario we need to add
some links to say that that this person here refers to this
the same person is this on the talk over here
well individually at your eyes to these particular little chunks of code to explicitly identify
the person that's referenced
this is what one of the the chunks of code looks like so rather than
having a blank node blank node at this stage we basically added in
you're right it says that this chunk of code refers to to this person hausenblas
so this is really as simple as it gets to take the social network information
the comes from five thematic make it into the data
in this case have chosen to use the either the because uses to describe to
identify himself and his own profile
increases example confined foaf after him on the so so in this case i took
the URI for the crisp which is generated by
semantic we semantic media wiki installation which is running semantic web to all the
in reality i could chosen any other URI for many other datasets identifies him so
i could have taken your URI from the linked data version of the pedia to
identify him
i could have taken the URI from data dot semantic web to or which is
the semantic web corpus of of
information about semantic web conferences
in the end it doesn't really matter as long as all these other your eyes
are tied together somewhere then it doesn't matter but i which one choose
in the
in the long run is best for me to choose your eyes which already
more widely used for two you always use the most popular your eyes then there's
the there's an increase in the kind of convergence the network effect which come from
this is basically of a property in the foaf vocabulary so there is a way
of identifying people uniquely without exposing their their email address
you know what what happens is that in the form you put you put in
the person's email address and that's prevented with with male to come along and that
string is then hashed
using shell and some shallow
yes exactly the idea is that the either if i if i know who chris's
email address and i cannot find the notices this him or supercomputer that can crack
and spam
o thing
we have a
the the idea was that the the people didn't want necessarily expose their mailbox and
we should be able to achieve some sort of of convergence theorem for nothing like
this one
this is
in case also linearly separable streams this thing to work
so we should be able to
do this is best the perceptron
so now let's see how to analyse this one
the prophecies is pretty simple
i mean there is at least the people through
oh by the way historical this algorithm is this here
can be viewed as a of basic is the first of all are going by
dates back to to nineteen sixty seven fifty seven
and this is an iterative algorithm for solving constrained convex optimisation problem
in which you basically
iteratively take the most violated constraint
they can use this
this is also a special case for the case of
of the constraints of the people that i agree
OK but
then the version that deal with nonseparable streams
our original work that been done recently by the machine learning community
but it is
in increasing in plane
between a musician
convex optimisation community in the machine learning community
as you might
observed by reading proceedings of the machine learning conference but it's extremely
it's an extremely active field
so now
let's do the analysis of convergence
so again
use patients of this is the hinge loss
on the example
and we know that by definition we just showed
that this is not the unknown example
after lot zero because this is the the way we may have to go back
to you
the fact that you have to what you think last year
but we know that for any of these conditions holds
so now we can write something like this
we can write the difference
but we can write
the hinge loss of
this is a positive quantity because we have made up so again we are focusing
on round
that were at the
because you as that the state of the art in the chain so we
you can just ignore
OK so that the place here
this guy here
positive and we can write
just because of this condition
as this paper
so we subtract zero
so now we can expand the definition
so we know that this is the maximum of of different was within their
maximum because zero and so the different so we can
and we know that the difference is positive because these guys are involved so we
can write the
the difference with picking out the maximum
so we can actually write
because we know
that is not the place this was one of one this
and we can also write these
which you know is wrong
that the achievement in one
that looks very simple
what we do now we just
because of these guys and they can collect the guys
so what we get is why the
the difference between the w
times the xt
which is the thing
so now
we can use it can use the ricci short here
in that
and the fact that y t
is OK what they can get so the next thing anyway it's more than one
so this is the most
the norm
of the difference between the w
in the normal vector
so we have now
the relationship between the loss
the hinge loss
so that for all
it is a symmetric
the action these valid
all this true
b is for free
can go through approval here
just so the face where f is reflexive
so we have seen previously that
if f is reflexive
k implies diamond
remember this is just
this is a
just to contrapositive form
that tx
so what we're going to show now
it is
that if
t is found in the frame
f must giving back
it is
there in
right so i suppose
box p
means that for every father each and every one
well you know
it's true
again provide country
this is the case
this means
that's that
that said falls
the reason no is
now define evaluation
and the environment few
the the set of all
so that's that
which is
it is the successor this
make people throwing all the subsets of z
now since
f is not reflexive
that is not
because they want to it
this means that
it also means that
it's not true
we define validation pieces that is true of
this means that
box p wise p is false
remember to make this true
made this falls
we make this true
showed peaceful falls here
books people true
so again we showed that
we showed it
really if it is valid in a frame in that very much
the same thing for the other actions
so to be clear in one point
guess sets
there are several more logics
it's not a model obtained by extending k with
standard actions katie
it is also the
talk about publication
and is KT four
no my s four
last light
eighty five o five
as far i can actually fine
as s four plus the axiom
s five basically
said that he
prams characterised as five
so the approach
so this means that axiom four is actually a year as before as
an extension
the moral operators we have seen so far
basically assume that there is a single agent
moving on the world
as it goes along
consider the case where there
multiple agents
i think this one
so they have their own sets of these knowledge and so on
to formalise this we
his introduce the family
one operators
box and diamond
we have set a
point region
this is called multi modal logic
quantum number introduced sort of them Back to the Future work we have brought in
the experiment by steering and gear lack where they sent the beam of silver atoms
through an asymmetrical on magnetic field and observed the deflection but deflection in 2 directions
deflection up and deflection down indicating that there was something strange that had yet to
be accounted for in several years later these to graduate students lighting them of food
goods men and women back proposes that the electron in fact spins doesn't simply orbit
the nucleus but as it orbits its and since we don't know the absolute up
or down in the universe it's possible that the electron some of them may be
spending lot of according to right hand rule they would be spending by our convention
anti-clockwise and some of them might be spinning clockwise in which case according the right
hand rule we would consider them spin down and in any arbitrary crucible full of
molten silver
half of them are going to be spent on behalf of the spend down and
sure enough we see that the splitting and so that's where we we left it
on friday so about viable maybe we can now go to the periodic table and
figure out what's going on there so if we look is that of the kinds
of electron configurations we would expect where x n equals 1 which is k shelf
we know that the selection rules allow for only 1 value of L and that
must be l equals 0 which the spectroscopy this would call lower case s and
under these circumstances and must be uniquely 0 and ask can take on values of
plus or minus one half so there's really 2 choices here 2 choices so there's
In the n equals 1 shall if we follow according to the selection rules that
we spilled the last day if we got any closer to this would be the
else shell and 1 equals to well l could take on the value of 0
or 1 and when it takes on value of 0 then and must be 0
uniquely asking equals plus or minus have so we've got to electron configurations when l
equals 0 when l equals 1 and can vary over 1 0 and minus 1
of us will always be be allowed to take a a half so I've got
3 times 2 is 6 so all involved in the shall I have the possibility
of 8 different configurations and we'll just do 1 more here so we get to
in history of and 3 that would be M shall by the spectroscopy notation 0
by the way l equals 1 would be the p p orbitals and so in
this case the delicate equals 0 balcony equal 1 where l equal to
1 l equals 0 then and 0 and explosive minus a half so I can
pick up to
electrons here in other words have occupancy states 2 electrons the orbitals you consider as
bins in which you throw electrons 1 again so here I've got and another 1
0 minus 1 that's against what has exceeded 6 years well equals 2 and can
vary party and can vary from 2 down to
minus 2
against customers have so this is 5 times to here and so this gives me
an infidel 18 so
you know there seems to be making sense and we talked about period is city
in properties so let's go and take a look at what we have and see
if we can reconcile this so if we look at n equals 1 here's an
equals 1 hydrogen and helium and indeed we have to electron configurations there over lithium
lithium is a equals to so here's to S 1 to S 2 and then
here the 6 associated with the 2 p and here's 3 s 3 s 2
and then
something's going wrong something's going wrong what I have here is I've got there's the
3 s
excuse me the 3 p there's 6 of them and now it's telling me I
should be able to put in 10 more but before I conclude in more I'm
already over the
potassiums for not only finished with 3 so clearly there's something else at work here
in other words these energy states are not filling just in ascending and number so
there's we need to we need to add something else in order to explain what's
going on in the periodic table and that's something else is essentially the the filling
sequence What is the filling sequence of filling sequences of electrons in a word of
thanks OK just on it by and health and S
inadequate inadequate for something else at work here it's close
but not complete and the answer to this question is given by the alpha about
principle of the Aufbau principle comes from the German word which means it's essentially construction
work or building build up principle and there's 3 components the Aufbau principle the first
one is the Pauli exclusion principle the poly exclusion principle which was enunciated by Wolfgang
Holly was an Austrian who did his phd under Sommerfeld in the Munich and the
post-doc with Max Born going and also with meals bore in Copenhagen so you can
see these people went to comparable schools they work with the same people in this
group and kept the vigorous discussion going eventually got a position at the University of
Hamberg worries a professor of physics
what he said 1st of all is that that in any in any system
of electrons that the set of quantum numbers
but again well in number and s
the set of quantum numbers unique unique to each electron unique to each electron but
the end of the system
the gradient's lower and the gaussian noise won't mess it up.
by adding gaussian noise during training
you can force these guys to be binary
more or less
then what you do
isyou take the binary codes that you've got for documents
so here's the document
we now have a neural net that'll turnitinto a binary code
you treat the binary code
as an address
and you go toyour memory space
and at that address
you put a pointer to this document
and if you're not a computer scientist, it hasn't occurred to you to worry about collisions, and if
you are computer scientist you know what to do about that, so you don't have to worry about
so now we've got a memory space in which
each address
may or may not have a pointer orachain ofpointers to
one or more documents
and we can do what i call supermarket search
so suppose you want something that's similar to a can of sardines
what you do is you go to the cashier in the supermarketand say
where do you keep the sardines?
that's what this function does
and then you go to where the sardines are and then you just look around
and there's all the things that are similar like that
pilchards and the stinson
unfortunatelytheanchovies, at leastif you're inamerica,
aren't there. the anchoviesareover with the pizza toppings
but that's just because it's a three-dimensional supermarket. well, really two-dimensional
this isa 30-dimensional supermarket
in a 30-dimensionalsupermarket, you can do much better
you can put
if you really had a 30-dimensional supermarket, you could have kind of
the organic thingsand the non-organic things, and the things that are reduced and things that
aren't reduced, and the things that are kosher and the things that aren't kosher and
you can have all these dimensions all the same time
you can actually model similarities quite wellin 30dimensions
if i want to find document similar to this one
basically what i do is i go there
i take that binary address
and then i enumerate the list of similar documents by flipping bits
and just looking at what the addresses point to.
now as far as i know there's no faster way to have your hands
on the list. you have to something to get to the next one and then
you have to followapointer.
so essentially this already has allthelists in it.
if this space has a billion
pointers in it,
they're allordered into, i've got a billion lists each of which is a billion long,
which is quite good for only a billion addresses
so basically
if i have stored with the document
halfa word,which is its address,
that half word that i've stored with it is a list of all similar documents
soi didn't have to do anysearch at all, i've already got the list
see, i promised you i'd show you how to do it.and it doesn't depend on the size of the database, right?
as long as you've gotenough memory to hold it
we've onlylearned with 20-bit codes
and it works very well
if you take the,
now you're gonnaget this list
and then you can apply much slower method
to the things you already foundthat arepretty similar
a slow method is called TFIDF which is sort of the gold standard
and if you use this is as a short list, it actually works better than TFIDF alone
and is much much faster because TFIDF only gets applied to things on the short
there is a fast method used fordocument retrieval, calledlocality sensitive hashing, and our
method'sa lot faster than that, because
it doesn't involve any search term
now i want to talk about
another application of deep belief nets
and i want to make the generative models more complicated
so let's think about
building a generative modelthatcan generate an image of a square
for the top level i say what the object type is
and what the pose parameter are,where it is and what size it is
what orientation it has.
so the idea is i mightwant my generativemodel to take this information
and convert itinto information about where the major parts of the square are,
and the problem is that
unless i'm very precise in saying where these major parts are,
i'm gonnagetamess. i'm gonna get things that don't join up properly
so it looks like if i just have sloppy top down information i can't get
a decentsquare out
i'll get one of these, and one of--this is meant to be a distribution--i'll get
one of those, one of those, and one of these, one of these, and so on.
but supposei generate aredundant setofparts, like the sides and the corners
andsuppose i know how the parts are meant to go together
thenif i give you this distribution, this distribution, this distribution, and so on, and say,
pick a consistent set
then you can get something like this
in other words the top down generation
could give me distribution for these parts
and then lateral interactions among the parts could cleanitup into an nice coherent whole
and in generalthat's a much better way to transmit accurate information
i have an example of soldiers on a parade ground
suppose you'reanofficer and you want a bunch of soldiers to form a nice rectangle over there
so what you do is you getoutyour GPS you say, ok, soldier number one goes
to the following GPS coordinates
soldiernumber two go to the following GPS coordinates
and that's a huge bandwidth, right? you have to tell them exactly where to stand and if you get it
OK so this is that
it's been a long day
let's go to the next topic which is from probabilistic graphical models
so it's huge topic and you know you could spend a semester and i do
defend but we're not going here we united colours so that the terms
in the beginning
he was there was some some equations so what i graphical models that it's basically
marriage of of probability theory and
graph algorithms
taking graph theoretical notions of complexity and argues that defined on graphs and applying them
to take for distributions over
very large set of variables
and this
the other thing to remember is that graphical models are kind of a language of
visual language that in many ways more expressive than
then you have to do with equations and et sort of it once again to
its current state of mind
almost where you know you can communicate much faster and your colleagues by joining something
on a piece of paper that actually writing out which you mean in terms of
so i think it's a powerful engine this is for me this morning when i
read the papers
the graphical models the first thing i look at is is the the picture of
the model and phi phi understand that then you know i mentioned in the paper
so so it's it's really
powerful i think it tends to sink way to to tell the story to tell
what's happening
your system or in your domain so so a language and a tool
OK so why should you care about graphical models and we we this we talked
about doing course supervised learning of course an unsupervised as well
governor model seven nice way of computing handling both handling both in a unified manner
that that's that's sort of consistent has certain certain deep underlying
guarantees principles because missing data one of the problems that we have in
both also gives in supervised classification might have features missing or you might have some
some superset in
probabilistic models can handle that naturally
as well
but i mentioned before is having a language
that can expresses things simply allows you to communicate much
much much
more compactly and expressed the structure we're trying to to say without
spending pages and pages
with the structure come
algorithms are going to exploit this this graph in order to do things like inference
you've all seen a lot of graphical models american instantiations agent comes
as common filters as my current fields in
and maybe other places as well it's good to study them also in the kind
of more abstract level because the algorithms
inference are
a much more general and concepts you all the other
all the other ones and seeking to learn once and i use everywhere else
and you know again applications graphical models are
throughout the
machine learning machine learning disability speech natural language processing vision robotics combine control communications many
many more
OK so
we basically get into two parts today one is representation so what does the model
meaning when you draw this thing what are you saying what the assumptions the implications
animals have to do is conditional independence
look at can be directed and undirected model
an algorithm for determining conditional dependencies
because baseball
the inference using the model
in the could to exact inference algorithms for that so i guess that this is
a small chunk of the whole
graphical models story but hopefully
something that allows you to look into
other literature easier
OK so
what's realistic models so for our purposes we assume that this the joint distribution or
a set of variables and hour talking about discrete variables
we can also generalize some things to two
continues from memory was gaussians but for the most part i think of these things
are discrete
what we are doing distribution
we can ask all kinds of questions that i have some evidence above we know
it gets multiplied by itself; it gets sent up there
now it turns out that'savery standard model of
how to deal with static images. it's called the oriented energy model
and it'samodel that's beenpushed along by, by neuroscientists
as a model of what simple and complex cells are doing
and by computer vision people
as a model of how to extract stuff from image patches that's useful
but it just drops out of doing this three way
energy functionthen factorizing them
except that when
it's proposed by neuroscientists or by computer vision people, it's not seen as a generative model
it's seen as a sort of a feed-forward computation for oriented energy here
here it's perfectly good in all directions. it's a generative model in which
the states of these hidden units
top down will determine the sum you compute here
and the messagethatgoes to there should be this sum times this filter here
or another way of saying it is
this factor
implements a weight between
pixel i and pixel j
thesearebothcopies of the same image,remember
so it'simplementing a lateral interaction between i and j
and the strength of this lateral interactions
is wif times wjf times whatever this sum is
so these hidden units by controlling the sum, that's kind of again on the lateral interactions here
they're controlling the correlational structure of the image
in the generative model
what that means is we can now
and we know how to learn all this
so we can learn
multi layer nets
by stacking modules like this
in which
at each level
the states of the hidden units
instead of specifying what the units in the layer below should be doing, specify the
correlational structureof the units in the layer below,
andunits in the layer belowhave to then run an MRF for a bit to decide what state to be in
they can also directly specify what the state should be
one reason that's really useful
if you think about what have vertical edges
like this sort of vertical edge here,
and you might think that a vertical edge means dark one side, light the other
side,but of courseit might be the other way around. it might have been dark this side,
light that side
and there might have been no contrast at all. it might just be difference in texture
maybe difference indisparity
so if you ask what's the sort of abstract definitionof avertical edge
the abstract definition
is about the correlational structure. if i tell you there's a vertical edge here
and i ask you, if you can't see this pixel, what do you believe about it?
you'd think you can interpolate from these pixels, but you'd be foolish to interpolate from pixels
the other side of the edge
so a vertical edge is really a statement about the correlational structure of the image
and in this kind of model
if this guy represents a vertical edge
what you can do is say
i'll have direct interactions here that say make the image smooth
that is, do interpolation
i make this factor
override those direct interactionsandturn offthat interpolation
so this model has a sort of expressive power
to allow
thingsat one level
to control correlations of the level below
it's a much more powerful modelthan astandard RBM
and we know how to learn it
there's asort of general principle here which is
peter dayan and i
made use of many years ago for reinforcement learning
you want a hierarchical system
you can have sort of guys at a high level tell guys below them exactly what they
should be doing, that's liketellingthe soldiersexactly whereto stand, and it's a mistake
it's not what you should do
because it requires high-bandwidth. it'll--it requires the guys at the high level to figure everything out
alternatively, the guysatthe high level can create an objective function for guys at the level below
it is all
on the
you know
and then and there are
that's all
i mean there are
you can
the most that
so that
you look at the distribution of
is the
it is
in fact
o thing
here's another
o five
so he
it's a
and here
it is that
one of her
we see
it's all wrong
but if you
the kind of thing
try to give you
some of these
that is there a
i mean
you can be
and that this is represented in terms of internal states which will say
correspond to the expected temperature the best guess
of the expected temperature and the idea is that this is its internal representation and this little but
thermostat hear
at hand the way that moves in relation to the heat source both minimise free energy
variational free energy
which basically means that minimizing the prediction is used in the sense that the difference
between the sensor samples and this predicted based upon its internal state representation
the difference between the prediction error at the level of these
expectation and prior expectation or privately so there are two quantities here had is satisfied
and his cartooning that's in the usual way here by showing the like distribution
the prior distribution
they poster distribution here
the key thing that i want to illustrate here that is that if i change the prior beliefs
i'm gonna drive the poster
towards the prior
which means that i have now
change the situation from the point-of-view action
that is now
that is still trying to minimize the same quantity but can only change the sensors samples
if i change the priors just do them
by this training prior beliefs basically the set point from the start
i pull
the poster across this changes
the security police are expectations it changes the prediction error and induces action to minimize
prediction error so that i can cause
we made these system here
fulfill its prior these the temperature has increased by moving closer to the thermostat so cells
it's a trivial example is just meant to
we recast
adaptive behaviour homeostatic behavior
purely in terms of inference i can reduce the problem now to minimizing free energy
in essence the survey
and somewhat complicated form sort of behavior that i'm gonna be
i'm trying simulator to understand
neuronal dynamics in the brain
just a complete the theoretical part as a this presentation as on the
focus on the nature the minimization
of variational free energy with respect to the internal brain states and action here
this also minimisation gonna be focusing on
just because they appeared to be more biologically plausible
the other approaches
based upon these equations here which you don't know too small to reed this more like this road
of how we get from the notion
while minimizing variational free energy
two biologically plausible simulations of active inference and
so neurobiological constraints what done here's just write down the
equations that constitute the generative process in these world hand they process determining these dynamics
action internal brain states has eight gradient descent
free energy
these told us here correspond to you if you
generalized states in generalized coordinates emotion
which simply hear mean
the state its first second hand
or higher temperature derivatives so far cast
the internal
brain states of internal states as a gradient descent
on these giant on these
free energy of these generalized sensor observations i actually induce other term here that corresponds exactly
to the prediction turn off the camera filter that we heard about in the previous
talk so here's the prediction turned and his the correction term based on the contention
that if
these prediction errors here
so i have a very general form four and form a minimization free energy
the continuous time
formulation here
using gradient descent or i need
realizes and produce particular simulation
the very nature of the model
that constitutes the system
the model of the external dynamics in the world i'm gonna be using hierarchical
dynamical model where so it's successional cascade
of state space models and on the state space models so these are disgusted differential equations where the output
of one
state and non linear state space model constitutes thee the forcing term of input one below
and so on until you actually get to be sensory data
and if i take this model
and plug it into this equation
i get these equations out
which again may look complicated from the about the fact that should simple all they say is that these
rate-of-change of internal states
involves the predicted change which we already have as we just heard about
that's a correction term which is a linear mixture of
prediction errors and the prediction errors
of simply the difference between what is predicted
what is actually being represented at each level of the hierarchy
the lowest level of the hierarchy of the difference between the sensory information
the predicted sensory information sources sensory prediction error
you're right well let's say you will that some people might recognise this has predictive coding
space generalize sort
generalize both in terms the courts emotion andin terms the nonlinearities
so both eight bayesian or generalized or extended kalman filter
found also it is exactly predict occurred in the both
the same thing from the point of view this thing
with one little difference i have to account for action but action is very very
simple because see anything that action can change
are the sensory
therefore i only have to worry about the sensory prediction error when driving action
so the action variables
very very simple in relation to the internal states that during the bayesian inference
and if you just look at about and look anatomy
what you realize is that these are
simply classical reflexes the so you get the knee-jerk reflex
just self-correcting suppression of prope receptive on movement prediction errors
so i've done is
derived from french minimization
predictive coding with reflexes
and that's
useful because there's a lot of biological
evidence in support of
predictive coding
i'll give you a couple examples to to solve validate the common
and in many at the rest of this talk
just a motivate so that these sort of the scheme the biological scheme
that implements as predictive coding
i've just written down
the hierarchical generative model in terms very dependency graph or in graphical form so we have some
hidden causes hear that excite dynamics and hidden states here
that produces an output that is sent down to the next level to excite dynamics in
some lower level of the hierarchy model that ultimately we would produce status is the world
generating sensory data
basically if i do bayesian inference and i'm versus model what i'm doing is trying
this is the tutorial on statistical modeling of relational data and i'm here to the
make from the university of washington
so here's what i'm going to do i will begin with a little bit of
motivation and then i will spend some time covering the foundational areas of modelling relational
namely probabilistic inference statistical learning logical inference and inductive logic programming
requests only do the very briefest overview of each of these
and then i will talk about how we can put the pieces together and finally
spend some time on how we can use of these
we can use the result for lots of interesting and challenging applications
so here's in in
in one slide the basic motivation for this tutorial in this whole area of KDD
most traditional data mining really thinks about a single relation
but the data that we mine is almost never in a single relation usually it's
in multiple relations and often they have very complicated interactions between them and we would
like to model these directly not after to first shoehorning them into this form at
great expense and effort and maybe even get results are not so good so that's
that's one basic motivation there's number of a number of other ones that are closely
related one of them is the following
statistical modeling
usually assumes that the objects that you modelling are all independent of each other they
i i d in the in the in the jargon meaning independent and identically distributed
but again in the real world objects are interdependent your data is not IID
people influence each other web pages point to each other you know things interact so
you can look at each one of them in isolation we would like to look
at at all of them together
another one is that we almost always assume that you know the the
type of that you mining is only of you know it is one there's only
one type of data mining in a given time most of the time however that's
not the case we have multiple types of objects we may have even whole hierarchies
of classes and we have multiple types of data
and you know things like text images databases HTML spreadsheets and often the things that
we want to mine spread across sources of these different types not just one and
again we would like to be able to handle all of those together
very closely related issue is that
typically in KDD
people assume that the preprocessing has already been done
and you know it
practice has shown that this is almost always will actually most of the cost of
data mining is
because we have to do the preprocessing and that's non-trivial we have to take all
the sources of data we have to extract the information we have to integrate we
have to clean it up
and we need to focus on doing these things better because it's actually where the
bottleneck is these days
and finally most of the mining today's or you might call knowledge portals
we have an algorithm with some very weak ideas embedded in this algorithm runs on
some data hopefully produces some results but there's a big distance between this and what
we would really like to get out of the data mining system which is the
actions that you need to take
in order to go from that actions we actually need knowledge about the problem of
how certain things because certain things how certain relations that are maybe not present in
the data but necessary for your inferences and for deciding what actions to take how
those things interact
so the way
to handle all of these things are placed one way one good way to handle
these things is to look directly at modeling multi relational data as multi relational data
and that's what we're going to try to do here
here are some examples of areas where these issues are important web search
of course is is is a very famous one you get better results when you
take into account links between pages information extraction very important area
in two different extractions interact one extract entities of different types more generally all natural
language processing and perception is another nice example medical diagnosis
people do a lot of work on medical diagnosis datasets they always assume that your
patients are independent
we know that this isn't true when there is an epidemic of something you know
if somebody has one particular illness somebody else is actually more likely to have an
extended family members of the court because you have been in contact with the even
more likely so
this is a good example of non ideas
computational biology another important area where were you know every single one of these issues
i mention this person
social networks and other very obvious one and you know one these days because computing
and so on the the examples go on and pretty much think every area
where we do data mining if you look at it carefully you will see that
the issues that i listed there are present
so of course trying to mine multiple relations directly instead of you know one simplified
a data set where there's only one relation has benefits and also has cost so
right so the idea here is that this is sort of an explicit information diffusion
mechanism so you know this is actually from a it can forward it to its
followers right so if a creates the this is it in his let's used in
stream of tweets they can be sort the press the button and say oh this
is an interesting thing i want to i want to include it as part of
my statement so that my followers get to see the right so these are followers
of the and the way you see here is an example of of what we
do and he says this was originated by some right so this was sort of
the original person who wrote this now somebody retreated that we can again be can
spread this this way how really to its propagate propagate through networks
right so if people follow people up the information spreads from top to bottom
this sort of
two two things two things how how we can we can work with content contrary
to what is nice about it is that we have called follows from network and
we have relative is sort of these keywords also the pieces of text that conveys
meaning hashtags in URL's and see how information spreads on the the set the third
way how we can information online is through what we call me that great so
means are also short textual signatures fragments that travel relatively unchanged through many articles in
the way the way the case study that i been talking about here is basically
is really saying let's look at the text that appears inside quotation marks right so
there a quotation marks in this text and of quotation mark and the interesting thing
is about if you take this spin data which means on any media the time
blogs you get about one one point twenty five quotes per document in the data
right and the quotes are very interesting because people tend to use quite a lot
they they follow iterations of a story as the story evolves and the other thing
that sizeable it's but it's very clear
who said it when they said it and where they said right so it's very
easy to attribute quotes to people it's much easier to called people the second or
prevents the attributes and kind of keywords events and right reason xing hung now i
have this the what's going up what happened here i have the quote i know
where happen it's very easy to trace those things so the first problem we find
out this quotes or particular some parts of the text is that these things you
take quite a lot so what i'm showing you here is this is this is
now more about three years old this is from the from the two thousand eight
u s presidential campaign just before the election sort of this is obama versus bush
election three years ago in november two thousand eight where i have a particular also
a particular quote here this is from sarah palin talking about obama palling around with
terrorists right and what i'm showing you here is all different mutational variants of this
particular long quarter long statement from sarah palin and the edges of this graph shows
some kind of approximate inclusion relationships so the way you can think about this is
the sort of information that the more complete longer pieces of information at the bottom
and ensure that these short pieces information sort of new data or were extracted from
this longer pieces right so this is usually shows you all different mutational variants of
a particular longer quote right and you can see that you know sometimes people must
have misspelled the change they change the
bands and they take a particular set part of the long quote and so on
right so the first task if you want to extract information this way is to
is to
the is story east of the story is to identify this mutational variants and one
way to to to find mutational variants of of piece of information or a quote
or sort of a short sentence is that is to form what they call an
approximate quote inclusion graph right so the idea is that they take a short quote
and i try to approximate and i do sort of approximate substring matching into longer
quote right so the idea is sort of to say if if i'm a particular
quote who who could my parents be right for example here eight ABC could have
evolved from a b c d or it could evolve from a b x c
right and if i would want if ABC would evolve from here there will be
zero and one OK
and what this tells you this one for example would be
all i believe that all possible probabilities of heads are you know equally likely
this is actually do you think that's a strong statement of using that's not a
strong statement
it's a very strong statement
because you're saying that you're you know there's a fair amount of mass
in towards the end so you're sort of saying actually
exactly this one here actually thinks
you know
could be that a bit of cheating
not so much as as in here
so the beta distribution has the following expression now let's ignore this bit for y
let's just concentrate on that's so
you see that that it has a very strong
i guess the guys in the end dancing because you have the heads of the
people in front of you but anyway
i would love use a by
to the power of alpha minus one and then one minus five to the power
of the ten minus one
OK so it's very similar to burnley so far this this bit here is very
similar to bernoulli distribution
in a certain way
you can sort of say
i have observed
that that i actually skip maybe skip the important thing you're for me
check back here with my slides
let's go back to this equation here
if i had observed the data set and i had observed
and going to assist and and
out came k heads all right
now the joint probability of that sequence of tossing
it is independent of the order and the reason for that is that
i'm assuming independence in my coin tosses OK so it doesn't matter in which order
they can i just i can aggregate the information OK i just want to know
that i posted and times and the work k head that's all i need to
know is of sufficient statistics as it were right
and now i can compute the probability of the whole sequence would be
pi timescale how many how many heads and one minus five
and minus minor the number of of tales OK so there would be sort of
my my likelihood
now if we look at the
the beta distribution
it has a very similar form
what this would be sort of saying so alpha minus one was sort of play
the role of k
and beta minus one sort of play the role of n minus k so this
would be like sort of saying i have observed alpha minus one
heads in my in my previous life so to say and i have observed beta
minus one times
so these two parameters help you encode
actually two things
the some of them are of minus one plus beta minus one is going
give you
an idea of how sure you are right because the sum of the two is
it is conceptually equivalent to how many times you repeat the experiment OK
so if alpha and beta are large for that too large quantity then the beta
distribution whatever its center is going to tend to be peaked OK
and now the ratio of
overall plus peter roughly is going to give you an idea
of what your prior is what the mean of the prior
it what you know
so here
for example this this is the beta
three three
no because i find beta are the same it's centered around zero point five OK
and this is the beta one one
this is the bit that sort of says i haven't seen anything
but i believe that it's really
how does everything but i have strong ideas somehow
OK so these are two possible priors that i could encode OK so how my
going to use this priors now
well now what what is it that i want what is it that i want
to compute
what i want to compute now is this is the prior and now i'm going
to say i'm going to observe
a coin toss
OK so now
as i said earlier
if this was the likelihood OK
the likelihood for the two possible outcomes to find out of second only once OK
it could be had or it could be a tale OK and the likelihood
was the bernoulli so it's going to be private was has is going to be
one minus five four stages
what is the
what happens to the posterior what are my beliefs on pi now
that i have my prior if i observe a single
head OK i second once on its head
OK what do i have to do
it's easy
i'm using i'm using probabilities i just need to use all the calculus of probabilities
i don't have to think that i have to come up with estimators or anything
like that i just turn the crank of
i already shown you channels about is all function class only contains one function then of course
the pointwise convergence is the same as uniform convergence
so then general policy now
we simply applying
right side of channel
we're done
now what if finding many functions in our class
if we find many functions it's also easy to solve this problem
what basically
uh one get something like this for each individual function uh basically at all
it gets a statement which is a little bit was only by a factor of
interesting cases is what if there are infinitely many functions
we can multiply the right hand side infinity so we have to
then think about other properties of these functions such that
the right side will still be effectively
and that
turns out to be the case
and so
that's just looks
just things slowly because two functions so what we have two functions
this all function class
we can then rewrite this quantity that we're interested in
it is
this the probability of a certain event
this is the probability of drawing training sample such that
four at least one of these two functions the training error
it differs from the test error by more than epsilon
so this can be written as the probability of the union of two events
and the first event
that characterizes the
training samples from which the
four first uh
function training and test error differ by more than epsilon
the second event
likewise fall
second function
and we take the union dissidents
we can actually up bound this probability on the right side
we can just rewrite it using basic rules of probability
this quantity
interview we have the probability
if the intersection we don't know about this intersection is but we know the probabilities
negative so we can
this quantity
but some of these two individuals
so there might be cases where
functions according to the principle of the moment in time but we don't worry about how
we just write something
therefore each other to terms we use telephone so we end up with this quantity from telephoned times to
and of course you will see if i can functions and we get exactly the same
factor in you
so that's the easy case
but just recall that
we are losing something in this step
and the something exactly the cases
when these events are not disjoint
now what if we have infinite function classes
interesting case
and in
this is the case that are shown in his work done for a long time
so there's uh you need an additional idea hard to solve the problem
and the idea is that
you look at this
and for dealing with
so here
and here is
which is the only the only refers points
and so
some are
the function class implying is twenty always
looks effectively finite because you
the discrete input points in the outputs of plus minus one
so this is always behaving finding this one
so what do we do about this
just to
the first point again
the training error
the same points on these points functions
i think was to be in space
that's all plus minus one point
and once is only to be in
different cases in that sense even if the function class is infinite
accuracy that's not the case but this
metric one can use here
it's course symmetrization it's used
in a lot of
process theory now
and the
basically through this but i think you will all leave me
it's a one these
triangle inequality time
this quantity which is the one that we're interested in
and we can all this
the following probability
and here we have the deviation between the training error and test error
and here we have the deviation between two different training errors
so basically what this
and we have some tools
what thing is saying is if it's the case that
whenever we go
two independent training examples
the injuries are close to each other
it's also the case that terrorists are close to
so this is symmetrization and if we use this
we can take quantity that we're interested in
i think you know we have
to empirical quantities
and the empirical quantities are effectively behaving violently
and then we have to
think about
and how does the behavior