as it well as it were
support for the features that i've learned through the years
really want they may or may not actually use all of them
but they want to know there
so fields
boolean search
proximity search user space basically TFIDF writing
some variation of that
and try to to make it scalable
two reasonably large collections but also work incrementally so they could added document and then
right away
and i have to have it all batch processing
and i was thinking about
it would be useful for collections about to maybe ten million pages was sort of
the ballpark
i had in mind when i started
so the architecture
fairly straightforward there's search API
and applications colony doing searching is an index is the average is called to
documents the index search API then calls index these clean modular distinctions
in order to access the index
all the persistent storage is accessed through an abstract API
so we can replace was stored how taxes analyse into words
there's an attractive you that you can replace
sort of the basics the indexing algorithm
probably the most notable thing was seen got little attention actually found
this is the last year i just i just saw someone to papers published in
the conference both
essentially lucene indexing algorithm and for the first time in in academic literature which shows
that any good ideas become obvious over time
i just or something like that
i think there is independently discovered with a paper reference each other saying that someone
else had independently discovered this
and one of them even said this is that a lot like what was intended
for years so so that
strategy the goal is to have the same behavior as optimal behavior which is
building this sort of multiway merge sort
but to be able to also have things searchable incrementally
and i think about process
if you think about
how a multiway merge sort works
which may be
maybe that's obviously maybe it's not so easy to be documents
and the idea is to create an index inverted index for each document
like this
and then you take a set of indexes
then you merge them into larger indexes
like this and then you take those larger index numeric them again so that's that's
the classic
that's what multiway merge in classic computer science agree now you can change things around
in time little and not necessarily do things in that order
but rather
you have three document
as soon as you get three indexes murdered up to one
then you add three more
merge up two second
three more third and then also you have three in the society merged those into
three more numerous this
you've added two more sources they were right now
in this in this indexes
if we have one index with nine documents one with three
and two with a single document so you would be the goal here
it's too at the end of the day doing
do the same number of
as if you're doing that the the the optimal
we're sorry but at any point in time have the minimum number
of indexes that you can
so you don't have to search a bunch of different indexes so they were able
to get away with it
four indexes
in general
you've got
log and indexes
at any one time
it is with this with this gives you which is that it's pretty good and
that's because i think i know that now well documented approach to
but having good
large scale performances well is being able to make small updates
so here's some
notes on this i think i can
mostly skip
there is
variations of change parameters can you get to make it actually look like other
indexing algorithms
search are in scene
are all based on merging
streams of postings lists of documents
so you've got
things ordered by document or the proximity search by the position within the document
numerous trees can also efficiently skip ahead
in the streams
two two particular document
you know again not the way that
most people i think in the literature had search before to to do it exclusively
emerging one nice property is uses memory space
proportional the query size rather the proportional size of the collection
so you even further
the most pathological cases of very common terms you is a lot of memory
and it has it operates in logarithmically in the same amount of time as any
other search algorithm pretty much
it has seen what's the full array of
and query operations
range searching and so on
what you'd expect
we've seen this
widely used hundreds of folks
reported on that they're using it declared that using it
is used in wikipedia search for you
wikipedia is just behind the scenes using the same for example
eclipse the development environment uses lucene
well this online documentation
what's it called
should the downside remember beagle
the desktop search on
on one x
it uses
does anybody here is the same
these are the basis for five folks here
what's interesting is all that before people here have not
and in cigarette smoke extremely fine dust particles
a few tens of micron in size
ideal for rayleigh scattering
and then we have light coming from below
and the right
is unpolarized light
light bulbs there
he will have lost
and it's very fine dust
scatters the light
you're actually what will be the core of the right
because the white light contains red green yellow blue everything but
the blue light has a higher probability to be scattered
so my smoke if the particles are small enough
well the blue
if the particles are not small enough
that's what we
well people who believe me
but not only that
variation comes up like this
and everything every person in the audience is an ideal position
you all at ninety degrees relative to the scattering because that's the way i made
the arrangement light comes out like this and then it goes like this so all
of you are very close to ninety degrees
so get your polarizes out
and you should see
that the vector
it is in this direction
four you there like this
for you there like this and for you like this so we're going to kill
two birds with one stone
it will be blue
and it will be linearly polarized
ready for this
OK now look at the smoke
that bluish
o agrees to say yes
or doesn't agree to say no
thank you
can you see that when you rotate your polarizes
that polarizer polarizer in this direction
you can see that yes
you can not see say no
thank you
now comes the double-header
if i keep that rotten smoke in my lungs for a while
in the paper
in my lungs will precipitate onto these small particles which initially are smaller than a
few tens of micron so you get rayleigh scattering
but now when i profile to smoke
you have
we know what drops because of the vapor in my the water vapor in my
and now the particles are too large for rayleigh scattering
and so this kind of light
i will now the white
in other words there is no preference anymore for blue over
and so
what i will do is i will alter to smoke in my once for a
just before i posted out
i'll show you again this
smoke so that you can have a reference of the color
so what you really believe this is blue
and then when i puffin out
you will see there is a distinct difference in color
it becomes white
so using three things that
number one
the light
that's scanners
very small particles few tens of micro
we first blue
blue has a higher probability
ninety degrees getting hundred percent linearly polarized but if the particles grow beyond a certain
there is no longer any preference for the blue
big difference
also the difference
so i can
we can see the difference in color
thank goodness
OK will have a break
i can we cover you can recover five minutes
four minutes
so the sky is blue
because light can also very fine dust
and even all density fluctuations in the atmosphere due to the thermal motion of the
and the clouds are not
because the clouds are very small one drop like i had in my lungs
so that's why the clouds
let's take a look
and you're standing
on earth
and that the sun being in this direction the day
here is the atmosphere
the thickness of about depends on how you measure it how to define it sixty
seventy eighty kilometres
and you look in this direction
and is white light coming in
but the probability that blue is scattered europe action is larger than red
and so this guy
works well
if you look in this direction
this angle is ninety degrees
not only is the sky blue there
but the light
from the sky and ninety degree angle away from the sun is hundred percent linearly
and that is linearly polarized in this direction perpendicular to the blackboard and you should
be able to figure that out for yourself now
so you have a linear polarizer
so we solve
this which which is our according number of states
one of the one then
some of these
l you
cumulative loss of the guy
the squared
norm squared norm of u
find the of the
a lot
normal you
normalized maximum norm of x
square root of the same here
this is because of the second equation you end up with a radical
OK now this whole for
for any streams
at any point of time
this can
this is a uniform bound to any point that was that we stop the algorithm
doesn't happen on the point about the when you checked we could just pop any
points and this was an invariant over there and the output of the three so
let's look at it
but this is
due to this is
if you move
so this is the
as a function of
OK so you have some of into losses
and the regularizer is regularizer
and then you have the
also this squared number the active here
which x scaling factor
and then you have makes the addition of water
but this
hold for
and you will see that you see there is a trade here
the city
you fix the stream
you as it change you
you may a new that is the shorter so you gain on this
but it here because you know that the
linda lost depends both on the orientation of the on the angle
of you but also the legs can reduce the heat loss by increasing the length
of your when we've been with regularisation
but this
if you like it i call this oracle inequality
i like it i mean this is the name used in statistics why oracle because
without caring about you
automatically the perceptron strikes the optimal trade-off
competing for
this is kind of cool because we we got this without making any assumption whatsoever
the whole
for any u anything any time
there's no parameter the outgoing parliament
maybe not actually seems to be the seems to be different colours after all different
bits of material stacked up to the point is you know the inference you make
is based on the shading and the contour if i manipulate the contour that you
make a different conclusion about what's happening in the sea so again fusion of shading
and contours
and in more
typical machine vision setting this is the kind of thing that we do here is
a program that is usually using stereo sound two microphones and processing the delays of
one microphone because of the other rather like your is do too
estimate where
well where a particular sounds are coming from and so on
when a particular person is speaking what you get is a whole cluster of hypotheses
clustering around that person
it is not very
it's not very directionally specific i mean sound you know you can that you can
you can be alerted to the change in position of sand rapidly but it's not
particularly precise whereas vision
it is far more precise vision will give you a very
precise fix on the position of a head but in this case you know with
the appearance only will be difficult but not impossible but difficult to tell who is
speaking with the sound and vision together one can home in on
exactly who is speaking so fusion of sound and vision are you know very doable
but it would be nice to have a generic framework in which diffusion of probabilistic
processing is natural setting which to do that
the last reason for using probabilities is
to incorporate the ability to learn so if you wanted to learn how to detect
faces i mean i suspect you know by this stage in the we if not
before must be preaching to the choir here
you know you would like to be able to show a program many examples of
face and perhaps all of examples of not of nonfaces and you what you don't
want to have to do is to try to describe
by hand as it were what the properties of a face you know this is
not such a crazy idea people spent decades trying to do this before they decided
that actually you know trying to write down rules about the placement of the eyes
with the nose was just too difficult and didn't you know did too difficult to
make it cover the variety that you that you actually see
and but if you if you are learned by example using any of the techniques
have been learning and will learn this week
of course you can very efficiently process training data and i think actually there are
two reasons for wanting systems to learn one is this idea of describing complex concept
is just too hard to do by hand and so you really like to do
it by showing by learning by example and the other is that large scales large
scale systems engineering systems well the vision systems in particular tend to have many parameters
in the need to be adjusted so you can sort of think about a realistic
vision system like maybe the one that the not one that is you know picking
up the motions all of those into of the body the rule for the parameters
in their potentially and i think of this as being a little bit like one
of those mixing desks you know that you have in the disco with the sort
of you know twenty rows and twenty columns here you for hundred knobs that you
have a look at the mixing desk and wonder if there aren't knobs on that
have never been turned on the whole lifetime of the mixing desk but
the point is that there are so many
parameter to control how are you going to do it by hand is just too
many more one two three knobs and it's going to be too many even for
someone who's you know become experts just to control all those knobs and therefore having
systematic procedures but just parameters by examples of good and bad behaviour surely the way
to go
here's an example of learning in the image domain that i particularly like this is
learning style
paper by david simon singh and his collaborators so the problem here is to take
a photograph and rear end written in the style of let's say van gogh here's
the van gogh but how are you going to how are you going to even
you know begin to express rules for
what van gogh
is like i mean you could sort of i suppose go to a painting manual
and sort of try to try to use the process to construct a random process
for painting and bias that random process in the direction of particular photograph sounds hard
you know british very effective way to do this is to take the van gogh's
and get your scissors and chop them up into tiny pieces but take photocopy first
and then this is part of the fragments of the van gogh
other than in some sort of nearest neighbour sense your model of what van gogh
is now you can imagine exciting that
prior model of engulfed with a particular picture and getting something you know that has
the subject matter of the photograph but in the style of i think this is
potentially money-spinning idea
here's version of it i particularly like this is bill freeman
who also worked on this idea at the same time and here is bill freeman
rendered in the style of pile
so you see learning of textures it's it's a powerful thing
OK so you know i know you're probably so long this before but reading the
probabilities i think is the only way to go and you know here are very
arguments why with respect to visual data
reasoning with probabilities is is the thing to do
i want to do that
i'm not
which is why
so if you think about what
first of all
surely there
one of them
but now
and so that's what we
see what i mean
t is
that so
if you want to talk about that the problem
i don't
it's just
i he is
what happens is
so now model
at that
it's because you have
it's the
so so we
i trying to
thanks so much
and this is what is being used for him
here the tools
that's all
so what
to have some kind of these things and will have something like that
so i see
you might wish to start with this
take those vectors that see those data and
and then you take these into the state and your mother model
the question is
when i learned all three things like that all three models
what do i have
and i initially thought when you got model at all
you've got three models
you got one model of the data
and you got another model of what those
feature vectors are doing you're not one of those features doing is not one model
and then you have pointed out that actually computer was one model but is not
the model you expect
so you might expect if you lose one model
it will be a big undirected models
where you have w three and w two there with
errors on both ends to me undirected
and w on their with errors on both ends
so the big balls membership
but that's not the model you've got what you've got is
a model where the top level
is was is a restricted boltzmann machine
then below that you have directed belief nett
one was saying what i mean by saying that is if you wanted to generate
from this model
what you want to do is go backwards and forwards here
ignore all this stuff go back as force here
until you reach equilibria
then having got
a sample of equilibrium here go to shock
so it's not an undirected model this parts directed
in particular when you go back and supports here
all these weights down here having no influence on what's happening
which they would it was under the
it's got the kind of valve that directed model has the things at the other
end is the unobserved and influences
there's no influence comes back from here when you generate
OK now i just asking to take that on faith and i'll explain why that's
true later
before i explain why this trial share nice example now one of these deep nets
doing something
you i don't want to do say
now i want to explain why that's what i do
OK so we first need little aside
if you take some factorial distributions in your average
you don't get the factorial distribution
i think typically don't
so in an RBM
if i give you visible that
the factory the distribution of the hidden units is factorial
if i know
i have say two visible but doesn't half the time i give you one half
the time to give you
i want to give you one you get actual distribution and give the other you
get factorial conditional distribution
when you have these two distributions together what you get is not a factorial distribution
we had to get the it all sorts of correlations
in general
it sort of surprised some
so collecting the aggregated posterior
was you train restricted boltzmann machines
and i show each of the data vectors in your training set
for each of those data vectors
you have the posterior distribution is factorial across the hidden units
you know the average all those distributions together
and you get complicated distribution
which i call the
aggregated posterior
so you can think of
a restricted boltzmann machine
this is something that takes the data distribution
and converts it into this other the distribution
this aggregated posterior across the hidden units
and the converse such a way that
the hidden factor
pretty good reconstructing a data vector
and then these hidden vectors have some complicated distribution
so you can think of it like this
one to find the weights my restricted boltzmann machines
that defines
prior distribution over hidden vectors
that is if i were to take this model
run the markov chain because of forwards
and then sample from the hidden units
i guess some distribution
that's the distribution model believes
and we'd like that distribution
to be a good model of the aggregated posterior that you get when you share
so in a sense converted the task of modeling data into two tasks
try and get this
prior over
in vectors defined by these weights
to match the aggregate posterior
and try to
to get it so that by using the weights again
when you convert hidden that indivisible that
you get the data distribution
in this sort of split into two tasks
both of which used the same parameters
so what we learned restricted boltzmann machine we've learned to do this and we learn
to do that will make it sort of compromise because using the same parameters for
now we can do is we can keep these weights for doing that
and using different parameters for doing this to do a better job of it
so really what we're doing is we're taking the task of modeling data
and we're splitting it in a funny way
into sort of parametric b here
and then this aggregated posterior which is the number of things
which also trying to model like this but later on we can model with something
which is actually can be a high-level restricted boltzmann machines
thank you another way think about the later
so you get two chances to understand it
so here's the way i think about what i just said
the probability of the visible that
given a restricted boltzmann machine
the sum of hidden back to this
the probability
the you generate that and that if you went to the equilibrium distribution
times the probability that given that you would generate the fact that
both of these depend on the weights
and to maximize the probability of the visible vector
well you'd like to do
is increase
these probabilities in here
and suppose i freeze this to
then to maximize the probability it somehow like to change the prior of hidden units
so this gets bigger
and you probably know from fitting mixture models so when you try and said the
mixing proportion in the mixture of gaussians
what you do is you make the mixing proportion be equal to the post era
of probability was used that has
so in general when you're adjusting priors you want to
to be more like the post here is that you've got using your current values
those priors
so that's what we can do here we can try and adjust our model of
p of h
to be more like the aggregated posterior the court
and this is basically what
randomized quicksort could be formulated as
and then randomize BST sort is going to make exactly the same comparisons is randomized
we're picking the room
essentially randomly
and over here in quicksort you're picking the partition element
randomly same
same difference
OK so the time
this algorithm
he calls the time of randomized quicksort
because of making the same person so the number of comparisons is equal
and this is true as random variables the random variable the running time this outcome
is equal to the random variable
the cells in particular expectations
the so
OK and we know that the expected
running time of randomized quicksort an element c is
and again
i was or there
OK so in particular the expected running time of these disorders and log obviously this
is not too exciting for sorting point
starting was just sort of to see this connection
what we actually care about the reason i introduces BST sort is what the tree
looks like what we really want is that search tree
the search tree can do more than sort in order to reversals are pretty boring
thing to do with the search tree
you can search in the search tree
so i
OK that's still not so exciting you because sort the elements and put them in
a random binary search
the point of binary search trees instead of research arrays
is it you can
update them dynamically we will be updating them dynamically in this lecture but we will
on wednesday on your problems
for analysis of warm-up let's say the elements are changing building one tree
from the beginning
with all we have all an elements ahead of time we're going to build up
randomly randomly permute battery then we throw all the elements into a binary search tree
that's what BST sort does then it calls into reverse i don't really care about
the traversal what i want to because you know we just analyse b
short lecture i would
what we want is is randomly built
bsc which is what what we get out of this algorithm
so this is a tree
from random BST sort randomized BSD
the a resulting from randomly permuting here and just inserting those
elements using the the simple tree in search of
the question is what is that tree look like
and in particular is anything that we can conclude
out of this
back to the expected running time of BST sort is an log
i mentioned chris only
what the running time of BST stories several times
the song
so this is the time of BST sort
on n elements
the sum over all nodes x of the depth of that now
death zero
and works its way down
because the root element you don't make any comparisons
beyond that you're making whatever the death this comparisons
OK so we know
that this thing is
in expectation we know that this is an log n
what does that tell us about the tree this for all nodes x symmetry
does it tell us anything about the height of the tree
for example
right intuitively since the height of the tree is they log in
not an
but in fact it doesn't show that that's why
we feel that that's just intuition but it may not be quite right and it
let me tell you what it does say
so if we take expectation of both sides
here we get n log n
the expected value of
here's morgan
so over here
we get the expected total that which is not so exciting let's look at the
expected average to
so if you look at one or and
the sum over all n nodes in the tree
of the depth of x
that would be
the average depth over all the nodes
and what i should get is data
and log n
over and
because they divided and
on both sides
and i'm using here linearity of expectation
which is log n so what this
what this fact about the expected running time tells me is that the average depth
of the tree
this log which is not quite the height of the tree
remember the height of the tree is the maximum depth of any no
here just running the average depth
it's like
example of the tree
my favorite picture
so here we have a nice balance tree let's say on
the nodes
or a little more
and i have one really long path
hang up one
particularly doesn't matter which one and i'm going to say that this path has length
the total height here i want to make it and
a lot bigger than log n
this is roughly log and it's going to be logo and minus three ten or
great thing
so most nodes have logarithmic i
and if you compute it's a logarithmic depth
if you compute the average depth in this particular tree
for most of the nodes states at most about half of them
the same
most of the nodes have high log n
and then the root and the most down here
which have
that's the most pretend
so let's
so most to and factors like at that deal
so this is
this is an
this is an idea
it's a
average depth i have to divide everything by and
and again would be rather large average
average depth
the average depth here is log n but the height of the tree is square
so this is
not enough
just another the average depth is log and doesn't mean that the height is large
OK but the claim is
two cases we motivate the matching loss
it's essentially using again
the binary relative entropy so
your age of c
could be this
the two i wrote this way
link function
inverse link function
these are convex conjugate of each other
and now you plug into
the formula
so by duality
logistic loss
is this one
is the same as the entropic loss
which is this one
and we were using this system matching loss for the logistic transfer function
our model uses two divergences one for the parameter domain
and one for the loss domain
when the two are the same
it's sort of the canonical case
it corresponds to what conjugate prior case
but they don't have to be the same
OK so this is what i wanted to say
bregman divergences
and how they relate to the exponential families
you can always go back to the exponential families
and sort of
clean intuitions from statistics
exponential families is the make mainstay of of statistics and whatever these guys have done
you can kind of look at and see how it fits in your thing and
learn from
the past that these guys have taken from
so that's why i linked
i linked bregman divergences back to
the exponential family
can forget about all of this complicated stuff the underlying probability distribution
maybe not so good at
doing integrals
so forget about that and just go back to the definition of bregman divergence which
is convex function minus linear approximation
you can completely characterize which break whenever this corresponds to the exponential family and basically
it's a bregman divergences with a convex function has these
of some of exponential form
not surprisingly because that
corresponds to
in some deep way to the to the
what a cumulant is in general
i always like to study
the simplest problems
i talked about in this thing about the experts setting which is rather simple setting
i talked about linear regression which was large simple setting online learning
now let's still
the simplest density estimation
the simplest case of density estimation
gulf density estimation
and i'm going to tell you
what we found out
using the methodology of divergences
and then i'm going to tell you
again here in alternate game theoretic one which goes a little bit beyond this stuff
and it's kind of interesting in its own right
so what
gaussians density estimation
you get about cloud of points
and is supposed to predict the mean assume the variance is fixed simplest case
so all you do is you take the mean
in particular the average has so that's a good thing to do but it turns
but for online learning
what's online learning in this context you get one point at the time right
at one point you have to predict the mean
interest in loss for half a year of
you get another point if to predict where the mean maybe of the previous points
that you have seen etcetera etcetera
c two this online
and the question is what a reasonable model and so forth
so the loss
in this context would be log of gaussians
densities which is of course quadratic very simple
now why we interested in quadratic well we take derivatives are linear and we're very
good linear
so we want
to derive for updates and actually what we want to bound is this kind of
the total loss
of the algorithm
the in hindsight best
loss of the best parameter
OK so
we get one pole we have i mean we get appointed carlos we get another
now we have a min
we get point carlos we make up another mean get the second point in carlos
make up another mean get the third point get lost
we some these losses
that's what this is this the total loss of the algorithm we want to compare
this against
the in hindsight best loss what's the in hindsight best loss well
you get all points
and you get the one that minimizes the total loss and actually that is always
alex that yesterday
the average point
the average of all the points including the future
the online algorithm does not the future point so it doesn't know this but
i still can compare the total loss of the online algorithm against the best of
so this is called the regret
now there's lots of models that we're all familiar with for doing unsupervised structure learning
but for the most part they assume that you know the right structural form and
then what we what we don't have this is what seems to be going on
in human cognitive development science some kind of a universal structure learner if you like
this is i mean admittedly ambitious but something which replaces all these different algorithms which
learned just to structure a particular form with a method is able to find the
right form of structure as well as the best structure of that particular form that's
best suited for particular domain
i'll just tell you since since time is almost up
just a little bit about our
initial work on this problem
the first step here is to give some kind of hypothesis space have different structural
forms that that we might be able to learn either thinking about what might be
going on for human child or in scientific discovery setting
and we're going to work with different structural forms that can be described by simple
generating processes using what are called context free graph grammars these are so-called
node replacement grammars where the idea is that these are these are we have a
hypothesis space of rules for growing structures
graphs basically by taking a node and its in and out links and replacing it
with two other nodes connected somehow and specifying how the in and out links of
the seed node go
get assigned to the new nodes and just by taking the simple rules
simple generative processes for graph structures we can grow
many of the forms structure that show up in basic models for unsupervised learning so
flat clusters are partitions
dominance orders chains
rings hierarchies
trees with late nodes by taking cross products of these
production rules we can take we can grow higher more complex structures like by taking
a cross product of two chains we can get a two dimensional space or chain
ring give us a torus
sorry cylinder
you can get the tories by taking two rings and so on and the idea
is to use these graph grammars to specify a hypothesis space of structural forms and
do inference at all levels of this hierarchy i don't have time to tell you
all the mathematical details are actually any of them but the basic idea is that
well the probabilistic model for this level is the same one i told you about
the smoothness model issue at all at this level here there is a fairly simple
kind of bayesian occam's razor going on where this graph specifies a prior over possible
so this grammar specifies the prior over possible graphs and there's a there's going to
be a preference for grammars to generate fewer graphs with with fewer nodes and if
fewer links because they have fewer alternative is just the usual bayesian occam's razor and
then we're going to do joint inference that both of these levels of the hierarchy
so here are a few results
she under various kinds of psychologically plausible real world datasets so here's here's result for
the animals domain taking the same kind of data i showed you before to different
datasets but again you start off with the matrix
at this level here matrix of animals and features
and what you learn is that
you learn
here we're showing the best tree but what this represents is the best structure found
for this dataset is the tree as opposed to a chain or or cylinder two-dimensional
space and so on and you can see that it's learning a reasonable psychologically reasonable
tree structure taxonomy but it's nice to know that
this model is capable of recovering what we think is the actual right structure that
forces are required to learn the tree structure in here here we have a different
kind of domain is here this is the domain of political opinions supreme court votes
for all the judges who served in the rehnquist court's
this is sort of the eighties and early nineties and what we what the model
recovers is a a chain one dimensional structure roughly correspond to the liberal-conservative spectrum with
thurgood marshall
and brendan over here on the left scalia and thomas over there on the right
you know that are familiar left-right liberal-conservative spectrum but not all but the models made
a higher level abstract discovery of structural form namely that this one dimensional spectrum is
the right way to organize this domain are the best most compact way of thinking
about it logically it could have been the tree structure or could have been a
two-dimensional space like this is the two-dimensional space recovered from face images varying in a
racial and gender dimension they were these were realistically synthesized actually have these two latent
dimensions but the model here is able to recover that as well as a to
recover the sum
so cylinder of latitude longitude for citizens the color circle
since i'm basically at time and i will skip the nice stuff about relational data
but we can do this same the same kind of things with relational data and
even study
look at the parallel this is the rate this is the heat flux
instead of mass fluxes heat flux of this is joules per
metres squared per second
goes as minus
some thermal conductivity times the gradient in
temperature is the potential
acting on heat conduction the way concentration the potential acting on diffusion
and this is thermal
diffusivity and then he says
why stop at two
let's go for the hat-trick let's go for three he says you know what this
is just like ohms law
this is just like ohms law
well you know ohms law as v
why are
but you can write the
as minus
the gradient in
electrical potential
minus the great electrical potential gives you voltage
and then i can write instead of resistance i can write conductance
so i can map that into
since i know v
v equals minus that i can write onslaught as the currency this is a current
if the heat flux this is a current it's a mass flux so let's write
always line up with potential as a function of current let's write current density
this is an switches coulombs per second per square
goes as minus
the conductivity g
the fee
by the next
so in one paper he unifies
electron drift
heat conduction and mass transport by diffusion
not there
not bad
this guy was in medical
it shows you the knowledge knows no boundaries
so what is diffusion let's define diffusion
let's define diffusion as mass transport
mass transport
atomic motion
by random atomic motion
like point by the end of the lecture so you'll understand what what it is
what does it tell us so far tells if we want to increase the rate
of ingress remember were still running this this doping operational BM forgot about our
but are silicon fab line here we're still trying to do this with boron so
it's telling us that if i want to get a higher flux i need to
get a higher gradient which means i need to have a higher surface concentration
so if i have a higher surface concentration
i will increase
increase the flux fly
c sub as which means thanks chris the pressure of
b two h six so that's good
but there's another way we can increase the rate of ingress
we can increase the rate of interest we know from experiment
increase j by
increasing temperature inside with the kinetics
chemical kinetics well
worst temperature i don't see any temperature effect here unless you're going to say well
concentration is density density is the function of temperature no here's all the chemistry is
it's inside the diffusivity because what's diffusivity going to be related to
if it's boron moving through silicon
diffusivity must be related to adam mobility
an animal building must be related to adam arrangements and what dictates an arrangement
it dictates bonding electronic structure you see chemistry is not just a litany of silly
laws rules and facts
there is a unity here
so the chemistry is all contained in the
and that's also where the temperature factors contain
it should come as no surprise to you that the temperature dependence of
always an arrhenius type relationship where
we have some pre exponential
which instead of a non arrhenius is denot
they don't honorary is when they talk about diffusion just put the not exponential minus
q not to be confused with the heat flux this is the term they use
and q is
the activation energy
it's an activation energy for diffusion
the activation energy for diffusion which reaches an activation energy for atomic motion
and you're not really going to see it rt
are simply
not to be confused with the rydberg constant this is the gas constant which is
the product of
ever get thrown number
the boltzmann constant you're going to say well how do i know where i'm supposed
to put the boltzmann constant here or the universal gas constant simple
the exponential must be dimensionless
so if the units
of q
joules per
adam then you're going to use the boltzmann constant if the units and q are
joules per mole then you're going to use
the gas cost otherwise you're going to be on pioneer factor six times ten to
the twenty third and that should tip you off that something is wrong
because you're going to get diffusion coefficients that are either
blindingly fast you have atoms moving at
gazillion times the speed of light for
you will have
five times the universe to dope silicon with boron that should tip you off something's
wrong and as far as typical values go
q is on the order of about two electron volts
or two hundred
killer joules per mole
when we're talking about
diffusion in solids
and i do want to draw attention clearly we're talking about matter moving through matter
solid it's gotta be diffusion in liquids we can have cooperative motion convection stirring but
you can have in kappa is narrow fissures you can have diffusion in the liquid
state and in the case of the liquid the
value is on the order but it turns out that of o point two EV
which is about twenty
killer jules
per mole
in liquids
in liquids give you some sense and that means if we plot
the natural log of the diffusion coefficient as a function of
the reciprocal of the absolute temperature as we saw before with the arrhenius plot for
the specific chemical rate constant you get a straight line with the negative slope
high temperature is
the left one over t increases to the right and the slope of this is
minus the value of the activation energy for diffusion
divided by the boltzmann constant or
the universal gas constant
that's the
that's the story
i want to try to give some insight into what the activation process must be
what's going on at the domestic level that we're trying to
activity for that go to this cartoon
we see the cartoon showing that this is now
diffusion of metal close packed
we see an atom with the vacancy next well that's the first
adam must diffuse into a vacancy
there's no vacancy the atom can move
but we know that have to be vacancies
we've already seen from earlier that it's impossible above zero kelvin have a vacancy free
can use the world
it's a matter of matching at the interfaces right
OK so
this is another research motivation
what is reductionism reductionism
figure how to cut problems in the small problems
and the small problems in the compose and to solve the problem
one of the reasons was kind of interesting direction to look research twice because this
his works extremely well as at times in the past
so in particular
computations can is it reduced to transistor
you think about it
just to one very simple computation and you compose the right way and
soon after
getting very good for rendering scenes
the basic element of rendering is rendering a triangle or maybe a very simple polygons
and then actually much science can falls is reductionist approach say
he take some
you try to figure out how to predict the most elementary things and then used
to compose these predictions two
figure out what specific on and so forth
OK so
the last thing is actually pretty easy to use
figure out what the type of the learning problem is
this is something she always need to do
and then
you can find some premade reduction
from your type of learning problem too
whatever learning and you want to apply
and then you just
composer these things
so in your data
and you get a predictor for your learning problem
maybe this is a bit easier than than other approaches which so were to other
another approach is to just invisible learning our
to solve
here the type problem
there's even caroline who is is a very good vision coming
on friday thank
he would say that the
right thing to do
is too
figure out prior over the different engineering distributions for the
and then
take the prior p with a lot of the posterior
so four three
may be specifying the prior
a little bit difficult
it can can be a turns
maybe this is an approach which what you just try something quickly
and it works great and if it doesn't then maybe this it down think lot
what i'm trying to say is that
this is
sort of a reasonable
first past approach any particular problem
very recently classification
and it may be worthwhile to specify exactly what i mean the classification
so these are pretty standard definitions
you have the classification problem is defined by some major
extract zero one so they think of the probability distribution you can draw example of
an axon pair the wisest is going to be one bit
the classifier something which is maps from
feature space
now one day
and then out
classifier learning algorithm
it's going to be given some
and is going to define a classifier
with small air so the error rate
is the probability that under random draw from the
classifiers from
you want to minimize their
so what is
very different
about this analysis from some of things you see
it is that we are not assuming
but the data
is drawn independently
and in the way
so maybe this is something which seems kind of
esoteric but it's this actually pretty important thing
the reason why it's important is
all announced going to tell you today
applies to
every learning problem of some particular time
think because you can always stay there is
producing some test example
and since we're not actually going to assume
training set
is drawn from the same distribution
this will always apply
there there so
i guess
we can only say
for any particular example there's some distribution is drawn from
this distribution may be entirely dependent maybe actually deterministic image destroy all the weight is
on one particular example
but there's always some process
producing the test example
and that's the process that was actually going to be analyzing
it's kind of
but it's interesting that you can
analyse this at all
you see what's possible
any questions about the basic set up
following this tricky
so we're not something i did
so this is the outline
i'm not going to go through four reductions
one is from importance weighted classification classification so that sets this one over here
another one is from
the class probability
predicting the fire
the description classification
and the ones from multiclass classification to classification
which is this
and one from cousins the classification classification
so this gives you some range of tools and hopefully give you some idea of
palace all works
so importance weighted classification
is very much like classification
you have importance is
the distribution is over
ontologies that works on the market because it's the
ontology library and moved so you get something like that so many human lives
o ninety between cities
that's fine
stick and call from them and so this is very important busy
so what you
that is get first cut
so as i said before getting a sense of the overall structure
and here we can get
and get some simple stats
about the total number losses of
o cruises
being present in the world
all the time
name is here
this is
more precise
how to what's going on
a particular person
this is what concepts are actually
same lck really
good question
the easiest way to find out is to click on
and i will give you a little explanation
well there
and more familiar with mean
so what
all the teams conjunction
restricted social occasions from so you can a lot
one of the most
it was
also for
the first
this a lot
so there are three times more than
contains and also
o and research as well as
o thing all these facts rules and
there's not much
so this is the way
first get very limited idea
a sense of what's going on ontology and we should say this we look at
the property tree
there should be no hierarchy
given that there are
the year
you get into the system so
just the surface structures may be just one the ontology
and we don't have any reason turned on and we're just looking
at the service of two thousand there will be different
ontology were name from the first of all you have to compare two but first
in the world
in area
parents which is war
and we'll see some ontologies
it is interesting is that there is no multiple inheritance
this is really here here also interesting structure to ontology is not
want are seeing
this also
now all
this search for
inheritance but the infrastructure will and in fact if i turn on tell just do
the trick jumping
you'll see that the
the reason for this is one case
we're get to the recently
just to see that all these things so as you can see which is more
americans just like the reward
one we get we get all of
and then we can navigate actually to that class from the look
so i wanted to understand
he said there are several different ways to
in the world
is that we
it turns out
just few
you might want to this
he said that
she is lot of so
of the cell
all right
one is you
at the problem is
so my
so it's more
even more
so this not a
so you see
and here
in try
just a new just trying to get
this is
so what
it was just the right thing
you will
well just read this
just as
this is what she
i would be any more which is
it can be shown
one train
you might not see what she heard
so she read
they were in
so here or
were used
i want to see her
you think
so we're going to
and here
i think it's really very
of her
and which
it's a very
in this work
all we know the rest
people first
at the end of of the war
this is true
this is one
so what you see here the rule is
well you are
this is three
the war
this was
you can
it so it's reasonable
or one
it's better
we know
that theta
is in the span of all the fall x
and wise
what the axes are drawn from the excise the wiser are drawn from the entire
now do prove this
that's basically what the theorem says here
well it's actually quite simple
we can always decompose theta parameter
into a space
into victor that
in the span of the fourth example wise
and something that's orthogonal to it
if i have something to say to
you can always decomposes into
data parallel
theta orthogonal
in terms of the inner products here
that the the text with the fourth example lies of fourth fixi wise
this component
doesn't appear
its orthogonal
so by it's very definition
this term is completely irrelevant
it's just the function of data parallel
now for that expression here
while the non square decomposes into the norm
of the peril
and the orthogonal complement
if we want to minimize expression
what's the best way what's the best thing we can do with orthogonal
well we to sierra
it is it's just an additional term in our expansion
and the consequences that
if this spam
five weeks on y
it is finite
then we have a parametric optimisation problem
he e
not just for me
one of my
i'm sorry what should read it to this is
the square brackets go around here otherwise this expression wouldn't make much sense
is depends on the surrounding the soil
so yes
that practice because of the
geo site
is the log
of the integral of the sun
of each to the
five of x i
with theta
now this expression here
i can write
has been the product between falling a x i and y
machine learning one one
let's consider this one dimensional
supervised learning task we have a pretty wide given x
and if you're given these examples these
green stars
course there's the true underlying function that relates the wise and the y axis may be some noise
and you're trying to guess it using these examples
that's a simple thing we're trying to do in in
here it would be very easy
in one week you see what i would be very easy isn't
i can do that
examples are insufficient number
that's can cover
ups and downs of the function you want more
because they can cover ups and downs and the function you will learn you basically
just need to interpolate decision on the next slide
so you can do it you know in a very smart ways and there's a lot of
statistical machine learning
you know
with very beautiful mathematics like kernel machines
that's nice and
what it doesn't really is it exploits
prior remember i said one of the crucial ingredient in machine learning priors
what's the prior here
prior is what people call the smoothness prior is
the value of the function you will learn
test point x
should be close to
the value observed in the neighborhood so the function is small doesn't change rapidly
so that's why interpolation works
that's nice
and we should use the prior
but it's not enough when you're going to higher dimensional spaces where they
the set of configurations of interest and becomes exponentially large
and maybe the functions you want learned are that's worth
then you get into trouble
because the number is the number of ups and downs the function you like to
covering number of configurations like two separate
could become
much much larger than the number of examples you could ever hope to get
what do we do
one idea people had
but fifteen years ago is we can solve the problem by reducing dimensionality
but we've shown with some some theory that
it's not really dimensionality
you can have a one-dimensional function
it can be very hard to learn
what makes it really hard as the number of ups and downs is the variability
in the function you want large
and furthermore even if you able to reduce dimensionality
it might not be enough
because the functions maybe the manifold on you which is data concentrate
very alive and actually we do see this in
in the applications
now this this idea of manifold learning however is very inspiring and it has been
inspiring for me and for many people
and again it relies on another prior so
we talked about one prior which is the smoothness and the second one here
it doesn't apply to every dataset
course like priors they apply to some problems but not all
in what it says here is not be
mass concentrates
in other words
if you get if you look at your data and you look at the variables of interest
and you consider completely random so uniform configurations of few variables
these random configurations
it would be very unlikely you would you would expect a season so images where
you pick the pixels independently you get these white noise
and these are not at all like natural images
if u if you look at sequenceof random characters they don't look like english
what's the chance that you produce a natural image by randomly picking pixels or what's
the chance that you will pick
and actually looking up english sentence by by picking characters randomly for a long enough
exponentially tiny
so that's is something about the kind of data that we are working with here
in many i tasks the data has this manifold structure the probability concentrates in
continuous case we think about concentration as regions
i've low probability
i've low
so geometrical view on machine learning is we're going to try to guess where this
probability mass concentrates
end in order to face the challenge that there's an exponentially large number of such
places where we could put a probability mass
we're going to go through this notion of representation learning
the idea is being in change
we can do a change of coordinates we can move to a new space
where things are simpler and potentially dimension so in the figure
we see this one dimensional manifold which is twisted
if only we could now
the point on the left
whose space whereas the same manifold now corresponds to a nice flat line even horizontal line
then the modelling problem which he would be much easier right on the right-hand side
you can just use a simple galaxy and you basically get it right
so the key is gonna be learning these representations that's
some we make
the learning problem easy
so game to emphasize the same idea
somebody gives us data that's what we call the empirical distribution and from a geometrical
point of you can think about these points in space
in the space of configurations
in each of those points we know that these should be high
we know that
if one of axes x and others why then
i one expected value
the corresponding wisely
right that's a raw data
and what smoothness tells us is
neighbourhood configurations
r slightly
and gives us a little bit mileage
but not that much in high dimensional spaces
instead would like to figure out the
these points are kind of aligned in some way they have some structure
if we can find structure
then we can generalize much more accurately
then with this simpler
as i units this will be as a unit
recall that one test which we write one capital
that's life is an extremely strong
magnetic fields
the magnetic field of this magnet
is only two-tenths of one that's a very strong magnets
often use therefore unit which is the gauss which is not as i unit
you see it often in books
in one thousand
standard minus four tests
the earth's magnetic field
the gas
so these magnets
about two
with ESI unit is that's what
if you look at it
or the screen of your computer
you have the fluorescent screen
and television there are electron guns
address this can be fluorescent screen
on the television screen o five hundred twenty five lines
and the electron gun scanning one thirty is of the second
and the intensity changes of the electron beams
create images
if you look at the
two from the side
the electrons
one moment in time they may
like this not moment they may be here
the rest of camp
so it's clear that if you bring a strong magnets in the vicinity
of your television screen the dual
distorted image
because you are now
the motion
of these
currently these electrons
there is a very famous
art is not mu pi
i will use this
for his part in almost every major museum in this world
has work
by now you like
with distorted images
using magnets using television screens
i don't want to compete with
nomura but i don't want to show this to you
i have there
television sets
and i have a very strong magnets
and i will try to distort the image
and give you
the best lights that we know how to
i suggest we
try to find a program that we hate
so here
is my magnets
there is an extremely strong magnet
and that's the
the television and that's the one we can get first
i don't know instead of
what about the
you i
i a commercial for commercial
i commercial now works closely
from my mac that image
you say that
don't do this clear
because once you've done this
they lead to look the same
but these electrons now
OK distortion
so quite OK
so you've seen
you seen that we can
with the magnet and moving charge
so that we can
change the direction of the moving charge
on the moving charges
if you have an electric field as well as the magnetic field
then of course
you have also the electric force
and so the total force
on a moving
charged particle
more than q
times the electric field vector
the crosby
and this of course we've seen before
an electric field
can do work on a charge
remember q delta v
positive can be negative but it can do work
it can change the kinetic energy of the charge
the magnetic field can never work
on the moving charge
and the reason is
that the force is always perpendicular to the velocity v
so the force is always perpendicular to the motion
you can change the direction of the motion which you can change the kinetic energy
so that's the fundamental difference
between the electric force and the
magnetic force
now i want to calculate which you to force
on the current that runs the wire i through it
and we have a magnetic field
so i'm going to be slowly going to be more and more quantitative
this by the way is often also called the lorenz force just the combination of
the two
that one certainly is
so let's start with a
a wire
and the wire
one is the current through
is the wire
and the current
as i
and let's say at this point here
we have a magnetic field
and the magnetic field could be defined along the wire in principle
i have the charge must be q
and this charge
is running through the wire
we say
drift velocity vd
let's first think about what happens
the code is zero
if the current is zero
at room temperature the free electrons in these wires have huge speeds
three million meters per second
way larger than the velocity
but they are in all
sailing directions
random motion in the film
and so
on each individual charge there will be four
the average out to zero
it's not until i run current
that these charges are going to walk through
with very slow drift velocity
and now for the net force
he went
you will
so this is
well comment
problem is very much
years before following
we already have
because people
well so
there you go
we have
the problem
of course
i also
so really is
prof PH
it is part of the first
i would say
i hope
o and
part of
and the in the
the that
because the probability of being
one was not
all best
it's very
very large space image
do not
no way
a similar
what best thing
using this
as well
but all
know what i mean
the rest
useful information so
it was
should be
one of
you know
these are all
the most common
very well
well all the
we should
it was not is
so that they can be
i don't really
that you can prove the only way to avoid contradiction is that p searches for
the first provably elegant program q that is large enough be but it never finds
it because in your formal theory you can only prove that individual programs are elegant
if there smaller less than or equal in size to be
you see
so what this means is that any formal axiomatic theory that only proves true theorems
can only prove the finally many programs are elegant and in particular can only prove
that the program is elegant that program is smaller in size than the number of
bits of axioms in your theory because this gives you in a way of measuring
the complexity of the mathematical theory
i view of mathematical theory of software program again this is my universal approach and
i view it as a program that runs through the tree of all possible derivations
from the axioms and mechanically produced all theorems endless computation and the number of bits
in the program but does that
is the complexity of the formal theory
and that's roughly speaking the number of bits of axioms it's also the size of
the proof checking algorithm
you know the sort of a natural measure
so if that's the measure of the quality of the complexity of the mathematical theory
a mathematical theory cannot prove that any program is elegant that is larger than its
complexity basically
it was what the shows
ah i think i would have been very surprised by this formulation this is not
how the this is on the completeness theorem but it's the sort of incompleteness very
different from kernels kernels incompleteness theorem is i am i am unprovable
and therefore it's true if and only if it is unprovable and so this is
a very different flavor result get doesn't talk about complexity with get result you see
it's easy for people to ignore go
mathematicians in general ignore kernels resulting going working as before assuming the mathematics give that's
the truth and assuming that the formal method for mathematics
the axiomatic method is is the way to go
and basically get nineteen thirty one exploded stream but people ignored why because the assertion
he found that is true but unprovable is bizarre it says i am unprovable
and this does not look like ordinary mathematics now i don't know if this look
like ordinary mathematics i mean mathematicians can ignore this too because they can say i
don't i'm not interested in showing that the programme is elegant
but what this does introduces the notion of complexity into discussion incompleteness so from this
approach not from god original approach from going to report you couldn't tell if
if incompleteness is ubiquitous if it's commonplace or that only happens in very strange degenerate
cases like i am unprovable
which looks a bit bizarre but this approach sort of suggesting incompleteness is a more
pervasive is big because it says every mathematical theory has a finite complexity but the
world of pure mathematics has infinite complexity
just if you want to just proving the programs are elegant for all possible programs
would be infinite complexity
you see so this makes incompleteness look very natural
state in complexity terms the world of pure thought has infinite complexity but many of
our formal mathematical axiomatic theories can only have finite complexity therefore incomplete is natural and
maybe should be taken more seriously
although that's controversial i believe
i believe that but
so so this is not in my opinion the most important consequence of these ideas
this measure of complexity the program size is impractical because i i only care about
i don't care about time i only care about conceptual complexity and i don't think
it you know the idea comes from the philosophy of the scientific method right following
lines and while while
but in fact i think the most interesting application in my opinion is
the epistemology to give you a new viewpoint based on complexity for incompleteness so i
think i still have
some time so let me tell you
a more
and even here this is a very simple
proof of incompleteness
and incidentally has the core library holdings a holding problem has to be
there can be an algorithm to determine the halting problem because if you could decide
if the computer program not
then you could decide if the program is element not because basically what you have
to do is look at all programs that are its size or less
decide which ones hold
the ones that don't hold you can forget about the wonderful to run them and
you see what they produce and then you could decide if some program that is
smaller than you are the programme that you want to cite as elegant produces the
same output
so then you could decide if it's elegant or not
but i've just shown you that you can
so that that gives you a different kind of proof of the unsolvability of the
halting problem so this is a different view
what this is about giving you a complexity view
but a kind of conceptual complexity ideas view of two famous results from nineteen thirty
one and nineteen thirty six currently cinnamon and turning thing on the whole problem but
they don't talk about complexity and what i'm point to make is that if you
put in this complex concept which i think can really be traced back to alignment
through her violin i maybe
stretching the point a little bit but you know like it's also
he just he knew about binary arithmetic i mean he had a lot of the
idea let's say he didn't put them all together like this but i'm sure he
would understand this instantly but he probably could understand everything and simply so that's not
OK so this is what point to make is the complexity this kind of complexity
shed new light on two very basic results from a nineteen thirty one and nineteen
thirty six by government are OK there is a
and this is a very easy proof of the incompleteness i'm sure you'll admit
there is a more dramatic
consequence of these ideas
can connected very closely to the halting problem
and that's the number
i like to call may go
this is a real number
between zero and one
so the idea of sort of here is
to take a look again touring solving problem turning showed in nineteen thirty six there
from this and these vectors
so big x one two x and b two b and vectors of
less than this kind of x one xn is the
sets of finite linear combinations
but you can make from x one to x and
that's the thing there
and you have
the notion of whether
you can
well i think there
the family of the exercise is said to be linearly independent if the composition of
any y in the subspace spanned of x one x and as the sum of
the excised unique
and then converts need for the same if the you know
it's easy to
expand vector y that is in the span of x one xn as the sum
the number excite now
this decomposition may be
may the uniform and its unique if and only if you're vectors
are linearly independent
so maybe i'll write getting example
you are
in all two
now we've just seen that if you take you
and the to be that
not in the same direction
then you can write any acts
in s
as this
well actually if you add another vector certain victory
let's see
this one here w
and it's still through that for any vector
here are two we can write it as the sum of
the first component u
chris second component in the press certain conference in w
OK but now this these these skaters there are not unique any more
and the reason they are not unique is because you can find
if you
let's see
if you add up human
and a smaller proportion of
and w two maybe twice time time w
then you get a zero vector
so each time
because you have this linear combination
residents in this thing is
maybe one search
one third of the
last two w is equal to the vector
then for any x in you know in r two
if you take those carriers here here here sorry those care
x u anxiety nxw and if you have two one one two XU and
one thirty two v and two two x w then you get you get exactly
the same vector again you two
is that here
yes there
so basically because you have a combination with nonzero coefficient that makes this thing you're
then this this writing there's not unique for linearly independent vectors
there's no such combination in that makes that decompositions are unique
and also
gives you the dimension of the vector space that is generated by x one to
xn and the dimension is exactly the same
the cardinal of the largest family of vectors that is linearly independent in the subspace
are these of dimension d
after two years of dimension two obviously
importantly when you're running this algorithm you don't actually have to visit every point in
the state space
remember the idea something is that we're just going to get a few places in
the state space and that's going to give us an idea of what's going on
in that problem so if our algorithm hat to visit every point in the state
space it would be useless algorithm because we might as well just enumerate them all
what we want is the
the probability of where the algorithm ends up
it could potentially see every point in the state space
and that's sort of what it means that it is valid because we're able to
sample from distribution
that's fair could sample from anywhere
we're not actually going to do that and so we shouldn't be
when we're analyzing algorithms looking where they can work we should actually be saying well
if they're able to sort of recover the frequencies of the visit every point in
space to the right frequency because many states it's never going to visit the
number time to go there in the run of the algorithm will be sorry
OK so
how do we actually do this i said that we want a transition
operator that satisfies these two rules and for this problem with three states redundant matrix
that happens to satisfy this this rule i mean i ask where a plucked matrix
from but
i think we can write down a quadratically size matrix so how can we come
up with the transition rule will satisfy these properties without having to do some computations
which was hard as the ones that we're trying to avoid and it's a bit
the opposite to the problem that are usually given in mathematics classes so mathematics classes
they will give you an operational cell derive the i can
values i can functions like vectors of this operator here we know what
and we know what the the i vector we want it and now we have
to construct and operate has i back have a lot of choice and how we
can do that
we don't need to be able to do it in some tractable and
this is the principle which a lot of people using this is usually an introduction
two books on
mcmc that allows us to construct transition
operators that have the correct stationary distribution and let's called detailed balance is actually very
simple principle
imagine that you've got some
walk through
you should should use state space is the trajectory of the you just look at
two adjacent states so sometimes it was in state x and the next time i
went to stay ex-prime so you've got a pair of two adjacent states the probability
of seeing that pair
in a very long run of the algorithm is the probability that this would be
drawn from the stationary distribution because
as long walkers exploring the stationary distribution
multiplied by the probability that given your there your transition to express
that's what we got on the left-hand side detailed balance says this joint probability of
this apparent pair appearing in this order text text prime should be the same as
saying the pair in the opposite order so should be just as plausible but you
would see this picture along walk which
at some point because the prime and then transitions to that's
so that's why i think sort of this what process is time reversible it doesn't
have a preferred direction it's just as likely to end up here again here is
the other way around
and so the reason that this makes things easier is that we just have to
cheque this condition for every pair of states we don't have to in order to
cheque this condition we don't have to do a big some all states or anything
like that and this condition implies the one we want the stationary distribution conditions because
we just some it both sides x the left hand side from the defects is
but among with some decided that this here is the probability distribution of x
the probability distribution sum to one so that from just disappears and we're left with
this and this is the distribution of we wanted the condition that we want
and things are not some has worked
it's mathematical condition and happens to satisfy what we want and
if you puzzle for the mobile industry some trust
removed one
which she
the problem
all we need some some
the image
o which is
there is some reason
i'm not sure questions or replace it with a different one and you can it
might be the thing say
this is the necessary condition
sorry it's a sufficient condition and that if have this condition anything we want it
isn't necessary condition
OK so
this doesn't have to be true for this to be true
and now it bothered me so you read these books and they give you this
sort of magical
rule and they say make your change satisfy detailed balance and that's what happened this
a sufficient condition but not necessary like well
what i want to be able to transition operators like you know if if if
you can condition operators don't satisfy the then what do they do and i think
it's unsatisfying most of the books don't tell you what the
the necessary condition is so here it is
imagine that
first of all this is going to be something which is necessary and then i'll
show you that
OK imagine you've got transition operator which
does satisfy the property one we're going to start off is that starting point
then for any such transition operator
we can define another transition operator in the following way we say
constructed different transition operator t told
whether per if you're in ex-prime then the distribution of going to act is proportional
to this thing here
so we can always do this we can say we need to define probability distribution
so we're just going to assert is proportional to some positive functions
and the more we normalize it to make it a distribution
if the state space is discrete and then we can definitely do that you might
worry about
whether we can normalize the general
OK so
we that's what i've done just
done general thing we can always do i've invented in probability distribution and then i
would say well what is the normalizing constant are just some this over all values
of x which is what the distribution is over here is the normalizing constant
OK this is looking a bit like bayes rules that should be fairly familiar now
this thing here
one side of the station conditions so because team
that we started with is the transition operator then the thing here just returns probability
now i have to find a new transition operator which is equal to this
it's completely general you can always do this for any transition operator now
if i just multiply both sides by this that i get this condition
so this looks just like detailed balance except the told
for any t