so we have this energy band diagram which is the plot of allowed that is
important electron energy states in the material is function of position
along a certain direction
and you see
there is a band gap between the
energy of electrons in valence band and the minimum energy of the conduction band
and this is a very important semiconductor parameter
in silicon this band gap is one point one electron
and the room temperature we can calculate what the concentration of electrons and holes are
occupying these energy states
it is one point five times ten to ten square centimeters so for
people who work in semiconductors silicon this is one of the most important numbers they
should know
so you see we are talking about the energy bands so many energy levels here
and now of course we want to know
which of them are occupied by electrons because they are not occupied
all the time
i discussed already when we are at
let's say
zero kelvin temperature
we have no electron in the conduction band all are in the bones so actually
or are in the valence band
as a function of temperature we see that we start occupying it's still more and
more of these conduction band energy states and the function that describes this occupation is
so-called fermi dirac
distribution function
and then using this function i'm not going into details there is a formula that
finally we can calculate what the concentration of electrons and holes in such as semiconductor
material is
and using this formula we can calculate it and these are again important semiconductor material
parameters that we use to calculate the concentration
at a certain temperature
and this is again numbers for
silicon crystalline silicon
so now to give you some examples
how the situation changes when we
go to the doping so for example you see we have
though please
this is phosphorus atoms so we are making the material and that we have no
more electrons
then holes
we call
these electrons when they are
in larger concentration than intrinsic
situation majority carriers
and why majority carriers now i want to explain it to you
so you see let's look at the
how many
phosphorus atoms we introduced in the silicon
so let's say
in this case i took an example of ten to seventeen in cubic
now of course to realize what it means you should know how many silicon atoms
in intrinsic silicon in cubic centimeter you have an idea
what it is
what is this number
so we take a cubic centimeter of
crystalline silicon is this one
and how many silicon atoms do we find in one cubic centimeter
how many
well our current numbers
twenty two
so it's five times
ten to twenty two
now we when we take ten to seventeen phosphorus atoms to introduce it into
the let is so we have five times ten to twenty two
and ten to seventeen
so it's flawless six orders of magnitude so it means
we have to have one million silicon atoms and one million we just
substitute one
that's what we are doing with this level of doping
is it clear
in million
silicon atoms we are substituting just one
so not many
and you can see what it means
i did not say it but when we introduce this phosphorus or boron atoms
i always mentioned the room temperature that's already enough to the
that's a fifth electron on the hole in the case of boron atom
you can move
can be liberated from the eight
so it means the room temperature
the concentration of these majority
is equal
to the concentration of dopant atoms that we introduce into the lattice
so when we take
ten to seventeen phosphorus atoms as in this case
then we know that the concentration of the
electrons will be ten to seventeen
now compare it to the situation
intrinsic materials
it was ten to ten
so we have increased the concentration of electrons
in the order of ten to seven
so enormously
so instead of having i would say one electron now we have ten to seven
so orders of magnitude
how we manipulated
and because the product of
b and n
in the material has to be
always the same
it means that we also manipulate the concentration of falls
so in total it has to be two times
ten to twenty
so you can easily calculate what the concentration of horses
so now
in this situation when we don't is phosphorus was ten to seventeen
phosphorus atoms in cubic centimeter
we have a completely different
concentration of of electrons and holes
the intrinsic materials we have ten to seventeen
electrons and then to free holes
so almost no holes there
is it clear so
properties like electrical conductivity
this weekend you want to sign up before you go sign up early but don't
sign up often because you only need one section
if you're CPT student every once in a while you hear me refer to as
cpt students that stands for stanford center for professional development they are the folks in
industry you actually take this class
of the broadcast internet CPT student you're automatically enrolled for sections so you don't actually
need to do this in your section will meet so far as CPT and if
you're wondering whether the student is you're not one case so as CPT section needs
from one fifteen to apply it needs live if you want to go there by
instilling auditorium
but if you want to promote meets on channel
it seems we are same needs on channel and what does that mean meet simon
meets on generally two that is grammatically correct way of saying are so
there's a little bit of
more administrative kind of stuff now textbooks right experts there's nothing quite like the extortionate
is textbooks so
there's two textbooks that are required for this class one the course return textbooks course
readers called kill the robot learning job you can pick it up at the bookstore
it's relatively cheap was actually written by eric roberts here and surprisingly enough the textbook
for the class was also written by eric roberts the art and science of job
which is available now in your local bookstore including the bookstore on-campus so you can
go and pick up a copy of this so both these things you actually want
to have because they were part of the class will go through all of them
will go through basically everything except the last chapter of this book so should get
your money's worth we're just going to do it a little bit out of order
but will go through the whole thing
so email
how many of you have email account
i have to respect is anything at this point some people just don't want to
put up their hands how many people don't have email accounts
on how that is not the complement of the folks at the hands up previously
emailed required for this class chances by being at stanford you've already got email account
for your son i d but if you don't have an email i can get
an email account that i will stay in contact with us that's how will stay
in contact with you except possibly with you live in person on the email is
kind of the general math communications manufacturer first assignment part of your first assignment is
to send us an email just because we love you and we don't get enough
emails it is so you need to have an email account to be able to
do that so if you have not already been trying to get ahead of the
game and go set up your email account i don't where you get the first
summer next time still get like two days of breathing space before something goes up
there's not going to be lots of an atom cluster b given out in class
they will be given a possible answer post them online in case you missed
and how much real work to do in this class is always kind of an
interesting question so let's talk a little bit about assignments a little bit of other
just call things
so assignments what's called the dreaded signs there are seven programming assignments
and if you look at the syllabus and number two it tells you one of
them or do all the way through by day so you can plan your whole
quarter it's just that much fun
and the seven programming assignments are weighted slightly more toward the last simon because this
image will tend to get more complicated that doesn't necessarily mean there will be more
programming it just means conceptually they'll become more complicated so we tend to weigh the
more towards the end of the class later sam's count more than early assignments
how do actually doing programming is using a little tool called eclipse and eclipse thankfully
is free so you don't have to pay for it is manufactured and download from
the CS one of six a website and if you're wondering how you do that
don't worry we'll give you a hand out next last explains to the whole
ruling process of downloading and installing eclipse and you can use this either on the
mac or PC so if you have your own computer you can certainly work on
this ship yourself you just downloaded your own machine will explain the whole process in
and out if you don't have to compute the public computer clusters on campus will
have eclipse installed on them and so you can use eclipse there so you should
have happy to go either way
OK now
the important thing to mention the whole notion of software engineering in the class and
that's something we take really seriously so seriously net effect on you turn your assignment
what they do take assignments and just kind of you know look at the interesting
there you go thanks for playing
and you learn a whole lot from that so in in order to actually learn
a lot from your assignments we could take the assignment to write a whole bunch
comments on and handed back to even that's kind of not enough
we're really is a little bit more that makes some more fun is every week
after train your assignment in your section it looks it over and grades it you'll
actually meet with your section leader for about ten to fifteen minutes every week or
every time an assignment is due to actually go over and something referred to as
interactive creating and the chance to sit there and talk in an actual human being
about what's good in your assignment where some of things you need to work on
what are some of the software engineering principles you need to develop and that way
you can really sort of get more detailed information and be able to ask questions
to develop yourself as the programmer as well i get help if you need help
OK and that's in addition to go in the section on the class and all
that stuff so another fifteen minutes week you'll actually schedule that time with your section
leader on a regular basis when you have interactive rating or just a fraction affectionately
referred to as IG's because at stanford you know everything just short we just can't
say like you know psychology that's like so
it's i g just remember that
all right and then how are these things great so the other thing we could
do is so i told you could describe being handed back to you
but we found that that's not really great because people get all wrapped around the
axle about the grade and so far we did numbers in real icon what we
give a number between one and twenty and so what happens there people get all
wrapped around the axle about numbers so we thought how was a happier time when
we were in school
i remember when we were in school and we used get back assignments and they
have like smiley faces on them what we can do that and you know it
doesn't appear to be rigorous stanford class
instead of the smiley face we come up with something else
which look surprisingly like this
it's kind of involved actually draws finitary support
that's kind of the beginning of our grading scale OK and the way of grading
scale works if we start off with the check in the middle
which is this is a pretty solid program you know it meets all the requirements
for the program maybe it's got a little problem here there but it to check
we have sort of two grades on the two sides to check plus and cheque
minus check plus is like
you did a great job you got everything right things look good nice time on
your programme nice software engineering and the program works flawlessly good job this is like
you know whole way a
chuck is kind of like you know there's a minus b plus maybe on some
but it's kind of like you know it's pretty good work you're in pretty good
shape here and so a lot of great in this class ends up being checked
pluses and checks and if that's the case you're perfectly fine grained white
check minus you can imagine this is kind of thinking about the minus yeah there
are some slightly more you know significant problems with your programme but that's where it
so he is now
he of the
in machine learning
and what their group in southampton and before that he was a full professor at
a whole
holloway college london and basically i mean he's probably one of the people who you
would have encountered at some point anyway doing machine learning statistical learning theory in europe
seven he's been around at least as long as i can remember even though you
don't look like it and OK of spatial data that we have the better to
present this OK thanks
OK so thank you to the organizers for
this very on by this invitation to
presented the summer school
so when i was asked to talk about basic statistical learning theory
i was trying to think
what i couldn't hope to
do for you in this
a period of time allotted and what you might be able to take away from
a set of lectures
and suddenly came to mind was a series of books that are actually sold in
the UK
known as the bluffer's guide to
and you can get a bluffer's guide for all sorts of topics from
psycho analysis
two schemes
philosophy or whatever and the idea of bluffer's guide to apply for somebody sort of
makes his way by not really knowing what's going on that has the right terminology
and can sort of get by the cocktail party
so the bluffer's guide book gives you all the key to this and tells you
you know
how to use them in the right context
so for instance you know if you
start talking in
statistical learning theory about the ghost sample
you know you should know that is the
the dataset used in your last submission
on the double sample triggers is not actually something to do with cards and
and so on
concentration is not about the level of alcohol in your blood and so on
my intention and i mean i mean that's joking aside i think these books actually
also are quite destructive in this surprisingly informative give you
the sort of levels strategic level view of that subject but often it's very hard
to get
from a textbook which will go into more detail a lot more
of the
you get lost in the detail you don't get a sort of overview so in
a sense that the first level i would like to try and
reach the people come away from this with a sense of what i was statistical
learning theory is attempting to achieve
what is this sort of contribution to i want to bring to the table
of machine learning
to what extent it successful in doing that and to what extent it it fails
or needs to be further
i suppose in a sense putting it in the context of of the research that
you might be doing and how it relates to that search
so if you like that will be the level i would hope everybody might take
away from this
i think also i would you know also hope that many of you might take
a little bit more than that in that i will hope to cover
some of the
theorems and
ideas behind the theory
in a way that i hope will if you see that there's actually a lot
of interesting things in that theory and a lot of nice ideas that fun to
work with
so in a sense i like to hope that some of you will actually feel
that's really interesting that's something i you know
didn't know now have have learned
and finally you know also i might
i hope that
many of you will take
an inspiration from this to try and apply some of the ideas to research you're
so what
in this sense
that would be the major goal will be to see that yes OK that actually
applies to one thing it can help me understand
all further illuminate the actual algorithms i'm working with the process the techniques of music
in my research and and actually those techniques could be applied area
so the idea is to use the sort of three
o levels and striving for
but certainly i don't want to get lost in a lot of detail and i
want to try but i want to try and give you some of the enthusiasm
for some of the key
ideas so on that note of forward
and give you an overview of the basic structure that i'm hoping things i'm hoping
to cover
particular 1 but this is a pretty natural way
free variables
since those free variables are the guys that can be anything
the most convenient choice is 0
X equals
for the
pivot variables
so what does that mean in this example which are the 3 variables
which which is the variables that we can assign freely and then then then there
1 and only 1 way to find the pivot
there x 2
and so X 2 is 0
presented no column without a pivot the 2nd column has no pivot and
what's the other 1
the 4 x 4
is 0
because that those are the free 1
0 0 and the columns with no pivots so you see what might is so
when I'm not 1 x 2 Annex 4 0
I'm left with them
the book or 1 of my left with here and just left with
the now I'm not using the to free columns I'm only using the pivot columns
so I'm really left with X 1 the 1st equation is just X 1 and
2 x 3 should be the right hand side which we take to be a
and the 2nd equation is 2 x 3
as it happened turned out to be
I necessary
of guidance right and again here
with X 2 and the explored knocked out since set them to 0 and you
see that we're we're back in the normal case
of having back we're back substitution will do it so x 3
is 3 halves
and then we go back up and X ones
is 1 minus 2 x 3 that's probably minus 2
so now we have the solution x particular is the vector of
minus 2
0 3 halves
that's 1 particular solution and we show
could plug it into the original system
that really have on the quiz please that's a good thing to do
this up so we did all this is these their role operations
but this is supposed to solve the original system and I think it
so that's effects particularly
which we got
so that is that that's like what's new today
the particular solution comes 1st you check that you have 0 equals 0 so your
OK on the last equations
and then you
set them free variables that 0 solve for the pivot variables
and you've got a particular solution
the particular solution that has 0 free variables
but that's only 1 solution and now I'm looking for all
so how do I find the rest
the point is I can add on to
add on X anything out of the null space
we know how to find the vectors in the null space
because we didn't last time but I'll remember remind you what we got
and then
all add
so the final result will be
that the complete solution this is now the complete Guide
the complete solution is this 1 particular solution plus any any vector
all different vectors out of the null space
xxx on OK why why this pattern because as patterns shows up through all of
mathematics close it shows up everywhere we have linear equations
let me just put here that the reason
so that takes particular
so what is a x particular again
that gives the correct right hand side the
and what is a times and X in the null space here
so I
and I born in parentheses
so xp + x
it the + 0 which is being
so far
0 what am I saying that he does say it in words
if I have 1 solutions
1 solution I can add on anything in the null space
goes anything in the null space
has a 0 right hand side and and I still have the correct right hand
side b
so that's my system that's my complete solution
no let me write out what that will be for this example
so in this example in this example
experts X general X completes the complete solution is x particulars
which is
minus 2 0 0 3 0
with those zeros in the free variable plus remember the reverse special solutions in the
null space
well i think they can show it
show here brick
so the interesting thing in this example is this is the danger of being entry
in freebase and you know his types
the type of entity that is this is the person
and also deceased person
and separately his profession
is politician
now if you want to connect this to
the rest of of words the ontology to know the politicians are kind of
sort of a national roller something like this to other kinds of things with that
then you can just to the mapping at the level of the type you have
to the new level that feels similarly there will be entries where the
if someone
you know there's gender someone we can double-click and added here
you know we can say oh he's male
OK i just updated freebase in real time so the genders male
but if you want to connect the two what men did something well that all
the the concept of men
is you know is an is a hierarchy and here you know male is an
attribute of this this thing so
what we've done is basically make a kind of cross mapping said across mapping knowledge
that maps from the
either from the types or from the attributes of different roles into the corresponding word
category and some of that is manual manually done knowledge some of that semiautomatically because
you can take some guesses based on this thing and other kinds of clues so
so we've done that kind of work and some that's quite interesting and more generally
as you start doing more and more kinds of integration of resources i think these
really interesting challenging problems it will be figuring out how to do better
sure first of i marked could
so the question is about word in fact extraction and it looks like we might
be extracting triples how far beyond triples can we go
and actually were really extracting far more than triples
right now in some of these things that i was showing you here
this is second one
yes you actually got to you got the subjects and you've got relations you've got
objects you've got the when of something you've got the where
you actually will have reasons for it
you actually have about some things about embedded in that context we also extract out
some other kinds of sentiment features and in general
the we have this huge set information that's extracted out into our semantics
and one of the interesting question is how much of that makes it actually into
our index for efficient retrieval of large scales but there's already an awful lot of
information in these systems more than just a small table
OK so the question is how we deal with knowledge on the one hand and
trust on the other hand
so context and trust so super context there's multiple
ways that context plays in one simple way is with things like word sense
as you know if you have some ambiguity in word sense one word can multiple
concepts which won the right concept we want to be able to tell the user
how we're going to rank prioritize we are employing were sense disambiguation can take advantage
of the local context around these kinds of things similarly we have to do anaphora
so if it says he knowing this actually doing paying how do you do that
multiple choices again their contextual approach is that the work on their
and there's also specialized national context here which is certain facts may only be true
within certain contexts so
only in someone ambiguous reading this certain factor where some of the things are true
in all contexts or something maybe in the context of a believed thing or stated
o thing or negated context so
there's many context and you know it we take advantage of them here on the
theme of trust in the current model
we're not addressing trust you saw the stacks they showed you are extracted you know
it's it's equally trusting everything but actually is able to use some statistics when sorting
organised the results to say well you know how how often is this kind of
fact repeated
now there are some really nice work on using trust and confidence from the level
of documents and being combined
i just recently read the paper about not go
the principal components
by introducing nonlinearity you get something else
which somehow means that when you stack these you get something nonlinear that turns out
to be useful
once you've stacked a bunch of them
you can
you can tag list logistic regression on top and then optimize
all the parameters go from input to those predictions
in a supervised way
so actually doing this is very simple
not as well as IBM's but much better than training a deep architecture from scratch
there is another variant that is interesting it doesn't work as well but still works
better than
trained from scratch in a supervised way
say something about the power of just having a local criteria
so you could train regular one hidden layer neural network predicts
your classes given some inputs
and once you've training you can throw away those parameters that
go from the intermediate code two
the prediction
and just keep the
first level parameters
and then as we did for the autoencoder you can take that as input for
next level
train the second one he that
and you can do that
several times and then just two logistic regression at the end and then fine tune
and that
is really worse than using autoencoders but is really better than trying from scratch
so there's supervisors unsupervised
part of the unsupervised component is important
but having something just local also by itself gives benefits yes
so that's a good question so it here you don't care with anyone in supervised
but in your could you would think that if you had
more notes than inputs then could just learn the identity and would be very useful
now in practice for some reason it doesn't happen
because you start from small weights and you would need very large which the identity
and also because you're tying the weights of the
and called apart the decoder part
in any case
it doesn't seem to be an issue
but that
but other versions of autoencoders i'll talk about the sparse ones and denoising ones i'll
talk about
i don't have this problem that they can learn the identity
so it's reassuring but it's something one should worry about in the first place
why in principle you could
yes yes yes
actually that's exactly what
collobert weston have done in their language modeling
to predict the next
given the previous work
and it works very well
i don't know if anyone's tried
but i don't see any reason why not
yeah in general use
you can use predicting the next thing is very powerful wants the y signal here
and someone should try it for images
one thing i want to mention is that kind of bomber in these experiments is
that it looks like
you do need this final fine tuning
to get the better results so this curve shows
classication error
on some task on digit classification task where
for the first part of training we just two
unsupervised learning out of the lower levels
and then at some point
we introduce supervised learning and we can do in various ways one way which works
best this is purely supervised so we've completely removed the surprise
component of the gradient
and in one way just remain unsupervised and an intermediate ways involved
combining the two
these need experiments it looks like
fine tuning gives an edge
and when we do understand that is very simple we're here
in the end we're interested in the classification task and if we add the two
criteria ideas rise in the rise
well again
makes a compromise between the two
if we
are low data regime maybe that's useful a regularizer about
otherwise it might actually hurt
that comes
most of it might be useful
well you you would think you would think that you could have a lot of
a lot of these are useful for classification but let's see some of the more
faces that express the squalor the corruption of the smug carnality of the bourgeois
world that was to become the most docile supporter of the dictatorship
in the dada movement the attraction of ugliness emerged through an appeal to grotesque
propensity for disturbing situations and mostrous images is evident in the surrealist
manifesto of nineteen twenty four
and in films like bunuel un chien andalou where we see
repugnant operations like the vivisection of an eye bataille immortalized big toe
and flowers as objects of disguist
later the informal movement was to reassess what had until then been seen
as unrepresentable in other words the more inaccessible deaths of matter moulds
dust and mud new realism rediscovered the detritus of the industrial world and
fragment of destroyed objects exponents of pop art like warhol appealed for an aesthetic
an aesthetic recyling of waste and pierro manzoni presented in the
gallery and sold at the very high price heart is shit merda d'artista
today we recognize as artistically beautiful all those works that had horrified our
fathers the ugliness of the avantgarde has been accepted as a new model for beauty
and has given rise to a new commercial circuirt
certainly in contemporary art the borderline between beautiful and ugly
has been canceled
contemporary art doesn't seem still interested in producing beautiful objects
but rather in producing
forms of provocative behavior
but it has been said that
the borderline between
beautiful and ugly has
by now disappeared also in our everyday life we today coexist with
contrasting models because the opposition beautiful ugly has no longer any
aesthetic value
ugly and beautiful would be two possible options to be
experienced neutrally
it seems so
if we consider that monster can be ugly in many science fiction movies or in
the various nights of the living deads but oders are certainly lovable
or like ET or the extraterrestrials of Star Wars and fascinate not only children who
are also fond
of dinosaurs or pokemon and other deformed creatures but also adults who
relax in front of splatter movies
where brains are reduced to pulp and blood spurts onto the walls
or amuse themselves by reading horror stories
but the same person do not seem to have lost the traditional sense of beauty
since they still take aesthetic pleasure in a fine landscape a handsome child or a flat screen that
shows the cannons of the golden section
the same people today accept ideas of furnishing design teams of hotel
architecture and of entire tourist industry which sells classically pleasing forms
see the las vegas versions of venetial palazzi ancient roman dining
rooms or moorish architecture
and at the same chose restaurant or hotel ennobled by twentieth century avantgarde
paintings genuine or reproduction that their grandparents would have considered the negation of
the ideals of classical antiquity
the cinema television and magazine
advertising and fashion all propose models of beauty that are not different from the ancient ones
and we could easily
imagine the face of richard gere or nicole kidman portrayed by Renaissance painter
but at the same time people identify with these aesthetic or sexual ideals
also go into raptures
over rock singers whose features would have struck renaissance man as repellent
and the same youngster often make themselves up
tattoo themselves up they tattoo themselves and they pierce their flesh with pins so
they look more like marlyn manson that like marilyn monroe
see a comparison between a contemporary example of piercing and two faces painted
by Hieronymus Bosch
but bosch wanted to portray
the enemies of Christ and so he painted the them as people of these
days conceived as barbarians
or pirates
and that's
let us not forget that as late as the nineteenth century psychiatrists
saw tatoos as a sign of degeneracy
today piercing and tattoos are thought to be a generational challenge at most but they
are certainly not seen by the majority as a criminal choice and a girl with a
tongue stud or a tattooed dragoon on her exposed belly can take part in
in a march for peace or for starving children in Africa
neither the young nor the old seem to find the these contradiction
a dramatic one
the late nineteenth century aesthete
who favoured cadaverous beauty
i wanted to say goodbye
the support spring school
postcondition not put a personality discovery on
got abundances logo yet
which we call a comedy movie comedy show in operation can be just as there
was twenty moment if you know what little but stop when in fact the more
data problem you puzzle making the kitchen could because they don't fit anything product get
in but the the typical took k partition OK so so much easier probably a
little more than about the support of atkinson camomile that's the only among the hyperlink
in the losses they bought tickets to to propose that local mcmullin will put up
the control of course e
that's avoiding there is also a of parts of speech but has been much talk
consolidating means so was made apple designs
look call
OK well
similar internet not just like in was the
before on the route request because the company mawkish now so probably polyester class get
caught up in the midst of all so interacting in kind as kind of there
is year
so anxious was the most effective committee available a team of tallest building in one
the end
but upon arrival as a collection of because of school there was something strange in
constable constable my passion for each percussionist within mostly
lockwood one listener asking with the leader in quaking because now we delete all of
which are more common within its academic motherboards within that i look at the time
interval that could kind of course the problem
is a
it's about grammar monocyte because of me
also connection on is always uses the challenge the
but could do she the in those sorts stories of people because of course it
is a graph in the next step is so much in my more portuguese solid
performers are made in the image which can be so they that activity outdoor was
not called up for the energy and in
this so so it's is crucial for documents output input is a specialized studios in
graph cutci problems in this essay the support of other parties lmage new major supposedly
second look on cell behavioral as they book can while my one
right because the title of catch you put them on the wild bunch
model which only on can also the manual approach in a big question is nominally
set of topics those mankind in the yugoslavia
the fictional brush on his about justice promoting or the oil city and you will
see LC but because satanic only just about the same time to try forge cult
by guy says goodbye
i will make you organize oxygen in and it mark nemo was the bigger cox
you what they organise serious problem and it's impossible to accomplish on the pressure on
a maximum of public by your nobody it by simple legend of believe that there
they a cintron sometimes which logical sort
socialist which
we can use
should should
OK so
and OK now so this is the sort of the questions that that were used
to ask what we can ask for smaller networks what is for for example more
more interesting ask for bigger parties like how many nodes going to remove from the
network so the network like can be separated into two pieces or something like that
right so would be like a different type of questions that starts to make to
make sense and you have a much larger network right and what we want to
do now is basically want to develop some kind of statistical tools and statistical methods
to study these big network site
and the whole problem comes from the fact that we can not the kind of
draw these things right and
what there are basically three two three two three goals we have first this can
be can be find analyse quantified is a statistical properties of large networks can be
modeled can be like
can find simple generative models that would be able to generate this type of properties
and then
even the models then the next step is to predict what will happen and things
like that
and so here is the outline of the rest of the talk
i've spent some time now into using these properties of real world networks that i
want to talk about kronecker graphs show
some properties of them
and then present how to feed them in real graphs and present experimental results
OK so for example here is a list of
properties that can be fired funding
the real world networks and so for example the first one is like a small
small world effect they call it so it means that the diameter of the network
is very small even if the network itself is very large so i'll explain about
it's more like the other the other properties like the transitivity or clustering which in
social networks means that if i have two friends that probably different friends themselves also
of this we like create triangle i have a friend here come from here and
then there are also friends of this this this is called sensitivity of testing then
a different statistical process
let's take a closer look by considering samples
this is the case of mister hadlum versus missus hadlum which was discussed by barnett
very interesting paper on of section was was point so yeah the birth of a
child to missus hadlum
happened strangely three hundred forty nine days after mister hadlum left military service
and if you consider that the average human is a station period is about forty
weeks o two hundred eighty days
mister hadlum has
obviously some
that feelings with this and of course i thought that this baby is not
and the court has to decide if it's possible or not
and interestingly the
the judges did was they asked doctors is it possible
from at some point of view is possible
that this baby is most of the baby
and the doctor said theoretically
it could happen
what the judges did was to reject mister hadlum objective
barnett in seventy eight
so thirty years ago thirty years later
pick that up and
analyse this by some statistics what we did was
just to
take some
three thirty thousand thirteen so something sorry observations of
the station periods
the station periods are plotted here by histogram
and you see that this is
this follows quite nicely gaussian distribution around
the normal meaning of forty weeks
in the case of helen was elements fifty weeks so from statistical sense statistical point
of view this is clearly an outlier but as i said the doctor said
it's theoretically possible so
we cannot
make a difference so
taking a closer look to put it in the in the direction of
hawkins definition what do we have here so we have the statistical basis of
thirteen thousand observations of the station areas
in blue
histogram and green
is caution distribution fitted to the histogram
so this is the
the underlying process the generating mechanism
and you see it
with the very low probability
for the birth of mister missus hadlum
helen strands child for being
generated by this mechanism or in other words to be
produced by mister mister
and in rats this is the assumption of mister hadlum
what was the assumption of him he said that then
what's trending generated by this mechanism
which means that
in this case if you if you have this mechanism here
different from this mechanism here is is however a very high probability
of this gas station
what once again we have
what concerns one generating mechanism
modelled here by gaussian distribution in green
and the old was
produced by a different mechanism
in this case around the right questions to
obviously nowadays there are
better ways to
if one is the father of the child or not
not only have limitations but genetic tests of course so all the other applications for
the detection of course there are so many
applications for text just to name a few
so fraud detection for example you can before you try to detect credit card abuse
by looking at the at the
purchasing behavior of users
in medicine for example
you could have unusual symptoms test results that may indicate some
diseases potential problems whatever
in this case it's interesting that not only the measurement itself the nominal value of
the measurement itself
it is important to decide if it's another model is
the potential health problem or not but also other
the features of the patient for example gender age or whatever
could be interesting so
you have to be more than one
variable more than one attribute for objectification of one
public health is also very common application for example the occurrence of a particular disease
scattered across various hospitals of city
may indicate some problems corresponding nation program
again here
usually have to consider spatially
frequency correlations
not only the measurement itself but also other
features are important to decide whether another is really on outliers is really signal
sports statistics
very familiar with that so many sports was various parameters are measured
four players and you can relate
performances as outstanding positive and negative sense of course
in this case sometimes players should show only only exceptional views
the negative sense only a subset of
four of those combinations of is not all parameters not all
values are
important here
another very important for application of that section is a measurement error detection
for example in sensor data usually have a lot of measurement errors
and here in the case of the detection could
indicate measurement error so
you can remove for example measurement so you can
make something out of it whatever
special treatment on on the these measurements
but this is something like two sides of male because
yeah this is a very famous statement one person's noise could be another one was
the signal that means
if you detect an outlier and say this noise another person could say no no
it's not nice this is a clear signal for this is
knowledge which i want to know
remove it or whatever so
now the sections quite quite
subject is not really object
and it heavily depends on the application domains and applications
if the
signal detected outliers are really interesting and
coming back to the basic inclusion of hawkins in light of these applications
then we have to see that data is usually multidimensional so you have a lot
of measures are
object point
and if you recall in in the basic model you just have a one-dimensional
dataset so
the case of helen was you just measure the
the length of the station period
just one measure for each
and but usually is not the case usually multivariate
usually you of the basic intuition also assumes that you have just one normal
generating process so in this case only the green processes process that
generates the normal
objects normally
that can be understood
through a series of models that have not had time to present to you with
a a large body of
a theoretical work that developing trying to try to put this
mechanism to work
and that we need to blocked
and we think
are partly developed novel metrics
to monitor the development of arts
one thing i'm not at all discussed is extremely important that not the same in
either of us are more as which i think it we discuss privately between us
the core
of the fundamental systemic instability of the french market
let me finish with two predictions
illustrating the methodology
one was a prediction that we actually
published actually it was communicated to hedge-fund conference in stockholm
in early september i was invited to be the kind speaker two and a lot
of hits from managers the better manage in the world
i said to myself should to present something that would excite the interest
so we did study and we
by looking at the super exponential exeter and of the
chinese means the market
we identified that by the turn of two thousand and two thousand six seven seven
two thousand eight
so i refuse generative because it we should have a big collection
we should have actually changing channel regime
one i presented this prediction to this panel of experts who
where there exists a successful investors the autonomy
you are wrong
it's impossible
the chinese market does not continue for trajectory
on until after the olympic games
impossible that's was one hundred person convention
happily for me crap and i believe because it my prediction was actually incorrect in
the exact timing the crash occurred in the
you might remember it twenty percent drop and then subsequently i mean
if you have invested in china china united so such which
because the market has going going down continuously with very severe
this is an example where show that the exact timing very precise it was indeed
stochastic event
but there are
but we can do
first above second have some idea of the time spent remain some idea not exactly
there's a lot of serie that can rationalize why it is of course of stochastic
morrison prediction i would finish with this one
wars it's a big debate
all right OK or price the question is
why all has gone from thirty
below a barrel in two thousand six to grows to one hundred fifty dollars a
just a few months ago with the peak
big debate
paul krugman my best adversary
his famous economist you know writing in new york's time very famous economist was adamant
that there was absolutely no global no speculation
towards pure and simple
supplied very interesting
how rationalisation my mind comes about when you see the data and and real real
options stories for the new into the technology was
to the full
so what we did with data analysis and summarizing about what if analysis because
here i felt quite an adventurous water to stick my neck out with this very
important issues but nevertheless we should actually in may
showing that first yes we believe there is a degree of speculation with a superbly
component in their position of the order of
secondly this is not sustainable
the peak is going to be rich
and of two in july
OK so that he once again
so these should again that we have a degree of predictability of the
my main message
are those that try to tell you about
for some reason may be typing you as humans we look at this and we
even if we don't know the answer the question we know that's not the answer
so we're calling that stupid but what's what i'm starting to think of is maybe
we need to change are
our notions because you know there are some tasks that at least those of us
in the AI community are very familiar with
they are considered a i complete these are the problems that in order to have
a comprehensive solution to requires an AI and we don't have it we don't know
how to build nobody really has any ideas except that you know mluleki in
occurs while
i think they know how this is how it's going to happen but it hasn't
happened yet so these are some problems that
you know the machine vision problem it's the kind of thing speech natural these are
problems that humans don't think to solve you know we just solve
if you look at the picture and you see what's in it
there's no processing is no computational complexity somehow just works
but there are problems that we are terrible at and that if computers could talk
they probably say
you forgot your appointment was at twelve o'clock what's the matter with you don't you
have a clock
computers and so that you
have the tortious voice in mind
telling me when i miss my appointment
so there are a whole bunch of things that
you know
computational systems are really good at
maybe we need to change our notion of what stupid
and what's intelligent
and i think that in collaborate you know the kind of collaboration that now seems
to happen on the web
so this is the story of captures if you have haven't heard of the captures
of these
again these images that you have to
type in what letters are skewed by some photoshop effect and you have to type
the letters in there and you know it was used as a way to prevent
spambots from getting free email accounts that was the initial
use case for them
and about a year i think after they were developed
there is somebody broke
and the guys who develop the capture storage oh my god you know spammers solve
the machine vision problem you know they built systems that are reading the the the
characters in these skewed images and what it turned out was really happening was that
porn sites were downloading the the big if images of the capture
and popping up onto the screen of somebody that was browsing the pawnshop site at
that time and say hey you want to see more free-form what does this say
and then they would take the answer and send it back and fill out the
form and they had enough people browsing the web site that they can get like
a thousand free meals in minutes or an hour whatever the rate
that's great just fantastic if only we could find more appropriate ways to motivate people
to do work
or maybe not enough
what makes the problems
to solve that were possible for this combination of
you know entities that can solve the left column and entities that can solve the
right problem and put them together
so that's what i wanted to
and then you have this what i call what people call heavy tails that means
you have what it is not really visible on this image but it means that
the pdf will be relatively large
very far from zero so you will have seen much
a larger probability of having the larger values nanoparticles in this section
the first is
really nothing different than what
i call super gaussianity
forty slides
thirty five slides ago
in other words it is this kind of behavior is typical of distributions that have
a strongly positive
so from the point of statistical modeling we see that sparseness is really the same
thing as super gaussianity well it's not just because it is also the property that
the distributions are well in the in the basic case distributions are symmetric with respect
to zero and then you see strongly about
if we formulate linear sparse coding
so that we want to find this representation that we have seen a hundred times
and we want to find we want to determine this mixing matrix of the basis
vectors a so that the components is i as fast as possible
now if we do this we will see that well this is
this is just the same as in all of this thing in your model is
just the same as with ICA
and when we say that
the components must be as sparse as possible while it's the same thing as saying
that they must be as well it's almost the same thing as saying that there
must be as non gaussian as possible so we see
finding a linear sparse called maximally sparse code is just the same thing as doing
with one reservation
well if you think about maximisation nongaussianity as maximisation of the absolute value of kurtosis
then if all the kurtosis are positive then of course the maximisation of of kurtosis
is the same thing as maximizing some of us so that it is so if
the maximum everything of maximisation of nongaussianity as maximisation of the the absolute value ten
if the kurtosis always positive then of course the maximisation of the absolute value is
the same as maximisation of those itself so in that case maximisation of sparseness is
the same thing as maximisation of nongaussianity
of course it might happen that if you have that you have distributions which are
negative kurtosis and in that case maximisation nongaussianity will be just the opposite as maximisation
of fast but that is not what usually happens in images you always have distributions
which have positive kurtosis and therefore
maximisation sparseness is the same as maximisation of number ten
OK but
sparse coding is not just ICA has one
it has an extremely extremely important interpretation which was actually the motivation for sparse coding
in in vision modelling in the first place
which is that
now when you
it takes one input points
and it's a neural representation the ENS is four
for that particular
a data point
then because the distributions of s
as such that they are usually very close to zero
and only occasionally gets significant values that are significantly different from zero then it follows
that for any given as most of these days i will be very close to
zero so what it means that you are basically representing
each of your data points using only a small number of active components as
and this is really what sparse coding originally meant so that the the representation for
for each data point is sparse in the sense of using only a small number
of active components
and check the next OK and so
always open people can just grab it they think you know willows an invading inning
grabbed the stack and and take over as the the innovator so that forces us
to keep on running red sold so the the goal willows to foster an industry
not just the company uh so that we're we're looking at potentially spinning off companies
in vertical niches you know like maybe whatever you want to picking elderly care but
not to own the whole industry to really founded industry the reason that wealthy founders
want this is because they want to see robotics happen before their old adept at
bid and then so sold the idea is to foster it and build it in
the article the Foundation a case so far so Ross is that the robot operating
system is driving this easy recombination we practices by having these Sprint's internally so people
come up with an idea make the robot play pool and you for 1 week
1 week you know to make it do that and often these become all those
on that often the people who were then working on that are the primary process
so the motor control person might take division role and the vision person might take
the motor control rolled the ideas can the software support people just rapidly innovative and
spend that's like this standing on the shoulders of giants that accept notes Geico a
case of going over a little bit of Ross Ross was a robot operating system
and it's nothing new this has been reinvented like 20 times Microsoft Robotics Studio is
similar they're all similar they're basically not quite an OS that's a bit transport system
so Ross's the man in robotics these had genius distributed systems and the idea is
to make it easy to work over that and uh so as to what we
have is slated to cement operating system is basically how to move data around and
be able to run on multiple platforms across multiple things was appear to that's are
other product which is teller presence robot the ball from Ross at Alan to agree
when you're working on the appears to some of it might be running head internal
to appears to offer and some of its brain is running on your own computer
or someone else's computer maybe 3 or 4 people's computers they're all running parts of
its brain and we also have a a cluster that that's starting to run many
of things and the robot and this is just invisible to use it's trivial to
run across anyhow also so so what grosses a publish subscribe model is producers and
consumers that are rise up in the distributed fast and someone might produce saying I
can produce images and another person might that another node might say I wanna images
so there's a master know that coordinates that and of images are being produced and
someone wants of then there's a connection that's established there and then and so there
is this Ross master that coordinates all that right now it's a single point of
failure the rest can go up and also offer when you work in the robot
all the time mode most of the brains of but you're taking apart down and
up and the rest of its just running because it images go away than the
things that use images go the rest robot as runs right and messages Golway than
the things that need those messages go into that no idle loops and then when
they're instantiated all comes back together that's that's what Ross does of course we're now
looking at distributing the master had so that multiple robots can work together off of
multiple masters so this is that it's a message-passing system is a talker and listen
there there's also things like services so knows that only come alive when you ask
something of a could be in addition node stages to numbers what are they and
it'll it'll give you a message back to this to models 1 that's always listening
and talking and and this service requests than and service replied there's also another action
model that says that I want you to do something and tell me here tell
me if you could achieve that goal so like move an arm to certain location
it might not be able to achieve a full report back then so this is
there's a talker was there in the right Mastin coordinates them after that they just
talk amongst themselves like that Saturday Saturday Night Live skit if you know that so
this everything that is that just going over Ross again it's a BEST model opened
and easy to use it allows easy distribution not different than a lot of that
it's of the flavor of many of the things people put together the only difference
here as it opens commercially or or privately we like BEST because we want drive
business so we don't wanna have to force you to open you just use it
we wanna make progress Chen demand Ross is run by these messages that there's a
lot of details the messages can be expensive the passive here in images something so
we we have that allow you to work in shared-memory you can declare that this
message must be the residing on the same machine and and then just pointers are
passed back and 4 other than that it looks exactly the same as anything else
so through a few parameters you can get all this behavior although the underlying code
as the same so it makes it very modular and easy to recombine things and
this is possibly 1 model of how you can do a plug and play with
open-source so over a bill this is a complex model but a so that it
Gross's organizers packages and stacks and trying to make a coherent that Ochoa this effect
spoken CD but but the stack circle here processing things so there's an object recognition
stack and there's a arm you know the motion planning stack and then everything there
sort of coherent and that talks with the same data structures and say messages and
and this is something and trying to bring an open CD so that it to
end on the right story these are the existing repositories as of today so there's
there's know about 20 of them around the world this is independent repositories for people
running things and there's a master search engine so I've been working in Ross and
then we don't use fire wire campus where we are because turns up their fleet
you need the fire watch able slated for distributing the data it when it flexes
and whatever they can the break so but I think I had a our Khamenei
after I need to use it's not just the driver but actually and that that
puts time stamps in all kinds of stuff on and so I just go on
the Ross repository searched someone and Pittsburgh or something had written this note I just
pulled and since all repositories always build themselves all the time you know it just
works so that I pull the code builds its working as a node I'm often
running you know that's the the positive side of this it's just you know easy
to share recombined parts of different stacks the other worked so that's the dismiss as
you know this is somewhat a model for a perhaps finer grain like I needed
that particular driver to work with a particular thing a search of the world I
got it added pulling their repository just that just a one-note okay so moving on
look like from these two partitions
now the problem is is that in practice we don't have that much training data
so what's actually going to happen is
when we use history and fit medians to each cell in the corresponding partition we
get estimates that look like this and you see movies here and these are cycling
over different realizations of training i think they are
a few hundred training points in this example
and what you see is that the the crude estimate at the top there very
a little bit
based on the training data every once in a while certain block turns white or
but the more
detailed partition the finer partition has a lot more variability associated with it because we
have some very small cells there
and there's not so much data and they are so different realizations of training data
might give you a very different majority votes in those tiny little cells and you
can see all the fluctuations caused by
this is really what we mean when we talk about overfitting it's this variability associated
with giving your model
more degrees of freedom then you really have the right to use because you don't
have enough data to support accurately estimating all those three three parameters in the model
so this is this is a picture and idea clear
so this is just the same picture again but a lot of time especially in
regression problems is called the bias variance trade
and we might say that here with the coarse partition we have a low bias
so rather large bias being a poor approximation
with the finer partition we have smaller bias meaning better approximation
but at the same time the course partition gives lower variance
and find partition gives higher variance so it's not clear which of these two partitions
entries would be better in this type of problem do we want to go with
that kind of crude approximation but very stable
or do we want to go with the good approximation but very variable depending on
the outcome of the training data we happen to see
and so you have to strike a balance between these two issues we can have
a better approximation but more variability or poor approximation and more stability
to be a little bit more careful about describing is i'm going to
refer to the various estimation are sometimes
and the biases approximation error
and to give you an idea of what's going on with such as had t
denote the classification or regression
rules associated with the treaty
using empirical median mean fits on each cell
and let f seven p denote the the classification regression rules associated with the treaty
using the true median means the true with respect to the underlying probability law p
and each cell
and we can now
look at this and ultimately what we're interested in we'd like to know what's the
rest of our empirical rule
relative to the smallest risk we could achieve
this would be say the bayes classification
probability of varying classifications
and then we can decompose this difference
in the two terms one term is the difference between the risk of that happened
the risk of
and then
the second is is the difference between the risk of after he and the minimum
and the first term is called the estimation error which is essentially the part that
stochastic the part various because it involves the training data and this
prediction rules derived from training data so that training data random that risk was random
and the second term is the approximation error which serves as well how good using
this stream this partition could i principle approximate the
the optimal
the optimal prediction
so the two terms are one is stochastic one is not stochastic one is deterministic
approximation rules deterministic estimation are stochastic and so that's that's stochastic term gives rise to
the variance
so what we
look at this estimation error kind carefully in the regression classification case
i'm not going to bother you with this will derivation here because it would probably
take more time to go through is very elementary the main
i have
o point that you need to recognise is that the expected value that has equal
to f t in regression
so what that ultimately leads to is the variance if you well in this case
is just the expected squared error between f and
that's what the variance term ends up looking like the variance being the estimation error
so you you the slide we post and you can look at this in a
very very ask questions about this little calculation we can talk about offline but i
don't want to bore you with
in the classification case
we're looking at the expected value of that estimation here again
we can break data into the two
components this is the risk of f had this is the risk as
just using a little triangle inequality here we get that that as the expected estimation
error variance is bounded by the
absolute error in expectation is the difference being one case in regression it was the
squared error
in this case is the absolute here
and saying variance in quotations because normally we associate variance in the way i was
using the regression case here i'm just sort of using the word variance to mean
variability but technically we would we call the estimation error not variance in the classification
OK so
let me now
kind of explaining the overfitting problem with this picture
so what i'm showing you here is the empirical risk
this horizontal axis is the
number of leaves in the partition this is the size of the partition of the
complexity of the number of cells in the partition
which other notice
the cardinality of t that will mean the number of cells in the partition
equivalently the number of leaves in the tree
so as i increase the
number of cells in the partition of course i can fit the data better and
better and so the empirical risk just tends to go down to zero
on the other hand if we really knew what the true risk functional looked like
degree larger point five that seems not very painful so they can do is you
can sort of go back and to find a couple of border constraints i've done
that you can
look for the william extreme cases say OK what about if it belongs to
the old people to a degree of zero really doesn't belong to the set of
old what would you think down here i mean if it doesn't belong to the
old people at all it really shouldn't belong to the old and tall people also
down here you should definitely have zero up here same argument if it doesn't belong
at all to the tall people should is up here and of course if it
doesn't belong to the old and or to the tall people on both of these
abuses european also expect
the same is true for the one i mean if you if you have the
degree of membership here of one and here of one then long
there's also a degree of membership of one to the set of old people up
here you would assume that this has has one and then you can sort of
and this is just one example of doing it very simple all the sort of
the line of people that belong to the old and tall people to point seven
is probably somewhere here point five goes down here so you have sort of this
program done but the the extreme cases you definitely want to observe them if this
is zero for the
for mu old for the old people you definitely want a degree of membership to
the to the conjunction of zero small said mister here and this corner pieces of
definitely needs to be true
i'll get back to formalising that a little bit in the second we can do
the same of course with the disjunction between the or
and we can do the same argument you but what would you expect if one
of them is one and the other one is something not to force would definitely
expect a degree of membership to the destruction of these sets to be oneself if
both are zero
you would expect a zero if both are one you definitely expect one so you
get a sort of inverse picture
all the way on this line would definitely expect a degree of membership of one
to the structure of these sets down here is that the case we would expect
a degree of zero and then you sort of get these lines four point five
point but you formalise this is a little bit better but that is not proposed
to do
is he proposed to use the so-called mean marks very you define conjunction and i
hope form pops up yes that they define the conjunction of two fuzzy sets a
and b
that's the minimum of the degrees of memberships of these individual sex so the conjunction
here is defined as the minimum of the degree of membership to set a and
the degree of membership to set b
i down here just a little examples this would be our the blue is the
membership function for my set a and the green line is the membership function for
set b
popped up but only the minimum which essentially be is zero line here it's all
there is zero then starts declining agreement that going to just get this little rectangle
here this just make sense but it's want to belong to both sets you have
to belong to both sets the maximum so this suggests what the the operator for
the disjunction is still take the maximum of the and i mean note how it
works right for the disjunction up here we do if one of them is zero
because if both are one we get a one so the extremes of the the
extreme case we we exactly the way you want them to do the same is
true for the maximum if one of them is one will end up getting a
one if both are zero newfangled we get a zero and if both are one
we also so in that case the maximum you essentially follow sort of the the
whole of these two groups opted to go back up here that would be sort
of the
the structure of of these two sets and then we can also define indication what
would be sort of the degree of membership to the set not
and will define this by using one minus and again the works nicely for the
willing cases it was you're you're end up getting a one if you want to
get this is converted nicely in all sorts of intermediate cases i think can again
this is the
the red line here is the disjunction and not a this the special and so
not a is true essentially all the way out there and all the way out
there and just declines and here in the core region of my set a it's
OK so this works nicely
became defined different operators just to demonstrate that this is not the only way of
doing it actually many around you really want to go into the the book describes
some more there's the so-called product bounded sum norm the conjuction conjunction is defined as
simply the product of these two membership functions again if you look at that if
one of them is zero it is zero if both are one you get once
the most extreme cases work
the disjunction is
this expression again you can place one so what happens if one of them is
one if one of them is zero that's fine
and the negation stays the same
and this time we'll get
well since the product it's not quite as high as this one and this is
actually already and also previous conjunction was an example for fuzzy set that has the
height of not one right behind in this case the two point two five the
the nice thing here is that the
this is the disjunction is little bit higher here because you end up in the
news practical difference here
and the negation stays the same
talking find knows that playing with these things
this is probably but if you want to formalise this more you would start stumbling
across but i don't want to do that today and brilliant minds he would stumble
across the notions of t norms and s norms which is from data describing different
so what is that it's the last two
each player thai fighters rocking you choose rock player one chooses row
thirty two the columns if we tie
the book is zero
if i choose paper you choose rock with backwards that i should get one and
you should get minus one
if i choose paper newspaper we get a zero ppt scissors
should be one minus one and this is minus one
so it's not rock paper scissors OK but anyway that's the model of just the
standard game written in normal form
any game that involves multiple stages can always be converted to one of the simple
tables even chance you could conceivably write although in a very practical in one of
these fables in repeated game playing the same game over and over let's say we
just had two players to be simple
what do we get we have these rounds each round
the players are simultaneously choosing an action i choose arose the column and then we
find out usually what
our path is
what do you find out what the action of the other player was
and you get payoff
the goal of course is to maximize
average long-run average equivalently along with total payoff
i mean this is the natural setting for learning rate you don't have to know
your opponent and you don't have to know
and actually in in the models we consider you need to know your point is
in fact you don't even need to know what the game you're playing is you
can find out as you go along
we only feed back into is you know which actions you have
each time you choose an action
and for simplicity we can even get by with less feedback the feedback you get
is just you know
how much you made
and how much you would have made
had you chosen any of the other actions
so this could actually be very big table that many players but all your feedback
you really need to know is for each of your actions how much made that
time you play and how much she would have made had played anything else
so this is very much like the online setting
because you're going on online and now you really do have an adversary so the
adversary way of looking at things
is very natural
for this setting
and the questions
to do understand mostly what the repeated game model is playing this game of an
overactive is we see what the opponent did and we're trying to do
of course we all know that in rock paper scissors
the best thing to do is to choose according to the distribution
to randomize well we don't all the
but it turns out that if you can
if you're going play this game a long time you better best of enemies actually
really need
programme i've seen that will play it will be you in rock paper scissors i
don't know i forget where i saw this but it's program you play it and
it will almost always be true in rock paper scissors and the point is that
people are very bad at minimizing definitely coin
basically this program will be able to predict better predict what you're going to do
with probability better than the third and the u
more often than not very frustrating
yes i was thinking the same
well i mean the simplest thing to think about it you see what your opponent
we can get by with less than that let's just say OK i thought i
play rock paper but i knew the game
i thought what he did
that's fine
so if i choose an action a each time he chooses a one a two
a three b one b two b three i choose it around i have seen
a one b one b one a two b two
up until
a i minus one minus one as well as this matrix here
as i said the
in some sense the best way the equilibrium of this game would be the randomized
so you want
the column player which is you know some distribution which again represented new
and some other distribute the row player has to choose another distribution maybe the same
in anyone guess what distribution this is
this is mu because you know you got them you just like move
what distribution do you think this is anyone's guess
you get this is that the greek letter news
this is new OK anyway thank OK so
the opponent chooses from a distribution
basically the same and that and since we all know what nash equilibrium is this
is a mixed strategy nash equilibrium means that given the information about what distribution you're
my distribution has to be the best in response
and vice versa
and equilibria always exist even if the game is not zero sum
so what is the zero-sum game of the this is a zero-sum game meaning that
whatever i make you lose
so there is no
money coming out of nowhere else and always add up to zero
so i guess
i looked first appears notes i wasn't here when he gives lecture but i guess
he didn't cover boosting in games
something like nobody OK well
grouping and so
this is some of his research that
so suppose we write this zero-sum game we can we actually have to tell you
one of the entries the payoff to player one
if it is zero sum game because payoff to player two is
the opposite the negative so they have to play one is a i j if
player one plays rho
i n player two plays column j
the payoff to player two is minus the i j
going first is disadvantage in this situation
of course if the disadvantaged have to go first if point can see what you
we think that we're playing simultaneously just a second imagine going first
many of you have seen this minimax how many using the minimax theorem
good so this is going to be very simple proof of the minimax theorem using
the weighted majority algorithm
i'll go through the proof but i give you the basic idea
so if you go first to do more stuff if you go first that means
that i get to choose
it's a bit
the column player and i have to go first
that means that you youtube i magna choose some column and after to use the
colony going to zero
the payoff to player one will be this value
it's going to be
less than of player one has to go first and he chooses
rowan then player two can get were based on whatever choice
player one
makes player two can choose a column to to minimize
anyway if if if you don't want to get into detail in all is going
first is disadvantage
now you can also talk about the same statement with mixed strategies for that strategy
and then the opponent chooses a mixed strategy
so i tell you how i'm going to randomize in rock paper scissors and then
you get to choose how you're going to minimize
thanks much for the invitation i guess the
the programme as far as i missed that this morning was
excellent i mean score and
and the monk presented
and very interesting work in egypt prior get
for this talk was kind of quite three of these if my integration will be
an event related
she would probably know on the event related potentials
in cognitive neuroscience this is what i'm working with my interest
with that
the talking a bit ways of putting the guys together so we have g and
then predict the fmri
four UVF nine hundred to or you can go down to the
black box like neural signal that is at the bottom of the death of the
of the signal that be looking at uniform mind try to
come with diffusion model are common generative model that
it gives you
the idea of how these types of signals
for any one of you who hasn't been in norway this is a very good
research environment there's also
scenery this is a mountain in bergen about ten minutes from my house this is
my view from my belt balcony and pentecost
eleven PM i didn't do anything to the colours here just this is how it
looks like there a small church was small house is a small town close to
so it's all in all of a nice place to be
we are
calling to national competence centre i don't know how much it means no is four
point five million inhabitants berlin has five or
something like that you have
given take so
we're kind of collecting competence for my research in EEG research and method development in
that direction were part of a different bunch of networks not centre of excellence is
something integrate across
sweden finland denmark
with say helsinki and all of work
two things i have to put this slide in here
neural activity which is the black box to me
and the sort of the signal which is easy and therefore i have something to
to do with cognitive neuroscience how we can
use these signals to make inferences about human cognition
it has to do with the practical aspects of things so
e g you use because it's all around everybody has one
i got four amplifiers wanna take you home with me but when i one of
to play play around with EEG and my daughters easy very cheap you can do
it in humans you can do it all the time no side effects and are
known is not invasive
the widely available
and the temporal resolution is instantaneous so so you don't lose much of the
temporal resolution of the gene
of the of the brain's sorry
on the other hand you have
no spatial resolution and you have to heavy undersampling and you have the inverse problem
and then
that can be solved with the from my where you have good spatial resolution you
can do in humans you can repeat it a couple of times is no known
side effects to speak of if you will
it becomes even cheaper
it's invasive and
well every hospital has one and
you can do it from ryan almost any machine while on the other hand to
get to real neural activity in humans is chronically difficult need an epileptic patient or
someone else whose skull open or can be opened
and that restricts your
sample to sick people
or two subhuman species it's pretty expensive if you will compared to these guys
and you can't repeated or you have to do one chronic
it's invasive
and there are side effects to humans due to surgery
and and flexia infections in its restricted pretty much specialised centres in human study it
what i'm interested in going back here
my my my education
it was mostly easy so what i'm interested in this type of waveforms
which looks really nice to me i don't know
who shares that impression
this is an oddball so-called super simplest paradigm that you can do well second simplest
paradigm that you can do with it was invented easy takes a two tones one
is high and one low and the little one is rare or freak and the
other one is frequent is held subjects will push button to that tone which is
thickened or not so what about to the to the town rare gives up to
the task and something to discriminate and when they do that
well well
a lot
the people are of
that's right
of our
the problem here
this is
as a
you have a problem of
there are
i had a little
he played
i i
one one way a
which is life
there are
so neither of these sorts of ways of analyzing things the perfect what i'm really
saying is
you can carry out comparative studies in classification methods detection methods
in this sort of context
but don't put too much
value on the precise numerical results
you should imagine them with larger bounds not just due to
statistical area sampling error
but due to
all sorts of other things you don't know about changing economic conditions and so on
so here is the just to illustrate
given the cautionary notes that i just mentioned just on the random performed just on
the split
not the the thing changing over time just because i know that some of you
would want to know which of those methods is better but as i say i
think you should be interpreted cautiously
you probably can't see we've got
the blue bar is a single transaction
rate is
activity records averaged over one day
three days seven days down using a cost measure t one is the down is
lower scores are better
lower parser better
this first
a set of policies random forests a random forests evaluated on single transactions activity records
over one day three day seven day
random forests
logistic regression
support vector machines
the naive bayes and so the cart
this is nearest neighbour
in this case
these three of the best
random forests support vector machines
logistic regression but as i say
you should not stick
too much face on the precise numerical values
i haven't bothered to show you the
future performance very similar sorts of plot
what is clear from this is the performance
gets better
as you increase the length of the activity record
but probably the three days in seven days
are of about equal so somewhere in that sort of ballpark figure is probably an
appropriate length of activity record to years
this measure of course cost measure here
it takes time this into account and the way i described
i've already referred to some limitations of these are just like two
raise some sort of cautionary notes because in all of these comparative studies
it is in
OK in the academic literature in the data mining conferences and so you see lots
of papers describing these things and they basically uncritically interpret the results of this
i think represents a serious gap between what goes on in the academic world and
what goes on in reality
so just some limitations of these sorts of comparative studies here
the real world
is different from
the laboratory
in the laboratory
in our case for example we eliminated all those accounts which only had one transaction
during the course of that time period
couldn't do much more with a simple model so we're done here you could do
much else with random effects models and more advanced statistical models you can do something
but in the study on describing here
if something had one more in the field of transactions
it's not included in this analysis
but in the real world you would want to include
you'd use different kinds of methods
we also have two
consider what's meant by method now i listed methods i said random forest support vector
machines nearest neighbour method and so on
but what i didn't tell you because you know when you go two hours not
three weeks i didn't say
in my definition of the methods did i including the method the pre data preprocessing
transformation that i take a lot of amount for example
she should regarded that as part of the method or not
i didn't say anything about variable selection i just told you know eighty seven variables
per activity records
is variable selection part of the method
or what
i didn't talk about optimisation methods
i didn't talk about numbers of layers in in
in the neural network and so on
i didn't tell you what we did about missing values missing values are right in
this area as in any other area involving human beings
another issue is who will use the method the
people working on this particular study know about these classification methods are experts
but when you move this into a bank you can't really assume that
the guy working in the bank was in knows lot about thank you will know
about neural networks random forest
there is also this issue about what is meant by
best of the higher level and i think again every club mention the same sort
of thing
we might find some method method usually ranks first
but sometimes lasting method they always ranked second or third which is better
and obviously may vary between application domains datasets also things different kinds of fraud
so it is take a message if you like it's meaningless to evaluate methods as
you have to
really worked closely with in this case the bankers
to decide what is appropriate
OK let me switch to
the other classes
this is what i want to give you an example of
as i said
given the number of bits you have
and if and typically we use thirty two bits and so that means that the
period would be
whatever to the thirty two four billion or something like that now four billion is
that's not a long enough period so the algorithms that people really use has much
longer periods i mention this
t random three generator which is based on something called the
msn twister
algorithm that has a period of something like ten to the six thousand
which is
absurdly long
how many nano seconds have there been since the big bang only something like ten
to the twenty seven something she attended six thousand before you repeat sequence
the problem with something like two random three algorithm and this is typical of many
of the algorithms that have longer periods is that the state of the generator is
defined by the single valued by many values in the case of the random three
forget something like six hundred numbers so if you want to stop the sequence and
recorded stated
generator and then restart say in a separate calculation with the same sequence you would
have to write down something like six hundred numbers
which is for computer for you to do so it's not a problem
but so there are many deterministic algorithms i didn't i think a mention briefly the
idea of actually using a physical process as the basis of a random number generator
and sometimes those can have very specialized applications like in cryptography or something where you
might use thermal noise
in the circuit
it's the basis of a random number but the
it's certainly in particle physics that's not really an application we're coming interested in
the idea is
she goes to
to this
OK so
so we talked about for example using a linear discriminating function you have some number
of input variables
and the idea is to write down
something i think
the idea is that you have some
number of
input variables
the components of this vector represent different measurable quantities for each event
whatever the jet energy and so forth and recall that the example that i showed
with the fisher discriminant is to say to you
simply a linear combination
the idea behind the neural network is to allow for a non-linear decision boundary between
the two classes if you use this you're discriminating function that would be equivalent to
having a hyperplane is the is is the decision boundary so here's the idea is
that you say that what we can
represent the best is a sort of diagram u u
draw a layer of nodes and each node represents
one of the input variables x one x two x three and so forth
now i draw
was called the hidden layer
and i associate now value with each one of these
nodes in the hidden layer
which is related to the values in the input layer
and what you take for the value in the hidden layer
is the following
is you take this linear combination
and you use it as the argument in nonlinear function
and this nonlinear function is typically taken to be a sigmoid function is function which
look something like this
has some sort of
a linear term nonlinear turn on the goes from zero
o to one
and that will give you some numerical value
at each node of the hidden layer
and then you do the same thing you have an output node the value of
the output node is obtained in a similar way you take a linear combination
of the values in the hidden layer
and you use that as the argument of nonlinear activation function
so that's the basic idea you can generalize very easily to an arbitrary number of
nodes in the hidden layer
you could also have more than one hidden layer
although most often you typically only have one
there's some theorem that says that if you only have one hidden layer but with
an an arbitrarily large number of nodes and that can approximate
arbitrarily well this optimal solution which is given by the likelihood ratio that's what you
would like to have
but but we
you don't have to explicitly
so that's the way that the neural networks basically work when you then need to
do is to take samples of training data
which are obtained safer monte carlo models
and use those to optimally determine the parameters of the network which are basically the
coefficients of these linear combinations so every line in this diagram represents an adjustable parameters
which you have to determine
the actual
so carrying out that calculation is used
it can be numerically challenging their tools to do that
strong networks take a look at the TMVA
it's a good place to start for more information
you that something about how those are used in
i mean so so they are actually very convenient to use nowadays
it it takes you like dave moved to get started on something and you train
then you get some reside the difficulty in terms of experimental analysis is
that it's rather than transparent what it does
you know
if i have got to digest mass and i see a peak
in that on some top some background and i believe OK
that looks like really is sigma with the neural network uses some sort of band
in the high school region what is called one
you don't know
i mean less intuitive it could have exploited something in the data that looks different
to your estimate background you've used to training and by chance that looks like a
sigma but isn't really the signal so so so typically these techniques are
more applied to really mature experiments so they were applied at the end of lap
there now apply to the temperature when people have already gained a lot of understanding
and that of the data is very controversial to to apply them in the beginning
for instance at the LHC because it's harder
to really understand because some sort of arbitrary me OK not arbitrary but it's it's
it's in and transparent function could be what it does and we don't
no what does this mean that the plot of the into put variables make sure