t two g for the octahedral case
the difference in energy
between these sets of orbitals
is this
sign here sort of the delta zero sign
and actually o and that after he trolled was up to huge role
and it's the crystal
so it's how much the ligands where the field so this
theoretical case up here there's no splitting going on
you bring in
the ligands and they causes splitting because some orbital to go up in energy in
some to go down
and the distance between them to the degree of splitting
is this octahedral crystal field splitting energy
now the overall energy of the system is maintained
so if these go up in these go down
to get everything to be equal
so these parts some of these should go up
trying to draw the straight from this line
these were going to go up in energy
five plus two
the octahedral crystal field splitting energy
and these three orbitals are going to go down
in energy
will be stabilized
by minus two for this
the octahedral crystal field splitting energy so two orbitals are going up so it's by
three orbitals are going down so it's by two this because
it's going to have to equal out so you're not for creating a different system
here the energy is is going to be conserved the overall energy is maintained so
torvalds up to thirty three orbitals down
too fast
so that's really it's a very simple idea
instead of the
we're all the ligands are everywhere
when you put them in octahedral geometry it that some of the the orbitals differently
than others some inner orbitals go up in energy some go down the overall energy
it is maintained
so let's look at an example now
and figure out how to put electrons into the system
so let's look at the case where we have
nh three three
and we are
so first we need to figure out the oxidation number of chromium
having everything in the graph here
i mean that you have six ligands total
three NH three ligand three b are ligands or from i'd like it
and those are all in one bracket there's no number in the corner of the
brackets so that means the overall charge
in the system has to to be equal to zero
so what will be the oxidation number of grammy
should be minus one
three minus one
what about NH three
as a unit
so three times zero
and what is that we view with the the oxidation number of chromium
so we have prostrate so now we can figure out d electron count
so we need to look up the group number
the group numbers what
can you see it up there
most people seem to be saying six
OK so that's right
so x minus three
it's great so this is the gene three system
so that means we're going to put in free electrons
so where would you i mean to put those electrons down here up here
what if i do this
would that be good
so we we are coming back to some of the role of the learned earlier
in the semester
so first you want to put them in the lowest
energy orbitals
you don't want to ever have won with two parallel spins because that would give
you the same four quantum numbers
so that's not good
and you also have a choice want to put them in the same
energy put them in single eight before you start to pair so those are all
things that you talked about earlier in the system
earlier in the semester
so we put our three
electrons in one to each orbital
all the spin
so we have a lot principal pauli exclusion and also huns rule all at play
here with how we put in the electrons
so now we can
we can
talk about the d and electron configuration
and maybe i can rate over here
that's just the way of expressing how many electrons are down here
electron configuration
so that would just be able to
t two g
so the three
so you list the name
of these sets of orbitals and that's really why these have labels because it makes
your life easier instead of listing all the orbitals each time so there are three
in this lower energy levels
now we can also talk about
crystal field stabilisation energy
crystal field
you don't get this confused with
crystal field splitting energy
crystal field stabilisation energy
and it's abbreviated c
and that's really just thinking about how
much to stabilised by
this splitting
he was the first one to record the and had very very few neurons i'm
not sure we can rest
shared with those data
i don't think wolfram schultz wolfram schultz is kind of the expert of recorded dopamine
neurons in monkeys and i don't think he's ever done similar stimulus reward
you might also ask what about stimulus reward reward
you would want to stimulus to hide of twice as much prediction are nothing to
the rewards so there are still things to be done
people have put this theory to stringent tests not only the ones that we saw
with different probabilities in different magnitudes but also
one hundred buyer all winter and it is they said well
we know that if we have regular temporal difference learning
the value at each point in time should be
and exponentially weighted sum of all the previous rewards
you can work that out out of TD learning and we won't work right now
but you can check it later the last reward have the highest influence on the
critical value then the one before that less influenced less according to
the learning rate so there are exponentially discounted because of the learning great
so the question is could we see that in dopamine neurons and what they did
is they gave
the monkeys different amounts of reward in in each trial and recorded the prediction error
the the
dopamine signal any child
fit a model
well let me be very clear now we're looking at the prediction are sort of
prediction should be reward minus value right so the last word should have
o weighting of one
minus the values of mine this kind of
and so they took the prediction regression on all the previous on the
last ten
the magnitudes of the last ten
rewards and indeed found
these points the black which fit amazingly well to the red line which is the
prediction of the model
with the concept learning great
and in the same study they
they could also
there kind of a slightly different analysis where every trial
and the model predicted what the prediction error should be after fitting the learning rate
to the specific monkey
and the measured firing great is on this axis and you see that basically
a straight line as you could want from noisy
biological measurements
after the prediction error of minus o point one then it kind of
it flattens out that's
that's an issue that we're still that people are still grappling with the thing is
prediction errors if dopamine firing is the prediction error it there can be negative firing
it can only stop firing completely
right so at some point this has to level out and something else maybe has
helping representing negative prediction errors are hypothesis is that in other neuromodulators does this
or that the length of the gap in firing that passes from hand by the
length of of the gas
represents how big this prediction are the negative prediction errors but least for positive prediction
errors are so nice
linear relationship between what the model says prediction should be and how much the neuron
so the idea is the dopamine
prediction error
and we know the prediction errors have a role in reinforcement learning prediction errors are
learning right
first of all as he said
dopamine project mainly to the basal ganglia basal ganglia
are these
complex structures on both sides kind of inside not in the cortex inside your brain
if you go kind of from here to its the middle
and what we know about what do mean does there is
corticostriatal synapses show dopamine dependent plasticity so this is quite a mouthful but
right i have
this is the neuron in the straight
and they get inputs from two directions from two areas one is from the cortex
from from outside the
frontal area of the cortex mostly so this is this for coming to this snaps
and on the other hand it gets don't need reference kind of hard the synapse
is called the neck of this five this is the head of the five hundred
index of the spines of each and every snaps
and it turns out
but if you are
if you excite the neurons here so you invoke activity in these neurons and in
a way that causes this neuron to fire
and measure how that affects the strength of the thing that's usually LTP long-term potentiation
and hebbian learning prescribes that fire together wire together if this virus and this virus
their connection strength
but it turns out that in this in these
cortex two straight synapses
only if there's still around that happens so here you see
these measurements
i don't mean
was around and so
the height of the activation of this neuron became higher after
carrying their activity their activity
in the bottom here there was no dopamine around and actually even became lower
so the idea is
that's not not regular hebbian learning here but three factor learning rule you need to
have both the presynaptic neuron and the postsynaptic neuron
and dopamine around for learning which is exactly what we wanted we wanted learning contingent
on prediction errors if there's the prediction error you should learn and if there's no
prediction there you don't need to learn
so so far
what we have is the conditioning can be viewed as prediction learning
and we already have
an algorithm for how to do that given by reinforcement learning which is temporal difference
now we have a neural implementation of that we have temporal difference areas in dopamine
that affect learning in corticostriatal synapses
in the basal ganglia
this is very very very exciting for neuroscience because we want to understand what does
it mean does not only do we have an answer here but we have
a normative theory for why dopamine firing is the way is it's not only telling
us that the prediction error tells us why
what would we want this to be this way one prediction errors for optimal learning
of values that predict future rewards so it's it's much more than just describing the
function here
and this is
also an example of how
once we have a computational model of learning that allows us to look in the
brain for hidden variables that the model postulates OK
prediction error is basically hidden variables you can see it people's behavior or in the
inputs from the world it's something that the model
suggested and here we found it in the brain and we'll see other examples
and this was yale university press
and these were three lectures he gave at yale university in nineteen thirty two
the open world and if the subtitles says metaphysics
of science
you can see this is a book on philosophy
of science and mathematics
and this book is not as well known but i think it's an even better
book in some ways
there's a book of her violin nineteen forty nine which is much better known
which was originally published in german i won't try to say in german but in
english it was the philosophy
of mathematics and natural science and it was published by princeton university press
in nineteen forty nine
that's a very well known book of his own philosophy but the open world is
not as well known
and in this book i discovered
one day
a very interesting idea
which i'm going to write down to you now
and i'm going to say it two ways of saying it
the way
hermann vials of say the way in your language
the way from involves that it is
if a rule
can be talking about a scientific law is the law can be
arbitrarily complicated
arbitrarily complex
then the
of law
becomes vacuous
when all or
because there's always along
it is always
the law
now in your language the way to say this would be
if a pattern can be arbitrarily complicated
then the concept of pattern pattern becomes meaningless because there's always pattern
that's the same idea
and herman viola
cool says that this idea comes from
of lightness
in sixteen eighty six
from the the metaphysics
discourse on metaphysics
he scored
and in fact if you go there you find it i think it's
it's paragraphs five and six of the discourse the metaphysics
there's a link
from my home page from my website to the detect national france where you get
this book for free
in france
i also have a link to an english translation
the discrete metaphysics is a small
outline that live in its wrote
in sixteen eighty six
he was consulting
on how to pump water out of
silver mines
and there was a big snowstorm many had free moment so he wrote on some
of his ideas
and then he
he sent a just a summary of the summary
in the letter
two a fugitive french philosophical are are no more nodes
who was a fugitive because he was afraid that qatar's didn't like his ideas
and and are no are node will only recommend this gentleman a are
the inference i always say the grand are known
he had a great reputation as of peoplesoft and arnold was so horrified that these
ideas of like he said that they were heretical
but like it's never
never never sent arnold the the complete the the the complete works
and it stayed in
enlighten it's is among languages papers
and was discovered i think it was something like eighteen fifty more than a century
after alignment as deaths
now like this is like this is personal papers were preserved by good fortune they
were preserved much of what is best work is either in letters to people
or is notes to himself when never seen by anyone else
and the reason all these papers are fortunately preserved
it is because there is the state library of hanover because like this is really
a day job is my job was being an incredible mind doing philosophy mathematics all
kinds of things
but his day job was
advisor to the duke of hanover another government responsibilities of that sort so his papers
were most of his papers deals with affairs of state
and there are preserved in the hanover state library but scattered among these papers dealing
with affairs of state which no one cares about any more are masterpieces
dealing with every conceivable subject
among them was the disk with them at the end of his
OK so
let me
try to explain this idea of a little
and to do that
what i wanna do
it is
give you a toy model of the following question so i think the key question
is whether a pattern spurious real
another way to put that is when i tell you how live said by the
which is different from the way remember also that the way let me put it
is like this
what said is take a piece of paper and just sort of scatter spots at
the close your eyes and
throwing spots of at
like i said no matter where these points are
this finite set of points there will always be a mathematical equation passing through those
the existence of a mathematical equation can not enable you to distinguish between a set
of points that is lawless that was done at random by
close your eyes and black ink against the piece of paper and a set of
points that
the following along
so how can you tell the difference well what light it says if the equation
is simple
then then that's the law
the search engine
looking into some
related questions because i want to show you how to process
two types of information
it is very important in many information retrieval and language processing tasks
this is probabilistic language models and link graph
and also i want to
i apologize because
i modified my presentation and it's a bit different from
the version that you have in new
text books
beginning from language models before discussion what is
link the language models and
what we can do that i want to give you
activation example
imagine that again for all
the search engine we decided to add
search suggestions i'm talking about
decided to
make suggestions about to write a feeling of the query
user submitted to the system
our users
i submitted this to work
britain's the
this is
actually very common
there is a page on one popular
search engine
about about misspellings in in the lab
and on this page you can see
it's usually stuff space so
the name of this well known singers
this is not the most three where may be number four
number three
if they are well educated programmers developers
how we can select right
variants of this work
because we have
good programmers
you know that how we can calculate
similarity between streams
and usually
we are using living
distance this time distance
american pronunciation
basically the number of edit operations that hundreds
one string to another string
our misspelled the name of this
famous goal
it can be converted into
alright spelled word
the first is
and in this case you need to
edit operations
it's all of
for example we can remove y
and i
it can be can where we can convert
also this to edit operations
first name
OK so
talking about number of edit operations
it doesn't help here
they have the same result
OK so in this case what we can do if you remember from all the
second lecture we can get
huge training set at all different misspellings
and from these training set generate different rules how people
how people
this type of work
and using this huge set calculate probability of every modification it's like
eleven signed but with probability
and i
i one hundred percent sure that in this case
when ification to breed
it be much more probable
simply because
a one i is pretty common
three ground in english language and a i and is also pretty common and based
in the simplest case because just say well be right
you know we can do like maximisation standard statistical inference procedures
we write down the likelihood of the log likelihood function
so it's just the sum over the counts and then so the observed frequencies and
the log of
the probability of war of the observed word given the document and that
you know it's just this mixture something
so we can try to maximize that
of course the problem is with these you know with these types of mixture models
you know you might have seen this before you know you get a non convex
optimisation problem and you know that we have to resort to resort to
approximations doing that OK and so on
i will
go over the
some of the details here the argument that's used again we will use the expectation
maximisation algorithm so familiar with that you just take a moment write the model OK
but i would do this here even if you are familiar with it might be
illuminating to see
what the solution really is so in the expectation maximisation algorithm
we are alternate to step one step the so-called e step where we compute the
posterior probability
of the
later the unobserved variables OK what are the unobserved variables here we're basically what our
model assumes is that every occurrence of the term in the document is associated with
a particular concept think of it as the hidden cause you know why is that
term occurring in the document well because the document is with a particular concept OK
so the question is if we see w in the context of the document d
what's the probability that that is somehow has to do with the particular concept c
and well proportional to the probability that the document deals with that concept and the
probability times the probability that the word w expresses the concept can then just smaller
and then these posterior probabilities are used to
we estimate the parameters OK so you you have estimates of the parameters on the
right-hand side to compute the posterior probabilities and those go to the right-hand side and
you compute new estimates for your parameters and the way you do that is also
very trivial
you know for instance here right what's the probability that the word expresses the concept
well you look at all occurrences of the word and then you look at the
posterior probability for each occurrence of the word whether it expressed particular concept or not
just that this
and then just knowledge
right so these equations are really trivial right so you know there's basically nothing else
but how often is term associated with the concept
i mean of course these probabilities
how often might not be a cold but rather some action number and on the
right-hand side we have you know how often is document associated
and now we can just you know reiterated two
and you know that's what the EMI with which do
so for those of you who are not familiar with the model with i also
have a little
on on how more formally
you could actually write design OK and then we show you
just the flavour of how you how you typically do this so
you know our log likelihood function is some some overall observations and here actually i
assume that have a document word occurrence and i just have an index are
OK just has to do to be able to deal with multiplicities of the same
term occurring in the document can we just number them by OK every occurrence of
a term and the numbers are
and what we can do actually
it is to come up with q permit lower bound on the log likelihood in
which in the following way
where we
you know this q are fuzzy or q is is not probability distribution over the
concepts and for every
you know for every observation we can make a choice for that distribution
and then we will we will actually get lower bound on the log likelihood now
why sisters-in-law bound on the log likelihood
easily follows from
jensen's inequality
you know basically the log likelihood function
signal as we would have gotten if we whiten the data
but without spending the time that are required to whiten the data
so all the hidden units are going to see
is the underlying data
but the learning signal connections
is going to be the same as they would have got
if we if we want we stopped one the data before we did this
so how does that work well
imagine pixel that can be correctly reconstructed by these pairwise interactions
we go out we come down again
it's correctly reconstructed anyway by the pairwise interactions
so for example it doesn't need any top-down input
OK we get the right anyway it's the same in the data reconstruction so the
learning signal for it
but if the pairwise interactions get it wrong
then we get a big thing as well as an edge
so the learning signal you get from CD
it is like the learning signal you get away data
you don't have to wait to do the right thing
or rather the time it takes you to to reconstruct is sort of the time
it takes to do the two would take you to the widening
but your inferences going straight through already you're ready inferring things in higher layers while
doing that reconstruction
and the point of the reconstruction is not to get a better model of the
it is to get the worst model of the world
they give you better learning signal
that's just a theory
so so far what we've been doing is just
learning to
change the
the top down input to hidden units
to visible units but not actually modulate the national connections we assume that fixed
what would really like to do is be able to
what left connections so i can tell soldiers to kind of stand to arms length
apart when i can
obviously generate one like that
we don't want to fix tomorrow i would like to be able to much more
and in fact the the general principle here
which is if you want to build the hierarchical systems
things one level can tell things that have low exactly what they ought to be
they can tell things at the level below
well they ought to be trying to achieve in some sense
that's a much better way to do abstraction a big management hierarchy the guys at
the top level shouldn't be telling you
you know where to put your hand on the desk so you can we should
quickly so you can fill in the next fought this should be telling you that
they should be paying you of fulfilling all forms quickly
and then you figure out how to do that
well i think it's the same in more enormous any hierarchical system you don't want
to micro-manage
and so what you want is wonderful should create the objective function for the level
and then the level of to the optimisation
so for example
if you're a faculty member you should explain to your students what the true objective
function is that is the number of papers with my name on really counts and
then the graduate students optimise the very good luck
so long time ago terrace and ask you pointed out that
this is just a sort of quadratic energy function there's no reason we should make
it cubic i think you can probably generalize beyond that
this will be good enough for us
and the learning algorithm will go through you just have to measure the sufficient statistics
and i triples of
so i can think of unique as acting as a switch
so if k was the hidden units and this was too visible units when k
is all
we have the weight w i j k between these two visible units in the
case of we don't
OK so k can switch in this way
and you can actually view it causes symmetric you can view i switch on wide-ranging
k two
so you could use higher levels machines like that for example modelling image transformations
is this pixel goes there
and this pixel goes there
that's the consistent translation
so we could have if we had units represented translations this screen unit could say
i've got a big weight here and i got a big weight here
so when i see this pair
both of them
this pair times out weight causes me to get lots of input
and this pattern that would cause me to get more input with several of these
overcome i bias my negative bias and i turn on saying i believe in this
OK so that's how you make some the detector translation
it can also generate translation
by you give this and you get this little is that
OK and we can learn using the
CD learning
but the problem with this is
we've got lots and lots of these parameters because that we have one parameter for
each pair
of these times the number of hidden units we
so more recently we tried factorizing
this is basic argument is if you think about translations of images
you don't really need enough degrees of freedom to represent arbitrary permutations translations on my
so let's suppose we need less parameters maybe we can factorize useless parameters
so we'll factorized this
in this way
it looks was initially we're going to say we can model this
this this is the weight tends around american minimum attendance
as the sum
a whole bunch of factors
in practice and each factor is a three way outer product of one dimensional vectors
and when you add all these up
if you add up enough of them you can model any turns
but if you have less of them you can model tensors that have nice regular
structure and that's what we want
so it is these guys only have two indices so we only have quadratically many
of these and three times quadratic is much better than cubic
you can think of his my three way to protect the product of the WIF
the wj from the whf and that me tensor
that's a rank one tensor
but one add up enough i can get tens of any running
and we can think of
one of these guys the hidden ones
as specifying the covariance matrix
sorry an inverse covariance matrix here
this is the energy function the pairwise energy function between the eyes and the joes
the inverse covariance matrix
so by taking
which combinations of hidden units we can synthesize inverse covariance
now i'm
now the camera is moving off the cycle can be moving in between
the two cameras and sticky encyclopedia if they use
and when you're just like in the other guys
looking straight at you
a renowned computer scientist from
a heinrich
and it's nice when he looks at using this
OK so one application for this in teleconferencing supposing you got you know
super laptop with you you can get now with the camera very
and you are
teleconferencing girlfriend has the same that top pretty good except an annoying thing is that
you don't quite
he doesn't look at you you don't look at it's not being rude it's that
it is looking at the
you know picture viewing the screen you can't looking at the camera competent both
and you know short drilling a hole
in the middle of your expensive black top and poking camera through
you know what we can do about this well here is one possible technology
forward which is that you mount the camera
on the two sides of the laptop or maybe at the top and the bottom
usually shorter and now synthesized
the view in between
and actually
we can simply cite the cycle continues that would be
you know in directly in between
but we can also synthesize
you know if you anywhere
along the line joining the cameras that would be good if you want to you
know you've got a window
based computing system you move the window around that has the person talking in the
more general but can do whatever the window not
OK so
just a few minutes more on stereo matching problem then will be nice btw tomorrow
or methods for solving the optimisation problem
so so far we talked about
using dynamic programming to solve this problem
along with two epipolar lines
and you know that sounds quite good except the result you get when you do
not always what you would wish also here is the disparity map derived from this
pair of images of
the pentagon
you know the pentagonal
this is a a very popular in the
very for some reason
i think because they paid for the work
and you see that there is a sort of quite frequently artifacts were all aligned
you know something failed minutes it work most of the time because most you see
looking reasonably
plausible but every now and again this the castro's catastrophic failure the entire
a small part in this place backwards
and and so now that the whole the whole thing is
the ship
and it will not be very difficult to stop this happening only prior
on good disparities within were not restricted to
what happens on line but also to counter the neighbouring lines
and so we to do something about that and you know this point we might
you start to get very creative about inventing priors the work in two dimensions but
you should feel bad about that because what's going to happen to the programme
yes it's going to be totally missed messed up because once you get two dimensions
there is no natural ordering of the data from the dynamic programming is not going
to work and because we might try some sickening hybrids where you kind of moving
raster scan order down the image solving with no programming is you go and you
get a least half the constraints because you take the line we already solved and
use the line you take it as if it was correct problems still being inferred
and then use that inference rigid constraints the next line of work they might do
something a bit but you know you're for professional you're not going to put up
with that kind of thing
all right
not even when it nearly in
you know
we really would like to have some
the constraints between neighboring epipolar lines and you know is what the constraint what to
you have
in fact
and that is a problem
are more
in fact
each of
there he
he is
you can
they are as
four years later
it is
well in that case for
it inverts
what we do
all the
that means that if
but when you constructed back
u you don't suffering reconstruction sorry
right obviously if you're reconstruction error is zero then you have a perfect in color right
and in particular if the number of hidden layers the number of hidden features here
is much smaller than the number of inputs
dimensions and you have perfect reconstruction
and you have perfect compression of the data right you can also view
these kinds of models trying to compress the data
now the interesting thing about these models is that's
if the hidden
as well as the output layer lean years
and you're trying to minimize we reconstruction here
then it turns out that you can recover piece you
you can recover principal component analysis
so if you look at these key hidden units they will span the same space as the first principal components
so it's kinda interesting if you basically make this model bilinear when you recurrent piece
you many of you probably heard about you see it's like a one of these
heaviest use tools
a fourth
you know across many many different domains data compression there are
so you can view autoencoders is non linear extension of see which can be much more powerful than piece you
if your data is binary then obviously you can also is a decoder in decoder
stage in your also uses a nonlinear
decoding function
in this case sigmoid function
you know this is has become very
also successfully used models and it actually relates to something that's called restricted boltzmann machines
relates to both machines and graphical models
so one of these key components in a lot of these models is that you wanna get sparse representations
that turns out to be you
a very useful thing and empirically people found that's you know if you wanna get
good features u you wanna put some kind of sparsity on on
on the latent representations and here you if even if you're trying to discover binary
features you'd like them to be sparse
and that's exactly
sort of the model that was done by
and why you're group of a few years ago
we're again trying to minimize every decoder a function that attempting to minimize the reconstruction
error so this is this is the reconstruction error
this is the penalty on these latent features you want these features to be sparse
so you put one penalty it's a common thing to do
and this has been courting function
it turns out that's been coding function is also a very useful to students to have in particular test time
it's a very useful
an explicit encoding function because the test time
when i show you a new image show you a new web page
you'd like to get the latent representations very quickly right
and an explicit according including function allows you to do that
now one of the things that people realized you know five or six years ago
is that well he can actually stack these things
so you can learn
you know
first layer features
then you can repeat the operation can say well can actually take these latent features and then call them again
and so forth and maybe at the top level i'm gonna have my classification model
or whatever you want use them fore
come now when you look at the stacked autoencoders you know you might ask why
people have that salting caldas existed in the last twenty years
but only five
four five years ago people figured out that you can actually stack them
the question is why people haven't thought of this thing before r
this a natural thing
um why people have tried doing that's
and it turns out that you know if you look at the stacking here it's
not obvious whether it's a hack or whether there is some deep mathematical insight
behind these kinds of models
and i'm gonna show you'll
that's taking makes sense in terms of actually
optimizing a certain kind of objective function
so it's not it's not a hack
this is known as a greedy layerwise pre-training or greedy layerwise
learning of of the features
now at the test time you can remove the decoder if you're just interested in
recognizing what's going on in images as well speech signal web pages
and just in code
given an input tax you just go through multiple layers of representations and then u
you can use it for four for classifying things
in general
you know you can use standard am in colder and that's sort of equivalent to
a neural network model a neural network architecture can use convolutional which is
of this line
OK so
we all know what a galaxy distribution is a you know what accounting processes probably
right so that's how you go from the finite dimensional world international world for function
the you do that you just say from many international world of functions i take
a finite number of points
and i asked them to have a girls in distribution
i could never find a collection of points
five by core theorems
i put a measure on function
public health process
we can do that same procedure all kinds of other distribution of the gaseous like
and so the dirichlet distribution is financial for distribution and i can ask to put
a distribution in different order of objects by taking finite dimensional
sample over here as it
consistency something else in case
i have to have these points in the single so measure five overlapping points to
the same destination of points
well you it is richly distribution also get an called the dirichlet process so the
way that works is that i think some underlying space called that omega
and i thought now into a finer partition
and again points now getting cell of the partition
and for each of those cells i assign a measure that cells not is the
underlying measure on this space
and not a one is the measure signed a one hundred not and so on
to cells so do not have a at the wonder measure citing these cells
and if i plug in i get scaling factor caused directly probabilities can you are
parameters can be positive and from the one
then i can plug these numbers into a dirichlet distribution
and i give myself a random sample of numbers that sum to one
if i do that again i'll get another set of numbers that sum to one
of these is the underlying parameters for these fixed partition
like in the gas in case i think the point i have a alpha point
now i can do that for all partitions
and i get consistency i use the same cell here multiple partitions would get the
same problem find itself
and you do that by the dirichlet distribution by aggregating cells in the dirichlet distribution
i get pulled directly probably which is the sum of the hyperparameters for those cell
the work
so you get the commodore vaccine holding
and therefore there must exist an underlying process on on what now
well on measure
on measures
functions in more but i measure because the measures
OK so that hopefully give you a flavour of the of the definition and the
fascinating fact about this is that is now a distribution on measure what sample i
get a measure
that measure turned out to be an infinite sum of atoms
it's the screen probably one no matter what not
give you a little flavor that's interesting
a little flavor why that occurs think about the poster process if i sample t
from a dirichlet process i got one of these measures and then sample theta from
what the poster prof
well for a fixed picture partition
one of the data fell in one of the cell
so by the usual the risley updates on on the financial world
the exponent of that
cell one by one and all the other thing
the usual dirichlet multinomial update
but that must be true for any partition therefore by for myself to be really
really small around that data
always been export going by one more health small that sellers
would suggest adam nelson there that data
so that the posterior process of the same gene up extra data
now back to doing this
eventually reveal all of the
and while the final for infinite sum of atoms
that's what you produced and from that argument was around already in the seventies and
i must say not very many people understood it was in probability theory and no
statisticians really grab hold of anything with
OK if there hard paper story but you know i think from this discussion hope
read them and they want
but in the nineties finally someone actually prove the theorem which is much easier to
and and give you construct procedures the common works the problem is that it's an
existence theorem always right no construction
but the romans showed that
g this object that we have is mysterious on the previous slides actually has a
representation as an infinite sum of and
this is logarithmic anymore
and it's the sum over pi i don't think it was but iraqi delta theta
look and the locations are coming from the not so this red thing here is
not so let's say the gaussians for simplicity
and then i sample atoms from you know that blue things
and i get an infinite sum of atoms
with certain weights in these weights are what are called stick breaking weights and where
they come from is product of beta
distributions samples from data i was stick the goes from zero to one
break up the first piece in the stack under beta distribution is called beta one
the second piece is the remaining part of the stick breaking up another bayonet that's
been to get these links here
and that's what these parts are
right so if i did that once get a bunch of atoms
and i'll get about to pi values get and put them all together i get
a big g that's what the blue thing it's like a picket fence
by doing this again will obviously get different atoms and i get different pi values
linear motion evolution equation that is the state that phi x
a simple linear combination of the state at time exposure time them the wall
plus some kind of ocean this
with the appropriate metric
so the
something time it's relevant in this context
all these things are just markov process
because what i can write
so this is the punisher and from
experiments what makes a gaussian distribution of arguement xk
i mean x minus one
on compliant even that sigma that is the the the distance
OK so this is very popular
bowling talking on this is ue the learning some applications in computer vision
another the type of
addition of the markov process
OK for example the very as you interested in speech signal
very very basic
models of speech
i don't see the learning basically
this page and they are also this is what i mean is simply to say
that the page time testing the switching time is simply a linear combination
of the previous value
the speech signal
at time n minus one minus the
some notion of
these things are obviously
can or return
as a markov process
what you need to do what you need to do to do this just the
state you k which is pretty x
it's a minor point you might as well be used back
in the same picture the value of the node on the end of the day
on your rewrite everything
you see that will be extended process
then you have also only
gaussian evolution equation which is very similar to to the politics of the new except
that now
the metric of the metric are different but nothing
nothing only
the prime it's still a markov models
so could be a bit more fun
the call says if doing it you know it's very good
because in particular
which can be non stationary or anything like this
the three of them
and on the surface
you say well is fitting or
markov also for person they are
but well already and they are in this because it's not stationary maybe it could
be more fancy and try to put some kind of non stationary component in it
so for example you could say well it's already and they are the kind of
time varying
so in this case what you do you could try to put also
a kind of varying evolution of the occupation
so this thing well
that defines once more on the show
evolution equation for the the diffusion
on is that everything together you with the time the opposition of the speech signal
then these things can also be written again as the market also we kind of
false evolution equation
doesn't matter if the market
this is the last example
w with that any more
i'm quite interested in all the financial economic points
on in all application and we working with continuous time process
for example it is very popular modelling financial econometrics
which is the that it's the model is very simple idea
we're essentially to try to
model the dynamics of an asset price st
using a stochastic differential equation there
like an the infinitesimal increments xt
is equal to unity californian company kind of job also live process
a very popular type of model
all these things have tried to work with and our exactly
when you try to do inference is that you can for continuous time called so
the most basic
i think people are doing when they want to basically do
particle will people think those models
the first thing to do is the discrete discretized
the discrete time model simple scheme
you just keep approximate the
very related by some kind of a finite
finite differences are not due to model
which one will where can be right
and the simple
the origin of the simple markov also
on here
this is it on
there are many many if you look at basically the literature there are many continuous
time models of this one is the this is for example about net
if you look at the the model for
the dynamics of population dynamics although small enough
you by it
well when you were willing parties discretised them on it becomes this important time up
all the techniques cannot disperse all those parts of the sequential monte carlo techniques are
actually been successfully used in this context
so this is that this is a lot so now this was the
basic model
for the process
of interest in the second
of the target could be basically
the local activity of an asset or whatever
a little bit of an asset
i don't think this markup office model
the prior distribution of the process
but i don't have access to it
i don't have access to it
so what i assume in something very simple
we generalize that later on
i will assume that
xk might be
he does also
access funds
to another related process y is also
the discrete time markov process
and in particular
i will make the following statistical assumptions
i would assume that
if i knew the policies xk
i don't know if i knew it
then the salvation y a
with respect to be independent
o marginally distributed
two why we don't see e g
is this is
so there's a few things in the system that are a bit different from what
is often done in terms of sort of structure from motion
pipelines and so on so we're not necessarily detecting all the features we can see in every image
we're detecting features when we need to
so this green box flashing around especially hunting for new features
in spaces that aren't already well covered
by existing features
so you see that
worked with initializing new features has new itself
this income interview and once new features appear within tracking them
very stable
so this is a little bit more on how the tracking work so that's also
not done bottom-up it's done in a very predictive right
so in every frame
we have a
the current estimate where the camera is
current estimate of where this the features are in the world so the yes men
where the camera is now especially when was on the last frame
plus some kind of motion prediction
with an extra uncertainty added to it to account for the fact that you know has uncertain dynamics
enables us to basically predict which features should be visible
but also where image
should they
you are we most likely to find them
so basically dynamically calculating search region feature these features
one each frame
and then we basically
trying to match each those features by correlation search just within these small
prediction regions only on each frame
and that's one of the things in the early days that made the system
fast and unable to work in real time
so this then shows the output of the system
running in real time at thirty frames per second here
this thing flying around is an estimated
three eighty position of the camera so
six degrees of freedom for position rotation
displayed here is this kind of flying graphic
and then each one of these things here is one of the landmarks in the scene
so you see that has a texture patch associated with it which is kind of its unique
and here we now see a three d e
ellipse representing uncertainty
regions so you see that when
new features are initialize they appear in the map with big uncertainty particularly in the depth coordinate
as we make more and more measurements the uncertainty
shrinks down
so at demo of what we could do with this system is is some augmented reality
so here we basically going to put some virtual
objects into a real video
so this is straightforward if you've got a system which is giving you
in real time
six-degree-of-freedom position for the camera on every frame
all you do is
seven positioned opengeo
and so you draw me a shelf has this from position
stick it on top the real
and if you could the quality of your camera
emotional state estimation is good then they shall should look like they're really stuck
so the real world
and we've got some good news here for adjusting their
positions in the world
so you can see this data the results are
quite good the shelved certainly stayed pretty much in the right place you you can see the some
just a particularly when this some
inclusion of some of the features
but it's not bad
so just a shows a couple of either
applications of exactly the same algorithm
so this is an application to a humanoid robot in
lab in japan risk collaborating with
so this is just a
sequence the robot walked around in a circle
this guy's just
this is just a cradled catching case it falls over
the robot basically what random the circle and there's a camera and its head
that we were running
one slam on
um so this is the view from the cameras it works
and this is the estimated
camera trajectory and map features from
from one this land
so you can see that we will crawl around in a circle
building a map features
yeah but basically the same kind of behavior
this video is particularly interesting because it shows the loop closure so the robot comes all the way around
there's a point where suddenly these
uncertainty snap from being quite big suddenly getting much smaller again and that's happened when
the robot comes all the way around the loop
and is able to we observe
things that it's all very early in its trajectory so those are landmarks have a very accurate
positions in the world because it's all them
close to the time when it defined its coordinate frame
at the start of slam so once it can every registers with is
the other features that it's initialize more recently get pulled around with it and not so much better
estimated positions
so that's kind of classic
slam behavior
is another
demo this is something i did with one quarter mile who is now a
at the university bristow and you probably still have the running
obviously next year
but he built back in his speech to this
really cool a wearable camera system that he called a wearable robot
but had a
cameron basically a servo
actuator platform
and then so someone was wearing the collar
moving around in the scene
and we could do things like
tell the camera stay fixated on one particular object as the person is moving around
and then decatur fixate on another object
and stay looking back
so all enabled by real time position estimation from from slam
so since those days we we've
grown quite a lot in
the sophistication and what we can do in real time
visual slam there's there's been a number of things kind of going on
around the world in more general
research and a lot this research has not necessarily been in computer vision it's happening in
robotics where people are building robot mapping systems using completely
different sorts of sensors like laser range finders but still the general character of these mapping problems is very much
shared so for instance we now have a pretty good understanding of how to make really large scale
mapping systems
because basically if you can make
something that can make a good map locally similar to what you've already seen
you can then as you start exploring large areas
just basically make a chain
these local maps start building one map when it gets too big
pocket start a new one
remember the transformation between
you get a chain of connected mats
and then if you have a
another component this is often enabled by
and image retrieval type
vision system that can basically say hang on are described an image that looks really similar to what i grabbed
you know twenty minutes ago
i think i'm back in the same place i've been before
then even if there is some drift that's occurred
in these
in your chain of local maps which is inevitable because they'll always be a little
bit of error in each local map
then you can correct it you can say at this place actually joins up this
enforce the constraints
and do some kind of optimization over my whole
and you know that this image retrieval part can now be quite fast and robust
the correction of the market can also be quite fast and robust these days and you can get back to
globally consistent maps
to go beyond just people are connected people are not connected
and basically the you will be
that the
the links that will be looking at will we just i'm i'm connected to someone
not connected to someone but we will try to to go beyond sort of capture
let's the sentiment standards of links and so on
the the
OK good
so here is series of of things the things that we look and so the
first thing i will talk about is
one possible way how to sort of something that we did together in collaboration facebook
about how how to predict links or how do you recommend friends social network and
how to do this in machine learning framework and then we go beyond not just
saying what people you may know what you actually start thinking about how can what
you what you think of people so so what your friends what your enemies and
then you sort of been
one is the same how how do people evaluate others people how do people evaluate
content the they see what kind of mechanisms could be used to just see so
based on the audience that appears on the page how they become much like page
OK so these are some of the
three or four parts to the door
the second so here here and here are the things right so now i want
to focus on interactions
the first thing i will be talking about it will be a big part about
how do i recommend links in networks and then i will show you what that
that the strength estimate the strength of their tie strength of the connection on facebook
then we will go
the same not just require the people i know but what do i think of
them are my friends are my enemies of my photos and then we start seeing
about how do people evaluate others other people how they evaluate the content created by
people and so on OK so this is this is the place and we start
with the first talk about how become an example networks of how do i recommend
your friends to create OK so the second will be the following so the way
we do this is that we will be able to take a graph and we
will take a graph
the sort of music some outside sometimes it is your right and say OK what
edits are going to happen in this graph let's say the next month of our
idea will be to produce ranked list of links that that not getting the present
graph and that are predicted to appear in the
in the future snapshot of the right so you will be i'm taking the face
the graph of facebook today
i want to generate a list of new possibilities that will emerge interface will grow
in the next one OK so that's that's set and then of course how do
i measure success the way i made myself is to say OK how many of
the edges i predict that really appeared in the this future best right and the
way you can capture these kind of performances to say OK what is my precision
on the top pop right so if i say here are the most likely no
edges that i think would happen in the future how many of them you get
correct so that that is one possible way to evaluate and this is obviously a
tradition passed a prediction task was formalized this way by a little david lieberman john
kleinberg back in two thousand three and the the
facebook example sort of using moderate use this sort of is based is based on
is OK so
the idea is for example the following so so you can take in this case
collaboration networks from from different areas of physics and you have about these networks have
a few thousand of authors
and then of thousands of collaborations and now you can take for example
displayed timing to have no
one such split time in house and say OK what the new collaborations that will
happen happen in the future right so the idea is that you only you only
have to you want to create is ranked list of edges in these networks and
the way you can do this is basically the for example may be for every
pair of nodes is somehow
compute the proximity or distance and then during this paris by the by the proximity
top one on the bottom the other on the part of the the ones that
are far apart at the bottom and then the the nodes of the best of
nodes and problem is are predictions right so for example you could say i had
one way to link to engage us would be by the distance in the graph
right sort of this closer are the in the graph the more likely that just
to appear right that's maybe not so good predictor right another possible way to to
quantify the proximity between a pair of nodes to say how many common neighbors right
so the idea would be a better people that have lots of common friends together
i believe that they are more likely to create edges among themselves right instead of
sort of common neighbors i was shown here you can do that jakarta similarity between
what my friends what are your friends and was just got similarity between these two
sets there is
there is a method that will turn out sort of an unsupervised method that turn
out to work best is something that that that is referred to as a damage
on that score when sort of i go
i goal all the common friends a pair of nodes has then i take and
a some instead of just counting them which would be the common neighbours i think
one over the log of the degree of that common friend we have together so
the higher degree of the guy the less last week it will add to the
sum i could for example say the probability of two nodes connecting is proportional to
the product of of the degrees of the end points and so on and so
i have so basically for every pair of nodes in the network i could go
computer the score and now with the rank nodes by the score and predict the
node with the highest score on the top and here is how well this would
work so what i'm showing you here is results from the paper by even when
playing with these are different methods this is the this is the score higher is
better and this is the relative performance versus making random predictions right so basically the
if the charge doesn't change the charged surface density doesn't change and so the electric
field inside remains constant
so exactly what we did there
and now i'm going to
move them further apart
therefore i'm going to
make the larger
and that can only happen
the potential difference between the plates increase
i will start off with thousand balls
by these one millimeter
and then i will open this gap of ten years and then i have the
potential difference
ten thousand volts
but since the
in the capacitor
is one half
a few times the potential difference
this is the same as this delta
and if q is not changing but if i go
from the from
one thousand volts ten thousand fold is very clear
i have done work i have increased the electrostatic potential energy
and this is what i want to show you
we're going to have that there
so i changed my
television and i'll have to change the lights so little bit so you
i can see that
and this one or this one of
wait for the light to settle
and we want also the
currently is on the one on the right there
is the
and these the current meter
and you see here
these two plates
separated now by about one millimeter
i have here
a very thin sheets
transparency which i can move in between to make sure they don't make contact
here is my power supply
and i have there
this the propeller type thing which is
some kind of the voltmeter
and if going to move in this direction
that means that the voltage between the plates
so i'm going to charge now
the potential difference of
thousand and as i do that you will see a very short search here
on this and here
it's not very spectacular but at least you can see for the first time in
your life the charge is actually flowing
from my power supply
onto the plates newspapers
that's it
only the current as long as the charge is flowing
let me first say that
look at the there
three two one zero
that's all it took
the charge this place
now fully charged
thousands all different
and now as i'm going to
increase the gap
there no reason for any
charge to go away from the plates so the media will not do much
probably nothing
but you're going to see this propeller which indicates the potential difference between the plates
going to see it move because
i'm doing all this work i'm going from one millimeter to ten millimeters i'm creating
always electric fields and it's hard work pays off in terms of increasing the potential
one thousand volts
ten thousand volts
so there you go
two millimeters now
look at the voltmeter is going
three millimetres i always hard work
doing nothing for many many years
i'm creating electric fields
we should be proud of me
i'm creating an electric field look at that
electric field remains constant between the plates because the charge is trapped charge can go
and now it's seven millimetres
seven thousand volts
eight thousand votes
i mean nine millimeters nine thousand both number and needed there's nothing no charges
following to replace no charges flowing from the plates
i'm now at ten millimetres
and now i have created
huge volume electric field and the potential difference
ten times larger than it was before
and so you see
i indeed
have done work you see it here in front of your own eyes
all right let
this down and i'll take the
lights back up
and we go back
two normal
i have here
eight hundred michael for capacitor
dangerous baby
and we can charge that up to three thousand volts
and when we do that
we get three
tens of the coulomb of charge
on that
so the
it is the number
so it is one hundred
going to put the potential difference over three thousand balls
gives charge q
o point three coulomb
and that means
one half the square
which is the energy that is stored in the capacitor
is four hundred and fifty two
this will take fifteen minutes
so i'm going to charge it now
because at the end of lecture i need a charged capacitor for demonstration
so i can show you there
potential difference over the capacitor
which will slowly change
and will keep an eye on it during the lecture
and then by the time it fully charged we will have reached the end of
the lecture
and then we can
so here's is than this
one hundred microphone what i call it the monster
the complexity of the
examples that were actually observing this is coming from the empirical rademacher complexity
component we use
and is measured by the trace of the kernel matrix so that's another nice
property that we seem to be
so getting for free in this case
i think
you know there are no
other factors the only thing that's disappointing compared to say the VC proof
is that so maybe the large margin covering number proof is that we have a
square in fact coming in
and as i say that really seems to come from the way the rademacher said
that doesn't seem to be an easy way to get around
we are handling the case where we have soft margins because we've got the size
which we didn't handle directly
in the covering number case
though i should mention that
there is a technique
extending that previous covering number analysis to the soft margin case
so you can actually do it using those those results
and still
keep out of the square and territory so in some respects
i i have a sort of
slight preference for the
previous results as far as the SVM is concerned
having said that i think the best bounds for the SVM the new PAC bayesian
bounds that
i think you will probably
due to his
this section of these lectures
it simplifies even further in the case of gassing kernels because the
the kernel of
o point with itself in the gas kernel is always one
so this is just through them
so you get for of ten gamma
this is the form of the case
hopefully that gives you the flavour of one applications
o of the band
the trick is in the case of linear functions the bounding the actual function class
itself linear functions is really quite
needs and straightforward
then the technicalities coming when you try and
you know translate that into the actual application that you're interested in
so in order to sort of
i that i thought it would be good to look at
one of the case in point of applying this and so i'd like to spend
the rest of the
time we have which is
roughly half an hour
just looking at kernel PCA
to give you a flavor of of another application hopefully get
you know sort of the idea that this is applicable technique and you could think
of applying in other areas as well
OK so how does kernel PCA work
what we do is
we we can actually compute the projection of a new point into the space spanned
by the i find back to the correlation matrix
this is the correlation matrix in the kernel defined feature space i'm assuming here five
projection into the kernel defined feature space
and we'd like to compute the if the projection on the i th i but
we can do that by this
computation that doesn't involve actually computing directly in the in the feature space
it involves the eigen vectors of the kernel matrix
and the idea value of that i corresponding eigen values
so we need to do i can analysis of the kernel matrix
and we then can get a dual representation in terms of that i can value
and i can but
so this computation gives us the projection of this new point
on to the
i th
i can vector in the feature space
and the idea values
corresponds to this is also the i value of that i can be in the
in the
i cannot find feature space so this is the idea the kernel PCA trick essentially
sort of
compute do the analysis in in the dual space in the
in terms of the kernel matrix and then compute projections as if you're working in
this feature space so i won't go into more detail on the
on the algorithm itself i'm sure that that's been covered
elsewhere in this
in the summer school
this implies that we can perform PCA in a kernel defined feature space
in the normal orthonormal basis given by the eigen vectors of this
normally PCA is applied to low dimensional feature spaces so normally i would imagine doing
it in this sort of thing you given explicit factor and say i want to
project from hundred dimensions in
five or something
suddenly applying in these very high dimensional feature spaces raises the question whether that's a
sensible thing to do
if there is any statistical reliability to the
actual future directions that you
so this comes down to be like a question for statistical
learning theory to analyse
to try to estimate to what extent that those future directions are sensible in terms
of capturing the data so that is essentially what
this application of
of rademacher complexity is attempting to achieve is attempting to try and
analyse that
so it should hopefully be able to highlight the critical elements that affect the quality
of the kernel PCA
and so what we can do is considered can perform PCA on a randomly drawn
set s
of size m in the feature space defined by the kernel kappa
we're going to project new data onto the space to be that
spanned by the first k remaining the largest k i can vectors corresponding to the
largest island is in in that features
and what we would like to be able to us to the following it is
the result which says that
what we're interested in here is trying to bound how well that features that
space have those projections are likely to capture new data so we're going to get
new data
we're gonna projected into that feature space
we learn from the samples
what we'd like to be able to say
is that that feature spaces that that subspaces are sensible
space to use the new data and that means we like to be able to
say that new data will have a significant projection in that space
therefore that it is orthogonal
projection into these
orthogonal space is relatively small
and what we've got this right hand side
this notation means the projection into the orthogonal that is the orthogonal complement of the
the hands of a randomly drawn
you know this is the expectation of that projection square
so this is the amount of information that is lost
if you like when we observe the new data point and start working with it
in the in this
projection space we lost information about it by projecting it now
project was started in nineteen eighty eight he there was the international project because i
think for me and also involving six countries
it was located there was competition between the initiate even private initiative and at the
in two thousand three it was officially consider the stability
so there some preliminary results published in two thousand one the web address of of
the human genome in two thousand three it was the final image and also the
official find that there are some technical terms here
what's called the final genomics when it's solved some accuracy in some this is the
so according to
the the standards of civility technology was finished in two thousand three and so on
sources distances the two thousand one five down all the draft of the human genome
which is you can download the sequence of letters
of DNA of the of the
after getting k so that the human genome eye focus a bit on the human
genome because it used to the about but also many other organisms that have been
sequenced single organism so you have longer genomes have been sequenced but overall the what
we remain in the history of
missus this denmark papers that is and the first thing dimension
so the question was whether or not we have to do so we can solve
everything we can cure people can find all the g is protein structure so the
thing that went very fast obviously that there was a boom in the field so
this is what the feel of bioinformatics really was expecting because because it's about from
it is roughly speaking refers to using
informatics technologies so conscious and sentient technology mathematics is to try to understand the processes
seeing is a computer this requires string analyses requires signal processing centre
and things went very fast so we started before of course but something before this
started earlier but the number of people voted by twenty five increase lots thousand
so the things that we saw for many successful applications of machine learning very only
for instance
so we some feature graphical models
remember all those sentiments are are welded these were like you know applications to find
genes in india is remembered DNA is a long strand of six billion liters you
know that you think it encodes the actual parts correspond to proteins
that could be and they and there were people the organisms based on HMS and
become models two given DNA sequences speech processing text processing that they were able to
it was quite electricity to detect the genes in the in the genomes of
there was an automatic ways to
to find the genes stop referring to his
actually write some good live
and there was some first finding that was that would disappointing for researchers first discovered
that a few years ago we thought they were
the there were many of the protein so one question was how many genes those
human contain it was an open question ten years ago
people speculated about one hundred thousand perhaps and each time a new draft came in
the shape of the know the the decreased so i think nowadays estimated field twenty
five thousand
so that's also number twenty nine
if you take the
cool the human genome
which one of the function of which is to encode proteins there are fifteen twenty
five thousand positions which are called genes
that encode proteins
in fact it was a disappointing for for many people because it's not
it's not so much compared to to other organisms just take more than a slightly
more than a simple is equal to
two monkeys
so that's what we discover and so something more that we discovered that five these
these twenty five genes that are possible in a on the cover
of the order of of one percent of the gene
so currently we don't know exactly what the remaining so there are other parts which
are not genes but we know functions but in the current season operators
there's a limit of ninety seven percent of the genome that is considered as
j DNA just we don't know what it is worth ninety some people think that
it is used this is just that evolution doesn't care about having been genomes so
we cannot begin until only one of two percent of it is useful
but this is of course speculation with an idea of where what it is
he is also a the centre of terminology there is a debate here about twenty
five thousand genes which is
roughly speaking twenty five thousand
places in DNA that codes for protein now when you go from
the province had the simple just that one
DNA a gene is transcribed into one RNA and one protein but in fact there
are many processes that that means that one
jean DNA can respond to several proteins but that things called alternative splicing that says
that you're not allowed to take all the gene so when you out there and
a process can be cut extended there are so we see is good is going
we were come said
what is the genes
OK so
so this was the genome
and that was a big motivation for
it but in fact something even bigger was hidden behind the
which is
sensible set of new technologies and there were some of the countries with the
advances so they were taken committees and there were things that were made possible the
genome sequencing projects and these features show you just some of the new technologies that
that have been developed for recently so in the last ten years for sure and
that would be very useful for bioinformatics because of technologies to say that you know
the capacity to two
generate huge amounts of data
and this data with with the starting point of
research in bioinformatics
so this is
sequence are you know this is what they can when they a sell you obtain
your ten is just such that for the human genome it was
thirteen years initiate even because it would be in the first thing basically the sequence
and not fall
the other four hundred thousand dollars
it is very some companies of the world are because the countries evidence so now
this is doing continue consequence of cats
if you want is very
ricci is to
so it is becoming a major technology
now all all these features
technologies like this
now we know how to
two is to sequence who enhanced and we also because we have sequence of the
genome with some of the positions in the DNA that vary between individuals
so no this is possible to take many individuals many people like you and me
and to focus on the other positive our between g humans who twelve you know
your genome
i think i like what are your letters
in the position that
humans and this is a unique identifier for
is the set of all probability dist
well both statements
in one particular probability distribution where those
statements are true is a particular element
the particle instance
of graphical models
it's important to have that in mind because in the context of learning when we
are actually parliament rise in these people by some people
and we are doing learning or very theta
according to
we are changing actually
itself the model right
when we look
we are trying to find reach particle model instance of that class of graphs
these things things that gives us for example
much like for the data like
so these are graphical model
and again
the questions will be interesting estimating parameters for the models
computing probabilities of things in the model of particle outcomes of particular
i find particularly interesting realizations for example the MAP assignment map assigns knocking out that
just the configuration with maximal probability
and in order to manipulate
such a probabilistic model we need
we need to know about the base basically
we have p of x which is of probability distribution right
not to compute things with p of x we need to know the structure of
your facts to represent
with the representation of facts
we saw if we have
what the representation the representations of position over two
small functions of two via
if we have conditional independence
we will see some
what the representation will be when have an arbitrary number of
and now we also need to find ways of computing
things efficiently with these representation p of x the
right because that the critical thing we saw that if p of x is not
simplified in anyway
if you just assume we have the original your facts
we all the variables and we have we don't have any structure on probability
we want to compute p of x i
we need to sum over all the instances where x i hope
that's an exponential sums not feasible so basically
we will actually need find new to find ways of computing efficiently without our graphical
so these are the questions that we need
so let's start
but the rest is questioned by thinking about some exercise
in question so far we can continue
let's think about an exercise
assume you have been provided the initial everybody
let's assume that this particular conditional independence statements
this particular
x one independent think forgiven actually
what you can do
you can
as the factorized form these problems but people
conditional independence
which is given
by these
is one of the ways to represent this particular
this thing is independent of this thing given this thing here
you're just suppress the second thing here have p of x one x three
p of x one and p of extreme conditions on x next sort
this is just another break algebraic
description of this concept
according to the definition of conditional independence that this often previously
let's expand here
these expression of p of x one two and three
what we have
i have basically the following
p of x one given x two
p of x one three
p of x
well we really needed to see the
i probably sleep type is OK
this is based this will be just a few of exterior
i i wanted it now because this is latex and this compiler have to comply
so this should be p of x o
and then immediately just the disease
these first
it is given by the
and then you will think these factorizations
good so
immediately we see that we have here some type of factorizations
but has arise from a given conditional independence states
well we start to see that these structures
the sample space
is such that
the joint probability distribution
he's factorized into some particular function
so that's the structure that's the structure continued to exploit
we have some factorizations here so now when we are going to compute or marginal
for example when we are with some these functions over x one or x two
and x three compute that some that was exponential
if we didn't have any simplification
actually have apparently
to take advantage of the fact
we have a factorized form
for these objects
in order to compute those things more efficient
and that's the basic of exact inference in
graphical models
sorry for that
and to just flowed through graph to see when
functions the same thing
well we're almost a mincut maxflow thing here the observations supposing you've got a graph
with positive weights with positive weight in which there is no positive flow from fourth
they got a graph is no fly
what what is that name
one zero sum center nodes here and i can get
see on the top one on the bottom
but there are some nodes i can get to from zero
and there are some nodes i can call those b one
i'm not saying get to one there's something get zero call is easier
now that means there's no edge
going across there with positive way
because otherwise i could get from zero through part positive way
the zero
means said
the zero the all the nodes can be reached from zero and it has a
nonzero weight with positive weight and he's the one rank that means there is no
going across here positive way otherwise
can't the definition that node being easier not the one and hence
the sum
of all
the edges which go from the zero to the one
they have zero weight
so the costs of that partition
and since it since has cost zero must be the minimum cost partition because
got positive weights there cannot be a partition of the graph which has less
this way so
my graph
has this property there's no path from zero to one defining the
the best partition is trivial
find the ones you can get from zero and that is the best
partition has zero cost right
so what about
that's the proof so what good is that well
if you want to find the minimum cost partition
you start out the graph
pushing flows
from zero to one
no more
no more is possible
so i i find afloat
which goes from zero to one
by reweight
the graph according to that flow
my previous theorem said that represents the same function
usually one except the constant of flow right
it doesn't matter whether i try to find the minimum partition on the original graph
all the final graph families others will do it on the final graph which trivial
so my algorithm is
bush flow until i can't push and more
then label
according to
as you get different zero
it's easier one
and that will be the minimum value of the original function
so here's an example of this max flow algorithms
taking the taking graph
on the left
which has the a weight
now look at some
the red arrows i can obviously pushed two units there
six two six push
two units afloat
along that that's six comes for
two become zero remember have to
backward graph with a zero
and the a six so now i have a graph
with small weight
so let's try and
find flow in that the right hand one
i that three four what pushed three through that they get
two after finally in the middle
the more complex more ground left across the
with one minute and i get to that graph on the right now you see
graph zero
there's no way i can follow those errors
and get to one
so i cannot
do any more
pushing more
so let's see what the nodes
by following errors which can get i can get two x one from zero to
take the arrow cross there to get to x two
but i can't get out of extreme errors going direction so
my solutions x one x two equals zero and x three one
that is the minimum cost of the function represented by the graph
on the left the same function
on the right in seven months
so here's a summary
all quadratic pseudo boolean functions can be expressed graphs right the function values decrease cost
corresponding partition
show that
four way to pass the the min cut in the graph is equal to the
maximum permissible flow
and you can be parametrized graph reweighted
and the message that f three cents x four is
according to again this rule is the product of the messages that got in times
the function itself summing up all the other variables
so is the product of this message and this message that it got in
times the function
its own function f three which is a function of the variables x two and
x four
and then summing up all the other variables
that is something i x two
so this is the final message that f three cents x four
prove yourself
that if you take this
and you
normalize it to sum to one over the values of x four
that will be the probability distribution over x four
represented by the factor graph
now what about if we observe some evidence
let's say we observed that x one takes on the value a
you know this a
x one is the binary variables a is zero
or something like that
now how does this change those probabilities well
you initialise all messages to be one but then when you observe x one takes
on the value a
then the message that x one sensor f one
a delta function on the value x y equals a
x one is the binary
valuable taking on the value zero and one
instead of sending the vector of all ones the messages
one zero
that's just too
to represent the fact that
x one takes on the value zero
and then everything else
falls through
in exactly the same way but because this is the delta function on x one
taking on the value a
when you
he said the message from f one x two
product of that message has the factor here
is just
the function f one
as a function of x two but with the value x one
set to a
all this falls through and this is what you get is the message after reset
x four and again once normalized this as a function of x four
you will be able to confirm that this is
the probability of x four given x y equals a
so any questions about this
i'm sure this is pretty fast and it's quite hard to follow all of this
but i want to give you if you have encountered this
before i want to give you a sense for the algorithms
we're sending messages on these graphs and how
they can correspond to computing probabilities
on these graphs
any questions
everybody is ready for lunch
all right
so i talked about factor graphs and directed graphs in the abstract
you actually see them all over the place in the machine learning and pattern recognition
in fact a lot of models that are very familiar
two as
like hidden markov models and linear gaussians state space models can be very
nicely represented as
directed graphs are factor graphs so here is the directed graph for
a hidden markov model which is also the same
four state space model common filter model
you have a bunch of hidden state variables and you have a bunch of observations
in your modelling time series of these observations
shaded in these nodes represent the you've observed these guys and these guys are hidden
connection to do so will have on the fact that is a function only on
the bottom of the
now let's suppose that want to compute the matching
the distribution of a
well this is the sum over all of the remaining viable of the joint distribution
now i can write down my factorizations
there the factor graph
and performed the same mission and doing that i realized that we need to perform
to the power of three
some nations that means
number of submission which is this potentially in the number of viable
i have to some of
now though we can think of a bit more clever way of doing that so
if we
look for example
this first that it does not depend on the them means that also the second
term doesn't depend on the them is that we can push
this estimation
here before
after three fact
and similarly for the estimation so i will end up there
i can distribute
push this summation further and i feel if i look
i have to compute here to some of the the one we said despite over
to some plus two something you just something that means that we have two times
three some missions
and that means that the number of mission which is non linear in the
and the number of viable to some
so we we gain something if we get only two in this case but
you can imagine that if you have a big graphs
you can save a lot of computations
well we can see this procedure the kind of message passing
so what
we can define an
this there was some excerpts from the bible the to the valuable c
and on this before from here then
so i i can define
as an aside from the bible it c to the right it would be
and finally this
as the methods
from b to a so
basically what i can do this us
passing messages
from the body will be up
to the reliable eight
now if you think about him to compute the
join this to the margin of c instead
we will have to pass messages in
names in bold direction coming coming from this
so from all the factor that lead to see in this case there are two
the fact that i think this is to pass messages
from the end of messages i can
i can see that
in a similar way
in the more complicated cases in which i have bunching three
the minister for example you factor is a function of three nodes
things get a bit more complicated than i have is not sufficient to define available
to viral messages that has befallen to define the fact that the bible message and
divided would factor measurements
the cl
you define these kind of messages
let's look at the bible to factor such
if a viable here
i want to compute
the most to from the bottom of the
to the fact that as well
in order to do that
i have to multiply
the i
coming the messages from the front door
which are
the link with the body will be so f one vessel into the
two answering to be able to compute the message from one two
the the message from two to be multiply them
and then i can send i o thing the message from b two
is that clear
if i want
two cents
and this that from
fact or to everybody so from that too
i will have to gain
compute the messages from
in this case we want to have
two two
so all the messages
from the all the valuable to define exact
obviously the the masses from the two
more to apply
multiply by then this the that's with a
i i right here
then multiply
these two by
by the fact
and then some over
the two rival here
and you can see that what
we have someone here is exactly the same you can take a look at that
more closely
released in the slide
and if you want to compute the marginal as we said we are two
i just think the
the product of all factor valuable message
for the fact that link to this
now let's give a little bit of an example of inference in hidden markov model
which is a very popular models