log p y given theta log p y given the previous parameter and so if
i subtract these two
you know for any theta and
it's even sure if i make this if i if i
if i insert the new theatre plus one
so i'll have
the distance
i have the difference between these two use these two L's and this is greater
equal to zero because
theta t plus one is something which makes this
i think maximum
right so i've choose this
they t plus one to have
this guy and maximum so this
must be bigger than that
so the difference between the log likelihood
is greater equal to zero
that's the proof that i go always in
in the right direction the the proof follows from simply from convexity arguments not from
differentiation at all so
we can go back to the mixture of gaussians
well i probably have mentioned this before
when i was explaining the mixture of gaussians bit that you can actually write
maximum likelihood
in terms of these responsibilities and their responsibilities if i simply take the responsibilities at
the previous timestep at the previous iterations
then this turns out to be
the EM algorithm update
the running time from
there's an ex
this is how the music the means are estimated but you can also show
that the mixture components are estimated in the following way
take all the responsibilities use on the map over all data points and normalized by
the number of data points so just take all the responsibilities for
component case on them over all data points and then you get the total weight
of that component
as a new value
maybe i'll show
right should
maybe i should make it slower and just go through
through the calculation you want to see for instance
how i would get this
one to that's what we're here for that
we don't skip things but
because i thought it was useful thank you
the details so let's say we take a mixture of two gaussians
the mixture to gaussians
so we have to form now
we have performed
the data and stated he for mixture of gaussians
so this this is we have to take the sum over i can we have
o is the log probability
and we have to take the
if i go back
it's a good question
so the log probability of
why i said this is the observation
we got
OK this is the hidden variable we don't know from which wearable it comes from
which component it comes
and there are the rest of the parameters the parameters the means on the mixture
coefficients so we have to average this
over the responsibility of k
data points
came from k
the previous time step
and then we want to maximize it with respect to the parameters this is the
this is the stuff that we have to to do
so in practice this looks in the following way
so if we have only two components
we get p
of one
given y i
there is a
the log joint probability is minus one half why i minus mu one squared assuming
that we have
p one remember the joint probability
p of y common k
and for given
these p of k
times p y
OK so this system mixture from the probability of the mixture and that is the
that's essentially the gaussians this is one of the risk
two pi e to the minus y
minus mu case square over two
and this is
p one
in the
right i forgot to get all the two pies now for simplicity
we've got
contribution from the second one
why i
minus one half y i
minus two squared
plus log
p two
this is
this is the
now we can optimize it with respect to mu one mu two
but i want to show you how to optimize with respect to p
so if you're interested in
for instance the l by DP one because we're interested in what what is the
update for this mixture coefficients
we get some over i
pt one
given y i so this guy doesn't depend on p one
i get one over p one and i've forgotten something because
p one and p two have to sum up to one so i have to
do a constrained optimization
introducing the grolsch parameter minus
p one class p two
minus one from grass parameter that guarantees to these two things and up to one
so now with the liberals parameter i can do free variation and get
lambda are equal to zero
so that means
that i have no
p one
equal to
the new estimate for p one is equal to
about one over land
the sum over i p t
why i so we only have to find out what land
that is
and if we just
some up p of one
class PS two
three which is c
the advantage that we are avoiding this access
the disadvantage
is that
maybe operation system can cash risks because it has more information about its geometry and
we can catch them to compress
it's again not very good idea because we are using a huge amount of memory
so the access into the all these memories over again not very fast
therefore using u
things that you never see cache of course this in any implementation of search engine
they can cash result
caching results is much much simpler can
do search
and give this result in memory expecting that we do have the same query game
it's very simple
it happens have the results of internet search engine on many pages and browsing
because when we click next page we're doing the same query again and again
the problem with this is that unfortunately people
don't click on the next page
and another disadvantage that
most heavy queries usually don't repeat
because when we have this long query
usually takes a lot of time
user look into this result doing one clique and that's it or
user after this
the query and again it doesn't it doesn't work
we can cash temporary results
that idea how to do this
it is
we can
create some query
that the game has some query language model
and this query analyzer
divides our query software
and we doing this up whereas in separate joint
and also we have some cash
and this
well this multiple times they can look into cash and check if the result of
this square is already in cash
they don't intersect actually posting lists
this simple result is is simply put result from castile
final drawing and to result follow search
i can show you an example of how it works
imagine that the calculated sum although of course arguments of words in color
and we have a very britney spears album
software can
cat from from these
we can
coakley probability of every phrase
using OWL
statistics from previous query i will talk about this very briefly all of his section
of his lecture
so we can
estimate probability and we see that for combination britney spears
the probability is high
this is a good candidate for software that can be cash
because we know the probability that in another query
it will be again reduced is pretty high
therefore we can not intersect forcing these four
three and four what's p
but we can take from all cash registers and intersect only these or other work
and that now
problem but we have a problem here the problem here is that for these temporary
we can do the cancellation
because for britney spears we cannot for this temporary
subsequent query
we can to get only feels thousands of results
because we don't know
so what are all the parts of the square
other parts of this query can change our ranking significant
so strong
that our temporary result is not relevant at all
therefore for this temporary results we need to get a lot of
a lot of course things
and it's disadvantage of this method but it's really implemented in some systems
so we talked about cash
in all that we can improve speed using cash
and now we are coming to the last part of the one i want to
discuss with how we can
a search
in two clusters
the problem
again what is the problem
we have
a number of
computers that are working in parallel
we have a query
and what we want to achieve
we want to parallelize execution of our query
there is no other way
how we can do this
super eight
processing plant of all data
the different box
and then combine result
no other way how how we can implement this
in our search class
it will be two types
two types of bugs
it will be aggregator that can combine results from our processors
and it will be retrieval boxes that
using index
and adjoining parts of this future results
how can we do this
first of of all we need to think about this interface about this means between
we discussed
the same problem yesterday when we talked about index
but for
search in cluster we have a bit different demands
the problem is that we don't want to get
this result
sorry so there are some problems existed therefore
such strange color but
i i think that it consists of services
tempora unlabelled
so it's well-known http response
so i want to avoid this resource
so the user can leave we can again be happier is maybe not perfect
in in some particular cases
but the user differently
doesn't want to see is something like this
o how we can estimate how we can deal our cluster how we can estimate
processing in this cluster such way
but we never see this result
first what we can do is we can not think about our protocols some stream
passing data from one box to another
but it's better to look into our protocol as the number of calls to some
this is a remote
first procedure call
so when we are doing this search we're calling box and getting results don't have
maybe we don't exchange a lot of lots of data because we want to keep
all communication as fast as possible
the second is time are
if we have
some of this
retrieval box
and this was for unknown reason became too small
if i take one vector like this guy
another factor that have come from al adam after world
you see that that i'm going outside
if i just add something from p and something from l
they're not normally what will happen is i'm outside the union
and i don't have a subspace of the correct answer is
is not
OK now let me ask you about
the other thing we do is take the intersection
so what is intersection me
intersection means all vectors
are in
is this assumption
so i guess i want to go back up
the same question this is or is not a subspace
you can answer me
and so the question first before
this particular
example this picture i drew
what what is the intersect alpha this case
it's only there
and he so that this was the artists ideas he growing
that are the line l was not in the plane
and went off somewhere else
and then the only point that was in common with zero but
is the zero vector by itself the subspace
yes absolutely
and what about
if i
if i don't have this plane in this line but any subspace and any other
so now can i ask that question
for any subspace
so maybe our writing
up here
strong enough
so this is the general question i'm subspaces
as in fig
and i want to ask you about their intersection
everything he
and i want
it here
if you see why
you see why if i take the vectors that are in bold won their involvement
the sub base
that's like a smaller set of vectors probably because of
we've added requirements has to be in there and in c
how do i know that some place can we just think through that abstract stuff
and then i get the exact
so why
i suppose i take
a couple of vectors that are in the intersection y
it is the sum
also in the intersection
OK so let me give a name to the factors say BMW
there in the intersection so that means involved in that
it also means are both in t
so what can i say about the plus w
is it in f
if if i take two vectors v and w
that are
it both in and then the sum of because this was the some
and if they're both in t
and i had them
the result is also in t because he was
so the result
the plus w is in the intersection it involved
requirement one is said
requirement to was the same
if i take a vector that symbol
i multiply by seven
seven times that vector is in s because the vector was
seven times of activity because the
original one was in t
so seven times that vector in their effect
in other words
when you take the intersection of two subspaces you get probably have smaller subspace but
it is this
so that's the like sort of
this emphasizing what these two requirements for me
again to be out there
the above the circle of because it's so important that the sum
and the
scalar multiplication which combined
in two
linear combination
that's what you have to do inside the sun
on two
the columns
OK so my lecture last time
started that i want to continue
OK so on space on the main
can i can i think an example
say one two three four
one one one one
two three four five
that's my matrix
so it's got columns
three colours
those columns are vectors so the columns so the column space of a of this
i mean let's say with this example for world
the column space of this matrix is a a subspace of are
are one
so what space so we and if i'm looking at the columns of the matrix
four right these these are vectors in our four
the algorithm
to me that what is interesting because it it's somewhat different algorithms that
that i usually usually see learning theory
so the trick here is that
so we have this input matrix
we have here
m collins and n rows with inputs and we have fixed
we fix
OK and and and you want to find the best rearrangement into blocks of the
rows and columns as stable concreteness consider the minority
a cost function
and the trick going to do here is to take just a random sample
of rows and columns so rather than considering all of the matrix will just consider
a random subset of the rules and around
subset of the columns and only look at the entries of those crossings between these
two runs
so what we do is
we chose
from the columns which is
columns and we choose the walls completely at random i mean
independently and then
if the my
sample of a child is small enough
what i'm going to do is to consider all possible partitionings of the sample
so that's how it become the sample size is going to depend on epsilon on
close i want to be the optimal so
the sample size is a function of epsilon now consider all possible partitioning of this
it's path
matrix that come contains only the entries
the of myself
for these metrics i will consider all possible positions
OK so what they do is they take
a sample of the rows and the columns
the size here is
now i p
it's going to be
much bigger than k
and there
so now i consider all partitionings of those
in two k blocks here and blocks here
which is going to be which is going to take any time
proportional to pay
to the power
so i consider all the possible partitionings of these rows and columns so i get
clusterings of my sample
and then i want to extend it to the clustering of the full matrix
so if i get the clustering of the sample
i also like the other thing is that i only have the sample
so here is my full matrix but i only consider some
small subsample of the matrix
and now i cluster this up some so saying he was the partitioning of they
consider for some
so assume that under some sample the majority here is one and the majority here
is zero and here it's one that's one
now i want to extend it to be clustering back clustering of the full matrix
so what they do is if i have here any columns want to know
in which blocks surely put this
what they do is they take this column the column is always zero one zero
one zero zero one
i can look at this column and say what will be the cost of this
column if i put it here and what will be the cost of this column
if put it here
because i put it here all the zeros here are going to be considered
and because
this is a big one
in the sample
if a point he always it was going to be considered errors
and if you put this column here
the zero in the top part will not be considered as but as it was
in the bottom part because it so i can
calculate the cost of putting my column in
each of the blocks of columns
so i take every i think every column now
and put it greedily into the block that will be
best in terms of cost for this column
that's the way i extend my
partitioning of the sample to the partitioning of the full matrix
and i repeat the same for the rules
so i think it's wrong of and i put it in the in the blog
that minimizes the cost with respect to the labelings of sample
so what i do is a
i think i consider all the partitioning of the sample
for each partitioning of the sample i extended to partitioning of the full matrix now
what i get that we just finished fifth question remains OK now what they get
is at the end i get to go to the timescale times
partitioning of the full
a clustering
the full matrix
for every
partitioning of the sample get the partitioning of the informatics and now for each of
those partitionings of m i calculate its cost
it's true cost
in terms of my minority function and then it choose the one that minimizes the
total cost
i know i can not completely there
on the one hand
only consider the labels of some
i completely ignored the ones that i repeat the same process for everyone regardless of
the order in which the rules
the only thing that will not affect anything here
and now the trick is to claim to the
this is the output so the algorithm that you chosen columns and rows in at
random you consider for each of the possible partitioning so if you look over all
because of all possible partitionings for each of the possible partitioning we extend this partitioning
we compute the minimum cost according to scholar
in each
part and
so we extend we expand this partitioning provisional the full matrix then compute the number
of errors of this partitioning of the full matrix and store this number and in
the end we just take the one with the minimum number
so the main the basic claim here is that it's there
if you consider
the real optimal partitioning
with high probability one of the partitionings of my sample will be a good reflection
of the true
good partitioning a good reflection in the sense that for most of the animals
the estimation of the core supporting the l here will be close to the real
cost supporting this
color in there
true optimal clustering
right most blog
so the main claim is that main statistical claim here is that
by picking a constant size sample sample size depends only on my precision parameters that
from there i can guarantee that when i consider all possible partitionings of the sample
one of them will be
a good approximation a good indication of what the true optimum
clustering is going to do
and therefore when i
add an edge or delete an edge or vertex and edge we can evaluate the
local change in the score very very efficiently
if we want to put some prior
information on the kinds of structures that we expect to see
we can put a probability distribution over the model structures and simply
at the laws probability of that to the score
and the greedy search algorithm is as follows start with some model
consider modifications of that model by
deleting adding or reversing edges and then except these modifications if the score for the
new thing is better than the score for the thing and just repeat that process
we can also use these scores as part of the
mcmc or markov chain monte carlo method on model structure so we can sort of
bump around in the space of model structures and find the posterior distribution over model
structures given the data
the key problem with all of this is
that the space of possible
the graphs is extremely large it grows
super exponentially with the number of variables in our model so any kind of search
in that space is going to be dangerous business
the classical way of
bayesian learning of model structures
when you have
incomplete data
remember what i just talked about was completed
if you have incomplete or hidden
then the classical algorithm for this is
called bayesian structural EM algorithm by near freedman
and it involves the following
the score that we really want to compute is the probability of the data given
the model or or the lot that equivalently
and unfortunately that intractable as i mentioned because the integral over all possible parameters and
the sum over all settings of the hidden variables of this distribution
that's gonna have generally exponentially many terms in it so we can compute that score
and so what the bayesian structurally EM algorithm does is the following
iterates between
the following steps
first it
it starts with its current model structure imagine we have the a car model structure
and runs
and is a little ECM algorithm within that to find the maximum a posteriori parameter
state had for that model
given those parameters state i had it
infer first the distribution over the hidden variables x they can do that by doing
a little bit of belief propagation
or a junction tree for locally connected graph
for a small set of candidate structures these are now modifications from m to n
primes by say doing an edge addition or deletion or reversal of an edge
compute the score of those candidates by evaluating
the expected value under the invaluable distribution that is computed in step two
the lord of the joint probability of the data
and the hidden variables
for that particular model structure
and sometimes this needs a little bit of approximation as well
and then it
picks as a new model
locally the change that had the highest score and then it keeps doing that is
basically doing a greedy search in the space of models by
finding a better structure with this score yet questions
OK it's it's
it's a bit of a misnomer
in that you're doing MAP estimation of the parameters here
you're getting a point estimate that so the question was is in bayesian a bit
of a misnomer for this
you're you're doing a point estimation of the parameters
you certainly need or
the argument was that you need that point is not to be able to run
some sort of belief propagation to infer the hidden variables were
and then use that to to get an approximate score so they're just many levels
of approximation in here
the original motivation was quite bayesian you read the paper
which i reread last night which i got it right you read the papers starts
with a very grand thing
that is trying to do
and then it clobbers it with a lot of approximations so the final algorithm is
not i don't think very satisfying but this is the
standard thing people use for doing structure learning graphs and i think the variational bayesian
stuff will talk about
is a little more elegant than doing this yet another question
yes it's going to be very sensitive to the initial structure that use
so you better have a good job
you do a good job choosing that are being lucky
so if we have the ground the question was if we have the ground truth
for model will this conversion the ground truth
or will it find an approximation
in theory
the question was in practice
i believe i have done it but i believe you can show
that for certain kinds of models
going to be consistent in that it will find the right structure in the limit
enough data
one of the problems with that also is that there might be equivalent structure so
we will find something that's one of the equivalent structures in the limit of an
infinitely much data in practice the space of models is very very large and it's
going to be hard for it to actually find the right structure
i'll show some
examples of that in a few minutes
now with this algorithm but with the variational bayesian algorithm
so too much things and then we can take a bit of the
a bit of a break and then move on to the next lecture
directed graphical models i mentioned in the previous lecture are very
nice ways of representing causal relationships so what happens if you actually try to learn
causal relationships from data and i think this is a very very important area this
is something that people are working on more and more these days
the big and the reason they're working on it is that
causal relationships are really fundamental both two
human cognition
and also to scientific discovery so if you're trying to model
i don't know biological processes
from data
you really are interested in the causal mechanisms
the problem is that
even though the independence relationships
be identical for set of graphs there are very because all differences between putting the
arrow in one direction or the other
it makes sense to say that smoking causes yellow teeth
but certainly
you know you would think that yellow teeth cause smoking
most almost all the money in the money market
account and that's not a good thing so
you really it's really important to do
field tests of light paternalistic policies
five point is the importance of channeling
existing economic interests
there's a lot of economic interests that stand to gain from people make mistakes
credit card companies wanted overspend in fact in some countries from what i understand
they will take an animal
and they will die they what they
like make blood sausage or something like that only the animal almost died
make the blood sausage and then they'll keep the animal life until it does prosperous
will more notable either
so there always and this is the kind of harvesting blood out of an animal
i think that's a really good metaphor for what what for what credit card companies
do to people
they try to bleed us the ones to pay fees and once they just don't
want to go bankrupt they want to just keep us just barely alive
the fast food industry they benefit from us eating and over the chief rapid foods
the industry to the diet industry actually benefits from obesity you might think that i
industry on the side
the consumer but if everyone does then they would be out of business
now banks benefit tremendously from overdrafts
realty mortgage companies that's very produced the slide before the mortgage crisis but was very
timely now
they benefit from people over-extending themselves
hospitals and pharmaceutical companies benefit from people not taking care of themselves
states nowadays in the united states all the states of lotteries which they used to
finance education and stuff like that that benefit people playing the lottery of course casinos
pornographers is that when you start thinking about just pretty horrifying the array of economic
interests that are aligned against
the average person
so i think that the economist
remind me never explained where the economist as therapist
the term came from
somebody asked me the question reminded is probably not the best moment to explain
the economist
there this needs to identify commercial or government interests are aligned with those of the
individual for example
and in the united states health insurance insurers in the veterans administration they have to
pay for people's health care and so
they will benefit people are healthy
i'm not saying health insurers are wonderful companies but in some ways the interests are
aligned with those of the consumer
drug companies i think drug companies have replaced oil companies as
the new major source of evil
in the world
but even drug companies
benefit when people take their drugs and there are some drugs that are beneficial
investment companies
again no one is not enough
populated by wonderful people there are interests are the same as savers but they do
benefit people put money into investment accounts so they generally are some
economic interests in the economy that are aligned with the interests of consumers and
the economist one of the rules of the economist as therapist as i see it
is to align these types of interest
so tell you
ten minutes
this perfect
all of eurasia shuttering this feeling dismayed
i try to try this ten minutes
i would love to have some questions
and to tell you about two
projects that are process and one that sort of in my
and one of them has to do with medicine compliance one of them has to
do with weight loss
and the one that has started but
looking for
the reason talking about is looking for partners to work on this
is the idea of how much savings
so this is the study on
warfarin adherence unexplained organism in its
project with kevin volpp
and stephen kimmel
we're both positions at the university of pennsylvania
and i think it is a good start for illustrating the importance of process
the value of field experiments
and also the alignment commercial and the possibility of aligning commercial and individual interests
so we friends
also known as comandante is an ancestral medication it actually serves another purpose does anybody
know what that is
it's a rat poison was originally rat poison
the way it works is because the rest is we rest bring it back into
the next election
and then it then love and their blood becomes so then they don't die of
internal bleeding
then blood turns out if you don't then too much
it turns out to be really good if you've had stroke are also for some
other things like organ transplants and so one could have been one
some pretty remarkable statistics i i worry
that there might be a slightly exaggerated but it had a stroke in the last
year your chance of having another strokes
twenty one percent
and have a structure of course like heart attack and stroke is not a good
if you take more french correctly
you can reduce that the risk of having struck down to about three percent
and we're friend does have some side effects like the linear here
die a little bit but the side effects and not very bad so we're friends
really wonder drug is also basically free as record
but basically
if you go to a if you look at the situation that best for waterfront
compliance i people you can design we tried to design situation but up until now
the best anyone has been able to achieve in terms of appearance
is sixty six percent if you actually
look at people who are going to a clinic devoted to giving people were from
that's all the does
people at this clinic
they have not been able to achieve higher than sixty six percent a year
which i think is really pretty shocking given the benefits of the drug
i think part of the problem
when you
are at risk for a stroke you just feel normal doesn't feel like risk suddenly
a stroke but before you start to feel totally normal
this is what some refer to this kind of work assignment killer
but it turns out
that for every ten percent increase in missed doses is fourteen percent increase in the
under coagulation which will get that means strong
and there's also
the more irregular you are the more the greater is the rest of over coagulation
so i ran into this guy
four at a meeting
in wisconsin
and he told me that he is interested in using
economic incentives to help people do what's good for that
and i said we need behavioral economics let's try to let's try to combine
this economic incentive based approach with behavioral economics and see if we can improve compliance
a couple of insights that we
incorporated into this into this intervention
the first is it's really important to deliver frequent feedback and rewards
ideally the day also people are taking the work daily one l every day
it's really important to give feedback
you as you as u
iterate you get close to the place you don't wanna be
the simplex methods followed vertices whereas interior point methods
mention these black line
they are
i mean that's space
switch colours
so in the simplex method if we just had a two-dimensional polytope gone
and this is feasible region
if that was the metastatic color
as the primal
simplex methods so it start feasible
and arrange
you know we might start out here with the optimal solutions over here
the simplex method
iterates like
from here
here and then declare yourself of the
end in two dimensions that doesn't seem bad but
in high dimensions
the word on the street is that you know there's lots and edges to get
around the polytope and
you can take a while
whereas in interior point methods if we started feasible anyway
starts like this
well maybe can start exactly and all that to good
you start somewhere like this
and more less points in the right direction
it exists we actually take a step back ninety percent of the way to
until something gets violated which should be that's there are
and then you
take a step goes ninety percent which is something gets violated
he goes in like that's
so in this little two-dimensional problem the simplex methodology three defense and interior point methods
it will take more than three hundred so the simplex method looks
more compelling but but the two-dimensional pictures deceptive
in reality is i think i convinced you the other day the simplex method takes
and plus mover to pivots are something like that so in a manner large
the simplex method takes lots of pivots
whereas the interior point methods extraordinarily robust it takes
twenty iterations
i mean depends i is that europe's tolerances and when you wanna stop but with
reasonable tolerances in double precision arithmetic
on modern computers
it takes
roughly twenty iterations and of course some problems are harder and some problems are easier started guarantee
and by the way that's that's a practical statement from from real experience these complexity bound is that it takes
o squared end
which doesn't grow within
but in practice it stays basically constant with an
and so
the simplex methods might take several thousand with this might take just twenty these
the work per iteration
to do this is this is inverting a system of
of equations
this is a and b i am
system of equations here
there you have to invert
in order to solve a system involving it
and that's more work than one that the simplex methods one pivot
is like
just part of the girls in elimination step we do any those calcination steps to
to solve a system of equations are vernon biometrics so
so a pivot is a much smaller operation then matrix inversion
are matrix solving a system of equations
and so even though it takes very few iterations is that deceptive because
there are expensive iterations to do
i hope
was that's
parallel computing would come to the rescue here
the simplex methods is sort of inherently sequential i can
go from here to here until i know that i got here to start with
so simplex methods
inherently sequential
well of course digital media is also inherently sequential which inherently sequential forward twenty rather than having several times
and if i could make it to these things a lot faster
then than i could do this quickly whereas what's going on the pivot is a smaller
amount of work to start with and so there is less opportunity to take the
the paralyzed that's
modern computers
but this proved to be rather difficult because
you're trying to
do this quickly
in parallel
computing were is a sparse matrix
x diagonal matrices
y transpose is the transpose survey
reasons about the capabilities needed to accomplish those higher level task and then figures out
how to appease those things together on the fly to get things done
sorry i have to skip over details but i just want to mention his three
other kinds of applications there is a lot of work into software interoperability surprising that
i've been involved in as or i
we use l
and derivatives of hours to reason about how systems existing systems can be glued together
for a particular purpose we have we have descriptions on the left of
tasks that need to be fulfilled is like a training event and those are described
in terms of processes that express analysis like formalism and in terms of the capabilities
that are needed for the different subtasks
and the other side descriptions of resources in terms of their capabilities and as an
analytic component can automatically identify different combinations of existing systems that can be used to
successfully together to carry out these tasks
is fair amount of work work over that will work in my opinion and there
is science this this is courtesy of carol goble
we're not has migrated from a few years ago i think the thing to emphasise
here is the support for reproducibility in in terms of scientific procedures workflow
picture the right here which biological scientists can set up in know experimental routine which
is going to be reproduced possibly many times in many different datasets and managed services
notations have been used to help manage to reproduce this procedures reliably over and over
a number of different grounds
and finally the last example are one dimension is similar services technology analysis in particular
can be used via reasoning infrastructure for autonomous vehicles so
this is for
this kind of work i think what's important is the ability to describe the
defectors and the sensors and autonomous vehicle has with the terms of science environment affecting
environment they can be very naturally described it as web services and then using similar
service descriptions you can put together reasoning capability allows that provide the infrastructure for the
autonomous vehicle to interact with the environment and also has infrastructure for simulation and planning
which can be done offline or can be done before
the the vehicle actually needs to commit itself to a particular activity so
that's the end of
section back to you know what you think just maybe to running high here is
o thing
as you know my glasses
right so one thing you get for free in this presentation is you see
david myself comparing two ontologies
so an ontology is a formal description of some domain any we have two high-level
ontologies for somewhat the same domain web services
i'm going to talk about the web services modelling ontology which mainly came out of
some european project starting in two thousand four
in correspondence to the high-level diagram david showed we have
four elements
that's used to describe a web services based on ontology
that's obvious to to this audience then if you remember we had two different roles
we have the role of the client and the role of the provide
we represent
ontologically the client as separate ontology
to the ontology that we use to describe the web service so we describe the
clients will have when they vocal web service
and that's called the gulf
so we ontologically decoupling
the viewpoint of the requests and if you viewpoint to provide
derived from previous research on problem solving methods and task descriptions and the basic idea
is that in many circumstances and situations you can structure
and organize request made for web services so for example in some knowledge intensive domains
so if you're searching
to something if you want to diagnose
a problem with the calf you want to diagnose what illness the patient may have
the wait structure those
can be read in vertical domains such as booking a holiday
and i showed you a slide earlier
so some of the most the booker holidays normally going to talk in terms such
as the
number of children they have the price range and you constructed into some goal description
and organised in the library and reused across application within was most
the request i don't have to be satisfiable
so for example to take an extreme case i may have the desired i want
england to qualify for the next world cup
in south africa and of course there's no web service that will guarantee that for
me but i contend that designed and maybe other similar services
related to
booking trips
in the relevant year to learn watching games on TV et cetera
and then we use ontological relationships and mediators which escalated to link to
the goals
from the client to the descriptions of the web services which are provided
OK if i move over to the description of web service somewhat similar to OWL
s we distinguish between the functionality
of the web service and the how you actually invoking
richard turn the capability in interface
so this is a pictorial representation
although with no representation of the web service description
we have functional properties
again similar to alice we have dublin core
properties to do with the quality of service versioning information
financial information in with moses on on not hardwired
so if you have extra nonfunctional properties you can add
we had the capability description
the the functionality of the service which is used basically for advertising
and discovery so some discovery engine will match
the goals of some clients
two the capability descriptions of web services
and in terms of the web service description and differing
slightly from this we distinguish between the choreography in the orchestration the choreography describes how
to the relationship between the single climbed the single web service
so what are the messages that could be sent between the two
do i need to send my credit card details before eyebrows do i need to
log in et cetera
and what their constraints between those so this is really a description of the external
of the web servers and the
the requirements of the invoker can be matched against the
on the other hand for certain types of functionality a single web service may not
be somehow powerful enough so you want to compose
web services together to provide the desired functionality and this is called the orchestration
so this is a control flow data and control flow over a set of web
services to provide a single functionality
to give you a pictorial flavourful can happen so here's a web service for booking
the virtual trip
so we have a web service looking at trip and there are four components in
the orchestration description which are goals
condition is equal to distraction
this is equal to this
now if you write about this problem
the factors and everything cancels
it's called telescoping
because if you you then on the diagonal these things start cancelling and this is
the only thing that remains
so this means that the sum of the losses if you use bayes for sequential
prediction is actually equal to the code length you get
for the whole sequence is encoded using the beijing called
so now
and ideas
which goes back to nineteen eighty four
due to fill davies and amazon
is that if you look at what is based on predictive distribution
you see that for large n it resembles more and more the maximum likelihood distribution
for example if you use a uniform prior to the bernoulli model
and the maximum likelihood distribution given
let's say s ones
in a sample of as divided by
maximum likelihood would be this
number of ones divided by the total number of outcomes
in the bayesian predictive distribution would be less plus one divided by plus
the so also called the class estimate
so it's almost the same
this conditional distribution is restricted to look like
the maximum likelihood distribution given the past so this suggests that you can actually approximates
this patient distribution by this distribution
or actually by any other reasonable estimator doesn't have to be the maximum likelihood estimator
it turns out that you can do this
in general there are some slight confusion here which i'll skip
you can
if you use the maximum likelihood at each point
new sequence to predict the future at all the losses
the total
lost you get
is equal to the best predictions you could have made with hindsight so with hindsight
after using all the data
given your model then you should have predicted with theta had all the time
it would have given you the smallest
the largest of the probability for the smallest total loss
but instead used always makes like estimator based on the past because she didn't see
the future
and the overall to get by not knowing the future is k over to logan
plus order one so this means that the central term
which doesn't depend
which depends on and still k over two log n
we're case the number of parameters this means
you can use this sequential maximum likelihood scheme
also as a universal code and you can try to do model selection based on
sequential prediction strategy
another way to view this is that if you do MDL it's something like selecting
the model
which is the smallest accumulated log prediction error if you
the model to sequentially predict the future given the past
this most of the season
this actually does not hold for all data sequences
so i've been a bit sloppy this holds it depends on what models you're using
but in general this this is a weaker statement holds an expectation if one of
the distribution your models
it's true
the number of parameters
well with the set so did this of course is theta had tested something to
do with the distributions
so if you have a large sets
k is larger than of course you will get it if you have different things
will happen you will overfit more
so the number of parameters
it's not so important for the complexity when the sample size is small
but if you fix the number of parameters that the sample size go to infinity
then it becomes dominant
in determining how many extra bits units compared to the best
distribution in your model to encode the data
so noted this view
the MDL procedure is very similar to cross validation leave one out cross validation with
one essential difference
and leave one out cross validation use the whole sample except one point to predict
that one point
you do that for all points
and you at the total loss you make and then you pick them up with
the smallest total loss
he also predict all points but
at each time you only
base your prediction
on the past data and not all of the data
interestingly you see that asymptotically
leave one out cross validation
works like AIC it tends to select more complex models
then the MDL are base
where's prequential validation we don't use the future you only use the past make predictions
well we've already seen that it's like MDL so not surprisingly behaves like BIC
so the final important thing is that in practice of course we want to compare
of an infinite number of models
if you do that you can not just
take the model
maximizing this probability or minimizing minus log of this probability and so this is basically
the final really crucial point no
very important
what we want
it is we want to cast
learning in terms of data compression
so the way we do this in any are always we start by designing a
quote which we can use to encode all data sequences
and then based on that code to make inferences
if our goal is not model selection but just predictions
now let's contrast that with what happens in the second movement of beethoven's fifth symphony
where we have a lyrical long flowing
seem OK
OK i will stop
so that went on if we heard the whole thing actually goes on for thirty
two nodes as opposed to four so motive versus longer
seems ten maybe a little bit more we work
now let's go on to the third we said that there was dance derived but
in this case would be of and it's very strange dance if it is danced
arrives just a little bit different than most of these third movement but let's listen
to it anyway
because i'd like you to when the branches come in think about what you're hearing
and think about that these are the the first solitude the third movement now
OK so what happened there when the presses came in
how did that relate to the first
four of something as simple as that that d the
tttt same rhythmic ideas so that use of the motives there and that's how these
movements are tied together a little bit let's go on to the finale as we
listen to the finale let's think about what we heard at the very beginning and
talked about last time the the
but the mood at the beginning of
created what we had these adjectives appear negative anxious unsettled how do we feel now
about the finality
this just environmental because we go down so
why do we feel differently about that i think we do
what we feel that while sort of upbeat positive
what's turned all of this around
but specific
well with the first moment we said is generally going
that kind of idea but now it's
and will explore this we get the harmony this idea of major and minor so
you have an
that's the change from the dark minor to the brighter major we we're going down
the the first moment now we want
going up and instead of having just the violins playing we have the trumpet the
heroic trumpet so it sounds very triumph
very triumphant so in this forty minute interval we've gone sort through an emotional musical
journey from despair despondency uncertainty to whatever to personal trial and in a way that
mirrors some of the things that were going on in beethoven's like
OK let's go on to talk about the second piece we finished with this idea
the genre of the four movement symphony is going to talk about the piano concerto
concertos are generally in three movements of the concerto is another genre
it's a genre in which a soloist will confront the orchestra no be kind of
give and take
spirited give-and-take between the two
so now we are going to listen to the beginning of the first movement took
course his piano concerto
you work with this already see you're little bit familiar with it and at the
outset here i have two questions for you
it is the beginning here played
played by
brass is are the strings in other words what are the woodwinds what family of
instruments playing here and is czochralski using a motive or is he using a theme
at the very beginning of this concerto
let's that again listeners that again so we can hear the in the beginning
so what about that being or motive at the beginning
motor right so here it was i think
how many nodes in our motives
same as in the base of y is in the same well we get a
skip a debate of an hour
here which took cos he's coming down the straight down and you
down consecutive intervals are for the most part
and both of them are however minor
with the tchaikovsky they all the the intervals are the durations of the same
he pop pop pop pop up but with the with the bait of d d
d d
short short short one so cost is a little more neutral in terms of the
river OK so then we go on and the piano and here's what is the
kind doing so let's hear the piano coming just play a bit more
that's not here so what's the piano until well the piano is just playing chords
playing them
in octave succession and we'll talk about that a little bit more to
so what we have here in the next section do we have seen or do
we have a motive and which do this are the violins play are they
and if they had theme or the motives what's the piano had seen them all
let's listen
OK let's let's stop it there so all was what the what where the violence
a very galling race rememba eighteen minutes i think it takes an average to roll
this very long course
of upstream against the river
what's important about this is how long these guys keep their rules synchronized that's determines whether you win or not
in this but if you can see this is the two thousand seven boat race oxford lost
by quite a bit they had this photograph is taken
only about a quarter of the way we
course they have already lost that's left hand or there is flat
yeah that was
are right angles to the water
the person at front is already at time of synchrony with other guys
that's absolutely screws screws them can be used massive
so what we did
because the important thing and here we have them in the training sessions only rowing machines
measured in the usual way
the change in
endorphin production
from the pain threshold he considered it twice forrest
you can see it's nice uplift that you get from just the physical activity
and then we got them to repeat this in virtual but so birds
we bring machines are linked up
five computers they're rowing in synchrony now
what you get
is a hundred percent increase endorphin production purely a consequence a single has nothing
to do with how because we know there rowing at exactly the same our
on all four occasions we have set their power
right at the beginning
and we told them to rotate them and their professionals they can do it
and we can check whether they're doing it or not on the computer rapidly on the top
other machine there
which records the power output it's exactly the same way across
but every time the raising they get this added up says something about doing stuff together
and in synchrony
not necessary in perfect sync things i mean tango
where the couple are doing it completely solve opposites as it well but they're highly
synchronized their behavior they're getting the same search
given all at
and that's the way things
if you like on relationships and naturally built on networks and naturally service
i think we have a problem that was becoming more global
is becoming increasingly urbanized that's a big problem both of those have very serious negative effects for social cohesion
and force-sensitive engagement and in the political and social
well this so the problem is
the problem for you guys
i'm too old
doing about it
the problem for the future i think we gotta work on fast is how to cut through
these constraints
in order to increase one on its use a concrete example how to present that
prevent e u finally falling apart
since it's the process that being said
and it's a serious problem and i think the only way we can solve the
problem is digitally through the digital world but at the moment the digital world is
if you like not doing it
the question is for
to grapple with i think
is both to understand the world we come from and how it works and then
to see what the real opportunities are
in order to increase the sense greater
social cohesion in these very large
political and social communities like e or even the whole planet
having forced a living now and into the future thank you very much
so just what the social cohesion parcel of
social networks are so that i can see is kind of a social network based around
keeping track of exercise of most of what people are necessary in order to do
that because you get endorphins from
exercise exercising
so but not actually
this is an interesting question i've talked some guys microsoft
you know this we box
and on the right
you know if you can do that now with somebody in
i don't know siberia meeting ever seen in your life the fact you're doing something with them
in principle might kick the mechanism and we don't know what i mean is very plausible
hypothesis so
you know i'm not the problem is we don't have time
to play virtual tennis
against s
whatever it is six billion people every day
if there are there are gonna be kind and if you like to a network
constraints that are built into the system but
you know that's the kind of maybe that's the kind direction to go here
thank you
thanks of course for the presentation
one point concerning the title of your presentation so far you facebook will not get us any more the
and can see also some aspects which are mobility related to technology and not just to sociology
such as for instance the type of social network in the sense facebook is a
closed system which is based on difference
and as you say
difference model is stable and constant
well what about a social network which is that this model based on a community of you know this
would such an option models that allow us to a so all the mother
relationships which are probably different from the traditional french
this and we have actually already solved this problem to some extent in the course of human history
because we know that a hundred and fifty years this is the the classic hunter-gatherer community size
very self-contained is exactly what you see in the villages
you know all around the world in the remoter parts and the
you know sort of the highlands and islands scotland for example in in the third world
you know it and everybody is friends is everybody's hundred fifties everybody else and fifteen it's very self-contained
but in the course to finish since the neolithic ten thousand years ago
when we invented villages and stuff so we start to get bigger and bigger political units we have these
same social cohesion problems problem-solving grappling with no we found some solutions to that
because he managed the question is how well they work the best
model and that's actually the military the military public follow these numbers perfectly
right the way through and beyond fifteen hundred they go you know you can still
see the rule three going up right the way up to division level over fifteen
thousand men or something
but they do it by discipline
and imposing
enforce discipline never that's fine on the battlefield was are released on traditional battlefields that's
why it doesn't seem to be terribly well and
everyday life but what are the ways we seem to solve the problem quite effectively is having these
so the position vector has no length so clear
that is zero
one is the angular momentum
at time t one the object is here
well that angular momentum
it's clearly not zero
because you see here
position vector and you see the velocity so clearly angular momentum
was changing
now you will see of course it was changing big deal
because and you momentum has a velocity vector in
and here the velocity vector is changing all the time
so obviously you would say
the angular momentum
yes that is not a bad argument
but i will now show you case
where the velocity is changing all the time
the angular momentum is not changed
i choose
you're going around the sun
the earth
at point c here is the sun
this is the position vector are
of c
and the earth has a certain tangential
and the speed
never changes but the velocity does change
so this is the position vector
at a later point in time
what now is the angular momentum of the earth going around the sun
relative to point c i pick scene
well that angular momentum
if i take the magnitude of the angular momentum
because the direction is immediately obvious if the object is going around like this this
is the position vector
direction will be pointing out of the blackboard that's easy
so i'm really worried now about the
the magnitude so the magnitude is the
mass of the earth
times the magnitude
of the cross product
between these two vectors
and notice the angle is ninety degrees
so i can forget about across the sign of theta is
so i simply get
we now being
the speed
this is the case when the object is here but very objective here the situation
has not changed again
our crosby
the magnitude is exactly the same because the sine of the angle hasn't changed
so you see here case by the velocity is changing all the time
which angular momentum relative to point c is not changed
suppose i had chosen point q
is a norm and
the changing relative to point q you better believe it
there is the time that the object will go through point q
but the omentum is clearly zero because the position vector is zero
if the object is here you take to implement relative to point q for sure
you meant is not zero
you have a position vector and you have the velocity
so only
relative to point c
very special case now
is angular momentum not change so angular momentum
is conserved in this special case but only about
one c
now i want to address that
a little bit more general way
i take the angular momentum
and i choose a point q
and i know the definition is the position vector
relative to point q
i think the derivatives
time derivatives
relative to that point q is always important to state which point you've chosen
relative to which you take any woman
that is going to be
the or
the team
trust me
of q
this is the way
did you take the
time derivative of the cross product
we calculate the angular momentum
relative to point q
so the index
has to be q throughout the equation
position vector
relative to point q
and this equation
you see the correct index q you see correct index q here
but i slipped up here and i put to sea there
there is no see in this problem
so this is also
of q
sorry for that
this year
is the velocity of the object
the velocity vector which is always in the same direction as the
so this is zero
dp two
that is the force on the object we've seen that before
eight one
so now we have that
the only two
that if two
a point q
the position vector are
from that point
cross process
and this now
it is what we call
and we write for that the symbol tall
this vector
and i put in that
q again
this is one of the most important equations
that will stay with us
four at least
five lectures what is is telling you is that
if there is a toric
on an object
the angular momentum must be changing in time
if there is no to work on the object and you know momentum
will be conserved and now
you get some insight into this situation
that we just discussed
the forest
the attractive force
gravitational force
exerted on the earth
it is in this direction
position vector is in this direction
so cross as is zero
there is no talk relative to this point c
the angle between the two vectors is hundred eighty degrees and so to sign of
the angle is zero
linear us
christopher edling worked with us on the number of sexual partners and again everybody thinks
that we have a few don giovanni is out here
at this one don money because the opera
and there is a sort of the rest of us
somewhere in this region for the number of sexual partners and this is our experience
and of course we could nobody could believe this scale free
or perhaps more familiar examples are the ones you've heard this meeting which i will
try to repeat
but the most striking example only for us in the most relevant example earthquakes
because again experience teaches us there are no earthquakes
except big ones like well everyone knows about positano
we know about the
but but they are not believe about twenty years ago
there is another big what we all know the big ones but we don't we
don't know anything else but we know there little rumblings and but the concept there's
one single line that describes the histogram of earthquakes is surprising concept but it's true
and it tells us in earthquakes the same thing that tells us in stock prices
the mechanism of big earthquakes is quite possibly the same mechanism of little earthquakes so
we can study the little ones of which there are many many more orders of
magnitude more tend to be more in this case
if we want to understand the the big events
many reasons not to believe this yes this is very important excuse me
you see
why would the person be skeptical of this first of all i will say that
the log log plot everything history
and second of all the significant deviations of the negative fail after about twenty or
thirty standard deviation
and thirdly the deviations of everything below about half a standard deviation and fourthly the
data are not exactly on this line you see the fluctuates you've inferred if you're
a good artists who could draw
you can fit an elephant the joke you can draw a sexy curves goes up
and down and up and so that's one reason not to believe but the other
reason is you through all the data together you can make you know you can
and make horses and cockroaches and find something in common and that's what this is
in excess horses and cockroaches so with a little bit of effort more
we analyse individual stocks there are thousands of them
and for each stock be the same log more plot and calculated the same slow
exponent alpha
expecting hoping to get everything very close to three and indeed they are very close
to three because of finite size effects we don't expect to be exactly three and
almost all the data within about
about twenty percent of three between two point four and three point six
some companies and firms for reasons that we don't particularly understand that are there are
significant difference
so i'm doing this sort of falling off the of the chair
we look at other quantities you see in critical phenomena people started by studying a
requirement is huge singularities like susceptibility
and then later dealt with specific and things that are much more delicate
so one thing which are little more delicate is the volatility
the volatility also is a histogram this time it's the PDF and already economies knew
full well that this is a lognormal distribution lognormal this graph paper or paper is
a problem because the log of the domain is x squared is ninety six squared
and here is the problem that everyone knew
however because we had all these data twenty million data we can look for rare
events volatility and these appear to fall is not very convincing is less than one
decade but whatever it is is that this problem i didn't draw probably coming down
but it would have come down roughly where my pointers
and the data are vastly different than that
and then we did another thing which is what the critical phenomena as we do
is they were if the economy is like a critical point there should be long
long-range power law correlations
because that's what makes critical points special
fluctuations are correlated inequality over large distances and large times
and it's
the essence of critical phenomena but when you look at start prices you look at
say the autocorrelation function which means that if the price
today is one in some units what's price a certain number of minutes later you
find not to power law at all but exponential decay and that's because this graph
has log on the y axis
and linear on the x axis so when the data are approximately straight that means
the function is decaying exponentially
and this exponential decay is the characteristic decay time of only four minutes which is
very short
so this is anything but long range correlation on the hand something which is long
range correlation is the volatility we're volatility is defined as the absolute value of the
return not to return itself
the volatility is long-range correlated roughly over more than two decades
as you see from these data with this slope of roughly minus point three
and this fact was not know economists
if the volatility is long-range correlated over notice over almost one hundred days for a
long time
when think this if you open the newspaper today
today's prices have anything to do with the price is a hundred days ago
but the data say otherwise
you have to accept data sets often and
and so the volatility is correlated which means that the prices themselves to make the
this cannot be independent they simply cannot be serially independent again contrary to our central
magnetic dipoles
and it induces
magnetic dipoles at the atomic scale
now in case that the
atoms or molecules
i have a
magnetic dipole moments
then these external field will make an attempt to align these dipoles
and the degree of success depends on the strength of the external field
and again on the temperature the lower the temperature easier this
to align the
so the material
modifies the external field these external field today i will often call it the a
vacuum field
so when you bring material into a vacuum field the field changes
the field inside is different from the
external field from the vacuum fields
i first want to remind you
our definition of a magnetic dipole moment
it's actually very simple how it is defined
if i have the current
a lot could be rectangle doesn't have to be a circle
and if the current is running in the z direction
seen from below clockwise
and in this area is a
that the magnetic dipole moment
simply the current
times the area
but we define a according to the the defector a according to the right-hand corkscrew
if i come from the local clockwise
the factor a perpendicular to the surface and is then pointing upwards and so the
magnetic dipole moment which we normally write new
is then also pointing upward
so this is a
factor eight which is is normal
according to the right-hand corkscrew and if i have enough of these loops
then the magnetic dipole moment will be and times larger than they will
support each other if they all in the same
i first want to discuss with you
dia magnetism
all materials
when you expose them to an external magnetic field
real to some degree
that external field
and they will generate on an atomic scale
EMF which is opposing
the external field
now you will say yes of course
it has nothing to do with lens law
it has nothing to do with the free electrons in conductors
which produced in any current when there is a change in magnetic field i'm not
talking about changing magnetic field i'm talking about a permanent magnetic fields
so when i apply a permanent magnetic field
in all materials
the magnetic dipole moment is induced to oppose that view
and there's no way that we can understand that was a little too
can only be understood
was quantum mechanics so we make no attempt to that really accept it
and so the
magnetic field insights
the material is always a little bit smaller than
then the external field
the dipoles will oppose the external field
now i'll talk about ferromagnetism
there are many substances by the atoms and molecules themselves
i have a magnetic dipole moment
thirty atoms themselves the molecules you can think of them as being little magnets
if you have no
external field no vacuum field
then these dipoles are completely chaotically oriented and so the net
the magnetic field is zero
so it not permanent magnets
but the moment expose them to an externally
magnetic field
this magnetic field will try to align
and the degree of success depends on the strength of that field
and on the temperature the lower the temperature easier it is
so if you had a magnetic field
they like so
if you really feel you vacuum fields
you bring in there
paramagnetic materials
then there is the tendency
for the north pole
the go little bit in this direction
these atomic magnets then
would on average try to get the north pole of a bit in this direction
if i speak the language of
the magnetic dipole moments than the magnetic dipole
will try to go a little bit in this direction
if you remove the external field of paramagnetic material immediately there is complete total chaos
but there's no permanent magnetism left
if you bring
paramagnetic materials
in a non
magnetic field
it will be pulled towards the strong side of the field
and it's very easy to
to see how that works
suppose i have a magnet here
and that this discrete north pole of the magnet and is the south pole
and so the magnetic fields
it's sort of like so
notice right here it's very non uniform
and i bring some paramagnetic material in there
let's say i think of it as well and in there
not to scale them going to draw
and here
is that one of them
and this one and now
has its own
magnetic dipole moment
and this magnetic dipole moment i would like to align
in this direction
support to field field is trying to push it in that direction that suppose is
so if we look from above
the current then in this animal in this molecule
is running in this direction
seen from above clockwise
but that would be ideal alignment of this
and orders is molecule in that external fields
this current loop
will be attracted we want to go towards the magnet
let's look at this point here
that point the current
it's going in the blackboard
here is that current i
and the magnetic field is like so the external magnetic field is like so
so one direction is the lawrence forces or the direction i crosby
and i crosby
i crosby
it is in this direction
that's the action of the lorentz force
so right here
it is the force on the loop in this direction
therefore right here
it is the force on the move in this direction and the current
so everywhere around the world
there is a force that is pointing like this
and sort of clearly is the net force up
so it is matter wants to go
a priori the prior distribution for the parameters gaussians
then this will also state was
and this is very restrictive because in most situations we would assume that this distribution
can be
very strange piece we don't know what the distribution of the parameters in the hospital
is and this is what this quantity should be representing this is a little graphical
what's going on so we started maybe with an uninformed prior as this sort of
indicating thousand distribution as uniform distribution without any specific direction so this indicates that maybe
the variance of the standard deviation of
if we then obtain data for this one situation we will for the first
it's more focused posterior distribution and eventually the parameters for this particular model converges to
something like the point distribution
if you get more and more data
the parameters converge to play
now but now if repeat this for many different hospitals and we we can observe
than point estimates for these different hospitals
so if you have a lot of data for each hospital and if are lucky
the will also because in distribution and by just adopting the
the hyperparameters of the skulls from the centre of the covariance matrix we might be
able to fit this reasonably well
but in other situations and probably more than on the case this distribution will be
very odd shaped like maybe this banana shaped over here which cannot be fitted any
standard distribution of costs and whatever you want to implement as the prior belief
and this is the problem in hierarchical bayesian modeling sort of limited and why we
sort of need very flexible model for this kind describing our
the prior distribution
so we cannot we should be very careful when using a very stiff assumption about
prior distribution this might be perfectly okay for specifying our prior belief about the parameters
you don't know much up really so we say it means zero some from the
variance over here but we also have to require that this parameterisation can also represent
the learned prior distribution and this is very unlikely to use the parameter distribution
and this is the reason why are we going to have nonparametric distributions
and so this is the the key idea why this usually model was so important
is that
gives us a means to sort of say OK maybe i want to approximate my
prior belief by something more complicated and this it should be done in a way
that a priori it should so i think of my my uninformative prior belief but
later on it should also have the flexibility to
to implement a very complex distributions
and the into it is that is not exactly how it is done by the
included that is to say OK if i have five assume constant distribution is my
prior belief but to this graphical representation over here so this was my uninformed prior
belief about the parameter theta i sort of approximated by a lot of
the last of but finite number of of fixed to value so i don't allow
the whole continuous range anymore i just determine if a very large number of a
large enough that and here is that it's exactly here and here
and if i'm lucky this is not very important and this just to to to
get the idea of this of course not the way to spend in practice but
let's assume that i for example if i sample this sentence from this distribution and
then sort of turn this into a multinomial model with additional prior
i sort of approximate one is two through fully my prior belief in the distribution
of factors
and of course what i can do now is to to learn sort of the
g function which is essentially the amplitudes on these little peaks over here
so this is again doesn't make too much sense because we are talking about a
finite representation and you would need huge number of these peaks due to be a
very good results but this sort of the principle what is going on we replace
an uninformative prior distribution by something which has high degree of flexibility
you can think of it another way of thinking this you do you sort of
split up the private space into little boxes and specify a discrete probability to to
land in any of those boxes and in this way we approximate something like this
in terms of some steps and then also the learn posterior in terms of the
first step stepwise approximation
this enhances greatly the flexibility in your model so certainly we pick a large amount
of data to for example by sampling from the from the prior distribution one from
private distribution and then we like sort of this g
terms over here we we apply it usually distribution priors on the cheese and we
end up with essentially the model we have discussed in the last section
it's good to go
it is also may be no coincidence that i use this particular notation that the
results of the
to assess workload that and not something else because they're really now the parameters in
different parametric model
and this is the gene also sick exactly that you before it was the hyperparameters
and the non informative prior distribution hours specifying the probabilities of this multinomial distribution for
the for the factors over here
so this is sort of conceptual
step one has to make from this simple model of certain dyes estimating probabilities in
this situation to generalizing it to very general situation because now as i said before
these figures are some parameters in some
models i haven't specified that there could be linear models that could be nonlinear model
to continue network that could be
so what does this tell us this tells us that
shattering coefficient does not grow exponentially
the ball becomes nontrivial in the sense that
it and goes to infinity
this thing is zero
this doesn't work
so i think zero
because what is called be sealed by challenges inequality
or sometimes called tail
it makes a statement about probabilities or something means in the
tail of the distribution of something being wrong
basically uh can on the probability of the data distribution
and just to remind you in
this kind of the two types of randomness
what is this
which is
the probability of drawing
the the training examples
uh with this property
and the second one is
at this one
numerous itself also expectation
something something probabilistic is occasionally on test examples
so this expectation with respect to the underlying
joint probability measure between x and why
and this is the probability
with respect to the program measuring
provision which is constructed from the same underlying
no product with itself
in the two times
okay so this is
the basic idea
and you can then
if you want you can
right is found in a different form
you can specify
the probability with which
you want are there's that has to be close to the training error
and so what style
he said that is equal to delta
so for epsilon then you get
something like this
with high probability of promiscuity is one minus the
been arbitrarily small number
you have an upper
on the
test error
which is the sum on this
addition this confidence to
the training error on the test error can be
the training error
this is the
before that you would normally see of uniform convergence bounds
in machine learning
we have a something that depends on the machine
on the machine and the problem and distribution
end you along the test error and it's
this bound is independent we have made assumptions about
which function if we have this was just the supremum over all functions in our learning machine
it's not just through full
four function that minimum training error is true all functions
there are other modifications such as the more specific but this one is that is one
throw function so in particular for a while minimizing the empirical risk
this is just a
function that tells us
how different training errors people from test errors if we pick some function that can
be implemented by the learning machine
so it's
the simplest but want
people have born with the constants and so on
people have also use or absolute capacity concepts
maybe we should also say uh you can't simply say
we know that minimizes
by over it
because because
the basic idea with the
what is happening is
rather than just minimizing the training error
we want to minimize something more complicated so in the end we have a small
test are because although it was used as the test error
you can't do that directly here because
although this quantity here
is a property
and all this is the training error and is a property of the function that using
this property it depends on the whole function class so you cannot
influence this just by choosing a different function you can infer that by choosing a different function class
japanese have suggested methods do this which was structural risk minimization
which all underlies a lot of learning algorithms that
try to approximate to do something like that
so i've shown you
only this shattering coefficient but i want to show you a few more capacity concepts
from learning theory and the
i don't expect you to understand all this
and don't i only want to talk about this today
you're going to have another lecture on statistical learning theory in the same way
by government policy
in much more detail
maybe it would be good to hear some of these things twice although they would
probably some quite different when he
it talks about the more advanced material
but basically
the reason why i always like to include this material is that
i think it's good if you've seen it once if you were a machine learning
approach in a new species mentioned but it's good to see it
now if you've seen was the basic idea maybe remember exactly how to derive it but
you know what's behind it into the scale of it when you see it somewhere
else you know that in principle i could i could look it up and understand
and therefore i want to
also show you
concept so you've seen
although at some point
on each example
we had this very excited tells us what's the loss
of the function f
example x line
and it was simply zero one loss function is one of only two variables
and if we now have a larger sample
in pounds
and we look at different functions from the machine
we can get whole
set of loss vectors
and then went back
for each
observation one entry
and for each function we get was someone such that all
and can ask the question
how is this
the syllable and so we choose readings from various sources and the text that i've
chosen is the best of a bad loss
OK it at least overlaps to a greater extent than most of the other books
using the text + these archive notes I think you'd be able to piece together
what you need and you know there's a 3rd alternative I don't know if you
know this may be on the campus tour the kept away from this part of
the campus but if you go over to the east coast of the river there's
a building it's called the line
you know what they have library they have books and if you go into the
library you could find books on topics that we're discussing here
you could read on but I wouldn't dare suggest anything so radical OK
and 0 by the way speaking of text but we are not my office got
a call from the purveyors of text quantum and the coupon I work for them
and this is purely a courtesy so that the what inventory keep trying have a
show of hands of people who were planning to buy the text but haven't done
so you
but 1 of the 2 count as I just hold your hands up keep talking
but that he is we just wanna get a rough idea so we can tell
them they need to have another 20 year they need to have another 100
I into 2 significant digits is good enough we don't need to know
OK so I think that's everything that I wanted to cover 0 yes of course
the webcast is available so that if you something during lecture you lecture altogether you
can go to the website click on web cast follow what happened in
let's see let's get on with the lesson last day we started talking about taxonomy
and we looked at our classification scheme starting with democritus which was very forward-looking and
then the backtracking of Aristotle and I like to go further we started with just
the 7 medals and the carbon was sold for the point of departure for democracy
the Aristotelian view held for a long time but eventually started to crumble in the
light of more data again all of these slides and I'm showing all converted pdf
and it'll be posted at the website so you just watch notes unit the copy
every last detail so by the time the American Revolution and these are the elements
that were not
and here we have the
arsenic antimony and bismuth 3 delightful elements that were given us in the 12th 13th
and 14th centuries by the alchemists and 13th century India knew how to isolate metallic
zinc in fact a pillar their of high-purity zinc that stood for the duration is
almost a thousand years now and it's in high purity
of platinum was unknown until the Spanish came to South America
I know it's an American
plan an American model and oddly enough it was given a bad name applied to
silver so platinum is like a diminutive of silver we now know that platinum is
far superior to solve is far more noble has a higher melting point higher chemical
inertness fantastic
American and then and then all of a sudden we have discovered discovered discovered discovered
when is this means what are we saying that until 1774 and there was no
oxygen because this government know what does it mean it means it was isolated isolated
and characterized isolated and characterized so
the was characterized oxygen Cavendish characterize hydrogen
it's synthetic experiments you can create
data from these models and that's always a good way of testing
whether algorithms work and
OK so let me talk about score based structure learning for complete data
so consider graphical model with some structure and discrete observed data d and parameters theta
let's assume
we can use their racially priors on the parameters
obvious score to use
for a dataset
like this and the model class of models and is simply the probability
of the observed data under the model class
called the marginal likelihood because
that's the
likelihood functions sorry that should be a comma
the likelihood for any particular parameter settings but averaging over all possible parameter settings according
to the prior
OK this is the marginal likelihood or model evidence that karl talked about in the
context of gaston processes for example
this score
the probability of the observed data given the model class
it turns out can be computed exactly and analytically
if we have fully observed data
and dirichlet priors on the parameters
and that's where i remember that normalisation constant i talked about for the dirichlet distribution
that was a bunch of of gamma functions well
the score here is the integral of
a dirichlet distribution and ends up being expressed in terms of a bunch of ratios
of gamma functions we take the logo
so that's the marginal likelihood when we take the log of the marginal likelihood to
compute the score of a particular graphical model
what we have is this very nice and simple expressions
where we sum over all variables
and the settings of the parents of that variable
and then we compute the log of the gamma function of some fun some some
of the alpha
the centre of like this with alphas
in some cases and
the tilde is in other cases so these are parameters of your prior these parameters
of your posterior
after having observed the dataset yes question
this score does not marginalize over alpha the score is for a given
the dirichlet distribution
which is your prior over the parameters this will give you the score
four model
if you want to marginalize out the office you put the distribution over the alphas
what that implies is that your prior on the cpts on the tables is no
longer surely
is an integral of the dirichlet with respect to some of us
this is the different prior on the parameters so i argue that there's a participant
flexible so we don't really need to integrate over alpha to compute the score
we just need to come up with some setting of the alpha before we observe
the data
yes so depending on the question was what the choice about the change which model
you find and that makes sense it should change which model you find because if
you have different priorities and different prior assumptions about
what you think the table entries should be then
that will give you more or less evidence for different structures
now the important thing is not that the score decomposes over i the nodes in
the graph
which is great the lovely thing about that is that each little
the family corresponds to
a child and its parents
in the graph
OK each little family
can compute its core
independent of all the other families so we can
we can evaluate what happens when we change a little bit of the graph we
for example
the architecture
of the system
are going to be completely different
then standard databases
the last thing is that
we need an incremental computation of queries
because we
cannot store
all the streets so we will get back
in this data
phone systems there are two main approaches for defining continuous queries
first so the user can build kind of data flow
two define a query
there are extensions of the query language
as before
graphical combination of apparatus on
the idea is that the data stream management system is a
to capture
input streams and then the use of
the user wants to define new query defines it
as the combination of some operators to produce
the output stream also mandates on the dominant table
so examples of operators off to
matt union choice
i'm not going to
get deeper into this approach
the other approach
is to extend the SQL language
two continuous queries
and the idea is to query strings
exactly like permanent tables
this is not so easy
what's the problem so i
i give an example
here i consider to be tween
the stream
sending orders made by customers
and another stream
sending bits
sent to the customer
and we assume here that there are several b
one order
the question is
we want to know
month-by-month department by department
four if all the bees
the total amount
if all the cover the total amount of the old
globally for the department
this can be written
this query
which is the query which joins
g all the stream and the bill
stream and aggregate
the information
by month end by department
for all those and bill
permanent tables no problem
if now we we consider that older than b cell streams very is big problem
to be able to process this query
we need to keep in memory
all the all the
and all the b
this is the problem and we have to say that we don't want to
all elements of history
so that's the reason this system
enable the user to define windows
on the street
and this problem call blocking operations because they can become finnish
the end of the stream
you can
avoid this looking at variation
considering on the oldest three
only the last ten days
and on the bitstream
on the last day
and if you do this
you unblocked
the query
and you are able to process it
with bounded memory
and incrementally
so this is the idea
of these data stream management systems and its extensions to SQL language
so you have to trust me that we can do an incremental
you don't have to
little tilde and if we integrate this thing out what do we get we get
the natural log of c
goes as the natural log of the initial concentration c on
minus katie
what what i'm talking about is the
the way that i can determine what with the order of reaction is is to
look at the functional shape of this in other words all whether its first or
second order
two point five or they all
look like this the curves
so what i really need to do is is what the what that i is
capable of doing is detecting something simple like a straight line
so if i'm clever about it if i take instead of c
versus t
if instead i'm i'm at this into functional so i map c into some function
of c
and a map into some function of t
that is embedded in
physical chemistry of the process so that f of c
should be a linear function of g if team whether it's this or whether it's
this that i can inspect and i can say that looks linear therefore the assumptions
that underlie those functionals must be what's going on
and that's the way we determine order of reaction
one of the reaction i want to give you even though it's not chemistry i'd
still want you to understand this falls under the rubric of general culture radioactive decay
o based first order kinetics
let's just
let's just take note of that
radioactive decay
his first order
so for example on
here's the reaction you two thirty eight
can decompose to give
two thirty four class
and if we plot
if we plot the concentration of
uranium as a function of time starting with some initial value seen not we'll just
have this
attenuation but if we map it into
the natural log
of c
versus time will get a straight line the slope here will give us minus k
we know that this is an equals one because if you see a plot of
log of natural log of concentration as a function of temperature for to straight-line bingo
that tells you that this must be first order and the slope of that line
is minor scale it turns out the people that work in a radioactive decay
i don't like to
express the rate of reaction in terms of the rate constant they prefer to use
the different quantity called the half life
the half-life half-life is all more
practical it has its more directly
it is obvious what it's related to
and so the half-life is basically what you get if you take this equation here
and plug in
c not over two
it's the time it takes to consume half of the reagent the presence of i
start with c not and i plug in c not over two and sulfur time
that's going to give me the half life
if you do that you end up with
t the one half is equal to the natural log of two which is
zero point six nine three over k so that the half-life is inversely proportional to
rate constant and mediated by the natural log two entries out for this reaction the
half life t one half of this reaction is four point five
a billion years four point five billion years if you still this into
the sandbox is the neighborhood park is going to be a while before you can
go back there
and play it will take you four and a half billion years just to get
the concentration down to half of what it is and then
nine billion years ago the down recorder et cetera et cetera the nice thing about
half life and the only time whatever actually calculate half-life is in connection with first
order reactions because only for first order reactions is half life independent of concentration for
every other order of reaction half-life is a function of concentration which case it's a
useless quantity except perhaps
professors of chemistry so we will not ask you for this except
in the case of first order t one half independent of concentration
and equals one