maybe that's not so into intuitively
you can work that out for yourself and ada one problem
what it means is
that you can define this as actually equals zero ignore gravity completely
and set of differential equation
as if there was no gravity
this is actually full zero so you off over a distance AX
from the equilibrium position
we only allow for and bring forth minus kx
and everything works
and of course you should be able to
to prove that that is correct
every spring oscillate in simple harmonic fashion
and we have such as spring here
because if you can do
we favor and get it up here
then i should be able to demonstrate
that's a
uniform circular motion
on the wall
called shadow projection
you should be able thank you more calls
should be able to
have the same motion
as much grain
provided of course
that's very very carefully
make the period of oscillation of this brain
exactly the same as the time
for this object to go around
we don't shadow projected on their
and then i will even try to these this one
it's very difficult at the same time that this one is here
and what you will see that
you will see the uniform
circular motion projected
becomes the simple harmonic motion and you'll see this point
simple one
so i will try to do that in
shadow projection will make it to the doctor
and for that i need some
light here
half OK
and we also want to the so you see the spring and there you see
this object
which is rotating in a circle
but you think it's as simple harmonic motion that's of course my objection
my objective
so now
that is difficult i will have to block
you for a few seconds
i will try now to realize this
the same time
and also at the same amplitude
wasn't my best day was it
this is perhaps the best i can do today
don't go exactly next to each other but you see have the same period and
they both are present
simple harmonic oscillation this spring
because we just calculated that
and the projection of the uniform
circular motion
if we
return to the spring and maybe we should remove this
if we return to the spring
then we have the period it for scoring system
which is two pi
times square root of m k
and i want to bring this
two attest to quantitative test
how accurate this is
i'm going to double the mass
i'm going to hang on that spring
going to measure the period
and then i want
the mass which is twice as high i want that period
the square root of two times higher
that's what this equation predict
now whenever you want to do the measurement in physics
well you want to compare numbers you have a certain
goal in mind
measurement without the uncertainty in the measurement is completely meaningless
you must know
the accuracy of your measurement
o and one
five hundred
the bottom line is o point two grams
it's thousand
plus and minus o point two grams that's the best we can do
that's an extremely small error
this is an error of only o point o four percent
categorize different anomaly detection techniques according to different criteria
let's start from the left
we have this
point anomaly detection many times to
basically find
individual data records as anomalous and basically
most of the policies for dealing with here also tried to convert them into this
problem because it's much easier to do
you have this classification based techniques
then you basically have
both normal and abnormal data available
you can sort nearest neighbor based techniques
and then you try to detect anomalies based computing the distances between data records
clustering basic things are quite similar to this
you have different statistical techniques which obeys
it's don't parametric and nonparametric
well statistical statistical approaches
and you have some other techniques which include information theory based spectral composition some people
try different visualization techniques and so on and of course we the national this collect
contextual in collective action
if you have real
time system you have to have an online anomaly detection and sometimes
the data the data is
dispersed along
physical locations
you have to deal with distributed anomaly detection
sometimes you can not merge the data
have to deal with you know how to make this global anomalies don't we don't
know what talk briefly about this idea
any questions so far
OK good
i'll start with explaining briefly the classification basically
as i mentioned earlier
the main idea is to build a classification
it model for both normal
anomalous behavior so basically you assuming here that you have
lower the labels from both normal and anomalous behavior available
so of
what does it use here must be able to handle this kind of skewed
the data distribution
for example
if you have ninety nine percent of
data the correspond to normal and only one percent correspond
two anomalies using simple decision tree may not give you
very good results because using these techniques
designed for
so in this case we are dealing with two types of approaches supervised and semi
supervised classification techniques
in supervised
basically solving bought
labels available both from normal and
and you have to
costs are different types of classifiers
between normal and anomalous
and finally in the summer surprised you're assuming there is only a label from the
normal behavior
available and then using some kind of one class model
define what is normal
and then to detect deviations from this long beach area
four numbers so
basically you get the data from the normally you're trying to construct the model that
describes this more will be shown here
and then using this the model to go to the new data everything that fits
this model would correspond to only have everything else
should be anomaly
so obvious advantages of these techniques are the
one can be easy to understand because you know exactly what is normal it is
since we have both normal and anomaly
you can achieve pretty high accuracy in detecting this event
in semi supervised techniques also the normal behaviour since you know what is normal can
be actually
very well learned and you can use this description of all bishops to the fact
future anomaly
kind of disadvantages include in both cases you require
the labels
in supervised case require both labels from normal anomaly as i was surprised acquired labels
from test
and in real life applications this is sometimes not visible because the labelled data
let's say you have
millions of data records in it some time
the drawback of surprise discussion take techniques can usually
they cannot detect this emerging new
anomalous because they know what is normal anomaly and everything
outside the range they just belonging to normal anomaly depending on the closeness
we are not building characteristic descriptions but we are building discriminating descriptions with which we
want to select such attributes which discriminate the best between the classes
so rule set representation we have a set of rules
it is the disjunctive set of conjunctive rules
in the form if condition then class
we can also write it differently like and
plus if condition or conditions if class
sometimes to use this
arrow representation sometimes we say if then we have seen
let's see if
of course on communities normal then played tennis yes
so that's the class
these are the attribute values which in the condition of attribute values
it represents the condition part of the rule and the conclusion part of the rule
is the class
and this is the set of tools for a particular class
this is the simplified rule representation actually we can have if
in the form of a conjunction of attribute value then
a certain
i not of the set of all the possible classes so it is not necessary
for these conditions only the
these conditions would cover
just examples of one class
they may cover
examples of different classes then the majority class will be just assigned to the
conclusion part of the rule
and here we would say what what what what what is the distribution of classes
what are the other classes for which the rule holds
and then finally when once we have a set of rules this rule one rule
two rule three will have a set of all these rules and in addition we
may put a default rule next to it by default rule is
and it in order to improve the classification accuracy of the set of rules
so let's again look at the data
this is again the customer data
and we could say well
we could use the following rules
if income is larger than so and so much then
the person is the big spender
there's another rule for big spender and there are three rules for not big spenders
here and in addition we can add the default rules
which is as big spender yes
so this defaults rule simply says that the majority of the examples
which have
in the set of instances has
the following class
a third
in some approaches the default rule just says
what is the majority class
in the set of examples which have not been covered by the rules
explicit rules above the default rule
when using the rules for classification it can occur that none of the rules would
cover the new instance which we want to classify therefore in order that every instance
is covered we have to add a default rule
so the what does it mean that the instances covered
that is an instance or an example which we would like to classify that satisfies
the conditions of the rule then the instance is covered by the rule
if none of the a
none of the rules covers an instance then the default rule applies
and this provides us with the classification into the majority class
for the conductance example
we look at the different representations
we have again rules like production is reduced
then contact lens no
here we have the class distribution
over the set of training examples
zero examples of class soft lenses zero examples of
plus hard lenses and and twelve examples
of class no lenses in the training set
however here
this rule
is not such a clear clean rule
although the conclusions soft lenses actually
this rule satisfies
five instances of class soft zero instances of class heart and one instance of class
here you could or to say that well before in order to
i have a rule which is
i mean
which doesn't cover which only covers instances of a particular class
then we need to be
another attribute value added to the conjunction of attribute values
but such rules could overfitting the data
therefore the learning algorithm has decided not to add one additional condition
to the rule but rather to leave a probabilistic distribution of classes in the conclusion
and assigned the majority class
so you will see that in these rules can be
i used
as a classifier either
it's hard rules like
assigning this class
if the condition is satisfied or as probabilistic rules so in this case
we would have zero probability of class heart and five divided by six probability four
class after and one divided by six probability of class
so the rules can be
either probabilistic or hard so most of rule learning algorithms deal with probabilistic rules and
with probabilistic classification
even one example could be classified by different rules into different classes again probabilistic classification
would be used
so this is in the case when we have an unordered rules and we could
have on the other hand
ordered list of rules that will be shown later so in on ordered rule sets
which was the case in this the first examples
the rules
classifica nditions is led by first determining the class
and then the conditions which are put
into the body
in this sense i think you could say well their order because they are consecutively
and if it is different names to different things there is called that way of
stating the unique name assumption in how
because that you make the same assumption that there is no such thing for the
closed world assumption it was debated in the working group because clearly people wanted but
there's no it was not well understood enough we should do it properly
so you write should be my
you have some simple piece of all
you just described communities mentioned class class professors
and the descendants of this classes saying this is class with that name
and it's a partial definition and is also closely
so this is not everything we know about associate professors because it's part of the
nation but what we do know is that associate professors are subclasses of academic staff
members a very simple subclass of statement and we could say that i associate professor
assistant professor disjointclasses
i the same for professors and associate professors
they don't overlap and we can also give complete definition is particularly simple definition namely
faculty the class faculty is completely defined by saying that the government is saying these
two are equal
last night
so this is all very efficient
this is the abstract syntax is that yes and there's a bit of software but
i have it's of you can run locally or because of you can run over
the web that translates in and out of these in the RDF XML syntax
here's some more interesting cases so for example
we have a property a has arranged nonnegative integers which is reasonable for age and
these data types are stolen from the XML schema
they and so we we have the property is still by
and it's domain is cause the range academic staff members and subpropertyof involves
so you can be involved in the course and being involved as a teacher
both court
and you could say well teachers is the inverse property of told by
the property and of course the domain and range
in the
you could say that two properties are equivalent what your lectures in which he teaches
maybe there could be properties
you could say that the same great as is transitive and symmetric property
which arrange the main student two students can have the same gradient as the transition
this is the kind of notation and you could imagine just typed message or writing
on the blackboard
the sort of like
it's not
whatever came simple enough
some people say list like that
OK so it is that we talked about classes we don't know
visual cells
this is a particularly simple case and this is the name of the individual and
the individual is an instance of the class lecture
and this was in the idea way of spelling instance of
he is more interesting case where this individual is is not only instance of the
class academicstaffmember but for the property age it has the value thirty nine
and it's important to be data typed literals so it's not just the string theory
nine but this is just the string thirty nine properties and in
OK you could say that is to advise functional so you have at most one
teacher for every course
and if you say that this individual
these course
and it just
for course and it stored by this individual and installed by this individual and we
know that told by the functional properties and therefore to individuals must be the same
by inference
OK if we nevertheless say that these two are different individuals which would that we
have an inconsistency
so then if i've written all this stuff and i've written something
all of it can't be true
this is detectable
and LDL is complete in the sense that if you write down something that's inconsistent
the readers will find
and this is the kullback way of state was should not just saying to the
individuals different but the whole bunch of individuals there here there could be many more
useful individuals your entire domain in one big different individual statement
he said there are different
making unique name assumption
and they you're back database level
so here some more interesting class definitions
this is the ideal university were first year courses
this restriction that they are told by
taught by all the values from this law must be of the class professor
and is also strange university because of the the any math courses and in the
classical mathematics courses on mathematics course as this reaction is my property that
it is the value of this individuals all the mathematics courses are taught by the
same person
this is saying that academic staff members
teach some undergraduate courses you could almost
it is literally and this is that courses are taught by at least one person
minimal cardinality one
so you must have value for
is thought by
and you can of course combine these things so you can say well department the
class department is partially defined by the fact that is minimally ten members maximally thirty
and reason
partial means that these are some of the defining properties but not all of them
you are i think that this is a subclass of the class implicitly defined by
the convention
if you put complete here they you can still add further causes but these clauses
they must then
already implied by your definition and if that's not the case you because it's so
this the default is that you give partial definitions
OK and if you want to four difference to be closed
it's a complete
and nobody else can change the information they can add further clauses for these tools
can only be because it already applied the the original definition
and if it's not the case and they don't something
OK so the
giving five parts is kind of general introduction to statistical machine translation and also the
issue of evaluation for machine translation which is somewhat open issues
and about how to you the decoding
with phrase based models how do you learn phrase based models and then
all we have time for that two more research she kind of things to work
that we currently do in edinburgh on factored translation models and this kind of training
so i think the machine translation as
it's very easy to use
i understood problems
so you get things like this and you try to make sense of it try
to figure out what does that mean i have no idea what that means i
could that have been done at some point
still would explain it to me
so so this is one of the oldest problems in artificial intelligence and artificial intelligence
research came up as a as a topic how can we build intelligent machines
machine translation was considered one of the problems
to tackle besides playing chess
and to do really well
the general assumption is that you need to do all the hard things in artificial
intelligence you need to
no one world knowledge
you know what semantics about what things mean what what what does everything because they
always some translation cases where you really need to know what you're talking about
we try to do something much simpler
because we don't know how to do all these things but we try to get
as far as you want so we would be doing is inspired by the story
of the rosetta stone that you might have heard about
so the egyptian language was a long time in the mystery now we know what
it meant
they had all these funny symbols of i is some camels what i know
and it probably was some some of that but nobody could encode
until seventeen ninety nine someone found in the desert the stone that had one part
egyptian one part cream greek and other parts of language but
and that enable them to people to decode
the egyptian alphabet because you just look at the egyptian you could look at the
corresponding greek you so all you have another greek word occurs and that different currents
and if you do that for awhile you can really in the world the words
suggestion i
what we are
in the simulation of right now is that we have a similar situation where the
computer can discover automatically how to translate
so we have now available to us a lot of texts in electronic form
thanks to the internet and all the other answers
that computers can analyse
so for some language pairs we have on the order of hundreds of millions of
words translated
even before like spanish english not hard to get hundreds of millions of words and
to give you some idea of what that is so if you if you just
prior book and the book store that has maybe a few hundred thousand words in
so maybe it's a good guess that ordinary educated person writes about ten thousand words
a day series maybe three and half million words year
and annuity had million words in lifetime so the computers
have access to
translated texts in the volume that is comparable then you able to read lifetime
and if you look the modelling world text
computers have access to much much more data than you ever be able to read
so if you try to read the internet
it will keep you busy i think that number
some thirty thousand years if you read takes on this of
that's how long it's gonna take so
i mean it's somewhat stunning that
yes we learn language and you probably smart development language because we learn language in
a context where things are pointed out to suppose that this is you know table
this is a screen and then we can learn things that way
in terms of raw language that we are confronted with
computers actually have a huge advantage of second process much much much more
text and be able to do
OK so the
statistical machine translation models are talking about
and just give you a quick rundown of basic principles
so we have two different models
one is the language model or also have been speech recognition and one of the
translation model language model is there general
storytelling here is to translate from a foreign language into english
so the language model is there to figure out what is good english what is
fluent english what makes sense in english
and the translation model
the purpose is the more obvious
you have to find out some correspondence between for instance in english sentence
so two mathematical models one tells you these two sentences to the match up
another model cells who is the english actually good english
because you want to have a translation only only
adequately represents the input you also want translation that
fluently and the output lacked
so given these two mathematical models you could take
any two words sentences
and measure
is the output of english
and to test the input and the output correspond
and so that the small problem remaining is finding the best sentence for a given
input that has the highest probability
in terms of taxation moral
and the language model so probability world pretty much everything is possible you could take
any possible in sentence as possible translation for
so spanish input sentence
and all these models should give you some probabilities for it
so but you can list up all spanish sentences after being little bit smarter finding
good space
so i talked a lot about the translation model and going on and i don't
much about language models
OK so another slide from here
so this is
someone called quiet
triangle list of our parent better so you have
kind of the process how maybe humans actually do translation
so when the translated for instance into english
we read the foreign words we know something about the formal grammar we have
we know what the words mean you've kind of now a concept of of the
meaning and ultimately in our head is the meaning of the sentence
and given the meaning of the sentence
we can then go around find what the writing of concepts with the right words
what is the right syntax have to put that in
and ultimately whatever set by the paper
all the models that currently exist
ignore the entire top part of the permanent
so very simple models take the form would shuffle them around put it produced english
once he moved to more free space you can move up a little bit in
the parameters
because he realized that some birds grouped together and have meaning
that is independent of the individual words and a lot of effort is currently in
machine translation research and i don't have much about it is to move further up
to use syntax and grammar
to build better models
all the work on this event is very much driven by
what works now
can you build a system and show me that better
OK well i
so this the first of its about the processes
the method
and the ways we
build and maintain the kernel today
and look at some of the things we would be doing in the future
so this is what used to have a long time ago
new delhi the capital which is the table it on the floppy disk
was actually bigger and when it's not fitting on one floppy disk because this is
clearly maintainable would be impossible to deal with more than one megabyte
had people and carried around in the most popular
everybody packages to this guy called this
new everybody by name
i read every page
commented on every email
strangely enough we don't do it that way anyway
after what became obvious
you can't actually just feed one
so system if all were a small number of maintaining particular part
collected packages
check checked the centre leg is still commented on everything
various things happen to support the project again got a lot larger switches
in nineteen ninety five nineteen ninety seven
let's have children
dramatically reduced his ability to spend large amounts of time on the project
there's lots of other problems with
the way it used to be done
if loners went on holiday per week there were no updates for
and that means you could see if you actually got tree
what else everybody else have been doing
there was no way of
taking your particular changes
fixing clashes between change everything stop
and you have one central coordinator
which has its advantages and disadvantages
various people played with CBS the
the current rationing system
policy vs is the reason to system where
single person
look at all of the categories in
actually your sending these horrible it's not going in the end
so there is no system editorial control
there's no way for people to sell to the good from the bad
so we start with this one central coordinator must maintain
another problem is change long because you want history
why would the change in nineteen ninety four a
it might be important in when you're looking at making huge change
so how do you manage change logs available and edited
and usually wrong very complete
one of these is immediately tells you need something better
so we need something that could be tracked all of things that are going on
and the first thing that came along with the some arguments in the community doing
things properly and this this does not scale
someone called lion void created a non-free project called bit people
most was refused to use because it is not
various people did use a got less and less free over time
so and each gel hopefully reverse engineered
was much complaining loudly of people that trade secrets breaking licenses
whereas in fact the individual reverse engineer
he tell it to the
we got to command line like problems that help
which point they keep the server from help take part in with the list of
all of the command understood
there was a bit more simple and my
larry bull had because they
ten try to take his coat off with it
this debate in the world
so let's spend a couple of weeks writing a replacement of the first version of
was called get
get is very different something like CVS get is truly distributed version control system
so everybody who is using it as their own complete source tree the machine
you can make changes to this
with change love removed
merge changes from other people
and apply your changes up and so on
instead of having an idea whether it's the same as repository
is a single central point with is the defining point
you can have multiple trees and you can push data between these trees said that
and that means that maintains complaint code together with change log
develop the code
take patches from other contributors
and then push the law in one easy to manage show to let us
the margin
change to merge
it is merged
any conflicts can be resolved
so that the first kind of real tend to use the technology things
getting from
today's model looks something like this
possibly have yet depending on your particular distribution
so it's still so far
get close to have full URL if you can get all the rest of world
you will get a table
sort of like that table you get
get archived with that of
CD into it part two
variables now called
why is the observations
and sets of parameters they correspond to observed and non observed parameters and now introduce
these axes in the case of the
i see a it was the sources these are things we do not observe they
are the latent variables and the model is we think
the total probability of what we observe
composed in such a way that is the probability of the the unobserved variables
and this is the conditional probability of the observation given
so latent ones so this again
it's just the way of writing
joint distribution
so i have
forgetting about the parameters per second
this is just the way of writing that he
y and x jointly observing
in this structure usually i have an idea if i know what the latent variables
are i know
how the
the observations are rated so in the ICA model if i know what the sources
then i believe the wise are just a linear operation on the sources maybe add
bit of noise and this takes this into account and i have some ideas how
the latent are generated
right but unfortunately we don't observe x so what we have to do is we
have to get p y
and that means i have to some
over all possible values of the axis
or in case it continues thing after integrating over x
i have to do
the summation over x and that's what
i wrote to you
and that makes a bit
the problem
on the other hand
no no not that well there might be some parameters that i have to tune
and this probability and maybe there are some parameters that i have to tune in
this probably it just means both of them can have parameters which i want to
tune using maximum likelihood
but what want
well i mean if you want to make a set of
i mean
i mean the theta x does not depend on x maybe it's the wrong it's
the wrong way of writing the text simply means it's those parameters data that appear
in the extensive so it shouldn't be considered a function of x
so it's just those are the ones that are here and those are the ones
i mean i didn't want to give them the same nameplate and then it would
just mean o is this the same fate as that now just there's
something does here something else there
so the the most
the most simple
and well known case is a mixture of gaussians
so we know how gaussians
and then gauss in data look like
but what happens if we have more structure in data so this is like a
histogram of
data that have sort of two humps and he was one of
you can't sort of model this by a single gaussians any ideas of is introducing
a mixture of gaussians so
that's the way of writing these things
so what i have is
i have
couple of gaussians
this is a
in density
and for each
what i call the component i have the mean and the variance
they bases on this picture
there's things like you know were yes the number of hops right so you would
have this one actually it seems like it has one main is another means so
here and this is sort of easily
you can easily see what what happens in then mix them together in such a
way that again you have a normalized probability density so you mix them with
weights that sum up to one because if this sums up to one
and then you see these there are nonnegative and sum up to one then you
see that this is valid
the total likelihood again you would sort of take all your observations y is independent
and so you have this is the model so
what you have now is we observe y but you don't know from which goes
it comes actually so
the number
the k is
the hidden variables the discrete variables
so it is clear i mean before we had to move
we had these axes and x corresponds now to the variable k
we would like to do
maximum likelihood and maybe i just go
correspond to an output false zero so we can see it in this situation
we cannot draw line in separate perfectly all the positive on one
side and negative on the other f i was to draw decision boundary
that's linear is actually kind of famous example it was shown
with use in sorry the in the perceptrons book to show that a single
neuron has some limitations however much like don't describe
me i can transform my input space into another representation
and then get a problem that simpler in this case can be separated
by a single neuron by a linear decision boundary
so what i'm showing here on this side is what if i take my input
space and instead now two dimensions with which i'm going to
draw my inputs my examples the first was going to be the n over
the negative of the first dimension and x to and the second
dimensions going to be the end of the first mention the negative
of x to so in this case this example here zero zero
would have an and for both both this and this and b zero
so what actually map to this point here
and actually this point also if we run through the
calculation of both and here will also
wrap into the same point and we can go through the derivations and
and find out that for both these points they also live essentially
the same place so in this case i can actually drawn now line between
the positive negatives and the thing to notice here is that the
function i've use to now draw my data differently
are these to functions that i've shown before i could actually
represent with a single neuron so what this example suggests is
that if i first compute a few set of neurons and i have some output
neuron that is connected to these intermediate neurons
and now i can start modelling nonlinear decision boundaries
a in this case i can actually perform
model this this function here the x or function
as that is at the core like why we are interested in neural nets
one neural nets interesting is that the allows to go beyond
linear classifiers and actually model non-linear decision boundaries
any questions far
right so that brings us to multilayer neural net
i'm to start simply with a single hidden layer
neural network so in this case what this means is that f between
the input in the output i'm going to have a layer of what i call
hidden units each of these units all like artificial neurons
that is they are connected with the previous layer the input
and perform a linear transformation
of the input and then apply some activation function
ok so you're seeing here essentially a
just like a different notation in the context of
one hidden layer neural net but we see the same for for the pre-activation
it's a bias so this notation i'm i'm using the exponent to index
the layer so this is the one because this bias
for the units the first hidden layer and then this index eyes to
indicate that this is for this is the bias what the i with layer
sorry i f unit in the first hidden layer
and i'm going to take that bias to get my pre-activation loss summing
over the contribution of all the input units so all units in the
previous layer weighted by the corresponding weight of the connection
between the g with input and the i f hidden unit one for which
i'm showing the computation of pre-activation
and again here this matrix w which contains all the weights between
all pairs of hidden unit and input unit i'm i'm storing them into
this matrix w one that i'm using exponent to index to refer
again to the first hidden layer and i can actually write the computation
of all pre-activation of all units in the first hidden layer
in vector form so i can just take the bias vector b one
and i'm as you've seen here what this operation response to effectively
is to take the vector x and multiply it by the row the highest
rho of my matrix w so if i just take the product of the x
multiplying on the right with my matrix w well in the doing is
for each row i'm going to do a dot product between x and the corresponding
row weights which means that i get all the contributions to the
pre-activation for all hidden units so to sum up
my pre-activation is just this vector-valued
linear transformation on my previous layer input layer x
and then as usual neural for regular units
i get my hidden layer activation by applying my
choice of activation function g over my vector applying it element-wise
and then finally to get my output put imagine
performing binary classification so the output would
like neuron between zero and one that gives you the probability
belong to the positive class well i'm again going to take a bias
so b two now because i'm at the second
layers which is the output layer and going to multiply by some
weight vector connecting my output unit with all the hidden units
that i'm noting w to multiply by the activation of the first hidden
layer which is h one or here i should probably have a
one here so that's for single layer neural network
the questions on the notation for anything related to the slide
so i case describe the case of binary classification more generally
more commonly would be interested in
classifying to multiple class performing multi-class classification
so in this case what it means is that an input my belong to one
out of c capital c different classes and so if i wanted to do
independent subspaces multidimensional components
but then well that's
the first starting point but then the question is that
well what kind of dependencies can we have inside the subspaces
one nice thing i see is that when we say that components are independent then
all that's that is remains to be determined about the component is there a one-dimensional
this probability distribution function or the probability distribution functions
but they are one-dimensional so that kind of with rather limited they are not too
difficult to estimate but if we say that we have n dimensional
let's say OK dimension well it's OK if we have k dimensional subspaces
and we can have any kind of dependencies inside the subspaces then the complexity of
the model completely explodes because we have k dimensional probability densities and well that's extremely
that those are very difficult to model or estimate in engine
so what
one approach that small is motivated by these applications ICA the feature extraction
this is a one one two one o approach uses the idea of universe is
based on the idea of invariant feature subspaces by michael
so what gonna cities that's well linear filters
necessarily lack any kind of invariances well you would think that for example if an
input is
minus x instead of x
then the output of a linear filter will necessarily changes sign so you wouldn't have
a come cost have even this kind of simple
a simple
invariance with respect to policy
so what propose is that's a very
mathematical framework to model dependencies is two subspaces and in particular that looking at the
moment of of projections onto the subspace so we have in the end we what
we have is some WIC that spans some kind of a invariant feature subspaces and
then we will get the linear projections and take the sum of squares of things
well this is certainly not
i mean this idea doesn't really come out of the this kind of model for
invaders have been used for a long time in in subspace classifiers for example that
the idea is that you present said one class of objects by subspace and you
then you project onto subspace to see whether whether you are in the subspace
so now if we combine these two ideas
multidimensional independent components an invariant subspaces what you get is what we call independent subspace
the idea is that well this invariant subspace
tells us how we can actually define in a meaningful way
and and a very simple and very simple way but if the distributions inside the
subspaces we can just say that these distributions inside subspaces hospital symmetric which means that
they depend only on the norm of the projection that is only on the value
of invariant features that we have actually simplify the matter very much because now inside
each subspace is we only need to be on the only
freedom left is the distribution of that no
which is you know again the one-dimensional probability density function and not more complicated than
the one dimensional PDF seen basic ICA
so in
first two well if we not talk about this thing from with the point of
image processing and computer vision well of course people have their figured out many different
kinds of invariant features features in invariant with respect translation of of scale or anything
but here the point is that we are not
specifying which
in what way these features should be
invariant we are just saying that OK let us we have this kind of subspaces
that can be estimated from the data and when we estimate then we will probably
get some kind of independent sorry some kind of invariances but those invariances will be
determined by the data itself and not by us
so this just a simple graphic description of how we then compute in this model
so we have this WIC just as in the basic ICA basic ICA case we
linear dot products to get
some components
but now the point is that instead of processing each component separately
to compute the PDF or whatever we now have now put them into groups for
example here groups of all components
that the PDF is
is a function of of of this of taking the squares of each of these
components and then in some inside the school of subspaces
well here i show the square root which is so if you want to compute
the itself instead of the square on but that doesn't really matter
so this what is so here we get then the value of the invariant feature
so what happens
when we have apply this image data
what we see is the emergence of the of so-called complex cell properties so these
feature stops this subspaces we'll have properties similar to so-called complex cells in the visual
well it doesn't matter if you don't know about complexity but well basically in the
primary visual cortex basically people distinguish two types of sensors simple cells and complex as
simple cells
usually more by some kind of a linear
linear models or at least models that are very close to linear models and that
can be estimated by linear systems identification as complex cells are then something more complicated
something very clearly not
one of the
OK let's get started
so hello everybody and we'll come back to that part of the machine learning in
bioinformatics lecture
i'd like to start with a brief repetition of really have what we had last
time so i think i lost a few people there and you have some questions
just ask during
OK so i would like to mainly started many talk about bioinformatics i guess it's
all kind of you know then i started talking about string kernels and yes yesterday
i was talking about large scale data structures and introduce a
in the last time i talked about the structure of learning
OK so
i mean he talked about being kind of we had different data types in bioinformatics
but i mean you talked about string so and here in some ways of defining
a string
one way is to define the feature space explicitly and then computers to this kind
of product and that i showed you a race of how to do this efficiently
using string indexing structure
another way was to derive from the generative model like hidden markov model markov chain
these things that i've shown you like the fish account of a simple probabilistic model
is actually equivalent to the great degree which i have described
and you can also derive from a similarity measure this coverage which is called the
local alignment kernel which is something that every program to compute alignments that defines
OK so
so i talked a little bit about these string data structure the string indexing data
structure so you cannot i mean you can speed up a little bit of a
single kernel computation so i mean but it cannot be much faster than linear in
to see
so what you can be part that when you compute linear combinations of kernels and
you can be actually faster than the sum of the length of the
OK and the idea here was that the
exploit the feature map phi x is sparse only few elements not
and also a linear combination of the features of this feature is going to be
OK and the sparse vectors
we can represent either by
explicit maps
sorted lists or suffix trees tried binary fission
and then we can do operations on these spot feature
and this being accommodations to be used when we compute the output of an SCM
for instance we have a set of n support vectors and you would like to
compute the output of the whole test set this test set can be pretty large
like genomic scale you can have like the human genome sometimes billion data points i
would like to invite you
and they really speak
OK and here a data structures really help
also talked about so
this is but this is
so i also talked about the diffusion
so that least three ways of integrating data so that you typically don't have you
typically have more than one kind of information points when you're classifying genes you might
have expression data might sequence and other information in the question is how do you
combine these two things
so one way would be
two integrated early
so you simply take features
hence the feature vectors concatenate them and then use one can and come up with
a classifier
another way would be intermediate integration so you have
one can metrics are one to features you drive because each feature set
then these two come up with this
so what you have seen yesterday in article of the highest talk with essentially late
integration so he took a different features that came up
with many kernels and discriminant function and at the very end he combine several discriminant
functions to come up with a multiclass classifier
and in some cases this might be preferable other cases
one typically the intermediate integration is that time
CV here
so for instance you could i mean that there's some work where you can exponentiated
these take
you take the sum of the kernel and then
i did
so so you can exponentiated these kernels that at the right to take the long
back so that's another way life
we want
know there was some by
according to do so he worked with exponentiating kernels and
on the internet
but here will only
give proof of one
of of the
of the five live
steps right
so we're trying to prove that
g is connected and there is exactly one path between any two vertices so i
have two indices
the and i know that there is exactly one path between u and v
then i would like to
prove that
it is connected
but the removal of any edge disconnected OK
if you if the first condition is true
it's connected
then this part is true too
it is connected to there's nothing to it we just have to prove that if
we remove any action
the graph
i will be disconnected
so let's take in any
from let's say x and y
it's an arbitrary
if that is if if this one is true
this means there is exactly one
path between x and y and that part
it's just the edge
if i remove the edge e
there is no pattern between x four
so there must be in different components
connected component
so the graph is not connected to the present
and here the proofs that i'm not going to vote go
two because i would like to cover it be more
the only question
there may be more than one wall
let me give you
one example
i have
that's a
from x
two y
there is only one path that would be let's see
that would be w so
w that is the path between x and y
unique but here is
a what
the y
so what
which goes like this
so then we one more than one one
if we if
and it's true if you start walking then just
so part is notable it is
and walk it maybe you may walk with wander around them
the but that is very important
consequence to this theorem that the stated above and through just one-fifth of the of
and that is
contains at least one vertex of valence one
here we have to be
all graphs that we consider here are finite
because for instance for infinite graphs
this is not true
let me give you an example of an infinite graph
which this is not true
and if you need three
so that's an example of an infinite tree
there is exactly one
path between any two vertices
so that's three
but these three has no
a vertex of valence one each vertex valence two
so one has to be careful
here's the proof
suppose g is a graph
maybe three right
in which every vertex has valency at least two
then by the handshaking lemma
we have
the number of edges is one over two
time to some of the valence
of our graph
but remember the valence of each vertex is at least two
so this is greater
we have three of g
valence is so this must be
later equal to one-half
times is one half from here
view of g comes from
blg times two comes from this
now these two into castle and to get g so what do we get
we get that the of g is greater or equal to the of g
on the other hand
if g is three
then he of g is less than
energy because you g is just
view of g minus one
as we
we've seen in the in the in the previous year so that's a contradiction so
if you have such a graph then g is definitely not true
and you see
the this handshaking lemma
holds for
we're fine finite graphs called for
this is called for
of vertices of valence one have special name
there are called leaves
what is the spanning tree
a spanning tree is a spanning subgraph is three
and it's very important
that a finite graph
if and only if it contains a spanning tree
here again we have to say that the graph is finite
because for is for infinite graphs
the existence of a spanning tree
is equivalent to the axiom of choice
so that's
you cannot prove it
you just have to assume it by my actions
but for finite graphs it's easy right
if graph is connected
it must contain a spanning tree
so we have a finite graph
it is connected
if it's not three then by that theorem it must have at least one cycle
the cycle
any edge on the cycle removing it
and the graph stays connected
keep doing that
because the graph is finite there are only finitely many
so we have various tools
we have for example
exactly the sort of unfortunate
were sort of tracking bug
it has a user interface is about ten years old web design
it has
its environment is completely non user-friendly uses very technical language
it's very hard to localize only speaks english
very slow
if you have large numbers above
the biggest problem of all the above the love is villa is just good enough
nobody has written replace
but it was a little bit worse find somebody would have replaced with software
but it sure yesterday
there are lots of things we can do with exelon
one of which is that if for example somebody followed by the door
which turns out to be kind of
somebody else while the volume and returned that same kind of
we can't merge this back together coming close
we can't link them with the kernel
so we never pushing but ran between distributions finding common things between distribution
we've got no way of actually working out
dear passing about on from one place to another
re-entering it using all of the
cc lists
a lot of messing around
we have a regression tracking system is point new
and the idea is to these to find things where somebody said this used to
work stop words
because of the often very easy to debug because if you know when it stopped
you only have to look at a small amount to see why
we have a lot of time
usually checking you regression which turns out to be hard
somebody said you still have traded to the new release now doesn't
after much investigation you discover the CPU fan filed the same day
so in fact that it was a hard problem
the motion tracking system is very bad
it has a superb user interface is called rafale
initially financed that
we so badly
the human body is human regression tracking system we may automate in the future if
doesn't scale
but for the for the moment it's a one-man show
it's very very useful
he's also tracking patches west
sometimes people to actually fix the regression and again this
is actually saying this one is needed to look at this is a regression that
thank you got
arjen and event is playing with the idea of statistical tracking
it is the
o thing you get the kernel when something goes horribly wrong
and that's a
a lot of data registers
all traces
and i just wondered since we've got a lot more users that
we should not enough people we can use this
if we set things which distribution should tools
which send it seems to me central site which are now in the light door
i believe the latest about two hours
you should be able to look at all of these things find common
and the idea that we would be able to start the same thing thing
in the most obvious ontologies
the most common but occurring is this one
it is really really useful in terms of what is that we should think what
the most
well it
to a certain extent it's probably the one most people see
the second thing is to do with not really done some very large companies with
huge numbers of service have done in
it's the condensed ask questions saying
all machines the crash what is common about
so you start the statistical correlation
for example
does everybody you see this particular this problem western discourse each out
maybe they all have the same distance from
maybe this problem certain age
so you can start to actually look at look at the data and ask questions
on very much more scientific fashion
and in theory you can actually do but not the analysis of
so you can do things ninety five percent certain p ten so you
statistical data sets
ninety percent to ninety five percent certain p
the this is linked having this hard
it is very very useful for debugging
and the great thing about this
it's the
statistical stuff
doesn't need the end induced to do anything complicated
on their machine in some sense the and the support of all
software to deal with
you know why they have to do any idea push about saying
when it comes saying your machine crash previously
i have recovered the
the error of
and i think it too
four analysis yes no
so it's very scale
because we don't teach everybody had to use
one i think
people do a binary search
two six twenty four to six twenty five doesn't
what's the first thing you do is developed
one the first the things you say
what's the middle two six twenty four
release candidate for
release candidate two
release candidate three no
you know if you can't figure out why something has changed
you don't know there is a new narrative to small
you can look through that changes i want to change abruptly
it was developed but not all do
you need a lot of CPU power the very no longer problems
you need a lot of memory memory is not a problem
in a lot of this this is definitely not a problem
so it's easy to do
the problem with is that is
i mean a calculation here
so i'm going to do it with a six hundred thirty three
laser light
and this
so the being of that laser is about three millimeters and then we have this
this is the opening this is the
and we can make the
so we we already made predictions
then i mentioned
if this
if the opening is only a tenth of a millimeter
you would expect that the central maximum on that screen which is about three metres
away that's why i chose to three meters that central maximum will then be two
centimetres wide
but i can make it we wider
because i can make d
way smaller than tens of millions
this is it
all right so what you see now
is that the
so that is
very large very open
i don't know maybe millimeter or so
and i'm going to
now but at one point here so that you can this is a nice moment
you see that central maximum she are powerful and overwhelming that is in terms of
its brightness
we understand now why because this crazy function sin beta divided by the square
we already know
it is here although i would say five centimetres
it's already now this thread with must be less than the tens of millions because
there will be two centimetres if it were tens of millions and i hope you
you can see this being distinctly those dark location
you see a lot of them
keep in mind that the mean maximum next brought maximum
is only four and a half percent and get
smaller and smaller
hello and low as you go further away
so now
and i go way beyond one tens of millions smaller
we're a small and i'll keep in mind when i make the slept with smaller
and less likely to go through i can help that
so the whole image will become fainter that's the price i pay
four leading less light
but what i'd blame is
surely the absurdity that the centre maximum gets wider and wider and wider as i
the senate
smaller and smaller and smaller so this is no narrower and narrower and narrower and
narrower in the center maximum that you see there is almost full
so the centre
the opening of my slits must now be something like
the only ten microns are so extreme that is very highly
highly accurate
the device whereby we have
the option of making this liquid
the smallest
michael using this is the
the result you get
i will now
make this list
open open open open up here we have the point
i make the centre point about two centimeters
this liquid which is about now is about content
of a millimeter
all right
i now have to make
an important confession
about the gradients
some of you
we're very observant
you may have noticed
the maximum
one of the greatest that showed also when i did experiment with my own
one of all
the same right
what's the difference
no one asked me about it and i was hoping that no one has
and the reason for that is
each one of those groups
has a finite size opening
and each one of those openings ac
this way
they cause diffraction recall that the fraction right answers semantics
and so superimposed on the greening
this causes diffraction and the net result than this
but you get
the product of the two
so if i am n here now
no i'm removing this debate and of course this is now
four grading but debate is defined this wages d
it is the opening of the school of ukraine
and the
is the separation between the grading
then i can write down here
the sign
of and delta
at the histogram of its values of its components
i can get this kind of girls in shape histogram
and when i look at the end one solution it's very different again the kind
of the reserve values of x seems to be roughly uniform except that there is
an enormous peak here which indicates that a lot of these x components are actually
OK so we see in fundamental difference about to which problem we look at between
the l one solution until
all right so
in this lecture is we can be very interested in solving underdetermined system of equations
of course we all know that if i have fewer equations than unknowns
i can not
so underdetermined system of equations
but we're gonna be nevertheless concerned with is situations in which i have fewer equations
than unknowns
and of course we're going to make some assumptions about the unknown so that the
solution to this problem at least has some meaning
and so we can assume that the unknown vector x that we interested in recovering
from unfortunately too few equations is sparse
in the sense that most of its coefficients may be zero
and what we learned during his lecture
is if we have an underdetermined system of equations to solve and is arise
in a countless number of applications and if the right hand side happen to be
sparse approximately sparse then what we learn is that in one
minimisation often returns the correct answer and i'll show you some applications and this phenomenon
really has thousands of applications
OK so
there are many problems in which we we have unfortunately fewer equations than unknowns but
the premise that what we're looking for is far reading radically changes the problem and
makes the search for solutions feasible
so i'll show you two examples and we'll see many more examples during this
one example which is extremely modern is
something has to do with gene expression arrays
so in gene expression array of course
are other people who are not familiar with gene expression arrays
all right
OK so in gene expression arrays the idea is that you put
genes on the chip
and you're gonna measures amount of
protein that the
OK so what we're doing is we're measuring the change of expression levels in in
lots of genes simultaneously because we all put them on the chip that looks like
this we have little dots you put the genes in there and then you measuring
the expression level
and the idea is you have to pay a person who is healthy person we
sick and you're trying to measure the difference in expressions of several genes compared between
a and healthy patient and sick anticipation
OK so the idea of a gene expression arrays to quantitatively measure the expression of
tens of thousands of genes simultaneously
and so you create picture that look like this where if you have a green
dot i forgot in which way it goes but it means that the gene is
overexpressed in if you have already done it's underexpressed and if you have a black
dot is about the same
what you have is because there is no easy you have observations about data of
interest y of the form x players e
why is the measured data as this is what you measuring and despite number i
x i is the true change in expression level four gene the gene that you
put at spot number i in the eyes
it is a stochastic error which has to do with things that you cannot control
so we have data like this but in genomics applications
it's very
common to assume that if we're looking at the disease of interest only a few
genes will be actually responsible for this disease and what that means it means that
the unknown the things i'm looking for is actually exhibit extremely sparse
such analysis would expect that
you know the number of genes coding for a certain disease will be at most
in the hundreds and so you expect on a hundred locations point is vector x
this thirty thousand dimensional vector x you would expect that only a few hundred at
most would be non-zero
OK so this sparsity easier the knowledge of the priory knowledge that what you're looking
for is sparse
really informs the methods of analysis
of statistical analysis
another example is again taken from genetics
it's an example of sparse signals in genetics where for example there's a quantitative trait
that you're interested in
in the knowledge in in studying for example cholesterol level
and so
so there is this quantity is is variable y which is a cholesterol level
so you would like to read relate cholesterol level with is eugene attacked
OK so with the genetic makeup of a patient
all right so what people do in the field and in genetics they're relate the
cholesterol level which is why
the model the linear model of the form y is equal to EX plus
but two
people in the same way the sorts of people do i have
the other is
one more
what we're doing
and when
there is about one
so far
it seems like using bases his
one zero
well is
we don't want to
how can
what we do
how we think
and of course we're biological and we learn things and and
we were born with the brain but now it has complicated computational processes and those
are the ones
that i'm interested in
so four
or you could say that anything
that's like saying there isn't really a table is just tiny part
but it doesn't matter at this highway that's what i meant by insulation the higher
levels are probably much more like a computer then like heart
a hard has the
interest intial connection of muscle fibres it's all one thing there's no not a great
deal of separation in the brain there are separate functions wonderfully isolated from one another
most parts don't interact unless
there's a good reason for them to
computer screen
no one knows what how dreaming works
and the standard
there are three or four theories
one is that dreaming is like
garbage collection in last
another is that it's
it's a great and nice theory which was that
a lot of ideas share some neurons
and by alternating least stimulating them you kill the connections that are relevant but he
didn't have a clear idea
how that works
but i wouldn't want to answer any questions about sleep because no one
understands it
incidentally you probably has ten different functions
because almost all animals are either nocturnal or diurnal
it takes two brains to survive in the
when is light and when it starkers there's different kinds of predators
so almost all animals have opted to
to disappear in
either in the day or the night
but once you have a mechanism like that at the evolution uses it for ten
other things
the muscular like
they like to
which is
this is
the whole
one these
and then we
it is
so this is
you know
and on the
you can see
one of those
the same
this station
are the concept
she is
what you see here
most of the time
the case
o point
what we
this was
so this
also see that
he said
we also want to do
so let's see what
we all we
his son
and the
this so called
some of the brain
it's true
we've seen that he knows the difference
some the
so the easy way
so strong
in this area
trying to
see want
the consists
we want
is always
it's not all
all right
let's see what
you're you're
thank you
all right
i mean it's
right so little
all rest
and you it
so what you say what
o two
and what i show you
it remains
he said he was
the students of the challenge
it's a
real job
so just
being with
o two
one one one
the majority
due to set
we show you
so that
so and so the problem is
the first role was always
to do
so many years
and so
it should be
it is
from one
it's a
we know
and the implementation of details if you try to apply this
and start off with the required total thomas level aiming for
it generally takes an age to get started so there is a kind of adopted
tolerance schemes we start off with large values slowly decrease the value we were interested
in the one
there's also an approximate sequential importance sampling algorithm for by system itself and should be
a few problems up to point out a couple of weeks ago by robert christian
and company
well this atoms
so far so good and but there are problems still very slow to converge
we've got this acceptance rate here in this acceptance that here
when we make very slowly
and so on
often we have more help available to
i'll illustrate this with reference to the branching process problems in the moment
but we've got a parameter theta we can split it into several blocks you can
arbitrarily many
the gibbs sampler concentrated then which follows we draw the first value the first block
the towards the conditional density given in
the block
and so on the data
that often turns out that although we don't know the complete likelihood we can calculate
part likelihood that we know some of these parameters and then we can calculate sort
of these conditional distributions
to pay for that we know this conditional to the distribution of theta one given
p two data we don't know this one
so we could then do a ABC within
it's kind of template on ABC one metropolis approximate probability hastings including gibbs
thirty the following
we are first block from it's time to get close to the city
this of course is an acceptance rate of one
and the second block we do ABC to withdraw from its parameter we see data
which have to fit the data is good
so this way we got this automatic acceptance here
we the ABC here we can explore the
their posterior space quicker than one of the b
the case
yes because you want to draw from it
if you're doing the metropolis hastings version of it
so from the previous slide then
you want OK you can you do it you got acceptance and and then you
would calculate that if you get to take a step one
OK so back to the examples before we call this this is a branching process
generating the data in some sense and the red bits of the discrete observations we
so it turns out that if we condition on known history
all the three parameters that the distribution of the sampling points are often
tractable because the slightly might be be passed on
mutations along the branch lengths so by the fossil finds of
so i can
so concentrating on the
climate evidence from from moment
call what we're trying to estimate was that at this point here how far back
in the past that we have to go
to find the divergence time of the primates when they first evolved
the data we have all the fossil finds that we know of the way painful
discovered fossil finds linear all they get is a snapshot wanted we reconstruct something about
you also need to think about how to choose a good summary statistics
and if you only have a an unknown the problem we have to do is
in in general
so what we want is somewhat summary summarizing apple as
and some ideas about what they say
which is sensitive to changes in the parameter but both variations in data
so we call this is
a stochastic model so over here this is two dimensional data the green my output
from a particular parameter value this from another parameter value can so we get a
cloud data for each by the premise that we want to some that actually going
to separate these two
it promises continuous
but what if you
so obviously the location column emails and there is a good starting point
but in general is
nontrivial how to come up with a good summaries takes away the intuition it seems
about the problem is dealing with
and they injured results well so
and been found that sometimes you can add information to summary so increases summary adding
more information you expect to die
new inference an example that happens everything falls down him and that's probably happening because
you your model wrong all the wrong yes
and what might not to fit the model one summary of one of the summary
statement about the same time is difficult
the battery to model some kind of model
discrepancy also can have
model error there that
but what we would like ideally
it's some kind of systematic approach for finding good summary
one of the most recent data
so talking about primates
the observed number of fossils perhaps i should have said
the the picture isn't actually simple
in that time is divided geological epochs and we can't they fossils that precisely the
we can do is count the number of fossils found in the my scene the
number we found that you see and and so on
so data is actually discrete number counts the number of primate species we know from
so the next one of the metrics we tried was the following measure the distance
the simulated data real data
the nice thing about
the ABC methodology is that you want your simulators may comes you want
you can try many different metrics you want you have to revert everything you people
people your data
OK so what we this a went wrong and the the tracer MCMC output and
this here is the
prediction of the number of modern primate species
so we we know
the number of modern primate species about three hundred fifty where the models predict predicting
about fifty
well this is very simple to solve using ABC methodology all we do is change
the metric we have determined the metric which takes account
the predicted modern population size
so we know that these three hundred seventy six modern species roughly in and so
what we do we compare estimated output with three seven six days for why we
penalize the model
and then this gives approximation from this posterior distribution so the posterior distribution of the
parameters given the data
the value three seven six
i release it
from a point that is at least two and a half times the radius
of this circle
above the zero level if i do any law lower it will not make it
think about this that is something that you could not have just easily
predicted it's very
strong result but it's not something that
you say intuitively oh yes of course it follows immediately from the conservation of mechanical
so if i release it that that two and a half radius point by the
way somewhere here
so if i release this object
way below that
it will not make this point
let's do that
you see didn't make it go to the higher
didn't make it
go higher to make it
a little higher
still didn't make it
i go to the two and half mark
and now to make it
two and a half times the radius
conservation of mechanical energy tells you that that is the minimum it takes to just
go through that point
of course if if there were no loss of energy at all
there were no mechanical energy loss that means if there were no friction
and if i were to release it at this point
it would have to make it back to this point again
with zero
kinetic energy but the that one that's not the case there is always a little
bit of friction with the
track one thing and also of course with air
so if i release it all the way here
you would not expect it that it
bounds of all the way to here will probably stop somewhere there may not even
make it to the and we can try that
made somewhere to hear a little lower than that level
because there is some
friction that
an avoidable
all right
this is the classic one
many exams where this problem is being given i will give it to you this
time but it's a classic when you see it on the general exams of for
and it's simply a matter of conservation of mechanical energy
that's not a good situation whereby a and b are so far apart
that the gravitational acceleration is no longer a constant and so you can no longer
simply say
that the difference in potential energy between point b and point a is simply and
so now we are dealing with
very important
concepts and that is
the gravitational force
you can think of the earth
acting on
or you can think of the song
on a planet
whatever you prefer
but that's what i want to deal with when the distances and
very large
let me first
give you the formal definition of gravitational potential energy
the formal definition is
that the gravitational potential energy at a point p
it is the work that i will tell you wouldn't have to do to bring
that mass
from infinity
to that point p
now you may say that's very strange that in physics there are definitions
which were waterloo in comes in well we can change it to gravity
because my forces always
the same forces gravity was a minus sign so is also minus the work that
gravity does
when the object moves from infinity to that point p i just like to think
of it it's easier for me to think of it as the work that i
so if
we apply that
we first have to know
what is the gravitational force
this is an object capital and then you can think of this as being the
earth if you want to
there is he an object little and
then you have to know
what the forces are between the two and this now is the
is newton's
universal law of gravity
which he postulated
he says the force
that little and experiences
this force
equals i'll put little and here in the capital and you so it is little
an experiences that forces due to the presence of capital and
he calls little
times capital and find a constant which newton in his there is no no yet
what the value was
divided by
are squared
if are
is the distance
between the two
this object since newton's third law holds
actually equals minus reaction
this force
which is
o indicated as capital little and it is the force that this one experiences due
to the presence of this one
it is exactly the same in magnitude but opposite in
direction and that is the universal law
gravity is always
gravity sucks that's the way to think of it always attracts there's no such thing
as a repelling forces
the gravitational constant g
is an extremely low number six point six seven
times ten to the minus eleven
in our
as i units which is newton's gram meters per kilogram or something like that
that's an extremely low number
it means that if i have
two objects which are each one kilogram
which are
about one meter apart which i have now here about one meter
that the force
which they attract each other
is only six point six seven times ten to the minus eleven newton's
it is an extremely small
this water of
and i am here this is my mass
when i experience
the force
which is given by this equation this would be than the mass of the
of the earth
now because i made
so if i need you experience
the gravitational acceleration
and the gravitational acceleration of the experience
it is therefore given
by ng divided by are squared
you could abstractly think of being associated with nodes in the graph so
one is to predict the category of an object based
obviously on its attributes but also based on
it's like maybe the number of links the degrees something about the structure
attributes of linked objects
objects that are linked to
objects that are
link to and so on
so there's rich
kind of feature construction the potentially has to happen in order to get these attributes
the you're going to use for making predictions
and so that's like
the simplest
kind of application
as are all type task
another one that's
obviously very closely related is object type prediction so
here again you want to make use of attributes of linked and the link objects
but maybe it's that actually the object is the different types of might have a
different structure so if you think trying to
the type of a publication whether conference papers journal or workshops each of those will
have different attribute
so if for example you're doing information extraction
and i figured out that the journal then i should try and get the volume
number and the issue number
and so on
verses if i figured out the conference proceedings then i need other kinds of information
so but still the actual label
object type is very much like
classification object so
this is the simplest set up and now one of the things that interesting
in the case of statistical relational learning
is the fact that you're not going to predict
these things in isolation
but you have a whole
a collection of objects
there are unlabelled
you have to optimize over the labels of all of the objects that one so
you're not doing one shot classification but you need to do this kind of collective
classification this happens in the number of the all problems that you need to do
a kind of joint
optimisation two
solve the interesting inference problems
so the link prediction
again he has
can be associated with the kind of edge
the task so one is as simple as
you know that analogy
putting a label on an object is putting a label on lake so i know
these two
people are related by the friends did they go to school together you know
what the relationship
a second type is just
predicting the existence of the link so in the first case i know there's a
link i'm trying to put a label on that actually is a much easier problem
to do well
because you conditioning on the existence of the link verses
predicting whether between two arbitrary
they are authors whether or not they published a paper together that can be harder
to predict but it's one
people want to do all the time
you know you're trying to figure out how do these two people know each other
and then
a third one that
and i been useful in a number of situations is
predicting the the number of links
predicting citation counts for example and it's interesting to
keep in mind that this really
is a different task
in different inference task then
doing the link existence prediction now if you have a model that predicts link existence
obviously you could just some over
all possible length
but if you know that you don't have to actually
distinguish between
you know who someone
publishers with her salon in may be better to build the model that directly just
as the cardinality estimation
you know that's the model that potentially at a much higher level of abstraction he
may be able to
get a more robust
and estimate
this and so you should keep in mind when
you're doing this what you're goal is
these are
the edge
kind of task