whatever it is I'm not saying you have to use last year's data by any means its an example
of what you might use in building a prior
but but the mathematical point is either of these choices still leads you
to the same position but you're not combining the data
you can either combine them completely or not at all but you can't do anything inbetween and the effects are
simply that you slightly regularize the estimates so
for example
hospital A we really annoyed about this cause it had this perfect rate before
alright it had this perfect
didn't kill anybody before but now these bayesians are telling us
we a new mortality rate because
bringing in the prior information is reflecting the platform they were a bit lucky they didn't do
very many of operations there were a bit lucky to to to to
they were a bit lucky to get away with it
let me get back to this point I'm not for a minute suggesting this is a serious analysis of
this data I'm trying to show you the the the implications of different styles
of modelling
and of course if you were really in the position of monitoring public health you you'd
take the process of a prior choice very seriously
which is best well neither of those is best really they both have problems
cause you only got the data from hospital I used in inferring theta I
here's a here's a slightly different way to think about it
let's imagine that
twelve hospitals are not the only hospitals in the world these twelve hospitals are themselves
a sample from a collection of hospitals
and that
across that collection of hospitals there is variation of theta I
so that's one way one way to give a concrete
as it were interpretation of what a prior distribution might mean it's really a
it's not a it's not just a degree of belief now it's a model about variation
across the different hospitals
let's suppose we take this beta distribution we'd we'd be in the same position
of how do we choose values for Alpha and Beta Well there's circle empirical bayes approach
I'll say a liitle bit more about this tomorrow where you get your Alpha and Beta
From analyzing this year's data
so you do something like this I'm not advocating this in the details are not important but
take something like this year's data you you summerize you'd find means and variations means and variances
and you'd you'd you'd use that
that observed empirical variation in the
mortality rates as a guide to the population variation in hospitals
sounds like a sort of sensible thing to do
and the difficulty with it mathematically and
in in principle is that you're using the data twice you'd be essentially using the data
to decide you prior and you use that that
prior to analyze the data and so each bit of data comes into the analysis twice and the effect of
that is is is a bit like saying we got twice as much data
as we really have
but of course you have more data you have less variation so the effect is that you're going to estimate
how precise you really are
so the the the hierarchical approach avoids all these horrible pitfalls it it avoids
you having to take the extreme view about whether hospitals are separate or all the same and it
avoids you recognizing the differences in what without counting data twice
and what it comes to is saying there's another level of variation here
there are only three levels of variation
it's not just parameters and data there are three levels
the actual hazard of this kind of operation how how dangerous is this operation
we don't know so that's uncertain
OK so that's a random variable
then this variability in the actual rate but a particular hospital
has practised
so some particular hospitals might be more or less risky because they have
you know the surgeons have better practice or worse practice whichever it is
and then this chance factors the individual patient's outcome
you know even if you know
that theta is exactly point zero seven that doesn't predict the actual outcome for
any single
single baby so we have three real levels of variation and the idea of hierarchical modeling
is to model those three as random variables and put them all together so the approach in this case
might be to put priors on Alpha and Beta
so Alpha and Beta are the are the parameters that describe the population variation
population of hospitals that that variation in in the individual
mortality rates
and we put priors on alpha and beta themselves there're three levels of the model
and that the effect of that is that you get so what we call it borrowing a
strength it provides a principled way
of sharing information between the different hospitals because we don't know what alpha and beta is
but the you know the first eleven hospitals
lead to us learning something about alpha and beta and that information propagates down
to things we say about the twelfth hospital
so this is a common theme in physical modeling that we think about
variation properly at different levels and certain we consider adding an extra layer and that
the effect of that is to have a system have a method a
mathematical method for sharing information across
across units
now I don't wanna say very much about graphical models cause cause Martin is going to next week but
but these these these different choices can be symbolized
by these pictures these are called directed acyclic graphs in these pictures the circles are
variables that we you know we
the random variables that we don't know and also eventually things like
the data that we'll at some point know and the the the blocks the squares represent
replication the plates as they're called
and these these are the different these are the different situations and so the hierarchical model is
numbers that are really they belong a
don't belong to the set at all no matter fuzzy are not so the degree
of membership is zero numbers really nicely in between a and b
strongly belong to that set to a degree of one but somewhere here have to
this so-called all we don't quite know a number here just tiny tiny tiny bit
smaller than a still belongs to the set roughly in a b is would say
this has a degree of membership of one point nine so this is what the
this is this is it was the idea of fuzzy sets to model it using
membership functions the membership function that assigns elements the degree of membership so now you
can say an element belongs to the set to a certain degree not it's not
in and out but it can also be in the world and that we could
go back to this age example said all young people someone who is thirty years
and one day
OK he's underrated degree i don't know point nine five something that that chance to
decline a little bit and push this mid-life crisis out just a tiny bit
but but
OK so if you remember membership function that would already be
good interesting very very values are things when you try to model concepts that actually
have meaning like this age example
linguistic variable is very of labelled domain of the fuzzy sets something like age use
hominid how many many years does somebody have
this government is so to speak linguistic values of the labelled connection fuzzy sets understanding
so an example would be we have age car in this environment two fuzzy sets
and old could looks
this is an example that always needs to be adjusted for the audience so you
all again
something like that if that's our linguistic variable x
and we have are trying to figure out genius years and trying to
determine degrees of membership for the set of young people and for the set of
old people this you can see the they i shows the right now on the
something we can choose ourselves i'll get back to that in a second better example
will say everybody who's below thirty seven thirty is definitely young is not
an inch not a little tiny bit old he's just that you belong to the
set of young people to one when he hits thirty starts
declining some so some forty he belongs to both sets to equal degree point five
or something and then many hits fifty nobody nobody in his right mind so consider
and that not that
tells you that i'm not yet fifty
OK because of the same size as a tiny bit more interesting have three membership
functions and i just shows this example state of course these here the degrees of
membership obviously add up to one that's not something that we need to require you
can justify your membership functions any they you wish would have something size small medium
tall OK someone who's below a hundred and fifty centimetres considered small somewhere between a
hundred and fifty eight hundred ninety he gradually ceases to be small becomes more sort
of medium size and then that under nineteen would say OK everybody above is definitely
tall not medium small
but should raise questions
but i mean i mean it
we are doing this would work but i mean what about a basketball player boss
basketball player you certainly wouldn't consider one hundred ninety centimetre tall basketball player tall basketball
and those guys hardly ever make it to the NBA so for basketball players this
thing would completely different maybe start everybody below a hundred and eighty impossible really small
he will not make actually there are people come forward to something there's some there's
usually one value can be a little bit smaller impossible then you have people so
the film and eighty to twenty twenty there's sort of medium everybody about above twenty
twenty may be considered tall basketball players you see those guys that's probably even considers
but the same now is to look at this time for basketball players but but
what the jockey try to imagine someone with hundred twenty centimetres in racing horse
so for jockeys this thing is going to be very very different probably have something
like that medium jockey is probably somewhere in the range from fifteen sixteen and everybody
above finances is definitely considered tall so that tells you that how we define these
tables and chairs the those linguistic variables and is that has context dependent depends on
the context depends on what you are trying to model i'm trying to model long
snails fast race cars fast trucks it's a completely different scale again
remember the same expression appeared in step one
and is equal to
this down here we just like that in
and now we're just adding up over distribution so the sum over distribution is one
we just get productivity
OK and the third step we're trying to upper bound the training air
we already have a bound on the training year in terms of the product of
the normalization factors so now it turns out we can just compute
the normalisation constants normalization factors
directly exactly
so to see this we just write down the definition of the normalisation constant this
is its definition this is where you need to set the two so that
the sum of the weights will be equal to one
we can take the sum into two parts of the examples which are misclassified incorrectly
and now if you just look at this
this is just the weighted air
of the weak classifier which is epsilon t
and likewise the sum
is one minus epsilon t
and now if you plug in their choice of alpha t get exactly this expression
so now i can answer the question where did this
choice of alpha t come from
alpha t was chosen so as to minimize this expression we want ziti to be
because e t the product of ETS is an upper bound on the training air
so we choose alpha t in this expression to make it as small as possible
and that gives the choice about used by adaboost
and when you plug it in you get this expression
people are being extremely quiet so
please to interrupt me with questions and
kind of scary because partly it's a big group and partly and we appear on
this high stage so you know
it seems like he with a bolt of lightning or something if you ask a
question that i was OK
all right so
here i'll ask myself the question
so you just proved this theorem on training air
who cares about training year that's our learning is about learning is about minimizing the
test there
right so what can you say about the tester
that's a great question
actually usually say that's a great question what's question i have no idea what the
answer is OK
OK so how do we expect the test error behave
so here's a cartoon
we're in plotting the air of the combined classifier
the final combined classifier not the weak classifiers as a function of the number of
rounds as a function of capital t
so we just to prove this theorem that says that the training air goes down
exponentially fast
so we expect the training year to go down very very quickly exponentially fast
and what about the test error
well at first
at first we're doing a better job of fitting the training data so we expect
the test there
to also be dropping
every time
we run another round of boosting
we have one new weak classifiers to the combined classifier to the final classifier
so that combine classifiers getting bigger and bigger
and more and more complicated
so at some point we expect overfitting to send we expect this test there to
start going up
again we expect to see overfitting because they
combined classifier
like i said is becoming bigger and bigger and more and more complex
this is the entry for about this and other tutorials is
sometimes called occam's razor occam's razor is the idea that the have two
all else being equal you should prefer the simpler explanation
and learning that means that
give into me
which perform equal equally well
on your training data
all else being equal you should expect the simple one to give better predictions
now overfitting is a huge problem
it's a big problem and it comes up all the time in machine learning so
in a case like this
you really want to start training right about here to get that best test error
by your according to your training set
performance is getting better that's why it's called overfitting because things seem to be getting
better you seem to be getting the data better
when in fact things are getting worse and it makes it very hard to decide
when to stop training
so that's what we expect
here's an actual
typical run
so this is using boosting on top of c four point five
which is the decision tree learning algorithm on
a benchmark dataset called the letter dataset
and again were plotting the air of the final combined classifier
to understand the interaction of the network in order to solve the problem that's to
better understand biology
and one of the results that came out of we awoke he found in the
network motifs which are basic interaction patterns if it in the case in biological networks
this type forty but do
in the same markets
in the present a type of network future NATO form but at the moment so
if you know if you know for example in one
in fact if for example you can learn also
about the motives in my and and learn more about the understanding that the biology
for biological network which is also scale free was probably about she also is metabolic
network port au port network and this is the structure of the structure is very
complicated so we need to understand such complex networks in the to understand the biology
another example
it is a common design that which was also published by gordon bible-bashing and other
in two thousand seven
you can see what they did is it took a day in diseases
a the supremes and the links if the gene the same gene
a are influenced by moses and you can see by these because he for example
that you can group the diseases and you can find it all counts are actually
grouped in one place and that that this is another and you can learn more
about genes which actually a cause diseases and this i think is important for many
seem very important from this and so this is in biology and medicine
and we go to social network i don't have to speak not because yes the
very nice talk by rats and and he gave them together as example but for
example what learned last years in the few years last few years by papers in
nature and PNAS
by these people
is that if if you have community structure is usually goes like this that you
have small groups subgroups of people are connected to each other
very much and small it's only few connections to other groups and you can see
this is the forms of same form a network you can see the groups you
can only really coming out this according to ships and the people that i put
together they also so this is a complex structure of network and we have to
in order to understand better the social
systems you have to understand the network structure and this can pass better find that's
sort this is the figure actually that duncan watts sure yesterday which is the importance
of the networking social you can see for example the possibility to make a friend
if you if you have a if you have a if they are friends of
your friend is much i know that if they are not so the father in
the middle the closer of the ability to be a friendship and the father who
goes down in this wood is very important for
so shall
understanding of such systems
so this example is social network and show you another example
of global climate what can be learned something from the network first of all you
can see this is a typical network in in in USA the network of line
and this is the the distribution which means the number of lines the number of
lines that go form one city
so this is the degree and p of k the number of a
cities that have a degree of hundred for example and this is normalized and this
is the scale free degree distribution and lambda is around one point eight
can use this to predict something and this was shown in the paper nice paper
like all its own vespignani PNAS two thousand six
and they actually use the network
is the
and use the network an epidemic models
and if you as an academic more than and you want to see the epidemic
starts in the epidemic spreads and and that's what we found so they took a
network network and they make the model of epidemics and they found that they can
explain the can predict the principle road
this house epidemic started in in
eleven two thousand three will it be affected so for example the u
is the correct prediction of outbreak the outbreak was and this is then simply using
the airline network
global and will now correct prediction of outbreak and also correct prediction of not like
this other line that lies the only places where they do not predict well
is there a green places here where they incorrect predictions predictions so you can see
that actually one can use maybe this type of work and maybe to include also
the network the transportation like like
in their cars and all these things in order to better understand it
epidemics spreading and maybe to try to prevent it if you know the network which
causes the problem you can maybe also use some restrictions on transportation and to make
it not that it will not be the case where the
in use of network and application
it is related to transport and it will be somebody that comes out is on
the line it will be possible and the question is now
it can be improved transport
how can we make a simple food we need to improve transport improve all way
on the past all the links and nodes all these a subset of nodes which
is very important for full full a for the network which is critical to use
tool to improve maybe i want to claim to show you that there is such
a subset and if you can identify which is not difficult to prove this subset
is very small and this carries most of the ground transport in the middle so
first let me explain that the passport is very much related to the concept which
is called the minimum spanning tree
i mean it was running three
this is a network let's you meaning for me and and these are the right
the network you and the weights and then let's them now as it was for
with increasing frequency
if my frequency increases
the wavelength increases which is something absurd we always think that if
the frequency increases that the wavelength will gets shorter well i mean by that is
not the case
that is what dispersions
is all about
i can create
a pattern like this was to wait for you which i will do
and i do that in the graphical sense
that i have
two transparency is one transparency is
black bars on its many as you will see shortly
and they have separation the
and i have many of them
maybe on hundred i count
and have another transparency
which has
bars which are five percent
and also the opening between them
five percent larger
so here we have
one point o five t
and i line these up
so this is the very first all my sheet
this is number one
and this is number one
so they line up
this one
the opening the separation is five percent larger
what it means when i read here
all my sheet
number twenty
then i read here number nineteen
but they are again on top of each other
they are in phase so to to speak
so my number twenty
coincides with number nineteen year because
this one
five percent larger spacing the wavelength is five percent larger
that means halfway in between
the black lines rule
from this seat well exactly
the clips
he opens
of this one
so these black ones here
o codes to use the astronomical
phrase all called the openings and so this whole central portion will do black
black will be on top of light light will be impossible black and likely to
apply here however
it's back to what it was here
so you're beginning to see this kind of pattern think of this for now
as being dark
and single this now
has been white
this kind of pattern is what you're going to see if i put it to
transparency is on top of each other
as i will do very shortly
now comes the wonderful thing
not only will you see such pattern
but imagine now
that i move one of these should eighty appreciate
over the distance half the
so i moved it only over this distance
remember year
the black ones swirl coffee
the open once but if i shift by half the
it will be reversed
the black ones will no longer called
he open ones
and so this whole black area will instantaneously turn light again
that means
that is overall pattern
moves twenty times faster
then the motion
of one of these sheets
if i move this sheet
over the full distance the
this entire pattern that you see here which i think of as being the group
moved twenty times faster
and that's what i'm going to show you
the reason why i get twenty times of course because i have chosen
wavelengths to be five percent part
i'm going to give them a different
phase velocity
the first thing that i want to do is to give them the same phase
you see those two sheets on top of each other
i e mark one with the red mark and one was the remark
i think the blue one is the one that has five percent
larger spacing
and you see exactly what i predicted you see those dark bands
so this idea is here
these are the areas the dark areas where the
black bands of one of course opening of the other
and then in between you see
like here
you seems like there
if i can manage to move them both
with the same speed
so i think confirmed in in my hand
and i'm going to move them both with the same speed
that the bars
individual bars move exactly the same speed
the whole para
so that means the group velocity
and the phase velocity at the same tried it once more there we go
i from in my hands
so you see the group velocity and phase velocity at the same
now i'm going to move one relative to the other watch closely
i'm going to move one relative to the other you can see by the
you can tell by the by comparing the red spot was the blue spot
after lines look compared to red blood was the blue spot you can see the
relative motion
and moving them now
look how fast the group velocities compared to
the motion between the two you can actually hardly see
that the red one is moving relative to the blue one you can hardly see
but look how fast the group velocity is you see that
twenty times faster
you see how to read one separates from the blue one of the very low
speed that the phase velocity
it's the difference between the phase velocity that's really what i should have said the
difference between the face
and so then the group velocity goes
twenty times faster
so now i want to return to are continuous strings
when we
delta was continuous strings
we derive the wave equation
and i still remember how we derived it
we took into account that the tension is responsible for the restoring force
well you started from
again if the state space is finite that means that you should
to get anywhere
with probability one
of course if you have a finite state space if the chain is irreducible
because there is only number of finite number of
places you can go to of states you can go to
two of the positive pretty go somewhere is like having your
but you want to go to this place
the the world outside finite state space
and so
in the discrete state space
rec around means that
was number
of the
two estate
is infinity and transience
it is
that the average number of visits
two us they
two state is fine
in other words after
seven times
you never come back
to this state omega
in the going space
you just have to replace all media bias set a which dataset a
positive measure
your state a is wrecker and is that if starting from any x the number
of visits to your state is infinite
is transient if it's finite and when the chain is irreducible
the set of the same probably so they are all current
all chains
which makes him funny because
if you think that if you have a finite number of visits to the set
what the chain has to go somewhere else but if the space is continuous admitted
go farther and farther away and after one doesn't come back to this entry started
this is the one of the purposes of of infinity
redcurrants mean that
the the expected number of visits to the set
infinity there's something slightly stronger is called harris recurrence and i mentioned it because this
is the central notion for the ergodic theorem for the law of large numbers and
harris recurrence as you know that's slightly stronger
because not only is the expectation is infinite but
the value of the random bible number of visits to the set a is itself
of course it's it's strong
the probability that the number of visitors infinity is one method you come over and
over and over again and about all firing time you should
to come back to our set a for every set a
well this is course
now we write level that
of stability
that there
that if the chain is recurrent
it was just exploring space
in a kind of regular way that is after wall you visit set a and
afterwards to the set a kind of
stability that if you're on your chain a long time
we have
the picture
the support
of of your change
OK and you want to know
it with with regular monte carlo method this stabilisation as a kind of frequency
that you can work with this and this is linked with the national
of environment mission
your change is stable if it is reckoned it would be even more stable
hostettler are if it has an invariant measure and for measure
which is such that if you apply the kernel
to the measured
you get the sense
OK so if i should start
measuring your sets with the major part of your reply the transition
two your face
only get to measure
because it is difficult to understand if i is not the probability measure if by
the probability measure is just tells do that if you start from
i'm trying to work to
no matter what and is if you if you find distribution by time and your
destination by
at time n plus one and of course
over and over
after a time and
in the distribution by
once you have it
the decision
and this
should probably that is linked with and that if you have a
probability measure
that is in band for a chain of oil biochemical because kind of property it
tells you that
it is the fixed point four k
mike is equal to pi
if if i suppose measure that necessarily
recurrent change and you cannot have
trying to change that has the property measure as invariant distribution
so in that case we say that the chain is positive records
the trick is that if there exists an invariant measures
that is not a probability measure so it is sigma finite it is an infinite
you must have the transition
chain markov chain may be transient and enjoy an environment measure and if it example
is the random walk in dimension three
if you have are working mission three
it is transient so it would go to infinity but the measure
is environment
in dimension two it is recurrent and the back measure is inference
but not for
we just focus on this case
she we use we use markov chain that offers achieve wrecker
now just
from reason why we link the existence of invariant measures and monte properties of the
often frequencies y so important for political purposes
do that if there exists an invariant measure
it is not the remaining resume monk
range properties of your change that if you run your change long enough and the
if there is invariant measure
you will get close to the invariant measure
and the reason why
is simply a fixed point property
in the limit to the issues that from the
arbitrary measure
and if you run your change p is not k but it should be k
if you're on your kernel
ten times
and if you take n going to infinity and and in the limit
the two called gamma mu of a
you start from you
so important is actually something that is not
often mentioned
but is important
is that
even assuming
you would be able to sample what exactly
formed was still distribution of
clearly because the number of viable
your interest probably we would increase with
then you could the computational complexity of the algorithm for sample from that would increase
i mean sampling was always going to be inelastic but it expensive and sampling like
then followed
so it is important because it means that
we learn
if you could
from four
from this exactly
then that would already solved problem
the problem is that you want to come up with an algorithm to estimate the
sequence of distributions which are the kind of fixed computational complexity of time
to summarize
we have hold
we cannot use the full name of the cult sampling
i don't want to sample from p
x one n y one
on even if i couldn't that wouldn't some
i would also problem because i would like to come up with algorithm
so as to approximate the with computational complexity does increase the time index
so we need to come out
we need to solve part
and for going to tackle the problem
on then we'll discuss that later on
the first problem that is because i'm unable to form or
from the both help x one n y one n
i to come up with an alternative method of the element of the day
so what do i do
and then use a method called importance sampling
this method
it relies on the production
of the looks you i
o point distribution
which is defined in the same space
i the first l distribution of and so what i'm doing and how important it
was OK
point distribution who q which is different from the which is a function of of
x one x two x
the notation doesn't mean is it was still distribution you just means that is the
probability distribution which would find it can depend on your television to keep in mind
thing that i mean the without permission if you want to cite the fact that
i myself web oaks distribution dependent
on the television one for example this information would be i dimensional gaussian distribution of
even by the the
only the
which is diagonal with
that's important
so these started i distribution
i'm gonna ask
i want to add properties
i want to to be such that
the support of q
includes all of the target distribution
that is wherever
the first division i'm interested in is it i want to make sure
also i would be is all over the way i would yes
i want you to have some positive
the very simple one
but i still think the problem
is that
i'm going to pick two
so is that it is very easy
to obtain realization
so where i might be impossible or
in or for these guys
because of this women is probably where i was one of the i'm going to
select the u
from which it very easy to obtain one demoralization
so for example you could pick
divide gulshan mean given by y
on go and
which is you know
you can do but you pick it so that
you know what we're all in this
that's important
on the this the way
what we're have to do is is going to be very careful in the design
of the
OK so we've got this distribution
i'm not going to use and i don't know
which is based on the basis of on opening
what i want to commit suicide at some point you
there's already know nothing technical about it
this because i don't think we need to introduce something which is called an problem
on importance weight
is a function of both
the basic components on the validation uneasy called
the joint distribution of x and y
divided by the
distribution q
all these guys well first
i thing these things you can compute it exactly
we can assign truth values to
more complex
so the constant true and false
standard top
two is always true
and so always falls
and a and b is true is true and b
and not just in case of
it's a bit unusual is that the last one
is this meaning or implication
so a is a implies b is true
even on a is false or a is true and b
so if
the left hand side of the arrow
it was recorded and issued a statement
is falls then the statement is true
so this is called the material implication
in assigning the truth if we need out
the truth value of the property is somewhere even
an assignment of truth values to
properties that are
so let's formalize this
concept of william beveridge
within is just mapping function like from
propositional variables to the set of traffic
now we just represents set the truth so year in one
zero mean false ones
example of wooden pallets
this write it down
this mapping
for example x assigned to true white four and so on
now we say that a model
it's just within valleys and m
such that and and
so at valid true
on the validation
the valid and assigned
and you have
it about true
this is usually
with this notation
we have
because within protestantism at
so far the truth found principally in it
usually when we write down the value the only concerned that that appear in form
i find
now a formalized essentially william
describes how you assign
truth and
zero one two
form based on
the of its power
a very easy way to represent which is just to come
because the truth table
it's just this systematically all possible values that can take and calculate
the corresponding
the truth value of the context of these standards
definitions of and or
implication negation
and suppose
you want to know what's what's the behavior and become part the truth
the a x and y one to come through a and y
and it is systematically this of course classes
sounds like a
because these are billions is only
two possible values each day
so x is zero one
so on
is the unit ball
in reproducing kernel expect
so this is basically the space
of all functions if
and the product was between faith and for the next
four which holds
the norm
of data
it is less equal in one
and if i have
a so-called universal
now consider RBF kernel is one low-cost incredible is one
that's why the sock
o thing
this class of functions
is just as powerful as the at telling me with the peak was q
as these continuous function bounded functions are
well this is not because we actually have hope that
with this now
we know a lot about how to deal with kernels we can compute this quantity
so how we go about proving it
proof is actually very simple
so if people ask you well that's quite easy well and you think you zero
from training
if p is not equal q
then by the previous theorem which is due essentially derived from dudley there must be
some function for which
the expectations different
after all otherwise we would have a a contradiction to previous theorem
i don't know what the function is but there must be some function for which
this is
it's all
but since the hilbert space was universal
we can find some function the hilbert space
that is
epsilon epsilon over two close
this function which
as a witness for peanut not equal to q
and then all we have to do is we're just
so therefore i mean that expectation for if star
is also going to be greater than zero
that is now from the hilbert space
now i have to do is just shrink it back to the unit ball
that's not gonna make a nonzero quantity zero it's just gonna make it smaller but
not vanish
and thereby
it would have witness from our in polynomial space
which also
the difference of expectation between p and q
it's great to this year
that i prove it
this is great news
because what we've done is we've come up with a fairly abstract criteria
but a single distribution
we've shown that this gives us necessary and sufficient conditions
and finally we've now seen
it actually for
a very nice hilbert space
this also happens to be true
now all need to do is
empirical estimates for this qualities here
based on my data set x and y
they want to get convergence guarantees
before we do so let's make a small
which sort of the kolmogorov smirnov test
sometimes you would
musical come up smelling tasty if you have just univariate random variables you want to
with the
the two datasets are drawn from the same distribution
commencement of test is quite powerful and works well and easy to use and all
that and the most likely it's implemented in our matlab state and whatever
well let's just see whether that doesn't actually come out as a special case of
our definition
so the function class
so come made of test works in one dimension i mean the multivariate expansions but
you'll see afterwards that with this criterion that we set up
will get tastes which bits which we've done
the function class
i just real valued functions in one dimension
and let's just take all the functions with total variation less than one
so the total variation of a function
this is my functional ever
and the total variation
of a if
would be just integral
the if
absolute value of that
and what i'm going to do is i'm going to ask the question well
for this function class
what is this
distance between p and q
so i'm going to try and solve the following optimisation problems
overall the functions have
with the property that the integral
is less equal than one
the expected value
of f of x
with respect to p
minus the expected value of the q
well if it's
now this is a very special optimisation problem here
because the objective function here
is linear in n
so this clearly convex
the linear function is always convex
that's the main here
is a convex domain
you have to believe that the
you can easily check it
so what we have is
a convex maximization problem
it doesn't sound particularly impressive that been talking about convex minimization problems
all of yesterday
and i tell you how wonderful convex minimization problems
now convex maximization problems can also be very nice they can be very nice insofar
as there a theorem due to rockefeller which states
optimal solution of a convex maximization problem is found
on the vertices of the state
it's fun on the boundaries
so what this means is that if
my context i
of all functions if
rather than searching for the entire inside of that the main as well
i can focus completely
of c and this one again for the same reason by p
a might one
in the and then by my claim i know
that this is a model
so here
he the
this fact
there is some up over here and a good number of big
i set up here
and again why
the the
svm dual
four is an assignment of about
which is by weak duality upper bounded by up which is the thing over there
but that
can i can now right
the whole thing to more manageable way
by including content inside the objective is to get usually for you
all i get
big everything together to it sound
all the
one of the
that the man of one mistakes a one
is it most now i have
there i have one other means c one
which is the max
what we're seeing
and i have e
svm objective functions
we can write this
although i have
your credit plus c
some of the
that's it
but this is
the bound
on the number of mistakes of the one
in terms of the number of users couldn't you and you wanted him to build
for any value
depends on this you know
it is the two
because the school
or if the book
i had the
matched betting
this is you know this is nothing better than the perception
o to get the
just like in the perception
you will get the norm
the squared norm of being
the larger
number of the active
multiplying this guy
the viking perception you can do with
by looking at the the
by looking at the
the optimum of the SVM
i can i can bound the number of states of the one
in terms of the optimal value of the objective
this so
because by exploiting weak duality i know that i don't get with simon
now this
i have pointers
there that is this
this is a fake
now you can think of any kind of up
and that
that the
what is this
do not act on the
on a single the lagrange multiplier that he
but the then the tried to modify all the part the lagrange multipliers from one
up them
but that
is a second order kind of up
there's that
i mean you can look at
telescopic sum
and you can look
ways of
increase of lower bounding
the difference in the coping
but there are more effective than the
if you have all these that of showing you are first order up our like
gradient descent equivalent for classification and indeed they can be with with that
so you have more powerful computer up that
try to take into account the time he also
in a sense the measurement devices were found in the past
OK even if you have any more questions that they
forget repeat anyway
but you're like
i would move to
abroad in area organisation
the perceptron algorithm
which will input
you can run them in in
reproducing kernel hilbert space you maybe mention a little bit about it and then they
have a strong performance guarantees as i said because they do not need
data generation model
to be analyzed in the on the other hand you can derive stochastic risk bounds
using those online to batch conversions are going to be mentioned in the talk and
the back to natural active learning variants whenever the true label comes at the cost
you don't have it for free but you have to explicitly ask for it and
last but not least you can actually easily term in most cases you can turn
usually mistake bounds and so the analysis for online algorithms into an analysis that takes
into account the fact that the data mining be well explained by a single linear
so i i i want mentioned this but this is interesting and so this is
the case in which free cystatin is again the stream of data is such that
there is very very good linear feet for the for the first part then some
other good linear feet for the
central part and then yet another different linear feet for the part and all the
organs can be
modified in such a way that they are able to detect change points
in the the best linear feet of the stream that is facing without actually knowing
how many change points out there and the way they are situated in the stream
and of course the the
the bound you are able to prove it in this case this will depend on
the degree of most narrative of the data this is an interesting and interesting but
but i don't want to have time to cover it
OK so few
let's start by with the perceptron the perception is the simplest online learning algorithm
get a comes from the fifties was introduced by rosenblatt the to study the visual
the visual recognition abilities of the brain but is very simple linear model so you
have an initial empty weight it is the zero vector
and then we have to get this is just like that so
if you remember any
linear online learning algorithms just characterised by the
but this step here everything else is fixed and this is the only place in
which you can
you can say something we can show how the add what is the action of
the argument on the screen
OK and the update rule for the perceptron is is that is a whenever no
mistake is made on the current instance
then the weights remains the weight vector remains the same otherwise we
had the the
current distance multiplied by the label
so that's the very simple
at the true
so now
a little bit of intuition because this is
should be beneficial for for learning and so the idea is that
clearly if you're going to make a mistake
if you use the linear classifier
whenever you're margin which is that quantity over there
is negative so
whenever the inner product between the current winter clintonistas doesn't have the same sign as
the true label of course in that case you to make a mistake
so if you made a mistake in the coming to example then you want to
link then imagine was negative you want increase it to make it positive so that
you want in current state
if the same
it element comes up again industry
so now you can look at the effect of the perceptron update on on the
margin and you can easily see that
the up if the at the margin of the updated weight
is measured on the same example because the mistake on the previews with vector then
some people ask
it should be discussed in greater detail
should be the structure of proteins all touch on very briefly this morning different kinds
of bonding
tertiary and quaternary structure
condensation or dehydration reactions and in fact much of those issues should be many of
those should be addressed
in the recitation sections that's the ideal
place to begin to clarify things which although they were mentioned here
may not have been mentioned in the degree of detail
that you really need to assimilate them properly
and so i urge you
to raise these issues with the recitation sections structures that's exactly what they for
having said that i just want give back briefly into protein structure even though we
turn our back on the end of last time just to reinforce some things that
i realized i might have
i should have mentioned perhaps in greater detail
here for example are different ways of depicting
the three-dimensional structure of the protein by the way here we see that these are
beta pleated sheets in the light brown and these are alpha helix is there's two
of them here in green one going this way the other going this way a
third one going this way
and the other blue areas are not structured i e are not structure in the
sense that they are in any way obviously
alpha helix is or beta pleated sheets
here's the space filling models a space filling depiction of the protein we talked about
that last time here is a trace of the backbone of the peptide backbone of
the same protein
where the side chains are left out and obviously we're one is only plotting the
three-dimensional coordinates of each of the backbone atoms CC NCC NCC and
here is yet another way of planting exactly the same protein in terms of indicating
as we just said the structure these alveolar the other regions is the secondary structure
of this protein and here's list of fourth way plotting of depicting the same structure
of the protein
we're roughly one is depicted in the
the configuration of
i mean i said
in terms of large sausage excuse me
if one were to use space filling models we go up here so these are
just four ways of looking at the same protein
with different degrees of simplification
another point that i thought i would like to reinforce and make was the following
we talked about transmembrane proteins in the past
that is proteins which
patrol through the membrane from one side to the other
and the point that i realised i'd like to make is that if we look
at a transmembrane proteins here's one that is starting out in the cytoplasm of the
and by the way the soluble part of the cytoplasm is sometimes called the cytoplasm
here's the little a they violated we talked about it later
and here is is the extracellular domain of the same protein
now how is always organised well the fact of the matter is
we discussed the fact that this hydrophobic space in the lipid bilayer is so hydrophobic
that really doesn't like
to be in the presence
of hydrophilic molecules including in this case amino acids and what we see here is
the fact that almost all of the amino acids in this region of the protein
which is called the transmembrane region of the protein
because it reaches one side to the other are all
hydrophobic or neutral amino acids which are reasonably comfortable in the hydrophobic space of the
lipid bilayer
there happened to be two parent violators of this glutamine histidine you see these two
i mean glutamic acid is today
OK ten i guess it his today
one is negatively charged and therefore is highly hydrophilic and the other is positively charged
and is therefore hardly have highly hydrophilic and on the surface that would seem to
violate the rule i just articulated
but the fact is
the as it turns out of this particular proteins these two charges are these two
amino acids are so closely juxtaposed with one another
the positive and negative charges are used to neutralize one another and as a consequence
in fact there is no strong charging or polarity in this area
or in this area
the take-home lesson
is that somehow
proteins managed to insert themselves into remain stable in the lipid bilayer by virtue of
either using only structures of hydrophobic core
or non polar amino acids
or they use tricks like this of neutralising any charges it happened to be there
note by the way
because there are hydrophilic
i mean OS is down here
and it turned out that the hydrophilic amino acid around here arginine and here there's
a whole bunch of basic amino acids note that this keeps the transmembrane protein from
getting pulled in one direction or the other because this arginine likes the likes to
associate with the negative phosphate on the outside
of the phospholipids and the same thing is here and all that means is is
that this transmembrane protein is firmly anchored to the lipid bilayer a point we'll talk
about later in greater detail we talk about membrane structure
one other little point oh mentioned here in passing which will also get into in
greater detail
is that once a
protein has been polymerize
that polymerization is not the last thing that happens to it once it's polymerize ten
fold it into place
because we know the proteins undergo what is called post translational modifications
and as we talk about
in the coming weeks the process of synthesizing a protein is called translation
when we talk about post translational modifications
what we're talking about is opening our eyes to the possibility even after the primary
amino acid sequences but polymerize their chemical alterations that can subsequently be imposed on the
amino acid side chains to further modify the protein
one such modification by example is a proteolytic degradation
my talk about proteolytic degradation
i'm talking about the fact that one can break down of proteins
is the breaking down of protein and when we talk about degradation
we're talking about
destroying what's been synthesized
in the case of many proteins once are synthesized there may be a stretch of
amino acids one into the other that simply clipped off
therefore creating the protein which is smaller than the initially synthesized product of protein synthesis
i e the initially synthesized product of translation
here we see yet another kind of post translational modification because it turns out
that in many proteins which protrude into the extracellular space
six different modes of communication face-to-face guy
the phone
instant messaging
text thing and then combining email with social networking sites
and it's very striking if you look the top left graph there
the difference between face-to-face and sky and these other modes of communication i was actually
quite surprised how well sky because i thought it is actually to clunky
to to match face-to-face interaction but still
they're clearly much much better
more satisfying than these other
a single
modes interaction
and one of the several reasons for the we think one is the fact that both sky
and obviously face-to-face give you a sense being in the room together
that's is important co-presidents
as it sometimes called
but also its immediacy what multi-channel so you are getting many different
messages coming through quite redundancy in information you're getting but also the responses are immediately you can see
the smile beginning to
break on somebody's face has to tell a joke
is that having to wait
until you've told they read it if it's a text-based what
and this may explain why
you know jokes seem not to work terribly well
on email
the you know things that you'd fall about
laughing at t in the park you can look at it as an email
message and go
what planet available today
the comics that okay so
the suggestion is that
so the laughed that occurs in it
interactions is actually very important in mediating the sensor satisfaction or happiness you
so the middle graph here is simply the frequency have laughter
recorded in interactions either as real laughter
in cases where you can see or hear it auras
virtual laughter in the digital one side
hello saw
or something like that
and you can see that you inevitably get much more laughter in face-to-face and scott than any of the other
but the important thing here on on the right hand graph is that if you then look at
these these different media in terms the satisfaction
of those interactions relative to whether or not this
laughter curves the black bars at the top
are those interactions and laughter occurred again this is this the mean happiness
the bottom clause open squares
interactions when none of because there's a massive massive difference so
laughter seems to
interactions and hence all relationships to flow
in a very important way come back to that later
so the question is
why can
isn't it the case that
facebook opens up
an entire new
this therefore you
he also goes back to
the so called social brain hypothesis which is an explanation for why primates have particularly
large brains have much bigger brains body size any other group members by very considerable
mark margin
some of the key evidence for that's his
data like this is putting
a measuring social complexity a very simple one here
do with many different measures
this is just the average group size
first species each these
dogs is one species
and is plotted against the measured brain size
the neocortex is the critical bit so
this is the ratio of neocortex to the rest of the brain so it's sort
controlling fall
differences in total brain size really
the key
results here are there
a significant relationship between group size and relative neocortex size and there are serious and
so what i do now
while these robber robbers still in place
i think in the part
so when i take them apart the negative charge is trapped
and this positive charge
is trapped and so i have thereby
created a negative charge on this one
positive on this one and is equal in magnitude so i have the dipole
what i want to demonstrate to you is that indeed i have
the positive charge here negative here that that is the difference in polarity between these
two and that's
the way
i'll do the experiment
i will not show you that the amount of charge is exactly the same
on each which of course it has to be
so let me give you some
but i like we have to get the
u graph of overhead
you see there for the first time an electroscope
we discussed it last time it is
feasible one and four very thin
with a metal rod next to it
and when i put charge on the road will also going to be
aluminum foil
and they repel each other and so
the one in ten so will go to the right
and the more charge there is on it
the father
it goes to the right
so let me first
what is together
make sure they are completely discharged
and now
i'm going to bring
these two into an electric field
which is produced by this
rubber rod
have to rob was capped for
and i believe it was negative
but if you
you never have to remember what is negative or positive of course that is not
so important
what's in a name after all
but it happens to be negative
OK so now we go here
bring it here i hope you know sparks will fly over because the ruins the
now notice what i do rather like the role this year
i separate them
so as i was holding it there
things were going on in there and you and i couldn't see the electrons
there are always negative electrons were shifting in this direction
and this is not positive and that is no negative
if i take this one
and i touch was the electroscope
you clearly see that there is charged on this
how can i show you now
that there is
charge of different polarity on the other one
the way i will do that is i will approach this electroscope
i bring this fear very close to it
if this charge is different
then the charge that is on it
the electroscope will
the reading will become smaller
and why is that while the reading become smaller
is the situation of the electroscope now
and here
is that
all that you see on top
this is
upside down there
this is all negative
that's why apart is now i approach this year
with an object
which is positively charged and i claim that this one now is positively charged because
this one was negatively charged
electrons are afraid of the positive charge so more will go
the electrons all the positive charge so electrons want to come to the positive charge
so d electrons
drift down again
and so if they come down
if you will be here and so you'll see this
i put here
negative rods
then the electrons which are here want to go far away
they will stream up
and therefore
the reading will become larger so you can only through induction
what the polarities of your charge
let's hope that this one is still holding its charge whilst talking so i claim
now that this polarity is different
and if it's still there when i approached the electroscope come very close that the
reading should become a little smaller without even touching it
see what the works
see goes down
c goes down
goes down
so for induction i have demonstrated that this has indeed the different polarity from this
if i proceed with this one
it will go further out
and that it already is the the maximum let's try that
the same goes for about
so not only have i demonstrated that i created the dipole
but you've also seen
by means of induction
that you can demonstrate
that the
there's a difference in polarity
between the two spheres
if i create a
and i put the dipole
in a
electric field
the dipole
i will start to rotate
first talk about why rotates and then
i will try to
demonstrate that
by making the dipole they want this big
right in front of you almost as big as the one there
so let's have
the electric field
like so
and i bringing this
electric field
a dipole
this is the one i'm going to use for this demonstration
ping pong balls only decide they are conducting
and there can connected with a road which is not conducting
so he was this dipole
this rather is not conducting
this is conducting
this is a conductor
let's suppose this is positive
this is negative for now
and also how we get the charge on it
well the positive charge
will experience a force in this direction always in the direction of the electric field
and the negative charge will experience a force
always upstream
and now to work on this
and the user talk on this dipole it will start to rotate clockwise
and of course
if it overshoots the field lines
well it is in this direction the program reverse
it's very easy to see
so what you'll see is going to oscillate and if there is enough then thing
it will come to hold more less in the direction of the field one
and this is something that i can
i have two
a dipole
of this kind and the way i will do that is the following
this is no more
it is into later
and here
is this
as these two ping pong balls
the one on this side
as yellow mark early on that site
as an orange marker
and i'm going to attach them
holding them up against this metal board
in other words
here is
this dipole it's not the dipole yet
mental mental
and here is the metal bar it is a conductor
which connects them
then you can simply search
and we found say thousand documents
and stop
and chances are pretty good that you'll see
you get the same results as the research full index is not guaranteed a heuristic
notice that none of the major web search engines like you see past the thousand
so you can never prove whether they're doing this or not
it's it's a clever that's one of the several reasons why
the only see past thousands and this is one of them is that you can
you can optimize it
for this case but if you let people see past that the keeping things consistent
people can find out cheating
and not also distributed search
you read that down
where you can
have a bunch of nodes on the network each which are searching different collections
so we partition the database by document
and the new broadcast query to all of these
and collect the top ten results
and then display the top scorer
so standard
distributed search
that has some
ambitious scalability goals
especially for an open source project where we want to scale the entire web
pages on millions of servers billions of pages overall
complete calls can take weeks to run
the data is very noisy there's lots of badly formed HTML out there
lots of servers that are going to be malicious various ways
it also needs on the search side support very high-traffic you'd like to be able
support thousands of searches per second
like the search quality to be
state of the art
this is
obviously you steep thing if you look at the
the number of people it takes to meet these goals at that google yahoo it's
hundreds if not thousands of people etc so it's it's
big process
so we will probably not going to do quite as well as they doing right
but it's something to aim for
maybe over time we'll catch up
so to meet these goals some some sort of simple performance numbers
we this this is roughly what we've we've hit
we can crawl around one hundred pages second on CPU which means you can get
about ten million pages a day
machine that's
and this by adding more machines you can you can scale
we can update the database of what we've seen that about a hundred pages seconds
well that's we can keep up
and so that's the rate that it takes to pass
the page and then after that both of those required
and then for searching it depends on
this is how much traffic you have how how you want to lay things out
if you
if you if you had two million pages per no then you might get forty
searches per second or better even if you're doing index sorting
twenty million pages per node and you might get one service per second depends on
how many notes you have the how much
traffic you want to have a collection of this
time space tradeoffs there
but the is former looks
or is it reasonable it's not
we're in the right ballpark and all these to scale to billions
you know we're certainly within an order of magnitude of what what i think anyone
out there
it would google in our
in terms of the the base performance
we you we may only be we maybe twice as slow or something like that
would not usually off
so let's all get
so that's sort of where we were initially
and we have a few places where we we things were
there are some serial bottlenecks and we get a demonstration of a hundred million web
but it didn't really
scale easily to billions of pages
it was
running more than three running four machines
doing crawl and then running search with a full-time job
and if you had you know twenty machines that we would have been very hard
to really take advantage of them we we didn't have the tools to manage things
the space allocation got to be really really tricky dicky in copying files around looking
we're just full
so we were effectively limited for single user two hundred million pages what's in didn't
seem very good
started a new project
to solve this problem
if we want to get past a hundred million pages how do how do we
do it
this project is called hadoop started from the beginning of this year it was spun
out of some work that have been started within within such
and it's a platform for distributed computing
and the sort of distributed computing that we need for
for information retrieval tasks
and it's become the foundation for all of the
core operations
so how did has
two major subsystems the distributed filesystem GFS
which is modelled after google's GFS
and the quick overview the architecture of a single name no
that's on the on the network and it maintains the mapping file names to the
list of blocks that compose file
and then it also keeps the mapping from the block idea
two hosts that that can that have shown that block
support pair so it's very not very simple just these two tables and then
is equal to one over are square are is the distance between these two charge
groups obviously the further apart you get the weaker the attraction with one another
there are also what are called van der waals interactions
these are largely of interest
a very small community
of biochemists
you will probably never you may never hear this term beginning your life and then
towards interactions comes from the fact that if we were to have
for example two molecules over here which are not normally charge anyway let's just talk
about two
aliphatic chains again
and i will put in all the protons and everything but just imagine a situation
like this
what will happen is that because the fluctuations
of electrons because the electrons are swimming around here all the time moving from one
area to the next
there never
equally distributed homogeneously over a long period of time there will be brief instants in
time micro seconds or even nano seconds when there's
this happens to be more electrons over here the right here
just by chance
and this area of on air unequal distribution of electrons will in turn induce
the opposite kind of electron shift in neighbouring molecule down here
obviously depending on the distance between them but it the negative here will repel electrons
down here the positive here will attract electrons down here so you have these two
clauses i polar
arrangements here and here
very ephemeral
that is lasting for very short transition period of time but nonetheless sifts sufficient to
give a very weak interaction between these two molecules
which may persist only for microsecond then be dissipated because the charges then redistributed once
and as a consequence of that one has very weak interactions which in the great
scheme of things play only a very minor role
the overall energy which holds molecules together
now with that background my let's begin to elaborate on on how we can make
i have interesting properties that enable them among other things to participate in the construction
of lipid bilayers
which will be the first object of our attention still in terms of actual
biochemistry so here's a
here's the fatty acid
we see that up here i don't affect through the structure of the fatty acid
up here already once before
and what we can see is through a
a linkage notice esterification
we can create this molecule
so what do i mean by esterification
well in this case
we're talking about a situation here
where we have the carbon atom over here
like this with a hydroxyl group you see it over here and what we're doing
is we're dehydrate in this were pulling out one molecule of water and each time
we do that on three separate occasions
what we end up doing is to create
instead of this
is to create a a covalent bond
between these two and so the
the product of of the hydrating this
pulling out one net molecule of water
is that we end up with a a structure that looks like this
and you see that happening
on atleast three different occasions
here here and here
well actually i put carbon over here
so here we have
three esterification
a hydroxyl group in each case is reacting with the carboxyl group here
pulling out one water
and in each case creating a what's called try
try a sort glycerol or triglyceride
triglyceride refers to the fact that we start with the glycerol and and we have
now is terrified
in fact there are two there are two directions here in this kind of reaction
esterification is the kind of linkage we just showed here
and the truth is that vast numbers of biochemical linkages are made by esterification reactions
and reversed by
reactions that are called simply hydrolysis
and in this case we are referring to was the fact that if one were
to reintroduce a water molecule in each of these three linkages one two and three
we would break the bond and caused this entire structure to revert
the two precursors that existed or pre-existing
prior to these three esterification reactions
and time and again you'll see over the next weeks the esterification reactions are important
for constructing different kinds of
of molecules
now the fact of the matter is we can do other kinds of modifications of
a way
the glycerol like this here what we've done instead of adding a third fatty acid
no what was done here here through an esterification
let's look at this one here
instead of adding a third fatty acid we're saying we reserve one of the three
groups of glycerol
here's what we shot just before we've saved one of the three groups the glycerol
and put on instead
this highly hydrophilic phosphate groups
once again through a dehydration reaction an esterification reaction
and now what we've done is an insult to injury because in the absence of
this who had a hydroxyl here which is
mildly hydrophilic
but now
look how strongly charge this is here's two negative charges one electronic and this is
already the electronegative so here we have an extremely potent hydrophilic entity
and here the degree of schizophrenia between one and the molecule and the other is
greatly exaggerated
here in fact this is extremely high hydrophilic
and as a consequence of that is really likes to stick its head inside water
and when we therefore talk about we draw the the images of different kinds of
like this i showed you before the two tails
here saw that the tales i grew before in the diagram
here so what we can imagine they actually look like
in more real molecular terms
and the hydrophilic heads sticking in the water
this is just repeating what we saw before
become even more hydrophilic
if we look at a molecule like this let's look at this thing here here's
a very long hydrophobic tails
here's the two glycerol once again here's the phosphate
and keep in mind the phosphate obviously has these extra oxygen is fast we can
react with more than just one partner the glycerol down here in this case we
had this group appear
so I come from the Empirical Inference Department which I think is a nice term
for what we are doing in machine learning it refers to the process of drawing
conclusions from empirical data from observational data and one example of such conclusions is something
we we do as scientists we we do the scientific inference so we measures some data
points let's say we have two observables X and Y
we have two observables we measure pairs of these observables
let's say we find this kind of relationships than we might be tempted to say
it looks like there's a linear law connecting these two observables
but lately it's already pointed out the philosopher of mathematician latence that even
if you
I mean in this case you can maybe come up with a linear law but even if
you randomly produce points on a sheet of paper for instance by taking an ink
acquittal pen and just shaking it so you get some randoms point you will also
find some mathematical expression that somehow
more or less explains the data points
so if you have these random points here you might come up with more
complicated solution it might even be a curdle expansion that we will talk about more in
this lecture and then the question comes up why should we trust
the one solution more than the the other is there anything that allows us to justify why we
trust something
and are there any infor any general principles how to arrive at such at such solutions
now I mentioned this is a from the scientific inference and of course scientists do this all the time
and they have their own ways of handling it and this is a quote from the
physicist Rutherford who once said if your experiment needs statistics you ought to have done a better experiment
so this is the the enemy of machine learning and first machine learning didn't exist at
that time
so he's basically saying that data point should be such that the inference what is
the law
from the data point should be trivial so the real problem is producing the right
data not producing inference from data and of course we are specializing in inference
from data so we want to convince people that nowadays this is different and in
the sence even from our point of view the interesting part is hard to do
the inference from data now here is a second example of empirical inference this is from the field
of perceptions but this is also something that we do all the time
as animals
and here are some visual patterns that we have no problem recognizing this is one
of the favorite data sets of machinery people the US Postal Service
set of hundred digits and
so if you see these digits you have no problem assigning them to the correct class
however just to show you that this is actually not such a trivial inference problem
if I apply a permutation to the digits
and this is the same fixed permutation I'm just changing the pixels
apply the same fixed permutation everywhere
I get these kind of patterns that have the same information
but now it's difficult to assign them to the classes maybe you can still see that the
zeros look a bit different from the threes
but it's it's no longer trivial to recognize these patterns so this means that
well or one of the explanations for this and maybe the main explanation is that this
appears trivial to us because we've been trained on this kind of patterns for a
long time
so we've been trained on the contiguous smooth patterns in general and also specifically on
on hand written digits we've been trained a lot so for us it's easy to recognize these but it's not so trivial to recognize
these even if we were given a sizable training set and for a machinery algorithm
unless you do something very clever and try to add prior knowledge these problems are
in principle the same because these images are normally represented as vectors
so far machinery algorithm this is as hard as this one and we can tell
this one isn't isn't actually that easy
to begin with
and there is famous neuroscientist actually once said that brain is nothing but a
statistical decision organ so
we have different organs the heart is a pump and the brain is our statistics engine
so from that point of view I think we have a neuroscientist here I think
very good to have neuroscientist here because if we want to understand what the
brain is doing and if it's true that the brain is a statistical decision organ
then we need to understand statistics and the inference
so this so this second example was an example of a relatively hard inference problem
and I'll say a little bit more about what I mean by this before I show you another hard inference
problem which is from more standard machinery problem nowadays from bioinformatics so in this case
the task is to
is a classification task on human DNA sequences
so you can use portions of the DNA sequence to predict or classify certain things
in this case it's a three-way classification problem maybe you don't have to worry about the
biological details but it's a classification problem from which we can get label data
so we can perform biological experiments to check which of the three classes our piece of
DNA sequence belongs to and we can produce a large
training set and then
train some machine and system on it and it doesn't matter so full of I want
to make what system it is and also doesn't matter exactly what error measure we use
or what correctness measure we use the only point I want to make here is
this is a program where we have up to fifteen million training points over here
and if we use few training points where few means let's say a thousand or less
then our performance is more or less zero so we are more or less at chance level that this is certain kind of error
measure and if we use a lot of training points and we can
be very accurate
so this is a kind of regularity out there in the world which we wouldn't see from
small data sets or which we wouldn't see as humans because there's no way for
us to look at 15 million sequences of DNA locations so if we just look
at the data as biologists we wouldn't see the regularity
so this is an example of of such a hard inference problem that we as
humans cannot solve because we didn't grow up with this kind of data so we grew
up with visual patterns what we didn't grow up with DNA sequences
and i'm gonna say
the following say it
the probability that this is zero half
obviously the probability that this is one
is a half
we can actually
right down the inference the probability that this is one
given are zero one one
one minus the squared
by half
divided by
the same term
down squares downstairs like this
you know the term
you know the explanation
and i can simplify this lot
when you cancel everything out
you get
one minus
so we've now answered in the table we just had are going to have
we've looked at one rather that's
the road a zero one
and now what we've worked out is the probability
that's is
are is one
it is in fact one minus which is ninety percent
so it was a sensible thing to say you should guess
right and i can repeat for all eight possible answers
almost all of them will come out just the same way this one did but
if you receive zero zero zero one one get a slightly different
answer for the probability
what the code says you should guess
just affinities of
labouring it's because it's good to be clear on the simple case
and we can go and
two more complicated ones
the probability that it was a one
is bigger than the probability that
it was a zero
this is one
is the best this
and it's the best guess because it involves the smallest number of flips
so i'll leave as an exercise
during the case are is one one
so you can work out the posterior probability
in the case
now we have a new task
this was using probabilities to do inference
now what i want to work out is how well does this decoder perform
so this is an example of forward probability
i want to ask the question if we use a repetition code
think codex
with senti over a binary symmetric channel with the flip probability at
and then we use the majority vote decoder
to give us
what is the probability
the estat
well not equal
less well i'm talking here about a single bit so we send one bit over the channel using this procedure
what's the probability that the asshat we end up spilling out about decoder will not
be the same as the bit that were in please have a chapter you neighbour
any answers
the flip probability is after
the probability
an error in the system
what probability distribution are you thinking about anyone
the binomial distribution and that's
so is the binomial distribution and what
part what outcomes would cause this thing that happened which
over all variables can be written in the factor form so the joint distribution over
the variables x is whatever some normalizing constant the product of
these factors
where the notation i'm using is that
x so
it's just cj is the subset of all the nodes in the graph so there
are k nodes in the graph k variables
cj is the j th subset of that corresponds to the j factor here except
cj is just take the subset of the vector indexed by siege
if we have a factorisation like this
then we can specify an undirected graph in the following way
create a node for each variable
and then connecting two nodes i and k
if there is some set cj such that both i is in that sense cj
and case that's cj in other words if there's some factor
we both
x i
and xk
both part of that fact
so these sets form the cliques of the graph is a fully connected subgraphs
so let's look at one of these
here we have it is an undirected graphical model the difference between this and factor
is that we're not explicitly representing those factors which is directly connecting the nodes to
each other with these undirected edges
OK so this
undirected graphical model corresponds to this
factorisation of the joint distribution of these five variables
again we have the fact that x is independent of y
given the
if every path between x and y contains some node in this set b
and again we have a car larry given the neighbors of x
the variable x is conditionally independent of all other variables
just like in factor graphs
and we can define a you know a a couple of other things the markov
the markov blanket is the set of variables for
these are these are markov blanket for x if only if x is independent of
y given v the for all
why not in the union of the sets x and envy
markov boundary is the minimal markov blanket that's what makes you independent of everything else
and that's generally does the neighbors of
your note
and you can define these more generally for a set of nodes if you want
all right
so i've introduced undirected graphs and factor graphs and they seem remarkably similar so what's
the point with the reason why
we have these two things one of them is historical as undirected graphs have been
around much longer than factor graphs that's why i think it's important for me to
introduce them here
but they don't represent exactly the same form
properties of this richer forms of distribution
let's consider these three graph a b and c are the nodes
in these graphs have exactly the same neighbors
right the neighbours of the ERC in the in all three of these graphs
therefore these three graphs represent exactly the same conditional independence relationships
so as far as conditional independence relationships go there not different
but c
also represents the fact that the probability factors into a product of pairwise functions
so consider this factor here
that connects e c and d
in general
that's the function of three variables
kate and here in the undirected graph we have explicitly represented the factor so we
generally need to have a function of these three variables to capture
the relationships between these variables
we're here
it's explicitly shown that
these three variables
interact through pairwise functions functions of two variables
this is significant from the point of view of representation in implementation and message passing
et cetera because
if if we just think of the variables is being discrete let's say they take
on k possible values then the functions in a and b are generally tables of
order k cute
whereas the functions in c are tables of order k squared
more generally if we have a bigger
network with lots of interconnections the factor graph
might represent
the forms
of the functions more compactly more succinctly than the undirected graph
because it can represent the fact that
these functions are not necessarily functions of
large sets that they can be functions small so it's very well when you right
the rest pressure conditions of the
qualitatively in terms of probability distributions in terms of conditional independence
they're going to be equivalent OK
but but i mean it's fundamentally different to say that this
distribution factors into
products of pairwise functions are three functions are some like that it's a bit more
fine grained representation if you write out each other factors expose
yes the question is in particular here
this is the subset of all distributions captured by the
that's a qualitative
so now why is that not y
can we just use undirected graphs and factor graphs well
in the given graph
there are separate not when i said yes
this is list
we can reformulate again this is
what was
each of the undirected edges
are you can well you can have that because in directed models directed graphical models
they are directed acyclic graph
right OK
you have models that have edges in both directions and you can have graphs that
edges pointing to the toes to go to their actions
but those graphs has have nothing to do with vision
that's important sometimes i mean of course
language is highly overlord the graphical models and should go the
the computer graphics literature they will
i think we are talking about something very different
OK so
let's keep going here
let's see what's the initial for markov random field
so basically
in the same way that vision therefore was
a set of probability distributions
it was consistent with the
traditional forgive
directed acyclic graphs so much in the field is also set of probability distributions p
of axioms
and we require that every possible probability history is for people
such that there exists an undirected graph
with disjoint subsets of nodes a b and c
in which whenever c d
whenever c separates a from b
in the graph
this conditional independence hall
in p
look it's also
so four
you need to exactly understand what's going on
we have to
parallel worlds here we have the will of probability distributions we have the all the
these definitions saying well it's actually relating those things excelling well
we're going to talk about the class of probability model
that can be represented by a graph
and the way you understand the probabilistic model is precisely
the both probabilistic models they are able to in cold conditional independence statements
if you define conditional independence in that grass is given by
graph separation
and this is critical because
i mean
their that probability models that you may not
be able
define the conditions existing conditional independence statements as graph separation
but we are talking about that models the model but
models for example
you have mixed type model hybrid model which parties
bayesian network and part of the microphone feel for example
i mean those
more complicated types of models and
of conditional independence statements that can represent
with those models
is large
but also but in practice we just say well the microphone if you use the
undirected graph
what it actually is is
the set of probability distributions
who's conditional independence statements can be
read by graph separation
in an undirected graph
the connection between
yes there are no viable sorry is implicit here
that there are no viable
yes i a b and c
the nodes of the graph they just represent the environment
in this case a
these are separate from the virus
OK so i just
a quick look at this so basically i mean we saw the vision that have
a convenient factorized form
we saw the factorisation of business after comes from the conditional independence statements in the
we saw the the converse is also true
so the factorisation flight condition the pen
in this sort these equivalence is important
because it connects what we know
which are the local
conditional independence statements that you can
get from the domain experts for example
with what you want which is
the is basically a probabilistic machine
that p
of x in the factorized form where we can actually compute things
the question is do we have something analogous with markov random field
i mean
in bayesian networks we had
i do have something from fields
which looks like factorisation as well
or some other structure
we need to have something
the answer is yes and now we're going to go into that
very beautiful subject
let's see some
definitions concerning undirected graph because this definition will be required
so that we can make progress here OK