so you can say well it's it's a negative and so let's try and move
the variance back to the closest valid proper method which is the point
well i mean you don't suddenly become massively confident again
locally about your distribution
which means that everything around in the graph has even become less confident it turns
more improper messages you don't get convergence to a good solution
and the are other things you can to be sending the last messages again is
probably never converge or you cannot converge
and more
what you think you can try to stand in the next again less confidently you
know that at some point somebody said you know
to be less certain so let's just try doing that
and on the other the other sort of suggestion that coming up with this to
sort locally temporarily switches to variational message passing which i was saying that that we
know this uncertainty getting is not very useful
it's not likely it up
clearly it's not valid outside the space valid police so
just switch instead making a local estimation but i haven't had any success getting that
work so this is still open
an open question but this is this is a serious problem
one of
i think that think
it it is to it is to a certain extent because if you ask the
if the point where you see the first improper message you ask the entire graph
what is my posterior over the mean it will be posterior
it's just because locally
you know we've divided out effectively the output message that we get this this locally
improper message so in some sense you right but
so so one of the solution i've been trying to play with exactly that is
trying to sort of say temporarily ignore
dividing up the backward messages he put it that we know that much about doesn't
work either
but it sounds like something to be easy to fix and the method just that
we tried lots of different things none of them seem to work and getting increasingly
hacky towards the bottom of the increasingly desperate
he was
this is one
the that
you just short
i guess that's what we're trying to do with the with the point mass approximation
may be the better
by way approached projecting back into the
this is
that is making valid
so the problem is in a sense we can do that brings it back into
the valley space
again you can into about
so what might be the case you stand up
just continually saying on the boundaries of space and
and no actually converging to the solution
well what the problem with that is when you have to
pretty it won't diverge purely because the but what you get is that
the is that you'll get
when you try and projected back into the gas in family would then
you would then not be in the in the gas
OK so
tom can help tell the question the question was if i discretize all like it
is distributions use the discrete representation i'm not going to get improper messages
my first magnetic charge number one
which is where is the
companies organisations everybody is
just drowning in data but when you actually come
the mind that there are
typically find you can get
that you have to start essentially from scratch
typically all the selected within the their data stored the wrong way not right be
well that's that's all that effort was was basically waste of of
putting this together
the solution i was indicating
very very specific specific solutions with
with the data is very close to we formed a company called the jim which
today is going on as revenue science and on
targeting behavioral targeting of advertising on the internet
good stuff
everything went well amazing set of clients probably use case studies from those clients you
these are all the companies who actually
we're very comfortable basically saying what you can manage my data for me to make
it work
which is good stuff
lots of VC funding for customers over time
this was the second learned lesson
which is
even when you
it was true
even if target solution
people didn't know enough about it lies in the business which is what led me
to essentially formed DMX group
which was a company
basically to the southeast
this is that you might have been science
and turn them into your business to deal with something on the part of of
the problem
but the thing
this to a churn predicting all sorts of stuff like that
the DMX was eventually acquired by part of story is why
that position happen
so the mission was to make
they were
right is not enough to is believed to have tools
you actually have to actually do one do
so i started learning here will have actually from bob grossman
was it
the companies and actually many organisations struggling with
was making strategic shift
this is how to actually think of your data
as a strategic asset come
and that's that's a big ship that's not
that's the thing about this which is basically a weighted by issues
all the data stuff
the things like revenue
to optimise the operation
decreasing attention now a lot of you in the audience you work with it all
the time so you take this
i challenge you to
any reasonable enterprise
what to
the management team
and see if they can make the
and what this company would have no idea
i don't think there is something crucial to think of it the site
you know
something that the systems you have to deal with
and it's a cost centre
you know sometimes they get something stuff out of them will report
you know all that but not something that business which which was a big shift
so at DMX group
and in fact
the number two which is
data mining within operational systems forget about selling data mining
forget about the this somebody divided
and i think it is what you want to sell them is an operation is
is that i was sure problem right
and we used to give you keep a good case study here
with the
actually one some
is an exercise we did
which was basically studying and this is actually early on
so of slides actually work good formerly was part of the business working in this
we went to project prediction for large
telco providers
pretty good exercise
we actually picked features
and we got to the point where we could predict sure very active
right so we do have a meeting with the exact
you know what
i can tell you that by is going to leave your service and with
we pretty high confidence within the next two months
when i found in the
well even the exciting
and this is wonderful
they couldn't act
because i didn't know what to do with a piece of information
it is by going to leave my service to another
so what do i do
one eighteen
i want to get
given monopoly on the concept
omega three diet
what do i do
it turns out you think the time
they don't
a lot of these companies don't have very sophisticated ones
so i think actually immediately without
but somebody should keep or by somebody
and actually the
chart that i borrowed from
what is this one
it is actually a beautiful visualization
this is something you would actually is shown
two executives
in other words
let me just tell you what these things are
this is the probability of children from low to high
the customer is going to leave
and this is the podcast like this from negative by the way
a lot of customers very negative and
a lot of you know twenty to thirty percent of the customers destroy the company
and you make another fifteen percent of the profits a very small group which is
very high
lifetime value
it is very important for companies to be able to compute this on an individual
if you don't have it you don't know how to act on that information you
can have the best predictor in the world which in my opinion
but you want to
that's you could try to this and i'm showing you here actually these literally from
different marketing programs
and you're deciding what to put them right so you can say
the people that i'm going to give an equipment upgrade to hundred design right people
i think you know about half brothers charles and then you know
pretty valuable to me
for those of you who are here on time and i wasn't those
so far from the sort of thing
everything in the mac is excellent except that
and they charge fifty dollars four
ran back to my hotel room
where when i hackney that today said to myself this is the one most important
thing to take and then i left it there because it was standing right next
to the telephone cord which looks exactly the same
the classic object recognition problem
presentation OK
so the sanctum inference learning that i don't have my notes each so unlike
driving blind that's fine so i'm here have
you know you won't forget me now after so many mishaps
and i'm princeton university
and the reason i decided to give this story all are basically
well the one reason is that the first learning has the hear me by the
reinforcement learning has revolutionized
our understanding
of learning in the brain in the last two decades or so
but this might is only for the camera does doesn't
it's not connected to anything but you can hear
so it's on
you could also come and sit closer because there
closest c
so as i said reinforcement learning is really revolutionized the field of neuroscience in general
but more
understanding of learning in the brain and it
turns out surprisingly that not many
machine learners
know this
and i thought this was
kind of amazing first of all i think you should know this because first of
all you can take pride
and no that you know if you study reinforcement learning there are a bunch of
neuroscientists the media papers and then convert that knowledge about the brain and for some
of us it's important to understand the brains that can be proud that you
but you contributed to that
the second thing is you ask you know not
only what can i do for neuroscience walking neuroscience do for me so how can
neuroscience advance reinforcement learning as the thing that i want to try to try to
show you today
mostly talk about
what we understand about the brain given reinforcement learning but it's your job to do
the opposite and and i'll try to point out some places where where you can
actually do this
inversion easily
why are you here
except for the fact that he had an extra fifteen minutes reading emails
hopefully you're here because you want to learn something about learning in animals and humans
and because you want to find out the latest about how the brain does reinforcement
and as i said to find out how understanding learning in the brain can help
reinforcement learning research so these are the three things that all covered today
and the
the point is if you here for any other reason
your valley
that span
elsewhere so we're not going to
i'm not going to talk about the brain in general too much are not gonna
teach your reinforcement learning
reading email could take so i just i just a quick survey so i know
i know why are you are really here so how many of you on the
scale of one to three with one being
not very to being quite well in three i'm an expert in and how many
of you know reinforcement learning so first one is not very
kind of
OK so they're not there will have to like two quick speed up
learning on this
because i'm not really going to introduce reinforcement learning in its basic i nothing for
neuroscience how many of you don't know very much about neuroscience and the brain
how many know
kind of
how many are experts
there are scientists and the crowd OK
some asian over all the other variables in the graph
so every node can do
again this local operation
in computer vector if it's the discrete
variable at every node and the way it does it in this time is it
it takes its local evidence the site function there and then it just takes the
product of
some of the sheets sustained
OK it's going to take the product of terms all of its neighbors
and i'll take all the incoming messages so just right and then i'll walk you
and so it's going to compute
and so the pictures you've got this guy sitting here no tests
it's got a bunch of neighbors
you can just collect in this case you collect messages from all of them
these are green
and you just multiply them together
in doing so
so i got a message along each one of these edges
this thing is something that either called the some marginal
or it's called the max marginals
right so
there we basically have the algorithm
message passing you collect multiply operate pass
and then
when the algorithm converges when you have a stable set of messages
you collect all of them from everybody multiply and you include your local evidence
now so what you get is a vector
if you've been doing the sum product form of message passing then you would have
computed the marginal distribution you would have computed for instance the sum over all the
other variables in the graph
you would have computed exactly this quantity here
so no tests that mu x invested i've written would be exactly that big summation
you would have some doubt over all the other variables in the graph
and if you were computed we using the max operation instead of the sum you
would have computed the max margin or you would have
computed vector which is obtained by maximizing out all the other nodes
so that's depending on exactly this little switch
did you do max or did you do with some
and those are the two forms of the two most commonly used forms of this
OK so any questions about how the algorithm works
it's very easy to implement its etc
sort of is as exercise if you just implement it once you get a good
feeling the first time you see these equations they look a bit mysterious
but what you just one i think is the equations are coming from distributing operations
over products
it's essentially it's to divide and conquer principle this is the form of
the form of dynamic programming but it's it's dynamic programming on trees actually
so his question treated wanted to this sequentially so i guess the issue is how
would we order the computation of the messages
on a tree so if you actually had this graph then if you wanted to
save computation what you should do is maybe pick one node is the root
and if you want to do the minimal
amount of messaging then you would pick that is the root and then you start
at the leaves
and you're essentially to a leaf stripping operation you pass messages from leaves to the
next guy
and you to collect everything at the root and then you redistribute see algorithm one
had sort of a feeling of leaves to root and back down
if you did that ordering of the messages and what you can check is that
you actually have to only send a message one message per edge
every guy would not be operating in every round in the first round believes would
work this guy would do nothing this guy would do nothing the second round this
guy would work believes would do nothing third round the route work fourth round the
route passed back fifty and so on
so if you think about that that that algorithm obviously would converge because there's no
sort of iteration it's just a finite to pass algorithm
and that's one way if you run that algorithm you will
find a set of messages
and if you plug those messages into this formula that i just gave you
you will compute the exact marginals
right so that's called the serial ordering of messages that's one way to update your
that's attractive because it somehow does the minimum amount of messaging per node but it's
unattractive because it's not it can be parallelized and it somehow there's synchronization to some
level required
right if you have parallel processors
and if you have sort of
a process at each node
this algorithm is wasteful because you know in the first round leaves are working nobody
else is working
in the second round
you only a subset of nodes are working in each round so when you implement
this on parallel systems that so of a cluster or when they implemented let's say
before i can't on the stone
bricks and theory i want to show you a few
examples of these events
others and has studied
in detail
here is the log you should be looking after victory of the has p five
hundred stock the
forget about the
this was carried correspond to different implementation of models
so this is the data you see this
characteristic acceleration of the price of course motivated by some situations
the crash occurred here
in october eighty seven
and what is interesting about this example
it that one u
look at the different explanation but have been
propose to understand the crash
all of them at least a few of them major explosion has been proposed
they are all based on
what i call approximate
approximate goes
you know the
specific technical effects you
specific mechanism
as opposed to
a different view that
i want i would like to develop with your later on
which is to view it the crash
the kind of contamination of the and
of quite long preparation time
associated with the problem
but before we go to this we show you another example which is the
october nineteen twenty nine crash again
this kind of acceleration prize
you see the crash here
and what hear an extract two quotes from the book famous book of
the famous economist kenneth got got right
wrote a specific book analyzing all details the great
the great crash is the title of the book
and the
for example shows that
it could be actually definition of graph
is one the economies after the wrong
actually one the economist for example the famous for irving fisher
just it
the two weeks before the crash that is so the economy actually
continued to grow
and the present value of the market and under appreciated and valued significantly and he
was saying much stronger position
similarly we're speaking at lunch hobart
harvard economic society and to insisted
that's the market was going to go up in a very significant way
the problem of course is that this crash correspond to very strong nonlinearities change of
which cannot be
obtained by lena extrapolation quite good at doing pollution
this kind of prediction are really where
completely outside the scope
this economy
jumping back to two thousand this new economy again the log of the nasdaq composite
index the index that measures this new enterprise around internet communication technology
you see again this
acceleration of the price motivated by different structure over time over here three years of
followed by
the crash
what is quite remarkable in this later latest example
that if you
look at for example the constituents of the another in istanbul five hundred
you find you find that just the constituent
which are which were characterised as this new technology internet and so on
rose by four hundred percent just in two years
compared with the old
a concrete and mortar they called companies or companies that car companies and so on
which values remain basically flat
we compared with the four hundred games so that as a whole
this index SP five hundred gained fifty percent over two years but only
the right push by some
part of the of the economy
and actually the standard for technology sector among the five hundred stocks
correspond to just one hundred talks about twenty percent to twenty percent of the stock
push the global index by fifty percent by them several one percent the rest
four hundred companies
and a lot of excesses like price ratios of the two thousand something negative
and the new economy
spirit that is so sure
the phenomenon of social characteristic that you see in the newspapers in the discussions between
appendix and so on between commentators and and so on
it was very hard of force course in the minds and mouths during that time
commencing in april two two thousand
i want also to remind you
this is not new
the same term new economy was hurt in the
speech in the discussion before the crash of october twenty nine
new economy at the time with the utilities was also hot in the minds
and the discussion
before the crash of sixty two nineteen sixty two there was also a crash
two of the trunk boom crash following trying to build the new economy was electronic
the emergence electric company so
there is nothing new under the sun
this idea of you know something that we need to change fundamentally so that the
these concepts have have to be so that the
pricing methods have to be modified as shown in this slide
actually is an error that we see again and again repeated
here in these slides
describe the major
in gradient arguments
put forwards by
economists who
we're trying to justify the upsurge skyrocketing price
as well as the strategist in image the investment banks
and the most famous one was michelle motion was on credit suisse first boston the
well known analyst and strategist for all of the world
basically his message was we need to
changed completely
the weight evaluation for
by introducing this new effect this new mechanism which is the
mechanism of
pricing real options
you may know what the
financial options that contract give you certain cashflow conditional
it's nominate instrument the concept the real of francisco just the same thing
in the framework of decision making you see all you want to to make a
decision in the future
you're making decision of investing if
considering all the future cash flows discounted to the present value
this future earnings are larger than the initial investment right
the real option to say well
they something additional along the path
seven at the same time because there's no edge there
so you want the sufficient statistics to be local
and we'll see examples of that in a minute
right so here's
here's here's one example
again just on the simple grid graphs
you might imagine that we're trying to model an image again or something else
in in this case are cliques member just edges so you could think about some
function of the random variables here and here xs and xt
and you've got some local function at each
note so overall you get an exponential family that had some over the vertices of
the graph of some local functions
and then the sum over the edges of some of the local functions here
right so this
this thing here this again is just a big exponential family
what's he now is an exponential family that's the sort of breaking up on the
all of these terms are local with respect to the nodes and the edges of
the graph
so it's a kind of graph structure exponential family
and here the normalisation constant is a if there is just the log of the
summation over all possible configurations
this was binary just be overall
zero one to the end
of this big exponential so this this is something we for instance would like to
another example we've seen that we can go back to understand this is simple markov
and hidden if we have noisy observations y i here
so here
we just think about function sitting on these edges and functions
associated with these observations
and it's easy to see that
these exponential functions here to simply logs of transition functions
so the thing on the edge from two to three will be log of px
three given x two
the thing on here
coupling the observation decks five would be the log of the conditional distribution of the
observation given the hidden states
so that's that's another example that we can rephrase is an exponential family
another example is the multivariate gaussians
so we've already seen here on this board we see an example of a single
this is just a scalar gaussian random variables
but often
for instance in
PCA or factor analysis like sam roweis talk about you have to deal with very
large dimensional gaussians you have many gaussian components and you'd like to understand the structure
of that kind of random vector
so we can do that quite easily here
it's easy to think actually does to write the sufficient statistics in big matrix now
so you have a long this
rho here
by symmetry along this column you have
the mean vectors
so x one x two to x and these are the first order moments
and this matrix here
it's just the matrix of second order moments
so this is the
second moments squared x one and similarly along the diagonal
and these are the correlation terms
and then you can just think the multiplying this guy remember we just have log
linear models so you have
parameters multiply the potentials you'd have another big matrix of parameters here
we looked at before we just had one gets you would be the special case
of just looking at this two by two block you'd have one parameter for the
and one parameter for the second moment and that's that's what i had here in
this notation data one and data two
you will be theta one and theta one one
OK so what's interesting here is that
in general the matrix could be completely dead right it could have
all nonzeros
but what it means for calcium to be to be a graphical model to respect
the graph structure it tells you something very specific about this matrix
by the way this matrix is not the covariance matrix this matrix is actually the
inverse of the the covariance matrix is often called the precision matrix
so what this tells you if if this is going to be markov with respect
to graph
it's sort of says that you know if edge
it's a
one three for instance here at one three does not belong to this graph
then it's telling you that there can be a term involving x one x three
that means the data one three here has to in fact be zero
what that tells you is that if you sort of plot the adjacency structure of
this matrix here
what you see is that have zeros
wherever this graph does not have edges so one three there's no edge that zero
o five one
five one there's no edge that's also zero
similarly to
two four doesn't have an edge
so in general if you have a very big gaussians
but one that's quite sparse you can end up with a matrix here if this
graph is sparse this matrix is going to be very sparse
and that's very important practically to have sparse
sparse grass like sparse matrices for computational purposes
one last example this again is also something that sam mentioned that we can think
about is an exponential family often were interested not just in gaussians that we might
and and then you can do for you need
so sentences in document collection of aircraft
representations of human male for two
to have precise matching
between your question and the document collection
you see also there that
network technology you want to do a probabilistic reasoning with these data then you can
think again about
these the mediation networks
so here
question is an example of what company small greeting cards and send sentences how much
means the largest maker of greeting cards
and this shows you
first problem in question being
the problem of
you see that
not exactly the same
it doesn't mean
it's not completely this has the not have completed the meaning
as your question and sentences
sentence does not have
completely the same as you question sentence
but you see believe
you the difficulty
well of that
how to come
well from the sentences
how to make sure that the and so there is
some paraphrasing here
there has to be used
now there are many other people have the time in question answering
many other types of questions
we are
by solving the problem
so we are quite quite good to show you the results of track two thousand
seven in this in this area
we are
we have
the value
some technology
four and the actual question
so in fact extraction
from document collection
but the question is
for you well
you have to
to some paraphrasing
translated into other
in two other concept
use some breathing techniques
so like how did socrates die
in the next three games
by applying high directly died to drinking poison
poisoned wine
it's not so much
an easy question for
and you
it's not easy for
what your machine
often we
we have list questions were
you have to listen
in what countries according to
the class here although is factual information
we have to use many different document and put it put it doesn't answer
to this question
people have also explored interactive question answering systems
maybe you're going fire by
expert taking expert system technology
it allows you to interact
communicate with the source
so the question that you posed
might not be very clear i might be solvable for your machine
the machine
it might
q additional question
of course
this means that behind
you have all the structures
and all the representation and the knowledge
to do so
to have
to be able to do this quickly
for large document collection and i go back to the talk of max the first
talk of max who really large document collection
suppose we are
able to do with our information extraction techniques to model all this information
and many other additional information
certain world knowledge
to make interaction possible to make the answer to the question of whether we want
to do lots of research
how do this
how we can do this in a scalable way
in a very efficient way
that we have here
time very quickly
it's very slow with very low latency
and then of course the people dreaming
about another question the logic of questions
analogical reasoning in question
so that
united refer to the expert search
where mushy on UK national needs to happen first
on really
riddick things
very sophisticated well performed very sophisticated
human reasoning
on the data like analogical reasoning here
in the US moving towards fashion
well maybe
to find out all your document collections from your fact actually OK
i think you
the film
now i give you some leads to finalize bars part i
these are results
two thousand two
that compare well that given that you have more of the world
the university has
i don't know
has performed come back to that
of many different question answering systems
doesn't take
or in square so the analysis is correct up to the point where we set
the worst case one answer was or and
is therefore
that's the wrong step
one every see bugs improves you want to know which step is the one failed
so you can make sure
you know
you have a confusion there
so let's do the in
proper analysis OK
so let's let
c by
the the cost
and so
so that's equal to
if i minus one
is an exact
so as i was going through here
was only when
i inserted something where the previous
one had been exact power of two because i was my table size that's when
i got the overflow
and had to do all that copying
and otherwise the cost for example for inserting six was just one i just inserted
so that's what's actually make a little table here
so this is a little bit more clearly
OK so here's i
the size of the table thereby
the cost step i
let's see the size of my
but it's that one it was one
at step two it was too
step three
that's why and to get three in the table
the size
i had to
we had to double the size
are services for
and if i had to pump up to eight
six it was a seven was a it was a nine sixteen
that's the size and let's take a look at what the cost was
so the cost here was one
insert one
cost here was i had to
copy one and then insert once the cost was too
here i had to copy to insert one cost was three
here i have to just insert one
the cost was one
here i had to
copy for insert once cost by
its history i think it was
you see i cost five i
it's for five if this is the power to
one one
and now nine
one again
that's the cost a little bit easier to see what the costs are break them
OK so let's just re
draw this as two values is always the cost for inserting
one thing that i want to search
and now the residual amount but i have to pay is that one here
four additional
and it's parallel but easier to see
OK this is the cost of copying versus the cost of
just doing the actual insert
you're taking notes some space here because i come back to the stable layer
OK so we will better spaces come back and
or or what have i done
what have i done
what is it twenty points
we have the problem
is it is not working
any one of you have an idea here
whether there is something wrong with the equation of what does something wrong with walter
and the idea
you try to worst case
your suggestion is not right
you're accusing
my point one five
in the same way you could do better than point four seconds
and then of course to be consistent with thank you
very nice
that's a very good suggestion not what you begin
things like a physicist you also felt like a physicist because indeed
my answer is higher than point one five
you could be right
in this case we will be with friction later in the course
has such
like small effect it could be merged into one of these two
in any case it's almost the same for both
good shape has not changed it's a very good suggestions
friction doesn't come near the proper explanation but you tried
that's good one more try
said really
you may have heard it but i did say
can we please take it to prove to you
i said
the mass of the spring is negligible
it is
now what do we do when the mass cannot be ignored that's not so easy
but i
so mandatory reading
and i'm sure all of you have done that before
this lecture
and the mandatory reading friends page sixty sixty one among others
and friend says that if the mass of the
the spring itself is capital and
and if capital and divided by three
is substantially less than the mass
at the end of the spring
very very good approximation is
that the period of oscillation
is that this
and he actually derives it
is high
so we can bring this to attest now
the towards the mass
of the spring we have to wait that
in our case is hundred seventy five point six
plus or minus o point two grams
and so and divided by three
is fifty
eight point five
was minus point o seven grams
that's a very small error by the way
o point one percent error
and so we can now
do the following test
we can now
take the ratio of these two
and then it thereby
OK so we can write now ten t
divided by ten t
is not square root
of two
it was and divided by three
divided by one
plus and divided by
and that number
it's easy to calculate because you know
and to you know and what you know these numbers
and i have calculated it for you
and it is one point three
seventy seven
and the uncertainty is so small compared to my timing uncertainty that i don't even
have to allow
for any uncertainty that number
because remember uncertainties in the masses was of the order of one percent
that was the uncertainty
in the observations of time
which were closer to one percent
so we can bring this now to test
all i must do now
is multiplied if i want to find out ten
and i think one point three seven seven
and i multiply by and one
finds plenty and one
so i take this number
and i'm really getting nervous not joking
o point nine seven
multiplied by one point three seven seven
that is twenty point six one
and the uncertainty would be the same uncertainty as in there which is one percent
so that is o point two
this number
you can now compare
with this number
the button
within the error of measurements
there are no agreed
this is what we observe
and this is what we predict
if we apply
proper relation
and take the mass of the spring account
so you see that physics works
except that this equation
was too simple
to be used for our
notice by the way that this one point
four one four
in our case is
all right
eight o sweden
we will often
i don't not always
complex notation
and the reason why we do that is that
it can time simplify your life
you are completely free to choose when you want to use it and when you
don't want to
you can be the judge
so let's talk a little bit
about complex numbers
i started a circle
and this is the complex plane
like what is complex brain is quite promotional affordable export
and here
i call this axis the
real axis so all the real numbers are on this axis
and that this people plus one
this been minus one
and i call this axis
imaginary axis
so this one
this was j
and this one is minus today
is the square root of minus one we don't call it i in general because
i is
sense for currently at j
i know
opposition here
which now represents a complex
call angle
data and i project this
his position
complex numbers
this is the
the real part of that
complex number
and this is the
imaginary part of the complex
so you can see that in the city
can be written since this length is one
is the cosine
donation that somebody
and actually something i've forgotten to tell which is very
very but maybe not when we
we find something is that when defining the
so it to bits
this is what what's it called
so i tried to do
just what they did that here for the information that this is something i have
not whatever you have
fixpoint operator as viable and do not use reuse
twice the same viable always that the definition is missing so this is exactly like
i mean
four different quantifier just
for free but should work i mean the definition to the
right so that it
so we keep going with with what could have a look at this are way
of four
connecting the dots on the top and r
particular out of something on normally
you know i've already for finite was due to four language languages
all let's the the
two matter determinisation what you may also have already encountered
ultimate fighting it
something about the termite and is now
OK but with the countries straight away but so it is very similar to statement
on it and it was that the most natural way to
so you have an automaton
they read only twenty but it denotes the numbers
set of strings this training matter
so that the path
which is infinite the pattern
example of this is it
infinitely often
instead of heating once state which it calls that i think about this in the
in the final
and you would
tell me that came out from the next step
former best in my automaton which is famous tech its back in finer structure
so for example if i want to know such a termite it has one model
i simply look for strongly connected components in strongly connected component containing one accepting states
strongly connected components and it's very easy for me to form the
so this is the way to define
sets of infinite objects here in phoenix four
so we can stay here
so that's the first item
and the please film just saying and this object was introduced by the he and
what it
so he he and
and the make the
or in between them
a win in in a way to reason about all of us to launch a
and also second order
logic on structures but
and so the second family
over time the family farm
in trees
so basically
so that to the logic which is not going to talk about just one
which is going to talk about
trees infinite
binary trees for second order logic to success
is decidable
this is by associating to every monadic second order logic
of being able to associate some automaton
and he learned societies
how can it work for in generalisation of what people would have expected for infinite
you give it the full binary tree with a particular
labels on nodes and while in the trade will perform some computation
so now the computation with additional have been an infinite path
in the automaton
if i i will give him an infinite tree and the competition will be infinite
tree is where each branch of the tree
but i have given
so this infinite
we call accepting if
every branch
i mean to
accepting conditions people have considered for infinite so that
but the matter has some winning condition called fishing conditions
king state i would say that my trees except that if
and that could will
on the from the computation
in this sense i found an accepted one
and then see of particularly exotic with the
islam is not constantly thank reasoning
there's more to it
for more information go go from one
if you have more point
however this happens if only the number of clusters and bone as well
if i found the number of clusters which is what typically parametric clustering does
in any case in any clustering you don't want to go more classes were not
because then
it means that
way too many
or it's very unlikely that you want to find to construct and so
for any candidates for the square root of which is the domain of clustering really
is bounded by
the logarithm of the number of clusters
so it is about bounded what i six k but it's about in general
and the consequence is that when k small because the is concave and grows fastest
first and then levels up
force located in the business grows very fast and it's very hard to
OK there are many things that
could be said about the state of all
about three minutes
so see them with pictures
so this problem that i mentioned that two clusterings that
do different things to
the unmatched are of
i considered different from the
at different distances from the origin of clustering does not appear in the variational formulation
because you clearly there is less information
to describe this change that they need information to describe this change
so this image is discriminated
this a is bit
and the division of information
OK and
what is that supposed to have one set
and two clustering so the audience would
a certain distance between
and another set with two clusterings which have nothing to do with the first
and on to join
i think you know that but they keep the clustering
and i want to know the distance between this clustering in this cluster
very easy to compute is just the weighted sum of the parts of the these
weighted by
the size of the building
well and that's why i call it convex additivity because the final this this is
the convex sum of the distances on the parts
what is relevant
think of it as a hierarchical clustering think of it the following
from this side back
for discrete data like this
and especially
same way so have two clusterings that identical the first level
but then you will learn differently and the next slide
this says that the two
this is
all this that you can treat each side of the plate independent then the results
that linear
just second composition of or decomposition
if one side is it is the view on one side
i means that the
the of the distance between the two clusterings would be but this is on the
other side multiplied by the size of the plant
or in other words if
i take some clustering that change only one class of
i get this
that this will depend only on the size of the clusters
for the clusters and the data is partitioned to
that's like saying that if i take or think about this i think image
a segmented image and to
how many faces
and then measure the distance between the two segmentation
i would like to not too
being influenced by the fact that in the future is also or not
it's like
the same one part of the image the show
not affect how the that different how to measure the distance in
and this is true for the idea this that is true for any business
for many other avenues
so i
the daily news
also as a result of this
the property of
if i split the cluster i get like small clustering together small business and proportional
to the size of
i want to mention that
this is this is not same thing not to do
the only way people measure distance measure differences or compare clusterings and in fact statistics
it's difficult people use in this is an index is something that is one of
the cluster is identical
and to make them so that
bounded between zero and one
there are many of the
i talk about because although being used if to you look at what properties they
have a lot of what you can say about
so you can say more about you can see list
the properties that they have like
the ones i mentioned before they
massively fans from
and so
although sometimes something that is zero one is like a probability because between zero and
one just being in that range to make the probability you also need probabilistic interpretation
that lacks
for most of them so
is now it is a very simple message worry about your performance is good you
use very complicated this that
lot of inference you don't get human again much your performance was always each
we're going to move to the next
have is about parameters for kernel selection and practical issues
so at this point so any questions
OK so so we move to the next time
try a practical example
this is the message from this for particle physics
well i have no idea of these areas is this this is a data set
from one of the users
we are using a so-called spots for to store these that's it
now we see there are four features for the state house in one four three
and four
and the first column is actually correct labels
so this is why
why we want to use such reform OK using these one two to indicate
the features the reason is because
in quite a few publications we actually very sparse data sets for example like text
data analysis talked about yesterday
this the
for the vector model
vector is very sparse so you may only like so i suppose you want to
depends or something that you don't need you me only ten of the are non
so you use of indicators window for which they should stand zeros
but of course it is what is the situation for many you
it is very so we don't have to use sparse right
OK so now we have such a thing as a
well there are more like this
both training and testing sets
so this result training instances and also for some of the existing instances
well so i can see a little bit about the story behind this data set
is a proper use so he actually from sweden
so he said to me and say OK using
or somewhere in the initial particle physics the location where the first said why don't
you come gradually you were easy to use and i page but but unfortunately it
me astonishingly bad results
so this
but also how does this help tell to tell us
this tells us that if you want to say something bad to present you say
something good first so so because of these
i have no choice but to say OK please send us your data is i
want to solve the problem for for him
the the then the the hedonistic also for is that
so so i guess he stayed a little bit of the data set the this
on top of that he said both training and testing data sets so as i
told i was able to achieve like ninety ninety seven percent test accuracy so
is that good for him with the
he said that we had a copy of his phd thesis is in this sense
that you get a copy of his phd certificate
but they should get together of his phd thesis on my of these
so that's the whole hog hunting for this dataset
so we just directly try
ten is it has it
we use the composition method six of iterations the optimisation is finished the number of
well one thing
strange here is
the number of support vectors is quite large we have three so the support vectors
with this she instances through what we believe that resulted in training instances so that
means nearly all training instances they are support vectors
so that means that there is something to do
most often they are positive and the number of
this is not good because he said if you but support vectors the training time
is bigger and also the model is more complicated
they we do test so now we test so way we test is OK now
testing set and of course we have model five you can
you mention that the amount of five stores of other i
so use i don't know why it was the support vectors
now we do in april that putting support vectors and the true testing vectors and
we get these days
one of the five so is only sixty six percent
and the being of the here this
number is the number of support vectors for must be is the OK this makes
part of the support vectors is how many i the upper bound for number of
five equals c
if someone tells us something because i said that the number of upper bounded off
five i
is are related to the number of training errors
so why this fails sort of thing you know this is that if the training
we get nearly one hundred percent of support vector and other things to ease the
training and testing accuracy
that is they are very different
so what if any you
we mean we
the training data test
twenty five minutes so here we
this is something that we training data and you use earlier models we can block
nineteen ninety percent so you can feel cold the training instances
so you get very high training data as well of course is not good for
hide this thing occurs
so what has happened so here we are using the idea of kernel
o was this is what is the value of c c that the of of
one so his seat seat what what you could
in this form but is common come as the kernel parameters
remember a minor sky sometimes something so here about what is actually one divided by
while is no we have four features so somehow which is divided by the number
of features
and what we can see is
this kind has two situations if i is equal to change things the same training
point is going to be one but it's not because the very very close to
heart so high that if we look consider the training data
we see that all the first features
the ranges of all this is twenty six
and you're like ninety one is positive and one hundred
but about the second feature
well it is much bigger picture is don't hear the two hundred
stress definitely beats
we know that stress and will be normal maxwell's because if n is sufficiently large
the claim
is this
roughly and about thirty two or so already getting
for other reasons not just because it's fun to get better
there you go so this is pretty good this is completely impractical so use whatever
this is
i have the reference and that is just trying to get theoretical there may be
others that are in between and more reasonable
that's not it
lots of time any questions
not done yet any questions before we move on
for matrix multiplication
one more problem
congress abrasion real idea i mean you can use it to dominate countries you can
use it to
to compute multiply matrices i mean what if i
a very different kind of problem you can solve the divine cockeyed is not exactly
an algorithm problem
in some sense
it's computer science that's this is very large scale integration cable chips
very large scale integrated
probably even more these days but that's the catchphrase
so here's the problem
and it arises in VLSI layout
well connected to many details you have some circuit and here i'm going to assume
that the circuit is a binary tree
this is just part of a certain sound down here this is the complete binary
a complete binary tree
looks like this
you know in all my teachings and run this figure for sure the most
my favorite
the height for complete binary tree because they would have something like that some light
i want to embed its
into some should play out on a grid
that's what
the say it has an early
i want to embed into the grid
with minimum area
there's very few prominent really shows you
another way in which divide conquer is
powerful tool
so we have this this tree i like to drive in this way
i want some drawn on the great so what that means is the vertices have
to be embedded on two
that's in the great talking about the square grid so as to go to vertices
of the graph
and the edges have to be routed sort of orthogonal passed between one dollar
another so that should be imagination across the northeast
why is don't like the cross
OK so
there is the obvious way to solve this problem there is the right way
let's talk about the is particularly obvious but divide-and-conquer sought to give you a hint
in the right direction
i even better as something like here
OK i'm going to draw the bottom because it's easier to
four three three grid lines and then started right
we have
i think that's going to be so
the bottom of tree this is like a little
three nodes there
and we just need a blank column
and the playing card
don't actually need to be this one called it makes it pretty dry
OK and then we work away
there's the tree
should be aligned
on a grid no crossings everything's had
how much area does it take
area areas
by area i mean to the the area of the bounding box like out this
blank space even though not using cal this blank space you know using
so i want to look at the height
it's called this
h event
and to look at the web
so called w
now it's probably pretty obvious h events like again
w vendors like and
two and whatever
but i want to write it recurrence because that will inspire us to do the
so each well
if you think of this is the recursion tree in some sense
we start with the big tree was split into two
two subtrees are sort of size and over two and because we're counting leaves exactly
over two on each side
for heights
they serve their in parallel so it's no big deal the height is the height
of this thing one of these two problems plus one
the way you have to add together the two words and also out on one
you don't have to have a one here but it doesn't matter
certainly at most one
so each of
it's just one subproblem size and over two plus state one there you have to
have one
w and
down here in the first place
so that w then is two times w then over two
order one
and the usual base cases
i mean these are recurrences we should know and love
large and it's already given away the answers
a tiny partial recursive function by appealing to
this minimisation property
so we want to find an abacus machine compute the minimize
asian of s
we're not in the next
given that there is already an abacus machine for
the binary function
already has an abacus machine
i have indicated that the diagram
with the thing in
that's the machine is given to understand what it is
now i'm going to create new machine
by adding six to all bit of data around
to compute this thing
so although it will take three more registers of the nine the registers one two
and three
because are used as numbers but let's just call that the
o registers one two and three
we're going to start out with
i came x register one
and we're gonna put zero and registered to
and basically what we're going to do
is trying to see if we can
find a place where
if you guys here
you start out this with one of the arguments is zero
i'm going to change to one changed to change the three
and successively moved through all the images
until we find a place where
if we decide it will be the least place because we started here
well satisfy minimisation thing
so somehow or other compute the values that like that somehow to compute the value
of f
and put it industry
well take some taking value away from three
now if it
it was zero that would be an exception and we'd be done
if when we computed f
and put the value industry
f turned out to be zero
well three whatever value zero
so we can try to take one away
we can exception
so we fall out of here
and we don't
of computer f x zero
if fx zero zero
then we're done and that's the exception
well the other cases of course that
if a computer some non-zero number
in which case
try and take
in which case what we're going to do is clear the register three
for the the next little bit
is the little
it says
clear three
keep on deck remaining
you get no more
numbers that you can take away from registers three
because what we can do is try new i
calculated couple of arguments
we got the number five
well five non-zero so degree successfully take one's own life five
and so left with nothing
and then what we do is
try new active
we now move to register two
and increase the argument that x
that six so we're going to do is now captain knowledge
it's wise and b it's one
so it
incremental i we stand at zero now going try for one and you do the
whole thing again
to get the picture
this little thing will successively
work its way up through the integers trying to find the least place if there
is one
to replicate this experiment and get similar results so it's the same thing here i
took my doctor and told you that it is partitioned into two clusters like this
you want to be able to replicated so you take some other sample of that
and apply
your clustering algorithm you want to see similar results
so it's very naturally the and
replication has been investigated in many applications of clustering the funny thing it's mostly
that the visual inspection and if you look at the papers in social sciences they
do application clustering but they just look at those pictures they like each other no
look at my baby isn't it nice
it's not very satisfying scientific way of doing stuff and we were trying to analyse
OK so the first step to analyse you have to define it precisely so here
is the definition so now we assuming because we want to take random samples we
assume that the idea that there is some probability distribution
so there is some probability distribution over the main to give to the point
and clustering is defined over samples so can take a sample and apply your algorithm
again partitioning of your whole data space
and we need the notion of similarity between different clusterings you what you want to
be able to measure when two clusterings similar not so we have to add to
our structure notion of similarity
which is captured in between those two clusters and for sample size n instability of
my article written on this dataset
is the expected distance if i take two independent samples of size m is the
expected distance between the clusterings of induced by the first sample and the clustering induced
by the same sampling
so much instability is the expected distance between the clusterings that they get by
clustering two independent random samples
as you can see the property of both my clustering algorithm and my data
and of course the sample size
so you have to define this notion of of different way that really true
different settings here one when the number of clusters is fixed in one which is
not fixed and you have to be able to define
in the and fixed number of clusters to be able to define what the distance
between two clusterings over
and there are natural definitions in order to get
into this but
for example natural definition is that
i take random pair of points
and as you what's the probability i as the first clustering do these points belong
to the same clusters all the separate in different clusters
and i can ask the same question of the other
and my
similarity would be the probability that both give the same answer
so you want to take pairs of points and as the two clusterings they
in the same cluster in OPT
and this is the notion of similarity that is
doesn't care about the number of clusters
OK so we we can overcome this problem so that a formal definition of stability
and the first thing you hope to do i don't know how many of you
have been working in classification in statistical learning theory the first thing you want to
get is a uniform convergence results no matter what my
the input space solution is
if i take n large enough things converge
and of course we cannot get it here so for example if my that is
the uniform distribution over the circle and then any clustering algorithm that take will be
because if i just want to partition into into two sets
take a random sample it will probably give me this partition then take another random
sample it will give me the partition
so it would be very unstable in terms of how partitions the point so
on saturday the sets would be very unstable maybe it's a good indication that are
cluster bombs
and the problem of instability could be that depending on the other hand if this
is my that is uniform distribution of the two rings
if i use linkage algorithms that try to connect point
when they are close together then when my
sample size is big enough
i'll get consistent some clusterings always get wondering
the other but if i use the word
not appropriate center based clustering like k means
k means on this picture would be very unstable
even if i just try to means it was just separated like this or like
this or like this depending on the randomness of the sum so
it shows me that stability can be a good indication to what is the right
paradigm the problem
clustering paradigm from a data here linkage based will work
k means will look very unstable linkage based look stable
maybe indication for this type of that
linkage based clustering is that
right now i'm now talking about i switch gears
and i'm now talking about clustering say
in our in
so your point your input points
vectors in rn
and you want to cluster them so we have more information
i there was this discussion of the axiomatic framework for x amount family always try
to address the simplest possible scenario
now i'm talking about something very practical that people do all the time
in many applications of clustering in the usually something done
points of vectors in rn
and i want to analyse these very useful heuristics
so i'm now working my input space is now are in
well i'm saying here is that stability can distinguish between
an algorithm which is appropriate for my dad and i was which is not the
proper time that it can also help me the number of clusters so for example
if this is if my input is a uniform distribution over those
a spheres
then if i choose to try to cluster into two clusters it would be very
unstable because i can get depending on the take a sample and a clustering so
i can either get discussing or that clustering depending on the randomness of the my
sample if a forty two have just two clusters
but on the other hand if a settlement for clusters that'll be stable
so stability can also not just had to choose between different clustering paradigms this can
the second set is and
so k in one in one iteration
i know that in this fixed point there will be at least
all the nodes that are labeled by a
that's already something
but by iterating my fixed point
the computation of my this fixed point
i think it grew
until it stabilizes
now i'm going to iterate
so what is this i have to take the image
one of the set of nodes
which are labeled by
what is the set
his drawings
so i
i think the image have those that already had
union what
in the set of nodes
which basically means
in the second iteration i get all the nodes that are either
labelled by a or
that have it right
which is itself labelled by a so it means that
in this tree for example
the first iteration i capture this node these nodes
how also capture with the second iteration so let me put an end
first iteration so that's one
and the duration to capture OK those once again so i tried to gain
but they get to
which are predecessors
of note fathers
of nodes that are themselves labelled by a
first we keep playing now
what do we would have the next stage you will have
those that are labeled by a
that are
you have to be careful with them saying
whose child
one of the child
belongs to f two
so that means
it has one child
which is either
immediately labeled by a
this is the way capture that this one is contained in this one
it has a child
who has a child which is enabled by a so after the third iteration
i get people that are either already marked or
that of its men one step
i mean one step the full for which i mean you need one more one
two rich somebody who was labeled by a
it's time you iterate this
iteration number
i will give you
that are far from somebody labelled by a with the distance is less than or
the number of iterations you have
so if you take such a computation it means that
if we treat this
what you will
is actually
if you imagine one
this is the
the harpers here so
i need some regularity arguments to make sure mean have a good feeling but the
idea is that you you will
in you fixed point
you will
let me show you the formula that you have here
folks fixpoints you
so i'm a bit
so in general i mean the cardinality of u
you said here really this
is not countable
but i would like you to understand that if
well we would see this but we're going to work on trees that are obtained
by an unfolding
of the finite
structured like you find that could cause structure
so it's likely because structure is finite and i fold it as an infinite tree
actually my interpretation
to compute nodes
if i if i
kind of
interpret it's not as a set of nodes in my tree but instead set of
elements of a set of words in my clicker structure if i iterate
to norway's apprentices one who
has a child who can reach lower blood but just at the level of states
might durations
will stop in the finite amount of steps
so what we see here examples but
if you keep them in just iterating this you should understand that you will catch
with this situation
note for which there exists
distance from this
two node labeled by a
because you take the least fixpoint
so it
what i what i want you to
is just indexed over the eyes
i have the original x variables there are still in writing like i got rhythm and in
other model
i still have the original x variables and are indexed by the set jay from one then
new variables the tea i is the index by the i variables or in the set i
and i want to minimize the sum of the deviations
which is the sum overall indices i
and i two kinds of constraints the lower bound constraints and upper bound constraints are
optimal one line before r but ample actually we after split this out separately
so i have the constraint is subject to you to given names to constraints and there's ample modeling language
and you can of course induction constraints so this is this is
and constraints written in what two lines
and so the constraint was that minus tea so i she is less than it
would be i minus the sum on jay
they i j times x j it's exactly the same as it was
suffer here i have actual subscripts
end and so on
here i have to use a little bit brackets and braces and you have to
learn the syntax a little bit
but it's very easy
and i have the right upper bounds separately that's one of the things that apple requires
also requires you to name all your constraints and you know why you have to name them
because it requires you to now
but the reason they
required you to is because after you've solved the problem you might one know the dual variables
the dual variables are associated with these constraints
if i say
print lower bound for free
i would get the dual variable
associated with without constraint so that's the nice reason why apple requires you to name
all your constraints because that's how you get out the dual variables when you're done
if you want
so we have a few minutes left i want to apply
that's apple model
the data that i showed you before r
and before i apply i wanna take you through a little bit of a thought experiment which is
i don't know
intriguing to me
here's a thought experiment this is about the parametric self dual simplex method
let me summarize how the math and works
we wanna get a zero
on the new line
and we initialize things in such a way
from the new larger than some threshold
where optimal
and then we iterate
and after a while
after a while
we have an interval
newsletters optimal
look at this lower bound and then we do a that based on what what
caused that lower bound and that makes it so that the next iteration
we have a new lower bound
i'm sorry newer bound and the upper bound
the the
this position which was the lower bound becomes the upper bound via a new interval
so as we are walking away toward zero
it looks like this
we have
and plus am inequalities
and because we do the simplex methods correctly
all the inequalities that are to the left of this lower bound are pointing to the right
and some of them are way over here some of the more negative no way out here somewhere
but all of them are pointing to the right
if a bill fore below this place and all the ones above this place are pointing to the left
we got a whole bunch and
when we do not have it
the element that we put on that's that's inequality only flips
today from up from lower bound and upper bound
all the inequalities change in ways that are very hard to predict
because it's all about the algebra that you did and all the linear combinations of
all those rose to do the gauss elimination kind of thing to do all these
inequalities come out looking quite a bit different
you do one pivot and it's hard to predict you know but but there's still
employees among them and they just move around who knows how they move
this from other when the land will over there this well but when the way over here
this one here
the only thing we know is because we a legitimate pivot all the ones that
are on the left of this place
o point to the right
and all the ones that are to the right at this place point to the left
and this particular place points to the left
okay so here's a thought experiment
how many iterations should this algorithm take
if those barriers didn't move and just stay put
well then i would say look i'm playing and plus them numbers on this line at random
probably have a more positive and half the more negative i don't know what the data the problem looks like
why should i think anything else
and have a more positive
know guarantee precision we've developed a strong confidence function of it is and if you
compare it to so textrunner is here in the dashed line this is really substantially
better and the other lines you see here are some follow-up work to textrunner there
was done with different training algorithms so there there are slight improvements over text runner
but again reverb is just substantially better
and the surprise here is that again i step here to discuss my pet peeves
so those are falling asleep with the technical part you wake up for the for
the pet peeves another pet peeve i have is over learning OK machine learning is
great i did my phd thesis and we use it all the time you don't
always have to use machine learning if the set of concepts is small you need
to consider the possibility that writing the knowledge by hand is a more effective approach
than using a fancy machine learning how right that doesn't make sense
if you have billions of concept but here what we're trying to learn is the
model of relations in english and what we found is that at least syntactically it's
a very simple thing
so there's no reason to learn so we naturally assumed in textrunner over years that
we need to take a machine learning approach and we don't and you see this
in other people's work as well i'm not the only one to make the mistake
so again i urge you to consider when you're attacking problem do i really have
to use machine learning
maybe ninety percent of the time the answer is yes sometimes the answer is no
and if that's the case please consider my paper before just projecting working through some
feelings here it's ok so
let me show you how this works and i should mention that this
the system is so simple and easy that we've made publicly available for download right
is an open source project that river this cs the washington edu it's easy to
download it just right on the sentences of your choice we also provided a sample
of our extractions available so you get a sense of what it can do but
let me see if i can
activities that directly
all right
it was
so here's our
really not
nine interface we have a set of of
sample questions that you can ask and which are the questions that it tends to
get good answers and also we have a structured interface where you can say OK
given identity you could ask you know what you know about obama you can ask
what is the relationship and was relationship between apple microsoft but only to start with
some of these questions so i ask asking what kills bacteria and has a very
simple question processor the maps that two OK the predicate here's kills
the second argument is bacteria in here is gathering information across literally thousands of pages
and finds antibiotics kills bacteria
the number here represents how often it founded it's doing a collapsing of
synonyms if i click here on the word i see all the different synonyms it's
collapse if i click here on the number i see the sentences that it came
from i can mouse over and see the URL i can also click through and
go to the URL at this point is somewhat old corpus not going to do
that if i click on a hundred and sixty two more it opens another page
with more answers to what kills bacteria and you start to get a sense of
the richness of the answers that pulls together you get antibiotics at the top but
then you get chlorine cooking alcohol bleach vinegar somewhere down there is honey silver all
kinds of things that kill bacteria and so this is really an example of this
information fusion kind of like in the rest minor reviews showed you right we get
the answers by pulling together information from large number of documents right which is much
better than the answer you get or can be much better than the as you
get if you go to specific document i think we have one of the best
if not the best answer to what kills bacteria anywhere on the web certainly better
i compared with wikipedia we have a better answer the question another thing we've done
is we've mapped to the
three freebase ontology so i can ask it things like what sports originated in china
in here it gets the sports and filters things through the freebase ontology so discard
a lot of the result and we see that you might not have known the
so basically you have that they
is independent
of b
but c is not independent of
c is not independent
of the
so can these represent the vision that
and these represent the market
so in other words
i would like to think
they have
and c
here i have to construct the bayesian networks
here i have to construct a markov random field
so here i need to add
basic errors in here have any
can i find
a bayesian network
where these home
can i find the market for a few
so that's the question i mean i would ask you to think about this
any ideas
so first let's think about the markov random field
it is a if a is independent of b
in the microphone feel them assuming there are no observations here OK
if a is independent of b
what that means
well it means that the the a
is isolated in the ground
are these isolated
you cannot have an edge between a and b
which you can not have an edge between a and c and b and c
so this is no good here
this is nowhere near
maybe this will be good
or maybe even this
but this cannot be true because you know that season not independent of b
and this implies that seems independent
so you must have a
is that so it is independent of b
is not independent office so there's problem
the film is to be
in this case is independent of office so i need to have these
but now suddenly a and b are not independent anymore and then you can try
to move on matrix you want here
there's no way
you're going to construct a markov random field where the whole
bayesian networks
so let's do the same type of reasoning
well what are the possible bayesian networks that we have
well in tree node with so few options so basically
this is one option
is it with this is that
is independent of b here
this is not from the powerful is not good
what you suggest
so a is independent of
of the but maybe we have something like this
for example
but then
see that cannot be independent of
bad as well
that doesn't work
it doesn't work needed
because we know that c is not independent of me
movies what
is there is going to work
so remember we actually saw this example previously right
so basically
if we want to construct a graph nodes
well those three conditional independence statements they hold
these three here
we need to have in this case the vision networks omicron if you want to
do the trick
likewise we can already
tell you the answer for the article yes
so i'm going in
it is in the OK
c is not independent of a
scene is not independent
so how many possible solutions first we know that a is independent of b
so there can be no pads
between a and b
so one possible so this cannot thing cannot happen
a b
because in this case is not independent of b
because i'm not observing invited remember if i also see
that is independent of b
because the factorisation for this we saw but
the factorisation for these is the following should be used only the blue one
is equal to one over z
a sea of
xie xie
times CBC
of XB XC i'm just using him mister klee four here
so this remember that the joint probability distribution of the markov random fields
is given by products of potential functions over the cliques
this is the first maximal cliques
the the second of march mostly
i have a function here on these maximal clique a functional is much more likely
to have the normalisation function here
if i want to compute
of a b
in order to have independence between a and b
p of a b must be equal to p of a
times he of the right
but when they compute
the sum
over c of these quantities here
and in particular it turns out that the many programs that many applications that you
can't program by hand
for example
if you want to get the computer to meet handwritten characters beats of handwritten digits
that turns out to be amazingly difficult to right
a piece of software
to take an it to take as input image of something that i wrote in
figure out just what it to translate my my my cursive handwriting
in two on into
in two
to extract the characters that i wrote out in longhand on and other things all
one thing to missus i do is autonomous flight turns out to be extremely difficult
to sit down and write a program to fly a helicopter
the in contrast if you want to do things like these right
to get some five helicopter have software recognise hermitage it's on
one very successful approaches to use the learning out have computer learned by itself how
to say recognise handwriting almond valley heritage direct recognition this is pretty much the only
approach that works well on the source of applications the hard to program by hand
the neon reference is also made
i guess sigma in rows and was sometimes called database mining on
so for example with the growth of ITN computers
on increasingly many hospitals are keeping around medical records of what sort of patients what
problems they had with the prognosis was what the outcome was and taking all these
medical wreckers which started be started to be digitized only about fifteen years ago on
a apply learning our so that we can turn raw medical records in two
well i mean music of medical knowledge in which we start to detect trends in
medical practices and even starts all to medical practices result of of medical knowledge derived
by applying learning algorithms symmetrical not by applying learning algorithms
so the source of medical not recognise the hospitals have just been built over the
last you know fifteen twenty years in electronic format
it turns out that most of you probably use learning algorithms and i think half
a dozen times that they are maybe a dozen times they all more
and often without
knowing it
so for example every time you send email via the US postal system
it turns out
there is however that tries to automatically right we'd zip code you wrote on your
and that's down violently
so every time you send us mail using the learning algorithm perhaps even more
perhaps without even being aware of it some of the every time you write a
cheque i actually don't know the number for this but a significant fraction of checks
the right are process by learning algorithm to learn to be the digits of the
dollar amount the road down the tracks everything re-checked there's another learning algorithm that you're
probably using without you being aware of it on
if you think it use a credit card or i know this one phone company
was doing this and lost it completely EV as well that the two electronic transactions
there's a good chance that there a learning algorithm in the back and try to
figure out if they are cut cost is still there if someone is engaging in
fraudulent transactions
if user web like like amazon and netflix that you know often recommend books e
by movie theater and whatever
these are other examples of learning algorithms to have learned what sorts of things you
like to buy was also movies you like to watch
i can therefore give customize recommendations to you
and just about a week ago i had car services and even then my my
my car mechanic was trying to explain to me some learning algorithm and in his
of my car this the thing is best optimise like driving performance and fuel efficiency
also think most of us learn most of us use learning algorithms you know half
doesn't doesn't maybe dozens of times without even knowing it on
and of course learning hours also doing things like giving us the growing understanding of
the human genome so it if some whether find a cure for cancer of the
average will have had a large role in that sort of thing that homework
so in teaching the scores on i have
so for three girls on one of them is just to help convey some of
my own excitement about machine learning to you on
the second goal is
by the end of this scores i hope
all of you will be able to apply state-of-the-art machine learning algorithms
two whatever problems you are interested in and if you ever need to
the system for writing reading zip codes you know how to do that by the
end of this class
on and lastly
by the end of this scores i realized that only a subset of you are
interested in doing research in machine learning but by the conclusion of this cause i
hope that all of you actually be well qualified to start doing research in machine
so it's a few words about logistics on the prerequisites of this class are written
on the on side one the handouts on are as follows
this was going to assume that all of you have so the basic
knowledge of computer science and a basic knowledge of the basic computer skills and principles
so assume of you know what big o notation is all you know about the
data structures like used as binary trees and all of you know no programming skills
to write read a simple computer program
it turns out that most of the class will not be very programming in terms
of the we will do some programming mostly you need matlab octave it's a bit
more about that later
also assume familiarity with basic probability and statistics
so most undergraduate statistics class lights that one sixteen twenty years that the
will be more than enough when thought you know what random variables although you know
what expectation is with the variance around the variable is
and if in case some of you it's been a while since i've seen some
hero at some of the discussion sections will actually go over some of the prerequisites
services refresher course on the appearance across the states a bit more about that later