templates so the table is one is likely to find the target
the same thing in this world
it provides areas and typology and they were not just in
this kind of features and not just as they are but just simple that filters
and again trying to localize them a little bit more love respective to the central
location of the object and then there is also the world by jimmy and collaborators
in which they try to have fragments of edges that they will tied to detect
and image and each fragment will vote for what they think is the centre of
an object
and the same work was also done by opel's instances
then there is another family of features
and that are also based on edges but they try to have a representation of
edges is more flexible so instead of having
and edge has been the basic representation where they have the histograms of orientations for
instance one of the most famous ones SIFT in which to take a bunch of
an image distract management in that patch and then four different bins divided into the
state by two
especially windows and at each window you can't count how many edges have a particular
so to build this histograms and that's going to be just presentation for that pixel
and the same thing can be done with shape contexts in which they on the
basic difference is that the been is donna bullock instead of being donnerstag great but
it's basically the same representation so at each point is going to have notion of
what's the structure of edges around that point but being very flexible just like histogram
so it's not an exact edge as the press as the previous representations
that simple representation can be have to be very useful for object recognition although it
was developed first on the much much in the main for object recognition has been
shown to be able to very powerful so there is this work by the intrigues
in which what they do is they take an image
and the representation is going to be for this track edges
and then they take a small patches and again they do this histogram in of
different orientations in the part that's going to be the basic presentation
and they are going to apply some normalisation so that everything seems to one of
his like that and those normalisation to become more important in order to get this
things to work to perform the maximum performance but then the idea is that once
you have transformed the imagine to be representation in which each pixel now contains this
vector instead of RGB values contains these vectors encodes the structure of the big so
now you can apply something like template matching and not to the object detection
so what they do is to train a linear SVM
so in that case will just be template matching
i mean setting which they have examples of pedestrians
but just the content pages that do not contain pedestrians and then the idea is
that you take
target image
for which you are looking for testers you will start all possible pages from this
let's say you think this but here
you extract this orientation my
and then to apply to have them play that you have learned from the SVM
so this will be the template will have some negative and positive weights and if
the value of the first of these properties more than a particular threshold with the
site of the person is not present and
i don't know if these
in the product of the template for by the features that define this part out
of a certain threshold and you will see the persons present so this is basically
the template matching just like what i was arguing before that even really make any
sense to apply
here they apply it it and they are getting really good results
so of course if johnconstable presentation and you have more flexibility for instance your parts
instead of having just read template matching the things work a lot better and so
in this case there is the world wide fund so that and collaborators in which
what they do
is they apply exactly the same idea that this template matching with orientation maps
but they are going to introduce also parts each part is going to be detected
also as if it was a single object so it's also going to be defined
by the same template matching operation
but all the different parts are going to vote for the presence of a particular
object so will have a global template and also templates that will look for parts
and they will put all these things together
and then will define an object so for instance the template for the last three
and this will be the template that will correspond to the global pattern of
orientation maps that will define the best
and these will define the different parts of the find pedestrian
so you can see that here there there are more details you can see the
face appeared in some of the shoulders and so on
and despite its
have a particular location so that you don't want them to move to match
and they have some weight that will tell you know who you are going to
penalize when this plots against the far from their original locations
so here are some of the kind of
four bottles guys so fast bicycles
exactly what secretary fairly well for genetic of this is not a solved problem but
not conducive for many things
so here are are some examples of detections from the skull of the set and
so here are the actions of this there's no reason to think that the visions
of shape note people people people and this is a false alarm so it's nice
when her false alarm the kind of funny and so here is the victim bottles
this but also for his personal is like motel
here is protecting cars
here's the thing cultures
if you have a have false alarm
but they relatively was relatively well in general
so so that they were not you can use in order to build something more
forest service
to express
lens law that it is always opposing
the change of the
we have a minus sign here
minus sign will never bother you believe me because you always know in which direction
the EMF is
it's clear that the EMF
it's going to be
in this direction that's the direction in which it
will make the current flow
but we have to put it there
be mathematically correct that's really lens law you're looking at lens law
so you can also write down for this
the surface integral of the don't be a
that open who appeared in cities
one is open surface
that's the third
look what i did i forgot to DDT in front of integral sign sorry for
if you put yourself inside the conductor
and you march around in the direction of the current
you will see everywhere in the wire in the electric field of course otherwise
there would be no current flowing
so if you go once around this whole circus
that you may have
we must of course also be
delta l
the closed loop
so you're watching inside the wire
you find everywhere
the electric field
and these little sections
i dl
ian dl always in the same direction if you stay in the wire
and so
this should be
the same
and it is a closed loop
so this is all if you want
what we call
fire this role
we never see it in so much detail
i will abbreviated a little bit
on the board there
but i wanted to appreciate that there is no battery in this area
there is only a change in the magnetic flux
through surface that i have attached
two the conducting wire
and then i get an induced EMF
an induced EMF
well put those occurrence given by ohms law
so i want to write down on that blackboard there
so far there is law in a somewhat abbreviated way because
we have all
maxwell's equations here
and so we now have that the
closed loop integral
a closed loop
if you don't pl
that's that induced EMF
you can take minus the phi
all the time derivative of the integral bwt a that's the one i will take
of the don't be a
and and this is over an an open service
and that open surface has to be attached
to this little
and that is violated a
we've got law
we and law
we have this one which tells you the magnetic monopole don't exist
this would only not be zero
if you had a magnetic monopole and put it in close to
come and see me if you find one
and this now is by this law
so you think that all four maxwell's equations are now complete
not quite
going to change this one
course even here we still have to return to another issue that we considered before
it is life itself
we're having is the very fact that you're alive itself a good thing
these are the valuable container theories which i previously contracted with the neutral container theories
you recall that according to the neutral container theories and thinking about the quality of
someone's like you just look at the contents
life itself is only a container good or bad you know what is filled up
but opposed to the neutral container theories we had a valuable container theories would say
that the very fact that you're alive
and some positive value above and beyond what was going on in your life
even the valuable container theories came in different versions there were more modest versions were
in principle
the positive value of being alive could be outweighed if the content got bad enough
and we contrast that with fantastic container theories according to which being alive is so
valuable that doesn't matter how bad the contents get the grand total is always positive
wanna look if you accept a fantastic container theory
then pretty clearly it's never true
that somebody could be better off dead
because no matter how bad the contents get
the fact that they're alive per say is so valuable it always that the sum
giving us positive grand total
pretty clearly from the perspective of fantastic container theories suicide will never be
rational because it's never true that you're better off dead because it's never true that
your life overall taking everything relevant into consideration gives us the negative
the question was
and the fantastic container theories what so incredible about life itself always tainted intrinsically valuable
and yes the answer is precisely the fans of the valuable container theories are saying
being alive itself is valuable
you may recall that i previously said other people talk the way they probably don't
actually mean
right it's not OK to be alive is the blade of grass they wouldn't say
oh wouldn't be wonderful that would have been most fans of the claim to be
alive per say is valuable don't really mean like for say they mean something more
like light
and as a person
because you have been kind of entity who can think and plan even if that
what your plans go wrong at least you were a person able to experience things
no things and so forth
if that's the reason for accepting the fantastic container theory
that we might wonder what should we say about those cases where
that the
p functioning has decayed and the person is no longer able to continue as a
person but perhaps can still feel pain
in that case perhaps life could cease to be worth living though
you know whether or not we should describe it that way also depends on these
complicated issues that we've discussed previously about with that still be you would you still
exist would you still be alive under those circumstances so the basic idea
behind valuable container theories is that life for the life of a person or something
like that has intrinsic value above and beyond the question of what's going on with
in your life
if we accept the fantastic container theory
maybe nobody's life is ever so bad grand total
this led to set of the rational thing to do because the value of life
per say so incredible that always the content it has to with the content that
that's that the philosophical view at the opposite end of the pessimists
the person said as a matter of philosophical reflection we can see that everybody's life
is worse than nothing
the fantastic container fans
the a matter of philosophical reflection we can see that everybody's life is better than
most of us i imagine find ourselves somewhere in between either we believe in the
neutral container theory i think it's a contentious matter whether the contents are sufficiently good
or bad
or we may accept the modest version of the valuable container theory
on that theory of course life
has some intrinsic value but it's kind of finite intrinsic value and in principle even
that could be outweighed if the contents get bad enough
so again it will be an empirical question we have to take a look and
in which case is do the contents get bad enough
i guess on one of these people in the middle
i'm inclined to think it's not true that everybody's life is worse than nothing nor
is it true that everybody's life is better than nothing it varies from person to
person and indeed not just since we think about what i want talk about their
life as a whole really what does life promise from here on out
sadly to to sad to say
it seems to me there are cases and probably most of us are familiar with
cases where the correct description given that your favourite theory of well-being is going to
be that
for this person
here on out what life has to offer is sufficiently bad so the contents are
sufficiently negative as to outweigh whatever value like itself might have
you can imagine somebody in the
terminal stages of some illness
the cancer perhaps is causing them a great deal of pain
and the pain so bad that they can't really do much of anything else it's
not as though they can continue working on their their novel or continue talking with
the members of their family because they just distracted by the pain and wishing it
would come to an end horribly enough many degenerative diseases leave the person less and
less capable
of doing the things that like value
and the very realization that you're in that situation no longer able to
spend time doing things are hanging out with your family or or talking to whatever
it is it may itself be a source of more frustration and pain
there are
medical conditions where horribly enough infants get born
where they're just in in continual pain and they never developed cognitively the brain doesn't
open and they died
and you look at these lives and you say these are lies i want to
say these are lives that were not worth having
these children would have been better off never having been born at all certainly not
any kind of favour for them to continue their lives
well let's focus on some cases like
the the terminal patient
persons got disease was that would be nice easy example not easy to live through
body easy philosophically easy example think about some terminally ill patients whose disease is getting
worse and worse and so there are fewer and fewer of the good things in
the the future holds for them instead what the future holds is more and more
pain suffering incapacity and frustration
when it gets bad enough it seems to me in some of those cases the
the lower the probability of y given x
it is
it is it is possible for the weight wj to be negative
and if the weight wj is negative
then a big via the feature function
it's going to reduce the problem to y
OK so much
i'm feeling a bit of a chicken and egg problem and talking about log linear
models because because everything is connected by
these weights
which are the equivalent of the vedas i had before that the parameters are going
to have a learning algorithm for that
and so
what we actually do is we define feature functions
and then
the and in the feature functions we define the feature function that measures some property
of x and y
and then the learning i was going to learn whether or not that probability has
an affinity with
why being more likely has an affinity with y being less likely
once the value of the function is
and it's pre-defined then the way that actually tells us
but when we define when when when when the human defines the function in the
human is going to define functions
that he thinks so she thinks is going like it have affinity maybe
the easiest if i were
move on to my
trying to
something examples
my car so
x equals sentence
y equals
tag sequence
so this is the same part of speech example then i have my
fj of x and y
it would be
you know axis
it starts with
a capitalized word
like you also to start with capitalized words that's not
so just
the second word is capitalized
second tag
proper noun
after a x y is second was capitalizing second tag is proper noun
feature functions are real valued but are very common special case of the feature function
is that the zero one valued
and so here's the feature function has zero one value
the second sentence starts with a capital letter
and the second tag is proper nouns
chances are that when we train this model
we're going to find that
the weight w j
is large and positive
what that means
what what that's what that's going to do is going to say that everything else
being equal
this feature function is switched on
tag sequence y
it is more likely
so here's another feature functions have
x and y
first word is capitalized
and first tag
is probably now
first tag is proper noun
must so
you know that this is also zero one feature that we can measure
that any sentence and any tag sequence first word is capitalized and first
tag is proper noun
there are going to be lots of sentences
well there are going to be lots of x y pairs well y
this the correct answer for x
but this feature function
those are going to be sentences which have the first word capitalized but at first
one is not a proper noun
and so
the weight
w fourteen that we learn for this feature
is going to be
pretty small
but the weights
it is this feature
the weight w fifteen we love this feature is going to be pretty big
if this feature is true
then y
tends to be
the correct answer for x
OK so these examples of william functions
and billion functions are special case of real valued functions and in general feature functions
are allowed to be real valued
but there are often
and they are allowed to be
positive or negative there are allowed to take any take on any real value
one of the most
among the
so how does that relate to what we had before
so this is the distribution in r two
and i just happened to give specific names for those coordinates namely height and weight
in general and might have maybe fifty images
of maybe apples and i might want to find out you know how much acid
they contain
i might have been also assume that somehow by from those images those readings of
acidity are correlated
so overall
we assume that we have some covariance matrix k
and all the while alive
so i might have some general correlation time which is parameterized by some function k
of x i and x j
what happened to be the same thing as a kernel that we did before
and i might have some an additive noise term
they can actually be derived is in a bit more detail what you say well
i've got some
parameter here
and drawing some variables from that some
latent variables t
and then
from that i'm getting some additive noise and actually get the observations y
just very much
short-circuited that
to save some time here
if i have
what i get is that
my overall covariance matrix
it's going to be
just as kernel matrix k
something added to the main diagonal
so this is a reasonable model of assuming
how a bunch of scalars are correlated
well depending on what my prize and how those very
is remembered for light
well i get a different distribution
i could just go and as well what's the probability of what crime given y
now of course
i know that this is normally distributed
because conditioned on some variables in normal given normal back
and after a lot of linear algebra
well actually don't really do it yourself you just look at the book like paul
which has everything in there about matrices that you never want to derive yourself
so wonderful book
this guy probably spent a couple of years just compiling matrix identities
so if you haven't got that book is required
this guy apparently for several years did nothing else but whenever he thought of
something useful for matrix he wrote it up in the end he compiled
i think it's like thirty dollars because
the great thing
what you can basically do is you look at the big
we look at this because variance matrix
with that the variables into those people served in those that happened observed
then collect the linear and quadratic
and then you just rewrite that back into normal it
into normal so this really not much else in there
but what you get is you get this
as the resulting covariance matrix for y prime given y
and this is the mean
yes of course
know that this action of formality so let's discuss the various terms
this species is symmetric that's the covariance matrix between the y fronts
so this thing so for instance i might have a thousand training observations and might
have fifty test observations
so this is actually associated tall and skinny matrix
p fifty by
one thousand so
couldn't even be semantically anyway
so this is like the the carbon center covariance matrix of a gate
just by observing the y fronts and
having observed the wise will reduce the variance in the y fronts
subtracted something from it
and the variance reduction will be large
if one y prime strongly correlated
and and also
if the y
i'm not very noise
if there was very noisy
in this covariance matrix will be large so one of the covariance matrix for very
small so the overall time
what you're doing is you're taking into account how noisy the y are
not wise are
and how strongly the wise and the y fronts are correlated
that's what gives you the very
for the mean i just get the original meaning that they would have had to
anything else
the need to correct
and correcting upon the surprise of seeing why rather than you
this is of course why why
what they assume how noisy the why store
if they're very noisy then i'm not going to get much about it
and by how strong otherwise electrons are correlated
so for instance if the what what crimes are uncorrelated and this will not natural
the other interesting thing is that of course this matrix here
it has to be positive semidefinite
because the main of the residual covariance has to be nonnegative
sometimes you can use such into theta take with the matrix is positive semidefinite for
instance take that this whole
and that furthermore
this matrix itself is positive semidefinite
sometimes that's also referred to as the sure complement
if somebody writes about that don't be scared
is it just fancy name
is a a couple of functions
and not very surprisingly all of our friends of kernels will just for fun
seeing all of those
you would think is completely trivial obvious inside
it's not true that it's trivial
so as i already mentioned kriging does exactly that
garson processes the same thing
svm so the same thing
so there are still books which say
well we work on least squares support vector machines
which are essentially gaussianprocess regression with a slightly different interpretation
and those three streams and people are still publishing in different areas and then always
really mixing
the results which is
a bit sad because it just means that sometimes we have to prove the same
results three times
but basically
you can show
support vector regression with a squared loss
and process regression are the same thing
the key difference being that if you use casting process regression you actually get an
estimate of the variance
so what you get
which is really useful
is an idea of how reliable or unreliable you this
this we will get that
yes to have
the short answer is just use whatever you using synchronous SVM
but that's not a very satisfactory and so i guess
long and so is you could for instance put the prior
on the covariance function
and then integrate that out
and then maybe i could try on your prior
and keep on doing this
as soon as you go beyond the standard cost model
a lot of those things and also he's anymore and then you need to use
sampling or variational methods to get anywhere
basically you need to talk to nando
we show you how it works
some training data
that is if you this
question from
the first time
implications of vision
and so in one of the biggest image
uses computation
applications that
so is the same as
and the
doing inference
this as far possible so far
you cannot expect to understand express we pushed solution seems to expressed some sense
keep like that
it could be
in fact the g three x three computer science
this is just an interesting because this competition
competitions because because we have to inside
because it
this is going to push sum missions inside
so just
this is something like that
so so so that
so i mean that's
it's just as well keeping a bunch of them unchanged
so that's the same imagine extract
it's just factor just in different ways
what about
first thing is true
the next three years percent ago
next to it
right so this is a few minutes
history is just passing messages from leaves
six months which is operations
but it's
exactly this
it's exactly this is another way of doing this
three this kind of got
you know it's
not so we have the specifications to messages
what happens to the the messages factor
simple thing that's gone
that's it
thing that's gonna change
so you think about it
and this that
and so this separation is straightforward
so you can see that the operations of extreme this is only sixty
and so that's it
that's the that's applications
so it's here
you you have because that's from the structure of business
the fact
that's coming back to the fact that with the same
actually sourced production from here it you is
it's exactly this
right so
this is a list of that
exact expression which which is marginalized out
the next one
you can see this is because we have
in after
after the visit him as opposed to
you before
examples street
using a factor in the computation tree
messages like this this is so because it's on the structure of the population is
the same
and you know you get exactly this
so this is a
the structure is actually quite efficiently
which was
ninety percent of people efficient this is
the story is set of models
right so
so successful was is
it it is
this is known as
according to them and things like that it's exactly this
so this is
these things
so it's
into the details
this is not useful
graphical models since the seventies which have been used in many different applications that
speech recognition that has been applied to many applications ever since so this mentioned
the sequence of this is
so this means it is it one and so
sixty minus one xtxt plus one these observed
the first step so this is first one factor graph and in
the problem is that you have
what is it that you
it can be solved
OK example relates to the example which is used in speech recognition
he was
it's not about
the sixty this is the case with three outside
this guy lebanon
so you will see that this person is going to allow the you to
mining and chance of rain
it just
about these two p atomic wavefunctions that are centered on the carbon right we're not
done yet
right so what's going to happen
so that will there no overlap
constructively and destructively interfere
and i
to see the
let's take this benzene molecule and rotated ninety degrees so that we're going to look
at it
from the side and view that you
so there it is right here are my carbon carbon sigma bond
two sp two two two sp two bonds
here's my arm
sigma bond between the hydrogen on the carbon two sp two wave function
and now i'm going to let the
two p
atomic wavefunctions not ivory functions the atomic wavefunctions and the carbon i'm going to let
constructively and destructively interfere
OK and here goes well they're going to overlap
i got
something that looks like
a pi bond here
i've got
weight function above the plane of these and i got weight function below
the plane of these atoms
it is a pi bond
that is formed by the overlap of the two p
wavefunctions the atomic wavefunctions are
right it's part
because it's not symmetric around the
now all of the body axis
there's density up here density up here
but not in the plane
let's look at it again from the top you
right so what i do well i lack
these two p wave functions here
so let's look at a little more carefully what exactly do they do here
so what i did
is for example
i let the two p wave functions and these two carbons overlap to form a
pi bond
i love the two p wave functions and these two carbons overlap
to form a pi bond
and i like these two
two p wave functions overlap to form a pipe that
well that's very nice
i could also
the last
two p wave functions and these two carbons overlap for these two problems
in other words i could have made a pi bond between these two carbons
are these two carbons schools
these two parent
so which one do i chose
in recitation the other day
you should have a look at the
lewis structure
of molecular benzene and benzene
and what you should have seen
is that you would be able to write several different lewis structures all which have
the the same set
of the formal charges
and you wouldn't be able to decide which structure you should here
based on the formal charges
rather what you had is the resonant structure
and that is exactly what you hear
instead of
the six x for electrons
which are centered on the carbon those two pi electrons right one year one there
one one their one there one there
instead of those
each one of those electrons being shared between just one of the adjacent carbons
o six extra electrons are actually d localized
around all the carbons
and so what you're going to form a year is not
a clear
o double bond between the carbon and this one and this one
instead what you're going to form
a kind of the whole
of pi bonds
that is you're going to let those six electrons
be equally distributed so to speak
around all all the six carbons
and so this pi bond here
isn't quite a full pi bond it's kind of a
right because
this current sharing its two p electron with carbon and with this current
and vice versa
thank all the way around
so we have this resonance structure i drew this is kind of of fuzzy
green line here we have the six pi electrons that are localize
amongst these six atoms of this part the brain
so these are the ones
i really
abandoning him
they are these bonds this band
is of more than a single bond
in terms of its bands train
and in terms of its distance it's closer than single bonds
but it isn't as strong as a double bond
it follows this thing here
and then you can then take the covariance
book but the expectation here in the in the middle so what you get here
in the middle is the lagged covariance matrix of this is the source signals and
you will have a and eighty
multiplying it on both sides that the point is that the way it lack covariance
of the rest of the source signals will be diagonal
by definition
well it it it really that it be diagonal simply because the sourcing site independent
and well also we we have to make the assumption that we actually we really
do have some kind of time dependence is some of the correlations which means that
which then implies that this this is really a non-zero by matrix
what this means is that basically
uh this is what i my i guess what this means is that basically
what we need to do is and i can value decomposition we have here matrix
that's well not exactly symmetric but you can take the semantic relation of that by
adding it with its transpose and this is a symmetric matrix is expressed as the
product of an orthogonal matrix by a diagonal matrix times the transpose of the of
the so this is nothing but i can barely legal
we can estimate a
and only if
the eigen value decomposition of that's like covariance matrix of the data
is diagonal
actually i think there was a small area here
so basically i mean here we should be talking about the lack covariance matrix of
z that is that the white and data
well the basic idea is to change so now if and only if document decomposition
is unique we can actually actually get a direct from the eigen value decomposition
now the question is that when you say i can value decomposition unit for symmetric
real valued matrix well it is unique
if if all those i can values are distinct
if not so i can values to one like and values which are equal to
each other than the eigen vectors are no longer uniquely defined because you can make
any kind of arbitrary rotation inside that subspace defined by those two i can to
one y
after this would is that we all that's going that is computationally very simple we
only need to do the eigen value decomposition we see that the bad news is
that is that it doesn't work always basically if all these all sources signals have
the same statistical properties meaning for example that they have the same order correlations then
this method doesn't really work at all
because the eigen value decomposition will be
completely undetermined
but still it in some cases it gives you a very simple and very simple
solution the problem
some improvements to these
the situation can be obtained by
looking at several time lag is not only one has been these basic case well
then what happens is that the computations are more complicated you can just solve it
by eigen value decomposition but then
but then you have more chance of actually separating sources
but still we have we even even if they use
arbitrary number of different time next we still have this fundamental limitation that if you
if there is the features of if the source signals have identical fourier spectrum which
means which is true for example if that if you
if the source signals have the same statistical properties
and then
this method just just doesn't work
the point is the point here is that
if you have two random signals
which have the same
that is the same according to spectra
then any some
in some of these signals which has the same variance the original signals we'll have
again the same the same for respect
and this very but the situation is very different from the case of ICA that's
so that if we have two variables so random variables
non gaussian random variables and we take some
what is this component perpendicular you can just
feel new stuff like that that is the one that is responsible
that is the electric field in the travelling wave that moves outwards because this whole
shell moves out was speed c
and load is this one is perpendicular to the the direction that i have chosen
of propagation
you're watching here
and they shall comes over you
and so do you feel that is perpendicular to line of sight that is the
field in the traveling wave
so our task is now
to calculate
e vector
well if you look at the fact that this triangle
is congruent with this one
then you see that the perpendicular
divided by parallel
he perpendicular divided by parallel must be you perpendicular to
divided by c delta t
but you perpendicular
we noted you
is a
so you perpendicular
is a perpendicular party
a perpendicular is now the component of the acceleration perpendicular to are i don't want
to pull value because it becomes too cluttered with you
i will make new drawing shortly put you in their accelerations in this direction and
so a perpendicular is like this
so i can replace
you perpendicularity
i can replace it by a perpendicular
sorry this is a perpendicular delta t you guys should have
shy guy should screen because
the acceleration only last for about thirty seconds
only delta t sec
so now i get a perpendicular time delta t times t
divided by c delta t
so there is a perpendicular
times t
divided by c
if no
i can calculate what you parallelise
i'm done because i know the perpendicular is
i put the parallel here
and i am
in business
before i do that i want to eliminate t
and i'm going to write for the st
are divided by c
so it is also a perpendicular
times are
divided by c squared
and so i can write down perpendicular is this times parallel
how do we find the parallel
o eight o two
gauss law
i make a pillbox
and the pillbox is going to be like this i'll make a drawing of it
and this surface is here in the world doesn't know yet what happens
and this surface here is in the world which is in turn more
which is in the transition
so i'm going to make that pillbox for you
so i draw here again this
this is aligned to go somewhere to this point here is not this one the
and here is my pillbox
that's my pillbox
and so on
in that little box
i have in the outside world
the outside world here i have that if you want
so i'll put it in and e it's in the world that doesn't know yet
what happened
that's really going to point o
inside the box i have this property portfolio coming in like this
and then going straight through the sides of the box is this one in particular
but this comes in
and perpendicular
and that the perpendicular
goes out
now since this is in vacuum
there is no charge density inside this box
so the divergence of e must be zero
and that means that
the vector here
must be exactly the same as the vector here
because the contribution to these two is zero so this must also be here there
is no charge inside the box
but i do know what this is field this
that is a don't do
if someone tells you that i have the charge here
sitting there
what is the electric field edit distance are that school of law
this is simple is not causal or it's the gauss law
but in any case you will find very easy that this is a vector
is q
divided by
four pi
absolutely absolute zero hours credit falls off as one of our square
you people should remember that from eight o two
so now
we have accomplished
thirteen minutes are almost up
he perpendicular now
it is therefore a perpendicular times are
divided by c squared
times q
divided by four pi
absolutely zero
times are square
you lose one are
and so this
is the classic derivation
also known in the
already were known in the nineteen late nineteenth century
which is now the
electric vector
the strength of the factor which clearly is responsible for the electromagnetic travelling wave because
is perpendicular to my direction or that i have chosen
it is inversely proportional to are
i will come back to that
that is a natural consequence of the conservation
of energy
and this field is very different from static electric fields which fall off is one
of the great
this is the traveling wave which is in the field that falls off
as one of our
not as one of our squared
before i write down the final four
we also have to take into account the fact that there is a time delay
if i observe so i am an observer
the fourier basis
and i may actually be able to acquire single by sending in time which is
what analog to digital converters do
and so the
measures are functions are just the sense it is the function that
given information are simply rocks and then i can calculate the coherence between the canonical
basis of the spike basis in the fourier basis and which was this calculation we
see that all the coefficients are all the same equal to one of his code
and so on and square them and multiply by ten
all this coffee quantity is equal to one and therefore the coherence between time and
frequency is one
and because we've seen that the coherence cannot be less than one what it says
is that spikes in sinusoids are maximally incoherent that is time and frequency our
four five
as it can be in this view of the world
does this make sense
OK and in english it means that despite
looks nothing like the sun that i need a lot of sinusoids to make up
with spike
or that i need a lot of spikes to make up the signs say are
very very different objects one is completely localized the completely global
OK so this is good because we we want no coherence and then we'll see
what you would want to have in in in in pair five size that it
achieves local humans
so for example you may ask what's since i want to use wavelets to do
my image reconstruction what is a going korean was wavelets well lots of things one
thing that i like are those let's introduced by roughly kauffman even a year and
it's kind was an interesting paper because it published
a paper in the early nineties saying this is the system that serves absolutely no
purpose is because it sparsifies nothing
in in particular it does not sparsify wavelets at all and so knows that kind
of random checkerboard
waveforms that looks like this in two d
and the ideal for this compressed sensing applications because incoherent with wavelets and they come
with a very fast algorithm which is useful in applications and when you calculate numerically
is the coherence between let's and wavelet get something which is almost minimal between one
and three
OK and again it's because we know is that it's very localized in in space
were wavelets are extremely low
this is one way to make measurements which
are incoherent in this just to
drawing upon randomness and so
if you just tried to design sensors that essentially correlate with girls in white night
so i i d plus minus one
saying that look like this
then of course
that will be incoherent with everything that is my main by by just design so
you actually have random sensors that are acquiring information about it
the signal of interest by essentially correlated the signal with random waveforms was IID idea
entries is are calcium all binary entries that will be incoherent with anything that is
and so
if you believe that no coherence is a good thing then this is a very
serious proposal because
what i would ask is to design sensors that essentially correlate an object with junk
and that's a bit of a scary proposition and i remember like soon after i
discovered early results in compressed sensing and visited the university and i visited a friend
of mine and i thought i was
i was giving an overview of the talk will be the next day was that
wisconsin actually and this friend of mine told me is a change in talk
o you go away and you go back to california
because you know suggesting that we should design sensors things was like now is whether
we are in two thousand four
OK but the picture is this which is that there's something very sparse that we
wish to sense
something that looks like this something is extremely concentrated except we don't know where
and so we have on the one side sparsity which we have is this kind
of concentrated factor and on the other side has is incoherent measurement which looks like
completely localised wave forms and so
the signal is calls but the measurements are global
and the point of this global measurements is that each measurement picks up a little
information about each component
for example if i have six opposes time
and suppose i have sparse signal in time for example let's say it has only
one spike
so everything is zero but this guy
and then it's zero
and i want to subsamples the signal in time well that is not possible
because if i if i measures this
here here here here here
in i skip this point and of course i missed everything second out samples the
signal that's not possible
but what will see is that we can subsampling very efficiently in an incoherent domain
by making measurements that look like this
OK so now let's look at compressed sensing
and incoherent sampling
OK so now
we have this sensing waveforms phi k
we have our image of interest which we call we
correlating we sensing way from phi k and so we're gonna collect data of the
form y k which is simply using the product between and phi k and the
problem is as usual that we have measurements were as we would like to see
and so we have too few data
right now it shouldn't come as a surprise that well if f has some sparsity
in some basic side then perhaps we should go about this was construction by finding
that image whose coefficient sequence in the business side has minimum one norm
and so out of this
all the solutions feeding the data we're going to take a specific one
and we're going to do is we're going pick the solution the minimizes the l
one norm subject to data constraints
OK so that's a convex optimisation programme as we've discussed in fact that's a linear
program i can recast this as a linear programme trivially and so this is something
that is in principle like and so on the computer
all right so here's the proposal
you make very few
measurements about an object of interest to recover using
and one
OK so
the result is as follows that resulted to myself and justin wonder
it says suppose that the signals and is indeed sparse that is it has less
at most s nonzero coefficients right so the right hand
i put on the computer screen
it's called the variational free energy
it depends on the adjustable parameters
q and by definition is
the average
interesting energy function
and the q
so q log q
of q and the theta dependence in here is
depends on theta theta is a description of how you just
and this thing has a name is called the variational free energy
anne because where this came from
and because of the fact that this thing here
it is a true statement but
after the theta
is lower bounded by
minus log z
so if we succeed in minimizing the variational free energy
we will have also minimized
the cale between q and p e
and the objective function that pops out about minimization if we can evaluate the variational
free energy at the optimum is a bound on log z so well for free
be getting something interesting
the variational methods i'll talk to you about today
are entirely based on this objective function there are other variational methods as well
but that's all i'm going to
do today
so let's look at some examples now so you can see how this works
can we evaluate this variational free energy
well for some problems for some red energy is e
the answer is yes you can as long as you constrain cuter have appropriately simple form
so let's go through two examples
these first example i'll do is the good old guassian
inference thereof
so hopefully remember this distribution
discussions all the inference problem
the assumption is that there is a normal distribution
the parameters mu sigma squared
it's giving rise to the data
we now want to infer
mu and sigma
so they read distribution
is the inference of
the variance
and we've looked about before
andy this is the new axis and this is the thing
square axis
what the nasty red distribution looks like
something like
the distribution that has the property that any slice through it in this direction
is a normal distribution
i didn't realize there are
and all those are centered on the same place in spite of looks like
role centered on x but are
the sample mean
that's redirect
okay so all three slices through our normal distributions
and slices in this direction
gamma distributions
maximum the posterior
under the assumptions that we had earlier in the course
is at a place called
sigma is
sector sigma and sigma red button on a calculator
however if we marginalize over all these gamma distributions
the projection all over all those on to
this axis
is a gamma distribution
it has a peak
a larger values of sigma
one minus one
okay so this is a very simple
we're going to pretend were
challenge enough by that we want a variational methods
so what we will not do
is introduce a variational approximation
be inference which is the posterior distribution on the and sigma squared given the data
this can be approximated by
a similar distribution q
how much we want constrain what form so we constrain it have
i'm gonna constrain very little indeed
i'm just going to constrain it could be
a separable distribution function and
they function
of sigma squared
so that's the constraint al apply
and then we can ask the question now if we write down a little
and minimize it what happens
so here's what happens
o m
thank you
we have temporarily lost
so there's the red distribution
and that's an accurate control part of it
if you do now
kickoff with any distribution qx obvious separable form
and then you say let's alternately update
the new dependent
and then the sigma dependent function
and alternately update them and see what happens
the answer is straight away when you optimize the new dependent one the new dependent
thing says i want to be guassian please
so you can do that's and then if you update these sigma dependent one
it say i want to be a gamma distribution please
and then you can ask the new depending on what you want to do now and it says of-course
i want to be a guassian but he will change as parameters
and then you ask the sigma depend one what you want to do so we can do this sort of
i alternating update approach to the optimization about funding is
after it'll all the variational free energy with respect to the distribution q mew
and then with respect to q sigma and then we can alternate this range
and when you run the convergence
you end up with
and optimise q distribution that is a normal
and optimizing the distribution that is a gamma
the optimized distribution
over mu
is a normal distribution centered on x by of course what what else could possibly be
but it's weird
isn't the same as this slice through
i think you can you can the one with the canadian on in a model
with an EKF you can kind
so i you basically readability risation each at each time step the appropriate because because
t to the question relates to just flip back to this nonlinear model i mean
i hadn't done any careful actually on that model but i think it can be
a this one yes so basically all eralisation hitting nonlinear function for the state update
and it's got an awkward term involving time i don't think that presents a problem
because you just get a slightly different linearisation for each time step
i think it still works
it it just becomes less effective it just becomes a constant offset at each time
in the organization you don't right
so that that's a red herring it doesn't doesn't bother us for that doesn't bother
the care
but this model will about the care because importantly it's got multimodality in the observation
function because you've got this x squared term here which means there is always an
ambiguity between x plus or minus values
the EKF extended kalman filter won't routinely be able to track both both positive and
negative going parts of the posterior density
which is one reason why you would want to use it for the model
right if i can find when were
they have the things but
i think we'll be here yes
right so monte carlo filtering them so
if we just concerned with calculating expectation is with respect to the filtering density that
is the question we're interested in
the integral is intractable and we're going to resort to some kind of monte carlo
integration so ideally
we like to be able to draw i i d samples from the filtering
density somehow
plug them in to get estimates
eight half of h have the h-bomb
of the
me which will simply be the arithmetic mean of those sampled values h x i
five to use the i th sample from a large monte carlo collection of n
capital and samples
because we can't do that in general we have access to direct samples from p
to p from the filtering density if we did we pretty much solves the problem
from monte carlo perspective anyway the monte carlo is really all about is usually about
how to use
actually draw
samples from indirectly from some very hard target density
so in this case we could do this using importance sampling
in principle we can anyway so it would take some
alternative distribution for x t say q vector t called it the importance function
and there are some minor technical requirements on that principally that it has the same
as the least is much larger support as the as the filtering density p x
to give north through t
now we make in random draws from this proposal function q instead of p
so you now have a different set of monte carlo samples drawn i i d
from q t
problem almost solved but not quite
to do important something you don't have to make a correction to ensure that the
expectation estimates good and the required correction would be the same as we had for
the static importance sampling start the talk called the importance weight w and it would
the ratio of the filtering density evaluated at the i th sample xt line
divided by
importance function the density that is sampled from q
again evaluated at the sample points
x i t
and then if we normalized importance weights if we then go ahead and take these
W's are normalised to sum to one
we've got our approximation of the dirac function approximation
filtering density so would approximately be this weighted sum now
of direct functions the weights proportional to the ratio of the target filtering building this
density divided by
the importance function
normalized such that they sum to one but still proportional to the rotation
which again gives the weighted sample estimates for
and this is just restating what we had before
we don't need to work through that's just working through the same steps taking our
approximation for
the filtering density is now a weighted sum of direct functions
and showing that the expectation drops out
the weighted sum of h is evaluated at sample points
that's what that's all around the globe actually because we're not going to be able
to do this because we won't be able to calculate the weight so there's gonna
be another step coming for the time being
let's just talk about resampling briefly stayed in the sequential setting and they're going to
progressing this importance sampling from one timepoint to the next the next the next
the whole importance sampling paradigm will fall down because will find that the weights in
this weighted importance sampling
well become very degenerate over time because of the way we construct the sample will
see see more of that in a moment in by degenerate i mean that's one
way to carry all the probability mass so one we would have to be one
and the others would all be very close to zero one will be almost more
than the others will be very close to zero which means that it's a very
in the form of engineering models
so this is a simple information processing model of the overall structure and mechanisms that
are involved in
human mind to provide quantitative descriptions of of
important thing is what this thing is based not just to the next picture a
set of interconnected processors things shown in grey circles here and memory stores
which is shown in the square
and i don't want to go through the gruesome details of this sort of a
quick example to show you how it works but
basically what this does is put together a whole bunch of phenomena that have been
observed into relatively simple form that is easy to see why
what's involved in getting a particular task done
so here's a quick example
before the quick example have to tell you the key box works which is this
thing called the cognitive processes
takes information from the production memory and long-term memory and working memory
and here's the idea this is a strange idea that to make sure of what
we are often called cognitive science the original idea developed in psychology and artificial intelligence
it turns out to be a very good way to represent human procedural knowledge if
you know how to do something what you have there's is a whole bunch of
this pattern action pairs
in memory
in production memory the patterns all tests in parallel but in the actions are performed
serially each one these takes about seventeen was second if you have a procedure that
you know are you have a skill what you have a set of rules that
once they get started firing they will
fire in the proper order to carry out the task properly to don't want to
spend some time on the details but this actually works out very well
in terms of accounting for human problem solving
execution skill and it's nice because it can be represented in the form of a
computational simulation so this is the only way to build a simulated humans that knows
how to do tasks and and that will represent how we think the test should
be done
the kind processors and this framework thanks by manipulating the contents of working memory according
to production rules okay each we can modify what's in working memory and that can
trigger which rules
will execute next so here's my cricket example but the simplest as psychologists ever study
is called simple reaction light comes on press the button as fast as you can
and you can write journal articles based on the results of this can maybe even
get ten years OK
but if it has been represented in this in this system
what we see is that after hearing instructions what the person has appropriate sets up
some production rules and in production memory in this case is this one that says
if the term stimulus is in working memory then put push button working memory and
we assume that the motor processor has a little bit of knowledge that's says if
push button is the command in working memory then
trigger the various muscles which will cause the button to be pushed the down
so in that first test starts off time because zero stimulus appears
then after the
video processors down thing after one hundred most seconds power combination of
processing the visual stimulus and recognising it takes a hundred no second son the average
for simple stimulus and we get the term stimulus being deposited in working memory
said that the time one hundred seconds
at this point the cognitive processor production rule gets triggered
over here
and we see
it fires and that deposits push-button in working memory
that takes another seventeen no seconds
and then the motor processor gets triggered by a push button commands sitting in working
memory that causes muscles to twitch
after two hundred forty milliseconds the but actually expressed that's a good thing
it's alright approximate estimate but it's pretty pretty typical for what a simple reaction will
take necessary clarification question
the trees were
a lot of things
all these values vary in various ways but the key idea here is that if
you're trying to get a system designed
oftentimes these approximations are good enough
why intelligent design from bad design if you're in a situation that requires more detailed
more precision then you can collect data as necessary to get more refined estimates of
OK so should be this is the first simple approximation works well enough for design
purposes and i'll provide more more extensive example of how this sort of thing actually
works in practice
OK so but this is sort of basic sketch of were psychology is in terms
of understanding a lot about
the structure of the human mind and how it works
the point of view of the engineering purposes if you're trying to get a system
designed this is not a bad idea
about how to view what goes on with
with humans
OK so that provides overall framework terms the big picture and the small picture
there's a lot more work going on in terms of
i have refining this model human processor idea
he said had more about this later on
but the next thing i want to get to was important phenomenon ideas about perceptual
motor and cognitive systems
so start with input basics these are this is input to the computer
which is output from the human
twenty miles as
an example of an ancient movement and the movement were studied extensively long before anybody
thought of a computer mouse
OK and profits who case mentioned
came up with this empirical relationships called fitts law
and here's what's interesting if you're making and aimed movements you're trying to point to
something using visual feedback interesting quantities the fact
if you plan how long it takes to make the movement because the function of
distance to the target
the cookouts
and so on
and the semantics as per DL in practice actually what we've seen really is the
OWL lite is not really used i think i think the
the realization has been the the fragment was selected there is perhaps kind of too
expensive for some purposes not expressive rather so it's a light something that i think
we're kind of not really seen
use particularly so perhaps that could have been
a slightly smaller language to be more useful
number of different ways of presenting these things OK so different syntaxes we've got what
what what's called the abstract syntax is you can define
the construction the language
and this was used to define the semantics and the number of concrete syntaxes serializations
so we have OWL in RDF XML
which is seen as the kind of normative serializations
there also an XML presentation syntax and people have worked over the last few years
on various kind of what might call human readable syntaxes which kind of tend to
be sort text based on the idea being that they're easier for people to work
on small examples the RDF XML kind of presentation is not really a human readable
syntax is quite difficult to understand just evolves into
a quick survey of the kind of constructors that we get and how
so i has a number of operators that allows to construct class expressions
OK and these have some associated semantics i talked about before
so if so we consider really the semantics has this domain
delta things and then interpretation functions map
the concept classes of a to set of things in the domain
properties to sets of pairs and individuals to individuals and i can then
so this is essentially tells me how to interpret my atomic things if you remember
when i talked back about the ontology had some kind of basic vocabulary that likely
me to talk about my domain and then some additional assumptions that i put on
top of this tells me how to interpret the basic atomic terms
and i can then extend this interpretation function to concept expressions
so for example i have things like i can talk about primitive classes based interpretation
this is just one interpretation function gives me
i can talk about intersection union so i have some and operators to allow me
california new class descriptions
i have a conference having negation
and over here on the on the left-hand side of got things like so it's
telling me that my intersectionofhuman male
to find out i find the collection of things which are in interpretation human pose
interpretation of male i find those those things which are in the intersection that set
this gives me the
semantics of my intersection so i've got some kind of very clear unambiguous way in
which i can interpret this notion of the intersection or union complement constructed likely to
explicitly name
as a class
through the individuals that are members of that class this this is likely to build
a class which
only consists of these two individuals john mary
i have explicit quantifications this is a very important thing in this this helps me
to avoid the kind of black telephone issues
OK so i can talk about universal and existential quantification so i can i can
talk about the first example somevaluesfrom OK so this is telling me this class description
the restriction of all the things that has the child somevaluesfrom lawyer saying OK this
is the collection of all those things which which are related to something by has
child relationship and the thing that they are related to
is the law
OK so here is that all those sorts some wine
x y related by has childminder lawyer case this is kind of allowing me to
explicitly kind of quantified relationship a consumer that to universal quantification which is saying that
everything is related via this relationship must be in this particular class
i can also specify cardinalities things that must have at least two children or no
more than two children and so on
that gives me a mechanism for kind of describing classes
one of n doing my ontology design includes some axioms and the axioms are really
the things that provides the
the background knowledge because these are things think actually the assumptions i made about the
domain so for example i can see a subclass of
i can see that is a subclass of animals so what i'm saying here is
something that in order for my interpretation is to be kind of valid models i
really expect the
interpretation of the of humans to the set of things which humans to be a
subset of the set of things which are animals so this is kind of removing
ambiguity OK so now you know all i'm expecting all humans to be animals
so you have to talk about equivalences so i can say i expect interpretation of
these particular class descriptions to correspond the okay so again i kind of restricting the
interpretations that your life thomas trying to force them to be close to how i'm
outline and one talk very briefly the basics
you know when you first look at it looks like it's too good to be
you know but so we figure out why it makes sense and there are some
interesting mathematical principles that underlie this fields
and also the an issue of recovery you know of you recover the thing that
you need from compressed measurements and i'll give you three examples all from from my
group one will be the construction of gradient fields using l one optimisation and
how these ideas can be used for iris recognition and also provide cancelability the third
one is that i'm not very familiar with the matter of my stories are working
on the whole compressive sensing is useful in graphics and briefly mention other applications of
course and can give me a signal for the last five ten minutes i really
want to spend time on concluding remarks i think that's what's spam
and the feeling is that from what i little i know that the breakthroughs here
we come not just from the processing site but by integrating sensing and processing site
for many years darpa has programs in the different sciences itself is known as integrated
sensing and processing
in the compressive sensing idea
OK alright relation is an offshoot of that so
computer vision researchers we've been expensive sensing what's
you know put thousand cameras and collect data and so on so suddenly if you
tell them no know you don't have to get all of them just get what
you need it's it's a big ship
my microphone
so that's the page i make because were eighty five percent ninety percent of computer
vision researchers we accept that that's collected by others or even by us and we
just processes
but now to make an impact in this field you have to work with the
folks who designed this new cameras and single pixel camera is an example right so
there are many other sensors like gradient cameras built in march and so on
so it's kind of a change in our way of thinking so if you want
to make an impact you go to work with the front end and which is
kind of good for signal processing types and then
from the early eighties onwards computer vision research
as seen in tons of work on the so called regularisation methods and the nom
that was very comparable to work is a altoona now we see that l one
arm not nom and so on and sparsity and so forth is very tempting to
redo all of them using l one norm and so on now
should we do that i would really make that much of a difference so those
would be my
you know can perform most of my concluding remarks sparsity is everywhere as you can
see you know have a periodic signal in the fourier basis the sparsity and if
you have background subtracted images background is huge for small the sparsity in spatial extent
and of course the compression folks so really rely on the fact that you don't
need to keep the signal in its glory and use it
a small set of numbers and so on in wavelet theory and many other no
basis that have been used in the past so again trip signal is another example
right well traditionally what we do we collect data we sample it and then we
we have too much better and maybe we can reduce it so that the traditional
the more you learn in signal processing and image processing process here the idea is
you have x the original signal and then just don't get all of it just
bits and pieces of it that's what the compressive measurements are and then transmit them
and how the method
recovering the original x so that's the name for compressive sensing what's somebody saying how
can you get
more from less
people ask me and said that in computer vision is asking for more from less
we're asking for shape from a single and the intensity image stereo is a little
bit better structure from motion right so we are used to asking more
from less so compressive sensing and the philosophical is more tuned to
no computer vision
researchers at the same time than you do
ask for more from less there are issues you have to tell people that this
is actually the
you know it's time you invest ten dollars and somebody said to give you a
hundred dollars you really think about right so
more from from less is always thing that needs to be justified and that is
the basic thing that we need to worry about
all right so
y here the compressive measurements fees some transformation x there that
that's the really interested in
so given y
how do you get x
in general you can because if you look at the feed the matrix it's what
people call it the fact
matrix right because
more columns in rows and so on so
t his is really possible
well suppose the signal
has only k core elements that are non-zero so that's the name for k sparse
signals it can be in any representation doesn't have to be in spatial representation would
be any basis maybe the case the coefficients are non-zero and then put everything dies
k fourier coefficients are non-zero k plus one on which is erected across it can
and suppose if the signal is such sort scholar k sparse signals then
mathematicians you know can be as tall
and professor donna and so on what on this for the last five years or
and say this possible but if you look at fee as i said before it's
not full rank and therefore you lose information and infinitely many x map on to
so if you are interested in sparse then maybe you can design the matrix p
such that
it is the color now the property that allows you
do that is what is known as the restricted isometry property of the idea is
to design fees so that each of its k submatrices are full rank if you
do that then you have the option of either doing zero optimization and since it's
pretty hard being an NP complete problem you can come up with an l one
the extracted sample in which we have no nodes change
so we were so this is an example of inference problem where you want to
of all the relevant information of this set is the pitch of the notes the
amplitude and so on
OK so
this is the fourier transform of a single flute playing
here's is the frequency axis and here is the amplitude
and as you can see there is a very nice fundamental frequency here first harmonic
sequence x so it is very easy to model this time series as a son
call signs
which frequencies are multiple of the fundamental frequency so if any course three then we
have this one
and sign is if initial phases coded
into the
images of the amplitude
and we have say two one two three four five six seven eight nine ten
well this one is very low so let's say we have eleven harmonics so this
is the parameter him
so we can model this time series
we something which looks like that
any question that is the
the problem is that this model is not realistic at all it will not feature
will have
so we need to improve it
if we come back to this spectrogram
then we hold we still have
the frequency components
but what we see is first the amplitude is not constant it decreases with time
and that the frequencies
i'm not exactly related as multiples
that is the first harmonic is not twice
the frequency of the fundamental it's
close to twice but it's not exactly twice
so you need to put this into the model as well
so first
how to model time varying amplitude
so imagine this is in blue the amplitude of the partial
so a good solution could be to decompose it into a set of windows like
and have an amplitude for each of the windows
and by summing up all these windows you might be able to reconstruct the overall
that's the first lady for the modernization
so we come back
two how model
so we are still some all the partial
here we have the cosine and sine which are
the partial
and this time we have
and amplitude which is decomposed on the basis of functions phi
we sum up on all the functions the basis functions
if i come back to the previous slide
the phi functions are
in red
OK each one is localized in time
it corresponds to this
and another improvement through for
compared to the previous model is that matters of frequency is not exactly equal
and i multiple of the fundamental frequency
right so in this example uses that
from the
from a set of that we can build
for example
for instance we have
it's a mathematical model it is not the probabilistic model right so we need to
probabilistic assumptions around
OK so
this is just a remark
if i consider for one i times the cosine
then it's time frequency atoms that we just discussed in in the previous lecture
and is the like that so overall what we're going to do is to project
time series and to a set of time for concept
just to make the link with respect
this model for example we have only
previously when only one node that is one fundamental frequency and the partials but in
true in real music you so all notes played at the same time so you
need to sum up
all the nodes in the time series
so now we have
a realistic
the music
many music
OK so
this can be very easily written in vector form
OK so i'll do it now into two simplifies the patients
so this is the time series in vector form beta victories vector of all the
the vector of noise and g
it is the matrix of
gaussian for
gabor atoms
it is the metrics made of these guys
OK stacked in columns and we want to predlrt number of partial for each node
and on the number of nodes so we have an inference problem in which the
dimension of the state space is varying
OK and
the parameter we want to estimate is made of
the amplitude the variance of the additive noise and the frequencies
if we assume aggression nice
it is very easy to write the likelihood
OK this is a gaussian likelihood
where we have here is model
the true that
the squared distance and
was in the gaussian distribution
nothing very complicated here
so the
in this example assume we want to learn everything we can do about music so
for example we would like to learn how many notes have played
for each note how many possible that have
and for each of these nodes
what are the frequencies of the fundamental and the partials
so this is a big set of parameters
i assume you have forsaken the music
we have three nodes each with its partial
i don't think there's much difference here really between the
sociologist economist for social physicists encounters this i think
this issue of computational versus dynamic definition is
across the disciplines
now some of you may have read john hawkins the end of science came out
a a little over a decade ago the best-selling book
another scientific american
and he has a chapter in there
two chapters which is very critical
of complexity approaches
santa fe institute things that were done there
he came up with this term KL complexity
he he cites floyd MIT compiled forty five
distinct definitions of complexity
and so on
the boundary here
so actually at the bottom of the page we have something
one of the things that hawkins came up with this difficult four
and cybernetics
catastrophe theory chaos theory
and complexity theory
now in the paper in nineteen ninety nine i want all these together to
in the pay paper in the journal of economic perspectives to call these big ten
and small time complexity was sort of what most people here would think of it
sort of
but what i call your heterogeneous agents type complexity
agent based complexity sort of thing one has seen out of santa fe institute
some other places in more recent years i think the sort of thing many people
in this room
are fact involved this sort work
and according of use these forces to dismiss
all said well we had this string of intellectual bubbles
first order cybernetics by decades
in the sixties was contested during in the seventies and newscaster eighties there we got
small time complexity in the nineties
they're all bubbles and you know
garbage therefore you know since guitar string theory with garbage all of the garbage
paper last year in the journal of economic dynamics and control writers attempted to revive
to test theory that the baby got thrown out with the bathwater other problems overwrite
all these over-hyped
but just because you haven't over-valuation doesn't mean you overshoot the other way round evaluation
defined kind of
valuation will measure what these things are
and i argued that in fact organ before it had a very active or inactive
point that there is a faint of continuity
and accumulated development through these ideas
fundamental link is nonlinear dynamics
and the idea of the dodgers
cool uris if you will and dynamics arising from these
nonlinear dynamics
i actually see
the cybernetics is mostly disappear
i see it sort of the best part of it is as a sort of
reappearing in a small town heterogeneous agents complexity agent based modeling will and both of
these other elements that that are useful in the analysis i see this as a
cumulative process not a not a sequence
dead worthless
bubbles it should be thrown out the window
but cumulative process of intellectual development and there are quite a few individuals around who
in fact some time i think who have been involved with a three if not
all four of these
kind of building on top of each other to kind of view of the economy
so i said i compare this to sort a how we think about certain terms
sometimes sometimes the terms we use for things are created by critics
i think the best way to think about this is in our our history
OK i think of the term impressionism
today an impressionist painting a real impressionist painting is worth many many millions of dollars
euros and swiss francs and if you if you had a roman a you know
you would be very wealthy he had very
go bankrupt to get your hands on it and you know the first came up
with the term impressionism as critic he was putting down overhears here is this painting
by this guy money
sunrise in london by just is not realistic it it's just impressions of you know
get a lot of people have sent away from the camp so you know now
is actually all and so so
i sort of take organs criticism just for that
morgan's right the forces but in fact this is the positive about this is not
something to sneer just have to keep keep the balanced view here
and not get all impressed that there are bubbles
over-hyping but certainly did have
now this view very much tied the dynamic complexity view from there i i drew
from richard de my predecessors energy about who that gave a nice
definition that i have used a number of occasions saying that dynamic complexity
it involves having a system in which you have died since we have
some erratic dynamics
more specifically not convergence to point not a simple expansion and contraction
and not just the limit cycle this fuzzy was about what kind of cyclical fluctuations
are in
any case you know you can get great discontinuity is you can get erratic fluctuations
the variety of things can happen
and i really for say most economists i'm not quite sure about sociologists this is
this is really what most practical
complexity economics they think in terms of what they look at
three years
and i'm not going to get off along the discussion here about certain details of
this are what these terms mean take
we've got that we have some of the fish to fry so hopefully you know
you have an idea and opportunity is in some of these other things
so in you know most of these systems are not there are a few cases
richard goodwin actually had a model in nineteen forty seven
alan turing who was able to to generate the dodgers erratic
dynamics that was a couple of linear systems flags
however if you reduced the system to normal form it becomes nonlinear
fuzzy definition many people study this particular equation just take this used by robert greatest
q two
then i use the superposition principle which we've used many times in a to one
and we say OK the net force on number two
it is the fourth studio number one
plus the force from number three
if number three
this is positive and this is positive and these were negative
then this force
would be in this direction
one x three
and then the net force
on number two
it would be the vectorial some of these
is it obvious that the superposition principle works
not at all
it's not at all obvious
i do we believe in its yes we do why do we believe in it
because it's consistent was all experiments that we've done
but the superposition principle which is very powerful
it's really not
and that of course
but it works we can always use it then we will
if you compare
o to one with a node two
by comparing electricity
you will see the electric forces
and we are powerful
then gravitational force
and the way i can best show you that
is by taking
two protons
which are distance
d apart
he was proton
he was about from song
and they are separated by a distance d
they repel each other
and the fourth by which they repel each other
is of course extremely easy to calculate
we know cools law that law is called afterglow
and so the force
electric force which which they repel each other
this is just the magnitude now of course
is the charge of the
one point six times ten to the minus nineteen that i have two
it's clear that
i have multiplied by cools constant which is nine times ten to nine
and i divided by the square
that's electric force
if i want to know the gravitational force
which is the force with which they attract each other
these are repelling forces but i just want magnitude here
then i have to take the mass of the proton
which is one point seven
times ten to the minus twenty seven
you have to square that
remember and one times and to kind of gravitational constant
the gravitational constant as i unit
six point seven times ten to the minus eleven
and i divide that
by the squid
if no i compare the electric force was the gravitational force
i divide one
by the other
i notice that the councils
they both have the square downstairs
and so you easy
to be able to show
this ratio
is roughly ten to
thirty six
so the electric forces thirty six orders of magnitude more potent
then the gravitational attraction
this teaches you some respect perhaps
four eight o two
these were the only forces that acted on the program
you bring them in the nucleus
which has the size of only ten to the minus twelve
suddenly those
the acceleration that the
proton will experience
is the
electric force
divided by the mass of the proton
because i a
the basis of a to one
and if you take electric forces
but you may the
ten to the minus twelve centimeters which is ten to the minus forty meters
you calculate this ratio you will find that this twenty six orders of magnitude higher
then the gravitational acceleration
twenty six orders of magnitude higher so you wonder what the hell hold the nucleus
if there is such a tremendous force on these programs well
so what is holding them together
and the nuclear forces which we do not fully understand
but thank goodness
the nuclear forces
not part of a two two so i'll leave it alone for now
so what holds them together
well the nuclear scale
ten to the minus twelve centimetres
very important that the nuclear forces
or atomic scale up to thousands of kilometres
it's really an electric forces
that hold our world together
but on a much larger scale
planets and stars in the galaxy
it is credited hold
world together
now you may say
that's very inconsistent with what you just told us
because it you tell us that the councils
if you compare gravity
which electricity
most objects
i'm neutral
or very close to neutral
and so if you take the earth
it is very unlikely even that the earth as a whole
whatever charge
more than ten cool the problem is already an exaggeration
so if i take the earth
and i take them all
and i put on both
the charge of ten cool
he is the earth
he is the moon
and i would say just arbitrarily ten cool year
and that put on here
you know minus
minus cool or
so they will attract each other but given that this is
it's almost nothing forces negligibly small
i think it is
which which is that
is the first time
it's like you
this the the when you because
and then
right next
they have been
grand prix fixe
so i made my presentation where is that
shares uses images but i think
actually because it is known to be
what is
the presentation
it was possible to search by
independently might
so like
electrons the color to some call it provides images where you have cited column
this system to the query was yet
i want to show that our
the way
it's not because easy
and remember
so i can come by
there was
just before independence the light calibration
i don't know
i was stimulated to
drop it was possible to
by the
so search by
and one
also we're all one
one of the possible
what we
they have to deal with these
the some
problem is possible
by the way to do
all the first
the the color texture color and texture like
among the positive could be coupled
some combination of features
they late so it's clear that they use linear combination combine
it was possible
it is located in italy
so i
and by the way
from the
and of course this case
deal with it
so there was
and that the combination of all
one more
which just mentioned
nearly all
and to
all the way anymore
but in this case
i met some people who tell them
and the idea is to have right to the
this is what it is
in end
because we can come out
so just about by
the main difference
comparing to the configuration is considered fixed onto so
last column
but some relations between different
this is the global picture
i can call you can do a lot
false positive
but when combined this global picture
some of the your
so here we
this debate
written by
the main
so you can see here because will the two other systems which are able to
write about the person
for the
which is is the real but all these systems are quite old
is that because eighties visualseek
i think it's also the least bit of i nineteen ninety seven nineteen ninety nine
like this but
all right
and they use
so we can finish university and it's OK so
you know that the face paper using sparsity now the reason i suspect that i'm
sure we can figure fingerprint paper things sparsity that we cannot go around
that road and we had a visitor from IBM his name is not known rather
than he gave a talk about cancelability
and biometrics what happens if somebody steals your face signatures and so on right so
they have been working on it for music it's not nearly as you can see
here in two thousand one he was looking at biometrics insecurity that basically cancel abilities
that help can you produce secure biometrics and then he showed this this method
OK i'll go back to this later again he said well this is how he
produces cancelability
where they have random projections nodes if the g is the give our features that
are used in iris recognition and they use a random projection
and then so they have no signature and why this is now is the one
that we used and in case it is stored on
you know you can again generate another and the production and so on and the
guy who steals your signature will not be able to recover your wife
because of this particular transformation random projection
then i told him you know what this is this is the kind of problem
that is in compressive sensing two
so what is the link between cancelability random projections OK well there is johnson
then tries to lemma that says when you do a random projection like that the
distance is almost research was you take the original image
OK you have a major a an image b let's say you calculate the distance
between these two images and then you do random projection on in under the command
we calculate the distance the distance would be very close so by doing this random
projection can kind of
change signal you're working with
all right but you will still be able to to recognise me because any method
that works on the original image
OK you can now brewed on the random projections so if originally made in your
feature extraction so that the transformation and then you can do that and the predictions
on the feature extraction right so that should be fine so this there is a
nice paper that kind of things the
i'd probably to jail in mumbai rich baraniuk and so on and so we were
kind of been surprised by this link but of course process online users so there's
nothing new under the sun
so i thought well we have found no link and then we go and look
into the golden couple of people have already figured this one out this paper and
family and i think this is a paper from
professor documents crawled because people have been working environment is along how also worried about
the security of the biometrics so here you have in for the what i'm discussing
application compressive sensing sorts of things come in many different ways first but i its
recognition sparsity based recognition
it's useful and then if you want to go cancelability you bring in random projections
and we talked about random projections the matrix p here again bernoulli goes in and
so on and that's how you also produces compressive measurements so that all kind of
sitting together so this is somewhat interesting
to me at least now i have one last one
and of course you can know show that the performance test and you know go
on and so forth again in the world down because you and production
well the graphics folks have been no worrying about getting reflectance functions because then they
can use them for relighting and so forth were making no cool magistrate so in
general it's an eighty problem for the first enough
for viewing and for the for the acquisition thing but if you make assumptions fixed
viewpoint and fix acquisition and things like that you can bring it down before
function OK now
right so the reflectance thing has all components to try haslam machine component shadows of
this peculiar in a given scene so called the sparsity come into play here i
think in the best example
of sparsity
compressive sensing and recovery is this paper so if you want to really get into
this field
before reading all the mathematics history this paper
you know i really like it it gives a nice overview
of reflectance function estimation problem why
it requires so much of the data to be collected
and then it says way compressive sensing may make sense here because britain reflectance functions
by themselves maybe part so so beautiful match on top of it
graphics works no-hoper set back you know are and experimental setup to collect actually these
kinds of compressive measurements so to me this is the other two examples i i