the people actually call which is like the ratio of true positive over the true
positive class
false negative
this is similar to partially an for the specific class
and of course the precision how many times yes
but out of everything that to predict how many times he made
a correct prediction this DP
over the people SFB
in order to get the good
trade between these two values people use f
in the measure
most typical ways to
use this formal here however the more general formula
is using the factor better
and in this case if you could if you have better equal to one get
this formula however if you want to and this is equal
the between recall and precision if one to put more weight into recall all precision
can change this parameter
also your so familiar that
people also use terms and metrics like that actually the falls alarm right
so it actually is defined in the same way as
recall it it is basically how many times i predicted something correctly
false alarm rate is basically trying to say how many times i see i'm saying
that something is and always but it's not is actually the normal
and as the trade between these two
values people usually construct our sicker and seek review
on the x axis using false alarm rate
y axis using it actually an ideal our seeker should be something like that for
the false alarm you can to achieve one hundred percent it actually
but this is usually positive in your life as you can imagine in most real-life
our secrets look something like this
so these are the typical
four hours
and of course the
people also trying to measure the area
under the curve as
as a metric to evaluate different it classification thing so anomaly detection techniques
in recent years people were also trying to
improve the measure of area under the curve by proposing
to compute how big our the class first making
so basically instead of
providing the measure for the test data that you're dealing with these basically giving go
impression how good generalizability the model has so i think there are
april and produce here proposing different
variations of area under the curve
OK and i mentioned earlier there are different applications of anomaly detection prevention network intrusion
detection their applications of different fraud detection like credit card fraud insurance fraud
in health care informatics and medical
the agnostics
we also have the problem of one likely to industrial them infection may have different
engineering systems that may experience some false
in image processing inredis will anomalies are extremely important to the text of some events
like the life back into the report something suspicious
and finally there is a topic of
a lot of affection text line
so in intrusion detection as i said
you're trying to monitor
the computer network
in order or computer system in order to
and the natural for certain intrusions intrusions usually defined as attempts to bypass the security
of computer or of the network and
the typical challenges in metric intrusion detection world
some of them did most of
industry they actually the current state of the art and character in the state of
the art
introduction to the most of people who think signature based intrusion detection systems
most of you have either divides can more than that is taken for the viruses
you you know that
you often have to go to the actually it's done automatically by the software is
going to the web site trying to download all the information so the viruses
and then it uses this definition is to
to to detect all devices and computers
so it means that is really important to have the behavior of each nucleon some
average everything so that's why microscopic approaches are not able to reproduce
these effects which
are trying to send only six nicholas difference which are very important
because you have really changed
in the limit scheme
just often
if you look at the angular velocity of a rotating nucleus you can calculate
these rotational angular velocity is
then to the forum nineteen wrong per second
i had a very powerful washing machine and it's only one one thousand three hundred
round per minute so it's really really
very high angular velocity
so that's why it's so you need a very strong interaction that with jack all
the part
i will conclude with the summary of this talk today
so i first introduce a macroscopic description of the nucleus in terms of illiquid
presented the fact that you have these data by taking a formula with different terms
it's able to describe the gross feature of the nicky i
but for many many properties you need really introduce
microscopic description so you need to consider the nucleons and the interaction
there are different
two kinds the shell model
where you have
and in car and particle which are p
but you take into account all the the exhibition from this particles limited and you
have the countryside which is the mean free
you have all these particles
but they do interact with the mean field so you have the restriction of the
interaction that take into account
conclusion many nuclei are found deformed in their ground states
and then this i really think that the information
this something that is obtained through express with very
but it's something that is really
important to do
to explain experimental results because the spectroscopy
strongly depends on the deformation
thank you very much
so this
when john for
if you have a question also how making modifications the greatest
you don't get
the other
there was a question at the beginning of my lecture that i told fellow to
ask at twelve o'clock
but then he sees somehow disappeared but i think it would actually be worth discussing
surface OK can i can i have a go that
generate some
OK so sometimes the feedback can become catastrophically lower
and painful
but let me just proceed the recall yesterday that there was the question
of an example of the use of bayes theorem
and i think that my answer that i get yesterday was not completely appropriate because
i gave effectively frequent
the example of the use of bayes theorem
so this was that this was the
i said that suppose i have two types of events signal and background and signal
events i have the distribution of some variable x that's like that
and for background events i have some distribution like that and i use bayes theorem
to derive
the probability that the event was a signal event given a measured value of x
is that bayesian user bayes theorem more or frequentist base there
the idea is is the following is that each event
being signal or background is itself a characteristic which changes randomly when i look at
different events so the hypothesis is that events the signal event because the event background
events is itself the outcome of a repeatable
procedure so this really is the frequencies used
of bayes theorem
for single given event i can also ask the question what is my degree of
that this one event is the signal a signal event and then that would be
equivalent that would be the same formula that would be a bayesian user base there
but i think the question what to do with the following suppose my hypothesis is
the value of the parameter some parameter theta
and this is a parameter whose value i don't know and i want to try
to estimate its value by making some measurements and suppose i have
probability function
which tells me what the probability to get to a certain measurement outcome x is
given the values data
and what i would like to do is i would like to get the posterior
probability for
given x and i use based
so tell that is equal to the probability for x given data
times the prior probability for data
and then this would have to be normalized
in some way
normalized so that the area under the
resulting probability distribution is a unit so now the question is
k of x y x is just like computing the inner product between phi FXI
and five x
so this is why it's it's very simple the kernel trick is a very simple
it it's
of obvious obviously restaurants very strong mathematical tools but it's if you just want to
use it if you want to construct your own
kernel method which is a little late because there are a lot of things that
have been done in this area but still you can try to to find a
new kernel kernel
i don't
whatever you want
the idea is that you just have to find the product first you have to
express everything in terms of dot product
once you're done with that then you know that you can do
you don't you can cook kernalized everything
and the optimal classifier now is just expressed as a sum of for i k
of x i x
plus b
so i'm going back to the very simple classifier talked about at the very beginning
remember that we have the
right point we have the blue point i think i take the heat
the mean of the red points mean of the blue points i draw a line
that passes through the middle of those two points and i say that all the
that fall on one side of plus
o point our positive point and the others are negative points
what we had before is that we knew that
instead of these we have the
classical inner product
and now i don't change anything
except that i did my my my little trick with the kernel trick
i replace the inner product that used to appear here by
k of x i x
and the value of alpha i is unchanged is still the same value as before
and the values of b easily be changed because if you remember
b is expressed as
the difference of the square norm of c-minus and c plus
and if you you you do the computation
you see that actually the versions of the square north sea minus is
so if you want to see
how it works
you have
c-minus that is equal to
that is the definition of minus
if you take the norm
the squared norm of this
you just
and so using the linearity and everything that you know about the inner product so
and here you happy
because you have not products
and you say OK instead of that
i'll use
and that's it
so this is how i get these these are like that
so now i didn't i didn't specify any any particular are kernel
and i'm going to
to show you
classical kernels that are usually there are used are that are well known and
that are used when you work with the vectors
first he got some kernel
usually when you try to do a kernel you when you first meet with kernel
methods and you want to try your first kernel algorithm what you're going to use
it for the gaussian kernel
because because it works
it's apparent arrest kernel because you have these is sigma here
that be
parameterized properly but usually
you can manage to to find good value and are you happy with your first
kernel kernel methods
the corresponding and he then implicit h
of infinite dimension
again i'll come back and this a little bit later on actually at the end
of the talk when i talk about more theoretical things and more theoretically grounded things
the polynomial kernel
it is very simple
it's just the usual dot product between u and v plus constant and to the
power of the
so you can see that the usual inner product
which she which correspond to the situation where c is equal to zero and is
equal to one
so the usual inner product is just the kernel as well
another kernel that has been used with support vector machines even though it's not
it's not necessarily a mercer kernel that is
you cannot say what kind of the mapping is a society with which is exist
is goes with with this kernel is the punch
so either it's not the tangent kernel which is the hyperbolic hyperbolic attended tendered rules
so it is that you can
i don't know i've never worked with it but i know that people have
what i want to do what we want to show you here is is how
can for for some examples of kernel
kernels how you can identify
the mapping that goes with the kernel
but you choose for instance
you take the polynomial kernel k defined here
so this is just the square of the inner product is not very very it's
not very elaborate cytochrome so you take the square
and this corresponds to the situation where c is equal to zero and is equal
to two
in the previous definition
and you can you can identify mapping that works there is a mapping such that
when you take the kernel between u and v then you have that k of
u and v is equal to phi of to the dot product between phi of
u and five v
so the the function phi
the mapping phi that's why i proposed to to look at is
this one you take x that is made of two coordinates its of x one
and x two and you build
three dimensional vector
that is
x one square
visualizations of what's happening in the in the LDA situation
right so OK so
we have place the dirichlet prior on mixing proportions in each group and we want
to take k to infinity as we have seen every where we take it in
infinity each document now is going to be
the infinite limit is going to produce a dirichlet process mixture model
and let's see what happens
so we have the dirichlet process mixture model in document one and then we have
another dirichlet process mixture model for the document to and because the documents
and because the python basically drawn i i d from this
from this dirichlet distribution we're going to have two independent draws
the same dirichlet process but there are still two independent ross
so in
document one we're going to have to set of atoms is given by the dirichlet
process and i'm going to go to the set of atoms
and what's the problem here the problem is that
if the base distribution is small so in this case the base distribution is itself
a dirichlet distribution
and it is a small distribution over probability simplex then this set of atoms
i will never overlap with this set of atoms
and i recall that the location of the atoms are the topics in
in our corpus so the set of topics that is used to describe document one
we not overlap with the set of documents with a set of topics that is
used to describe document two
and so
there's no sharing of topics across documents so that's
where this thing fails it's it's not sharing topics across the different organs which is
what we really want
just think
so this is the sort of so what's the solution to this the solution is
actually very straightforward the problem is that our base distribution given by this red line
in this most distribution is one where if you opt in
multiple draws from an is roster
so gaussians if you can draw lots of different samples because it and
every time you get a different number opt similarly here
and this so
the problem is the issues small so we're going to make it not small just
making discrete distribution
and in the discrete distribution we will
be forced to reuse
the topics basically so we we can make the base distribution discrete and that will
solve this problem of no sharing of clusters
and what the what distribution over
discrete distributions can we use
dirichlet process based on the first thing that comes to
right right so we can place a dirichlet prior on the key common base distribution
of this to dirichlet processes
OK so that's what we're going to do
we can do the following so
we're going to have a g zero which is drawn from a dirichlet process
and g one and g two
going to be i i d draws from the same dirichlet process
but the base distribution
now it's going to be g not
this is going to be are discrete distribution
so this can solve some problems in this thing is called hierarchical dirichlet process for
the obvious reason we have a dirichlet process on top of
the dirichlet process is a hierarchy
so let's visualize what's happening so is going to be drawn from a dirichlet process
so it's going to be an infinite sum of
of of atoms
so this is given by the blue
text here
and then both g one and g two
the locations of the
of the atoms in both of them are going to be drawn from g not
so in particular each of the stakes in g one will be one of the
six the location will be by the high could could differ
and the location of the sticks is basically corresponds to a topic so the topics
in document one will be shared with the topics in document
the new rules
far for the whole corpus
yes so you can think of
zero as this as first drawing the self topics that describes the whole corpus
and for every document
it will used exactly the same set of topics but you will have a different
probability of picking each topic
the red line is the base distribution the at the top
that thing here
OK so
so this thing has
been applied to document topic modeling
perhaps a shift
shawn little result here so what's quite nicely so you know you now do you
have to choose the number of topics so you can vary the number of topics
from one two hundred or something and you can see u-shaped curve where on the
left we have
high and low probability on the right we have no property and in the middle
we have high probability
this is
and the fitting of one overfitting on the other side there's a regime where
the number of topics is just about right
and the HDP basically was able to find
the number of topics
we can also apply this to infinite hidden markov models
welcome to the next slide so
so here is basically the infinite hidden markov models so we have a hidden markov
model here
OK so this our observations x one two x tau
and these are hidden states
change together as a markov chains that one goes to that too goes to the
tree and so on
and in the typical hidden markov model this that's only a finite number of states
in the model so we have the ten states
so we need to describe the the transition probability from each of the ten states
to each of the ten states so it's is matrix ten by ten matrix
whether rule some to one
and met
of you are not can
familiar with computer vision
to school
very few about five
for those of you who are familiar with
computer vision
how many of you are not familiar with
three d reconstruction motion or epipolar constraints for those things
about half
so this is what this problem is to imagine that i take a video sequence
and i walk around and take immediate and i'm looking at the world athletics imagine
that this could be in the
this is what i assume i assume they don't have a GPS or any other
sensor my camera so i have no idea where to those pictures
now i just give you all the pictures and i tell you
can you please
tell me what the position of the camera was twenty two those pictures
and can you please tell me
or make a three d model
from these two
the pictures
and this is of course useful for building models of those things but it's also
very useful in robotics for instance you can put a camera on helicopter
they could fly
and the helicopter can be the map of the terrain around and
so that he can navigate and avoid running into things we can put into a
so the question is how do you do this
and the traditional way of doing this is that you
take your pictures and you extract set of points or corners or point of relevance
for instance in the building typically you be corners in the wind
but this is done automatically is not that you manually click
although many experiments we do that for showing the performance there is that somehow you
can get corners in the first image and somehow you can get corners and the
second in image
and by looking at how these points move as a function of time
you can figure out what the camera positions where as well as building activity
of this
so this is what called motion the camera positions and structure is essentially what are
the coordinates of the points in three d space
is that more or less clear
the next level is well this is this is nice and this has been a
research problem in computer vision for the last thirty years but
this only applies to buildings
so have now look at a parking lot and there are many cars are moving
one applied because he
one part of the EU's moving one way and another part of it is another
way what if i want to apply to people
then there will be many motions or want to apply to images of water it
will work at all because the water is not known words that in sense
so the next problem and this is something that's been very popular over the past
few years is well
how do i ft multiple motion models to different parts of the image maybe here
the trees is moving faster than the background in media could segments
the tree or in this case you have a car
and the camera is also moving in what i need to do is
two reconstructions of the same time one the car one background but the but
i know how to construct with the camera was located but also what is the
position of the cart relative to the camera because now i have two motions at
the same time but
is challenging because i don't know which pixels move according to which
motion model event that then it will be
the standard problem so this is the same thing as fighting two lines if you
the models are a lot more complicated i have to feed
rotations translations calibrations and there's project predictive so there's a lot of riemannian geometry and
projective geometry involves just to solve the problem for one group
but now i have also the segmentation but so is the combination of
differential geometry
for the
motion itself and algebraic geometry for the segmentation on own
so this is the problem
given a video sequence determine how many motion models should defeat
what are the
parameters of emotional
so if you convert
you want to convert from finite to centigrade or the other way around
in foreign
nine fifty
time and temperature in celsius
plus thirty two
if you take long temperature
twenty degrees centigrade
i was grown up with
europe everyone uses centigrade there
then you can see that
in terms of finite
that comes
sixty eight degrees one point
nine fifty times twenty
thirty six and thirty two
minus forty degrees centigrade
it's the same
minus forty degree fine
check that
twenty two scales cross-over
almost the entire world uses set celsius scale it's part of the metric system
united states is one of the very very few countries
we're still in the robbers one way
uses degrees fahrenheit this is really a pain in the neck by these for me
i have very little feeling for it i just happen to know that room temperature
sixty eight because that's the way i set my
was that my home that's about all
i can think in terms of degrees fine
there is no limit to
high temperature but there is a limit to
low temperatures is an absolute
this absolute zero below in which you cannot go is about minus two hundred seventy
and if you take a system that cannot transfer energy
to any other system that is in thermal contact with
then it is at that lo was possible
this is the way we define it
about minus
four hundred and sixty degrees find
so we now have a third scale which was introduced by lord kelvin
british scientists
a lot of research on heat
and he introduced the absolute scale whereby uses the
the lowest possible temperature
as zero degree
but the increments in terms of
increase of one degree uses the same as the celsius scale
so an increase of two or three degrees kelvin is the same as an increase
of two or three degrees centigrade
so if we now compare the three scale
and calvin
then twenty degrees centigrade will be
sixty eight finite
and that would be
two seventy three point fifteen
plus twenty let's round often make two ninety three
and if we take
then we would have minus two hundred and seventy three point one five let's leave
that offer now
and its proximity minus four hundred six
we almost always work was degrees kelvin
in physics
and we'll discuss that in more detail friday
most substances
x band
when you heat them
and if we start with an object
which has length l
and i need
about thirty degrees
it gets longer
by the amount of
and delta l
can be expressed in a very simple way
it is all five
times l
time delta t
of size called the linear
expansion coefficients
and the units i
one of degrees centigrade
one of the degree kelvin is the same
because it's it's increments matter
very values for all five
different great deal
give you some values for of
if copper
the grass
if you buy rex
if in four
and i'll give you few and their own unique
ten to the minus six
o degrees centigrade
we will use some of them today
price is about nineteen
operators seventeen
three point three in four
o point nine and steel is roughly twelve there are many different kinds of steel
in four
it was a great invention notice it has a very low expansion coefficient is very
in the nineteenth century even today
to make instruments
very precise like clocks
clocks affected by
the expansion of the gears
so the invention of in far which is a
of sixty four percent
ireland thirty six percent nickel was invented by
physicist dr
in eighteen ninety eight for this discovery he received the nobel prize
in nineteen twenty
this something how important it was
get it
l or that has a very
low expansion coefficients
if we use these numbers
let's look at the expansion of for instance a railroad
whitaker railroad
and we take this stretch of rail
which is a thousand metres
we take the view i this is the expansion coefficients
and we compare called a small extremely cold recall there was a hot summer day
a cold winter day minus fifteen degrees centigrade
and a hot summer day left thirty five degrees centigrade
so delta t
would be about fifty degrees
so what is the alpha l
well that would be
twelve times ten to the minus six
times ten to the third
i'm fifty
there i i made an attempt to define something which was a little bit misguided
so instead of defining efficiency the way you've got it right there are going to
what what's
called something different for refrigerator which is called the coefficient of performance
so it's the following
we can define the
the coefficient of
written as a
here too
in other words we you know it's it's how much heat
can we
pull out of the cold reservoir
for whatever amount of work that we're gonna put in order to do that
of course would like that to be as big as possible
but of course this is just
q two
over minus
q one
plus q two
but just to be clear
the work in
so let me just rewrite that is i just want divide by q one everywhere
so i mean right this is huge two
q one
one class
q two
or q one
i want to do that because we know that q two or q one is
negative t two or t one so this is negative he two
thirty one
one minus the two
over t one i can
can solve those and multiply through by
t one
so this is just going to be t two
over t one
minus two
coefficient of performance
OK so it's a measure of how
well we can do
to run the refrigerator so
you know what the second law is doing in words it's putting these restrictions on
how well or how effectively we can convert
you heat into work in the case of the engine or work into
the heat extracted in the case of refrigerator
and it
it follows qualitatively
from just
your ordinary observations about the direction in which things go spontaneously right you know that
he isn't going to fall from the whole body to a hotter body without putting
some work into make that happen
and so
will be able to follow that further
and c
really how to determine the direction of spontaneity
for me
a whole set of processes really in principle for any process
when analyzed properly
OK so the first step to doing that is i want to just generalise our
result so far for kano cycle
you might think well OK but this is a pretty specialized case right we formulated
one particular kind of engine
and see how we can
analyse what it does
come up with relations
same value for efficiency and other quantities
how general is it
well let's take a look
what i wanna do
is make
a new engine
which really just consists of two engines
side by side
one is our carlo engine as we've seen
and the other is just some
any other
reversible engine
generalise or
engine results
the car park reservoir and
drive bigger we know it has to be be anyway since
we can extract heat from without changing the temperature
and on this side
we're gonna
right out of
an engine and we're going to say this is a common knowledge
on the side of it
we have
q one prime
we're going to have w prime
we're going to have a few
draw the arrows in the positive direction and
in these cases
or in the define directions i should say
are colder
OK so so here is just an engine that like what we've already seen and
i'm going to
specify that this is the car no
engine which is to say all the results that we just derived hold for this
and side by side
we're going to run another engine
so it's got
q two
it's got cycle
and it's gone
q one
so this is some other
it runs using reversible
i can define the efficiency of each one of them right efficiency for the
one on the left is
minus w over
q one efficiency prime for the one on the right is
nine w prime
over q one prime
now i want just assume
that in some way they're different so let's assume
epsilon prime
is greater than epsilon
so in other words like this efficient this this engine is running less efficiently than
kano engine
it's also reversible and
now since it's reversible we can run it forward backward
we could run this one backward
and we can use the work
i told you about the use of next new superconducting linac for these techniques in
crisis that
using accelerators for protontherapy carbon ions
the b-side to the single most probable
and i think of laws
for carbon ions in the light of the latest developments of the superconducting inside and
i tell you about
the thing which is the next fast cycling accelerator for carbon ions say
this is a need of the future accelerator in my mind a future accelerator growth
for creating moving organs you see this you have to what you have to force
open you don't suppose somebody has the tumor in the lung
one by the human pose
and and you don't want to be those allowed to board the needed to cover
the two because this means that the healthy tissues so you want to follow the
tumour and ways of knowing whether two ways nowadays many different techniques nobody knows which
is the best but then we may know where the tumor his but then when
you send the beam of protons carbon ions
you would like the one the walls these places and if it comes
in site why women who want to increase the energy to pass through even to
get the important to you understand that with the technology developed for LSE impairment of
control computers and so on this in principle is feasible because this is not the
target is not going the whole thing is that human beings so must be more
careful now according to see but still is faces but then you must have machine
which does that and you see the solution which has been tested by
a our colleagues in downstate is change energy by moving
and that's all because the end is the beginning of this accident is fixed
he moved this acts so
and then you the energy develops and luckily is easy with magnus can with these
and if you use this compensation you can give a good move in in front
of like this the symbols that you will
static this is an improvement on the front
but of course we want to implement and of course my point i point to
point to go into this new kind of accelerators which not exist is but the
solution if you could then the energy
but at to do with a millisecond instead and moving organs electronic if you machine
which is not fixed energy for a long time as a single cycles and but
you can and this is the idea
behind what we call a particular entail cyclinac cyclotron class in iraq
for image guided hadrontherapy see those decided or single cycle
you know what it is with a computer controlled source
which has been which comes out
charles short
the two five mike nichols' second lengths two hundred hertz for instance which gets into
many models
which are powered by generators and you get to be
in fact the being is
very short in electoral in but and you know it is very short few microseconds
and it additional weight is typically hand two hundred or so you get times a
second about
and now imagine that you can vary the power in this model is
and you can get any
energy you want
i changed a few milliseconds the same times it takes to move laterally and we
also want to do so you get this way of making it the conformal treatment
of moving objects in the city and it behind all this development and the development
of the data of past that if age is this i would have been working
on this for thirteen years
and this is what comes out only image
we call it either institute for the annual stick-in-the-mud therapy which is a cyclinac foucault
of the sources a cyclotron
of thirty
the most useful the pharmacy is the site of a major new at the beginning
you can do it by night a lot to modify this baby
use it to accelerated and you have here the energy available
so me and to understand and you can buy very fast and this is something
that building the first being built in this month's period we've made a prototype it
works building the first unit and this is built by company which is called the
publication of the text is made is in this spin-off company
which would be light
and there's an agreement with IBA to deliver both this and again because the game
is equal to the ones practically equal to the ones used by you by other
questions so this is the first bus cycle
called machine then we designed for
a fast cycling machine based
on a superconducting cyclotron designed by
colleagues in
and idea
which is called sent
which is used
accelerating courtney carbon ions
two and energy such that one i do not last seventeen centimeters so
this is the use of sand filters
for the second one has the patience yet but then it is only three hundred
million people look at these three thousand six hundred people
so you can go more than seventy centimeters and no
you can now
this is unique
strictly come bottom and you can get to city centre for carbon ions and having
again this possibility of varying the energy fast
this idea of combining this cycles with the line that gives you the possibility of
very fast fast cycling both portals and carbon ions
there is solution
which is still in design this big proposals for carbon ions is very difficult to
conceive a new type of machine
i think about three types of machine
at the beginning but was slide every know every speaker speaks from you here is
like because it's the only part the tools otherwise you do that in forty five
minutes and they not have so it is not true there is another type there
i hope this is quick
what are the
the some new settings in semi supervised learning one thing i think it is going
to be interesting is this online customizable west learning center
so imagine
here's robot to mars rover sent to mars and a it's taking pictures it's taking
with so high african frame rate that not all pictures can be sent back to
hours to get labeled for
from scientists so let's say this is the first picture is sense back and people
sense factories people say OK this is not an interesting picture so let's say it's
trying to classify images interesting that
so if you have this example which is a label which is zero
and the second image maybe you didn't get the chance to send inspectors so there's
no labels
and so on and so forth
then at some point it takes a picture and people
back at our so says OK this is interesting
so you have a positive example and so on so many
images will be unlabelled
and furthermore
there's another twist
after taking many pictures of these kind of object people
back hours my say OK those are no longer interesting right so the same kind
of facts might not change its labels
so what we have we have a learning problem on the reverse side to try
to decide whether an image is interesting or not
the number of examples throws
there might not be they also arrive sequentially
and you may not be able to store them all so cannot hold them more
most examples will be unlabelled
if you will be labeled so therefore its semi supervised learning but in this online
criminals setting
there's maybe there's no even no idea assumptions such that
the joint line joint distribution can change over time
so here's exactly the setting at
time step t
there's some
two story picks
o point
xt and on the line label
but this is not necessarily i i d
so it's going to show xt to the learner
the learner has the classifier to maintain so
at time t it's f t
it will predict ftxt
then we use a small probability
the world is going to tell the learner what
the true label white he is otherwise it will not
however so the
i remains on labels
and then finally the learner has to update
it's classifier fifty two fifty plus one
now with x
he or and potentially widely if not scale
but we also wanted to update the classifiers even if what is not given
and this repeats forever
as one example of this setting let's look at one particular
semisupervised learning algorithm which is manifold regularisation we've seen before
so let's recall what
the objective for the for that is so here you have
the this is labelled
the last term so delta function
this basically says is quite he labelled or not
big t is the total number of input but only a small fraction of that
we have delta y equals one
and those data points
you want to measure the loss of your prediction and the true labels
and you have this long term
then you have this across energy term which is
pairwise between a
now this is what we call the patch
loss function because it assumes you have
all big key example was their one and only vote in front
what we want to do is to say that we can not do that because
we don't have all the data in front of us
instead we can use something else which looks similar but it's an instantaneous loss
this loss has the subscript t
and if you look at that you know this could coefficient is really just
the term at time small t
and you have the same norm
and here
instead of
complete graph term where you have all pairwise
here you have
xt to all previous ones but nothing else
now there's an interesting property that this
that risk is the same as the average of those instantaneous risk
the way we define it
and what that gives you is the way to do
learning comics learning
in a very simple manner but still have some theoretical guarantee
in particular
we're going to
instead of
solving the
minimizing the
bach objective
we're going to
try to minimize the instantaneous
loss function
at every step but just by a little bit we're going to do gradient step
to try to minimize this instantaneous risk
so that's what we will do well
the former gradient descent
and the step size we perform this gradient descent has to be cared to certain
there's one thing that we need to
remember that the accuracy is not defined in this case
because we don't have IID samples
the accuracy can be arbitrarily bad close to one if the world keeps changing the
correct mapping so that's not the correct quantity to look at
the correct quantity to look at is instead how well
your ass
performs small as he at each time step
performs on those instantaneous risk
when you add them average them together
and you want to compare this
we is
the batch
loss if you
i had the luxury of all data points and select the best one to minimize
if you want to look at the difference
and here's the argument
if the world keeps changing the underlying concept
f star here the batch loss will be bad because there's no single
function that can
so one day i was this early this intermediate degrees it would like to combine
so we have two come
so i also talked about generalizing comes and he talked about what the kernel learning
so we try to find a linear combination of
so we have the combination coefficients here one
what you can
and then i would like to find the optimal combination of fish and you can
do this by solving slightly more complex optimization problems which is called a semidefinite programming
for second order cone programming and they can find the coefficients
alpha coefficients
what's more pictures and the coefficients what kind of the same time
so it's a globally optimal solution
this is one way of right
another way was to
extent have joint feature maps so you not only have come along the x
the input but we cannot on the outputs
so we include the labels
in the future
the phi functions
and there different ways of using this points the conditional interviews or type of about
maximum margin
structured output learning
here the idea is that the
try to learn a function
f of y given x
which scores segmentation why
well given x
and in this function we can predict label just by maximizing the function of all
possible y
OK so you have some all possible labellings and just take pretty with the labeling
which has the maximum score
one of the training what can we do so we can
so we end sequences sequence here
in particular of the
and now we would like to f
such that
score for the true labeling
it's much larger than the score of the problem
so on compute difference you have this kind of optimization problem would like to find
the function f
such that this difference here this is the score the the true labeling minus the
on april labeling
is large so greater than one
in a few cases the allowed to be smaller than one
but but this expect
and we have one constraints from leaving
because they can be exponentially many different probably
i mean for instance when you consider segmentations of sequences so there might be really
i mean different many different possibilities of place
OK so
other questions with
i'm going to use this in the applications later but again
so how can we solve these kind of problems so would like to solve this
so now i used actually so you
he was still had the function f you
now i'm using the kernel function the joint feature map between
between x and y and the trying to come up with a linear function here
and we try to maximize the margin between the true in the wrong
the idea is that
solve the optimisation problem what small set up from labeling
it may be just one from leaving the beginning we solve the optimisation problem
this the number of constraints still small
using this solution
you can find other constraints other labeling which
don't satisfy this constraint
b at what will come
we iterate this
the constraints are not satisfied
the size of given node the siblings of g would be a and b are
a and b all siblings meaning of the same generation of the same for the
same yes father the notion of so this one is an ancestor of of this
one and this was a descendant of this once you've got all this sort of
the cavalry there's one curious vocabulary on which people don't agree on which is do
we should we use for the sun all almost daughter
OK so i mean have seen both and there's a strong movement so we do
not want to use father-son mother-daughter would be better
i will not enter into debate
there are more definitions and there are cases where people are interested in having particular
binary trees
some which are going to be said to be for four means we don't like
dangling branches where there is only one of the two siblings so that means that
we will have either zero or two children
that's when you're going to say the tree is full
and perfect
or complete usually after complete here where i disagree with with mister wikipedia complete binary
trees is when you fall and at the same time all the leaves are the
same level
OK see you've got a very nice trigger trees obviously not just interesting for us
i mean there are essential for people working with with data structures because that's not
still is the best way to deal with variance in a complicated variance nowadays too
stop the data and be able to access is as fast as possible
OK some things about algorithms trying to return to what we've already said all strings
you can edit you can use an edit distance
OK which you can compute the variance people are not quite agreeing on what should
be the right edit distance
you do have tree kernels which i said that people have from problems agreeing on
what an edit distances one tree can it's also say it is not at all
as easy not at all a simple to be able to to do tree kernels
and get them to work
you can of course to find patterns in trees and try work with these the
general rule of the rule of thumb is that if you've got all the trees
so so i mean the world really matters and the trees in the first few
stargate for whatever you can do on strings you can do on trees
his agenda
there may be exceptions and basically i would work about as well the only thing
is that you do find yourself with a lot more syntax
in writing things in describing things because it suits it becomes necessarily much more
and it's difficult because of that
but i mean i know of
four ordered trees no problem that would say polynomial in the case strings and certainly
be exponential in the case of of trees
yes about vocabulary when you've got a set of trees is usually called the forest
and the sequence of trees is called a hedge
there are a lot of variance i mean these are just some of the things
i want to say about trees are just because yes well here with people who
have worked well working a lot on trees and they don't have the chance of
telling us about it during the bootcamp but there is a variant where the trees
or or in order sort of then you can sort of makes around the different
branches of the trees and becomes combinatorial clearly much more music
and and difficult
OK a quick word about graphs
which are the next step up or we could say we've been two two five
we've come back from that by saying the tree with some sort of attention to
generate graphs
and now what is the graph the graph can be
something like this or something like this this would be an oriented digraph because it's
got a little arrows little arcs and this would be normal graph without any orientation
so an undirected graph which is the second object he saw is composed of vertices
the singular is vertex and edge is
they may be loops even if they usually of no loops in that case in
the case of undirected graphs and the edges obviously or indirectly there's no beginning and
no end so you would say that an edge is incident to two vertices to
just say that it is touching at two ends on two vertices
and of course it'll only be incident to one vertex
if it is and
this is the vocabulary to be some so digraph or die directed graph is
this time composer composer vertices and
sometimes you will also use the word edges to indicate their edges with arrows i
prefer the word ox which is used places such as as edges
now of course an arc is directed and and has now you don't see it
start and that's why didn't put it in blue i was looking for the vocabulary
source and
the station
then to look at it
six states would be or sink sink vertex is one where all the edges arrive
and nobody's from the check that OK there is some vocabulary and it is worth
looking into the vocabulary of the different things and using the correct recovery if not
it becomes very messy the advantage of these theories with strings trees or graphs is
in the vocabulary of using the correct when it does correspond to interaction if we
don't have which is usually
rough word right well then we getting there
christians mixed up for example you get path in one case the change in the
other cycle and usually circuit
and connected is one case strongly connected not getting into this i'm just trying to
point out the fact that there is a difference of recovery
OK why do we like grophs wider computer scientists like graph because they are great
for modeling tasks
OK when you get a problem and wrote problem from the outside world it is
very efficient use these questions it is you will end up by drawing a graph
to represent you will not end up by in most cases represented by string because
the capacity of the string to model things is is not enough a truly is
usually not enough a graph corresponds to first order logic so you're working on something
which has a nice expressive power that is why people like coming up with graphs
so from the modelling point of view graphs already great and it is reasonable to
say well this is my you know i have modelled my problem as this set
well you can apply the junction tree of
this is the key observation
these are only be efficient for certain classes of graphs
you can use it in q four five
the only only be efficient for certain classes of graphs whose which was
this is the class of what they call for about
also called the only graph
the junction tree algorithm actually runs scored
also see what i call the is
according to court first in order to understand what the core of the graph in
the so what chord
it is something related site
four in the cycle
is an edge
connecting two nodes in the cycle
but which does not belong
you can see it as a shortcut decide for example if you see
his cycle
this cycle has no shortcut
this cycle has more shortcut so it has no core
these big cycle here
has won shortcuts
so these cycle has four
now if you look at these graphs here so this graph is is not chordal
because there are cycles
but these
the graph is chordal because any cycles of length greater than three
as the shocker
of course the cycle of length we can not have from each
so basically you only apply for roughly with three
for any cycle can think of here
apart from the three psychologically three
has a short
the core
so these graphical waterfall
one the graph very very special types of graphs
our technically speaking very nice things
that's exactly what graph with a junction tree of
before i said
i said separately
the junction tree of rules applied
any type of graph
that is no contradiction
what if the graph is chordal
you can add edges in the graph until it becomes chordal so if you have
a graph
which is like these
it's not a part of that
because has cycles
with no shortcut
instead of solving these problems
in this graph i can solve the problem is
because this graph was quite
you know that i can apply the junction tree of the rules that
then you can ask the question well you change the problem
before you had this problem
this problem which is different from
he was
a different approach
it's much more general problems in the world
more edges you you include the last conditional independence statements you are making
so by including edges and making less assumptions about my probability distribution
that's not the problem of losing information by doing
that's the price to pay in order to be able to run the
exercise like this not important problem because of this issue that edges can all edges
in the graph to make it work
because in the worst case
the fully connected graph
he scored
because any cycle
greater than three
has an edge has has a stroke
so you can always add edges into making graph one
you're just solving a larger problem
so let's see the steps of the junction tree
yes it's not
this is an example of how it's not unique
and this will lead to the restoration of learning and knowledge
so followers of of bacon established the royal society in
sixteen sixty two just after charles was restored
to england after the period of problem well
and there was a history
written of the royal society
a book about this thing
published in sixteen sixty seven
only five years after it was founded why did they publishing history so soon
let's look at this that the brothers piece of this book here's the late francis
bacon was said to be RTU minced or it
restore the arts
OK here's the president of the royal society the mathematician
viscount broker
and here in the middle being crowned with laurel is charles the second
why do they have him up on a pedestal
because they hoping to science scientists have
before and ever since
to extract some money out of the government to do their research
they actually never got it from charles but wasn't for lack of trying and this
is why they wrote the history
to try to make the case for being supported
OK now let's look at all the good things that will come from science
from the royal society
in the background you see what that is will blow it up
here there's a here to it on the bookshelf
if you look really fine on the bookshelf you can see that some of them
have title have written riding on the spine see with that one is
anyway really
what science book is a by the had
so astronomy
that's the telescope the back
OK or over here on the wall
but set that
the clock was shaped like a piece of pie
because it has the pendulum inside
so or ontology making good clocks
OK or here
what's happening
it's hard for you know
it's the wind gauge
it has been inside the blows on this and you can tell from articles on
the scale of strong wind is so meteorology
back here on the pillar
but of those things for
proprietorial thing
now what do all these things have in common that they are going to do
charles the second
good clocks
meteorology talk but
they all have to do
with navigation
right with making
england's strong and c
now back here's another science
that doesn't seem to have anything to do with navigation why would chemistry be important
to charles
to make gunpowder
it was the chapter about gunpowder in the history of the royal society
and appear at the top is the motto
which is newly used in where bob which comes from this quote from morris
and what it says is less you ask who leads me
and what household by large that's what philosophy i advocate
there is no master in whose words i am bound to take an oath
wherever the storm forces me
there are put in this the guest
so it's the experiment not the philosopher that leads you
to the conclusion
so newly use and whereby is in the words of non
and in fact the original name of the royal society was the royal society
for the improvement of natural knowledge
by experiments
OK so we're going to see as the course goes along
important experiments that really decided questions and in fact
bacon's most important kind of experiment was one that finally decides between two rival hypotheses
proving the one
and disproving the other say they do all sorts of experiments and just be
collecting butterflies no
i don't mean to insult people quite butterflies so finding the do
there's something special about experiments that really are designed to answer questions
now the bacon devised the name for such experiments and they are based on this
you have a road diverges and you need to know which way to go between
these two hypotheses
what do you need
you know which way to go
you need to cite
or this was across
it would not be bound at the crossroads
so the rock latin name for crosses crux you see what they call the experiment
that's the origin of the word crucial
it's the one that tells you which way to go
OK so here is
isaac newton
and is holding something
can you see what is holding in his hand
you here
it's the prison
while still in prison because that was his crucial experiment
and here's his diagram of that experiment with the prism
he called it the experiment encourages taking the word from bacon
OK so light came in through a hole in the window
through the lens and then got banned and dispersed into the different colors so you
get a spectrum here on this the different colours
now there is the question how does the prism a color
and a car
i thought that the light was a train of pulses
and is it goes through something like the prism or is reflects from a thin
layer of oil on water something like that that changes the timing of the pulses
and therefore changes the colour
in to look at machine lessons
at cock eventually nearing
and we already heard talk of professor plato
but deep kernels
there's some work on people kernels
by studied third problem and
try to to come up with support vector machines multiple layers that can be training
quite simple way and
can be extended whereas many places you want
so the contents of the talk progress follows first a
big plate a little bit about support vector machines and especially support vector machine request
because that will be in the pool
of extracting features
from input patterns
we will continue with how the deep support vector machine looks like how this waned
and we will most likely some experimental results
both on ten regression problems and eight or
classification problems
so in general machine learning as you know there's a lot of applications both think classification and regression
but also in the that control like
my background is reinforcement learning
i made a lot of like cain playing programs like commercial planes
as well for like shares cameron
also class thing out like the text is all particle
like a big ball like data different methods that machine learning
so in general use data
you to give us a lot of data stored
yeah obama data about four with data to get northwards
through the formal model
so some example applications with work for me is like seeing classification face recognition emotion recognition
and also object recognition sorry i have also worked on this
golf that datasets
well about support vector machines of course data perform use much better especially when there are
many input features
and very few
inputs are
fed fuel examples
then de yeah the best choice
yeah they're like shallow models are also of support said
well the deep architectures can perform better we have to find another notch the word for it but kind of like
this method result in the frame going
deep way
and they're five study this problem to do this support vector machines
so in general deep architectures have had the best results
now many image recognition datasets
and just jewel like millions of parameters
because it's
that don't use kernels that don't loofe exhibit your space
it's still very fast developed examples
because they don't have to compute a similarity matrix
which is kind of complicated
life big data use kernel methods
another thing is like support vector machines that results all fundamental law all the chosen kernel
but kernels not flexible i mean most people just solution rbf kernel
maybe some other grows they compare with but most the ball like if you
look farm bio-informatics and chemistry they
would just support vector machines as a tool
just use radial basis function kernels
and shown like sigma parameter
this off like going combining kernels that kernel learning
at all solved deep support vector machine
is that kernel becomes much more flexible
so the idea of the deep support vector machine is basically you think by many layers
of support vector machines
instead of multiple kernel learning way of weighting coefficients
basically the wall method
consists of like support vector machines
which are like support vector coefficients
and by shatters
there's nothing our this has been shown this system
to support vector machines requester because yeah we use the text
features because it should be configured features
yeah yeah basically based on the theory of structural risk averse taste developed by
vapnik six is ready
and the idea is to have a function
of them
the reason is
the city hall
the station
so far
these all
and this is all
she was
you see
i don't
while on
all i will
but this is
and not busy
she is
is is
i used
c one use
all these
and you we can see this
results of
this is
she is more
so long
he is
is you
so this should be so much
i will show you how
the following content is provided under a Creative Commons license your support will help MIT
OpenCourseWare continue to offer high-quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
visit MIT OpenCourseWare at ocw . MIT T . EDU
let's get started to weekenders over time to get back to work back to learning
a few announcements tomorrow quiz 2 based on homework to Thursday will be the periodic
table quiz on Member all you have to do is still in the wild wanted
to letter abbreviation for the chemical symbol
and Friday is the last day of the contest 5 PM send it to me
by e-mail can enter more than once you want you can have multiple entries you
can do the lanthanides and actinides both are test 1 will be a week from
Wednesday then I will say something about that
later in the week
and I will be available 332 432 for for office hours of someone wishes to
drop in
last day we talked about the validation of the boar model we saw that the
boar model was able to correlate the observations of instrument which had been formulated by
Baldwin and furthermore the concept of
energy level quantization of was observed
In the mercury is during the course of the front hurts experiment giving credence to
the notion that quantization of energy levels is not the property of
1 electron atoms alone but it's something that is more broadly applicable so was validated
and very very strong measure but there were also some contrary data and we saw
those 1st there was the observation by Michael who back in the late 18 eighties
and very precise interferometric measurements of the hydrogen lines and had observed that the 656
line associated with the transition from n equals 3 n equals 2 was in fact
Dublin you look really carefully defined it was not a single line 2 lines and
borders silent on such matters and then we had xenon who conducted the experiment of
hydrogen emission spectrum is a magnetic field and he found line splitting in the magnetic
field and furthermore that the intensity of the splitting was proportional to the intensity of
the applied magnetic field again the boar model silent about these are splitting into multiple
levels and subsequent stock did the analogous experiment but with an electric field and again
in an electric field line splitting observed the intensity of the line splitting varying with
the intensity of the applied electric field so there are some problems here
Sommerfeld came to the rescue in 1960
preserved the the broad concept of energy levels but he put some fine structure the
fine structure involved taking those levels that
quantified with the number on and assigning to those who levels and a little bit
of energy with
so that there is a plurality of orbits
some circular in a sum little bit of circular
and that bandwidth he called the shelf this is the shell model in order to
label the various
orbitals as he called them introduced to more quantum numbers l and and we saw
last day and then at the very end of the lecture we saw the last
what you see here
so compared the british with the german about
two hundred three hundred percent better
so they really don't know anything
but consider that this may in part be
this always immediately due to this twenty percent
production i think it's two hundred thousand
the key is another example of spain
they are slightly more realistic
and it goes to together with the less you say that the best one of
the russians
because not because they better informed
but there are less informed
so let's misinformed
note spanish meaning doesn't make the golden it doesn't know anything
that was the first
and the lesson was
one theory
widespread way
to communicate the effect of screening or five year survival rates
five years survival it's misleading in the context of screen
there are serious correlated this mortality is but they used by medical institutions by politicians
and policies
to mislead the public
you are
involved in teaching statistics
you need to prepare the next generation to understand these things
and also within statistics there are some things that are more useful than it
i would say
understanding five-year survival rates is more useful for the general public the confidence intervals to
p values
but in the talk
the second
of the three ways to
mislead the public conditional probabilities
so p values the conditional probability and the studies that we and others have done
we university professors was also teach statistics course students
revealed that image or doesn't understand what p values
they confused the direction of the conditional probabilities and all those kind of things
that's also remarkable differences instance psychology known for teaching students at least for two semesters
in statistics and the result is a ritual mostly
not undistinguished
conditional probability
let's start
with standard situation
happens to every woman aged fifty and older
and that's the way it's being advertised
ten to twenty year-olds consequences the i things that are particularly prone to breast cancer
i'll try something with you
i will give you know the information about breast cancer
in four
that's called conditional probabilities that still a medical student get
and if ask you what you tell women who just tested positive screen
i hope
that most of you are confused
i know this is a very special audience but there's still hope to list
many are confused
if you are confused and you can feel what they
the state of most of the doctors is that of trained
there are confused by these numbers
and then i will give you a different representation
the turns confusion into inside it's just the representation
so that avoids to send his doctors into statistics course which they would never go
because they have
gone to a minimum of statistical education and i learned as many doctors believe that
have no statistics g
and it's just teaching
so are you ready
being the subject OK
you conduct screening mammography screening what you know about the population is the following
the chains to the women this group has breast cancer is one percent
if she has breast cancer the probability that she tests positive is ninety percent
and third
if she does not have breast cancer the probability that you nevertheless test
the positive is nine percent
so we have the prevalence of base rate of one percent is sensitivity or hit
rate of ninety percent and the false positive rate of nine percent is woman
she just has to pass
she ask your doctor tell me
you have no press cancer
or what are the chances
it is ninety nine percent nineteen fifty tell me
but i know how to sleep
what do tell
that's all you know it screening
you know you can just typing typing typing monkeys shakespear what not and eventually you
can get away something that kind of work changing the world plus one minus one
or one move your copy-and-paste this there were i changed that name that in the
unlikely program that from external appearances works you know place hang whatever was the
the desired goal
but the internally is a mess
it's not well structured it's not well commented it's not easy to understand it would
be easy to modify it makes a lot of decisions that really suboptimal and were
we're really interested in producing engineers that have a good sense of design and i
really appreciate what is involved in writing good software well designed software not just working
software so we will be giving you feedback on both kind of the correctness functionality
of code but in this is important if not more so also on how how
well we think you did designing and implementing and and writing code that is a
high quality so i made a big deal out of that is something that is
not shared by other classes and so if you someone who was self-taught or in
a class that didn't emphasise this might feel that there's a little bit of get
there we need to kind of make up with you
and we can work with you because in fact this is a very individual because
there's not one good example of the perfect style that
in the way that a lot of different people
express themselves in written communication
very well but differently the same thing is true about programs right you will have
your own unique style and work with you to kind of coach one on getting
your style come through
and the beautiful now
this comes back to almost point one is well that we make heavy use of
undergraduate section leaders as matters in this program so we have a staff of fifty
or so undergraduates who worked with the one of six a BMX courses as the
team and they have specific responsibilities with their section so mentoring and integrating and then
meeting with the
section is on their to give individualized feedback on the programs such as well as
just the question solving problems being in the layer thirty plus hours their most weekday
nights about six hours and often well past midnight when exposed to cut off to
solve people's problems helping you when you get a little stock answering your questions and
making sure that you can all making forward progress and that comes back to point
one that then some universities i think where choosing to use their intercourse is kind
of a leader like well separate the wheat from the chaff early and let's make
it really hard not not provide too much support that we will make sure we
get people we want to have a different idea the programming is hard especially when
you're learning there's a lot of complexity the master and a lot of
details that they can interfere with kind of moving forward and we don't want you
to to to get stuck on something that we can very easily result three is
to try and make sure you have access to all staff members in person in
email regularly in section to help get through roadblocks and keep you moving forward
what you need to know to be sure you knew well
people who think that you know to be a good computer programmer you could mass
you need to be good at logic you need to be good
drinking joel i don't actually if it comes down to more personality traits and i
think any particular
technique to scale like you know you don't need to be good at math writing
you know how much you know calculus and trick shows up and this does not
very much relevant logic that helps you know
i think it comes down to more things like tricks like curiosity and determination hard
work that starting early asking questions when you don't understand something try to solve the
problem by logic i think is very valuable and how to think about how to
make makes that's why this case works and why that case doesn't work right thinking
about that logically
like the movie it all the way to think about but then i think these
are the skills that actually be the best and they said it best in this
class and probably every other thing you want to tackle but there's a lot of
time that we spend here to master this i can talk about programming only one
global y and you know it makes less sense but when you write it yourself
right it's a very different experience and that's where you know being being kind of
focused on staying on task and getting help when you get stuck can help you
move through that
all right
and questions about one-sixth but we do why do we do
that has nothing to say your afraid of having a voice recorder
world on your parents will come and see that you come to class you can
prove it
all right
my unbiased opinion about why one a six b is one of the best courses
at stanford
i'm not almost
actually can be
very useful when thinking about holistic wall
i've got something here to decide this might imply
and i want to know how all the pixels in my template move given that
i want the pixels to be coherent to a certain primitive what what kind of
saying there is that a lot of one top flight
and i know that
so save translation i want all these pixels to move the same amount
and things so if i look at these so that the pixel coherence assumption i
can cannot that this pixel here
given displacement i can predict pretty well because there's a high correlation between these
and if i look at these or in individual cases i can do a very
good job of predicting what the whole
translation should be
in looking at individual pixels
similarly so that's translation so you get well what about other things what scale
skeleton exact same thing because i worried about translation at the pixel level
but the damage what
it's actually more holistic so
i can i know that there is a high correlation between so this position in
this position in in in in in
an image and if i got constraint that all the movements of these have two
two of parametric what they scale
i can do a very good job here predicting this movement without having to exhaustively
search over scales i know that it's individual pixels related to one another and so
i can kind of based on this really simple
domain knowledge i can actually come up with a kind of a clever way of
solving this exhaustive search problem and we will contact from on the same again motion
fields rotations and things like that and so on and so forth and so that's
why i kind of like this pixel coherence assumption is so useful
and so it is the pixel coherence assumption is useful across all wall and so
most natural images like places and things like that
so another is the pixel coherence assumption is good is that now let's say that
i trying to
the this this box detection
and this is what template
and this is the input image so i'm going to go into here
i cannot sample every point
now the nice thing about the pixel coherence assumption it's it basically ensures that even
if this this is slightly misaligned because of this most graceful degradation in the in
the in the autocorrelation function
i can still get a reasonable maxscore here
actually still pretty pretty good job so as as i said above threshold appropriately even
though it's slightly misaligned it'll it'll it'll still do a good job and again that
doesn't apply to all TV signals some TV signals that might have nothing but edges
or lots of of noise and things are slightly misaligned those two singles
they'll be completely uncorrelated in one match
the the assumption that i've got some sort of coherent here actually enables me to
get a good idea of how i should sample
what space because i'm i've got a good idea of of perhaps how these image
image pixels across to each other
well yes i mean this as so there is there there are probably probably physical
physical attributes of kind of like a national natural natural laws of physics and things
that kind of governing things and also perhaps it could also about you like i
give me something that had taken evolutionary thing to do that we we kind of
we did that the visual system to come to take advantage of
what's out there in the world and what we tend to observe what we need
to observe
the center and the center is a lot of information in the low frequencies are
not so much information behind free
and so could be
and essentially or more pragmatic way is that this is the universe we live in
let's take advantage of that of the mind so kind of chicken and the egg
it's a philosophical question asking why like that but i think the coping in computer
vision and this is kind of what i'm trying to say
that's a nice thing in computer vision is that if you look at some of
these redundancies in the human visual system in what's going on in images you can
actually make you learning algorithms a lot better
rather than kind of going to things lively
again there might be slight degradation again it's still matches the c as the object
but obviously we can only go so far
if things are completely different then things start falling apart and it's county so we
don't have to sample every pixel we can actually be smart about where sampling and
we can actually look at the space discreetly without losing too much information
and this is kind of what a lot of modern-day things things OK so let's
let's go to the example let's say about my vector p
and p one is perhaps translation experts who is translation want to be anything could
be maybe rotation scale whatever you like and let's assume that i'm going to have
their own and were concerned so obviously if i go too far outside the image
it stops and things but at the moment our assumption is that well it's continued
i can i can go anywhere in here is continuous i can get to it
from the ground granularity which would take infinite computations
so what the pixel coherence assumption allows you to do is that we make as
but assumptions about where we judge
and generally now
i think people will be looking for the next slide of well OK so you
can't get this cycling here is the kind theory on how much jump should be
made unfortunately a lot of a lot the time whatever
this is essentially based on heuristics is based on what on what on what works
so people typically ten to scale and only search images in terms of of so
four introduction
and i would like to
talk about microscopy course
there is no reason across nations
today focus patient you which is given below
and so
last year she
that's it
and maybe the SEM as you know
this method is called i don't see them
that means some kind of a scanning electron microscopy to use and also was a
solution to result microscopy
so the basic principle
o this you
we have very fine being its conversion
and this is
what is this
it's all that means is transmitted
the electrons
and on this or so this is the rules of the high angle scattered electrons
now let's go to the exterior walls of the cylinder not six
so the whole signal
that we actually say
you are the high list
get also to
now if look at the usually this is
you can see them
a very small holes
we get this right inflections which are listed and is responsible for most of the
work which is down here i would hear
o bonds
thirty four new radios
so this was
the high heels
the only thing that
now you want to yes
some information on the chemistry
so that means that this is the record depends on the average number of the
columns of them and you get the best
this is the right
i would say
he who is not easy to
but you see it has some kind of correlation between the atomic numbers and intensity
get more so
this type of scattering
so these kinds of france
greece on the inside face data that can be huge
you to use the word because it was
the following is rescued elephants
i just summarized
so this is a kind the of sense
first it you had columns
every number
this is very important
it is approximately square
and there is a conflict resolution
here we have not been as you know in first case is
the change of
it means that we have almost always
this is you might what is
is independent of the book
and this is why call it the nation's images
we said we see as follows which is you know
is called the ones which have high atomic numbers
but for some reason i talked about it was the interpretation
we see
is not people
we also need
simulations calculations matching of the experiment is the use
now we can to do
search across the
well first of all it was given
that's what you need attention to
microscope which
there are also
actually go about this
four rules
this is
so this is time
that really has a very slow growth very small size
size of the
so for me is roughly three to four
this is sort of scary monsters
there other
important events
say a procedures this kind of stuff
first of all you know
see history
so we have some operations
and see is correct structures you would get much
this one
so is one of the solutions
i would love this statement
we have
and way in which means conversion which you can also spaces
and of course the
he was also very important
now this is from the
it means
we need know all
less scary
and specimen thickness is also very important
this operation is especially people
seven image
i would just show the differences
so this is