some kind of features of the interaction of nodes u and right i want to
estimate the
this set of weights w that sort of thing only that combines these features and
and whatever the value of this expression becomes that would be like edge edge weight
at strength here OK so
once they can now this weighted graph
now i will do the random walk with restarts starting from as so this is
personalized pagerank with teleportation back to paula jumps back to us and i will this
and now every node gets away which is the random walk visiting probability and i've
just going to the nodes by this the workers the probability and that my prediction
writes in some sense of what i'm doing is i'm learning how to rank nodes
in a graph where i would start with a simple graph i will learn how
to put weight on it so that might and walker sort of bias towards certain
parts of the graph and not biased towards the other parts of the graph so
the main question would be how this function as right how to estimate the parameters
w so that somehow magically by scientists edge strands well it quickly so that my
random walk ends up in one part of the graph and not part of the
graph OK so now what i will show you the way how to estimate is
about how to estimate this
a function that assigns a strand two and h OK so
here is how it is that right so the idea is first is to to
formalise this stochastic random walk transition matrix i reported you right and what it says
probability that that you reverse engine is proportional to the weight of the edge and
if there is no edge then probability of going
the two you is zero right and then five write down what is the pagerank
equations here is the page incorporation right i say
my my transition probabilities
are are sort of my my state is what when i was before or this
is the random jump right so with probability one minus five make a step in
the graph and with probability alpha i john back to my my and the work
of john back to the starting right and now that i that a computer that
they have this transition matrix q and computer agent b
of these of this matrix q where
and now i think nodes by the pagerank is the probability of of right so
that this is what i will do know my question is what how why how
do i figured out what this weight should be and we figured out a way
to to say what i want to know what the parameters w of my function
after that assigns is due to the edge weights the going to my
and what transition probability from random opposition probably i computes i compute these probabilities
and then i ran by visiting probability is OK so this is the way how
we how we are doing the whole thing so the next day the optimisation problem
we like to solve the following right so for every every node has has pagerank
let's call it visiting probability of score piece of your right and then i have
a set of destination nodes disagree nodes of myself of positive training examples and i
have a set of red nodes that have been called nobody knows this i colored
the was communities are the the which one great things in the future right so
what i would like to do is the follow so here are some of my
my optimisation problem i say i want to find i want to find w right
wrt the parameters of the function of the size and strength i want to find
w that is small and i want this to w to be such that the
visiting probability of nodes of the nodes are higher than the visiting probability of right
so i want i want to find such an w that ITN my positive training
examples are to visit more often than during the work on the negative training examples
right so all the sort of the the
the really what you want to do is i want to satisfy these constraints i
don't care so much about his WR's like i want to find w such that
all these constraints are satisfied right in the way i can do this is to
take these constraints input and put them into the objective function and say OK this
is what we want to do that i want to say hi i want to
find w such that w is small it doesn't matter and then he is might
want say right laws goes over all pairs of positive and negative examples and it
takes the probability of n being the probability of being of being visited and now
i think the difference and here is how i can so for example analyse distance
i say half if renault has using probability less the degree node then the difference
is negative and i could no penalty
if you the constrained in some sense is violated so we might negative note my
note to richard creating in the future is visited more likely than some nodes which
i created in the future then i got some penalty but let's is is proportional
to the east
the difference is probably right so now i think the constraints in the previous slide
i just put them in the objective function right so what i'd really like to
do is figure out w so that the sum is the smallest possible right and
this is like a regularization part of the optimisation problem right so this is this
is what we can and now of course what i want i want to solve
this problem so the way i can solve this is is to is to do
the following things right so what is
thing probabilities depend on the right independent w which is the
parameters of the extract the sine function the weight so the way the whole thing
works is right i have this this w goes into my
my function of the size and strength and standard defines the weighted adjacency matrix of
woodbridge then i what pagerank to obtain this but this rank this visiting probability speed
and then i rank nodes based on these probabilities p right and i want to
find such w the
in some sense for any for every node
you get a higher value than every read then every right sort of the nodes
linking nodes need to have need to be less likely to be visited the nodes
that i think OK so that's that's what we'd like to do so now the
question is how do i get publicity w together down here so there's a few
steps in between how WMP i think
OK so the way i can think about this is basically i can just think
of this as taking the derivative of this of this optimisation problem and try to
do try to some kind of descent gradient descent right and what is interesting is
if i think
now here's my function i think that would be the vector w and and if
i write now the partial derivatives the question the question because i think the idea
of the pagerank score with respect to my parameters w and what is interesting is
the same way as you as you have because way to compute pagerank scores through
power iteration it turns out that you can compute the derivatives in the same kind
recursive power iteration lightweight right so the derivative of of a particular w with the
partition of the making of a particular
element of my w i can produce using this kind of crazy right so the
which is sort of like a power iteration so basically it what this shows is
that i can in principle the way to find this
the parameters of the strand
assigning functions
time t and acceleration on p
if you measure the child's genes
then those should be independent of the grandparents genes given the parent genes
if you have some competition with lots of different teams
then presumably
as long as the teams are taking players from the very large all the ability
of some
he knew picking random is independent of the ability of another team you take random
and that all
so that the marginal independent
think like you know
some sort of big we
but now
it's not the case
that the ability of team a is independent of the ability of team b
if we actually know knows
the outcome of the game between a and b
so i just want to have one example of something where
conditioned on the knowledge which we presume is actually a function
these two two things then those two things that were marginally independent are no longer
independent conditioned on that knowledge
so any questions about that
OK so we're trying to represent conditional independence between variables
and let's start out with factor graphs although these are sort of the most
the most modern one there nice easy to understand
so in fact that we have two types of nodes we have the
represents the random variables like for example a and then we have filled dots represent
factors in the joint distribution
so for example there's still but here connecting a and c and that represents a
back there
in the joint distribution of that by factor i just mean
non negative function of its arguments
and essentially what a factor graph represent is
the factorisation of a joint probability distribution so
factor graph h here
represents the that the probability distribution of a b c d and e
factors into the product of a distribution over a and c
the distribution over
sorry not distribution a non negative function
between a and c
a non negative function of b c and d
and and non negative function of the e
OK and this term here is simply a normalisation constant
so that when you multiply these three nonnegative functions you get something that integrates or
sums to one
that was before
for graph b we are representing five different factorizations which have written down here
and just to drive the point home z is a normalisation constant in other words
in in this probability distribution is represented by the a factor graph a if all
variables are discrete and take values in
a b c d and e corresponding to the names of those variables then normalisation
function is just the sum over all possible values of a b
the PDE of the product of these factors
we're going to define two nodes v neighbors if they share a common factor
so for example a and c are neighbours
at the top i've just rewritten stuff that i had on the previous slide
now let's think about what the factor graph represents in terms of conditional independence relationships
between the variables
so remember
two nodes are neighbors if they share a common factor
and we're going to define the pattern to be a sequence of neighboring nodes for
a b b
in the past
and here's the back
is it
independent of y
this is that the
if every path between x and y
contains some nodes in the set b
just by looking at the factor graph and knowing that the factor graph correspond to
some factorizations of the joint probability distribution we can say all sorts of things about
which variables are independent of which other variables
according to the area of the fact
which is fairly trivial
is that given the neighbors of x the variable x is conditionally independent of all
other variables which we can write out
x is independent of y given the neighbors of x for all y that are
x and the neighbours of
and that's pretty clear because if this is true then every path between something else
has to go to one of its neighbors
so how do we show
a statement like this
remember we started out with
with the fact that this graph represents that the probability distribution factors in a particular
and from that we're making grand claims about conditional independence
but i think you look at the following conditional independence was x is conditionally independent
of y given the
that correspond to this big one way of writing that they
so we have the following
factorizations let's say
the joint distribution of x y
in the
can be written as the product of factor
between x and b
and in fact there are between y and p
and some normalisation constant z
so this is what we're going to start
i think this equation here
some this over x
so we sum both sides of the equation
over x
on the left-hand side we get the joint distribution over y and v
this week summed over x and that some one
on the right-hand side the normalisation constant comes out and we get some
it this one
and so on
if you compute the probability of
being at the same time sick and having a positive test and it the probability
of being in the
the upper left corner there ninety or one thousand one hundred
and in then it affinity different of
different from
the product of the probability of being of having a positive test which is
one nine c
divided by one thousand one hundred
and then the probability of being sick which is one hundred if you divided by
one thousand one hundred
obviously here
as would be expected you have
more chances of being sick
when the test
it was positive
when you have more chances of being
being being fits when the test is negative so you expect that the two variables
are actually not independent their quality corey and that's what is your right
no right
so the independence is defined as follows the independent variables
in the two variables x and y are independent if and only if their joint
probability is is the product the product of the
my marginal probabilities so the marginal if if you consider a vector x y of
two random variables the marginals
in x is the probability of x and the marginalize the probability one
it if it follows and if you have an independent variable
then the other their joint probability is the the product of their probabilities
and so you can see that since
the covariance of x and y
is defined as
if you remember the covariance of x and y
is defined as the expectation x y
nine is the expectation of
don't the asian of y
since as can be seen there when you have to
and when you have two independent variables and you have an expectation of two function
of the survival then you can break up to expectation into two single part of
x y then you see that the covariance
after independent
by one you
so this is all there was the
ways to to
was being independent is the following if you think about it in
if you think about too
volume was x and y
then the expectation of
u of x times age of y
we can write it in our two
with the with the densities i
p of x y
x y
since then
and since the
random variables are independent you can people broken into two parts
which are
the two more probabilities
and i can split up the citizens line or two in our as the product
of two into was two intervals in our right by building on on the left
side order
there an accident on the right sail sailed the terms in white and so that
gives you
the reason why could right
that for any function
i could break up the probability into the expectation into two parts
that would be the expectation of
p of x and that the expectation of it of y
that basically what's what's written there
all right so computing things for
joint vectors x y when x and y are independent is pretty easy
and also means that if x and y are independent then basically knowing that an
you have any information on on line
on the contrary when x and y are not independent then definitely knowing x gives
you some information on one
and so we'll we'll we'll see what the conditional expectation
the conditional probabilities mean then
the conditional probability of x given
given y
there's you
is the new probability on x
that takes into account what you know about why
so if found back to
two this example here with with
first on on the pathology
then we've seen
that the two variables are definitely not independent and you can
so if you look at the each rule it's different
for of stable
then you may infer that
if you know
exactly that is you know in advance for
festivities positive
and induces new
in new ship of the probability for y
if you know in advance that this is what positive the probability of being sick
it is ninety over one nineteen and it's different from from the total probability of
being sick if you don't know
that the test is positive OK
so you can substitute in
delta gene not minus or t natural on a because those are equal to each
and then you can rewrite
that equation
delta g equals or to natural law
so if you're interested
and this is a very useful equations
think about all right
well concentration of the reactants
how does that compare concentrations at equilibrium
so if you know where you are now
we know q now
know what is
you can think about the direction of the reaction think about delta g negative
going forward direction going first
so this is a very
very useful equation
predict the direction of the reaction
depending on the composition at that moment pairs competition
at equilibrium
less than k
that's going to mean you get negative
delta g
and to be spontaneous in the forward direction
so this equation
if he was greater than k
delta g is going to be
you're going to go in the reverse direction
so again this is very useful think about the relationship of human k a and
how that impacts
delta g
so let's look at an example
the same reaction
our given a value for k
four hundred degrees c
they were given
partial pressures of reactants and products
as are really here not
which direction the reaction
going to get
so let's
figure out what
q is
because we want to know the the relationship between q
and that's going tell us where we are are really equilibrium what direction will the
reaction go
all right
so here
what's going to be on the top of the expression for you
so what what goes on the top products we have
so we have one right here
so we're gonna put our partial pressure
other product
and then we have to
the geometry
which would give us
on the right other
we are reactant
consider the partial pressure
and two
the partial pressure of h two
against the geometry of the reaction
that's an equal
one point one
five point
science two point two
you could
and if you work out there
two point one
times ten to the minus two
so that q
it was listed as
one point nine
it tends to minus four
at the same temperature
so here
is greater
and so what direction will the reaction go out
so it will go
people said
toward toward reactants
world react
or you could say
reverse direction
NH three
well this is
just one point about doing this
i've noticed people continue to horsing around them when i say well what i meant
was right
and since i've done that numerous times
i suggest
you say
four reactors or toward products drawn aero
because usually that you actually write down what
my personal to to stay away from left to right on exams just just in
case from last year project we got it that but i've seen people before for
when knew the answer is just
here we have an example were able to predict what direction reaction go by looking
at you
and k
so i think about what else we can do more
from k
the size of the equilibrium constant portion of that value tells you something about the
so what does hey tell us
what does
is equal to
the reactants
so the size of q where size k a whether it's greater or less than
it's going to tell us about the ratio
all products to reactants
at equilibrium
is large
or we can say
really well
we're talking about the candidates greater
then one
you're going to have more products
reactance at equilibrium or high products
the products are going to be greater is the big number it's going to mean
that there are more products and reactants
at equilibrium
then the probability
that the dwarf
belong that the belongs to a OK the beam on the valuable corresponding to the
publication is simply the integral
of of the
the self is our you have a dual b is united by the total area
of squared OK where x and y are the counties in calling corresponding to the
location of the ball
so that's really the most basic thing you obviously you the fact that you the
assumption by mowing for uniform
yes and no
this you don't want to compute these guys exactly OK
because a for example has very very complex shape complex shape is not as simple
so-called then basically
what you're proposing going to discuss the simple numerical methods so as to approximate it
numerically this interval so
the way simple
so assume that europe's and search
what independent drops of rain each of them being distributed uniformly on the square
on the basically by d i essentially the random location of block i OK so
i assume you all to compute
there basis so this is basically what you so this is basically
the initial square you have you want them to see at the top you itself
can be learned of then each of them is uniformly distributed according to on the
u on the unit square
on basically you are interested in computing the our of the so-called where what could
you do with a very simple when the simple thing to point is basically forward
want to belong to the number
two to belong to the so-called that basically
in the uniformly distributed where you don't need to have done any stats to know
that basically good estimated that could be simply the number dropped accept that fell into
the so-called divided by the total number of blocks so that's do is said to
compute the point of view belonging to the so-called just guy come and go for
fallen into this article you about the total number of drops that these k called
capital so let's have a little bit of statistical justification for it really the basic
logic element well to do that we try to formalize a little bit what we've
been doing so introducing basically an indicator function for the set k which is called
to essentially one the the point of calling x y belongs to a and zero
on simply one and we're doing doing simple modification i realized the point it was
interested in but point that to draw belong basically
to this set a scene pretty
the expectation
indicator function
and these guys what these guys simply the uniform distribution over the square
so it is the fact
one four here because remember my my square rules for minus one to one
yes it is it found is that simple
so now basically
what we've been doing essentially
is that the through your introduce new on the valuable
OK which is simply
define as the
indicator function
applied to the former
valuable d
then you have be the which is essentially
one of the more restrictive value zero or one these within a new music video
equal to one basically if these are outside and in view of these equal to
on essentially with ministry right essentially the point distribution of interest as the expectation of
such woman volleyball and the uniform distribution
on the square of interest initial square s
so that's it
so essentially you think of it as an art
what we've been doing lately
the the initial kind of introduced me to the point that it was proposing was
basically counting the number of that fell into a divided by the total number of
draw you can write it simply as the so
of those one the rival
divided by n is just writing essentially of what i've been doing before
this is this really like a simple thing we formalising basically into them properly into
more on the viable what i've just been doing intuitively
again no
basically what do we know
when we know
that we have here is essentially
one of the the and some from i want to end of independent random volleyball
so basically if you take the limit as n goes to plus infinity
you have the strong law of large numbers that tells you that essentially
and so then i estimate come and more surely two on the expectation of the
basically the uniform distribution on the square as which is exactly what i was interested
the a century what we've been doing with what we have been using when we
are using this estimate is implicitly we're using the rule of numbers of that sort
so essentially when n is large enough this kind of justify the use of the
system OK so that's good that's good no one about basically
the properties of this estimate was what we know is quite trivial to show that
sn n is an unbiased estimate of the quantities of interest which in the case
of life particular points belonging to self code is equal to pi of form
my estimate is and i as was basically
the all to characterize the properties of the quality of a way to believe in
the use of violence so i'm going to buy and sell us which is independent
woman volleyball
so obviously essentially it's equal to essentially buy and one from the bible they're all
the same so i can put an index divided by one of the and the
number of samples
positive definite
so this matrix of all similarities between ten and training points
if this matrix is positive definite then
we are in the situation where we can construct features
and i will show you how to construct peterman
so before i can do that i have two
show you a few elementary properties maybe i'll let you
show these properties are trying to model of positive definite kernels which we are going
to use in the proof or in the construction of the feature space
maybe if you want we will take five minutes where you can try things out
and afterwards also the solution on the whiteboard
so what you need is you need to
i memorized this definition or write it down
because then i will move to the next slide where you
i have things that you can try to prove so
OK i'll i'll give you a minute to copy this if you are you have
slides right
OK so how many slides i'm missing actually because i wanted lies something sometime
they complete
complete located
this one
c c three to five these results
if you can give you some hints
well actually
the information was
you can
discovery of the same one as usual for all us
so it's
so i think some of you are really finished
first of of all
i would like to
what about all the way
this the first one
well one of the towns i exactly the class of compounds that correspond to dot
product in the space we have proven that yet but this first
the result of there is one direction of proof right given product in some space
this is actually positive definite kernel and
in the next fifteen minutes i'll show you given a positive definite kernel it corresponds
to a dot product in other space then we have both directions but this is
the one direction
and i want to prove this OK you have to substitute this into the into
this equation that we have to cheque for positive definiteness so
and we need to show that
no matter what the AIA AI and exi i are this quantity is non negative
now we can by assumption
this thing is the
OK i didn't say that but i think it was sort of here this angular
brackets thing on the right that the dot product in that space h
but products are
by linear
so you can take these coefficients in the endosomes inside the dot product
what i will do is i will
take the sum over i into this
the argument of the dot product is the sum of the into to this argument
to get this thing here and i feel again that this is actually both the
same so i cant i can rewrite this
like that and that's the norm of some vector
and this is therefore nonnegative
so we know that this is no matter what the axis in the eighties on
this is nonnegative therefore this thing here is a positive definite kernel
OK so now let's look at the second one
and what would like to the second one
you'll still be chinese beginning of the summer school OK
actually i might buy it just
as well
on a on an m dimensional manifold
and you in order to
to get a bayes rule anything close to bayes have to somehow be in the
business implicitly or explicitly estimating
the conditional expectation
right for the square loss in general of estimating the conditional distribution
of y given x
it's quite easy to see that whatever you know if you look at densities these
which are
i mean of course you make cooperate with respect to the big measure you immediately
see the true density
he knew it in the population that would be bad because this would not be
happy as we continue to speculate
they get at least some measure you have you have you have you have the
conditional density
they have
the conditional density of
what you
you this this thing of which
the x that you do see is the image
and it intuitively clear i think that these two quantities of the same because of
it's easy to verify the information is the same
right to know
two notable exception w
is the same
probability density doesn't know about the fact that you don't know t
doesn't doesn't
it doesn't care all about
for her role
although we're doing pinhead of y given x
we're actually doing you
you had y giving you
in other words instead of doing estimation of functions on
rd plus one you're doing estimation functions on rn plus one
few variables for example were
whatever dimensional space with line on the circle well
in one dimension should go
i actually do not believe that that's
that's true for all methods of estimation but
here is an example which suggests that
if you if you estimation
method is
in a suitable sense then
you should be that should be happening to even though you don't know what the
manifold is
in statistics you know very commonly one things of
of kernel
kernel density estimates so you have two classes
p one p not and q one and q not of the corresponding densities of
the underlying variable u
and of course
again this phenomenon is of course the like iterations of the same
basically i mean in way
the phenomenon is really
jacobians council when you're doing prediction
if everything is on the same value in both cases
so suppose we have a kernel density estimate of p one p northern not kernels
in computer science and
which you've heard of this morning
rkhs and these are just kernels in the statistical sense
which is you basically take your density convoluted
with something
and then you estimate
the density of the convolution which can actually do just from the data itself
there's been fancy really let me go on to the next
transparency all you do is you estimate the ratio while by what
you simply count the number of points which are the age of
from one population
and you take the ratio that to the number of points within h x
the population
well if the manifold is
there's more to right not just flat need some some sort of smoothness and so
on but it's intuitively sort of clear
since the metrics
are the same
it is the distortion cancels out of the box
when you're counting the number of observations which are within h acts
you are more or less just counting the number of observations which which are with
an interview
and therefore this ratio
which is the uniform kernel density estimate
you think in
the plus one dimensions
is actually an estimate in
and plus one dimension levels of
even though don't know what the manifold
this again resulted have been obtained by my billion on this
one question which is i think probably not that difficult but is actually quite important
what happens
if you use a fancier methods like things based on wavelet
four fourier series or things like that
i actually believe that in that case
you're in trouble
that is if you don't know what the dimension is
you use the wavelet so the wrong dimension
i think
i think you become west local methods
handing it out here can start right away
and out here
those of you have no seats come forward to get some seats
the call was still friends right away
and why don't you handed down here
you can also get people here
you can start right away
i'm not going to
do something
perhaps even more ambitious
and i'm going to now couple three oscillators not pendulum
but i'm to all
oscillators which are connected with force right
i'm going to work on this
mass is equal masses for strings
spring constant k and the spring constant the same
and i'm going to drive that's it
this is the end
in other words i have he was springs
here's the first class
second class
and here
is fixed and i'm going to try here
with the displacement at
is at the zero
because of course i only get
around the moment in time
this is where my hand will be
so this is at
this is where the first mass will be
remember always called displacement x y from its equilibrium that is it's the line
here is the spring
this one is here
so i all this
x two
the spring
and this one here
this is x three
here is the spring
here is spring
you may have noticed more than once now
i have
so this
and i always
offset them in the same direction do you have to do that you know
if you don't do it
chance of a mistake on the sign is much larger than if you always set
them off in the same using shortly one
but it's certainly something anonymous
but it is more
i find it as my positive direction that causes
three choices
this situation at this moment in time
the larger
that x two
the large
x one
the x three
the larger
the next
this assumption
have no consequences
for what follows
at least not for the differential equation
if x one is larger than ever
that first
the brain
is longer than it wants to be
because i've assumed that x one
and so that means
there will be a force in this election because this thing is longer than one
if x two is larger than x one spring is also lower than the ones
to be
so if want to contract
so force
in this direction
so i can write down a
differential equation for my first of
that's going to be and
x one double dot
that equals
my netscape
time x one minus and because that's the amount by which is is
longer than it wants to be
so times
x one minus at
that is this force
this force
it is now in the past direction
the first k
brain here is longer than the ones to be by an amount x two minus
x one
not only got one
the next one
that's my differential equation
the first of
and this one is always correct even if x one
is not larger than
because if x one is
much larger than than this
force flips over well
this also
that's why it's always culture and advisable
to make that assumption to start with because again it reduces the probability of making
a mistake
nothing else to it just reduce the chance of slipping
but let's not go through this object
if this spring is larger one of them wants to be
want contract
so this object will forced to
but if this spring is longer than it wants to be because x three is
large x two
but experience force
so i can write down now
differential equation object number two
x two
double up
notice that the one that is here to the left is the same one that
is you right
right actually minors reactions this ball is the same as this
so it is going to be that scrutinize minus sign always coupled oscillators
it was as the place here
going to come out he using sign
see that comes out nicely
the brain is long that it wants to be by maximizing
and the forces in the minors direction
and this one
it's not going to be a plus
x three
mines x two
now i go
the next spring
next object
so this object
the experience of force and to the left
this spring is longer than wants to be
once the contract
but this one
therefore the force two to display now also in this
because the end is fixed
so we get for the third object
act three double not
one minus k
five x three
my next which is this term which assigns
and then in addition i get minus
when you reach this point all an example
new pass
you take a deep breath
you go over every
term and every sign
if you put up on one side
o on casual mistake that you
even though you know it you can actually write u for instance of one free
it's all over
then in the waters
the problem will fall apart and may not even oscillate in simple harmonic right
so therefore
let's look at it
and that's one of the
one is larger than n
therefore forces in this election
along this direction
x two minus six
that same force here
it is going to perform the second one so that this is correct this is
this one is driving it
way from equilibrium x reminds x two got to be right
this term shows up here was a minus sign
i can go on there
and since this spring is always shorter here
both the right
i'm happy with my differential equation
so now
going substitute here
i don't need to compute it
you may want to compute even though you know it's one that i was
so what what is left
i mean
basically a quadratic operation because it's linear on next three but you need to compute
for every x
so at the end of the day you have an algorithm which has quadratic complexity
instead of could be compared
and of course
in terms of memory you are better off because here you have to start
or the cube
you have to support triples
here we have to start only
all possible
processing and
the requirements they they have improved
they have improved
again remember
as the result of what is the result of an assumption as the result that
and also
a given conditional independence
so this is just a simple example of how
conditional independence in an extremely simple model
the result
in the efficiency
in terms of
the question here is
i mean
how can we
we size in
in an accurate way the mathematical
what these examples that you just run to the general case the general case where
you have an arbitrary number of virus
if an arbitrary probability distribution
we saw the
the conditional independence
and p of facts
i structure that allows us to exploit the distributive law
to make things more efficient
the basic concept here is that
the structure that is created in the probability space
as a result of the conditional independencies
is such that can be
exploited by this
in order to make computations more fish
the question is
what about the general case
how these things translate
in particular what's the form that the joint probability distribution will take in general
given the set of conditional independence statements
well we saw
no that particular case we have three viable the given
conditional independence day
but have a simple factorizations over subsets of those one
i was going to happen in general case what the general rule
of which that particular example is just an instance of
right that's the general
i mean can use to exploit the distributive law
in the general case
you know
the trick we use it to make things more efficient ways to use the distributive
law can be used to sing tool
in the general case for now
obviously this is the question we should be looking for
that's not what we are going to be
that's going to this example he re writing the joint distribution
that's the this little exercise
here's my drawing history
alright joint distribution
these facts
the fact that
x a human xp
called p of
x a
why would you think
that's the first of the two
rules that they told you in the beginning you should keep in mind all the
that's the condition
this to the question of what to do you think
now we are going to be exactly the same
just defined
x a
has been the entire set
o files from x one to xn
you're going to partition the set in this particular way
the first condition here will be just x and the rest will be
from x one to xn one one
so x
will be called to xn
it will be equal to
x y
should take these definitions for x eight and x being used to control here you
get exactly the
joint is this particular
joint as well
for a small number of trials
and this condition
and there's no assumption that all the positivity
i'm actually very common and probably some overview
i have done in the past are doing the same thing myself was in the while
but let me call it there is
the modeling process
so we facing the big data somewhere in the cluster
what the some modeling on it
with some
two of choice sitting in our laptop
and obviously we not fit the data on the laptop so what do we do well
relegated downsample and somehow
so whatever we get fits in the laptop
well how do we know that you know this is the right something like we
don't know really i mean if it's the laptop right
so next going to build some kind of a model
tested little bit
and there may be pushed back the cluster
so what's wrong with this picture
well maybe the model that should go out now
maybe not
but the biggest problem is that there is no
this thing actually works
and next person which comes around and tries to like work and update model
i mean doesn't really know what happened
you know what to lecture was used build was they
o legal process what really happened and nobody knows
so it's really unmaintainable
and by saying so i'm only shooting down they
experimentation with small data
i think experimentation small data is very valuable it can provide little insight
when you have a lot of people doing this production pipelines
in really because mess
you can really
as like the de-facto standard will agreed that
so for those of you who probably know
about mapreduce framework and maybe machine learning frameworks operate on it
so that's question would be
okay why don't you just take
one of the existing learning frameworks which already operated by producers for day
i also want such an open source framework is called
so it is also party project
anton actually thought hard about it
could we use apache mahout to that for whatever we go
and the answer was not really
primarily for one particular reason
and the reason is the integration
really wanted to make whatever we do really easy for users to
actually interface with the end users and they then office
entation interrogate the
my house in big brother thing flows
it's very hard and not natural
i'm gonna show examples later on how this can be done
but this is something which would probably prevent a lot of people from
getting the maximum
benefit from using in machine learning
having said about what did we actually do
so first of all we build
a library machine learning routines
as i mentioned before r
we focus on fairly simple models such as
but just aggression for example
which are very easy to implement
end by implementing things ourselves were able put extra optimisations
which would otherwise difficult to get from outside
i will also together a bunch of our libraries and the extent we could so
with another thing implemented from scratch
the important thing was to build a bridge between this library
and the high-level processing languages that people use
doing things
jobs so in this case
ant colony five with some people use problem most the people
big male is the primary and the result of this effort
i was going talk about in detail
so this is how it works so there's this library
a low-level code which actually performs the learning and execution in machine learning
there's already
data pipeline which produces the data
there's an integration of
internal and external components
in the form of the library
there's execution love jobs
on hadoop using big
and there's this marriage of
machine learning via big e-mail
abridgement which i'm going to show you in a second
so let's start with just having gave very very brief overview of how mapreduce works
so usually we take data in the form of key-value pairs
produced by some process
we randomly partition this
into a number of mappers
which the some processing of the data so that they can be for example doing some feature extraction nor
transformations of words and maybe some approximate matching so and so forth
this produces another layer of key value
which are
sorted by the value the key
so what we start
and so
g is valid in the class of frames
bold face
founded in every frame
and the formula is valid
it is found in
class of all
so see weekend
later we see that we can restrict to the class of frames see reflected
and we get a certain logic
other properties like reflexive and transitive
this an example of
the team
let's prove
but can
it lies box
the free
sure it's found that means that it is true in all the world
all values
so i'm going to prove this by contradiction
this is not valid
this means that there exists
and said well
such that
four o
this formula falls
in order to make this phone calls
we have to make this falls
make is true
make this small
so we have to prove that
next book speech
and we have to prove that
box p
not true
that for
now because you is unspecified
could be at any point
that's just supposed to you is at this point
so we have to test all the possible points but this is supposed
this is the u
which is the frog
o clock speed for this
to consider all success
this means that this is true of
success as to p
then we have to
show that
this is the case
what about phrases false
again and one
you can see here
the successor
that should not be used here
four and then we see that the successor of this is for which
this is for
peters actually
what piece
box box is also true
but then it contradicts
it is not so
we show that
this is not the case that both
and the
two at the same time means that this formula is
actually says
what you
because you have to test for
OK to you is this
it can be done the same
now that example
so in this case we have
what the world is set of natural numbers
on the relation r is the last station on set
you drive traffic
western nations to its
so it
and we want to show that
china p
going to show this we just have to
i'm not with the world validation which is formed
possible by using the cosine
the world which is the number of p
on the
the numbers you get
this form is for
for example just take
it was zero
o five
now in order to prove this
we need to show that
this is true
want to show that
this is false
to see why this is true from zero
the successor of the series was a number greater than here
for any successor would of
here are the same
for this reason we show that
for any
and next
damon p true
now that means p is true only in the world which is numbers
and this just means that we have to find an even number which is greater
may have tens
so in HMM could be enough if you make a lot of assumptions are it
could not be enough you may want to have this still more complex
models and we are going to go a little bit on other models that could
be used for that are extensions of HMM
so they are all mostly in the family of what we call a graphical model
what is a graphical model
we are still in the generative well so we have we have distributions and we
want to model them and the
the basic idea of the generative model in general is to be able to model
the joint probability of several random variables
similar to HMM we see the same equations you can factor this giant into the
product of the purview of each random variable given all the other ones that now
instead of using all the other ones are going to talk about the parents and
the parents are those that we your prior knowledge you know influence the given environment
so you may know for instance that x one
is only depending on x two and x five it has no no relation with
x two
so if you knew x two and x five you could decide on the distribution
of x one
you could know so that the x two is independent of all the other ones
extreme as well that x four depends on x two x three so these are
prior knowledge that you know
you're going to build that into your mother saying basically that the joint probability
it is now on the product of these terms instead of being the product
of each random variable given to all the other ones
and this
conditional so graphically that's what we call the graphical models because now each arrow
present one of these relations so x one depends on x two and x five
we see here x one depends on x two
the next five
and you can go on and draw your life graph
and what's useful with these graphical models is that there's a lot of literature in
you can handle an arbitrary number of such random variables
and in any case there is negative called the junction tree algorithm that can be
used to estimate the probability of these joint likelihood
in an efficient way
although it depends on the relations you have in your in your graph the more
arrows you have in the graph the more complex it would be to compute this
joint likelihood but you will always use something similar to the junction tree algorithm so
this is kind of generic according to compute any
likelihood of any
a set of random variables
although you have to know that sometimes it's not tractable what i mean by that
is that the you know the computed you need an exponential number of of time
with respect to the random variables and so in practice you will not be able
to compute it unless you make a lot of assumptions and simplifications but
fortunately there are no details are a lot of those algorithm that computes
over tractable graph by making lots of assumptions so you have the junction tree algorithm
to compute the likelihood
and you have again you expected maximisation EMI grid and that can be used to
train again this is only true when you're you have tractable graph but if you
have an intractable graph there exist still lots of approximation algorithms that can be used
now one of the
one of the
possible graphical models that you can find and you may have heard of them is
called dynamic bayes networks which is basically a trained the model have now and temporal
value so it's kind of temporal extensions
you can either see there's an extension are part of graphical models but it is
a subfamily of graphical models
i just want to mention that the in the territory you can find the aliens
of possible graphical models with the associated
i gradients to capitalise you compute the
training etcetera
just to show you
there is plenty of them
that have been used for multimodal processing in the past the literature that's on your
part of the
and of course
i will not explain all of them but i have said that a couple of
of those
they want to to explain in more detail
but it's going to to be quite quick because each of them would be
of interest and take about an hour more
to explain which i don't have time to
so i just want to to have a kind of uniform notation to explain to
express our multimodal task
with respect to these graphical models
let's talk about notation first
so we have
i suppose you only have one
sequence of an observation which i'm going to call one stream
so for one stream we could say that we have a training set of these
of of the strings capital and of strings in sequence and each sequence now
could of observation would be noted all one o two o two o t l
and being index the index of the alpha sequence
will be just the sum over all states of j marginalisation exactly what the
coupling between g and i times the problem of all incoming messages to j
so you want to send a message from j to i take all incoming messages
to j
take the product of that problem
the individual potential
between g
in some order
they have the message from day one
i want to compute all the message
it just
compute the product of all incoming messages
then you have the march
you can actually prove
i mean you can do is an the cosine
from the user will actually give you the that these are will give you the
correct market
i mean prove
correct correctness as of these
there's a whole
o thing that we can
talk about in terms of factor graphs as well
what i will do is the following
i'll just go through
so the junction tree algorithm
and then we cover factor graph if we have some time
at the end of day factor graphs are just the nice way of
doing belief propagation but they don't add
much of
essential called
the junction tree algorithm is more important
why don't we
just go to
the junction tree
that's what the junction tree
then if you have time to to go back
we need to go for the lecture five is likely
i have added a few slides all may not match exactly what you will not
match what have been
we learn that
let's the magic
OK so
let's assume now that we don't have three is anymore i mean these are very
simple graphs
i mean you want to be able to work with that all the countries
let's assume we have well graph like this similar to
the graph have already seen
need to run the elimination i wish to compute marginals OK
so as you see we cannot use belief propagation here
in principle we can use but
don't necessarily produce the right results because it's not the three
but you can use the elimination of one because what the elimination of the elimination
of one is always exact
just sometimes inefficient but is always exact because she just making use of
of the distributive law
let's assume we want to compute
we want to compute p of x one
given x six
let's assume you have observed that sick
whatever may be x sixs
well the fact that
yesterday we had
we don't have training or
and here is the probability of having rain today and kill for example is other
temperature pressure level
and you want to compute
what's the probability that we have range
and i've given that we do have bring yesterday
so how do go on
actually compute these
probability new models
well that's how you do it you know
you need to run
nomination of
you're right at all
the expression for the joint probability distribution using the
factorisation hammersley clifford
delta just indicating that we have observed
the particular value of x six
so we don't have a distribution have collapsed the distribution into single
got single that don't have
we don't have any uncertainty on the variables of the delta function that's basically telling
we know the value of x six is equal to some x six model given
and the work is to i mean you know how to do it we just
learn how to
now they compute
compute my
my p of x one and x six and then just some of
x six here
have the condition
compute these quantities here
your sexy
samuel like one i think is
just divide
these by that
because p of x one given x six is equal to p of
x one x six
divided by p of x six
right from just taking the racial this thing in that
so now we want to compute something else OK let's compute p of extreme given
x let x six let's assume that
this is the probability that whatever it will
rain tomorrow given that yes they brain
now it's the same we just do the same thing
we go on compute things about suddenly we see that
there are some
computations here there are some
we know that
we know them from the previous computation
the same case head for trees
if we have different queries
and that's what always mentioning basically if you have different queries you don't want to
database and extract satisfy conditions
exactly the same thing so we are equating me is about in this case we
are interesting in interested in this going to eventually constrained by particle constraints and the
mining equipment and it can be
i would be willing to to be quite obvious kind of syntax is described the
form of a quite difficult for non-experts to system so we have the important to
the local some guy that can have not expertise then is system in the formulating
the query awareness improved
two things to do microsoft microsoft access system where it is
formulation by means of a query by example that is designed for use that are
not expert of as query languages so you can query the database and we don't
know the knowledge of the
the square and to the monitoring and is not an invention of the last three
years because the onset of the mining according to the first one is quite lot
that was defined in the form of relational database and so it is not about
the design two dealing with the degree of complexity that are in the
a special struck structure of graphical data
the plan was defined by capacity in nineteen ninety nine it is that doc doc
language for special time mining my data design tool to work on the data that
are stored in a single table of a relational database so it does not deal
with exactly all the degree of complexity that we have defined the for this part
of the mining task in both cases
in both cases they are inspired to describe languages so too difficult and as assume
single stable are some some so they are not suitable for dealing with the object
relational information that is the story of engines system
as you know quite language is the language that we defined in this case it
combine them
object the nature of the data with the specific especially mining requirement the language has
been designed and according to a set of data mining of primitives so that no
to facilitate in a feature intended for flutes this quantity of interest in the knowledge
of the primitive that we have used it included the first specification specification of the
parts of the data that i think therefore i want mining ghost the second is
the kind of knowledge engineering sharing to interesting is going to be going to school
where association rules classification training images in the classification rule clustering of clusters if we
expand with
clusters are addition to something that's the kind of knowledge to be extracted the but
no it that should be useful for guiding them
discovery process some some interesting transmission that are important in evolution process and the
and and then we can specify either
so in addition to we have we intend to have before discovered some
these different primitives corresponds are limited marked the missing text from
the language is the top level description of the business in texas so again while
query can be a statement or sequence of different statement issued statements can be a
statement for the mining part also or statement specified background nodes to a statement from
to specify and and this statement to specify ourselves should be displayed in but in
the case of the mining statement we have an objective way to select the portion
of the time we are interested in analyzing mine keyword the mind to introduce the
kind of bot to be discovered analyzer to introduce to the set of descriptors so
that we use in analyzing we into
to analyse these data for example a INEX and shown on the topological relations on
and when this great site to specify the discrete will appear in the past that
since these descriptors can be exactly the same this data that we have defined within
hard to deal with the markov networks
now one thing that is important to realize that if you look at the graphs
bayesian networks and markov networks
if there are some things that you can some independence relations you can represent compactly
in the markov network but not in the business work and vice versa
so neither one dominates in that respect
but the important thing to bear in mind is that the log linear form applies
to both say something is a compact bayes ill how it will be a compact
log linear form and something for markov network so as long as using the slogan
linear form in terms of compactness rho was OK
how do we do inference in markov networks we can use as we shall see
shortly algorithms like markov chain monte carlo belief propagation and so on
in bayesian networks
what we usually do
for inference is first converted them to markov networks and then we did inference in
markov networks so in some sense markov networks are the more fundamental notion
so how do we do inference in markov networks
well typically what we so the markov network is the model of the full joint
distribution of the set of variables and typically the questions that we want to answer
i things like what is the conditional probability of some variable given some others
what is the marginal distribution of some subset of the variables
and here is the expression that we want to do this over
unfortunately doing doing this inference exactly is a very hard problem it struck the complete
which means it's even worse than NP hard
however there's something that's actually very easy
which is the condition notice called the markov blanket
of the variable
the markov blanket of a variable in the markov network is just its neighbors in
the graph
it's easy to see that the distribution of the variable given its neighbors in the
graph is actually can be computed directly it's simple expression of the cliques that don't
involve that variable disappear things cancel out and so this this can be done quite
efficiently and so what we're going to see is is an algorithm for the inference
that exploits the
the algorithm is called gibbs sampling it's probably one of the most widely used algorithms
in the universe
there was a survey like i think by at tripoli computer years ago of what
the most important you know algorithms were this actually came out on top
because it used throughout science and technologies to do inference on complicated probabilistic models and
it's or more generally markov chain monte carlo of which gives sampling is an example
and it's a joyful simple algorithm for its power so it's well worth nine so
there's give sampling work it works like this
i start out by assigning random truth values to all my variables are focusing on
the building case you
and then i i do the following
i repeatedly go to variable
and resample its value
its neighbours
so i have its conditional distribution given state not taking you sample of its value
have new state and i just do this for a long time
so maximum cycles oriental some convergence criterion is met and then i just estimate my
problem is of interest as the fraction of states
in which the event that i'm asking about help
like can know what is the problem that this person has no disease x y
i sample which states and if you if if interstates eighty percent of the person
diseasex then i should probably point
this is really give sampling it's a very small simple that's but it's also very
there are the inference methods that are there are worth knowing about
new sampling in the truth is actually probably over that's use even when it's not
the best thing to the to have so there are many many variations of markov
chain monte carlo
so give sampling is just the best known represent this class but there are many
other there's also a new class of which called belief propagation
that that is becoming quite popular in particular for this
that's the problem we use what's called the sum product version of belief propagation
because what we're actually doing is we're doing sums of products to compute probabilities
there's also variational approximations and there's also a very large literature on exact methods
give sampling and all these other methods are approximate to give an approximate answer with
more time to give you a better answer there's also exact methods
however exact methods do not work on the large problems that were interested in here
so we're not going to focus on the much but there's certainly a lot of
you know there's a big later literature and so the other main type of inference
that we are going to want to do is what's called MEP from maximum security
so again what you see here is the range of possibility
that the
well the symmetric variance gamma process
can achieve so
again you see very much dominance by
by the end of the picture by the
the biggest jumps for small parameters and for bigger parameters you see another convergence this
is the convergence to brownian motion
instead of central limit theorem
within the class of of variance gamma processes
and you might say well what you are looking at here is really we zoom
into a a variance gamma process here
to see such a picture
and we zoom out
this is such a picture so
that's aggregate normality
that's quite useful for financial time series because in the very long term the normal
distribution is not all that bad but when you have a reasonably short horizon it's
just not
very useful for other problems if you if you take two shortened horizon and looking
to intraday behavior then
any of these models is inadequate anyway
but i get to that
if i have time at the end so i was saying really modelling freedom comes
from specifying the characteristics rather than the increment distribution
famous early examples have been stable processes that have been studied for their scaling relation
with the distribution at the time eighty
can be derived from the distribution at time t just by
by multiplying the random variable y y is a constant
so such processes can be obtained by specifying in may be the simplest possible way
the density
of the
measure new
you just take powers of of x
as as entities
so that makes sense for
alpha between zero and two
i've separated out the two cases here
in order to be explicit about what
kind of compensation use here we don't need to compensate any jumps and here we
can compensate all sounds other than that the two
the same is also alpha equals one which looks a little different and alpha equals
which is in is very different it which is brownian motion
there may be more interestingly is a class of processes
which is sort of the next most natural way you've got both a a polynomial
and an exponential time
well of course this polynomial time describes the behavior near zero
and the exponential term describes the behavior near infinity in the one case and you
minus infinity in the other case
so you've
you've then got a certain number of parameters this five parameters in this
this density
of our measure new
and that gives us
quite a bit of of modelling freedom
to start off with such simple definitions here you could go on and take linear
combinations of these are taken in take your favourite function
on the real line
as soon as it satisfies this is integrability condition of one minimum x squared and
you can take it as the
well if nonnegative as well you can take it as the density of
the nation news so that's a lot of freedom
and disadvantage then of course is that if you then asked to to fit
your model to data then while the probability density function is not available in closed
form you can have some integral representations or some
you can invert some characteristic functions are moment generating functions and and you've got a
way of of of doing the
in the model fitting
but it's sort of
a little less elementary then and by modeling the income distribution
i've got some
simulations of stable processes so you see
again very similar
behaviour in the symmetric case for small value of alpha
we get
very much much pictures dominated by small times for large values of of about five
one point eight is this one here
you get something that is moving closer together and if you let alpha tend to
it is actually some sort of continuity that makes this
converge to true brownian motion again
so in the
there is another interesting class of of stable processes where you've only got
positive chance or only got negative jumps as the case may be is positive jumps
we've got
due to our compensation
rule for for between zero and one we were not compensating any so we are
really just adding jumps in this process and it dominated by
my big jumps as alpha moves across one
we can compensate and to compensate all jumps
and then we get to behavior that
but has
drifts downwards but in that infinite sense that have been been looking at an example
and upward jumps
again big jumps being being quite dominant here
and while this is this is what the stable processes that look like
OK so
modeling processes themselves
we can go further once you've got live processes
because they are semimartingales essentially we've got stochastic integration at our disposal we can look
at stochastic
integrals either of deterministic functions which means that we take these increments of the jump
sizes and according to when it happens it scaled
by that function f
all we have is stochastic process that sort of interacts with the randomness of of
our lady processes or has some additional randomness in it
what about skill and the string kernels in contrast to
talks to conclude this talk about class consisting comments we consider string kernels which are
linear in time
and we trying to look like linear in the length of the string not could
this as it was in that case are trying to speed up such kind
OK maybe have seen large scale text classification problems string
problems that appear like normal text classification spam spam categorisation and basically said is given
documents the classes plus minus one predict linked to
next time and
we have
then for security could be like like given connects executable predict whether executable is a
virus or not biology has the same thing actually i'm working on also of times
of splice sites or the start of the gene and you want to predict whether
in the centre of the sequence this is this splice site or not
OK so one possible approach is to use to to encourage and support vector machines
and it's
actually at least and pilot for example in this case the diffuser large number of
examples and you can really get like high accuracy
OK so from the giving
given his entry examples here string kernels
like like vote and the kernel k may be scholars like spectrum or to become
and you want to train a comin machine on on say ten million examples and
it was created being examples also being example
so all these incomes look like spectrum can be a computes columns of
strings of length k
and to use these consonants summed up for each sequence multiplied and
and ended up in the system design in cancer spectrum kernel you becomes quite some
simple then identifies matching blocks and between two sequences and the longer the match
the high school
the higher this weighted and this summed up and all good
the thing that three hundred seven comments the data there's usually a large discrete feature
space behind it
full stop
so in
and you can machine in situ
john all sorts of beta which
these are valid kernels
you're quite often have to compute outputs for all
four test examples so for example have to compute this linear combination of of kernels
therefore the effort is
the first thing to compute singer
the computer system of courts for is like and then this is the to the
number of states constitute
after coming in a linear combination and is the time to compute computer to current
so if you have to do it for all the examples it's an
twenty two
and that's all for training training is forbidden and t so it's quite quite closely
the problem is that this is used in training and testing
so it is actually worth tuning
just OK so what can we do it for computing the kernel is already because
i mean the first approach will be just to get the current tools don't in
any time and
and this
i mean it must psychology is actually
quite simple idea if you are combinations of components you rewrite
the lexicon is not productive the feature space and you basically just computers w explicitly
in computer product
this not it's not at all clear that this
should be faster than using the original
general approach
it can be in some cases so when is it possible it's possible that you
w has allowed mention entity like the and the string length which
they spend you know if you see god
four questions you get fifteen minutes take o five minutes to read the papers forty
five minutes has roughly ten eleven minutes for questions on the same question might be
so i spent ten minutes number one and sold against five minutes
five minutes fifteen minutes elegant steam
twenty minutes twenty minutes in exams to work on number one
and it really is to solve this was the last thing i do
fifty five comes this last thing to do
now think about the math let's do the math suppose suppose there's an epiphany
eleven fifty four
you get a perfect score in question
it's worth twenty five percent of the paper you get twenty five o twenty five
gets zero and rescue write anything
you see what i'm saying
trial the questions
and good luck
i mean it there's no
there's no attempt to deceive come prepared
well defined and our goal is to bring those things get back to you
the following day repertory
i will post model solutions
and will be different exam in the afternoon
but i think it only makes sense for you not to discuss the paper with
people that are taking the afternoon
trying to run
school here that has some standards if
professional standards
and there will be plenty of information the website
alright let's get out the lesson today
so just to refresh their memories last day we look at the average valence electron
energy is a measure of reactivity and en route we discovered that
we can divide the periodic table into metals and which is about seventy five percent
of the periodic table these have low average valence electron energies which means that
they're very good these elements are very good electron donors
and up on the other extreme
or elements with very high average valence electron energy these are electron acceptors they they
they cling to their life electrons quite
and subsequently look the photoelectron spectroscopy which is a technique that allows us to determine
binding energies ionisation energies being just one
example but we'll see later on the PS can give us other
important information can calculate and then towards the end of the lecture we started looking
at reactivity and we put up this hypothesis that our observation is that
octet stability
seems to be an attractive electron configurations so we saw the
noble gases and then we said you know you can you can also achieve octet
and electron transfer if you look at elements that are just a little bit
the of electrons verses octet stability or a little bit ly
of electrons
so we got to ionic bonding and i think we just got to the point
where able start looking at the energetic so that we are at the time so
i want to resume that i think i managed to get to this point here
i show what happens when
the cat here sodium is
in contact with the and here chlorine and we reason that these two eventually reach
some kind of an equilibrium separation which were using lower case are
to represent this is the separation measured from the centre of the
sodium nucleus and there's this separation which is the balance of attractive forces because the
chloride is net negative and the sodium is not positive but both of them
regardless of net charge have
and so
when they become very very close
we spaced
there's mutual repulsion of those electrons
and so there's the repulsive term here
and so the balance of the attractive term and the repulsive term eventually
leads to to the situation where
we have the the equilibrium spacing this equilibrium spacing is denoted are sub-zero or are
and are not really is nothing more than the sum of
the radius the ionic radius of sodium and the ionic radius of chloride so that
we can just say are plus
plus or minus gives you are not
and writer right off the bat you notice that i'm making a huge assumption here
i'm modeling the ions as hard spheres
modeling was billiard balls
finite dimension
and so they
reached this equilibrium position
and we saw last thing we have the coulomb force of attraction which we've seen
carolinas plus one airliners minus one but it doesn't have to be this could be
magnesium would be two plus so here you put to
or i could have an oxide here so i would put minus two e in
this case we just have one one
and the repulsive term some positive coefficient and are two very high number and lies
between six and twelve and this is known as the born
help at all
if it's one one zero
then we can complement that said think get zero zero one
so it says that
everybody problem
on three labels
every code on three labels
these are being
should a weighted sum
choices you
OK so this is a weighted sum of the three choices
and then
if it's the case that
the probability of two
given x
it is
o point four five
the probability of three different x is
o point two five
and the probability of four given x is point three
and the correct binding prediction
each of these
classifiers is zero
the probability that
the labels in the set is zero
to get zeros everywhere you get this
and then
you just random
or maybe the the weighted sum
i mean you have to pick out
you pick out one of these
but but the point is that
this snake is arbitrary
because the choice because arbitrary you can have this distribution
concept between different possibilities
in such a way that the classifiers can take it out
OK so if see there are very motivational
but they have a small problem
and now i'll tell you
how to fix the problem
there is a way to fix the problem
the fix is to use
or just talked about this this probing technique
so in particular
make probabilistic predictions
rather than making money predictions
and then instead of decoding with
hamming distance
just trying to get the right numbers of ones and zeros
and the because l one distance
and if you don't know what i want is insistent to another idea
so if we get these predictions
these these probabilistic predictions for these binary problems here
there in
the distance
i guess on which would imply that you know people will always point nine one
zero nine away from that
o point four five way from
o point five four way
you sum it up
one point zero it
you this region
in arms
and you get different numbers
and you take the minimum
the claim is
this fixes the problem
the small we can you see
that's the problem theoretically
does it turns out to work
so once again we have the most datasets
in the
and we use a hadamard
matrix recurred of see with that is later
and you can compare
ECOC test aerated
creating output code test error rate
and cesarean accuracy which means small is good which means that
things will line implies that this is winning
and you see that for a support vector machine and decision tree
in logistic regression
to problems getting up because winning
on whole dataset
OK so let's go back here for a minute
some of them is clear clearing we're it's just like you see
we have a bunch of binary problems except now make probabilistic predictions
and we decode with
l one loss
with the code to define the smallest l one distance label
kind of works
and now we want to analyse it
so we're going use this one classifier trick again
we're going to embed
the choice of the subsets and the probability
into the name of classifier
so it's
so what i have what i said
well defined
the different probabilistic predictions for different subsets
just like that for that
and that this
peacock peacock peacock
these are men
b the distribution induced
on the binary classifier
and then we have this peacock transformed
it says that
for every number multi class labels
it the kernel that
for every classifier
for every multicast distribution for everybody has every multiclass distribution
the multiclass
minus the minimum multiclass rate
o is bounded by
four times
the square root of
the binary error rate minus the minimum
plain binary here it
discouraged by the way is not that great
score makes it worse
from the gaussians distribution minus one half log of the determinant of this negative hessian
this term in blue is called the lab class approximation for this
and it involves finding the MAP estimates of the parameters computing these quantities
from those MAP estimates than trying to compute the
second derivative of the log marginal likelihood
this article log
posterior with respect to the parameters
in computing the determinant of the matrix here
OK that's an equation
so we can use to evaluate this very complicated high dimensional integrals in general
and this can be used for model comparison selection is a very classical method
the people use
the problem with that method is that if you have a very big parameter space
of these very large computing the hessian and computing the determinant of the hessian can
be quite costly so much cheaper approximation is called the bayes information or BIC criterion
and we start from the class approximation
and we
the large sample limit as n goes to infinity
we draw any term that does not grow
with and
and what we get is that this term drops and this term drop because they
don't grow with and and this term here
the longer the term and this matrix
it grows with n
the over two log n
OK i want to show you how that happens but this is pretty easy to
to show that
so essentially the BIC
criterion is simply the log likelihood
number of parameters divided by two
log of the number of data points so it's incredibly cheap to compute and this
is the easiest way to penalize a model for the number of parameters that has
an we've shown that it can be derived by these two steps from the marginal
nice way to
lower bound the marginal likelihood is given by
these variational bayesian methods which we work on lot
imagine we now have the model with some latent or hidden variables x some observed
variables y
and some parameters theta
we can lower bound the marginal likelihood in the same way as i showed you
before you and using jensen's inequality so the log of the marginal likelihood
is the log of the integral
of this joint probability here
we take each term in that integral we multiply and divide it by
some arbitrary distribution over the hidden variables and parameters
and then we say
we we notice that the log of the average
this ratio is greater lies that lower bound with respect to that family of distributions
so even though we cannot compute this guy
tractably are analytically
we can often compute this lower bound tractably analytically
and in particular kind of approximation we can use is too
that the distribution over the hidden variables and parameters
assume that the factors
as a distribution over hidden variables times the distribution over parameters
so then we have a lower bound on the log marginal likelihood which is the
functional of this distribution over the hidden variables the distribution of the parameters and the
so we can maximize this lower bound
in in in like manner
optimizing the distribution over the hidden variables
holding the distribution of the parameters fixed
and that generally is this is given by this equation
that kind of like the e step of the EM here in the m step
we optimize with respect to the distribution over the parameters holding the distribution over the
hidden variables fixed
maximizing this lower bound is equivalent to
minimizing the kullback leibler divergence
which measures
in a sense the distance between the approximate posterior
given here and the true posterior which we can compute tractably
and this is the expression for that KL divergence
which is the difference between the
log marginal likelihood and this lower bound on the log marginal likelihood
and here is simply a comparison
of the classical algorithms
for parameter estimation
and this variational bayesian in algorithm
it it looks
very similar
so in the e step we compute the distribution over the hidden variables
that's the inference that
for graphical model this would involve some sort of
belief propagation or
junction tree
called in here
in the variational bayesian e step
we also compute distribution over the hidden variables except we use the different setting of
the parameters these are parameters average with respect to the distribution of the parameters the
main difference between the two methods is that whereas the classical is simply trying to
find a point estimate a single value of the parameters of the model
this variational bayesian the is trying to find the whole
distribution over the parameters of the model because it's trying to
that distribution