doesn't work
repels water
suppose now
take a piece of plastic which i can do
and i put
the negative charge on the plastic on one side and i put the positive charge
on the plastic on the other side
i can do that
i can have another piece of plastic
the positive charges also here and negative
what i think will attract negative
but clearly if i rotate them around negative will repel negative positive really help us
so now you think there is an enormous parallel
between magnetism and electric charge and that
it is a misconception
this i take the soul
and i cut this in the middle
the left side
of that piece of plastic
is only positively charged
so here it is
and the right side is only negative charge
now i take an axe
and i cut the
magnets in the middle and what we have now
i think i have the south pole on the left side
and the north part on the right side the answer is no you end up
magnets which did
i have a
north pole and south pole and this part also
as the north pole and the south
so there is no such thing
it's coming in magnets and then having one piece which is only the south pole
and one piece which is only the north pole
so you always have was a magnet know whether how often you break it
you always have
two polls
we call those dipoles in physics
died stands for two
the dialogue is the discussion between two people
you could make
one piece of magnetic material only the south pole we would call that a monopole
modo stands for one
monologue monologue is one person talking like now
so less electric monopoles exist
the positive charges monopole electric positive charges are more of a negative electric charges
but then the magnetic monopole
do not exist
someone in my audience
may find a magnetic monopole in the future and if you do
you will definitely get
the nobel prize
four physics
physicists have tried for decades
and still trying to
because from a theoretical point of view
there's no reason why they shouldn't exist except we've never seen one
so here is the task
for you
the electric charges are exceedingly small
they can move
you see it i could move them from the positively charged rule i could bring
them onto the
due to bloom
now the negative charges which have the name we call those electrons
a much smaller and they are much lighter than the positive charges
and so the negative charges can therefore move much easier than the positive charge
and when electric charges move it's almost always
the electrons that move
and when that happens
when electric charges move recall that we give the name we call that an electric
electrons can very easily move in metals
copper ore buyer and
on one
silver gold
metals conduct electricity
very well
take porcelain
the glass
plastic rubber
OK so this tutorial will be on
something which we can say introduction to network analysis will cover a couple of topics
and it will remain about network analysis of social network analysis of
i will try to show
things from the basics
still about some some applications which
we did in the recent times so
joint work with doing i and parts of the presentation were taken from the
tutorial on
networks from new telescopes
our guy
i think it's
at the moment
let's see physically first
introduction what networks are
very basic and the go briefly through the network properties
what relevant information what are what's
interesting information about the networks which we need to do it
if you want to do network analysis and two applications the and so on is
mining of email server logs some some sick people would know about this already and
mining MSN messenger graphs so some recent work from you would have actually
so first
how to locate network
analysis are complex networks
so let's see if if the context is computer science then we would
put complex network somewhere between machine learning data mining
theory for sure so lot of theoretical computer scientists would work with network statistics
the stations are involved in this as well
and general computer systems but well
it's a our position are
among our work with with approach mainly from this
from this side and maybe a little bit from
theory now if we put this context of computer science into the context of science
then of course dealing with networks is our the network analysis would appear in several
other areas especially social sciences social sciences will be the social network analysis biology physics
and industrial applications so this is some of their social network analysis would be placed
OK now what is the net
network first type of objects in the network or graph will be just nodes or
the next stage we add links
so which just connect this
not something else
and so the next feature which we might be interested in is
the direction of the notes
so each node of the links for each link have
so let's see if this would be
sending email is so
these nodes and numerical this guy
if introduced led probabilities
so that information would be
distributed over the neighbours and then this could be kind of probabilistic methods and one
more level
would be dynamic networks so now we are coming to this
notorious thermal properties
buzzwords using eq two so dynamic network so this would be
dynamic never would be something that all the elements in the network changing through time
so this means that we would introduce either
her new nodes are some of the existing nodes would disappear that edges are appearing
and disappearing through time would see an example in in the second and maybe these
probabilities of transitions what would change through time
and this dealing with dynamic
networks is really an active research topic so this is not something where it was
possible to say well that's what these are set of methods and is problems and
that's it so this is still a very active active research topic in
some of these areas which are made for
let's see now an example of dynamic network so dynamic that is really hard to
visualize because because it has this dynamic
dynamic dimension
so basically the demo
we already
here there
you know
where you
you get
i said
all of these
a very
there are
this is a not very
and i don't see
it well
people are
of the angular momentum
i calculated about c
which is the centre of mass
is simply equation number six
it is the moment of inertia
about that point c which is the centre of mass
times omega
about the centre of mass
so c
centre of mass and c are
the same point
what is the moment of inertia of rotation about the centre of mass that is
my one twelve ML squared
so now i have one class
else create
the kind domain that is not intrinsic
spin angular momentum
and it is the same for any point
that you choose even if i chose to point here in space
we can prove that is still the same
and the moment
now we're going to look at our application very huge number of applications and the
next four five lectures we'll go through many of them
in some cases you will see you
yeah that's intuitive that's obvious
in some cases you will say
not so intuitive and in some cases you will fall off your chair
it's completely bizarre it is so nonintuitive that you don't even believe it you won't
believe it until actually show you
with the demonstration but that's the way nature works
that comes later not today
on assignment number seven
i give you a problem
problem seven nine
in which i have a rule or rods
on the frictionless horizontal tables
the ruler has amassed l
mass and has a length l
and here is the centre of mass c
and i hit that
ruler i give impulse
two the direction
of the rule i give in input force acts upon it for a certain amount
of time
and that this distance
i think i call it deep in your problem
that's friction as they
i do this
very short hit
and now the question is what will these objects do
one issue instinct tell you
you will say well
sure it will move in this direction parameters frictionless so whatever happens after the it
happens forever never never never stops
so you'll say well is going to move in this direction that's very vague but
that's true
how about rotation
well it rotates
and if it rotates about which points
so you might say well maybe where the point of rotation may depend on where
i hated
it would be reasonable intuition that is not true
it must rotate about the centre of mass cannot rotate about any of the point
i suppose is rotated about this point just for sake of argument so after the
hit it rotated about this point
that would mean that the centre of mass
we then do this
and that's not allowed because the centre of mass behaved
like the point
in which all the mass is concentrated
f equals a hold for the centre of mass
and so as the
a single point because them at the centre of mass can always be considered to
be a single point was aldermaston at that point can never do this it would
be absurd
so from that reasoning alone
you must conclude
that's the only way
that nature
digest that impulse
by giving
the centre of mass
a certain velocity
in this direction
which will never change
in addition
it will give it
and angular velocity about the centre of mass and if there is no friction that
will never change
so a little later in time
the centre of mass will still be on this line
and it may have rotated one or two or three rotations that depends that depends
on a large eyes
and that depends on the distance d
let's assume
it is now like so
and then is happily rotating with angular velocity
and continues all the time
with that velocity the centre of mass
in their problem i'm asking you to calculate the velocity of the centre of mass
and to calculate
the angular velocity about the centre of mass
i'll help you a little bit
and i hope that it will help you a little more
for the centre of mass
what must always holds the centre of mass acts like a point source
so it was always hold that have equal and
eighty of the centre of mass
that is really one of the major characteristics of the centre of mass
if we look at magnitude if delta t equals
and a centre of mass delta t
the force acts for a certain amount of time and that's the impulse
but if you before i hit
if this velocity is zero
then a thirty
is obviously the velocity of the centre of mass afterwards
he calls eighty right
he was zero to start with
so you see now immediately
i that is the
in polls
he calls
and the velocity of the centre of mass
so the velocity of the centre of mass
because i divided by
and so i have sold for you
the first part
one of the problems
what is remarkable
that's independent of the the story we call the the it's completely independent of the
when you hit here
with the very same impulse or hit there makes no difference the centre of mass
behaves like a point source vehicles i may
the velocity of the centre of mass
only depends on i
and on the mass of the larger i the larger the velocity that's of course
quite intuitive
and the larger the mass the lower the velocity
but now comes the hardest part and i will leave you largely was the hardest
part but give you a few clothes
because they i want you to calculate
omega about the centre of mass
and now you have to choose an origin because you're dealing with sports
you're dealing with
changing angular momentum
and so you would probably choose CHU origin
and you will say OK
let's think about what the
angular momentum is relative to point c
before the collision after the collision if you call the the collision
what is the story
a relative to point c
well the talk relative to point c
there is here the position vector
of c
and the toilet is are cross have
OK of prime one point is the problem is exactly the in case in case
prime so this is what was in right because he finally signed five weeks prior
to this is value for money for
the convergence of the and how you approach
formerly that
and the kernel can be written as an inner product and you see that in
this case
the he especially chickens it's not really is based on victor is a finite dimensional
of functions that you can do that this is this is one of the basic
that human space no
it case i just like generalisation of euclidean space but actually to infinite dimensions so
here is the infinite dimensional
but for many problems that the converse
now it turns out that the human properties that i want to mention about RKHS
there is an interesting thing that we use the term
four kinds and grass which is that RKHS can be characterized
almost independently from but what is already so if you give me
so there are facilities around gives you a way to change even given hilbert space
of functions and these are just some not
well i can also remember that each of the rest unique RKHS
now suppose me
a function is a function sorry is a space of functions as basis of functions
how can i tell you whether it is the edges of the number of the
camels where there is a simple decision given by the rain
we say that
OK changes
capitalisation can OK
it is in fact the unique about space which satisfies the properties of the first
one is that your page must contain all
functions of the four on the from case
OK so you have to change that as fixed point east was the
which is the fraction of all of this has to be in your space of
functions otherwise it can be the RKHS
and the properties is that you can show that
as the features and function and any point east of the
the property that the sequel
if that's the case
you can change conditions you also turned on your space inside rkhss is associated to
the gap
so this is something we will use later to to deal with is typically in
the space of functions in which show that it is RKHS things to these this
and therefore we have accounts because you can rather than that
we can have important properties and and this is a
i think what you quite easy to to to derive quite important that you might
want to give some intuition of what he how can interpret the number of edges
incident because the number of patients the central and
so what is the number of edges how can you
what can you say about functions with a small number of big now
well there something simple that can support you have an account on the space so
you have space you can OK and together with this kind of RKHS page
now suppose you take any function f in RKHS in any two points
in your space of points
now if you could simply the different
between the values of f on the two point so you have it's in his
prime you compute everything to be prime
the get that you want to estimate how big or small this can be
here you can use a few properties of the occasions to have simple on the
so that by because this RKHS you know that have all these
is equal to the cakes
this was
back to the first one of the properties of each other with equal to the
inner product between cakes
so here you've ever piece
you have been trying to each other the case and the case prime and because
the other is is linear in each argument this is equal to
that's case and the case right
OK i didn't do anything here this is history to what you just said that
function can see in the dark ages
now the location these spaces the product
and like all species within the data usually quite which is called cases filed which
you probably know four
euclidean space is it turns that when you take the inner product between two vectors
the inner product is always smaller than the product of the norms of the victims
OK think of off to the initial victories you know that AWB is one of
the number of times the normal so in fact it is only also also RKHS
just a small businesses
space was enough for that so this is enough for the smaller than the number
of seen as pointed out chess
times the normal k expand case primarily RKHS
so now we because this is something want to be and try understand what is
not RKHS of k explain case prime
one member that's one way to justify their actions say we used are just the
right to say that
in fact this is one of the space
that correspond to matching being twenty two twenty perspectives where the initial space is embedded
i said that when you start from your space itself point
then you can embed each point
east to the function case
and then
the inner product between
o point into the space between functions case in case trying to get people to
the camel so you know when i was thinking about it i think about design
in that
this means that in this picture here are i said that you can imagine space
in the space on the right thing
OK and the point these here is not the case
and now we we what we have now is the norm between the differences so
the knowledge of the difference in case in case prior
so this seems like is exactly the distance
induced the euclidean distance induced by the kernel
OK well mean that
well the
the way to that is to say that can all induces a structure in your
so that's what i think this is all you can you can can not between
two points between two sequences
and this is exactly what you are
the the
this thing which is the norm in the space of the between phi of minus
five is prime so i think the distance between two points
induced by the camera
so if i give you can also use everything gives you directly not between your
initial between points you should focus on sequences and you can sequences anyone non between
sequences which i call the k of prime
it also gives you know weather i conditions not
so now we have which to that
whenever you give me to point six n is prime
well very
it is
right well
right well took a short break against really racial one and then we'll go through
a got the point i want to reach hunting at about five
OK so thanks well that's my internal there's still air version three still so
we had
some fun getting up the slides i don't get the opportunity to schools every year
i don't work in universities at the moment you may have noticed you
two various presenters profiles and things like that
no unless i'm extremely pleased to be here
i hope you'll forgive the occasional rustiness on the slides which i
have presented before that these things always changed little bit
and i might just
just catch on a couple of things i hope not too many things and gets
so anyway this is kind of part two of course the johns already started this
and therefore it's the kind of you once we know what logic is and what
you could do it
here's some stuff that was done with it
actually in the mid nineteen
around the nineteen thirties
which is very strong negative results actually around the usefulness of logic in
carrying forward big program
arithmetic and mathematics generally inside logic that that would be
because process of the program called always program makes that a couple of minutes
that program is still on the way the because of these results everyone has to
train extremely carefully around what happens you died assume originally
it was sort of a piece of hard work and know some of these work
so i called the computability logic and girls remarkable theorem we want be
we'll be heading to that girl theorem things tomorrow i will say what it is
and the course
this is the sort of course instructions
is based on a book by boolos and jeffrey and that's what i've sort of
i mean if i that stuff and to and said things around book
that's just me
but i'm intending to follow the general process of this
quite find text
this is the third edition which was nineteen eighty nine
but in honor of doing this course i went off to amazon
and found the fifth edition
now the new author john burgess as well because sadly
lost jeffrey
passed on so
and when i looked into it i thought oh my god they change the chapters
is moved around the cabinet secretary sir i haven't actually crime taken stuff from this
book exactly if you're looking at after this is not something it's going to
make any difference whatsoever to the course the talking we doing today
but it's
it would make a difference after that if you trying possibly i don't really refer
to page numbers or chapters or anything like that
i've got another book you just show you admin
OK so let's kind of get started and all distract yourself with the slides and
see what they say and
so the right thing
the first part of learning about logic
can be dealing with these sorts of topics i'm not sure john's chosen this particular
selection this year or not because it is
the vast range of topics in
first order logic and predicate logic
and the various metatheorems around those systems
what we're doing is following on from that
being up and this idea of could we reference in some wire embedded in some
ideas of computability
all finite computability
and there was a historical reason for this the people worrying about
so i will be talking about for quite a long time to die
the concept of
expressing in first order logic may be actually a few different ways
the concept of expressing in first order logic
the idea of computing function
or having some sort of definite procedure for evaluating the result of function
there could be a things you want to do pretty similar
it was to speak on that one
then we're hoping to get to today
the first kind of result from our perspective is that this approach may two
a sort of unfair result that first order logic which all set out on
actually there is in the end effective procedure which completely
categorizers every formula is either true
valid or not valid
OK so it's undecidable
semi decidable techniques are things we can do to turn things that our theory is
but we can't apply this tree techniques or variations of
truth tables and things like that
and always hard to get an answer that's really bad so it's pretty interesting that
that's the case and look how that works
we're looking at
particular sort of computing notion partial recursive functions
and we'll see by sort of amount kind of computer
and then we'll jump school here
OK so
sort of saying this stuff again one
give this a go through this page in detail
so here's the a whole of topics which
well skip through
and some of them and go into a bit more detail than others
usually my choice and going into a little bit more detail
it is not necessary that it's actually key because i think it might just
show you the idea of the style of reasoning people use in this particular disc
in this field
OK so it certainly simple enough to present in a few short hours
but it's sort of follows the style i think which is then used to make
so no way how do i set myself the goal of trying to
come up with any halfway decent proof of
the theorem is the main theorems in this in this area
but i will point to them and will say these techniques these strategies
this is the body of knowledge which have to build up
and so on
i put in the page just showing you some books that
so that we would use so there is that
book by boolos and jeffrey
at the bottom there outside the top there
and if you that that i thought that there are lots and lots and lots
and lots of books OK
a book that sort of just kind of came to my attention again
in the last few months because i was
preparing for this course
like last year
thing about it and found sky in cambridge
and these are not semester course
on girls there and he's got his book an introduction to girls their
absolutely underlines inputs involved in emphasizes
so we could hope to get through always results in a few hours
but certainly i would recommend this kind
what i would do is leave these books here in the right if you just
want to house and someone else have a look at them
of the counting in checking bags they can that place
feel free to have a look at them now flick through the
later on you know then you know what to look for in the library or
something like that as a few other books there some of these are pretty all
this lot anyway you guys in this anymore right you go to wikipedia
the samples here in training get point two three going to a small
well i tested
these new samples i get point three eight hundred rather worse so i thought i
was doing so it's illustrative there
this this fact that
it's not unsurprising that you get very small
the training set errors because
what you're trying to do is minimized the the training set error
self-fulfilling prophecy really so the only thing you're interested in is the what we call
the out of sample error
OK that is the
these these new points these on previously unseen point
and doing rather poorly
however what we've got is a scheme which allows allows us to work blind
OK because whilst we can still see things i do that for
obvious reasons given presentation
you can still do that now without
to c
the pictures
OK just purely
computational things that you can compute
so that's one way of going forward it's still widely used by lots of people
in applications
OK so we hold out a small part of a percentage p percent
we have to make those choices
it's very wasteful because you only get
one minus paper so hundred minus p percent
for training
your sample
using all of the data you possibly can
so that might
finally the quality of the final estimate
it's sample dependent if i were to choose a different five to train
the different five to test i get
a different answer
five ten million data points
and i chose half-and-half differently it would make much difference
we have to think
it in
the kinds of problems will likely to be looking at we will not have
a lot of data
have a little data
in some sense
a better way forward
in terms of using making use of your data
comes through
cross validation
and the most
discussed version of this is called the leave one out cross validation strategy
which says you train
estimator on every
sample except for one
you leave out
as in the hold out case
and then you put it back in taking another one
and you train all again
eight stage you test
trained estimator
gather up all that information
OK by doing it
n times
you compute your a performance measure
it's a very simple idea
course you've got to train n estimators which might
in carolina work
in the specific case of sum of squares
with linear in the parameter models you can actually do the whole thing
i matrix manipulation which is no worse
then the
conventional pseudoinverse
OK but there's a very special situation
so for instance you can do this
many times with different values of the regularisation parameter rho
and choose
rho which corresponds to the best
the value of your
performance measure
but you've done over your cross validation
something that is
more frequently use now
is m fold many fold cross validation
where you do the same sort of thing except you divide your sample up into
m is an integer obviously non overlapping sets
OK you proceed as above so you take out one of these sets
we train
estimator you test it using the set that you've removed
when you put that setback in
take another set and do this
the advantage of these techniques is that all of the data gets used for training
and testing
it's obviously a lot more work
ten fold cross validation strategy you have to do m
lots of training
in the one you do and lots of training
but what you get is much closer estimate of the the so-called generalization error
more loosely just
performance has going to perform in the real world as opposed to how it performs
the data used to train
and we use it very often to to choose these hyperparameters here my hyperparameter itself
is rho but you could use it for tuning the width of your radial basis
functions off for finding the
degree of your polynomial
or some other
parameter that exists within approach
the number of
basis functions etcetera
so that's what
his another
the powerpoint wizardry case just to put that into pictures
cuisine we've got all the training data the x's and the z
and there's ads can be multidimensional
we typically talk about
target but we could have multidimensional target
we break them up in this case the five fold cross validation strategy so we
break them up into five non overlapping
labelled an obvious way
OK so i'm going to look at the fourth stage of this process so we've
already been through we've taken
x y and z one
our estimator produced the outputs from the estimator that's why one
we've done that all the way up to the
so in that situation
it just means that will even if you use the really fancy model
you wouldn't be able to separate things
but since you only have a finite amount of data
it's very hard to tell whether you here of there
in some ways how when you plot the learning curve since on at least for
a given model class tell which is you are
but overall it's really hard
here's an example well
well clear nice several align will not be able to separate right from green
the so called because of problem
if you ever hear of that
this is what it is
if an algorithm argues it's good because it can solve the exact problem
don't read that paper
is a really simple implementation of this
not saying this is efficient anything
all this does is it just computes the product
if the sign is wrong
update things otherwise did nothing
perceptron if offline suffices
with any questions here
if you keep on living through about
it'll just average
so there is actually a wonderful example of where this happened in reality
has anybody of you played the game black-and-white at some point
so you've probably noticed that at some point it gets really hard to
deal with the avatar
and the avatar just starts doing weird things and you cannot be controlled it anymore
is exactly what happened
OK i need to explain people black and white this so is a game where
you play called and you need to get the adoration of people
and amongst other things you have some avatar which happens to be among european or
line or some other piece which will do things trying to mimic you can rewarded
can punish it and so on
and overall the idea is you
train this avatar to do things on your behalf
the people who
built this data set up a machine learning is really cool
so let us use a really kick-ass machine learning algorithm namely the perceptron
and so i thought you know
given all the environmental conditions if the creator does something that is not supposed to
the new planetary reward it you would just to an update like these life
and trouble is that maybe during different stages in the game player may because they
are not terribly consistent you actually might end up
not closing a fully separable problems maybe because the parameterisation is insufficient
so what happened is that the way to make just keeps on increasing
so always keep on updating
so things just average in the end which means that at that point three much
no matter what you do
the beast is not going to change is be a very much anymore
essentially what they did not include is the learning rate
and what they did not include the is anyway decaying regularisation
so to ensure that the parameter range doesn't really completely go a bar
they had included is the fact that would have been a lot more playable
is simple example where about machine learning algorithm can actually win the game
so how do we make things separately even if they shouldn't be
the problem is linear functions often really boring so
well how can we get non linear
i could for instance go and map x into for fixed in some feature maps
i solve the problem
so this will be actually very easy all have to do is just the query
of in it for the next next framework of the project
this works really well the principal documents
quite often it doesn't make much sense to go beyond bi grandson tri grams
so you might actually be able to
code but that out explicitly
now what have we gained well all the sun now we have non linear classifiers
the solution just
depends on what type of exam picking
here's a simple example
four that have had forced to close of the rest of this is that we
one us to die in the US
well as that i have got to come up with this for the particular case
so i
and very strong position
stop this information to
and this is where
it is typical for this kind of innovation that's what i like because i know
so first
he is
there seems to be you know the of business and does not hold is about
the station to this stored that causes should be
what we might
distribution over the last
of course of
she would
the above all
well i think about what i was told us not to do
but contrary to what is now
the part the
church and all could come into nothing more
the one concept because process from scope in some way
put within by
cooperation against according to which what i want understand how
but is it the
and i just want to come what is the what
what will show
vision simulcast below
thank you for listening to belonging to
traditional what has to be critical soccer would get with the kind of media attention
forces from the republic in one of the two of them
second without cash from
the introduction
a book in which a somewhat remarkable common characters
could it could be called to one
the talk and it was could around because you can trust
OK this is not a good thing we only report was one of them
it's impossible to be sure that because the question what about all of the above
does not
so this is not
what is the point
but in china just responsible computer
the initial proposal was
experts have also put down
but much longer companies and support for the rules regarding the current parameter so one
of the things support
and then you should be sure that you to put all those
what we do
but i thought it was to because support trust this
just so that you can make it could the learn about the exorcist because the
programs to get some the structure is not just the result of the compiler is
is that it was
this is the just the
the reason for the block problem some because it is so
it was intimately connected with one or two possible progress was a political practical similar
in shape to the world it is that would have
this point
OK well before the occupant attraction
the british monarch it's same
they thought it was interesting to watch competition for that it was performed in
so to start with a simple parental forces could also simple from to
the probability of being caught one more drive to windows and elsewhere
well spotted
it was intended to respond to integer
you might not
well also because it was like going to the reference point is
this is the direction of the talk about it will come up with a lot
about what i wanted to make the combined in the coat thickness what about the
the people who come because need the balance
which in one of the books one
two of the on the twenty three
to the next
so those
i mean
he goes
i mean we're are inputs are unordered sets of features in this will provide us
this kernel talk about provides the weighted very efficiently compare them in terms of their
when we're learning something from an image of course you have to choose the representation
and one way would be to look at the image of the whole and former
global representation so a single vector for every image that might be something as simple
stacking up the pixels in every image or computing the color histograms on
and in cases where you have some nicely aligned images such as these this will
give you a meaningful
description these images however we have real world real world scenarios where we have variation
in object pose or
changes in illumination and significant inclusion in clutter things like this the global representation is
known to break down
more recently
researchers in the vision community are exploring local feature representations we decompose each image into
some number of parts are local patch region features
and then describe it in terms of that set
and so a lot of work has been done to develop salient interest operators where
you find some salient points of interest in image and then each of those points
extract the descriptor
and some nice descriptors have been developed that will give you variance too part of
transformations such as rotations scaling translation and so on
so now reason for this set representation where we have very numbers of features percent
because each image will detect the different number of points potentially and there's no order
among those features
so it's common representation in fact in vision
we have already mentioned these intercepted operators an invariant descriptor also for representing shapes you
can consider two d contours in terms of local shape descriptors one example of the
shape context histogram which is like pulling jamie find each
contour point that counts up where the local counter points of that player following
and thinking of even higher level features we could have a set of features that
was representing a single object class or single object
so for face recognition maybe we want to have this set b examples of a
person's face under different viewing conditions in that way we could cover the space of
how they want to appear in terms of facial expression or illumination things like that
and what we really focused on vision problems it's interesting to think of some other
scenarios where you also have set of features say looking in gene expression data we
have sets of
data from different nations
in text processing we consider a document quite often as a bag of words again
on orders
even if you want to
potentially analyse code
for optimizing compilers
you could consider each method in terms of a set of instructions
so it's quite relevant tation we're most interested in some vision applications where we'd like
to use these local features
so now in this work well we're going to do is propose the kernel that
will let us efficiently compare the sets and then
with the hope that we can plug into these existing kernel methods and do all
kinds of interesting things such as image retrieval or
regression for parameter inference about an object or recognition of classes
and some previous work has been done to develop some kernels for sets
the standard for the different sort of categories these approaches can be described as those
that look for the model to fit to each that typically parametric distribution and then
compare those distributions within existing distance such as KL divergence
and these are nice and that you are allowed to have an order among features
and they can vary in size but they do have the restriction potentially that you
need to choose that distribution no that's a good fit for data that is that
large enough to make a meaningful estimate of those parameters
another general type approaches to look at the pairwise similarity between all the features into
sets and then take some weighted combination of those scores
to be the overall similarity
and here it's model for example approach however
you if you're allowing feature ones that map to multiple features in another you've lost
the description of the distribution of features of the whole
and also with most of these methods
really the complexity of the issue and it comes into play especially when we have
these images with easily thousands features
and so
typically these methods will take quadratically in cubic time in the number of features and
this is detrimental in practice for object recognition when we want to handle images about
the features and lots of images
we like to compare sets of features in terms of partial matching
which means we want to take two sets and find correspondence between some subset
from each of those sets
so what we're hearing how this correspondence would be useful for morphing between similar objects
use here we're going to use the measure of correspondence to say how similar objects
might be
and so the pattern matching were taken set of target features a set of observed
features and find the best way to map some subset of have observed features to
that target or if you can assume you have a threshold on how similar point
you're going to match must be then you can imagine a subset from each set
in vision
when we're dealing with images ignoring these extra features without any penalty to the similarity
score is very useful because this is what allows us to ignore
explicitly the background changes are clutter and segmentation errors that occur in images
now at all partial matching which would maximise the similarity
between them as points
is expensive
so here representing this pyramid match kernel that will allow us to do this very
so we have these two sets that going to match remember each point here is
depicting some d dimensional vector descriptor
such as the SIFT descriptor for familiar
so the basic idea of the pyramid match is two four multiresolution pyramid over these
features that
and then walk through these pyramids using a weighted intersection measure to count matches and
in this way approximate overall similarity
about optimal partial matching
and the way we use histogram pyramids to get a measure of correspondence is by
looking for matches from fine to course levels in the histograms
if we consider the spectrum of resolution levels in this histogram over the feature space
process that is able to take a small graph adjacency matrix and the like
in the sense that to get the adjacency matrices
nice nice structure and what the result is that these is on alaska scale fits
networks were so such a process of networks
very important is on a global scale of millions of nodes below thirty
so that's the first one hundred forty one and we can do
the second part is about diffusion and cascades so what i mean here is about
the processes that spread that it's so for example the first question is how does
information propagate
and what i'm showing you can actually his a picture from the paper and presented
on tuesday and it's about automatically in one of the
so here you get one million blog posts per day
this is over the three months ago when it was basically the US presidential campaign
and with this is automatically generated and you can for example be nice to see
what people talking on each day
what the most popular phrases on the web today and for example you can see
lipstick on a pig and things like that times by
the interesting thing is that
the overall volume
of people talking is about constant over time but still you get this huge spikes
of activity when sort of the whole
the whole
that's whole system concentrates on particular topics of particle phrases
so as i have as i can see things like that then i can ask
what how should i think about what is a model and for example it turns
out that such a topical burstiness can be nice thought of as a random walk
in the light and basically develop among the people of zero crossing model that can
actually capture both let's take the logical and structural properties of this information propagation works
and once they have
the modern understanding then i can ask what is the best and the task the
identified here was the the question how to find influential nodes and epidemics and that
so basically what happened network
which nodes should be that we wanted to that the days
you this is of information that
so what this picture here shows
is there
for every dot on this network is is a blog
and what to show sort of the the
sequence of how the algorithm selects influential bloggers so here these visualisations is going towards
the close the two
report on similar topics
so for example if i did the first one not to cover the whole lot
blogosphere so you can think of this as kind of
any of influence but but the public things very far away some sort of
detect those things lots of doing this
according to develop the call itself operates it selects influential blogs in a sequential manner
and you can see how like you
blogs holding
covered neighborhoods around around blocks and if i go and is up to them what
not nicely
basically the whole the whole
o lots there some sense
so this is sort of a quick overview of the two parts
and then the other
o team of the network was basically the benefits of working with large so we
work with some of the largest social and information networks that be examined so far
so particular the whole user base of microsoft instant messenger
water for billions of people and
two hundred fifty five billion exchanged messages per month
the other thing
one was explicit communication networks from a large on line retailer based
sixteen million sixty five commendations and awards showing the blogs that basically nothing more than
a year hundreds of millions of
but lots of things so what is the benefit and the benefit is basically by
working with large data basically you
c and find
let's properties and patterns of basic invisible or
statistically undetectable at small scales so on one one is the the
can this is basically we're looking at the community of clustering structure of large networks
and what the result is the same as in small networks to find these good
dense clusters that you can then lets extracted
call them community detection graph partitioning methods it turns out that when you look at
networks it just don't see such substructure something like networks
clusters find their own hundred nodes and everything else is big mass so the question
here is that this is some companies
why big networks
as as it seems fundamentally different from small
so what does sort of the
reflections on what what the questions and what the consequences of the disease so basically
the whole
the whole the main question was why are networks the way they are and how
can we use use this something each of these it will also nicely connects to
especially social sciences in the sense that only since recently basic properties of this network
has been observed on a large scale and many times this sort of conference
so social science intuitions and goals some other question so here i see
a good a fruitful area
those are promising trends water some were some problems that i see i i don't
want to say things aren't going to work
that's one of the lessons learned
but i do see some problems one problem we have in software development for the
semantic web is that you know you we can exchange data in RDF but
if i write some software for doing RDF that there's really not a good way
to write software way that's independent to the RDF
API that you're using
be great if we could have some work towards standardizing the
the different AP eyes
i actually think the most important problem for
from the perspective of the work that i've been doing and have been exposed to
at IBM and its customers
is this all idea in linguistics of connotation versus denotation connotations
kind of
without giving you a three hour lecture
connotation is sort of what reason do now the
connotation is sort of the what what symbols you can conclude from other symbols
whereas denotation is this murky connection to the real world between those symbols and what
they denote
this is actually of a
problem in industry
your eyes are nice idea i as i said i didn't really understand it when
it was first presented
that is the
it wasn't the
the k are in the semantic web was novel was the web
that was novel adding that aspect too
what we're doing in k are for twenty years really really was an innovation
that we're just beginning to
and this is one of the problems that technology creates a your eyes give you
an identifier but it's it's you still have an identity problem on the web and
we run into this all the time
really run into this problem space
significantly limiting a lot of the work done
as i already said i think this community is really weak on experimental methodology i
think a lot of times we published results
we don't really understand what they mean
if they are useful
anyone cares
how significant it is
i really think we need to do a better job we're supposed to be scientists
not just hackers
i mean it
talk i think if i have time about this notion of the very long tail
and how it impacts the semantic web i think it's very important
and you know how
how important is reasoning on the semantic web is a big problem that we have
i think and could put that there
the structure of the cut there
but i guess i do believe the ontology qualities is pretty important
i'm not very good sales but because of my
it's that
in the
the semantic web world at IBM i get asked questions about OWL and RDF all
the time
you know my murky explication of what the semantic web is
most people
i don't understand
whether they need reasoning and if so
even if they believed they needed a lot of people who believe they needed don't
really know why
i've had a very difficult time
selling the idea of reasons
what is reasoning really is solution to
i'm not saying there are none there are a couple of of these cases that
most people use reasoning if they use it all
to check the validity of their ontologies and that's it done with reasoning from that
the users who do want reasoning that i'm encountering again i don't i'm not talking
about people in the research community
we're already convinced that we need reasoning
certainly i mean this group of things reasoning is very important but i have a
hard time saying why
what most users i encounter one day they seem to get the idea of some
kind of simple taxonomic inheritance
they seem to get the idea of constraints although their mind boggled by
this sort of way
our processes constraints which is to say that you know if
if you say the domain of enjoyable experience if you say the domain and range
of some properties of person
and you put something in that's not a person the result is that
the result of reasoning that is the person
as opposed to something saying hey it's got to be a person this is an
invalid valid what people find that confusing
and then people
everyone i talked to seem to want very simple rules
very simple
rules over their RDF data
there are certainly another class of users think that OWL DL is not enough for
even OWL full just not enough does allow me to say the things i want
to say about my data and my semantics not because they care about reasoning just
because i have a pretty complicated semantics i wanna write it in english
so there is this
big class of users that are convinced they need ontologies as way to communicate the
semantics of their data
but they are not interested in reasoning at all
they just look at this
but in some kind of special language for writing documentation
fifteen years and you can see that article text is increasing exponentially
in the
vulnerability of your computer metrics is also increasing
on the other hand
this graph shows basically
what kind of philosophical station attackers have to have in order to perform and yet
the the tag earlier in the computers basically
appeared in the market basically not all nineteen eighty
there are only few
the number of attacks
in the level of sophistication in order to perform this attack was relatively high
this also correspond to the number of
tools that you can see that there are available to perform the computer attacks
and over time the number of tools
and the number of tax increases
one of the biggest sophistication of attackers actually the amount of the knowledge of the
celtic to have in order to perform detector significantly
so basically today almost every high school kid
can use some of the those from the internet and try to perform some attacking
the denial-of-service attack
scanning attack it's quite easy
people are trying to defend against these things
and security mechanisms usually have some kind of
inevitable vulnerabilities
and firewalls are typically not sufficient
to sure one hundred percent security in computer networks
what it actually intrusion
as i said earlier inference
OK let's have
OK so intrusions
actually that attempt to bypass security mechanisms
OK so you see these guys trying to scan the network
and when you find some computer that is vulnerable of his trying to launch
thank you for type two
OK so when is trying to find computer title and the second is computer and
he's trying to attack this specific computer
so first his can the natural for the vulnerabilities of some security calls
and then when he finds the computer
then he will here trying to launch attack on this specific computer the typical scenario
how through jean detection
is occurring
as i mentioned briefly earlier
intrusion detection systems are typically combination of software and hardware tools
and their goal is to detect intrusions of course
and they
raise the alarm every time certain suspicious activity
is occurring
i mentioned we also the traditional intrusion detection systems are based on signatures and they
work in a similar way like virus can make a field or
or or or not
and basically this here we show example
of signature of one of the
forms that are detected in computer networks basically every time and finishing bayesint interest text
is to find this combination
to to raise an alarm
this image should be used
intrusion detection systems have limitations and they cannot detect these new types of there's new
computer attacks
and also there is
because every time and it is a new attack you have to revise this manually
and then to update the database
and then you can take this new attacks so basically
there is hope that
anomaly detection techniques can alleviate some of these are so this a the problem because
they can affect
new emerging behavior
there are two
types of approaches that people can do in
intrusion detection using data mining techniques
the first was the first one is misuse detection
mean you basically have the knowledge about what normal in the network and
novelist and again this is similar to classification techniques
when you try to build different types of classifiers
but again they have they can have really high accuracy in detecting these intrusions but
also they may have problems with attacking this new emerging behavior
on the other hand you have anomaly detection techniques
as you know the
can be detected using this technique says deviation from the norm
but they suffer from potential high false alarm rate
OK so this is the typical kind of data says that you get from the
network intrusion detection
this is the source IP address
this nation for the destination IP this nation of ulysses source for this initial IP
destination port
number of bytes
depending on the level of information you have it dealing with network traffic back it's
all you're doing using their drawback it's you make an informational support from the back
the raw data and then the number of features can be
significantly higher
depending on what time to do it in different if using mutual defection
you have the labels here
he that something is back
i mean computer technology and then you're trying to train the model
from training set trying to learn the classifier
and then to apply these classifying it as they can get with the labels
OK so you what the labels here so far
if you're doing anomaly detection
let's say this is the data thing two dimensional space just for
just for simplicity
you're trying to define what can you normally hear
OK so far so good humour to detect anomalies all these points here that far
from everything else
and finally
you we do some summarisation of the network
i think using association rules
for example
all of this that connections if they have something in common you may apply some
standard association rules to detect two
replace all this data that is has to see
and replaced with carol's i'll explain a little bit
o this later
so this is
slide shows that
the system that was applied in the university minnesota
when applied to the anomaly detection techniques to detect real
intrusions in network that we have
here we here
the network we have
several tools to to collect the data they use the net flow tools
to collect only the packet header information
or you can use it you can also use this to be done
tool to collect those the rollback it information because emperor package information
if you're writing the main
it can contain exactly what you wrote
in the email
if you if you want to this information
there are some privacy issues as well
the netflix goes only contain information about the connection comes from that going
and what to the number of bytes in some cases reflects
so right now we have the feelings that the basically our computer security analyst is
light is basically
so that relates the two area of convex sets with convex functions
this definition the sublevel set of a function f
is the set of all vectors x that have the function value
as i recall two given numbers
and convex functions have the property that all the sublevel sets are convex
but the converse is not true
so fraction can have convex sublevel sets but it's not necessarily convex
so these are some basic examples or examples i will encounter of convex functions
well first of all the variables can just look at the graph of the function
and see the convex for example the exponential
or minus log x is convex
convex functions
certain powers of x are convex
so x to the power of five of his
greater than one
and you restrict access the positive real axis
some negative powers for example one over x is convex for positive x
this is a very useful function quadratic over linear so if you take a cesspools
defined by t
thirty is restricted to be positive
then this is an convex function xmt
joint in xnt
the geometric mean of n vectors is concave
log of the determined of a positive definite matrix is a concave function that will
the log of a sum of exponentials is convex
norms are always convex linear functions always convex and so on
four differentiable functions are some of
other characterizations
so the function is twice differentiable then it's session is always positive semi definite attraction
is symmetric matrix with partial
second partial derivatives
that's always
positive semidefinite
so that's probably the best known characterisation of convex functions but it assumes that f
is differentiable twice differentiable
four function you can also there's also property only uses the first derivative so if
the gradients with great i mean the vector of the first partial derivatives
so the gradient of
any function f defines a linear approximation a local linear approximation around x
so if you've elevates at some point x the function
and its gradient
then the
the straight line the first order approximation is the local
linear approximation to the function value
if a function is convex then this approximation also has the property
that's a lower bound on the function value everywhere
and not just the local
and that's if and only if if the function is differentiable
practice if you try to use convex formulations in applications
it's useful to have a sort of a set of techniques for
proving convexity or easily establishing convexity of functions
and so there are several techniques we can use so on this
we can just use the definition that works
the chances inequality
that works in
in some cases in some cases it's quite complicated
you can use for defensible twice differentiable functions can take the haitian is positive semidefinite
but also that can be quite painful
this session is complicated
and there are also set of techniques that often allow you to easily show convexity
by showing that the function is derived from simpler functions
nevertheless additional slides ago
and some basic
calculus rules for
that preserve convexity
so i'll go through these different rules
with some examples
so the first one is quite straightforward if f is convex then positive or negative
multiple is convex
or some of the convex functions is convex
or if you have a function is convex and replace its arguments with linear mapping
of some variable
then the resulting
a function is convex in x
so in some examples of this are for example
the normal express b is always convex
and that's true for any norm because norms are convex and uses property
the function is known as the logarithmic barrier function in your programming is convex
because minus log x is convex
here we replace the argument of
the function by linear or not find functions work is is a convex function
and then we have this functions for i want
so that's automatically convex
you need to
worry about the haitian order derivatives to establish convexity
this is one of the most useful
these characters rules
pointwise maximum of
a set of convex functions is convex if f one through ephemeral convex in x
and i define f of x as
a new function that has the maximum of this function values
and that new function is convex
and this is an example of this suppose i defined for vector in rn
a function is the sum of the are
the largest components in x
so it's easy to compute its a well-defined function of x can be computed by
sorting the components of x in descending order
and then just adding to our leading coefficients
so it's easy to compute it's a well-defined function of x
and is also convex and that's easy to see from this max maximum rule
because i can also write it as a maximum of a very large number of
linear functions of x
so take all
groups of our subsets
of coefficients of x
for each subset that exist some
and then if i take the maximum of all these some standard be the maximum
this some of our largest for that's so the practical expression for computing f of
because it's a maximal very large number of linear functions but this shows that it's
so the maximum component of f is convex to some of the largest two and
so on
this also extends to an infinite maximisation so here we have a finite maximum of
and so on
o notation to use the super supremum for maximisation of set that's infinite
or possibly infinite it's not specified
so here i define a function g
of x
as an so take a function f of two variables x and y
and f has the property that for fixed why the function is convex in x
and define a function and maximize over y
i have to some
over z
the effects
given z
he said
so multiply this by this
and then we have to some
over all possible choices
of the vector z so i have to sum up and after some the case
was z is one zero zero
plus the pastry zero one zero
plus the case for zero zero one
adult those three contributions
the first would just pick out
the mixing coefficients pi one
and guassian and new one sigma one
and the second component the second term in this sum will pick out the second
component so on
so what i'm left with is the sum of the components k
of pi k
times and that's given parameters nu k sigma k
so the marginal distribution is just are familiar mixture of gaussians
so this is an example
how we have
constructed a complex probability distribution which is not of the exponential family much more general
using the graphical model which the building blocks of exponential family distributions
so very trivial example
of very general approach to
solving machine learning problems
now we actually have an entire
data set of observations
and so the graphical model for the for the complete data set for the entire
dataset can be written
as this
so this is all plate notation
and this is the capital and
replicas of what's inside the plates well there's an observation xn and there corresponding latent
variables and
and i used this notation these parameters are the parameters not random variables we don't
have nodes
so just indicated them with symbols without any circles
but the shared by all of the components in the mixture so they live outside
the plate
so i hope that this notation is reasonably clear
OK let's go back to this problem of complete or the problem of
of the fact that we would not observe the latent variables so suppose for a
minute that somebody kindly gave us
datasets with the observations of supposing that z
it was also observed in other words a hundred dataset and say please for mixture
of gaussians to this
but really very kind today
i'm gonna colour in the data points according to which garrison generated that data points
you have what we call complete data now you have values not only for x
also for z
so now you can write down the likelihood function that's the probability of the data
given the parameters
we know we know what that is we know not the joint distribution is
i think the log
i have the product of these two guys and the logs will become will turn
the products into sums
so what i have then is the following sum of the data points
some of the components
znk that was in the in the that was an experiment that's come down in
front of the log on i got log pi k
on log n
and this is what happens now
is that by knowing z
this some appears outside the log so that the sum of the components the log
acting directly on the gaussians
so by observing z interchange mathematical to change the log on the summation nasty problems
gone away and i now have trivial solution i think you can
sort of see in your in your head without doing any that even using a
piece of paper that when i maximize this likelihood function what's going to happen is
each component
so remember this summer over
the sum over k
all these coefficients zero
except for the term
except for the component which generated that particular data points
OK so what's going to happen is and this is just the log likelihood for
single galaxy and so what happens then is that i just do the obvious thing
i think the red component to the reading blue and blue ink
and i don't need to
there is no coupling between them
if i have a collection
of charges pluses and minuses
no has only one value
it is the work that i have to do is to put all these crazy
charges exactly where they are
but the electric potential is different here from their from there to their if you're
very close to apply charge you can be sure that the potential is positive if
you really close to with the negative charge
you can be sure that the potential negative
you is only one number one values they're both scalars
don't confuse one
with the other
in a gravitational field
like a piece of chalk
i wants to go from
high potential
low potential if i just deleted with zero speed
then goes
i potential to low potential
in analogy
positive charges
we also go from a higher electric potential
willow electric potential
and of course
this is unique for electricity
negative charges will go from low potential
two and a high
suppose i have a
position a
in space
and i had another position
and i specify
the potential
so here
we have a
a and here we have point b
the potential
by definition
of the
as we discussed
is in the world
by the way these are
separated by some
random distance or whatever you want
so the potential of a
defined as
goal going from a to infinity
of e
that is the definition of the potential of a
which is four unit charge
so it is not working
if they were forced the i'll be work but it is for a unit charged
that makes it easier
so the potential of being
the definition
indeed well
to infinity
they are
so therefore
the potential difference
o point a and b
v eight
because in the world
from a to b
of e
and for reasons that
i still don't understand after having been in this business for a long time
books will always tell you
they reversed a and b so to give you beam minus
and then they say well we have to put a minus sign in front of
the integral of the same thing
the books always give it to you in this for
but it is exactly the same
i hope you realize that
this is the two equations that i have here
the same for a minus b b is the integral from a to b if
you got the article
if i flip is over
all i have to do is put a minus sign here
and the two are identical
notice that if there is no electric field between a and b
they have the same potential of course
the new march from a to b which the charter your pocket no work is
done sort of potential
the same
i will change this the or
two different symbol which i call the l
the would mean
that we go from a to infinity along the straight line
and then we go from b
to infinity
along the straight line
it makes no difference how you go
you go from a to b
this potential difference and you go in this way
and we a minus b is not going to change
so if now i introduced here
elements dl
small vector
and if the local effect here
it's like so
at this point here
the miners
is then the integral of e dot
in other words i can replace the are
by an l
and you may choose any past
that you prefer
and that's the way
we will show you this equation most of the time
so it makes no difference how you march because we are dealing here with conservative
let's not make the assumption
thirty eight hundred fifty four
and that be for instance is fifty four
so it's a very specific example
what does it mean
it means that if i
but prosecutor charged in my pocket
and i come all the way from b seven
and i woke up to point b
walter lewin
plus q charge in his pocket
goes from lobby b seven
two point b
i have to do work
and the work i have to do
it is the product of my charge q
with the potential so that is q
the work i have to do
is q
time of the
so in this case it's fifty times q whatever that
that i have in mind
is in joules
i go from lobby seven
two point eight
have to do more work
i have to do
one hundred fifty
hugh joseph of work
you can think of it i first come to a to b
already exhausted
i have supported
work to get all the way
it does
and now
the magic trick is the rules with differentials are i can pick what ninety theta
is and calculate the corresponding the
the food
so now
what i do here as i say that's my
that's the be vector i want to multiply by the haitian
in in order to multiply by the haitian
i apply the vs the perturbation to my parameters
and i propagate that differential is an infinitesimal per perturbation i propagate through the system
that takes my parameter value and calculates the gradient
obviously i have called for doing this calculation lying around because i'm using gradient method
to optimize the system
so somewhere i have code that given the parameter value will calculate your data
i now need to augment the code to take
the differential an infinitesimal perturbation and propagate that as well
and that the output i get the haitian product with with that
this various ways to actually
implement this one thing for instance is there c plus plus classes out there
we're actually if you're
if you function that computes the gradient is coded in c plus plus using doubles
you can just
change all the doubles two
this special class
and include the
the declaration filed for that class and what that class does is it overloads the
entire math library to propagate perturbations alongside it just includes all these basic rules that
you know the derivative of sine is cosine and all that stuff
so it's really under the hood
nothing fancy going on but it's very convenient thing to happen
so that means and this is something that even in the field very few people
know if you have code to compute the gradient
with very little effort
you can get code to compute hash vector products out
and this can be done in the same time it takes for two to three
gradient evaluations because the code inherits the structure of the gradient computation
so it's the same order cost
and there's a constant factor of two to three that's more complex
so this is
these kinds of techniques are our research in the field called algorithmic differentiation which is
one of these interesting applied fields nowadays
and they have tools out there so you can actually just sort of use that
and plug it in
you don't have to actually called up the session vector product yourself
this looks like a huge problem
if you don't know this trick
but in fact it's it's not difficult at all
with the right tools and the right tricks this comes for free
so now
the whole algorithm is is not that hard to do
you have the parameter update you have the update for the game vector and you
have the update for the
and all you need is this session vector product that you get automatically from given
the right tools
there's another trick i don't think i'll have time for it but
you can actually do this if you're
programming in matlab you can call up the complex arithmetic to do the haitian vector
product for you
so that's another neat neat way to do it
in that case you don't have to change your code at all
because matlab code already takes complex numbers
all right
OK some more analysis of this update i think of a skip over that rather
you can start copying now that's all that
the risk here
if we pretend we keep the gradient and the haitian and the parameters and the
town everything else constant and we just iterate our be update
it would converge to the fixed point
and this fixed point looks like a levenberg marquardt gradient step so this slide is
actually only of interest to people in a little bit of optimisation
if you've heard of levenberg marquardt and what it does
looking back mark but basically multiplies the gradient by the inverse of the curvature matrix
and the curvature matrix is a mixture of the haitian
and the diagonal matrix
it also scales like the haitian
on the diagonal
and the funny thing is this fixed point actually has exactly the structure
what that means is that my algorithm to some extent is a stochastic approximation of
levenberg marquardt gradient procedure
of course it's not exact because i only iterate this ones
and then i update the parameters in the games before it to the next iteration
so this never actually converges
two to a fixed point
it it's keeps getting jostled around too much to do that but it's sort of
reassuring to know that if i were to iterate this more often
and this means so this is the interesting this is the same
this is the impossibility of
at least according to and this is the interesting machine because it means that the
popular algorithms
is still not explaining all the information
so this is the clustering is interesting summary
by the way these numbers
like when the regime change depends on how the problems like also that
so it's an expert in a number depends on the know how many dimensions how
many clusters and how separated and it gets harder motivate dimensions with more
i would love separation
if want
so we remember when my first thought about some of it is that the current
find out
i suspect some of you want to ask me how about this result was installed
that is
this separation that these problems you are much harder than the problems that can be
solved by the computer science
if you look at these and so on
basically they didn't want to the results online and then look at what
all these and are less so quickly after two you can find
not really benefit from
this approach much more than what was promised by the
this meant
so you know that of course one can those and practical what so there is
information that much when the clusters are much closer
of course that they expect computer science would catch up and get better
get the answer but i got it will actually allow for error and and make
situation more realistic
question because every new pages a different conditions song
this is the first question
stability is another
as i said
people use stability to find the number of clusters
the solution is not stable
you should be somewhat suspicious
and this is the stability means i have defined the previous
so basically if you find the that
clustering is
as stable to to small perturbations in here the this is one of the things
that you saw
like to classification error or the idea is that
four actually
so that
you're calling the clustering stable and you called the
there's a lot of
but people have confidence that if the solution is
but this is recovering some structure and so it's telling me what how many clusters
and that's
practice a
here are some very new results two thousand six or just a few months old
so what
basically this is a technical result in this is that apply to class
and they say so that the cost function by l
and i
i have a lot of so these were all in the limit of large data
but this plan for the first
they the following it to my data by some by
less than one of the world
then the expect to see in for example
is more than one was quite lot of
so any perturbation that smaller than the square root of n
i also has a very small effect on the
and for any k
so what
because level
so a particular version interpreter
result saying it doesn't matter what kaye's my cost like those not always be stable
no matter the cost
whereas this here we're saying for some k find similar results for some other cases
i find unstable results actions
there's difference one case with the other one is that
this i see no think about
or the structure of the day doesn't always make it so you see is that
it is one is
so have nothing to
with that distribution
and probably have to do with the initialisation
this is called summer look love
the which is the building main
however i i think it's the end of the story
because in particular is assumed actually finding the minimal in resulting in a very small
and it applies to many many more things
whole world
if you talk about clustering this assumes that you all to the minimum of the
and what do we have
most of the time you look for them
and so many other things that way
and the interplay that they actually do it
on the structure
like in particular you find something we something is stable with respect
then there is something
that you can make
you only be performed
correct number of clusters but there is something that that is to come
this is the last but one slide
by the way i haven't talked about lots of things like hierarchical clustering
i haven't talked about others other things that people do that are like clustering but
i'm not
classical clustering like clustering by subsets of attributes of finding
extracting clusters one by one from data
and the most of the times
on clusters
think the background and other things
but is something interesting is motivated by
basically practical issues
one of the exploration the end of one
you're many algorithms many times you try also the parameters of the doing
and then you go
a few hundred classics
and the i'm other going to promote some of them
maybe it doesn't make sense to me
o everything and keep just one cluster
which is the solution this these people try to solve the problem which is the
best class
it doesn't have to be that way
four one
you don't know anything about the
then maybe there is more than one meaningful way of thinking
like think of the people in this room can them depending on the intended use
you're going to get different clusterings
and if you if you not
the one two
so i'll move on to so something very well
move on so so basically models the people statistics will be used to model data
so let's go from there
and we
looking at
two main areas in terms of modelling which is a generalized linear model and
all topics are suppose special topic unusual bits
and then
they will look at so called multivariate analysis which is more exploratory trying to find
out what's going on or
trying to
the data into
more sustainable forms
continent so
take the regression and generalized linear model
well that's
what's called linear models to the first
politicians for the regression is
the simplest form of linear model
the linear model comes with the whole
battery of methods for working out what's the right model
and the basic idea is called the analysis of the silicon and then
well at
this is called generalized linear model based that's linear models these generalized linear models look
as well so so just john and mention analysis survival data but it was really
special case one of the other methods
so that's the first time so i want to talk about this because i think
if you
what to do any statistical course but involve modelling these are the models to be
i have to use and particularly bits of the first one regression model
so these are really heavily used models in statistics world
and essentially what you're trying to do
it is estimated what's called the trend in one variable based on the values taken
by the variables so we have the trend of what we call the output based
values for several input variables
so what
well here is
more formally we have
what we're looking at in regression is the question of how is a variable y
this one
related to
several variables colon one x two two xm so that's
could be any number we want really
just lost its
to create something back
the world to the y variable and we try to find out what's related to
build this is
generally called the response
all the dependent variable of the output so response because
the idea is that you alter the variable x variables and see how the y
value response to this variation
as political response
and request is the same idea
but basically i think so
this is the
i'm assuming that your computer science based on stops space
so use the frame the the terms used in electrical engineering from this sort of
thing which is the output and inputs so the axes are input variables otherwise the
output why do we want to do this
pierre for standard reasons for wanting to do
find the relationship between the output and inputs
the woman sort springs to mind actually is
it is this last one
but we think there is actually a model
relating the inputs the output the causal link between the two so
so that might be
an example of that sort of situation where there is a causal link between the
two is what's the temperature
and water ice cream sales
the temperature goes up screen cells go and process
and also means that there is the sum in many situations in natural way to
decide which is the output which is the input in that particular example
it would be stupid to have the temperature is the output
because it's not
so then you can so now we have we have have ostensibly group constant into
atomic terms
and then you can for the wrong we can
use these sentences
it even larger sentences and
using the logical connectives and you can at priors on the cars
so long
the standard logical operators AND OR NOT implies
all traffic to function value is
the is get is using this operator
but their arguments
the arguments of these operators can be
cycl sentences
so human operator and
the first arguement is
an argument is the other understand
this is this
this is true
and singles four or not and implies
o thing mentioned these quantifiers of quantification so we can have our universe
and you can have existential quantifiers
example of you know
these things are english should see every all
all this stuff like that
for example of
all of be
universal quantifier or
all course
every person in this room is alive so for each expert it's person
and he is alive
is for all x this would be
universal want quantifiers
we can write this in
i think like this
so this is
like using universal quantification
so in the one to tell the all orthodox here
i would say it all
was there
auc is
belongs to collection dong
then the
so anatomical body part
this so this is that like
four orthodox it is just
as it can be anything
and then you go in
implies so this from this first thing so if
dog belongs to this collection then
this sort
this is another
a bit more complex rules
can you say put all persons so is the
every person in this room is alive so here is a
this implies
and then it will connect things together first
that person is actually
the second constraint is the person
obj is found in this room
so if this
all these things are true
then this assertion cause is like this would be