what does gene
look at this
i look i see you're
i don't see you p wave
but you have an amazing t way i know you have an amazing are way
it looks like you are waves in the wrong direction
you feel OK alright
yeah i can see if the have well maybe some people survive without the way
it's certainly an unusual
unusual hard
but if you tell me that you're happy then i'll take your word for that
i think it would be nice if you show class now we just stand up
for a while the two other muscles begin to act
and they will see then just under enough
you will see move little bit your arms
well he arms you see now you get the electric dipole field from the other
muscles in the body
which contract
this is even more interesting to your hartmann
all right down again and that's the kind of
and then you can clean up
looks good
part carranza not so easy to interpret
but i think you're looking fine
you feel like
that's important thank you very much for volunteering very courageous
and it's to clean that stuff of is water soluble so it's not so bad
what's your name by the way
you great
and i want to talk
aurora borealis
if we have a magnetic field
and we have a charged particle let's take
make it plus
and the velocity of the charge particles
in this direction
then the force on that chart particle the foreign force
because q
i'm the crosby
i'm going to decompose this philosophy now
in two one component
parallel to the magnetic fields
and in two components
perpendicular to the magnetic field to the vectorial some of these two is be
so i can rewrite this
as q
the parallel
please be perpendicular
across the b
but the parallel across was zero
because the angle is easier zero agrees on the eighty degrees of the sine of
the angle is zero
so to force
is exclusively determined
by this time
it's about perpendicular component
so i was going to happen this
charged particles
is going to circle around
but then it continues to go in this direction with the velocity v
and so you're going to see a
as like this
by the israelis are
that circle
that radius i still remember it from the lecture when we discuss that that was
envy divided by q
but we now is of course the perpendicular component
divided by b
and then in this direction
it continues unaltered the
which is the parallel component
magnetic field of the earth
not straight line
it is curved
so charged particles
inspire around the magnetic field
for the magnetic field lines
and they come down on earth where
the magnetic field lines enter which is near
magnetic poles
the sun emits
the plasma
highly ionized
electrons and protons
call that the solar wind
two groups so that the circle or ellipse is simply shows that these two clusters
hello there
you know subtrees together
next step would be
split this note further on this knowledge and
and so on so that
comes to the
in this case the sixty groups sixty clusters
so again this somehow show the structure approximately
this picture basically
does of for first
again the
projects are the clusters which are kind of close are on the picture
are also more similar by the content
and for each cluster but basically
corresponds to the size of the size of the clutch cluster response to the number
of documents which are
in the
additionally it has a couple of nice properties so we can zoom in zoom out
so it
it's pretty kind of you to do with this kind of structure
basically this is the picture of the taxonomy of the
of the topics in some way
OK maybe i can show you create them on this
in one
for this graph based visualisation
so we load in this case
a corpus of eleven thousand news articles from ACM
and then we simply
press visualize
in this case we will split them into
then groups
so if you please
so the lower defined the limits
see the structure basically now if you go in
we performed so
the technology news
basically so that's why there's are so many computers of computer related words so this
is obviously looks cluster
so if you click on the cluster we get
the most relevant keywords for this particular cluster
it's open source windows five percent
and so on
most relevant documents are documents which are the closest to the centre of the
clusters of this one particular
so here we have this HTML representation of this
of these texts
the news so
two thousand four the growing fuelled by something
the reason she
a lot of that
so basically a
here we have corpus of eleven thousand news
a couple of seconds we can see that the structure of this
news source in this case
OK i mean will be able to play a little bit more with this but
i don't have much time
another them which is this tiling based again the same collection
of the
one of the new
and so a here
so we visualize
and stopping criteria would be within it
clusters with less than one hundred documents one please
any more so
here we see
the structure of the press
certain notes then we see again keywords documents text and so on we can
then on this
the has a couple of
part of the left left part the needs of all known named entities extracted from
the corpus
the new bar shows
the relationship between selected
one of the selected name entities and other most most related to them
and here need to see the context so we are the what what the typical
conflict between
in this case microsoft research and MIT so the
one highly weighted work
and microsoft research and private agency
not probably
the reasons are many different different ways
this is the way how we can explore and here on the right we see
the whole profile of the
particular name entities so i can show you
short example
OK so here if i
but in very
then this is the most
and to the google news news google com
this was the same as
i been keen
here's the mean you
and then google would turn
set of
OK set of
o from slovenia
and we collect them in this chapter
so i want to repeat again because you take some time
just another it's you have the
news z
you may wonder whether you may have also sorry in this example here you have
this and he has mu z
and here
you had this for operator here
i just tried this tactic tree
of the formula and here's the question is whether we do have an article in
some way or not
if i have an occurrence of y here
the nations that
will be incremented by one
what is also a bit many
if you have not worked on fixed point you you can't really
get it immediately but if you
but if you bet together on the
greatest fixpoint only six point seven things of the same kind you don't
you don't get alternation like in
two men first the logic
several existential quantification to do not codifications they they do not at
complexity in
solving or in interpreting this formula
what's what courses and nation between exist for exist for its for and this is
exactly the same thing here what what is costly the alternation between
least and greatest fixpoints
because you may
compute the least fix points that are
put together
in one shot
using some pictorial
computation like domain something
so alternation just measures
how complex the formula is in terms of
how many iterations you would need
to compute
so this will play a very important role so here you will have an example
here of
formula as i said which is of alternation depth one and here it will be
of alternation depth two
OK so just to make
so what is important is that
things you can express
so the the
thickness of the hierarchy here
is that if you don't know for more than
the nation that
there are things you will not be able to express that you would be able
to express which takes this one nation
so just remember that it's like infinitely often
i cannot express it
without i mean
hello allowing me to
to kind of
but together into some
two viable is one
which which is
greatest fixpoint and one which is least fixpoint
so there's also something interesting about how many bibles
you can use to write formulas but this is another story if you know like
looking for solution
precision logic with two levels of
these lists
express expressiveness than first of the logic
and in in particular becomes disabled
which is not the case of fuzzy logic in general
for the next hour the show we see
we see the following
remember that's OK
writing mu calculus formula super the hectic
it's synthetically particularly
complicated subjects
let's see you can kind of
organize the formulas of the mu calculus
in terms of the complexity of
the reason great greatest fixpoint in your formula
in tracks
in the way
so we're not see complicated formulas anymore that was the
i mean really worst time you would have gotten a calculus i believe so now
will simply
try to understand
another tool
which is connected to it which are tree automata
there are very standard problems that you already know logic one is
we call it was chicken problem was just given the model
and given the formula
is it true that the model satisfies the formula
that is called
more than taking
satisfiability is given the formula can you find the model
also there's something really interesting his when you have
infinite objects
people want to know whether the mother you give me
so to do that you just take half
and you subtract
constant alpha times the gradient
of that functional
actually do this you'll get terrible overfitting so instead what we can do is we
can restrict the form of the update
to belong to
class of functions class of weak classifiers in other words we can restrict the update
to have this form
where ht has to belong to
class of weak classifiers
so we would like to do an update like this
restricting ourselves to do an update like this
so the natural thing to do is to choose ht which is as close as
the gradient the negative gradient
and that also
is equivalent to adaboost so this is another way of viewing adaboost so services is
called functional gradient descent because you've got this functional
and you're doing gradient descent or you're trying to do gradient descent
the advantages of these views of boosting is the
lead to all kinds of generalizations to other loss functions
another advantage is that this provides a principled way of estimating conditional probabilities
until now i've assume that our goal is to just predict whether an example is
positive or negative and to be correct as often as possible
in practice what we often want to do instead is forgiven example predict the probability
that example being positive and negative we want to predict its conditional probability
viewing adaboost as an algorithm for minimizing exponential loss is helpful for coming up with
a principled way of doing this
so again here's our exponential loss in work and thinking about the idea of the
true exponential loss
which is the expected exponential loss one
x and y are chosen from the true distribution that's generating the data
on adaboost is minimizing an empirical version of this
but if we could somehow
octane that true expectation
we will be able to write it in this form we can write it as
the expected value over the axes
and then we can look at separately at the case where y is plus one
to minus one
OK so then we get probability wise positive for x positive times the loss plus
the probability that x is negative times the loss
and then
then we can imagine choosing the f which minimizes this over all possible functions over
all functions f
and you can do that just by differentiating this setting it equal to zero
if you do that they get that f of x is equal to this expression
it's kind of logodds expression
which is equivalent to
the probability of x being positive being equal to this as a function of f
of x
to take the oath which is output by adaboost
and converted into a probability estimate we can just take
and plug it into this expression as an estimate of this conditional probability there are
lot of assumptions that are being made here like that the empirical
exponential loss is close to the true exponential loss
and now we can optimize over all of us
assumptions don't hold in general but
this can work pretty well so like here's a case on an actual data sets
the dots
the next corner of each one of these dots represent the estimated probability
using this method and the y value represents the actual
fraction of positive examples for some set of examples so
if this method really work well then you would get predictions very close to the
line likewise acts as you see in this case but this is what ten thousand
training examples
if user smaller training sets this doesn't work as well
OK so this loss minimisation view
OK so thanks everyone for coming and
staying in this room i
so let's talk about today is about
networks in the diffusion in networks and
we can so basically that there are multiple kinds of
so i should
OK it's OK you must
it is
OK so
i want to first make a short introduction in why why why why do we
care about networks why do we analyse them and so on right so
social network analysis later became like a nice area where there there is a lot
of interaction between sociologists computer scientists physicists and so on and there are many different
domains for social network analysis right now
large scale network data the was
became available in this traditional domains are usually analyzed the social social networks people like
frank friendship and
informal contacts among people collaboration influencing companies organizations
professions professional communities and so on but then we i emergence of women computing applications
that there are a lot of
venues for social network analysis of for example like online communities blogging social social networks
and social media electronic markets and and so on right and also there are a
lot of people seeking information in these in these domains for example
services like myspace delicious flickr linkedin yahoo answers facebook and so on
and just introduce if a few examples of networks or networks can come from various
domains like here i have a few examples so we can study the internet like
the level of autonomous systems we can have like citation networks which would be scientific
papers referring to each other you can have one where where nodes are web pages
and the hyperlinks between them you can have more
exotic type of types of networks like sexual networks of sexual contact contact friendship networks
and so on and there are many more of them and for example this
from there
what i showed what sort of information networks you can also have like social networks
of people and some kind of interactions and some very traditional networks are or well
known networks are of the florence families where there is a link between two families
in florence if a member of one family married the other one does actually karate
club network is also very famous and so on
there are also networks coming from not so social sciences for example we can have
like protein interaction networks can have networks built from text like semantic networks were there
are relationships between concepts or what they call language networks where there are links between
words and also like you can use your
they favourite open source
so after project create a network of
so mining social network data has has a long history and one of the more
well-known examples is this one from seventies by by the way actually where he observed
in network of social ties between in karate club at the university and during his
observation period that that was a few years longer what what what happened is that
due to due to some conflicts the karate club split into the two clubs right
and what what can what you can do is if you find like the minimum
cut these in this so the best way to split the network is to split
it is disputed here and what i also got color-coded here is that all the
people that went
the joint either one of these two kind of this newly newly developed karate clubs
and for example what is interesting is that the minimum cut can sort of explaining
how people went and each of the newly established karate clubs joined
the other
o point that i want to do it the four motivation is that go complex
networks as phenomena and just and not just some kind of design artifacts or design
systems right and what i'm interested in then is what are the common patterns that
emerge through these networks and even more right there is this citation i have here
that we want to keep laws of motion for the web right we want to
find statistical tools and methods to quantify large networks and
why why why do we hope to get from from these there are basically like
three parts to the problem i would like to know what to measure so what
better statistical properties of this network data was me once we know what to measure
the second question like pens what the design principles and models that can describe
this type of data and once we have good models that we want to do
the next step which is like understand understanding why networks are the way they are
we want to do predictions on the of the network evolution and things like that
so there are three parts to the problem
networks are also very rich data right traditionally
or let's put it is that you want to read things from the networks you
want them to be large so you want large-scale really speaking completely right don't want
friendships or links to be missing from the traditional you could sort of get two
out of three
of these things but now
through the online systems where everything is locked because we can get all three of
the the right you can get online communities where there is a complete waste of
user activities when things were created and so on
six same is true for email blogging electronic markets instant messaging and so on
we've seen this slide i think two days ago but still the scale of the
network data has increased tremendously over the last few years so
so you're just have like the the networks trying to sort of chronologically sorted from
like small ones to something decent of like four million to the largest social network
analyzed to date is that like all the people
some historical data
then that same statistic is being used to make a claim about the reliability of
the model which
and that's not
it's not a consistent argument
what's the simplest thing we can do to test so
number one simplest vanilla method of testing something is
training on some training data
have some new data which is used to test the status fresh you've not seen
maybe you had the last three years of financial
some financial index train your
you know whatever it is astrological
neural network
that's really what they call it by the way
and you
then evaluate that on some new data which is not
not seem like the next six months of data if
that's the thing that you test you look at how accurate that was on the
test data
so in the case of classification
we might be interested in things like
true positives true negative false positives and false negatives so
assuming we've got some positive class the negative class you might find it easy to
think about disease diagnosis in this case they were with screening test for cancer perhaps
or malaria which we're looking for from visual data
a true positive is when someone
as malaria and our system
correctly says that you have not a true negative is when you're healthy in the
system says you
correctly says you healthy
has two types of mistakes you can make
one of them is
false positive where you are
actually healthy but the system says sixty take tablets
and most seriously here
a false negative where you are sick and the test comes back and says you're
you're actually healthy
OK so there's various things you might want to look at and you know the
most basic thing is how many times to get it right
divided by the total number of cases that the accuracy narrators one minus that its
this is
right right absolutely we talk at the start about
the decision theoretic approach that's why you might have a loss function
this might describe how how serious is it
if you get it wrong
and you this could be perhaps a matrix of all the possible combinations and you
would say
if i false negative how bad is that the false positive how about islam and
then when you're choosing your class you might
try to minimize this loss
and so obviously in the case of nigeria false negative is a much bigger deal
than false positive
you know false positive means you've got to buy snacks drugs false negative potentially is
because untreated died
the loss on false negative is much higher and if you've weights that with the
probability of the thing being positive and negative
you know if you're not sure
it's the posterior probability from your classifiers says fifty fifty
this loss matrix says
we get a huge loss if we give false
negative and only a little less if we get false positive
and minimizing the loss overall
will tend to say positive
OK so this
the things we can do it like this that kind of decision theoretic approach looking
at the consequences of your
the things you can look at like the
the precision and recall
this very different measures and we don't really have time to go through all of
them in detail but again this depends on what kind of application you're looking at
what you what you're interested in
you know form
from medical data you're quite often interested in sensitivity and specificity
sensitivity is how many of the true cases
did you
did you manage to find
so that's the number of true positives divided by
true positives plus false negatives
OK the number of positives you've got the actual number of malaria cases you got
divided by the total number of people with malaria came into use your system
so that's the proportion of
actually sick people that you've you've
gone with the system so in in these medical systems are also interesting specificity
and that is
basically saying if you say someone's negative if you say the healthy
what proportion of negatives to you
do you get
and if you've got a hundred percent sensitivity and hundred percent specificity
then you're doing
if there are less than a hundred and you can see
how bad is that you can see how meaningful is for the system to say
positive or negative
OK so it could be different
things you might want to do with negative and positive depending on your application
training and testing is
great if you have
welcome to the
the last morning
c so
well i thought i would do is start it kind of give
quick recap we talked about yesterday morning
and so we we spent
half the time talking about an online learning algorithm and half the time talking about
game theory we talked a little bit about some connections for instance we
we saw how
we can use
the analysis of these online learning algorithms to
the kind of nice
effective proof of minimax theorem
and then we we talked a nash equilibrium of things today we going to do
is talk a little bit more about some some more connections between these two areas
and then the
in the second half today i'm going to talk about single the different about
some work we've been doing on
somewhat different way of thinking about kernel functions and more general similarity functions and how
and why use them
OK so
mean this
so just to do a quick recap so kind we're we're motivated by settings like
this one where you reviewed set of decisions so for me time
the suburbs in the
no longer right here in my work i have to drive to work every day
it's repeated decisions every day and make a decision and
and you don't
but c
and we would like to do
it is
i have some algorithm for making decisions even even though you really don't know what's
going to happen in the future
and we talked about algorithms with a nice property where you can every day and
make it tries to get some feedback to make it tries to find out this
information and
well you'd like to do is have some strategy so that in the long run
you're doing nearly as well or better than the best fixed decision you could have
made in hindsight
so i guess i should should make the point that
so most of machine learning we look at the back we have
imagine some big
collection of data probability distribution of data we get a random sample so if if
we were in that kind of world if we assume that every day with IID
random draw
then you could imagine
a simpler algorithm which would be the way it for a while just take howe's
each thing this record on average how well start after some period of time just
pick the thing is done that's in the past and use that
but we'd like to be able to do that kind of thing without having to
make those assumptions and also to be able to kind of immediately be making decisions
as we go without having to wait until we take data
if you get good statistics
so either because you don't want to wait or because you just don't believe the
statistics are there in the world maybe change
OK so we we talked about album for this
because we had this matrix view of the world
see OK so just to remind some notation can be
some some terminology will be using it so we have this this view that every
you go back
here so
we're doing this is the matrix the weights are algorithm against the world every day
we figure out the work which represents states impact my take every day
life picks column which represents some sort of traffic patterns indicates our cost how much
we would have paid had chosen heathrow and then we had a this entry here
our out on that day and maybe we get the feedback the algorithms we talked
about mostly one slide on bandit model but
most the model we get full feedback to find out how well you would have
done had he made your choices
that that's actually natural learning setting where these might correspond to different prediction rules and
then when the world is you is the the right answer then you can score
for yourself how are you would have that
OK so we're not that kind of you and then we
just our probability distribution over
what rose we plan to select next
we we keep like this
and then we define this notion of regret which was we look at how much
we paid on average per day
we have a set of new wave function
and we read that until convergence of convergence of every every everything for example mean
energy are different metrics elements
when you have something which is will converge
you can calculate all the properties of the nucleus in its ground state so you
have the energy
the state of the nuclear which is of minimal energy so you can calculate all
the mean values values of energy mean but also of the formation
for example you have different people operators
this is the
the scalar quadruple there is also a donation
where is this going on means that the proton and neutron we still
this is said before which are interface
so this is the final that and you can calculate the mean
that's the way we define the shape of the nuclei so here
two remarks first we are dealing with quantum objects so why do we consider shape
i want to answer that because of these mean function so we have
given the time we have
of having the article the nucleons in a given orbital all the articles have different
extensions special extensions so you have to
provided if present of different
nucleons and different orbitals
and this is because of these mean value that we we can say that we
we know the shape of the nuclei of the
i wanted to be calculated in the interesting frame
so of course if you this in the laboratory
you will have a mix of all these different then you have something which is
but the intrinsic friends of friends associated with the need to
it has
and information
if we do that for all the nucleons
you'll find that most of the nuclei are deformed in their ground state
only magic nuclei or nuclear which are close to major city are very cool
so this is plotted here so this is from infinite so hartree fock
speculation proton and neutron
so but i was in fact something related to these q two zero
and you see that
sorry there's a great quote
you've spherical euclidean spherical nuclei
for magic nuclei the other ones are well informed
for example here you see that the opinions are also well different
it is when you are interested in the state
but with this minimisation principle you can also impose some constraints so you can put
external field look at the response of the nuclei
so this is done with a well-known mathematical approaches
is the use of lagrange parameters
so then you have minimization principle
so you don't only
h here but again impose the number of neutrons protons and you can impose some
deformation here
so you start
that these conditions that you have the mean value is something that keep the given
value small q
when you do that
you can obtain what we we call potential care so very famous example insufficient value
so you have here the energy in any loss function of the political information
so you can impose here city and then increase the information here
two here you can even break into two fragments
so you here
the lowest energy state so this is the ground state
so if you do not impose any constraint you we only obtain this
if the constraint you can be from different nations
you see here that you have different values first and second barriers and here
what we call is very well
so it so well where you can have some state inside so it means that
you can have metastable states
in a different way that stable states here
and you will see that they are important for the fission process
now do you know what are the most commonly used constraints because with this approach
is constrained whatever you want
so these are some shapes
this is for example symmetry so this is
not very visible but this is a small fragmented make one
so constrained which is used for example to describe fish as i told you you
have a small fragment the big one
so you need repair ship
in order to to have access to cease shape to these fragmentation was a small
and weak one
so what is for example now the problems with this information
to my mind there are two problems the first one is that it's complicated and
in nature
it's not so complicated so it means that it should be principle associated two
hi interaction
so it will not be so pertinent
so the constraints the
and the deformations which are pertinent to the lowest PCD so the most simplest ones
the other problem with this one that integrates a lot of symmetries
and with this
o point you'll here
setting up UV
it's actually use it
engineer will come in with all the goggles and everything else but once it's actually
an operated you can change from the UV
two near infrared
but really because about
change to neighbours so just go through
this is a class one legion closure but it can be doesn't have to be
a safety interlock automatic alignment with optimisation and to get this wavelength optimisation what we've
in the spectrometer box
his remains the pass on
the original roman institute a single delivery path and that was always compromising lasers because
if you want to work in the u v
you would need one man said
and if you wanted to work in the infrared union other
so what we've done here is we optimized parkland and one for u v
one for visible and one for the infrared that is in all the instruments standard
now that means that your optimizing the delivery path
with this option you then optimize the roman going back through is always the same
so you only a single path going back to this
we have an option here to put out the fault with a fibre-optic probe just
plug in the india and you can then other remote sensor
that you see has advantages when it comes to attaching
to other pieces of equipment
high precision creating stage or to focus or to convert galaxy or to reveal insights
a selection
and basically everything in here is also validated and you can actually just check it
out so if someone misaligned
you just go back into the software back to default position
you buy it was running it may not be running perfectly but at least you
are run
to enable will go here o back
and technology
so this is the five problem
you put objective and here the set fire and optical fibre here the reason accessories
since sky
scanning electron microscope combined
for FTIR
combined effect and some of these are standard probes which you can use remote sensing
you put these into beamlines all sorts of things about high-pressure reactor vessel plasmas plasma
jewish you can take
the fiber to that under the what the
gives huge flexibility mika sampling again you put a an achromatic lens on the is
big bold if you wish to temperature control sales of coal sales because peacock also
liquid nitrogen and liquid helium temperature experiments you can do
using this material
we have some databases polarization you can actually set up before i change the polarization
laser depolarized always polarized raman depolarized around so if you look in crystallography
you can do all of these things and study crystal get what some information
and chemistry in high-pressure sales again
all available
and i think the important thing here is a flat flexible object path
the whole system is modular
you can buy the original
basic instrument
and all the time
i build the tower
to do all the other application and this is the same with the
if the same sky the family and some by the
and then
by urine samples or if you've got lots of money can buy it all together
it's target
this is done
because we know
using our own software
the software runs the control runs all electronics
does all the mapping has all the standard programming algorithms that the processing algorithms if
you want to do something special with your data
you can export it out and run in the program so that is all built
in an always part of the
this is the this twenty one CFR part eleven is purely for the pharmaceutical people
i'm going to talk about the nanoscale raman developments and i thank my colleague matthew
all this what i am very fast i don't need to do the work i
just presented which means i don't always understand everything that's going on but i freely
admit that but i'm
so that that this what what is a highly specialized why would you use EFM
well the main reason is if you're looking for things like
quantum dots
trying to find the
is the most difficult part
if you look in nanomaterials finding the material you want analyse is the hard part
so if you do this you have to use a another technique for you just
take a sample scan over until you get around p i hope like hell you've
the response to have to be
normal service so we had we had that been
plus an excellent
so the here
we had
which is well
forces the
well and generalized linear models we don't have to have an epsilon is normally distributed
we can have all the distributions not all things like the binomial in the past
on that were in
the nice thing about this is that
though is interesting solve you do you if i do this with a piece of
paper you don't need a computer this
or held for patients
in general nice reliable algorithm for fitting this model for estimating the basis so that's
what we like
and it's also expands the range of what we can do quite a long way
so small
and the most recent sort of expansion through this idea is was called generalized additive
which is exactly the same thing as before except
this is having
despite his being beaten times
this is a function of x
and the function of x
usually the what are called lines
and that allows to get
things that have local properties to model so here's an example of one of them
is the trend in this is affected by having
continuous so looks used what in fact it's only smooth
so it's smooth
the second derivative
continuous points the derivatives is a set of
piecewise cubic foot
so that's
allows it things like follow the the result plot here
rather than
have to keep going because it has a particular
so those
the main areas in ireland
this part of the world i suppose statistics
we can say
o model is generalized additive model fairly easily if future
use of the car do it trivially for your problem at the moment is we
don't really know
again what the statistical
all of these models so that's the current research area statistics
so we've got all those things i will come back then too
the linear model and how do we choose which pages are there and how to
estimate which beta
so what is it well that's about do estimation is we have a method to
much like
fifty years it's until fifty years ago fifty years ago
i went out into the field
other terms with lots set of
from agriculture applied statistics and we harvest it's
those was the statistics class are harvested
what the
the idea is
but when i got short story obviously twenty four kilogrammes it and it's not the
sole here is an experiment
and what we try to find out more
we these are output
so so i
this is the output we have sixty four
observations of the output gap is the beyond that of
a plot of land three meters by two meters
so the experiment the design fairly carefully
what we have here
it is
observations that
that corresponds to the type of users come back we
so the sea
on the twenty eighth of august so the twenty first of august nineteen ninety eight
we apply
this is a writer one kilogram per hectare and for that with these four
lots of land
so those are put through by two main bottles and those deals out and kill
killing in kilograms
and that's what we are
the columns signify
is that this one piece of land this these plots were almost killed in contiguous
block one and this somewhere else and these somewhere else somewhere else
and the point is that there are different positions relative to the root
and the ricci flow to the field so what we're expecting is that these
four places will have different
so some the characteristics basically
what we're interested in
if the effects of these these call frequencies the things that we can control this
is just
and after the feeling that we the cropping
scientific purposes
what know what the effect of this on the to turn it really bothered about
because nobody else has this field
this is a picture of the things that we throughout the experiment and to generalize
other people going to somewhere else
this doesn't help is very much what we would like to say about the operation
right OK so
so that we have
the axes the inputs will correspond to
the difference at the turn it back into market the difference only based on the
so in densities
we have labels for sixteen different combinations and the remember my is OK
his model we we might use to describe that
we are yield as a weight
as equal to some constant
beta times
that's be general so what is the
if j
if you want to receive treatment b
so that is
if what
j was the
so girls and boys would try to meet their
future husband-and-wife through internet and the idea was can we propose better beatings between based
on profiles of of the people
and that was quite an interesting application
there was an application for construction projects and there was very interesting application for the
european commission
in which we have analysed all the IST projects which were funded by the european
commission in the previous framework programme and the idea was to try to better understand
where the large amount of
the money went to do so we were using text mining and web mining
in order to analyse this data and i will illustrate this application as well
so starting with the mean media application
especially for the people from statistics you are very well aware of questioners doing analysis
of questions with statistical methods here we started with the questioners
about people
reading habits and habits of watching TV programs listening to the radio programs and this
is for a number of years medium has been collecting such information and there was
extensive questionnaire so it doesn't hundred questions obviously not all the questions were given to
people because they died on something so many questions but by answering the question then
you have automatically as a couple of others is still it's quite laborious process students
go to
two home
ask people about their habits
and did the results of these analyses are
then published in your publication it's basically the basic statistics about frequencies of reading listening
watching different TV programs and then distributions with respect to sex age education buying habits
and so on and so on so we tried to
an alternative analysis the for this we got eight thousand questionnaires
this was data for the year nineteen ninety eight and that was about lifestyle space
time activities personal viewpoints reading listening watching of media
and so on so it was very good quality data obviously the professionals have collected
and also it was cleaned before we got it so the medium itself cleans the
data so it was extremely good quality data so we didn't have to bother about
noise elimination missing data and things like that so basically we got
table of on top of
which in each row corresponds to one person who was answering his questions one individual
and the columns were about the attributes of about lifestyle the spare time activities and
so on
for classification purposes we needed to
select one attributes which was the target attribute for classification
and then after having done this data preprocessing then we did data mining and here
we are free to choose what data mining task
perform because the client omidyar didn't give us any
specific requests in advance so we decided to answer some questions like which journals
all magazines are read by the readers of another journal
what are the properties of individuals that are consumers of particular media offer and which
properties of distinctive for users of different channels
it was this figure explains two things number one you can predict the entries that
you have not seen very well but on top of it of course you removed
all of the nodes of the entries that you've seen because initially y minus and
divided by m squared on the visible set will be wanting to the noise power
so you reduce the noise level
by a factor twenty in the entries that you've seen
and you correct you print correctly predict all the answers
we've seen this was done experiments which is
was real datasets so we took a data set
that have temperatures
fourteen seventy two locations around the world
in two thousand eight so it's
what we have forty two for about fifteen hundred locations about three hundred and sixty
six days because o easily peer
and what we did is we we held seventy percent of the entries
and then
run this algorithm on only thirty percent to try to predict the entries that we
have not seen
and when we do is this
we see that the errors very very little
that is the
the relative error between the truth and the recovery
is roughly three percent accurate
OK and it's the reason it works very well it's because this matrix of temperature
data has very low rank since if i look at the best rank two approximation
that i can compute by looking at all of the entries
i would say that you know the relative error is about one point five percent
because this is is a low rank matrix and not surprisingly
we can actually
completed very very well
what i'd like to talk about now in the last
ten minutes some computational aspects it is
OK so now we have to deal with very large matrices we have to solve
this optimisation problem and how it can this
so i claim that it's a semidefinite programme therefore we all right and when i
say this is of course i'm lying
because it is not true that off the shelf semidefinite programming solvers as sdpt three
or c do me
can solve problems are very large size like this in fact if you use off
the shelf algorithms and you
see them with matrix completion problem they will choke
when n is about one hundred
OK then you can try to customize interior point methods but they won't do much
so it's extremely problematic because it means that if i want to use customized
optimisation packages that can complete matrices
one hundred by one hundred we very far from one thousand by one thousand thirty
thousand by thirty thousand or even the netflix size
so what i'd like to introduce is a very simple algorithm
that will
so nuclear norm minimisation problem
subject to convex constraints which is very
simple algorithm that happens to be
extremely efficient when the optimal solution has low rank
when the optimal solution does not have the the right may not be a very
good outcome
so i would like to explain these are gruesome in the limited setting of the
matrix completion problem which
i will recast as it is
so we want to minimize the nuclear norm subjective data constraints
so now i'm going to look at it explains the data comes cassidy data constraint
simply the projection of x onto the feasible set has to matter the projection of
a onto the feasible sets and what is p omega
well omega of x is essentially leaving the entries of x intact if they've been
observed and otherwise set centers
so it's a projection on to the locations that i have seen
OK so we want to solve this problem
OK so
this algorithm is very simple and what it does is it uses as the key
what we call singular value thresholding
so it's a nonlinear operation about the matrix to nonlinear transformation of the matrix that
goes like this
given a matrix x and i can compute its SVD just like this
and i'm going to introduce the frank
of x the depends on the parameter tau
it's a very simple thing
what i do is give me the matrix are right out this a singular value
and i push its singular values towards zero
by an amount which is
essentially the shrinkage parameter top
so what i do is i just compute the SVD and i reduce the singular
values by tau
of course making sure that they don't become negative
OK so
so i compute singular values and a decrease their values by tau
and if this becomes negative i decided to zero
more prosaically what i'm doing is if you're familiar with soft thresholding what i'm doing
is applied soft thresholding to the singular value
and of course this will reduce the rank of the matrix it is he will
not increase it
because of course
it will it can only reduce the rank in fact it will reduce the rank
tremendously if in a lot of singular values happen to be below the threshold tau
because then will just add them to c and a lot of singular values will
and now
the algorithm
is very very simple
you fixed parameter tau
and the sequence of positive steps times delta k
you start with an auxiliary matrix y zero which is equal to zero and you
go through this very simple iterations
we're going to take like a minus one and shrink its singular values at the
level tau
and then you can update y
so update y as y k equals the previous value of y
plus the step size times the projection of minus exc
and that's the algorithm
so this is simply the arteries image can be coded
five matlab lines and it's just right there
and these are in was inspired by recent work in l one minimisation in the
area of compressed sensing
and essentially by the work of stan sure and his colleagues at UCLA but
this is
algorithm so basically all the computational cost is here
the computational cost is to apply the shrinkage operator to y
several times
because this update is absolutely trivial
and that made s three VM which is this line
for the good
but finally let's look at the graph based method
and in the graph based method you have all these
data points one dimensions
and to the graph you will create
simply going to be a graph that connects all those points
one day
again we have some mismatch here
because there is no
well separated components
so when you do
graph based method it's going to propagate labels
as you can see the
this line the same
black line
actually always
farther away from the
supervised learning decision boundary so in the end it has a larger
error than supervised learning
so this is this example simply says again that it's very important
to get the correct assumption for some supervised learning and when the assumption is wrong
when it doesn't fit
your data set than the performance can be really bad
so this leads to the natural question how can we quantify this notion that
the assumption is correct or wrong
are there any theory behind this
so we will discuss
very simple version of
pac learning theory originally by balcan and blum
attempts to quantify the contribution of unlabelled data
so we will give a really quick review of a learning theory
OK so let's first go back to supervised
now in supervised learning you have this
labelled data let's call it the better training set
you have our labelled data points there are sampled i i d from some unknown
joint distribution p
you also have a family of functions that you want to pick things from for
example the family big as can be all linear functions
the way we're going to
two training in an abstract abstract sense is to say that we're going to find
the function small as within this big from function family
such that small has zero training
so this is yehat
of a function as is simply the training error so this is a boolean expressions
are one good to that's the training
OK so we assume that the training goes as follows you give me
the training set the samples from the unknown p distribution
i search through big ass and find a small as
that has zero training
and i want to see how well this small as forms
the quantity and really interested being is
the generalisation performance or the performance of future test data
of my function as an in here i give it the subscript the because my
f is picked
using the training set
so this he has no hat
that's the true error
it's defined as the expectation where you sample your test points from the on p
and this is simply how many of the error rate
can we say anything about
it's future test error
the big problem here is i do not know p
right so
we cannot directly
compute this quantity
but it turns out
even though i cannot give it a precise number i can bond
the value of this e
without knowing pl
here's how it goes
so first notice that
function that i picked as subscript d
is a random variable
is the venerable in the sense that
my training set these random so if you give me around the i have a
after a
so it's a random variable
with respect to random draws of my training set
this is a random variable therefore
there is a p although i do not know it's OK so
for any function
it's true error he is actually fixed
and in this case so i just don't know it but it's a fixed quantity
so i can look at the event
classifier as the
i train right selected
larger true error then absolutely
that's going to be around the event that depends on my random draw of
the training set
so this is a random boolean event
either happens or it doesn't have
so absent some fixed threshold
just this next part now take this too
really to the results
based on the goal line
in terms of slide
slide numbers aligned
in my numbering i did so i been adding some stuff and changing it and
i'm really grateful to you all for not hang on didnt say exactly that but
maybe i haven't had time to sort of harbor across
i also saw that the printed six lots the pages across to achieve
is that someone shares
well thank you sure look like not lies like me because i couldn't
but sorry for forgetting to here about sixty just just around sixty slides inside fifty
four so
we be done in the y just keep talking and mining up will just
go through its twenty past three will just go through the it after four down
one stop that's OK with everyone
this course it's OK
but nevertheless this is sort of the the
the point of the whole set of lectures
so if you could pay attention to this part the grateful officially
i think are all
and i didn't want to be talking about this at two o'clock is at least
data after lunch
he gets as part of this thing would have to go find it's not like
but all the
all right
well so
what happens with kernel memory where do we go from here that something on this
and work with the with the concept
we saw two
not going really YSL's about whether
well was that successor apostrophe who was
talk about that on this page
o yeah right structure the successor and
yeah that's right so
yes i think you right the intention there would be not to have the eleventh
variable would have
would be indicated by x with eleven
posture is after
thank you that's that's what makes it
and the actual successor function
it's the it's
all right
this is the next piece of work that you have to do which we don't
keep saying the popular
we have to set up some stuff
as a rita to being out for something more things and show that we dance
we've actually simulate the operations of the formal system inside of arithmetic or something like
so we agreed now the
that phi has neural kernel number
OK which are now use that terminology left and right corners
it has a numeral corresponding to its what the actual number whenever i choose to
go abroad
i think that's the rule
a turing machine
can calculate whether some particular numbers the kernel not expression
i suppose that was kind of like my hands
in the previous lecture
because it's unique and depending on the coding scheme we've chosen whether it's the original
colonel one in terms of prime decomposition
whether it's the clear the last one in terms of
strange sequences of digits
we could easily we can effectively figure out
whether something or other is the kernel number and expression
it also turns out
on display solution to you
that recursive functions can now be defined formally
in these terms
because of that equivalence thing
we took just went through
cherishing can
we can find a recursive function
what is that recursive function when talking about to know what it is we just
started day
and we're also going to need to be either
the idea
of substituting
attorney four
four four formula
my on my have free very
so applying value to function
that function is to be defined and it turns out that we can because that's
it decidable thing
inside formal languages
and we normally teachers who teaching formal logic some kind of pressure
just say
o like k which is going to take this formula
got constant i so we're just going to substitute achieve i
and of course there are some complications in this is exhibited right inside something
but of course to be official we need to
actually formalize the notion of substitution which we do as well
and here
what we're saying is that we can also define recursive function
to do that substitution
for the functions
then now getting to
we can define a predicate in
now formal system
not exhibiting that definition
we can define a predicate
and probability
he says that
let's see
the formula the intention this
so it's not
well on the next page so i posted to do
the provability predicate there
so the
it's the formula
is provable
in some language or other
in that same language
looked at all to prove
sure i get this right
for some close to
in fact he will turn out to be the goal number of this generation
OK so provability
is a predicate which says
it's got two numbers as arguments to actually two numerals and formal systems got two
numbers arguments
and it's true
in the full system
just in case
the formula five was proved by
the derivation that have ended up being cut is t
so we just simulating all this activity
that we normally do externally with learning logic courses in
great to see
now it's not not fact it's crucial it isn't yet
now i'm just saying
yes that's right
that's right i haven't heard anything about
not that provable i said is that there is an encoding
and the pos and the definition of predicate possible
OK because it's the function can be done is recursive functions
it can be embedded in first order logic
you will have just this effect
it's the
that's the special effect of this function
so defined inside this rich
formal language
has the five times higher probability to be scattered then the red light
and this
hold as long as the
particles of which the radiation scanners
are smaller than the wavelength of light typically a few tens of micro
so then we have really scared and then we have the dependence on
wavelengths to the depart four
if the particles grow in size this dependence weakness weakens
and then the difference between the red and the blue becomes less
and by the time you read five microns
particles of heaviside size of five microns and ten microns then the probability is the
same for all callers
and that's what i
i would like to demonstrate to you
very shortly
there is an extra bonus
any extra bonuses
it's not so intuitive but i will convince you of that
that's radiation that was carried over ninety degrees becomes
linearly polarized hundred percent on polarized radiation comes in
you are scatterers
light goes off and all their actions but goes off at ninety degrees
is hundred percent
linearly polarized i'll first convince you of that and then i will do demonstration
that shows that indeed it is linearly polarized that's why i wanted you to bring
your policies
see radiation coming from this site
and he uses electron that starts to shake
and if you have very small particles
one turns into tens of icons the electrons in those particles will begin to shape
and so this electron start to shake up and down and the electric field must
in the plane of are an
look very carefully
this electric field is indeed in the plane of are
and a this electric field is in the plane of are in a this electric
field is in the plane of our in a
so this is the direction
oscillation of if you
the direction of data zero there is no radiation going because the acceleration is like
this and if you go off at a different angle than the electric vector also
laid perpendicular to its direction of propagation
why now
is radiation hundred percent polarized
if it's carries over
ninety degrees
this have been of unpolarized radiation that comes to you
linearly polarized light comes to you
she she she she there is
the next wave
and the next word in the next race in the next wave and the next
word recall the unpolarized light
one comes in like this the next one comes in like this one comes in
like this one called the unpolarized light
you are looking here in the blackboard
at this radiation and their scanners
dust very fine dust
and so some life comes through
angle is ninety degrees right
because it came like this
now does this the whole board ninety degrees someone who is here
also ninety degrees
what is the direction of factor
when this life which is why i
is in the plane of a or
that means it must be in the record
the vector is in the plane of acceleration this accelerat issues like this that's the
plane of the blackboard this acceleration is like this and are is also in the
black or so sony vector must be in the plane of the record
but it must also be perpendicular to are so it must also like this and
also like like this and if you look here
it was also made like this
so when you look at scatterplots on the ninety degrees if it is
rayleigh scattering
you will see that the radiation is hundred percent linearly or
an amazing thing
and that's my goal
to demonstrate this to you now
he was a very dramatic experiment
which i put my house on the line
i'm going to to smoke a cigarette
and i advise you not to
and and this is work in a similar they have the signatures fall
computer takes the role so far
but obvious
this advantage of this system is every time a new have new attack
there is a delay in detecting these attacks have to go to the website and
all this the signature to take this computer intrusion and then you can take so
basically this systems are incapable of taking a new and emerging
hope attracts
and anomaly detection can be extremely important here because they can do this
OK i didn't mention briefly about for detection
so you made a deal with different kinds of fruits as i mentioned credit card
fraud some people trying to steal credit card and using music to buy something on
this typical and
it insurance claim you may claim two
lots of the people still something real but that's not actually the case or mobile
cell phone fraud fraud if you lose the cell phone in someone outside you use
that instead of
and in this case most of the time you can temporal data and you will
have to deal with fast and accurate real time detection so basically here data streams
not occurring at
regular uniform intervals so they occur every time a new kind transactions or something that
happened for especially in credit card transactions and then have to react fast because you
have to stop
fraudulent transaction
and to misclassification cost is very high
if so if you don't say something is intrusion you may actually the for example
company may lose a lot of money
in the healthcare informatics you may deal with
different problems for example if analyzing certain disease
anomalies may represent disease outbreaks for example that certain
the disease can happen sort of area
if you're dealing with for example people who have certain types of cancer
using anomaly detection you may
the take this cancer in advance or at least eight so and then you can
save lives
and usually in this case only normal data is available
very few instances of
class all of this can be available and in this case misclassification cost is very
high for example if you miss the fact that the cancer you lose the personal
life that's that's
really expensive and
the data can be quite complex depending on the problem for example in the case
of disease outbreak
they may be both spatial and temporal
i mentioned earlier that are extremely important problems in industrial damage detection in decision involved
engineering health applications
so many companies are starting to apply different data mining techniques
to help there
physical bayes model techniques to detect certain failures in that way
so they figure out that physical based models are not sufficient
to explain and describe the complex
engineering systems and then the data driven techniques may help them
so typical example is active
the safety and reserve
recent efforts from the mess they basically they try to use different data driven techniques
to detect anomalies from the flight record data so
the idea is to analyse the data from the flights during the flight
and then if anything unusual and happen you may give the signal to the pilot
the centre and say there is probably
robert full some so
this is also very important for aviation safety
and it can also save many many lives
however there are many challenges in his gate data since you're getting the data from
different types of sensors
they may may be extremely huge
can be extremely noisy
because you're mixing you know all different types of sensors some of some of the
more reliable so not
and most of the time the data is not available at all series you don't
know what is normally aut one
most of the applications because you're collecting this online here temporal became also have to
consider different sequential temporal anomaly detection techniques
and detecting anomalous events require usually immediate intervention
and again the course here is extremely high because mister take this
so certainly in this silly correspond to failure
in this case of patient safety males used hundreds of life
i mentioned that people tried to use recently different anomaly detection techniques in image processing
video surveillance
as you know we have more and more cameras everywhere so they called us if
you go to their political that's difficult to store called us
so people used to analyse this videos and images to detect some suspicious events and
to the thank you for that for example if an airport
people try to take this kind of some eleven package that's also very important for
the train stations and so on so using anomaly detection techniques can be
here very very important
and again there some key challenges
you have to take this collective anomalies from the previous case because you have to
put in the context of different pieces what can be normal what can be done
only in specific situations
and data sets can be extremely huge and you have to convert to the raw
image and video data into the data format is appropriate
to use the anomaly detection
OK so this is a taxonomy
not technically that is also published in this way our group
so we try to
and i mean by divided by the sum of all the viruses
if we put it should be what to not do point nine we mean that
we explain the ninety percent of the variance of the data by keeping all the
first k eigenvectors
PCA being used a lot for dimensionality reduction
but for many problems maybe not a good idea for example one two
two to reduce the dimensionality of our data for classification by
you can see from the features that if you want
project i would out in the in the direction
one of the principal component but they are not overlapped
if we find all
way to protect our for example
although using a linear discriminant analysis i wanted to was so the
so on
also featured not only discriminant analysis can be used
two o
other dimensionality reduction technique with this time
the max v v
vector of
the product of the government that i introduced before
it is quite
all this time discussion in computer vision a lot of people and we use the
PCA for dimensionality reduction as a preprocessing step of the things that is similar
it contains two
it's not the it's better to keep in mind
practical issues
i mean when i say that the more he becomes disconnected pieces
you know that alyson not well characterized so it's better to use
he said when the number of samples now we can get good
bishop of
i they that did not representative for the class and we can use linear discriminant
analysis to perform dimensionality reduction
what if we have two daughters
we want to find related direction on
to be that
and there are many applications where we need to do that like for example where
we want to do because language retrieval of documents and we have english and french
want to discover the relationship between them but we have images and captions as short
in the introduction
or for example when want to the speaker recognition and we have some i do
that is that the reason that for example movement
what we can do
we can use a few years of like inviting problems for example we can use
the principal component analysis on the joint that dataset the joint that is created
by the two people that is why
we can maximize by by fashion
o we can maximize the correlation between the two datasets by canonical correlation analysis
the same problem of principal component analysis that we saw before but i plug
or they
together or x and y is for datasets
and so
we have exactly the same problem as before the metric the objective function is made
by covariance matrices and the cross covariance matrices
all of the other
we want to compute the optimal projection wx and WY in order to maximize the
value of the joint the set
we can do the same thing you computing the ground but in the end you
get that again via problem exactly as before
and so it is given by the problem
the good news is that this article is essentially independent of it is been applied
the technique could be to maximize the covariance between projections
in this case we can solve the issue
if we think
this can can also see that this optimisation problem
up and down
and even they we've learned we mean that the solution to the same up to
to constant factors
it's also we went to the following problem and maybe
more he easy to
so to see all to sort of computer programs and again we
so what is a good idea and the have wx and WY equal to zero
and what we get is again and again by the problem
the last thing about the problem is canonical correlation analysis
we are maximising the correlation assuming the variance is irrelevant to cfd
what does it mean that time
an answer
give you an answer in the limit of so the complexity here is well technically
speaking after run this are going on forever
but you know in practice we do everything the finite precision arithmetic anyway so even
the most beautiful algorithms that converge in a finite number of iterations are subject a
small errors themselves and so to be honest when when you get within some small
abseil on the right answer he should be allowed to shut this down and say
i know there are and there would be just as good
but it's hard to know
how many iterations this you need to do
guarantee that you within some given a priority estimate epsilon
so that's the upside and the downside it's easy
each step is a regression problem you're just do this is called
iteratively reweighted least squares because each of these calculations is solving a least square weighted
least squares problem where the weights depend on your current estimate
and they just keep reweighting as you go
and you can prove that that this is convergent
fairly generally
but it's not linear programming and so i won't dwell on this algorithm
i'd rather go to the linear programming over them
all right
how do we model this as a linear programming problem
well just like the one before with are with structure and the hang weights wi absolute values here
end i has do a slightly different track but the
the takeaway messages whenever absolute values you should say yourself
i can probably make this a linear programming problem
here's the trick here is similar but different in the details
if you look at this thing
and i started calculus
end i would
teach methods and integration
and one amendments methods integration over time my students
use the greedy substitution
which means by which i meant
take the only is that you can find in the problem and give it a new variable name
and substituted out so and that's exactly what we do here
the analyst thing for us is this
the absolute values of this thing
so give it a name
we have a bunch these absolute values there indexed by and so a new variable
tiai i for everyone is absolute values
now i would like to say that he i is equal to
be absolute value of this difference
that's the truth
ti i should be equal to the set but now i'm going
be a little bit clever like we were a little bit clever
before with the absolute values
end say okay
that's would be good to write equals absolute value because they
haven't made things better but how about if i say look if ti i is greater than the absolute value
if ti i is bigger than or equal to the absolute value than ti i
would be bigger than this expression
negativity i would be less than this expression because
we want squeeze on both sides
and there will be true if t e i is bigger than the absolute value
the relaxation is okay
because i'm trying to minimize the sum that he is
and so i'll never leave
slack again it's the same idea never leaves slack
in both of these inequalities
if i didn't have slackened bottles inequalities that ti i wouldn't be the absolute value
would be bigger than the absolute value of poland and tight in every case
in cases where this is positive i wanna pull it tight on the right in
cases where this is negative and important tight on the left and leave no slack
on one of the two sides
and because i minimizing i will never leave slack on both sides and therefore
after mality eyes will be the absolute values
so it's essentially the same trick i showed you before r
and that's a linear programming problem
we can solve it
the simplex methods one
here's now here's another example model why not just spend a few minutes on it
this is the informalformal you
we least absolute deviations regression
so we've got to parameters and mendoza the site does give us the size of the matrix so
i've got a set of i have indices by indices
i don't have to write it this way
but anyway
i goes from one them jay goes from one then
and then
then they matrix is that is a matrix whose two-dimensional so indexed by isin jay-z i come jay
data be
the pages of canine hurt
which were registered together to compensate for the loss of the difference in the different
and the goal here was to try to investigate what is the viability
of the fiber orientation
so the main the first eigenvalue of the covariance matrix of the times
here's the orientation and the second order
the second eigenvector is related to the sheet in the structure
and this is this is the result of the statistical analysis and basically
so using
the fine environment and what we can show that basically this is a
the variance is very low almost everywhere which means that the the structure of the
poem is
in this case
so this means that
we can use such among the mean
and so as a model to simulate you have
a second
example of statistics on on an atomic objects
is given with the work of that on on
spines and it's basically
the idea is to study the formation of scoring it explains
so what we did is modeled the spine is an articulated object and so the
degrees of freedom of the pose related portals of successive that address
and if we are doing
statistical analyses computing the mean and the currents metrics on the whole
articulated model which is a
kind of factor of seventeen rigid body transformations we can extract the for for small
the variation and we can see here the full for small from
in front of you and that's you
and what is interesting is that the full
we were able to show that the full first small are related with the clinical
so it's a case where
using the right model
two tomorrow to which is which is geometric which is intrinsically in romanian manifold is
giving the right way to model
the and that
OK so let's go to the second part of the top which is now how
to work with
manifold valued images
but ground with with example so images
so we have seen
the geodesic interpolation so the interpolation between two values
now what we need to work on images is by no it right now
sinc interpolation
so how can we do that
well what we can do is
rephrased the
interpolation in terms of weighted means and this is usually what is done i actually
by no interpretation
the way to the well the the mean of the full
the value of the different colors weighted by the training they all all by weights
so if we are doing that the value of each at each point here is
obtained by the minimisation of this function
one thing that i did said
and this is too uncertain
thirty two but was concerned about the exact closed form
is that we have a very
efficient algorithm to compute the mean in any type of money manifold which is a
goes into
and which is usually converging in five to ten iteration to the numerical accuracy of
the machine so this is not something which is
i mean it's taking more time than the closed form
but not so much
so we can compute weighted means
the cost of ten times let's say ten iterations at each point and this is
the example
interoperation between these four concerts is euclidean interpolation between the coefficients
and this is the using the fine environment
so how do know
that we have a weighted mean
well we can try to use that tool to generalise to other types of algorithms
like point of course motion forcing
which is nothing that
a weighted mean
with caution weight
so this is the way we can do
gulshan missing this is this type of thing
we can go also for harmonic regularisation so in that case there is something that
happens at that
since we are working on the manifold
one derivative of this
the tree is the manifold laplacian which takes into account the curvature of the manifold
but there is one very interesting things in the exponential map remember i said this
expansion that is the basic tool
it is actually well
curvature geodesics
along the geodesics in that direction is new
so this is the
thanks to this property
this numerical scheme which is basically
how to compute the
one of the laplacian in the
in the exponential map is intrinsically taking into account the curvature of the money
which means that we have a numerical scheme which is very simple
to compute
the derivative of the child and we can
try to make it more
with the gradient descent
and this can be
then we generalised to anisotropic filtering
so here's an example
this is the raw image so this is around the particles so here you can
see that there are
a set of tensors which are
very well actually there is attract going around
so but there is also some some big errors some point so we want to
regularize that
if we take gulshan schmoozing then there are is there is some
fx which is not very one
what we won the big ten cells are taking over the small ones
before using the cautions was singing in the romanian setting then it's already better and
if we're taking the anisotropic filtering
then we can consider
the boundaries between different types of
regions a particular we can conserve some very fine details here
in the
the image
so this is
to show that we can utilize many different algorithms
on manifold well the the ideas
we also need to estimate the time since we just i mean the estimation of
what will happen to your covariance matrix
if the data
lives in the manifold
inside your space so you have the ten thousand dimensional space OK
but actually
the data for has the shape of some sort of
flying so span whatever it is it really only spans
a submanifold of dimension
twenty it's a what happens to your covariance matrix when you try to feed goes
into that
so the covariance matrix of size one thousand times a thousand right
now what happens to it
is offering
so what is it going to have
ranked twenty
now can you invert that things
cameron invertebrates
OK so what factor analysis does is it finds a way around of parliament rising
covariance matrices in a clever way
OK and then you can still throw girls and it
so how do we do it
this is how it sounds
the data we observe so now we need to be a little bit careful about
the x and y is not really matters so it's otherwise this is data space
this is your to capture the now is going to be
a thousand OK
and and twenty
k is going to be twenty
so captain k is really the size of the dimension of the space that is
the that sort of contains the data OK is your little pancake living in this
big space
OK so now
what you do is
you pose before only the following generative model you sort of say
the way
the data was generated actually
it is i had a thousand linear models
each of them
the inputs that live in a much smaller space of dimension only twenty
and as a
and actually
i'm also going to impose that this sources or or factors if you will
hence the name
this twenty factors they are independent
factors OK is zero mean and variance one
and now
what i do is
i take
let let d
just pick one of the thousand dimensions let's speak dimension
forty three
you can sort of see that i have a vector that is of size
twenty is the weight vector that that multiplies all of the sources and spits out
the value of the of dimension forty three my high dimensional space OK so have
this thousand this battery of of linear models
i remember is about how the graph where
weather data would appear here again who was like an autoencoder with with the bottleneck
and so there's been a beautiful stuff done in neural nets
many years ago in this in this sense here here we just take
the bit that that sort of generous the data OK
so you can see where the compression is going to come from
the compression comes from the fact
but i don't think there are so many degrees of freedom out their generating my
my data might look as if it's a thousand dimensional but actually there was only
random sources generating the data
one very cool thing about factorizes is that
it also says that
it also allows for modeling independent noise OK this one is really independent all the
so i have a little little random number here
and that's going to be
random noise so this this matrix
has size
a thousand times a thousand and its diagonal OK because all these noise terms are
all right so basically what i'm saying is
but actually
module on noise
my data lives only in a twenty dimensional space but actually also allowing for noise
all right
so it might seem might seem as it might even seem as as if the
data was actually feeling the space
but actually there might only be twenty sources of correlation
and the correlations that i'm interested in
i'm not so interested in noise
and this afternoon
will do an example with the
with the mnist digits
where will take we compute principal components and then we'll start to add noise and
see what happens to PCA if you start adding a lot of noise in particular
you can think about it over lunch what happens
PCA if i just take one of the pixels of the images and i had
tons of noise to it
OK just a single pixel and then to compute PCA
and for some reason i only want to keep the two principal components so one
of them is going to be a bit screwed right
and and factor analysis is gonna is going to be
perfectly resistant to that
so how how does my model look like now OK
i think everything is equations in next slide so we can safely move on to
let's let's try to try to understand how
this factory capital a little bit
we have this linear model so now
now i just used
matrices and vectors
because it's more convenient OK
we have all this collection of vectors that live in the big
captain d dimensional space we have
factors are sources that leaving the
capital k dimensional space which is smaller than
and the
i take
and zero one
priors of the axis so now
i guess
actually it's a pity that i'm showing this equation i would like to ask you
to compute the covariance of y
but since we did earlier
now we all know how to do it OK
you can sort of see that if i the the quantity that i'm really interested
in is what what distribution have i now defined over the data right
and you can see that you could you could compute it straight from here right
we know we have prior x and we have a prior over
the noise term and they both have zero mean so the mean is going to
be zero for that reason and i only have to compute the covariance but now
you all know how to compute covariances i take expectation of y times its transpose
and that may be and that gives me
the covariance matrix so you can now see
we're still going to use the multivariate gaussian to model our data but it just
has more interesting covariance matrix
if you have any questions comments or anything
one more
it's it's an interesting covariance matrix because it's gonna concentrate on modeling a number of