OK so now we have these
i suppose q r so are
formulation we use a vector and matrix formulation instead of summations
and this is really much of
but there's also linear term has been used to you
we also that
in two days
but if you look at these
so if you
if you move w into this position will not be here
so this is what is is is an agent of what exactly what was it
this is not about
so what you have this relationship as you are minus
my so you might start by transport stop
he held that stop minus the the whole that transport that so hard his minus
miners help that transport system so this is a new hundred
but we also have a linear content
this one is minus one minus summation so we have the summation of miners mines
becomes class therefore
we have is some mention of five minus the some
so this is already very close
two our new optimization problems is remember we are doing maximisation here
so if you reverse it to minimisation
then that's already held times up transpose q of minus some up really our the
objective function of doing that we mention earlier so we almost
so we still have to situations that
well it was it was easier or what is the sum is not zero
the tree using doing this
maximisation is where you believe maximisation right
then you can see that all different kinds of off
labour force another they give you
objective minus infinity
maximisation so of course i was thinking there can never be your optimum objective
the other thing is that that you do with the maximisation so of course minus
infinity then it is not maximum over do
so that means
do optimum solution does not have which is something why principles have is zero
therefore we only have two
so we don't have to consider the situation at all
we have to consider the situation we see the first situation
you will be considered for this you becomes a kind of conditions so that we
can strengthen over to do
so we moved these to be
the constraints of these
i optimisation problem so we so writing these and also have greater or equal to
zero then
we have to deal with constraints
and then we this maximisation with this is the same as the object the objective
function that we mention already city already to do we get
so this is the typical way of deriving the dual problem we want say i
want to mention here is
but if you look at some papers
little use bill is a bill exactly the same way as i using here
two weeks
two explain that something quite in the dual problem is what principles are much should
be easier for some people this
so the the lagrangian function
they know that they're going to minimize with respect to w and b so the
partial derivative with respect to w and also be
just like we do
we took down here so
they just show color the derivative with respect to be the linear ten meters
the these the
this these this is the linear tend to be
so if the partial derivative you get some measure of i y and it is
the oldest for that to be easier well that's not me
right the following these these these derivations you can do that and the reason is
because of this i mean if really is this is not the venue to minus
infinity and later we have minus infinity is is not going to be looking at
the problem do therefore it is not considered
because two partial derivative you need to have a strictly convex function of the variables
but our objective function is only street strictly convex on w but the if you
have been used to not be it is not strictly convex so
in this derivation usually
if you see some people they just the partial derivative with respect to be aware
that this not very
very correct away
then i want to say a little bit more about dual problems so it is
it is a popular technique so quite a few people just think that for any
optimisation problem is that do exist
and also strong duality holds what is actually wrong
in optimisation series there's nothing like that
we only have serious saying that in this optimisation problem is a convex problem to
convex programming makes the objective function is convex and also the feasible region feasible region
is the set of points satisfying all constraints so this set is also
is also convex we have a convex programming problems and not enough
there's something called constraint qualification so you're constraints
it must to satisfy certain conditions only for this kind of problems
then you will have strong duality
you can just write a new optimisation problem and then just write range in the
USA all strong duality holds
that's right
so that we
we will for our optimisation problem it satisfies all of these first this optimisation problem
is a convex it is strictly convex and but also colleagues on the acidic variables
so it's is convex so we are full of first condition than another important effect
for constraint qualification is if you have a so-called being in constant
then you're constant qualification is always satisfied
this year
and exception
see the primal problem
OK so here is the primary problem
so what we have is
that just uh it
so i'd like to first the
or get
the rule
why these optimality he holds
and then
the big problem that is how
and at the convention of people of similar because its local optimality
if you go back
i had to calculate it at least in principle all these conditional expectation
so the calculation of this such a
conditional expectation the knowledge
of the distribution of the sequence x one x two
otherwise i cannot calculate the conditional expectation
so the problem last for the second or they hall two
create a bit of the world
and then you could procedure with the same optimality prof feature here
the approach should be as in the best possible asymptotic growth rate if we don't
know anything on the process
if i get the problem that i can make a pretty deal IBM and coca-cola
then nobody we apparently what is the
what are all the multidimensional distribution of the market
but i have to happen and the code
that's particularly optima
for the proof i would like to
the tu
very nice the
concept is is the martingale difference
the choir
because in on wednesday afternoon when i proved that for i i d
one what is the best possible portfolio that
then i proved optimality and the main key of the proof was law large number
that is the average of independent identically distributed zero mean random variables the average goes
to zero
here i have just visionary but i feel i can handle the law of large
numbers and this will be
the law of large numbers are markedly different
i have two sequences
the and x
and i have here two requirements for the definition of
martingale difference one is that the and the function of x one x two xn
and the other one is that the conditional expectation of the and
preview axes
is zero
this is the definition of then i call the mach get different
with respect to
x that
and it is very good
because there is this year and i feel in
in this year i will use large numbers but maybe
you allowed to the data
probably this theory that if you have a fuzzy and marking your different sequences
such that the
the thirtieth on its convergence then
the average of is that the goes to zero we probably you one
instead of these the strong law of large numbers
i will
sketch of of the proof
not sketch the company proved that the average of marking differences goes to zero
it means process or problem which
the first step is that if we had a martingale difference sequence that it is
we find
forty four different it derive less than g
and i would like to show that the product the i the j
today we're going to talk about interference
of electromagnetic radiation
and i will start as a warm-up
with famous historical experiment
it was first
young in eighteen one
by the time
the issue whether or not light
was always whether those particles will still unresolved
not always like to particles
but the
dutch physicist
one of them to be weight issues unresolved
let's agree that if
like particles
and you have have the screen has two openings
and you will throw
article four like tomato
many the articles
a you collect here
and those made of don't get stuck on the screen but that make it
former pioneer of tomatoes and then for the
it's very difficult
articles but the situation is different
when we do with waves
because the moment that you have were coming in
say for instance we have plane waves coming in like this
and the way can go
both of these simultaneously that changes the picture quite dramatically
well no was already in the
seventeenth century
that if you have a waterway
going through a small opening
so here waterways
moving in
like so he was also wore
that which is seen coming out there
are circular way
look like this
they propagating out circular
and if the velocity
of the way here is the same as the velocity there
then the wavelength here
it will be the same
the way like
but if the velocities different of course using change
the difference in the
we fly
so happens
my country my
i suggest that in the seventeenth century new ideas
which is now known as hamilton's principle
we can think of this in very different ways
and by the way is
difficult to pronounce any one of you who knows how to say how things correctly
is also that
because you missed the new language you missed the your language
and the combination of our and is complete kill you guys
you know you don't get extra eight o three course credits if you can come
to to my office and say how things but it was certainly put you into
that category
so in the seventeenth century the inhabitants came was an idea which was later amended
by from l in the nineteenth century now known as the
boykins i will pronounce it your way since final principle
which works as follows if we have the playing monochromatic wave
and it's incident on the screen with an aperture this be in aperture opening
you have to have just two openings
and avoidance final principle states the following all points
in the aperture plane
thought of secondary point sources
of spherical waves
and the point sources replaced the real source
which is falling to screen
and the stream itself is a perfect absorber of the radiation falling upon and so
i will repeat the organ final principle which i will need to be
all points
in the aperture plane
may be thought of as a secondary point sources of spherical wave
in the case that we have one or this is a two dimensional surface there
will be served
but when you deal with light you can think of them as
three-dimensional that means spherical which
avoidance final principle
is very powerful
there is a wide range of
opinion to its scientific merit
and in a very famous book the principle of electrodynamics by melvin swartz
i read the following i quote verbatim from his book
he says hagens principle tells us to consider each point on the way from as
a new source of radiation
and at the radiation from all the news sources together
physically this makes no sense at all
light does not emit light
only accelerating charges emit light
thus we will begin by throwing out avoidance principle completely
later we will see that it actually does give the right answer for the wrong
so i will proceed my lecture today to get the right answer
for the wrong reasons
suppose now we have a
electromagnetic wave i'm particularly thinking of light
and i have here opening
and i open
plane waves are coming in
on the left
moving with the
and that this opening a
and that is opening the
i knew the centre of the two ways
this could be circular opening it could also be used it
most of the experiments that i was let's which are perpendicular
so there are very narrow
imagine that you point
and so
the way from point a will reach that point p
but away from source b
also read the story elected vectors there
i'm going to be and of course vectorial
imagine now
but the
minus a
imagine that there were one half wavelength
then what you get is that the months
of the vector he will coincide with the valley of effective from o one
so you get the situation that like was like
will give darkness we call that desperately interference
the way from
from there are one hundred eighty degrees
out of face
and if you take all the points
for which the difference is one of
that is a hyperbola will surface
it's like a ball
not only in the blackboard also comes out of the back like
and you're
five school days
that is
the sun
of the distance in a and b p is constant
then you get another
but if the sum of the differences are constant you get across
so you get an equivalent surface
and all everywhere on that surface minus a
what can be one lap
and then you will get the
the main consequence like like give darkness
desperate to interfere
the main roads don't do that
one two mateo
on top of another two may o
does not you know to me that is distinctly different from particles
and of course there also hyperbolic model surfaces
for which there is
a higher bias because they don't they don't have enough parameters to to be very expressive
but at least the parameters will be well estimated so they have low variance well
the models with more parameters like this one would have low low
bias because they are more expressive but there would have higher variance in the
estimation of the parameters so by averaging between the two then you cannot get the
smaller bias and smaller variance as compared to to each of this models so
so tends to work pretty well and there's been lots of different models that people
have explored for for smoothing  and this is just taken from a review
paper about ten years ago and they've compared whole bunch of smoothing algorithms at a
time and found that there're two smoothing algorithms that seem to do
much better than the other ones and and nowadays they're basically the the standard smoothing
techniques that could be my phone sorry okay and they're called Kneser-Ney so interpolated
interpolated Kneser-Ney and modified  Kneser-Ney what we would do instead is to
use this idea of hierarchical Bayesian models to to build our language model okay and
the idea is the following so if you look at the way smoothing works
like this where we have the smooth probability is this average of this tree models you can kind of
think of this algorithm as basically operating on a tree of contexts so
the the tree is starts off at the root of the tree we have the
context basically the empty context where we want to predict the next word without giving
without being given any information about previous words and then at the next level down
we'd like to predict the next would given only the previous word and then at
the next level down we'd like to predict that next word given the previous two words and so
forth and the idea of smoothing here is that you'd like to take a path down
this context tree and average the probabilities along this path right that that's what this thing
is doing and what that does is that it allows you to basically share information
across the different the different context and the weight this context tree is constructed
as you go up the tree you take a context and you drop the first
word from the context so you start off with a long south parks drop the first
word we get south parks drop the first word  we get parks drop the first word we
get the empty context and the reason for this is basically that the later words in
your context being closer to the word that you want to predict which is the one that
comes next is more informative about the word that you wanna predict and because it's more informative
you like to keep it in the context as you go up the tree as
long as possible so this of course looks quite similar to a hierarchical bayesian model and
we can do that so let's build a hierarchical Bayesian model on this context tree
okay so at every node of our tree we're gonna have a set
of parameters which basically describes the list of probabilities that for the list of
probabilities for the following word given that context so this G of parks would
aerodynamic coefficients that had to be there
for that maneuver to look like it look that within itself has some + amount
stuff goes you can change of validity still looks pretty good those 2 them were
and then we had a set of reduced air management today when you go to
the anemic Data Book which we hope to be able to get you copies of
it will have not only the coefficients for all members and the the back angle
such that it would tell you what the uncertainty in the function might number angle
of attack is really in system should be able to work with host
I will mention this ergonomic design substantiation report
and you'll be able to get a copy of that
place and all of that we're going to try to get a copy to to
just for you and should be available and you find what that did that goes
back him and for every coefficient Arango attack how we arrived at that specific value
and specific variations using both wind tunnel flight tests and super document and not purity
blood is an excellent technical document and that was done during the flight test program
and inadequate
I thought we had their land program that's primarily the backbone of the anemic database
of the show before the arbitrarily integrated vehicle and
mandatory testamentary vehicles 17 and 18 40 structural anatomy hours of 1 type and 17
thousand and we have that compared with the Apollo is this time we get about
45 thousand hours on the entry vehicle Apollo however Paolo didn't have all those movable
surfaces move services nice
and do a lot of things for you but you gotta test and make sure
that there
yes release of this facilities and country they still exists but a up away yesterday
still exist in the other ones arranges to will once the still usable unfortunately those
at Langley even though there there and they work and because of funding constraints Langley
has a hard time and bring in being used and that's unfortunate going of some
excellent facilities and
should used that we've got in this wonderful test programming found after spatial encompassing programme
summary uh that's that's about we can get this document pretty straightforwardly
In previous his nascent vehicle of few US hours and that's because you don't with
many surfaces primarily uh heating and that something and work on if you wanna get
project to work on
heating data and went
on a small scale vehicle
and make scale predictions
reasons near and dear to my heart alright there is a test not too long
ago and they still can match those 2 so good PhD thesis making figure out
how to do that have the right not a scaling parameter like plumes enough which
getting primarily really work with there's like data gallery images and it's like test data
and went later and lot about about doesn't
it doesn't bother us that much because we've got enough conservatism in the system and
uncertainties that we know we're safe flat but it does hurt you when you say
that heating radiators it should be
non BTU before it's great per 2nd and applied to this dataset is not going
to be united 1 where you have met another way but that I was looking
for something to get my plough into analysis theoretical stuff that's probably arrive at the
time of Toronto programmer and Aaron paid for that his budget by way and was
there's nothing else
i called is actually called zero
and i call this displacement
away from equilibrium
for small angles
i want to argue that he
is very close to MG
for one thing if you hold them vertically and you do nothing and there is
no motion is always that he's ng two forces have to cancel each other that's
but i can show you that even if the angles are modest
that that should also be the case
suppose i decompose t
in two directions
the vertical direction
so this is t
times the cosine of the that
and in the horizontal direction
so this is true
times the sign of data
if the angles are very small
the object is hardly moving at all in this direction the motion is almost exclusively
in this direction
so there is no
in the y direction or i should say
the acceleration in the y direction is negligibly small
for that means to high degree of accuracy the cosine theta is always the same
as g
i degree of accuracy but for small angles cosine theta itself is one
therefore she
equals MC
and so the force
that is driving
this object back to equilibrium
is t sin theta
so that force is ng sin theta to high degree of accuracy
i'm going to introduce again
the gamma is be over and sort of these damping
and i'm going to introduce that only gets squared
calls g
over alpha omega zero scratches g over LG over l being the
square root of g over being the
resonance frequency
of a pendulum length l
of the mass of the object as we have seen before
so now i'm going to write down newton's second law
so i get an axe
double dot
and then i get minus
b acted dot
that is the
the damping
is bx not
and now comes this force
which is the only one
he wants to
driving back to
equilibrium it's the restoring force
so that's force if you accept
mighty being MG
that is and
times the size of data
that's the difference in equation
that i know
i have to solve
that is driven system
no here i had driven system
and boy i saw force here
i don't see anything like that there
well this will tell will come into this picture
i always doing something
i have i overlooked myself perhaps
wouldn't change anything
i've changed nothing but i don't see myself anymore
so what's wrong is there anything wrong with this
where do i show up in these equations
way that equation two i show up
what is the sign of data
what is the sign of theta
what is side of this angle
mine is at that's walter ruin
x minus at
divided by l
there are m
so i'm going to substitute that in here and i'm going to divide by
that's not defined by and yet
just say
x double dot
a minus b
next up
and now we get
minus and g
x over l
and now we bring will to live the other side
and so we get plus and g
finds at
divided by
and that ties at the zero
the cosine omega t because i'm moving my hand
at is a function of time
right down and you here
and then will check this
so energy time sign fader has two terms it has an MG times x over
but it has also an times at over l and i bring that over on
this site but i know that at
is changing in time and so you see now walter lewin is right there
and i divide by n
and i substitute omega zero screening here
o i have been used to
we should have screened there wasn't and there i decided not to divide by an
now i'm going to divide by n
i get x double dot
in the ninety percent of patients
where there was no
effective response to the drug
the EGF receptor it was wild type was present in the wild type configurations it
might have been slightly overexpressed but it wasn't but it continued to function essentially as
normal EGF receptor
and this represents a major advance in cancer therapy because it suggests that one has
to begin to understand what subset of patients one should treat
with the drug which can happen on its own have quite toxic effects on the
and from now on to state the obvious when one gets lung cancer patients one
will check quickly using various reactions like the PCR reaction to see whether or not
the cancer cells have mutated EGF receptor and if they do
they will be candidates for rest treatment with the expectation that sixty eighty or even
one hundred percent of them will have to resort respond
and if they don't have mutated EGF receptor and they will not be subjected
treatment by the drug this is the beginning of a new era of cancer drug
treatment it's called rational drug design or rational treatment we don't just lump all the
patients with a certain disease together so let's give them all this drug and throw
things at me and see what happens
here one begins to do it genetic diagnosis of the genomes of the patient's cancer
cells in order to determine
whether or not they have certain mutated genes in this case we're referring to one
of these growth factor receptors
by the way we're talking about one cancer today right
if you are smoking now
i always as the class how many people are smoking nobody
has the
has the moral fortitude to raise their hands
but if you smoking now
and you started this age and you continue and by the way if you start
curating you continue small stopping smoking is actually a bit more difficult quite a bit
more difficult than stopping heroine
it's pretty interesting right
it is so if you continue to smoke now
you will be healthy for pretty long period of time
probably another twenty or thirty years and for you that sounds like
but when you get to be about forty or fifty things are going to start
falling apart
so you won't be able to do be very athletic centre lungs are going to
be able to are going to be great and by the time you reach for
fifty six years seventies
what's going to happen is you will on average have a six to eight year
shortened life expectancy
ninety six sixty eight years is not that much but it really is you know
when you get to be seventy and you think you're going to die next year
uridine six to eight years makes a big difference sixty years is an enormous difference
in life expectancy twenty percent of all people who died last year in this country
twenty percent of all this
cigarette smoking
imagine that
and when you die from cigarette smoke smoking sometimes you get lung cancer
there probably were i think six hundred thousand people have died smoking last year
six hundred thousand there were fifty five thousand american soldiers
who died in vietnam in the whole war
there were two hundred twenty american soldiers two thousand american soldiers who died all of
world war two
and last year in this and there were three thousand two thousand people died in
the world trade center
all right all those numbers
so last year six hundred thousand people died premature deaths because they were smoking
how many people died last year from smoking marijuana
maybe two
for three i don't know
and my urging originated do any kind of smoking i'm not saying marijuana smoking is
good for
but i just want you to get these things in mind
the perspective
if you smoke
you know in many countries including this one there's not much attention by given by
the government press dissuading people from smoking and here's the reason why
if you smoke
and you get it get sick eventually eventually the countries all going to pay for
medical costs right
so really we all have to pay for the costs of people get sick
it's all shared in one way or another
but it's not such a big problem for government like the american government because if
a lot of times we actually refer to the dimensions so think of this as
the unit hypercube
we have some measurements let's say they are point measurements of the function with some
noise added to it
that's it in a discussion like any other kind of noise
can generalize this but this is because it is large and is independent of sample
occasions otherwise the problem would be very very hard to but sometimes it not the
case in practice
and let's say this is the problem we have
this is just what you have seen before passive versus active sampling passive sampling u
s west of the questions first an active sampling u
ask questions one at a time
ben and
based on what you've seen before
so far this regression problems
what is
the goal of the goal is to construct a function
another function
that is somewhat closer to the true function as
this function closeness in this case means the l two distance or the integral of
the difference of the square of the functions
at each point
OK so
squared error
this expected
this is your loss function now wanted to be small
so there are two ingredients here
as i said before one is the estimator
so this function of the data that you're trying to
use to approximate the true function
the other one is the sampling strategy
she's the rule used to choose where to sample next so in active learning those
two things are very important in passive learning
this would be
the key to the design so it's not
like this you're just saying OK i'm going to take examples here here here here
to give the labels
OK so
let's see what
what can you say about active learning setting
but suppose you're trying to learn a smooth function
temperature in the room or
something like that
which does not a lot of sharp changes that states although smooth function just as
we've seen before outside of the smooth function two dimensions possibly high dimensional and
what can we say about active learning well
what pretentious saying this case that active learning some performance like this that x
expected error decays like that
and we can compare this with passive learning and see
we have exactly the same rate
what's going on active learning simply stop being helpful
it is not helpful in this case at least in the minimax setting as i
said minimax is very pessimistic way of looking at things the very worst case so
the minimax setting
sounds active learning
for smooth functions
just to help
and why is this
if you look at small functions they are
smooth they are equally interesting are equally an interesting everywhere
so there's nothing to really capitalize on no place where you can kind of sampling
learn more about that function because they the face is kind of boring the
quite onerous
other types of functions in marginal inner margin is or for sure that have
just like the step function or
some boundaries like that
below a little bit more interesting because the complexity of these functions is mostly concentrated
in a low dimensional space here it's mostly one parameter this describes function here
getting this maybe smooth function here and here
but you have very sharp
the boundary so there you might have a complex is kind of concentrated along this
in this case the one-dimensional curve
in this case active learning might have more problems in might work
so this is because of classes of functions are interested in
and let's focus only on piecewise constant function although some of these can be somewhat
and you should get them both are available at labyrinth bookstore on york street or
you get them online
i should note that last time i talked of course i used the markets reader
and when professor marvin chun taught his course last semester he used peter grace fifth
edition text sort of maybe allowed use copies floating around you should feel free to
try to get one of those
evaluation goes like this
there's a midterm
and there's a final
the final will not be held in exam period
because i like to take long vacations it will be held on the last day
of class
example will will be multiple choice and short answer fill-in-the-blank that sort of thing prior
to the exams i will post previous exams online
so you have a feeling for how these exams were
and so on there will also be review sessions
starting at the beginning of the third week of class that is not the next
week but the week after
on one each one day i want to put up a brief question
or set of questions
which you have to answer
and your answers need to be sent to teaching fellow you'll be given a teaching
fellow assigned one
by friday
this is not meant to be difficult it's not meant to be more than five
ten minutes of work but the point of the question
fifteen twenty minutes of work but the point of the question is to motivate people
to keep up with the material
and do the redirect
these questions will be marked pass fail i expect most everybody to pass all of
the questions
but it's just to keep you on track and keep going
there's a book reviews
a short book review to be written towards near the end of the class
i'll give details about that later on in this semester and is also an experimental
participation requirements
and next week i'll handle piece of paper describing the requirements the point requirements to
give you all experience
actually seeing what psychological research is about as well as to give us hundreds of
subjects to do experiments on
the issue issues sometimes come about how well force
here's how to do well
ten all the classes keep up with the readings
ideally keep of the readings before you come to class
and one thing i would strongly suggest to form some sort of study was
either formally or informally have people you talk to
when the exact prior to the exams are he's palling something next to her
i hope you know him
and in fact what i want do
not this class because the shopping period i don't know what's coming next last or
what but also to a few minutes prior to beginning classes for people just introduce
himself to the person next to them
so to have some sort of resource
in the class
this is a large class
and if you don't do anything about it can be very anonymous
and some of you may choose to pursue it that way
totally fine
but what i was
i suggest you do
it established some contact with us
if with me
are we any of the teaching fellows and i'll introduce the teaching fellows sometime next
you talk to us at the beginning or end of class
unless you're special circumstances i always try to come
at least ten minutes earlier i and i'm willing to stay late to talk to
people you could come by the office hours which are on the syllabus and the
sending email an appointment
i'm very willing to talk to students about intellectual ideas about cause problems and so
on and if you see me at some point just on campus you introduce yourself
and i like me people
from this class
so again i want to stress
you have the option of staying anonymous in this class we also have the option
of seeking making some sort of contact with us
that's the formal start of of course
what course about
unlike a lot of other courses some people come into psychology of some unusual motivations
maybe you're crazy
and hope to become less crazy
maybe one to learn how to study better improve your sex life
i interpret your dreams and win friends and influence people
those are not necessarily better reasons to take
this course
and with the exception of the sex part of this course might actually help you
will with some of these things the study of scientific psychology has a lot of
insight of real world relevance to real problems that we face in our everyday lives
and i want to try and when these issues come up when i try to
and make you try to think about the extent to which the laboratory research i'll
be talking about can affect your everyday life
and study how you interact with people how you might try to persuade somebody of
something else what sort of therapy works best for you
but the general goals of the core
are actually
i think even more interesting than that
what i wanna do
is provided state of art introduction to the most important topic that there is
that's how the human mind works how we think
what makes us what we are
i will be approaching this from a range of directions so traditionally psychology is often
broken up into the following into five subareas
neuroscience which is the study of the of the mind by looking at the brain
which is the area which i focus mostly on which is trying to learn about
how people develop and grow
and learning
which is the one term of the five might be unfamiliar some of you but
refers to sort of computational approach to studying the mind often viewing the mind on
analogy with the computer and looking at how people do things like understand language recognise
playing games and so on
there is social
which is the study of how people act in groups how people act with other
and there is clinical which is maybe the aspect of psychology people think of immediately
when they psychology which is the study of mental health and mental illness
and we'll be covering all of those areas will also be covering a set of
related areas
i am convinced that you can not study the mind
solely by looking at the discipline of psychology the psychology spills over the issues of
how the mind has evolved
economics and game theory
are now an essential tools
for understanding human by human behaviour
those issues connecting to philosophy computer science anthropology literature theology and many many other domains
so this course will be
wide ranging in that sense
at this point i speaking in generalities so
i want to post this introductory
class by giving five examples
other sorts of topics will be covered
and all strata topic
there will be covering next week on monday
what is the acceleration any of the system
i get them to minus one that is o point
one five
divided by the sun
which is two point three five
and that is approximately o point o six four g
proximity o point o six four g
it's about one sixty of the gravitational acceleration
but a very modest
what is the pension
i substitute by numbers for one and two in there
you can take for g ten if you like that
you will find that the tension
equals one point one
and no
look at what i predicted
they both way one point one seven g that's non-negotiable
that is my definition of weight the pension
in both size is the same that's my definition of weight this is the weight
this one had to wait one point two five
without being accelerate
you see
it has lost weight
as accelerated down
this one had a weight of one point one gene
see has gained weight because it accelerated up
we see the whole picture
vice together very neatly
and it's important that you look at it that way
i know want to return
the idea of complete
and i want to remind you if you like to go
how i was swinging you at the end of history
in the vertical
i was thinking you like this
and i was ringing
a bucket of water like this
and i want to return to that
i want to
look at you
when you are a
at the bottom of your circle
and when you are at the very top
of that's you
you go
around a circle which has radius are
here is that circle
a string here
we're here
and as a string here
and at some point in time you there
going around let's assume that you're going around was an angular velocity
omega and for simplicity we keep omega constant
that's really not that important
this is point p
and this is point as
at first
look at the situation at point p
you have mass
so gravity acts upon you
and g
there is tension in the string
there must be this is non-negotiable
centripetal acceleration upwards
otherwise you could never do this
number from the uniform circular motion
so there must be here
centripetal acceleration
which is only gas great art
or if you prefer
this great divided by r
if v is the speed and and gential speed at that point
it must be there
let's look here
right there
gravity is acting upon you
let's assume the string is pulling on new let's assume that for now
there's tension
stream or not new
non-negotiable when you make this
curvature here
there must be
the centripetal acceleration
and that's simply because the generation must be on because they are there is not
negotiable has to be there
that's no
evaluate first the situation at p
and i will call this class
now call this minds
so i get now is that t
my name is mg
must be
times the centripetal acceleration
i must be and
centripetal acceleration g
that looks very familiar looks like someone is b someone is being accelerated in know
that almost the same equation
the centripetal acceleration at this point
for instance where
ten meters per second squared
you would weigh twice your normal weight
tension here
would be
if this were five
meters per second squared
then you would
one of the halftime show way
let's now
look at the situation
point as
i'm going to call
this plus
and that minus
i'm going to find that
plus and
i must be and
times the centripetal acceleration newton's second law
so i find that the tension there
he calls and
minus g
very similar to what i've seen before
these objects
is losing weight
let's take the situation that a of c
is exactly ten meters per second squared and we discussed the last time when we
had the bucket of water in our hands
if a of c if the centripetal acceleration
when it
make when i got to the top is ten
and this is zero
so the strange
has no tension in the string of women
and the bucket of water and you are weightless
if the centripetal acceleration
is larger than ten
then of course
this string will be tight there will be a force on you
regression function classifier and then we use this variance founding idea is served intuitive way
of understanding how to actually select is traumatic come things that verification
OK in classification we're going to do the same thing some the purcell variances over
the leaves in the tree times the probability falling in particular
in this case these variances behave like one of the square root poems pl
so at the end of the day
down there you see what we end up with something like a bit more complicated
the sum over all leaves in the tree of cells in the partition
terms like the square root of peace developer
in this type of
very is found if you will for classification was first introduced by minister and david
mcallister who is the director here here is very interesting idea and this is the
basic intuition block behind why that might be
a sensible thing
we can get slightly weaker bond classification
by viewing this summation here is an expectation this being the object of expectation being
the probabilities that take expectation with respect to
and then applying jensen's inequality and then we get something that may be a little
bit more familiar to some people
the bound on the variance is equal to the square root of the number of
leaves in the tree divided by and this is exactly what you might obtain if
you use the standard VC type of bound for trees
this this this very sparse suggests the following rules for complexity regularisation
now here's trying to be actually selecting trees and what i wanna do is i
want to make sure that what i selected tree
i struck some balance between giving a small empirical error and giving me not so
large variance
and so the lambda here in these equations could be viewed as the regularisation parameter
that allows us to tweak the trade off between empirical risk invariances we like
we'll see later how that can be theoretically
shows in an optimal fashion but these are the basic classes were
complexity regularisation rules in regression
and in classification
with the two different variance bounds whichever one you like
the upper one being a little tighter than the lower one
one thing i want to mention is an interesting feature here
with the
variance found for the classification case above there's is if you know is that if
you think that the
the distribution of the axis is more or less around
spread around the feature space
then a very small
cells will have a very small probability of having features fall into that cell
essentially small will contribute very little
to this period found
relative to large leaves and that is not happening with the other two parties which
three or leaves the same and this is the really turns out to be very
important feature of the first found in and we'll see that play out a little
more detail in the second half of my lecture
t and so in the second have focus on classification so i won't say more
about that here but i want to give you an illustration of an example of
this very kind of idea
in something called image denoising so here's an image plus noise
this in the middle here is a partition that we've learned directly from the noisy
pixel values
and and then at the right is the denoised image and that the image was
obtained by solving
this kind of complexity regularisation
the value of lambda that's used in this kind of situation is usually something proportional
to the variance of the noise level which you may or may not know if
you don't know what you can estimate is ways to do that
but all we're doing is is following that complexity regularisation scheme i just described in
this is essentially a special case was
usually called wavelet denoising using a particular type of wavelet haar wavelets
and this idea in the theory of it was really
pioneered and popularized by the time i went into stone in nineteen ninety four
when we talk about the second half of the
will take a break in middle is the theory behind complexity regularisation how do we
actually start formally justify what we just described in the previous slides
in the case of regression we get optimal denoising rules of that form
using various concentration inequalities per year telegraph concentration inequalities coupled with some approximation theory in
the classification case instead of using those concentration inequalities we can use
chernoff bounds hoeffding bounds and again approximation theory and more less the stories are very
similar and i'm going to focus on the classification theory to give you a good
insight as to what's actually going on
in a minute
and i think that we can take a little break now
and resume maybe in five minutes and i'll go into the second half of lecture
when you get on time
OK this is the my time
all right so
as i said in the second half the talk and we try to give you
a clear sense of real
theory behind some of the things i was trying to give intuition about the first
you know i was thinking more than this would be the end of
it is a strange fish and we try to
h type
this is
we are
which is the
you are
so usually after
if you can
she would later
he said
i don't want to the user
if we do that know he was well
well but three we had to
one of four
i mentioned
and the twenty two forty three
by using
i'm afraid
i don't know you hear it all
and all this
you think
three years
i think
which is to get
two or are
three years
it's very easy
we to you
each time we
you can easily show you just you
it's not for
but he
it just
in a finite
this one
now try to
it's two
the problem with a
one of the
the interesting thing is get
OK but that is not enough
two thousand three
the only
so it
so is
sure he is shown
you know you can
brown said
OK so
there are many
the fact that
you know my
you can look get for to days
a big
and these are
the last
the question is a you
it is
my we're
in the world
this would whole even if you don't
so this is again well of course we know that i see is very different
from PCA
but here again this is something that you might think is similar to PCA but
actually it is not at all similar to be so this is what this sparse
coding is
a kind of dimension reduction in the sense
that's so when you have let's say you have a one thousand dimensional data points
and the new input into what's possible and this is what the sparse coding give
the representation given that uses only ten of of ten active components and all the
sizes so instead the where your kind of reducing dimensions
but it's not at all the same distribution dimension by PCA because those components which
active always different from one point to another
so the idea is that you have a very large vocabulary
yes i tools from but then to represent any particular data points you will only
use a very small number
of those of active components it's a bit like in language actually so
in natural language i have tens of thousands of words that i can use but
if i want to describe as a single object for example
this computer here
i will is only a couple of years because only a couple of for example
it's so that's actually people talk about what whatever believe is here so it is
you have potentially very large vocabulary but you will need is a couple of them
for any particular data point
and we finally get
so the results
so this is this is the basis vectors that you get when you do ICA
a or sparse coding on image with
so and so the point is that we have here
image windows of sixteen pixels five sixty six
and to get
from from the from which to estimate we we think we sample these small windows
from a large number of
of natural images
so natural images is bit rate is a term that is slightly vague what we
basically have is something of my life and loves and so on and then sample
and so
we they may be
something like ten to twenty thousand
some examples of these windows so we have to know twenty thousand data points
and so the original dimension of the data is two hundred fifty six because sixty
five sixty but then we do PCA for various technical reasons that we're not going
so as to reduce the dimension of the data to one hundred and sixty
and so that we do and then we do i see a and we get
we get one hundred sixty basis vectors each of these small squares is one of
the basis vectors and again called so that great is zero white positive and negative
so what you see here
well at least we provide well the first thing that
you would see is that most of these features are localized in space that is
most take any any single women who basis vectors most of it is is great
and only
this small part
of actually well
i wonder if you can see very well on this lighting conditions
so sixty pixels that sixteen
but i hope you can see most of the most of the feature is basically
grey that means zero
and you get non-zero values only in the typically in small spatially localized
of course the area will be different for each of these features
but and then the second property
it is that's not the most of these features oriented that means well into the
you can see that usually they have you know if have an orientation vertical horizontal
or anything in between
and the third property that is a bit more difficult to to see
but not necessarily well of the property because we call it multiresolution
which means that you have
which which which means that you have you have features that called for
very short small things
on in forty terms they have they are very high frequencies and then you have
the features that hold for larger things and work in a low dimensional frequencies
so for example well this is this is kind of coding for age of the
very low dimension where you know well most of these actually holding five which have
a much higher dimension and which are spatially much less
now these three properties
spatial localization orientation
and not a solution which is also
you would call it
localisation in fourier space
these three properties of atypical of the
so that explains data set sail to here
because this normalizes to one
it takes the form
so if optical data set on the design data
this medium alpha
model is more probable
simply due to this idea of normalizing which comes gain from this idea
having to look at all the other models
sorry all the other datasets these models could have predicted
if you go back to the sequence example
this high alpha model is equivalent if you like to six bit model this high
highly models of equivalent
to the
symbol eight single eight bit symbol
so it doesn't actually explain of data
if you had it would have given the very high probability that the next plane
of data
it's not the most probable
six bits explanation for that indicated sequence
well i did explain data but also explained allows generate a lot of other sequences
so it signed a bit low probability
model was just right well that explain the data
but it didn't explain much else
so that was the light so much that the most probable
that's occams razor work
both in
the discrete example i showed you the the very beginning
and also here
well we have sort of a continuous parameter space weights
if we integrate them out we can get this effect
in this case example by the marginal likelihood function
well we automatically penalized
we just one function calculation
models are not too simple
and models for the two complex
that would have been the end of the first
they have any questions at this point
this function
i have things quite fixed
same signal is not point one
that's the fixed basis matrix
that's the fixed data matrix
that only leaves out that i simply buried alpha
but in that actually to look at that indicated
so that's not too complex calculations
the negative log that
but as a function of alpha sigma squared fixed
all other variables are fixed
and that's the case again
OK let's move on
it's reasonable flexible talks to matter too much
running starting part two
so this is what part two would have be about
so i just want to extend this idea
how integrating and allows us to robustly of select model parameters in the model themselves
i will start off with another ten i
was going to talk about that sparse bayesian models and dynamically reconfigure talking at that
so hopefully convey
much useful information as possible and also shared in the end
eventually over spelling is that this is not a fresh in your mind
previously as in the moment again
we maximize this term
to estimate alpha things glad
actually estimates discovery fixed at the weekend
if you wanted to
it quite nice powerful feature
the bayesian approach we could have actually estimated the noise level itself
hopefully training example that later
but for now i want to look at
extending what we've done being even more basic
trying to choose a particular model
by model what i mean is show we have a look at
what the best set of basis functions as
and perhaps some basis functions of parameters
particular lbs function has the width parameter
can we automatically via bayesian procedure
choose those
this parameter and the basis set at the same time
so to do this we have to be a little bit more bayesian
and we're going to have to perform integrating at the earlier said we can do
but just start by
saying well
the model we're going to sort of
perform inference over
is simply
the collection of the basis functions and any parameters or just call it faces
and the parameter are
so we want to calculate the posterior
of the model
posterior probability the model given the data
this is the sort of essence
the bayesian approach
we simply calculate probabilities of what we want to know
conditioned and you know what we upset
ideally we don't want anything else on the right-hand side
that's some problems happen when we leave
parameters that need to be instantiated on the right-hand side instead of integrating that
if we assume all models are equally likely we have no prior prejudice and no
reason to
we can say that all models are equally likely this is flat
to find the most probable model
we need to find the model
it gives nice probability to the data
this commonly happens in the sort of bayesian manipulation
we assume if we assume a flat prior
we simply want to
find the maximum of the likelihood the likelihood of the data
condition on the model
so this is where the integrating outcomes in the game
because we don't want all these hyperparameters on the right-hand side we want to name
i have been given the derivation
so i've just sketched of the proof there is an asymptotic expression for the variance
of this estimator
you minimize the i think this is one of the things we can of large
u minimizes variance you get an expression for the q
and it happens to be that the constrained optimization problem
and because constrained because the some of the key over the whole space has that
up to one
o well the solution is that the solution to assess the effect
so the solution what you get is pfx times an exponential
now if you have a facts
written in exponential form
times another exponential you just add the exponent so you basically shifting the means
so i'm skipping the details here but that's what you will
so the true solution is impossible
so let's take it steps
you do an optimisation problem and you find out the optimal q
the optimal q requires this
this indicator functions so this is still impossible to do because direct
spiritual into
we're going to
do some large deviations theory which i haven't done
and this becomes e the feet some function of x
the i fx
is replaced by this kind of approach
and there's a lot of theoretical arguments as to why this is optimal
and then if this pfx is also say accounts in an exponential distribution
so x minus mu
square over sigma whatever
then you can add these two
and this will usually add up as i mean term so what you get is
in fact shift in the distribution
this flight details if you're an item in one d is just shift in high
dimensions this kind of
the way you shift to depends on the shape of heat you actually have to
solve another constrained optimisation problem
which can be very hard action
for full impact program for participation
that's correct
they affect the just brought because it's very specific example that people actually care about
a lot
first of all of
and it's also nice example because is one of those examples where you can crank
up variational theory and actually come up with
useful solutions
you are correct
another thing also one more point about this is
quite often
people tend to also use the proposal distribution that just
that's the mode of the distribution of food optimisation and you put a proposal distribution
at the peak
that's fine if you what you care about the optimisation you care about integration that's
a stupid idea
i wrote a paper in two thousand three
called variational MCMC total rubbish
because i didn't see that then
and people so long see it now
so in my list of selected publications
it has to go
here's the catch
if you putting a proposal distribution with the high again
with the test high-density point is is not with the mass is the mass again
of the girls in high dimensions in the tail
if you and integrate units some of them as you counting the area
in high dimensions
coming up with heuristics putting the everest except the modes like some of these various
approximations on inside it these days people still used loopy BP is the proposal distribution
and so on
i mean this paper superior for any conferences with high probability of one on this
they're not so
because of
these high dimensional behaviors
this interesting counting to really care where the probability is not with the density is
that sort of more than
three key thing
so anyway so the estimator again
if you don't know the normalizing constant
it's just
the ratio of estimators and basically it's just one estimate if you just take
this site
and you should define w till the to be the normalised weights i w divided
by the sum of the top
so if you have the normalized weights with that
another thing that we do is so that will give you a sample version
that will give you
samples excited with the weight
and you might instead of having samples exile with the weight
you might want to have
a bunch of samples with weight one over n
like we had before
so here is something you can do
i suppose
so they inputs to this thing is
a bunch of samples x y
with the corresponding weight
this gives you an empirical density
this sort of exercise
this is w i
that's the approximation of the distribution
now you can build the cumulative
so this is the CDF
we're going what we wanted to do is we want more
after having some falls
with the new index j
and here i had i call one two and
and i'm going to want only and samples
and this is for example people the graphics to simulate light
with the ray tracing
with this the party the samples actually right
they can only afford very few of these evaluations because they're very expensive you have
to solve a lot of geometry
and so what you do is
after you've sampled with importance sampling
you resample to reduce the number of samples so you choose and to be a
lot less than n
so we want to have few samples and we want him to have
alright one over n
uniform weights in other words
how we do this
we use the trick of called resampling
and the way resampling works
you pick the uniform distribution
good morning
your colleagues and friends
it's my great pleasure
to introduce to you our today's keynote speaker get gigerenzer
he is director of the max planck institute for human development in berlin
many of us
remember his generous hospitality when the i a s e satellite conference in two thousand
three took place this institute
former policies include professorships in germany and in austria and at the university of chicago
which he gave up to become director of the max plank institute for simunic for
psychological research and then in berlin four
the max planck institute for human development
a critique of the work of daniel kahneman and amos tversky he argues
the heuristics
should not lead us to conceive of human being human thinking as riddled with cognitive
but rather consider rationality as an adaptive tool
that is bounded by constraints given through time and space
in the environment
one of the most quoted german psychologist
and also of quite a number of
pioneering research papers
as well as author of
number of books for the general public
he trains medical doctors
in financial managers
in their decision-making competencies
one of his recent books was entitled reckoning with risk
learning to to live with uncertainty
and it had such an impact
that's the british investment banker
david harding donated one point five million euros
two to get gigerenzer as kick off for what later became
what then became what now became the harding center for risk literacy
the vision to to our concept of statistical literacy
that we are very proud and feel honoured that you accepted the invitation to
to be keynote speaker at a conference in the we very much look forward to
your presentation
in early
twenty centuries
the science fiction author
herbert george wells
i made the following prediction
if we want
educated citizens in our modern technological world we need to teach them three
statistical thinking
that it's
i with
to deal with
the risks
in an uncertain world or more generally learning to live with an uncertain world
how far have we got now
in the early twenty first century
in most western countries
we have taught
practically everyone
reading and writing but not
statistical thinking
and american
new newspeak once announced the weather in the following way
the probability that it will rain on saturday he said is fifty percent
the probability that it will rain on sunday
also fifty percent therefore he concluded
but the probability that it will rain on the weekend is under percent
you are a sophisticated craft but
do you know what it means when you hear on the radio
that there is a thirty percent chance of rain tomorrow
thirty percent of what
i have done this study
in five large cities in five countries berlin new york amsterdam athens and black
most people in berlin and amsterdam believe that thirty percent chance of rain means that
it will rain tomorrow
in thirty percent of the time
that is seven to eight hours
others believe it will rain in thirty percent of the area
is most likely not where i live
most new yorkers believe neither of that is correct but it means that it will
rain on thirty percent of the base for which this prediction has been made that
means most likely not all
and people in athens basically still probability free when it comes to rest on one
lady there said OK i know what it means
three major role as you think it rains and seven not
this is an illustration of the general problem going to talk about
percentages or
according to some sources
the most frequent now in the media
few people understand and most importantly
if you notice
that they don't understand it
in this particular case the
cause and the solution is crystal clear
a probability of rain tomorrow is a single event probabilities tomorrow and by definition doesn't
specify the class
if you are
meteorologists days
and people naturally think in terms of classes
and they made up their make up something that sounds
that's to them so he is default clearly into communication
not so much
in the person
and much of what i will talk today about
medical about because communication is
and not about the false of patients or doctors but
the problem
that arises because
the information is communicated in the way
that the mind cannot easily understand
so there are always two ways
communicate the risks
and so the foundational results of compressed sensing
that it's possible to recover perfectly sparse signal if we have the a form of
incoherence but the problem in real life is that signals are very often exactly sparse
so the only exactly sparsity always nearly sparse so we need to address what happens
when the signal is now dispersed and also
unfortunately i cannot design sensors have an infinite amount of precision so i need to
be able to tell them to say what happens when i have no data
because if compressed sensing was the theory that is a bit analog to analog to
error correction where i realize enormously on the fact that the number of transmitted errors
missing only seventeen and eighteen or nineteen and infinite precision on the bits that have
received the compressed sensing will not be useful in signal processing applications because i'm not
of sensors that can
measured data was infinite precision
and it would be really ashame if we had a theory that relied on the
twenty six digits
the measured data to work
all right so
in real life images are not sparse they are nearly sparse you've seen before so
here's a picture of
the cameraman and when i look at this with the coefficient table i see that
most of the coefficient table is dark blue or black
which means that the coefficients of the world and i see coefficients indicated by
bright colors that are nonzero
at certain locations which of course have to do with the geometry of the object
so one of the
the point is weighted the coefficient table
is to show you that of course the locations of the wavelet coefficients are non-zero
highly image dependent depends on the geometry of the image and also for to look
at them all will see that none of them is actually exactly zero
OK so what is compressed sensing so the classical viewpoint about sampling
these as follows which is that you have a sneery sparse object a compressible object
what you do is you measure everything that we have very expensive camera we can
measure all the pixels
when you have all the pixels to compute all the wavelet coefficients and you give
the largest
so you compressed down the images by keeping the largest coefficient and when you do
this to pay certain distortion which is the difference between the original object and its
approximation that keeps the s largest coefficients in this expansion
compressed sensing is completely defined it says no
we don't measure everything and we don't
we don't throughout stuff
what we do is we actually measuring by
calculating inner products with incoherent waveforms
so we take n measurements and we we construct a linear programming
and the main results in the field say that if you do this or this
to get the same performance provided that the number of measurements you make
is essentially is the number of coefficients you keep in your best representations
times is logarithmic factors
and if in this approach you sense
the object very few times well how many times the number of
coefficients you keep in your compressed representation something like factor then what compressed sensing guarantees
is that when you reconstruct by linear programming is the error
is less than
the distortion you get by seeing everything in keeping the smartest coefficient
it does this result makes sense
in particular
if this actually happens to be exactly sparse then f is equal to f s
there's no difference and therefore the reconstruction error is zero
but in general what you get is you get the same distortion as somebody who
has seen everything and has kept the swan relations
and you get these out of
a number of measurements which is marginally bigger is an
essentially as times log and this
all right
OK so what he says is that if you can design sensors who take that
take incoherent measurement because of this result said that when you making cohen measurements you
a compressed version of the object in your hand or in other words do simultaneous
signal acquisition and compression and so this discovery was made independently by david owen hart
exactly the same time
in two thousand four
all right so you holdings is compressed version of the object by
incoherent things about an object is essentially getting you compress data about these object all
you need to do to actually display is to solve an optimisation problem
which is what the decompression step involves and so to paraphrase denis healy was my
program manager that he said that whilst compressed sensing such the possibility of compressed data
acquisition protocols which perform as if you could directly acquire just important information about the
image of interest and nothing else
right so a kind of resolve this product which is
perhaps compressed sensing is a way of getting information that we will not go away
it's an example is something like this so bali cannot see my pictures
so this is a compressed version i looked at everything i compress it down and
then i look at three times the number of coefficient like you to get this
picture i sort of want something a bit more sophisticated than n one and get
something as higher PSNR so roughly the same
OK but you can't see my pictures very well so
OK so now we try to kind of
express this main result mathematically because it wasn't a rigorous statement what i give you
so now i'm going to give you requested
so the problem that we're looking at is the problem of recovering
a vector x in r and from what i call phi x now x is
going to be a sparse coefficient sequence and so we can have this kind of
underdetermined problems to solve like all fights where an unknown an equations
all right
one of the
that's not in the other set I suppose it doesn't matter which way around we
do it but let's assume it's this way around so the point the first point
in the first set I can assume is the first point doesn't matter is not in the
second set well so first what we'll do is we will subtract this thing here
from this expression on both sides and so we bring it on the other
side and so we get a zero on one side and we get some kernel
expansion on the other side which might now be a lot of kernel expansion it
might have so on the previous slide it had N points on one side
and on the other side so I'll bring it on one side I might have N plus
N  points but I might have a little bit less than that because some points
might be identical some points from X might be in Y or vice versa
so we to make it a sum of pairwise distinct points
you get an expression like this where the first point is X one the
first coefficient is alpha one remember we're assuming the first point doesn't appear in
the second set so in this procedure of making this a sum of pairwise distinct
points the first point is not going to get changed the first point only
occurs in the set X so that means the first point is still there and
the first coefficient is still nonzero was nonzero to begin it hasn't changed all the
other points all the other coefficients I don't know okay so so the first point is still
there the other ones are somehow from the rest of this set and
could be the coefficients could be anything so then we have this nice expansion we
take the dot product with the same expansion dot product in in the R K H S
and then get an expression like this and this expression now probably looks
familiar to you is the expression that we usually check when we check for positive
definiteness and we know that the coefficient vector here is nonzero because we know
that the first entry is nonzero the first entry is the alpha one which we assumed to
be nonzero so we have an expression where this is zero even though the coefficient
vector's nonzero and that's exactly what's ruled out by the assumption of strict positive definiteness therefore
the kernel cannot be strictly positive definite but actually we were assuming that it's
strictly positive definite so we have a contradiction so therefore the two sets have to
be identical okay so the so now we know that if we take a  strictly positive definite kernel
set of points into reproducing kernels hibert space with it and we take
a mean of set of points we are not losing any information it remembers all the points
so let's look at this mean map a little bit more so it takes a
set of points maps mean into that space takes the mean it has a few
interesting properties one is if we take a dot product between this point mu of X
so these mean they reproducing kernel hilbert space kernel mean for short
take a dot product between the kernel mean and some arbitrary function F and you get this
thing now you use the fact that K represents point evaluation of F which means that we
get F of XI here for this thing so therefore this mu in sense represents
the operation of taking the average of a function over a sample X so it's it's
the average operator so it's a compact way of computing the average of a
function and another interesting thing to point out here is if we now compute
the distance between the mu of sum set X in the mu of sum set
Y so we can first rewrite this thing this is also essentially schwartz by
saying that this difference vector  is equal to the supremum that we get by taking
dot products between this spector so the norm of this spector is equal to taking dot products with arbitrary
vectors F that have length at most one and then taking the supremum over this
okay I think you probably are familiar with this and here again we
have something of this form so we can use this  here we write it like this which
means that  that two means of two data sets in the feature space will have
a distance between them or will be different if and only if we can find functions
a funk function F in the reproducing kernel Hibert space that distinguishes the two sets of
of points so so the functions in Hilbert space distinguish the two sets of points in this
in this mean sense so the functions will have different values in average on
the ones at this point on the one set of points from the values
on the other set of points and if we have two data sets we can
also look at which function best witnesses this difference so if you think
about here which function do I have to plug in to maximize this thing
well actually is the function that's that's parallel to this vector but then normalized
by the length of this vector because here we have this constraint the function should have
length one so let's take a look how how this function looks it's actually kind of
instructive because if we now take two sets of data points let's say we take
data from a gaussian and data from laplace distribution one-dimensional and to make
it a little bit more difficult we will match the the first two moments so we
will make sure that the gaussian leplace both have mean zero and variance one
so they are not they're not trivial to distinguish you could say but let's distinguish them in
the reproducing kernel space of a gaussian kernel it turns out the gaussian
is strictly positive definite haven't proved that but with the gaussian we can distinguish anything
in principle so let's see how the gaussian distinguishes this so the gaussian has to
distinguished this by finding a function that best distinguishes the samples a function that on
twenty for that is the difference in
next is the defensive
is called the body and the body
monumentally metric
we can define
five hundred children this this is called the liberty the connection
but in this the course genetic of find an excelled
so the joystick
is a dependent of the choice of a five connections
so all
it doesn't define studies good morning the
one four
what a b c mean when your money or the
the it
of the also free
one actual so that those something is abundant she's
so we could put it
you know what it's a statistical manifold if
covariant derivative with the metric is called antisymmetric
in this case we can define
find one actual
it is called the order of one actual on one actual by this
in this case the data is also
statistical manifolds
we call the one or that you want to that this statistical one
statistical little the studies going to one of the structure of course
it's be the so this is the set of
density functionals parameterized by
instead of on show
can be divided the money the ways
local coordinate system c
then we can define e minimum imagery
by the fish
and commissioned the thirty six
we can define
one parameter family of
well i mean if i mean you will find connections like this
in this case
the medical structure
that this kind of forced
on the north coast
but as the functional
the function of
what times saying
there then we define local black
by this photo so
two arguments so
OK that makes a
up to the FA
a second
they were part
then this is a
thanks to all
this is a rule
these are
the functional elements
because it owned by the city
the derivative vanishes
on the second day the but if you move the money in metric only in
on the floor
that the but all the
the functional
we can define
a bit of
find connections
and in this case
but it but it's
mean only do one statistical manifolds
so we said that these models
in is study could money flows from the contrast function law
and this is example of other the functions
euclidean space
the the way
deeds of the euclidean distance
so set
half of
the square of the
the euclidean distance
in this case
is a contrast function
and the role in this is stunned the euclidean structure
the and stuff
among the euclidean metric
the the second example
divergence canonical divergence
we are open to all
convex functions going
we defined
want the functional
this and all indices of the statistical models
so the covered
over this connection or responses
but of course the euclidean distance
this quantity
this function is
you squared euclidean distance
it is also putting one day versus
because the discourse
four my diagrams one
so what
literally the contrast function
yes it over in points
we can define the contrast voronoi detour
it is formed
and we assume that voronoi regions for p
but so
mean in regions so
the plot shows
we go to the parts you
contrast voronoi diagram of p with respect to the functional
and then we must
so initially we think about the value of this is just the value in school
an interval has a particular value
OK we don't know what the value is so you think about this in the
bayesian way that we think all
i don't know what it is and to me the random variables
although it although this is one of the examples where
there's no frequency interpretation of this you can argue whether this is really random but
you don't know something to treated as though it was random
so let's try this thing is totally random
but in fact we treat the whole function of those random
we don't know what the function does until we evaluated
until actually compute what is of x equals two
well i don't really know
if i could just evaluate the function at all
at all values x then there wouldn't be a problem into
and then you can just then you could have some kind of about that so
you can evaluate all possible that
we get the recipe
you specify
distribution over functions like to say well
i don't know exactly what the function is but i assume something over the function
about the function u
the constant process
distribution over functions
and then
you start
measuring what the function values are
at various places
in this case does not make matter how you how you choose to export
you could use them at random or you could choose an equally spaced or
you could get somebody to just for you
it doesn't matter
so now
prior distribution over
together with the data implies the posterior distribution over
and the posterior distribution over f remember the posterior distribution just the bundle functions
that implies a distribution over the quantity the incident
because every one of those functions in the bundle
with a particular value to the article
now if you if we look at all the possible functions inside the funnel give
you all distribution
over the thing that makes it
so let's try
and do that
OK so now
now interested in the interval
over all the function
with respect
he here
where is the posterior gaussianprocess process
because this is just this is just the protection of the golf courses onto the
this function here
the result they were going to get out we also have gas distribution
it's an infinite dimensional projection but is just the prediction of the
we can compute the mean
and the variance of the thing
OK so that will tell us that
the assumptions we had about the functions
and given
the measurements we make about the function
we can now come up with a with the best guess the mean
and we can also
well what is the variance of the estimate
it doesn't just give the point predictions that tells us how
sure can be about the value
let's look at the mean function
in detail
if the average
if the value of this of this interval
in our interval here
and then we have to
integrate that with respect to all possible choices of the function f
from the posterior distribution like the posterior distribution of f is
that given the observed data
now we can we can we can swap around these two integrations and that'll give
us now
the interval of the
of all the average of the function with respect to the posterior distribution
this is just the
this is just the average
of the function
average now
outside perspective
if you think about this
the average function on the golf process
vector p
sometimes is p
we some covariance functions we might be able to evaluate this
well it's not going to the exact details and similarly with a little bit more
little bit more information science here we can also write down the variances again for
some choices of p in some grand function is things can also be computed in
closed form
OK that's the details in interesting times
the but in the slides if you're interested
here's an example