he was
OK so
all o
the reason why
nineteen for six
which would be useful to
this one
we want to
so the result
thank you for
it has struggled with
two that
for every one of these two
right is
that's the way love
it possible to with it
other notable
so what do you do distribution see the
he is
this the
so what
the problem is that
actually it
there is
i want to to be optimized
so what
the all right
so what you have here
so this is just a
you do that
three of
so what do we do
he also writes
did the
she wants
do that
and that
you to
so that we can do
there are just
since we use
some mobile devices and so on interact with whoever happens to be new neighborhood these
all use cases generated from industrial membership of our group and they say for these
kind of use cases idea schema expressivity is simply not enough
there are things
you cannot do that way
so that was the driver for definition of new language the web ontology language
the web ontology language of voices just horrible acronyms so i was much better and
also if any of you read winnie-the-pooh
OK then you know the story
so i only know it partially i think out loud
actually is somewhere in the stories OWL spells his name will
so what we found that the OK we can do that too brightly call out
and of course all of these requirements is quite a long list i had this
little list all staff and say saying was this long list of requirements of use
and then it's very difficult if you define what language does it all they have
some people that want some of it so you can't really agree on any single
language that that keep everybody happy so instead of defining what language you define ceiling
which is not allowed to say it you define what language with the layers right
now there was in job he
this single language with the different layers of expressiveness the idea of OWL lite in
because of transatlantic cooperation collaboration we have to spell it wrong way the idea idea
between by light is that it's simple classification hierarchy in the style of ideas schema
but with some simple constraints some of the constraints that you cannot say in in
schema so for example the domain property
formulated as a constrained everything must be from this type and if it's not then
it's the constraint that can be said in our
but it's very simple language
was the idea that OWL DL nielsen for description logics and that's because
it is based on description logic which
exactly balances on the point between maximal expressiveness while maintaining tractability so there people who
been doing homework for last ten
fifteen years maybe even longer to exactly met the complexity landscape of how much you
can experts say in logic while maintaining
reasonable tractability and OWL DL is poised exactly on so if you have a little
bit more to its complexity goes
and there's well understood formalizations for this kind of like six
so you can just think of OWL DL as a a well known description logic
was an XML syntax
that's that's really all there is
well in this if you mean that there is an there's an inference
the definition of prove rules and also implementation proved that are complete strangers
and that's
what you meant
well if people say completely so different things so yes you can do complete inference
in OWL and strictly speaking the theoretical complexity is bad news but the practical complexity
for realistic cases tool
and but this is not enough for some people some people for in particular wanted
this circular metal
what your question was was a thing is that you have classes that can be
themselves the value of the property or classes that can be a member of other
classes and these people want that kind of
certainly metamodel ndx expressions of OWL and so for that we all full
where you
basically you can do anything you want to use that ability in humans even decidability
it's not even the case that you cannot compute it efficiently you can compute it
it's not a matter to be clever enough there's no the universe that there exists
an algorithm will to complete reasoning for full also means that the standard formal semantics
that we use for yellow lights no longer apply have to do some non standard
formalisation which was developed more or less for the purposes of OWL full and well
you have all the syntactic freedom of RDF said you could you want i mean
you could do everything you want to stay with this technical innovation rules of RDF
including applying the language to itself
so you can say that the subclassof relationship has maxcardinality two
we saying that every class is most subclasses
that's really applying the language to its own constructions
so that already shows you that you can forget about the fisheries with those kind
of language
and i think it's complexity something like p space
so it's not quite higher order because the number of predicates elements still countable and
if to have
over countable number credit brokers dealing with before it becomes really order but it you
can add more or less predicates as variables
that is
let's do this year but this is like a very rich you could
we have things like it really useful for right
yes it is really just because it's useful i seem to convince in this case
is the one limit the classes
so we you have classes of classes often is problem when you model particular domain
whether you something is an instance of model something is the a class
so we had this debate within the only case i think so we have the
class of all boeing airplanes clearly class right now is seven four seven is a
of all the planes or is it just a particular
type of of airplane an instance of the class but of course a particular seven
four seven on the on on the platform tarmac somewhere that's an instance of that
class of seven four seven so depending from which viewpoint you look at the main
something is either class or instance also what happens is that two people with the
same domain one of the model is class one of model is an instance you
want to say that these two articles
but now the you can do it because you have to decide
idea class for instance between the inequality between two would across the boundary
so there i
realistic use cases i see increase schreiber two a mapping between the art and architecture
desires in wordnet and
which is about the village useful thing to do and it in a very elegant
way by using class construction get around this site
it just means that you can implement reasons for but you could not guarantee these
reasons give you all the
that's the price you pay
it doesn't mean it's impossible to reason with just impossible to complete
if you don't care about computers and people like that hayes said it was very
a great advocate all the same who can make this because you the data that
you start with a single did you start with incomplete in the first place
if you start with reasoning about stuff on the web already
so you can that your reasoning a little bit more incompleteness so he says that
all completeness
above all the others area
but then he comes with his medical applications is now if i want to argue
that there is not the particular driver really want know is there
in one those you know because i'm used to be my reasoning
there's really genuine case for you to believe
and got a in the long sequence
algorithm says sorry you can't match this
so moment what i'm going to do is i'm going to look here and say
OK failed where do i go back to
sorry i can't help you you can't done enough you haven't got anything that you
can keep for further so you've got to come back to the same place and
you're going to find yourself doing sorry here this column missing which is just saying
compare this a with a you have just seen
and you advance one compare the b with the next a same as before it
says sorry the b and they have different you've got come back to to start
so can the which is here with the first
then the b with the BCI everything's OK bnb that's alright they match to be
which is here and you can notice we've got the big the beginning of the
fragment a b
so the b compares with b
then you advanced version a from the little sequence and the sea
but what happens there was is going to say no it doesn't work but again
i'm sorry just the fact that got to see here doesn't help us we can't
say exploit this to be able to gain something so we could go back to
the start
so let's get to the interesting case
so then we compare the a with the authority a that we've got here with
this c then the a for a with the a
the be with the CE let's let's get to a nice place with a b
would be so as to be the case here the third which is here with
that is here
see with this c
and we've got all string and i fact my example isn't that useful because i
haven't sorry see the only place i did was here a b c
i would have been able
to just say what position
OK i'm sorry it's not it's not an easy one to explain to people in
string spend spend about three was not explaining this
now try to do it in ten doesn't work
OK so
just a quick conclusion about about these business of looking for patterns in strings looking
in patterns for strings is an open area of research where people are actually trying
still today to gain as much as possible but basically on the constants
you can't going on much more than on the concensus to try and really do
as fast as possible
these looking for patterns in strings
so just the word the complexity of KMP instead of being as she might have
the the
multiplication of the complexity of of the sorry the length of the first string by
the length of the second-string thanks to this sort of tricks we've managed to have
a complexity which is the length of the first string plus length the second feature
OK plus because you basically only
you never going backwards which is what's interesting it
OK so we've got the strings and now what we'd like to do is to
be able to put in order over a the set of strings all over is
a set of strings is given a set of strings and you wanted to be
able to go through that sort of strings in a particular ways what sort of
order relations and we have
so the first thing is when to suppose we do have an alphabetical order as
basic so that in alphabetical order over the
you've got that networking events from that
so once the alphabetical order
the first order and you can do on strings is the prefix for three prefix
or interest is to say that one string is
prefix office second string
one string is prefix of the country this is not a total ordering i didn't
say we only got to do to flooring but this is a nice ordering can
be used in certain cases easy second one which is the well-known order is the
lexicographic order this is the dictionary order
the dictionary order is you've got enough of a particular order on the symbols so
you can then put whatever set singles was so set of strings you have you
can put them in a dictionary
the dictionary might be in
so during the cancer say that either one string is the prefix of the other
right all they share up to a certain place a common prefix
and then if i look at the next letter with the next letter is going
to be the difference one just for the alphabetical order
OK there are problems with the lexicographic order they rarely problems the problems are that
you can't do
recursion based on that thematic lord
basically if you look at certain
cases i can if i decide that is before b
the real problem is that in between a and b
we would like to be able to get their reasonably quickly there's actually an infinity
of strings
for the alphabetical order
because i can do a
a b
and so on all these strings
or all
smaller than b
that makes it not nice ordering to work when we working with strings even if
it's the natural wonders of one we're using when we're looking into addiction but it
actually we do not have
an infinity of strings so it's not a problem but if we do have a
possible infinity of strings that with got
so the next one that is mostly used when people are working on saying grammatical
inference because that is my topic but you use it more generally when you're working
on strings is
ah the length lex order
the idea is to say we want to avoid this but we do like the
dictionary order so we just make sure that we start by ordering with the victory
all strings of length zero there's just one length of the string of length zero
so we basically recognised the
the remaining variance as the sum
this is the variance of the k column this is the variance in the cape
colony so two sides and time the best case columns and some other variants of
the k column
so we basically get the results
the the error is equal to two
times and squared
times the sum of the variances of discarded columns so these are discarded columns
so if we want to minimize its variance
so if you want to minimize the error
we should minimize
the variance of the columns we discard
is that makes sense
geometrically it makes no sense and ability put so that later
so basically this little simple purpose saying if we're doing feature extraction in such a
way that we're trying to throw away features from data in such a way that
we're trying to preserve this distance matrix
the way we should do that is discard directions of least variance
or retain directions of most variance
so how does that work in practice one
we like to do two dimensional
representations of our data
why do we like to the two-dimensional representations about data because we can show them
on slides
so if we do the two-dimensional representation about data so we retain the two largest
variance columns
from this data and then we look at a distance matrix
representation of data that's what we see
so it's trying to represent
so it's not doing particularly good job i mean you can see it's getting the
dominance a little bit
but not really because it's the flattening all the way across that if we go
to ten dimensions sort of things start to improve it
but still
it's not clear that the maxima is really one hundred eighty in fact this one's
gone a bit of minimum quite close to one hundred eighty for ten dimensions isn't
really helping
we go to
a hundred dimensions
now you can start seeing perhaps this minimum
about one hundred eighty you don't see this structure though this grading structure particularly well
rotation of each ninety degrees so some of the finer structure isn't really that
if you go to a thousand dimensions
so we started off with the four thousand ninety six dimensional dataset
and we have
governor three courses mentions
is actually a particularly great dimension reduction
now you really start to see the structure of things seen in about one thousand
dimensions if you're going to do feature selection
to extract these guys and retain retained the quality of this in point distance matrix
so in some sense you could say it's not a great algorithm the
there you go
so what we basically doing here
this is now
how high dimensional dataset it's got two dimensions and
and what we're going to do is we're going to try and reduce it to
one dimensional dataset
so so i can show you how that productions taking place
so what this variance maximum variance is saying is that we should look the direction
of maximum variance along this direction experience looks like a standard deviation about six variance
around thirty six
around this direction it looks to be more like
so there
the standard deviation sixteen
so here we should be retained in this direction and discarding this direction according to
the algorithm we just described
so what does that involve doing that involves projecting all these data points
o onto the x axis and replacing original data
with that
so all structure with throwing away their
between all these points immediately
great isn't so that's the algorithm
there's a bit of a more sensible algorithm that is very obvious
if you think about one thing
preserves interpoint distances i can rotate
this dataset
all the interpoint distances stay the same
so if i make a rotation
i'm doing nothing
to lose any i can be make any rotation like
so what should i do well it seems to make sense to try to take
the data
such that when i project
onto the
x axis
i'm losing a lot less information
so look at the size of these projections here
this is the size of the projection
and actually in this example there are quite strongly correlated you could envisage examples where
it was even true
well you've got a sort of less variance in that direction and more and sort
stronger correlations
and this becomes even true
in fact this can be very true for the digital data the artificial data we
sort of improved idea
is to do this rotation first
so we rotate
to align data so the experience in the directions of maximum variance are aligned with
the axes and then we extract these interpoint distances
so we need the rotation that will minimise residual error
we already derived an algorithm
for discarding directions
and it said that we should discard direction with maximum variance
the error is then given by the sum of residual variances
rotations of the data matrix do not effect this analysis at all
those distances all remain the same
what this means is we should rotate
to find the directions of maximum variance
we're so rotate so that the maximum variance directions are aligned with the axes and
then discard the lower variance direction
now you might recognise algorithm and will come back to that
but if you do that this is what you get
so on the left this is distances reconstructed from two dimensions
of the data set
remember the two dimensional example before
well that
i two dimensional example is already showing
we've got a sort of minimum one hundred eighty to one hundred dimensions before we
saw that structure
in the example we're just doing feature selection
this is distances reconstructed with ten dimensions
you're seeing the fine structure in the grids
with only ten dimensions
it took
a thousand dimensions
to see that before
if we go two hundred dimensions
low ph writes about ph three first forecast benzoate gas so
what's going to happen is this virion will respond in a defensive manner
there's there's the principle
that's in chemistry that is analogous to newton's third law
you know
action reaction
it's called alicia tell you principle
alicia telling principle
after the french
scientist who enunciated
should tell you principle
and it and it talks about the restoring force
the restoring force
exerted by chemical system
sort of force exerted by
chemical system
and what is this restoring force designed to do
it's designed to
minimize the impact of any perturbation
designed to minimize
the effect of any perturbation
by perturbation i mean out of physical preservation i mean chemical shift any kind of
chemical perturbation
let's say we have the
z iron sitting happily in neutral solution and suddenly the ph
suddenly the ph drops
how can the virion respond
what do i do to write two
bring the ph back to where it was before the disturbance
what is the manifestation of ph it's prototype
so somehow
the proton concentration suddenly one way up
driving the ph way down
annunziata iron sitting here
is there are right here
we consider in do to minimize the impact this flood of protons
well of the two possibilities how do you neutralise something you either flood this with
start flooding this with hydroxyl
in order to neutralize
i will consider i and i see no hydroxyl so that's no good
but what could around
there's a carboxylic acid and
an attachment site for protons
so what's the i can do
is to gobble up
excess proton
in order to
bring the ph back to where it was before
so let's write a reaction
it triggers this response which is
we know
when i put the
but the carboxylic acid over to the right here
so now this is from the solution
this is from the solution is trying to bring the ph back to where it
was before
the proton
and attaching the proton to this carboxylic acid and
so what's happened out its veteran
this and the negative and has been capped so better i'm now
is a net positive
it's not positive now over here it's not neutral
and it's gobbling up protons from the solution
so this is really an acid base reaction
for which i can write k
the acid dissociation constant and you know i'm getting tired writing all these characters our
reformat this so i'm going to say this is
the virion is going to represent as
proton plus the rest
this is proton
and what's this thing here this is now
there's been an iron
the which proton has attached i've attached the proton to the net neutral species k
i can rewrite this reaction in
the more compact notation so a captures all of this other stuff minus the
so i can write the k for that reaction
OK one will equal
concentration of proton
times the concentration of
neutrals virion over the concentration of this
protein it's better on the iron onto which we've glommed this
proton from the
solution and we're going to take a page out of sorensen's book and will take
the log of both sides
and then we can say that
pk one
is equal to
he h
but i'm writing ten here but you know in engineering if you see ILOG it's
typically log base ten i know some of the math classes
they use the
elegy to represent natural log but
it's uncommon engineering
right so here's the
here's the sorenson version of the equation
and what this tells us is that at fifty percent
fifty percent association words when fifty percent of the z orion has gobbled up
the proton to generate this protein eighteen species
this ratio is equal
fifty percent
z orion on protein eight fifty percent protein eight is of the log of one
is zero and that's the phd gives us the value of the
of the acid dissociation constant
fifty percent of
spiteri and we have
the concentration
of the sphere
the motivation
research point of view is that there's a great deal of interest on
something called deep belief networks and you're going to get three hours of lectures on
the belief networks by geoff hinton but let me quote him
even though he's not here
this is from scholarpedia
deep belief nets are probabilistic generative models that are composed of multiple layers of stochastic
latent variables you should hopefully understand what that means
and i can draw pictures as well
the latent variables typically have binary values and are often called hidden units or feature
detectors so just imagine multiple layers of binary variables
the top two layers of undirected symmetric connections OK so the top two is an
undirected graphical model of some kind
the lower layers receive top-down directed connections from the layer below
OK so the the top looks like an undirected graph and the lower layers look
like a directed graph that layer
the states of the units in the lowest layer represent a data vector so the
data appears at the bottom and all of these layers
on top of the data are hidden layers that are meant to explain
what the data
so that's it
a quote from jeff of what people eat that is and
here's what we're going to do
there's been a huge amount of interest in this area there are lots of papers
on deep belief nets but people have addressed some interesting questions in particular they have
to address questions of for example how deep should this network be given some data
do we need one or three or seven layers to model the data
how wide should each layer be doing the ten hidden units per layer or a
hundred or thousand for example
and and also what sorts of units should we have should we have binary units
continuous units etcetera so the definition had usually binary units or something like that but
we could have other kinds of units can the model learn this stuff
from the data
so the goal of what i'm going to describe this to learn the structure of
the network
and the approach is going to be
to have a nonparametric bayesian methods
the learned structure of a layered directed deep belief network from data so i'm going
to ignore this sort of definition that had undirected connections the popular and i'm just
going to assume is directed all the way down
the model might look like this
the data are at the bottom it's directed acyclic graph with layers
and each other some variable number of layers in each layer as some
variable width
how many layers should there be how wide should each layer b
all right so
what we want to do is we want to do inference over these quantities the
number of layers and the width of the layers so the way we're going to
do this is we're going to think of hidden variables
the structure of the graph
so we're going to say
z i j and horsey i j and keep a happy
is equal to one
means that j
is a parent of node i
in layer m
that is node j is the parent node i'm layer and so these are binary
variables representing the connections that appear in this
in particular if we specify a sequence of binary matrices one for each layer
all right so
start again
so just to
to review
we're looking at
general approach
optimizing the
by risk the expectation of five y times f of x
and asking the question when does so supposing we had complete information about the probability
or you could leave work in the population case when does minimisation of the
expectation of a
phi correspond to minimisation of the risk
so we have these definitions motivated by by considering the conditional expectation of five y
times f of x
when we fix the single x
and if we think about the conditional probability of x
having some value you
and we minimize over
all values that f of x might take
the conditional expectation of five y times x and that's
if we compare that to
h minus the leader
eight months later is the minimum of the same quantity subject to the constraint that
the value
the argument here that the alpha that corresponds to the set of x fixed point
has the wrong sign sign is different from
the sign of the minus one
so we compare these two certainly a cheerleader should be
the the optimum should be better than this this constraint up
what we like is that it's strictly better
right so
if we look
and focus on single x
and we certainly but i hope that
optimisation the constrained to have the wrong sign will lead to the evalu
then we may not constrained
because otherwise
we could get the optimal value
without getting the right side and then for classification would be in trouble right for
the risk indicator of going the same route would be in trouble
OK so we call this classification calibrated if we have strict inequality
inequality for all conditional probability is not equal to one
because that's a point wise
kind of a condition
the last definition before i tell you the result
and i'm
i'm standing the definition just for convex phi actually everything that i have to say
here is is true more generally
we just is more complicated for non convex five it's in the whole motivation here
is to use a convex surrogate for this this cost function you know it's
it's probably
reasonable to look at the specific case where phi is is convex it it's a
little simpler
so given a convex
we can define this this function
so i
so at theta it's five zero
h one plus the driver two
right now
we could equivalently written this as h minus one plus the driver two
right to the
five zero is for convex phi we can always achieve the optimal meant
five zero
all right so let's look at this example
you you recall this is the
this is the shape of a church when we looked at that truncated quadratic
it has this entropy like
sia theta as we move away from the half this thing is is symmetric about
i guess that's obvious from the
from the definition here we can change it to to one minus eta we're optimizing
over the old alpha so we haven't changed anything
right so these things are symmetric about half so as you move away from the
half we're looking at how does
differ from five zero five zero is the value at either equals half up here
which is one in this case so what and how h decreases as we move
away from
the maximal value and that this function
in red a sign
all right so this we can equivalently think of it as as i say the
difference between a ge minus at some value and h at that value
you know the gap right we want h minus to be strictly bigger than a
ge this function is is looking at the gap between the two in the non
convex case we have to do something else to make this a convex function it
turns out you will see later on we with the property and that's the the
right thing to do but as i say you know there's a little
a little bit of extra extra work but all of the results that that are
present go through in the in the case of arbitrary
five bounded from below
all right so
this is the main theorem so any questions about the definitions
so this these quantities you should all be clear
OK so so he is the
the main results about the relationship between risk and virus it's actually relationship between
so this is a unique name
the idea is that different rest
but there involved in the same potential function which is usually so i given that
so many of these two x two x five x was
graph that user x sixty two
OK that's the way because they appear argument conditional access
so the first thing to do the right thing to
parents and
after the draft directive on a section on the rest of so this not formalisation
because his parents very happy here
i mean
that's what i call
that's just take
explain this is really about that
o course
when we were beautiful
not forget and sees that might come up very different situations so for
in addition and put in all the links of his car power
so i'm trying to teach you and general procedure which is correct and also notion
of multiple queries
queries per
during learning with latent variables in the end and also when you call to infer
something about the world so these queries was
the in different
that's exactly area
first learning and also
right so that means for the tree structured graphical models
the first of all there no clue about changes
by the whole
the question models are also trees
exact inference of tree is the basis for
which is also the general exact inference problems already
that was the basis for many algorithms which we're going to to
that's very small trees
and more
in the case of trees because there's no explaining away trees can be very simple
for example so it's
in the last year graph one
makes problem
so just just to remind you you know this graph here
this graph here is not a tree
because this has more than one
this graph is still singly connected to but they are for example not to this
is simple
OK so
now in the first two general strategy
for surfaces
on trees and what is the
these trees
work towards node
so we consider
so some nodes in the tree
which has the highest
he died in the middle of the inference procedure may seem obscure to you
because i didn't talk about
clearly are the sons are converge onto writing
i think that but i just mentioned we have
that thousands the nodes
no i j is one
we're eventually you have to know why is that
and this is the symmetry of
when we said j
one of the variables excluded here actors create something of the
so that is the case here
we're these variables one by one and we the same variable we're left with is
conditional distribution
and that there are just so you have an example when we say that x
five from quite
got some
which depend on everything that was to on x three and x
six next so
when we said we want to use one only seven j
military what factors could be created
and tree
we can actually vary from state so that know
subtrees below j when say well i mean for history
now the nose in search of these because there are already some day if we
proceed from the leaves to root
once you get to j
everything is true that already
so in order the situation is that he always showed before
parents by the time we get to do everything in the
gardens so there's no way to any
factors involved no labels
and i think
if you have any other subtrees since some over a dozen interactive all trees
he has to treat so there's no
interaction between the particles so only the only
back to create the day
how do we know which is unique heritage
after years of conditional distributions
p j
so here's
this is true
there's true here some some three years later is a tree which she figures
we are almost ready to begin so welcome to the third
tutorial review session of this
workshop in summer school
as you know we
i have these sort of tutorial reviews running all through the school for ten days
or so
what we're going to talk about today is is
about geometric methods and manifold learning so what michelle belkin and
i'm going to do
is split of presentation between the two of us and hopefully what people would be
able to communicate to you is
some idea
class of methods that
i have received some attention over the last decade or so
and the perspective on machine learning that seems to have emerged over the last decade
two and it's very
sort of geometrically oriented point of view with which one can approach questions in that
recognition and machine learning
o and sometimes even in numerical computation
and hopefully you will get a sense of the way in which ideas from
probability and statistics
ideas from
computer science
algorithms and especially graph theory
and ideas from
geometry and topology
come together in some sort of a natural way
in this setting
the logistics of this is like this
i speak for about
and our no more than an hour and fifteen minutes after which we
they can break for about fifteen minutes may show with
then speak for about an hour after that
maybe an hour and fifteen minutes
will take a second break
and then
we'll have a closing session for about half an hour to wrap up odds and
ends and things of that sort
the context
in which all of this
really developed
is really the context of data analysis and machine learning problems in in very very
high dimensions
so increasingly we live in a world in which we are faced all the time
by learning problems in very very high dimensional spaces in genetics and neuroscience in image
analysis piece analysis or other problems that we might have worked on
the basic and fundamental sort of question that faces all of us is to try
and understand under what circumstances it might be possible
to make effective inferences in high dimensional spaces without running into
the so-called curse of dimensionality
OK so
as far as i see it
people have course known about the curse of dimensionality for a long time
there are at least
three different points of view
from which one can approach the central issue
the first and the most classical of these
is the point of view of smoothness
so that we clarify
it has been known for a long time
suppose you're trying to learn the function
and it's a function of several variables
has say
s derivatives
so it belongs to
what is called the sobolev space h HSA
so it's a function
maybe actually used
border little bit
actually show you are trying to use this hand
OK maybe i'll use this might maybe this is that OK
so i have a function
from are the
two are
so it's a function of the variables and it has its derivatives and l tools
so f
belongs to h s
something like this then the rates of convergence looked like this this is the number
of examples you need to learn a function
and i think
it's actually something
like this to us plus the something like OK not as would be but approximately
is already
if you look at that rate
you see that if s the smoothness
is of order d
the rate does not depend upon the dimension
and therefore
there is no cause of dimensionality
OK so this is of course known for a long time and so people realize
that if the function you're trying to learn a function of several variables in a
function in high dimensional spaces but it's very small and the smoothness
is in the particular sense
then there is no curse of dimensionality and this insight on this observation has an
algorithmic reflection
so based on this insight
people have realized for a long time that perhaps it's a good idea
to try and learn smooth functions perhaps it's try it's a good idea to try
and fit the smoothest function that you can do the data
any other set of questions or requests
it's more about this
the fundamental from the classifier
things where this one zero instead
that in here
all o
the part of the because i'm i'm surprisingly maybe
from what i sound like i'm not trained as a statistician
and i if you pick up any classic textbook in statistics they'll tell you about
frequentist theory
there are different kinds of frequentist theory as well
and i think it would do you really poor job if i try to explain
OK so
all talk about the classification problem
let me just show you a particular picture
OK let's let's let's deal with this problem because i think
the feature selection problem sort of interestingly related to classification
but still this picture first
in the machine learning community people have talked about two different
approaches are two different methodologies
generative models and discriminative models so you'll hear those terms being used a lot
imagine that you are trying to do classification with some input x
some classes y so why could be possible minus one
generative model
is a model for the
probability it's basically a model for all of the variables in your data sets so
it involves
a model with the prior probabilities of the two classes like for example you might
believe that one class is much more frequent than the other class of prairie right
p of why is the probability of the probabilities of these two classes which you
can learn from data
and then the other component is the class conditional density
so the probability of of
inputs x given the class label
OK so it's a classic example of that imagine doing classification i think
each of my classes is modeled by calcium OK
so class plus one is modelled by gauss in class minus one is modelled by
gaussians OK
then in a generative model what i would do is i would model the data
in class one with the calcium all the data in class minus one with the
gaussians and then i would apply bayes rule to try to compute the optimal decision
boundary which is
given by the point at which probability of y equals plus one given x is
greater than point five say that's or equal to point five percent of calls him
OK that method is really bad right
so why is it really that this is one of the places where
you know being a little bayesian can be very dangerous
the reason is really bad is that
you know the probability of data given class one
might be
you know completely nongaussian there might be some complicated shape
and by making the strong assumptions about the class conditional density
you can get really screwed
so naive bayes models for example i hate that term naive bayes because
it's first of all the not even trained in bayesian manner
and second of all
you know
there are there really i mean if because naive models
so naive bayes models essentially what they do is they say
the class conditional density
here the probability of x given y
it involves
it assumes that all of your your input variables are independent given y
OK that's what the naive bayes model and that's a really terrible model you get
really terrible results most of the time unless you're
input features really are independent given the class
generative models basically half the model of the data both the axis and the y
discriminative models
try to directly models the conditional distribution of y given x
in other words they don't have to necessarily model the input distribution the distribution of
the axes
OK so for example you're you're directly trying to model the
class boundary
you know or you could be directly modeling the last boundary the set of points
for which
if you believe that your classification
in two one classes
the same as a classification to the other
this is most easily
the seeing if we just look at one of these pictures OK now i know
that it's very hard to see see thing grey lines here
OK good
here's here's the bayesian approach to linear classification
before observing data
what i'm going to do is i'm going to believe that
the class boundary could be
any line in the plane so could be this line it could be this line
to be this line et cetera
after i observe the data
so first OK before observing the data i'm going to believe that it could be
any lines and i'm going to sign
a uniform probability to every possible direction of the line
so the same probability for any possible direction line now after i observe the data
and you can
exploit it
without having to do all the things that the system do is not having to
find collect put together installed
process manipulates all the semantic information on the web
so most probably the most famous
of the system is integer developing very gallery
originally the simple very simple entity lookup service this thing you give it to see
where i have entity
it tells you in which RDF documents on the web this entity is mentioned always
used always described
you can do the same with keywords
again simply use the keyword you semantic document contains entity about a given keywords and
now you can in addition to model structured queries i simple example is
if you use this one it's a bit more complicated because it's use what is
called content negotiation
meaning that you have to say
in the end of the request like
type of thing you expect so here they i say i want to RDF
and i want
always the RDF documents on the web that talks about much that can this talk
is not about me
r and then it give me
in RDF representation
saying that you are a number of results result one
it is
semantic entity
corresponding to match that in is the web page
describing in the semantic web that hogg semantic wiki this is very simple but when
you know that they RDF data in this place
but you can use and you can and that actually concern and is relevant to
this particular entity
which is me
you can do
a bit more structured query you can have for example for documents
containing entities that for full name that like
so in that case you will find myself to find basically all you can ask
for much like
as an entity
being of the class person so used to evade the city and organizational anything that
is has the same name you won't get you want you get person and in
any case it returned it gives you the precise location
of the semantic data for document containing all the that describe what you asked for
there is one very simple but very useful application
of that which is the multiple again for the drupal
CMS is the idea of modes
it is me it means meaning of the term is that it can link tag
used to annotate any resource
four pictures of articles or anything to your eyes
two implying that if you look to your right you specify what is the meaning
disambiguated you say my talk about paris
you say
you can link back paris two very similar name meaning that paris would become
the city and that are essential to know anything like this very very simple
plugin for drupal
when which you can use mode two
whatever you do it tagging it we got to see in each
and try new documents that content concerning tag then you can choose a i actually
link your taxes arrive and then you have semantic applications for your content
this is
or pretty nice one thing
that is
and i think we need to put it on the new zealand national semantic document
what you want to do with it if you want to exploit it if you
want to create a few simply to explore it you have to do it yourself
so watson
it is based on similar ideas because the first we call it the semantic web
gateway for the semantic web as it includes all
the future you need to find and exploit
unless i'm getting old
it better be the same inconsequential like
OK axiom system it's a
and the definition of
this is what we want to prove
to show this relation
it's the same thing as this
on the first of the formula
first i'm going to simplify the job of it
before the first
zero flee
i'm going to
observe that this is a two way
proof so by conditional
and it's always a lot easier than the
first of all if
there is a derivation
of a from gamma then
in the example
and by gamma
that's cool
of the soundness of this
and it is
this deduction
deducibility relation
there's everything it says is correct
the converse direction
is completeness
that is to
is it but it doesn't leave anything out
if anything really is
entailed by giving them
soundness is much easier to fix than can
so i'm going to knock off sound at first
concentrate on the real thing
how do we prove
but this
deducibility relation
is sound relative to the semantics
we're all
of course we do it by induction on the length of the derivation here
the shot repetition we always say
the shortest derivation of a from gamma
and that's all it indicates is that a case where we have the derivation of
length one
that the that's the proof
and then there's the case where it comes
by the mid from somebody
if b then c
and i mean function hypothesis we know
the is indeed help get
so is
if b and c
but then
it's obvious
the c is also
let's look at the truth table for b and b then c which i didn't
actually spell out because you know it so well
i mean
take any
interpretation the
and valuation satisfies everything in gamma
it satisfies this
it just buys this
OK so the definition of
is such that is obviously going to satisfy c
implication satisfied if and only if
c is satisfied albeit not that is that is to in
so the induction step for once is going to be trivial all the work goes
i got proof of length one
how could be very well
could be a member of gamma
now what if i don't know what selection bias is present selection bias may be
and they have
example in people with hypertension
well work and this is kind of tricky to understand
and it's tricky for me to think that if
continues trying to say
the causal DAG could not be the one in a way i could have this
causal that
because we
but what i mean by the square root note by the way
it means that this is
you know that that's instantiated
it's not an observer noted for selection node
it means for all
and it is of the population
this node is instantiated the same value
right so
i'm saying
that causes us
the causes
and everybody in the population has the same value of s
could this be what i'm observing
but i think it could be
if everybody was instantiated
remember the discounting
this node is instantiated these two are rendered deep under
which means that actually easy would be dependent
all right that's the for sale goes that way now
i mean x and y are independent
it's actually dependent on cx will also be dependent on these parents
selection bias could not be here
could be like this
because we wouldn't have this observed dependency again because that's instantiations so these guys independent
and because it's sale goes this way
that's would also be dependent on y
the causal DAG could be the one in b
could selection bias up you're going like that
because now i don't have this problem i instantiate the
for everybody
which makes axon http and
since these arrows both go this way and the head-to-head meeting
x h and y are independent
so by the d separation argument that means that some three
so this could be what's going
i could get get is pretty complicated like so what's going on that observing x
y z and w
and in the background the a hidden costs of as the
the selection bias going and with his very blocks but they could be what's going
on right it's it's complicated but it could be was going out
so i can
i can have this
now could selection bias here
this is the edge that i learned before the has because
you could this be selection by
no i can't because you instantiate this note
that's actually the same is again and and basically and largely appealing to intuition here
because it proved formally is much more work but
by instantiate this node that not much different than instantiating this one
member by noses value ranges actually y dependent because of discounting
i do the same thing these child in the same way because because it's child
depends on
and c
so by now
this value
i still discounting going
it's not much different than instantiating the itself
so i can tell
function bias like this going and
i couldn't tell the one to be even
and that's because of different problem
this node is instantiated
this way
h and w are independent
because these arrows both go and
h axis
so the independent would between w one x w one x being independent
not independent conditional on c which is
i was
observed that would have observed that and i'm not observing this
like the bottom line is you can never
turn this heroine
so i can tell us and i can't find this arrow going and so i
cannot either situation
i can't the selection variable without hindrance
because i can't ever with the hidden cause
two different reasons
one would be a violation of x and y be independent the other being
it would make w independent of x
so back i can
i can of this i can't that
i told you i can't decide really care about that
i could have done
so say anything about selection bias that i could have
has he pointing the w
this is the only one of these four possibilities i can have
so the bottom line here
is that
once to make the causal embedded faithfulness assumption
the thing is that when have a parametric model
when the parameter estimation d
then there is the way
to make sure that mentions these are the initial parameters using something called something called
the future is called victoria
this is the gradient of the log that you have
one of the of
it is he
these heuristic sequence
and is that so you have your from model we assume that you are estimated
one parameter
a zero here
that is optimized for you that question is suppose you get a sequence cannot subsequently
to victoria
what do we need to compute the gradient down
on the second of sequence with the model one of the famous made
so here is a great time so by definition of victoria
o mentioned the mission of that which is the which is the same for all
and what is it or you can make you can already so there is a
small tree here which are to the typically you can see that three-dimensional data this
is away from some street to victoria and then you can use the victoria as
input to SVM
so what do we do that well the justification for this problem would involve
detail that we should not i don't want to enter into now because
but in fact what you you see is what you get when you take the
gradient of what we try to use some that the parameters which is how much
each parameter inference is that the your
o points
OK i just sequence
this is given permission
try to use your model
two strikes the inference of it for you use all of your of different interests
and in fact the
is that you don't
in fact for the participation of these two interesting justification that that company should all
the first one is that in instead of taking the in the UK take strange
thing here
which is the normalized so instead of taking the inner product between the features going
to assume that the metric induced by the
fisher information matrix is twenty days but if you do that then you something that
that becomes independent
i found this argument
so what is that
here you've model
that's fine
set of distributions
it depends on the top
but you can use
that's right the same set of distributions with different parameter
noted that try to be friends well it turns out that if you apply like
you can here doesn't depend on the way you are which was any your
OK so it's because of the fact that the that says anything using the current
and more importantly always it's a bit tricky to prove it has been shown so
when the canal i was presented that
if you assume that your your fish can alter the model
the bible class
then you should be using SVM with gaussian kernel
should be at least as good as using something called the MAP estimate so i
will not until to the set of this but roughly speaking i'm not sure is
doesn't hypothesis which are usually not
satisfied particular occasions but is the beginning of the justification of why should use that
OK so this is the view that if use it in a few hours
i was that told to because then
the shock and it's good because we do as well as what we do
if you use the generative model the navy navy mean by making the classes in
the necessary probability of the class
OK i will not say more about that in practice it has been used because
in practice
the question is you can see that it turns out that most promising models using
but it is a graphical models for many others like it and you can easily
compute the score vector
i just called victoria
and so on
so it's and its some more efficient and i mean
editions the complete this you're doing estimation graphical models
but still it was historically the first one is that you use the graphical processing
you know the represent the stream by definition of data
now i will present the second
general class
of camels
l discussions on the use of basically graphical models for structural pattern recognition
since it's the last sort of lectures i don't want to be too
two technical
i want to give some motivation more and give you some examples of promised yesterday
i how use this stuff in
solving some quite difficult image understanding problems
again all do the same as it did yesterday today my mind go straight through
but not to host
so i want to do is remind you where we were yesterday
where we
ah yes here
so yesterday
i i been discussion on
what you might call we call the graph matching problem processing in structural pattern recognition
is the pattern recognition problem in vision
and that is the problem of matching features
a small set of features often to a very very large typically features causing
and we discussed various of modern approaches to that in terms of spectral methods misplaced
methods methods in bayesian bayesian network methods
and in talk yesterday
the game emphasizes the continuum between exact
the exact models and exact inference through to inexact models and exact inference and being
able to choose the right
the inside to choose the right position on that continuum to really get things all
functioning in useful particularly in our area with lots of data
and yesterday we focus on
three to illustrate the things on points at MAX matching and really situations also with
that will really not attributed
that is not just point so to speak of an additional unlabeled graphs
with adjacency matrices matrices and the like
well the training of the shared his vision is not like that when we
when we solve problems like matching ten places seems to think is we observe the
segmented typically from segmentation always tough to processes have attributes like orientation making of length
they have size colour
he has said yesterday and so
and so do the binary attributes not just distance
they can have very very very many different types of attributes so then the problem
really generalizes up to an attributed graph matching problem
so yesterday in the last a paradigm we we spoke about we spoke about graph
itself being conceived of as a markov random field
where each of the nodes with the random variable
because have the number of states
the discrete random variable and those states happen to be
the way we propose that the state of the same
and we pose a problem of graph matching deriving the optimal state for each node
which of course different by definition give you a solution to the problem or
template matching right
and we went through the junction tree algorithm has is one of the things we've
been looking at and compared to other other approximate like
the station based at
the markov property of the random field came from defining some sort of dependencies of
some vertices on his
and that this is typically the some sort of local local connectivity
it came about for example by triangulation call
world congress
and you saw how we then took those
those cliques
and then decompose the potential function is fixed pairwise which is the traditional thing to
do but we also noted yesterday that's not necessarily the only thing you could do
and all often depend on the type of invariance is the type of the order
statistics are important and those sorts of things
an extension to
that type of formulation for inferences
is really a problem too
attributed graph matching so what we simply do
is actually have
i hidden markov random field
and hidden markov random field is really a generalization of the a hidden markov model
so for every study
i have a series of observations or
i have a state dependent
the observation probability density function
like in hidden markov models i might have certain calling which has a certain probability
density being by
same thing with this problem for every every every state every time a feature for
example the distance different distribution of attributes for example the the
the iris may have a different colour distribution then for example a certain type of
pigmented skin
but the problem is still the same
i still want to infer the hidden states
now the hidden states using the
terminology of hidden markov models from two things
an observation model
and the markov random field model
just like in hidden markov models have memory model in the hidden markov model like
which is the markov chain
i have an observation model which are bring together
by that
in the dynamic programming algorithm all the that were shouting for estimation
the thing is now
hidden markov random fields
unless i create an inexact model
i'm not going to be able do exact inference because this is terribly difficult problem
these huge
so for hidden markov random fields
you have the same
you have the same you have the problem the problem of organ intractable model
in our case
the hidden markov random field i'm going to talk about
and similarly the trial will have patients that will be most likely to inform them so
this is actually quite revolutionary.
and then one step up from this the entire melanoma community is
is simply one node and cancer commons.
and so we have similar communities that we're planning to build for other cancers and
these will be connected
and the interesting thing is that there are many, many opportunities already emerging
to be able to demonstrate the the cross learnings between these communities. so for example there's
a drug called gleevec,
which was a wonder drug for a certain type of leukaemia, chronic myelogenous leukemia, it
basically made that disease something one could live with for a very long time.
it turned out that three percent of melanomas expressed a mutation that that drug happened to hit.
who would have guessed?
similarly the drug that I talked about the BRAF inhibitor in that I was talking about
earlier for melanoma may be applicable to the seven percent of
colorectal cancers that express BRAF mutations.
we don't know that yet and there are many, many mutations that are shared across
the solid tumors
in the GI tract and and along.
so this is an opportunity to do the the kind of cross learning that requires
the kind of thinking and applications that we can do in this community.
so that's cancer commons
and I would now like to talk about the AI opportunities and and challenges. so reframing
things from an AI perspective what we're talking about is a gigantic search
over the opportunity space of targets and leads
and that search is guided by knowledge, a lot of knowledge about cancer biology, about
drugs, about clinical response, tests, essays, all of those things.
the problem is that the knowledge is
largely uncertain still, there's large gaps in the knowledge
incomplete, uncertain,
much of it is no doubt wrong.
and so what we have to do
is use the experiments on patients,
ethical experiments remember 'cause every patient has to get the best treatment for them personally
but to gradually start to fill in in these gaps by doing adaptive planning
to be able to look at the questions that we're trying to answer and then
go back and try to
use patients in an ethical way to run these experiments, capture learnings, use the learnings to
infer what we can do about the causal nature
of cancer and the mechanisms of action of the drugs and then generalize from each patient
to many other patients in order to be able to drive the field forward.
now, of course, there's much too big a gap between patients and the knowledge ball over
there, so we've gotta have intermediate levels of learning and of course we've talked
about one so far,
which is the reference model,
which is a very nice crisp
problem where the goal is to be able to continually improve predictions.
but there are many, many, many other levels of knowledge and these are some of
the levels that are involved in the collabrx one process. for those of you
in the back pathway analysis mechanism of ana analysis what do these pathways have to do with
particular known cancer mechanisms, using that to identify targets, drugs, picking clinical trials and so
forth and we've got learning to do on every one of these levels
every day
with every patient.
so the generalisation is basically that each level
generates hypotheses
that can be then used
that can then be tested at the next level down as is traditional in the hierarchical learning
system and I think that the hierarchical base is very nice way to formulate this
because all the knowledge is probabilistic at every single level.
so in the in the time remaining I'm going to focus on some specific challenges
for and opportunities and challenges for this community in three areas knowledge management, hierarchical planning
and learning and generalisation.
first in terms of knowledge management I've already said that cancer,
curing cancer, treating cancer involves a lot of knowledge
and these are there's a very small fraction of the knowledge that's available just
on the internet and I wanna give you a scale an idea for
the scale of this knowledge, pubmed which is a major resource
from the national library of medicine
has twenty million abstracts of medical literature in it, about three million of those are
specifically about cancer but the answers don't necessarily come from that the answers may come
from for example literature on metabolism because cancer screws up all kinds of processes within
cells and if they may provide the clue about how to do interdiction. the gene expression omnibus
is a public database of gene expression data there's four hundred fifty thousand
experiments that are documented there,
gene expression and sometimes the clinical annotation that goes with them
that was last time I looked a few days ago, this grows by hundreds
of experiments daily.
clinical trials dot gov has nearly a hundred thousand trials
ongoing at any moment in time
and about forty percent of those are cancer.
and asco is where the cancer trials, american society of clinical oncology, it's a conference much
like this one just larger
where the trials get reported each year
and this is truly the frontlines and I wanna give you a report from
the frontlines of asco, a month ago I went to asco twenty ten,
which is in chicago
there are thirty thousand people at that conference the plenary hall
is at least as long as this one and at least as wide, it's the
biggest room I've ever seen
it's it's not like a sports stadium where you can actually see the players in the
back of the room you can see a pin point of the guy up in the front
giving the talk and then hundreds of screens scattered through the room so you you gotta
have a visceral understanding, this is a twenty ring circus four thousand abstracts are presented
in four days
of which about six of them make the plenary.
so those are the those are theones that are considered practice changing and those are the ones you
can read about in the new york times.
but there are five hundred or a thousand others that might be life saving
for some patient, if there was only a way to be able to get that
information and put it in front of the patient and doc the right time.
so I'll ask my question again, do you think a little AI can help?
here's another issue that comes up,
we talked about a few slides ago I said there was this drug for
leukemia that helped three percent of of
melanoma patients. it took nearly two decades to be able to take that knowledge
and transfer it
and and be able to connect the dots to be able to figure that out
so the the result
that said gleevec has major response for melanoma patients who express a C kit
mutation was published I believe in nineteen ninety eight by in two thousand and eight by
a friend of mine Stephen Hodi. but in nineteen ninety one
i'm told it's very it's very neat stuff and
they they have journal paper impressed with their where are applying this this are not
impressed in preparation where they are applying this to some some various kinds of real
world datasets but i don't know i don't have any results on that you or
i don't have any of the results but these these ideas of hierarchical models really
do show up lot in cognitive science and what i want this is what i
want to talk about progress the last fifteen minutes is ways that
but models which which find
some kind of abstract relational structure in dataset like some kind of tree structured hierarchy
have been really useful in getting us to think about the deep learning problems for
not deep learning well actually conceptually deep and also hierarchically deep learning problems for humans
so the way we actually model this thing which keeps showing you to motivate things
that never actually showed your model of these data but what we do basically inspired
by both traditional semantic networks and these results finding class hierarchical tree structured clusters of
object categories in the brain is basically do what kind of hierarchical clustering and you
can just i mean you can model these things pretty well just doing
generic are clustering but
for reasons that will show you in a second we prefer approach a kind of
bayesian hierarchical clustering where objects essentially get grouped into a tree structure based on how
similar they are and then nodes of this tree correspond to candidate word meanings so
for example this two for could refer to that this sort of that nodes anything
under it and just by seeing how few labeled examples clustering the tree you're able
to generalize the word in a very powerful way and get good inductive bias that
comes from the
from the structure of the tree where the rule of the unlabelled data is to
tell you what the tree structures and once you have the tree structure that not
very hard to figure out from a few labeled examples where is the best point
to generalize in that tree
and this is just some data which i will not show you but the model
fits the data well but what i said we think of this from a kind
of a hierarchical bayesian perspective this is the sort of picture we have in mind
there are some
features which you observe projects this could be
the you know each of these could be a neuron ninety that we can measure
the results from and then applying some of those tree structured clustering models to that
data would give us something like the stream so the idea is in a sense
which is where we have a generative model of how the features of objects are
are distributed over some tree structure then we can do bayesian inference in this model
to figure out
the poster over trees or maybe just to find the best tree
and use that to set expectations for new features like like the word label too
but the reason why we want to think about this from hierarchical bayes point of
view is we want to consider the fact that
not only what we now know what's the right restructuring have to learn that from
the unlabelled data but we might not know that we should be looking for tree
at all
if you look more generally across cognition you see a lot of concepts get organize
into things like trees but there are also other ways to organize concepts and we
want to be able to discover for example that in this domain of of
i thought a tree structure is appropriate but in some other domain another structure might
be appropriate so a picture like this where might consider different forms of structures you
a lot of which i talked about here like spaces trees if you're interested in
social relations like who
advisers who you might be thinking of something sometimes more like the dominance ordering or
partial order you know how how do you how are we able to discover these
different forms of structure in data without necessarily knowing that in advanced
here's just a little bit of motivating motivating intuition b
you know what i guess one possible response to this is to say well don't
explicitly try to identify
these forms structure but have some kind of the network that will just implicitly
i find but in sort of with enough with enough data to knowledge a completely
generic representational structure big set of weights to specialize in this sort of direction and
that's the direction and within cognitive science some people have been usefully pursuing that approach
like tim rogers and jamie callan have an interesting book basically applying to deep autoencoders
to these kinds of cognitive tasks
but we think there's good reason to consider a more structured alternative where you explicitly
try to identify structure of the right forum for example knowing that the animals
organised some kind of tree structure makes it much easier to be able to
generalize from just one example of a new species here's the does anyone know what
this thing is
it's do or wildebeest right but even if you didn't know that you can see
just based on a quick glance at it similar looks some sort of similar to
these things and not to those things in sync and this plug it right there
into the tree without having to consider all possible ways it could be related to
all sorts of other species
here's another example showing the value of this higher level structural form for inductive bias
against the first you particularly want american missile test here abstract knowledge of american geography
and culture so here's here's a few american cities let me tell you about the
mystery city
which has just a few properties so it has an average annual temperature of sixty
six degrees fahrenheit or in nineteen celsius
in two thousand four voted sixty percent for george bush
and the most popular foods are fried and barbecue
so where is the city
well understood just how and when i get to it
now let's
let's do MCMC
metropolis hastings with
in proposals
it discussion
OK but somewhere over here right
i was using an hamiltonian MCMC so you may be somewhere around right now again
you don't have to know that much you you may be thinking of a particular
city in mind
or you may not
but you know enough about how some of these features tend to co vary across
the two dimensional map of united states that from just a couple of data points
you can figure out of a lot about what i'm talking about
now we can also do
well actually charles
charles kemp and i've done a lot of experiments which i don't really have time
to tell you anything about except the take-home message from these experiments is you give
people various has just like what i was doing you tell them about a new
property or new object from in front just a couple of observations you ask them
to make predictions about what other properties of that is going to have or what
other objects are going to have this new property and depending on the the the
the domain you know if you give people biological species their predictions are best captured
tree structured models if you give people predictions about features of cities the best captured
image patch here what uses the characteristics socail which is the scale peak in the
scale the main and dominant gradient orientation different ways of estimating actually the scale and
rotation characteristics of the patch and then
if you have a matching
pair right so for example you can see these two image patches are similar so
they have similar descriptions they will match
for the ones for the matching descriptor you also have the size of the region
and the dominant rotation angle right so once you have the spare what you can
you can tell you determine the scale change between the two patches
and the rotation change between the two pi two patches will content change of
much two half
and rotation angle of twenty degrees
so each
descriptor pair is out in the scale and angle difference
and the assumption we make here
which is not which is not exact but it's approximation is that the global image
and rotation changes are roughly consistent
so it's it's holds exactly if you have a scale change between the images so
the image patches they will have the same scale change between the matching image patches
with the scared him to go and between them it doesn't hold if you for
example the viewpoint change there will be only approximately correct but in case of image
rotation in which case and is exactly correct
in case of perspective viewpoint changes rough approximation
OK and for example for the orientation consistency and so on
on the left you have query image on the right the image which has been
stored in the database and you can see for each point
we show the rotation
the angle in the rotation difference between the patches right and you can see here
most of them are consistent but if you look closely there are few outliers for
this one up here in the top right which is much larger than the same
and if you quantized this orientation differences you can see here
there's is the maximum
and this is actually the rotation angle between two images so if you look here
this is the maximum for this pair of images
if you look you it's pay pile for the approximately rotation angle of forty five
degrees between two images is found correctly
example for the scale consistency
you can see here
two images to different images of the ivory tower
yes approximately scale change of
one half between the two of them and you can see here we show the
matching matching regions
you take the difference of the characteristic scale and you can see here
that find the p q
at approximately one-half right this allows to fill the matches not only on the description
but also on the geometric consistency
and so if you keep this this histograms in mind
these are the histograms was for the voting so voting is not only performed for
image but it's also performed was angle and scale different
we've seen we have observed that these steps stops the independence of the rotation and
scale which is of course between two images independent
then obtain
the score for all quantities is quite hard enough scale difference for each image
and the final score
then filled in for each of these two parameters we take the in between them
OK so this allows us
two of ten matches that agrees with the main difference in orientation scale
this will be taking into account for the final score so if we have many
matches but none of them agrees into in the scale of the orientation that we
be also out
on the other hand if they agree
keep peak which is much higher in the end we are voting score might but
is much higher
and what
an interesting question and can i ask
it's to so
again further improvement by using the full geometric ranking or not
so ideally i would say yes to show this now spend results ideally the answer
would be yes because for now we just have done very weak geometric verification however
if we put the full geometric model on top of that we obtain
additional verification
and then something which is interesting as well actually if you look
at the the and the differences from images
we can observe that what would you think anyways for natural collection of natural images
most of features that take the same angle then there's the peak at high
and i which
so we can use the prior for providing our and the different which shows has
been shown to further improve the results
and following the experimental evaluation if created dataset for evaluation
which contains two thousand images five hundred query images nine hundred ninety one annotated true
one million described attractor images which have obtained from flickr
if constructed the vocabulary of an independent dataset also obtained from flickr
and our search system is almost real time showing them all in a minute
so how do we have made our results
those outside of based on mean average precision which means the bigger the better right
here we know
no no precision and one will the very high precision so basically decision is the
precision recall curve so if you have what we call one precision one that's the
best curve we can obtain
the average precision recall curves a few examples of the dataset
and then
a few images image sequences which on dataset so on the left is the query
images and
the right it's all the images which have
if have stored in this manner images which would like to retrieve
another example
poster from venice
and a few examples of the distractor images from flickr
and the evaluation for our holiday dataset
and law we show the baseline
so just obtain the bag of visual words
OK great pleasure to be here thanks for the invitation this talk i this seems
about time image and vision and geometry and so on
and how you told to is inspired by
geometry and two dimensional signals images and so on
it's so for a long time to be a one-dimensional talk i apologize because most
of the solutions we master are actually
can be explained in one dimension so easily and then we'll go back and actually
talk also about superresolution is very anderson application
OK so i i hope at some point to convince you that i'm not in
the wrong auditorium
OK thanks to the organizers to the sponsors they also first before anything else say
a set this is work joint work with terrible blair graduated from polytechnic year in
the colonial hockey two phd students and richard i PM until know what worked on
this while being phd student at EPFL
o thing and thirty five minutes so till eleven when tried to tell you
he's going back to very old result which is shown sampling
which is essentially the underpinning theorem for everything we do in individual processing in you
normal comedians on and and then also question the validity of random sampling for images
in the article about some motivation for the work described
and from there i will talk about signals which are sparse in some domain
but not in
is certainly not in fourier domain therefore they don't actually fit the shaman framework for
example diracs infinitely sharp objects edges and so on and define classes of signals that
are kind
which generalizes bandlimited functions
and for which are going to pose the question of sampling
that's what i'm going to do well in in section three one shows that actually
even though these signals are of infinite bandwidth and not in shift invariant subspaces i
have to insist better on manifolds can be sampled at least certain classes we can
explain very precisely how to sample them and we'll do this and actually pull the
sampling theorem exactly on on some type of signals and then from there on we
want to show that this is actually robust in the case of noise so it's
not just the paper and pencil result and is time limits all tell you a
little bit about the connection between this work and compressed sensing
and i'll conclude by talking a little bit about applications and and also an example
of technology transfer offices
of these mathematical results to actual applications
so the set up is extremely simple but i want to insist on the set
of it
we are we live in continuous time OK so my world is continuous time physical
world and i want to search the world
and top of the world i have sampling kernel it's an observation kernel it's still
in the digital photography camera or it's
you know it's the lowpass filter on the input of from a to d converters
for dual processing for example and san
i have an approximation here that's typically projection
and i take a uniform sample the two things that are keys it's continuous time
OK so it's t storyline and its uniform sampling and that's how sampling is done
in ninety nine point nine
percent of objects i know of in the digital world
not to say a hundred percent because it can always be an exception but that's
not how we acquire the real world so here's the real war here's the digital
world and the question is completely obvious is when you have a one-to-one mapping between
objects here from the continents world to sample set of sequences right and it's a
it's a very obvious question since we use this all the time
and the astonishing thing is that this set here is
here is only partially described as far as i know
so we'll extend that set a little bit
and the other thing i want to say is you don't always have the choice
about sampling the observation kernel so for example
this is the european southern space observatory
when you go there and you want to do the job signal processing people say
oh by the way here is sampling currently fifty million telescopes have seven of them
because so it's rather expensive operation so it comes and say
you know what i want to change the sampling current i would like to have
a pseudorandom sequence you know people sort of put your yourself things the desert
never talk to you again so that's really like this and then it also happens
that is sampling rate is often not your choice is given by technology by prior
design and on or simply by
constraints from the physics of what rate you can actually sample of joe wideband signals
which have ten gigahertz if you want to sample them at nyquist shannon bandwidth it
will be twenty gigahertz which is a little bit pushing the technology
so the classic result i don't want to recall it here the statement from the
nineteen forty eight paper is actually was reinvented proved many times or earlier shannon but
it's actually is the projection of the input space onto the space of bandlimited signals
and applying what formula or or something like this you can show there is a
one-to-one map you can approximate x in its bandlimited or small version
now what i call the nightmare for signal processing or image processing person is you
have an object that is very small that comes from the space of bandlimited function
and sends the devil comes and puts one singularity onto this signal so f of
are you let say x of t is is from the band limited space
then the devil makes new function f of the which has just two unknowns the
location and the high office of continuity i
the fourier transform is bandlimited anymore and there is no sampling theorem for nine
OK unless you're happy to sort of small out this edge which then you know
is equal to the integral from 0 to 1 of the Hessian of ex post
times minus X
times minus X dt this matrix that is of the vector
why is this statement true by the way
OK so
this statement is true just think of them is defined
the function of 1 variable T V of t to be F of X
which are the gradient of x plus seek times e minus X
so everybody see this OK then whom I up to now
you said lot
higher rates
right OK so high what is the of 0
it was really and about gradient of X and the question what is the 1
that you and I and what is the product of the derivative of this guy
with respect to the noun don't think that is known for is means you of
is the derivative of the entire vector
you know
if you go to the elevator was to the money that's
times consumers
In order to estimate
the Hessian evaluated here
and so now the fundamental theorem of calculus I know that you want find of
0 is equal to the integral is from 0 what the prior to the 1st
that's on the fundamental theorem can can now 1 is gradient methods the fear of
zeros gradient method next
and this is the integral from zero one the price of dt
that's the case analysis to prove it and I invite you to help me is
any make errors in
OK so here goes
so next month is
the exons my interest XML is a star is disability extends his X month the
Hessian inverse times the gradient
that's easy enough just rewrite this a little differently optimize articles because this plus Hessian
number and the gradient that kind of land that why is this true him up
you know
here in
what it actually is what introduce more rapid and introduces because it's equals 0 OK
so I
that is on the right is this is excellent that's the heart of the Hessian
inverse another book that formula
just great
this formula here from Proposition 2
the gradient of a star minus the gradient method that is going to be the
integral from 0 to 1 of the Hessian
X plus the storm
this guy
time based on
everybody with me but that is not a rewrite everything which has front
and this is a very passionate explicity times this phenomenon called agent
that's what I so would do it from set of this and I'm up to
you name is we've Nicholas would lead to an analysis
1 of the