i am that's a picture that is very similar to what i just made on the blackboard
so you can digest that again
you see here the year and
a person standing in this direction from the sun here's shadow would be very long
you shadow all the way up to this point is
i would be
and then you see this raindrop
just at the right direction forty two degrees away from this line this raindrop will be read
this raindrop
begins to be white maybe a little the blue site forty two degrees
i was not the first one to make this a
note himself was the first to understand
the rainbows
this is his own picture in the book of figure
you see here
the primary bow
notice the light comes in from the sun penetrates the water drop reflects in the back and comes out
this will be pure red
and this one could be read but it can also be blue
and we'll call it in here
would be white light and this is secondary
secondary allows for an extra reflection inside the raindrop
next reflections
reflection one reflection to
and they give you the secondary and the colour sequences
so you can make a rainbow didn't circles here
your whole body
fun great fun
i do that often when i s
the sun is high in the sky
you just put one all around you it's a great feeling of power
you all the way around the radio readily outside
you see some white light together here the u of course have to produce white
you have to produce
really everywhere here let's say what about
you don't have a lot of
well this is a painting
from the eighth century thirteen
in the bible it says i do set my bow in the cloud
there's something wrong with this picture
i call a sequence isn't quite right
so as possibilities reaction
you physics of different
eight centuries
what paper
made a mistake
all the pain that is very purpose
but we will always be possible
we will never know a wonderful thing
you can of
and you can apply the ball
he said well at time seven
and this is why we need to act shower
after the color in a rainbow i never see a rainbow and i take a shower with that
but they say it's a random
the robot
but colors and not quite right
read globally outside luzon on the inside it's a fake
well know when you buy something
the not
she cause
that's not slow
this is a reasonable
when which
at my door this spring water
from a garden hose
you here
so this behind me
you see all the features that we have discussed now
readily outside and inside
you see the white light
you may always have missed
and when you here
of course there is also water here
but no light comes back from these drops
this was not without problems
was generally freezing cold i
who am i
let's face you want
you see around the outside the
the only only time that
so from so far
agenda is going to give
back to the nineteen eighty three which is the physics of waves
and i really need
right rainbow is
the do
the second of senior secondary very faint
but i don't want to also make a second secondary home
and i succeeded going over my driveway is very dark
driveways and final is easy to make
it so if we have a feature map of this kernel the basic kernel that
compares elements of X then we can construct a kernel on these sets by summing
over so we can construct the feature map for the sets by summing over all these other
feature maps and and it turns out if you do that you will end up
with this kernel so so please try these two things and I will shut up
for a few minutes  so yeah so so I mean another way is
basically the same would be just to to write down the condition that we
want to check so we want to see whether this thing is non-negative right this
is our definition of our function K we don't know yet if it's positive definite
now we use the fact that this is a dot product dot products are linear
so we can take these scalars these factors inside the dot product we can also take the
sums inside to be more specific we have two sums one over I one
over J so we'll take the sum over I in here and the A I in here and we'll
take the sum over J in here along with the A J so we have the sum over
I here and we have the sum over J here okay and now we can see just like before in the argument
this is a certain vector call it  V and this is actually the same
vector and the only thing that's different is the name of the index doesn't
matter so it's a dot product of V with V and dot products are positive definite
meaning so they cannot give you negative values so this is non-negative okay so that
was the first  problem shall  we take a look at the second problem so any
anyone has an idea how to solve the second problem you can you can earn a point
okay I'll do the second one if you collective me promise me  that the next on
the next slide you will solve the other problems for me okay so
second one let's take look at this so I had this hint written down there  so
my hint was use this feature map  so we start with phi which is a
mapping it takes inputs from X and maps them into a dot product space H from that
we define a mapping phi tilde which takes its inputs subsets of the domain so
let's yeah let's say finite subsets for simplicity and as output again vectors in that
vector space H because some of such vectors is again such a vector so it's
mapping into the same feature space and let's do this for two sets so
let's take phi tilde of A and then a dot product with phi tilde of B
now if you remember from the first problem that we just solved so the first problem was
telling us I deleted it with the laser pointer the first problem was telling
us it's gone  whenever we take some mapping of some input domain into a
dot product space and we compute the  dot product after this mapping  we get a
positive definite kernel so now I'm saying let's take a different kind of mapping this time I take a
a mapping from a set of sets  also mapping from sets into some do prod
prod product dot products space  if I then construct this thing here by construction or by this first
result I get a positive definite kernel okay so  I just have to compute this thing
I get a positive definite kernel actually and it will turn out to be the
kernel that's written up there okay so let me substitute here's where I have
substituted phi tilde of A is defined here and and do the sign same for B only
I use a different name for the index so I don't get confused now
again I can use the fact that this is a dot product so I can use
the fact that it's linear so if you don't remember the produ properties of dot products maybe
it's good to remind yourself maybe check on Wikipedia or mathworld or somewhere I
am kind of assuming you know what is a dot product so if if you use this
you can take these sums you can take the sums inside or outside okay
and then inside what you're left with is this and this okay and I think you all recognize
what is this that's our original kernel so so K is a kernel directly on
the Xs and from this we can construct a kernel so let's call this this
is our kernel on sets of Xs so that's one operation already how to construct more
complicated kernels from simpler kernels if you want by construction it's a positive  definite kernel
so taking a feature map explicitly and making a dot product is one way to construct a
kernel and sometimes if you do it you end up with a kernel that's more
efficiently to compute and explicitly doing the feature map but of course you could also always
explicitly do the feature map if it's not too expensive okay so any questions
so far so if I if I go too slowly you have to tell me like like you
to throw something I told by the way I told Jan before the last lecture to throw something
at me if I'm too slow and I asked him during the break I said you didn't throw anything at me he said well
I fell asleep so if it's okay throw before you fall asleep okay so
here we have some more properties and this will be important because we will use
several of them to construct the feature space of a kernel so to prove the
second part in our even only ifs ifs statement I told you before that if
and only if a kernel is positive definite it has a representation as a dot  product so now on
the last slide we showed that if it has a representation as a dot product it's positive
definite but we now have to show if it's positive definite it has a representation
you don't need to discard
bayesian models altogether and migrate altogether too busy nonparametrics
but basically all it's telling you is
it finds a bimodal distribution because that's all it can do
but there's has a high uncertainty
so it's our guide self guards u
by saying well i'm very uncertain about what's going on here but it still gives you the model
this too much only
okay this is
now the samples from the prior
additional process case
so it is a process with conjugate base distribution which is discussed in distributed
and this is the fit to the data
this generated from two gases is expected to have these
two peaks
and this is
data generated from foegaussian
and now you have three peaks so this shouldn't be surprising because
we know that
the bishop process is going to fit to
the data
and it's going to use
the necessary amount of components
to be able to have a good representation of data
you can see things like this for example there are peaks
if we sample from the posterior there are peaks at
places where there is not any data at all
so that that's counts because
the the process still give some probability
other places than it so that it so you may see this as an advantage
or a disadvantage if you believe that's when your data is only what you saw
and there will be no further
data lying outside of the region that you observe data before then
maybe this is something to worry about then maybe
actually this is a model that you shouldn't use them because you don't want all
the flexibility you want to constrain your model
but a few if you want to be flexible and give some probability
to data coming from other regions then
this may not be such a bad idea
to use this
okay so
mixture model
so using additional processes is defined
by this so
we have uh we have data points are that we have and datapoints indexed by i
conditioned on some parameter
and the parameter defines the distribution of the data
and the parameter is drawn from some distribution gene which is drawn from the fission process this
these parameters of the concentration parameter engine on the base distribution
and this is the graphical model showing this
these equations basically
so this is this is how we define the infinite mixture model
you could leave you can show it like this rare
we have pi send
rather than designed
you read we have
tysnd that letters
we basically
using this infinite sum that comes from the stick breaking
okay so
given this model how do we do inference on it
typically the easiest case to use these models and practices to using conjugate base distribution
so that the parameters can be integrated out and the predictive probabilities can be computed using
sufficient statistics of the data
so peter was talking about to cancel
conjugacy one is the controversy after this process itself so the
posterior process is still in there's process that's one type of conjugacy
and that's always present in the dish
process models
but the
are it is the
when look there's a process models that say
ends the can type of conjugacy is about the conjugacy of the parameters of the model to the
base distribution so if you want to
an infinite mixture model with gusting components
you need to specify a prior on top of those components end that's prior needs to be
conjugate to the gas in distribution
because you assume gassing components porter
data generating process
so what is the
what is the conjugate distribution part a guassian distribution so if if you are using
a if you if you do
assume that was mean and covariance is uncertain
but the edge can not belong to the side
the edge itself for this is cycle this cycle is four edges
is an edge
that connects two nodes in the cycle
but does not belong to to the cycle
or another way to put it
is an edge between two non consecutive nodes inside
but this is why i think it is well it's a shortcut in the cycle
these graph is not chordal
because you have
one cycle
and this cycle has no core
immediately it's not chordal because every cycle
in the graph must have a record
of course apart from cycles of size three which by definition cannot have any court
this is the a quarter because the two cycles that you don't have acquired now
they have caught
why does important well you remember
that when we ran the elimination of algorithm
in that previous
example that we were suppressing successively the nodes
at some point we add
an edge right
what the edge was was precisely one of these edges
so one that it was on that it was necessary in order to make that
graph chordal
so you start to see the connection
with the junction tree algorithm will be
is exactly the generalisation of the elimination algorithm by pre computing
all those necessary
we'll get
so basically
what if a graph is not chordal well then you can use the junction tree
of all
in theory you can
but the point is that you need to add edges until it becomes chordal
these will change the graph
exercise why this is not the problem
i mean
if i have a graph which
it's not for
and they went around the junction tree of all which only works on quarter i
i can add add edges until it becomes chordal basically introduced at least one court
in every cycle and make sure that the resulting graph is chordal
or keep on adding until
i have no chordless cycles
but this will change the graph itself
so what am i changing my problem
this is not a problem but the question is why this is not a problem
well this is not a problem for very simple reason and also the more general
because by introducing edges i'm making less conditional independence assumptions
so in solving a more general class
of problems
so this is not a problem at all
of course they may immediately
you will realize by now you know what p
what a perfect map is
what you will realize that by doing that
i may actually
the ability to have a perfect match for example from my distribution
because if i'm forced to introduce some
i will immediately
be unable to enforce
some conditional independence assumption that previously were there
and now we are
go ahead
that's generally graphs
the first step is just three only graph
i mean
our from so that in practice we usually work with lithographs anyway
like chains or two treestreestrees and things like that for example
of that
and that means of the previous guy
together we are thinking
divided by the norm of x where
this is our up
OK so we wanted to analyse
these through the true identity so we compute the like function
all the topic of this constrained optimisation problem
and we end up with something that looks like
or directly
be the last prior to that i think about it i mean i think of
you got here
the this conference and this like multiply is actually
correspond to the
if people are learning rate
indeed there we
we see
so that this is
was equal to minus the house
of these where the
x is where
alpha and then we had the LP
of w minus one hinge loss
and the and the
and alpha and
it would be
when we
worse when we saw the when we compute the dual the primary we found out
that output
well actually
play the same role in the of learning rate
so the one we solve the
one we find the optimum
like to multiply the one that maximizes the world by taking derivatives
and then there will be one of the for all
we therefore can see from here the river is that they were or are you
get a point
you introduce the
the additional costs but you get
the other thing
is the learning rate it up here
so we've got this one
now we wanted to say
so this is the way
computing platforms so we know that we have to be performed
this corresponds to that
that's right this the output is far
because it that be optimal
i got applied mathematics one
OK now you want to go
it for the purpose of coming up with analysis of exactly what we want to
make the game
a relationship established the relationship between this problem and the
batch has been problems
but the problem is get
i'm always thinking of treatment genetic stream of length capital
text in the background
because of the SVM objective
with the same regularisation parameter vector see here
in the
so now we can we
a road to the world
but there will be an
and then we
we noticed that we could write world
in a telescopic weight so we could write it is
because OK write like
zero which is the wrong
part one thing
and we have a different one
but in
it might be
but there
at the end
the main one
OK so
mine this one can
and then
but this is zero we don't care
i don't write in the world but we had money
o thing
so we know that one zero zero so
we have
we're fine so we can just look at
call it here and we know that by which what we serve the foreign assignment
any legal assignment one out the
beginning of zero
if we call the
this up here end the solution of the
training the SVM problem of
the value
of the objective of human
we know that
the what
four in this league assignment of the is
always smaller than up it
so now
you know this fact
we have a relationship between the two world figure should be in the world and
these differences
and what we need is that we observe that
computing these differences
this was his last observation
computing the differences
one of
you remind me
he made
the red arrow
OK if you do the calculation you find out that this
we did
and we found out that it was one the
in game
but the
so all this means that
basically can plug is zero so you can plug this in here
and now you can say OK
i know that some of the the
of the dual for active aggressive which could before
i by the by
the value of the optimum
of the same objective function so
i i can lower bound
of partials but we also a random number which can be either minus one either
zero plus one and this is done so that you removed
you can end up with a name or number of fossils
so as to make it reversible that is if you start from the situation with
the even
a number of times you might be able to do the reverse
this is fairly standard you sample frequencies for the new did both roles
so there is a candidate set of frequencies
and you compute the metropolis hastings ratio designed for reversible jumps
so this is
this is the
the the
the ratio of the proposal of the posterior distribution for the new candidates divided by
the posterior distribution for the previous example OK so found the metropolis hastings ratio multiplied
so the prior becomes here because it's part of the posterior
and here you have the ratio of
i proposal distributions
as in the fundamental belief systems three shows us to to make sure that it
converges to the true distribution
and we either accept the candidate we i are rejected
in this example
you might have seen that all the candidates are
proposed by distributions q
OK which we call the proposal distribution
and which are actually is the key element in the convergence of the algorithm
this is what you can select OK
the problem the posterior distribution you want to sample from you can not selected but
but the probability distributions you can select
so it is very important to to respective few rules and into practical sessions will
see that if you use for example local proposal distribution which can be for example
random walk
you start situation from situation and you propose the candidate in the nineteen in the
OK so this will not
and sure fast if you're using global
proposal distribution you some situation and then you propose candidates independently from the previous accepted
in this case it will not converge very fast again and it will converge faster
to mix the two kind of moves so we see this in the proper in
the practical fish
so this is just an example of how we can design global proposal distribution which
is efficient when mixed together with the local distribution it to for example derive
the probability density function which is proportional to support spectrum
o of the signal
OK so this is just the remarks it's not very important
OK so
you've seen this is quite
big machine to compute
the music but i'll show you some results
and you see
it can be very powerful
need to plug the speaker
the problem there
uniform and she
just once a concern that that
should be working soon
OK so
this is an example of violin
what's happening now
can this for that
sorry about that
tried to fix this and if it doesn't work
the system
OK so now we need to work it doesn't
OK so that's office again the violin playing just one out
OK so it's a bit loud
right so i did it again
OK so this is the original signal
and with this is our that been using and we
put it into this being verizon and then it gives us a set of samples
of the parameters and from this parameters we can reconstruct the doctor and that's what
we can here we've
and if we do the difference between the original data the reconstructed one
we had to put this
OK so
sure some was the results later so here is a figure which shows the convergence
of the markov chain so this is the typical things that you might find
and is the structural parameters and as you can see
was easy
i move that we designed it converges quite quite fast
and this is from the fundamental frequency of the first of one of the because
there is only one here and as you can see
after the convergence is reached it keeps fluctuating
which is good that's what we want because it is supposed to run them to
the speed of sound
is three hundred
forty meters per second
that's a little bit on the temperature of about seven hundred
seventy miles per hour
when i speak to you might sound reaches use that speed
i produces certain frequency here
so the number of oscillations per second
they reach you UUU run starts to oscillate with the same frequency you hear that
i have here tuning fork
it oscillates four hundred forty times per second
your eardrum
four hundred forty times a second you hear this song
you have two hundred fifty six
oscillations per second
move around is now shaking going back and forth two hundred fifty six times per
second if you stay where you are and you don't move
and i moved this tuning forks you here
a different frequency
and that's what we call
doppler effect
my sound source
approaches you
you will hear frequency as prime
which is larger than the frequency of the tuning fork
if it moves away from you
which i will call receding
then f prime
below lower frequency
for instance i moved to you
some stories i call that transmitter
with a speed
of about
one meters per second
transmitter is the sound transmitter
if it approaches you here
you have prime
which is one point zero zero three
times as
this three here is the one part
out of three hundred forty
together with increasing frequency
if i move it away from you
then f prime
would be o point nine nine
times the frequency of the source itself
you stay where you live
i have here a tuning fork
generates four thousand for very high frequency
if i move it to you is the speed of one meter per second which
i can do
then you can increase in picture of point three percent that makes it four thousand
and when i move it away from you that is the decrease of point three
percent you can clearly hear that difference first make you listen to the four thousand
rupees without my moving
actually causes painful really
high frequency
most of you are young enough you should be able to four thousand hertz OK
now i'm going to move it to you one meter per second and away from
did you hear it once more
when it comes to you it's clear that the frequency
goes up and when it moves away from you
the frequency
is that
now imagine that i'm going to
the sound sources around in a circle
the sound that you receive the frequency that you receive
it will change
in a sinusoidal fashion
this is that circle
and this is the radius of the circle
and if you
are you
in the plane
o of the circle
then when the source
comes straight to you
with the velocity v
let's say to uniform circular motion
as prime will be larger than f
and it will in this case
rita maximal
when it is at ninety degrees relative to you
i don't have to give a vector notation as prime
calls f
when it moves
away from you
prime smaller than that
and when it is here again
when the angle between is the velocity and new direction is again ninety degrees
then f prime equal africa
so this phenomenon
it's called
the doppler effect
so if i turn it around
you know
here a sinusoidal fluctuations in
after i suppose i
a lot
as a function of time
f prime
the way you will receive reduced it still but i'm going to move
sound source around like this
then you will have a curve that looks something like this
some signs sinusoidal cosine sort of fluctuations f prime
this will be
the value f produced by the sound source itself
as prime
and this will be
if you could record this there is an amazing number of things that you can
do so
from this curve
first of all
you can take you can measure f primex
divided by s
because you see this curve so you know whatever it is you would have climaxes
and that should allow you to retrieve immediately
the velocity of the transmitter if that number
we're one point
zero zero three
then you know that the speed
in the orbit was one meter per second
so it is ratio immediately gives you the transmitter velocity
this time separation
if you immediately the period of rotation
but since two pi r
if r is the radius
divided by
the velocity of the transmitter since that is
i can reverse it doesn't matter two pi are divided by the time to go
around is the velocity of the transmitter
since you know the velocity of the transmitter from this ratio to noted period
which is this
you know also find
the radius r
so from that curve
keep that
with you because going to be important in what follows we can derive three things
the radius
the period of rotation
and the speed
of the object
as i truly around
i have here what we call a wind organ
when i told is around
it produces a particular tone we'll talk later about eighty to one wire produces a
particular time sometimes you hear two towns of trying to make you only one
and and as i it around
the sound is coming the sound source the transmitters coming to you
you really need to do something like this you can exhaustively enumerate all settings of
all variables
now if you want to actually code this
it's easier to code up in the formalism of factor graphs rather than directed graphs
so i'm just going to very quickly show you factor graph propagation as well
which is similar set of propagation rules
so where nodes are sending messages to other nodes
just to remind everyone the factor graph is
a factor graph is just the way of representing a joint probability distribution
as a product
functions on subsets of variables
so this is a normalisation constant
and this joint distribution is simply the product of over
functions each of these functions fj is a non negative function of its
this x
some s j is just some subset of variables
that this function is a function of so you know here you would have this
dot corresponds to the function of a and c
a non negative function
you can have negatives in their consumer multiplying all these together to get the probability
and then you need the normalizer so it sums to one when you some over
for all the very
so this is just a reminder of what a factor graph is
if you have a factor graph you can talk about the
neighbors of node x
first let n of x be the
factor nodes that are neighbors of x and n of FP the variable nodes that
are neighbors of factor
remember each
it is connected
each valuable node is connected to some of these factor nodes and the factor nodes
are connected to
some valuable nodes
factor graph propagation simply sends messages from
variables the factors
and the messages look like this
message from variable to factor is simply the product of the messages from
all the factors that are neighbors of x
is the product of all the messages x is getting from the other factors
not including
and then the message from
a factor to variable
again a product of the messages from all of the variables
that f is connected to
going to have
the product is taken over all the neighbors of that
not including x
and then you multiply it by the actual factor and then use some about all
the other variables so since these two equations
and you can basically run these two equations
which i have written down here
and once all the variables
what sorry of variables receive all messages from its neighboring factors we can compute the
distribution of that variable by multiplying all the messages and renormalizing
it's just these two equations is simpler than the belief propagation algorithm
that i described previously and is really pretty easy to code up
these things are again
functions of
if this has if this takes on k values then this can be represented as
a vector
of length k
that was factor graph propagation so
how would this actually work
well imagine you had a factor graph that look like this
let's say
was initialize all the messages to be ones
that means there vectors
of all ones
here's an example schedule of messages resulting in the computation of p of x probability
of x four OK we want to compute the probability of x four
i really do this well
x one sends a message to f one
the message is
the all ones message
then x three sensor message f two
we could have done many different order if we'd wanted to
f one sensor measures to f two
according to the rules
we had before
the message that
that as a function centre variable is given by
sorry this equation
f one sends this message two x two
and that's the messages says x two
f two sense this passage two x two
that's this message sent to x two
then x two
has received the messages from f one f two and is ready to send out
a message to three
so x two sends this message left three which is simply the product of the
messages a gottfried
f one and f two
and so if three got that message and now if three is ready to send
a message to x four
that they are not known then
and no normal inverse wishart distribution is the
going to get to the gas in distribution
all if you are fixing the
fixing the meaning ants assuming only
you want to learn the
covariance then you need the
inverse wishart distribution on the covariance
or if you know
what the
what the covariances are you're you're pretty sure you can set it
and you only want to put the
distribution over the mean and standard normal distribution is the
conjugate distribution forward the
and similarly if you have discrete data if you're using a multinomial distribution for example to
model your data then the addition distribution
the conjugate
distribution father multinomial so that you're using it
this multinomial
models it
okay so
of course are not tied to using conjugate base distributions but
things become a little more tricky
thank you may you want to use non conjugate models
and that's why
here i'm going to be
talking only about how to do inference forward and conjugate case
in something
what you're doing at each iteration is for each data datapoint
you're remove the data point from its current component so
you start off with some random initially is initializations
uh some initialization of
a number of components with assignments
two of data points to different components
and this when you start something here
a single data point from its current component
and if that's component has become entities so if they that data point that u
removed from the company was the only one that was assigned to it
utility that component from the representation
because nobody
onstad anymore
and then
if you look at the conditional probabilities of
the data points going to any one of the existing components are
another new components
u assigned the data to one of the components looking at this conditional probability is
basically a sample from a multinomial distribution with those properties
so what are those properties
so that they
companies coming from the prior and the likelihood terms
so the probability of assigning to components for which there are more than
zero number of things that scientists
going to one of the empty components musically is proportional to the number of things
that belong to that component except u
except that they point that's your something far now
so this is what this notation means so you take out
but i think the point
from the complement that it belongs to so it may have belonged to decay are
not we don't know that but if it is beyond indicated
and by one
if not we don't touch
so so this term is coming from the prior
and this is basically
the probability of the data
under that's component
so how likely is it to observe the data
given the complement parameter
the probability of assigning to any component is basically
proportional to alpha
times this
so this is basically the
the probability of
this comment this data point
under this base distribution so you integrate out
all data all parameters
using the base distribution
so this is
can kind of coming from the likelihood term and this is coming from the
we can we can do this
so far the components that have been associated with them because they already have some parameters
that are assigned to them and we need to do this we need to integrate out these parameters
there are infinitely many of them and we cannot physically
physically we cannot consider being assigned to
every one of those in many cases right so
this integral basically
says i'm taking into account
being assigned to any one of the possible
infinitely many
of course is proportional to how much mass the
the base distribution gives
to those
those parameter values
so we can also
so it's a little differently
so rather than
knowing the parameter values end conditioning on the parameter values get the predictive value far the point under that
the parameter value
we can integrate this out
the bayesian world
so some of you have done bayesian stuff already
right OK but you haven't so this a bayesian approach to statistics i told you
before their frequentist and frequentists had this idea for you
are principally in principle you're able to repeat experiments many times you're interested in sort
of what happens on average and you want to be good on average and things
like that
they since have more the idea you see this data point you see it only
and so
and bayesians get this idea that everything you don't know
should be treated with probabilities
there is i can't speak too much about her philosophies i only know half of
so maybe even less
the lots of philosophy behind it why this might be a good approach though bayesians
bayesians claim that there is a unique way of dealing with
uncertainties and the unique way is
giving numbers to uncertain things
which sort of sum up to one
and obey the laws of probability
we're frequentist think well you can actually estimate these probabilities by repeating experiments many many
times and then actually find out what is the true value for these probabilities but
for bayesian it may make sense
just simply to say i don't know but i think this one thing is more
even if you can't actually repeat this experiment and just throw many
dice are many coins
so bayesian simply say there is a need for incorporating
prior belief in the
right way of doing it is asserting
putting in probabilities for things that i don't know
and you should
the the probability for everything that you don't know
but you shouldn't put in probabilities for things you don't you just actually know
so the bayesian things in the following way let's say the bayesian does
the toy in the coin tossing
in a bayesian philosophy you say
well what i don't know if the following thing so a sequence that's what i
know of the data
observe this
but what i don't know is the parameter that generated the sequence so if i
don't favor any
specific data
among others i could come up sort of with well i don't know
and it's not actually write what i'm saying here but let's say it seems it
more or less obvious but that for some reason untrue which maybe i can explain
tomorrow why this
well OK if i don't know maybe everything is equally probable
seems to be a sensible way of of
saying so you introduce the probability density
you're unknown parameters theta which is let's say for simplicity uniform over zero one really
don't know what might cause my
before i have actually seen the data the prior distribution over parameters is all my
prior knowledge that i have before i see any data
and the maximum likelihood approach i only choose the model
but i don't say
which parameters i like more than others whereas in the bayesian world i say well there's some
parameters that seem to be more likely than others
but you could say well i mean i know that certain parameters you know i
don't think ten thousand is really
you know maybe it's is some some something in the physical world you know
things are small things are big so we just before
i know my parameter will be in a certain region
in other regions are less and less probable
so they since then do
they use essentially bayes rule for reverting
kind of like how cell structure
so what you say well i know is the uncertainty about the parameter theta and
i know what the probability of the data are when i know it
the first thing gives me
the the maximize the margin subject to constraints that the error on the training and
maybe not large and something so this is about the number of training
adaboost tries to make the training error zero
OK so the extreme case then we maximize the margin now we say OK this
should not be larger than something
some constant and then we maximize speed
OK so this is a discrete optimization problem might be some approximated
and somehow this trade off by
which is determined by a regularisation parameter
OK christian for the six services
this section is to
so then
let's go on two boosting and large margins
so here have a lot of sources that's again shape you're trying this very important
and also some important results by leo prime in nineteen nine
then by christine bennett i and years and john shawe taylor and month and i
also got some some results on that show you some results
OK so you have seen this this picture so we have the input space and
essentially this feature space is generated by the mapping phi
so in this mapping phi is generated by the hypothesis space so every function in
the hypothesis space is one-dimensional the feature space
OK so and we get the linear i mean we have a linear separation if
you just basing something on your input space
OK so
and you can essentially define the hyperplane which is simply five x times of of
this redirect
and you can simply write this in the finite dimensional we can simplify this industry
so alpha j i h j x
so this is simply are combined forces
so in boosting the always use normalized combined process so we normalize these offices such
that the one norm of the offices
one so they these are the sum to one
so essentially
defined this as the margin
and turns out that this
it is actually
the distance
of these points to the hyperplane is not the
the two distance like and support vector machines but it's the so-called l infinity distances
these points to the hyperplane
so this has been shown by maintaining history in nineteen ninety nine
so the margin is simply the signed distance of the point to the hyperplane
OK so let's come back to the weak learners
so the learner uses this example weighting d one to d and and essentially the
returns hypotheses h out of this hypothesis set which classifies these points into
plus and minus one
and those the
learner returns hypotheses which is consistently better than random guessing essentially the weight training and
that the number of the fraction of the
i mean that's the mass of the DNC which are misclassified they should be smaller
than half mile a half
so this this formula only works when the function are really i mean plus minus
one valued so there's another definition which be used
real valued outputs for the hypothesis so then the output can be between minus one
and then we define this quantity here
and this is equivalent to this one
so this this inequality is equivalent to this one so this quantity is called the
so this is the way training error
this is the edge
we use the same quantities we use DNA one x and and just this product
to the sum should be larger than come
so if the weight training i was half
OK then the action is zero
just a different formulation
so i say this is the edge of
the function h
OK so
so we can also define the edge of the weak learner so for certain probability
vectors of some beating d
that is p
best function which you can generate so the best age so this maximizing
the it's maximizing function so he the x for all eight
OK and we try to maximize this match for the given rating
OK so and if the base is minimizing weight training
then actually maximizing the set
OK this
so i've already defined the margin for the combined is just a rule of thumb
it's just this quantity here
now you might ask what is the connection between these two with edge and this
margin and is actually a very old hearing by for nine months in
o thing nineteen
nineteen twenty eight he proved the minimax theory
that is essentially relating these two quantities so the scum of the draw of and
it says
that he
OK of all distributions d
is equal to the maximum
margin of all
OK so
for somehow determining the margin of the training points to the minimum margin of all
training points
OK and this is the best found
maximizing the margin
and that is equivalent to finding the distribution
so finding some of the most difficult distribution such that the base learner cannot return
with a very large set
so if you can show that the base learner always returns
a function which has an edge so come off he is at least some constant
then we can then we already know from this this theory is that the marginal
must be at least
OK this is direct it follows from this theory
take the expectation with respect to the next state
so there's like one step lookahead
so if this one step lookahead
can return
as better value
that we have a particular state
just one state
then what we get
is is the policy that strictly better
so this procedure should converge on the finite number of steps
in the finite and the like if you have finite states and actions
and actually you can show that the number of iterations required by this procedure two
VHS certain precision is is not greater than the number of iterations required
value iteration
this is
sort of faster process on the other hand
OK so how does this target merck so
the if you want to make an article of their own without this
is that
what you do is you take the policy
some policy or guess
you compute its value functions
and then you greedy five suspected device functions you compute the
the greedy policy was respected by function
and then again you compute the value function of the new policy and then you
repeat this procedure indefinitely so that's the the policy
improvement of policy iteration are given
and so the number of iterations required five five policy iteration is never greater than
the number of iterations required by
in addition
but this is not a surprise
everything the policy here requires matrix inversion so it's it's a much more expensive process
then just apply the battle operator to a function
for some people believe that if you have the state space of size and then
this is
and times
more powerful two exactly n times more powerful
two to have a the policy and good if i
so if you come
if you compare the computational complexity of of this target and this makes sense
the other hand it turns out that we don't know exactly how many iterations are
required in policy improvement
and this is an open question if if you can
really have
and our given four and the p
who is computational complexity
i was careful and that is the number of bits required to describe b and
the number of states and actions
and in particular is the number of bits required to describe the discon factors
if you
things the discount factor analysis in this polynomial everything is fine but if the discount
factor is an input then you get this
dependence on the this factors so the number of iterations
as the this called factor
is is getting closer to one so
the number of iterations is typically vulnerable minors gamma times maybe log
of the same quantity
so there is that because the complexity of the target started to become number of
so anyway it's an open question and
and this has been an open question since the sixties so if you want to
become really famous
in control and reinforcement learning all spheres and this this question
should be
so the policy iteration are given bad out here
you have some initial policy
you have only appeared and you start its value function
in b prime
and then you'll
sold forty the greedy policy we suspect to the
and then finally to value function it can be
and then your computer if you compare the end the prime so if you've got
something bigger
then you still have has iterate otherwise against
that should be easy
the reason the are concert this all stop is because the mother target inside all
around is also
i will be adding also
OK so this just bad all the policy iteration resides in finite mdps can
and the optimal policies after a finite number of steps
it should be easy
so dynamic programming i guess
in the interests of seeing some time i'm going to skip that
what happens is that
if you think a little bit you can set up elena programs such that the
solution of the linear programme which is the optimal value function
and that these things on slice if you are interested in the does come to
the brig
and so
this is yet another way of finding an optimal value function and
and this is actually the way
people proved that these are giddens a polynomial complexity in the size of the state
and action spaces
some variations of the team so
moving to arts learning processes
so we that we are going to concentrate learning processes
we cannot hope to be able to have two
just axe acute the value iteration in exactly right
so that the the errors introduced in every time so maybe we are going to
use samples so what the procedure we are going to use function approximation
represent value function so huge state spaces
they are doing that introducing errors in our iterations question is if those editors can
screw up and
one way of looking at this
is two
so that the following iterations to the next iteration
almost the same thing as seen value addition you have the band operator applied to
the fk
plus some additive better
the way to sink about the same
is that you have your favourite battled after after some including value iteration OK
so that they come up with vague
the off cape last one
so the difference between the FP plus one
because we we could always multiply
one is j by
so for example and then divide the corresponding coefficients AIJ by two and that wouldn't
change the observations at all
but of course that's not very
mysterious thing it just means that well we don't know actually the scale of these
latent variables and we don't know the signs they might be multiplied by minus one
and that doesn't really we don't really know
which signed we should take that in most applications not very
and then in inconsistent to techniques like principal component analysis these independent companies don't really
have any intrinsic order so in principle component of this we say that we have
the first second third principal components but here we have nothing like that
so once we
once we make these assumptions here
then actually it can be proven that we can recover
we can recover
the independent components that is we can estimate the i j
up to these these and indeterminate is that i just mentioned and we can estimate
an inventor system and estimate the independent components up to this in in the middle
and this is something that that you can do with PCA of classical factor analysis
of well any other well known any other classical methods that this is ICASSP
well basically this the first way of estimating these kind of linear latent variables model
people have tried to do it for one hundred years but it was not until
let let let's say the late eighties that people really understood how it can be
so people for example try to estimate this kind of model by PCA
for a a long time and i thought that PCA
kind of
estimate this kind of model is that it really doesn't it doesn't do it properly
actually well i should say that it doesn't work properly actually does it it doesn't
do it really at all
the question is that how can we actually have an
estimates these independent components
but the mixing matrix
this is the first thing that you might think about this that well if the
independent components are independent they are OK they are they are by definition independent then
we could try to find some kind of a linear transformation that makes these that
gives us as independent variables as possible so
so what we know is that
x is a linear transformation of
the random vector is
and now what we could just try to make find some kind of
matrix w
because just try to find a matrix w multiply x by and then
look at the statistical properties and y
now since we know that there is i independent statistically because think that once we
find w
that gives us independent component is that once we find w such that all the
ln the components in why are all independent then perhaps we have recovered this
but actually it turns out that is true
so we this is the well this is one of the basic methods of estimating
ICA but it's just you know it is only very theoretical methods because the method
for the measurement of the independence of these components is then another question how you
measure the independent the independent some of these estimates components well we will see in
one that you can figure out something like that but the first thing that people
usually try to do is to find a matrix
that the problem that is the correlation matrix that is it transforms x so that
these components y
are uncorrelated
well the reason why people usually think about this is that this idea of the
correlation is very old one and it's it's very easy thing to do
well i was talking about PCA i mentioned that PCA gives uncorrelated components is the
principal components are uncorrelated
so there are many different ways so it is easy to find this kind of
the w
but the problem is that while most of them are completely wrong
well there are many different ways of of there are many different matrices that give
us that's it x and well
we really need some more information on how to on on which one of those
we really want to find
so typically nice context ICA we talk about whether it was closest
two days you have to check if you compare the dataset you are going to
do something like the results of the one
this is where the other people and then compare so you do
some nations and abstractions when you define this you have to be sure that this
image is actions make sense that you are not adding apples with oranges
comparing it across the sets
yes that's something to keep in mind before anything else that you want to say
about the this like properties of the data distribution and so on
it and its algebraic properties like operations make sense this thing that computer
and then describe two distances
i don't know until after the support operations that makes sense
no this is your compute your between two clusterings shown is that the confusion matrix
and this is the matrix
this matrix
that represent so you have to clusterings one with k clusters and one with k
you don't have to the the same number of clusters because as you can
two british
and cape cape this number is the number of points that in the intersection of
all cluster k
in the first clustering with
another classification right in the second
and so use of intersection and
obviously this matrix is diagonal then the clustering is identical but if in general the
most relevant to be non-zero many elements within
of course that's sum all the elements in m is equal to the number of
points and and if i by
this intersection by the number of points again
something matrix with entries from one and i denoted by p
it reminds me it would be interpreted as
probability matrix explain or the probability distribution
whose entries are this PKK which are the probability of
the point being in the intersection of
OK cluster candcluster seaplane prime is sampled uniformly because among all the
and of course there are some conditions like that of some sort of the confusion
matrix are
the size of the clusters
and the column sums up the size of the clusters and that clustering
and so on just the natural functions
now we are ready to define the first
this is sort the
we have to make it a little technical assumption that
we put
smaller clustering first
however this is commutative so it's not it's not a strong this other constraints
major innovations
if you insist that you have already seen this distance
this is followed by the matching so
i mean i the permutation of the labels
so i
i changed the labels of the clustering that much
i mentioned
the the label
clusters in one clustering with the clusters that clustering and then look at the best
on the diagonal matrix the probability mass on the diagonal that is this pk
of k
after permuting the rows
the thing to do that
that is the total match between the two clusterings under experimentation
what is left one minus is quantity the mismatch the permutations
and the distance i define is the smallest possible mismatch
and the role of limitations
and it's very related to what to do for classification except for optimizing over label
permutations that's why i call it the misclassification distance me
so what can i computing
yes it can be computed in polynomial time because finding a matching so you would
all the permutations that k factorial permutations that's not the naive algorithm will not be
very efficient in general but there is much more efficient algorithms based on linear programming
it's called the hungarian or
bipartite matching algorithm that solves this problem
also you know notice that it is the permutation then this distance is
the hamming distance is related the number of all points in which the labels that
divided by
to make matters even
also note fifty is one so it's sort of the probabilities and probability
the classification error on
if you think of classification
the less obvious but still i think is that this is a metric it all
the time one
why is triangle inequality important because says that i two clustering so close so
the two and that three
both close to the one that they can be too far from each other
that's all the time the inequality signify
and it's it's very useful in many applications was the use of it later this
however there is the problem with this misclassification
this is is great and very interpretable
if the clusterings are very senior it's small
actually in computer science almost everybody reinvents this this
not so so much statistics because they they have
prior they have other distances but computers and people just renamed it all the time
so it comes under many names
OK so what's the problem with this distance is large
well if the distance is large is
if k is large which means that is more likely that the clusterings are different
than the mismatch will be small
or the matching this small
by definition this is lower dimensional small
and this is only cares about how many points are measured doesn't care what happens
to them especially
however we may want to care about it and let me show you an example
i changed want to do that i can change it to the
the misclassification error says these two are about the same distance from the
because the mass the number of match points is the the same
however you may seen here
this group of your points is all read
whereas he this group popular point has to be in two different colors red and
equally likely
but there
so are
so now
very important for us
o down so
of them
and you
right show
well over one
o twenty
got the idea of you might be
so we now
in the u
that same
people are
the problem
it is interesting to hear what they did is they actually live the second year
on it
which given an input patch
besides we how to oriented so that it can run
the real detector
now turns out to work quite well they get sixty three sixty degree rotation invariance
the detector and if it would take to on top of
yet another convolutional neural net thing here this is the face detector again produced by
the group made the first network
and it's interesting
in that it's in multiview detector so detect your face
essentially any orientation
and it's in a single neuron it
which is quite hard to figure out how to do
so there's a little bit of complexity and figuring out exactly the way to do
this in the learning process and the way they did
was that they
first of all code orientations of ever
training set has orientations of faces and
and they code those orientations as unit vectors in some high dimensional space so typically
you simply say well is it in the section of the right was looking at
this particular angles also call
looking straight forward things like this you this whole series of different things at least
nine dimensional space here and he simply can make the unit vector out where my
twenty two in the space that's that's very easy to do and what you've got
these unit vectors the system actually is trained with the input image and non pose
and in fact also with face and all the things looking at so so it
using information you don't normally have when you're running the detector
to do the training and to find a good way of finding this angular response
out so i said you know data here
so you have you know that code faces and then zero for nonfaces sitting in
the central these unit vectors so typically list space something looks like the more minutes
there will be more like a face in some unit vector which points in the
right direction to the orientation
OK and the way use this thing is that because you initially trained with an
orientation you actually have to do search of orientations but that's a fairly quick gradients
so it can be done essentially in real time so this detector works in real
it is one of the more rotation invariant
it was
most of the
it has very good resistance to inclusion this is running individual image by individual image
has no temporal smoothing anything here
it's still quite smooth
on another approach human state
so this is based on local features
and what is going to do is is going to try to
use local tissues
some kind of interest points to case
i found the image so will take the image will calculate interest points
everywhere some of them will happen to line people
and will try to use the local appearance are the ones that haven't line people
is cues to kind of
bootstrap itself into voting process
to find the positions of the person so it knows on the training set what
kinds of interest points who produced and what the silhouette of the person was one
for the training set from that it has a kind of probabilistic model season interest
point knows roughly where person might be it's very fuzzy model what's in a couple
of interest points models start getting more and more precise until it can make kind
of segmentation of the person that based on this interest points
it can also
and occlusions and things like that by by figuring out
kind of assigning
interest points to a particular person models attracting that model and looking for other things
so this is actually fairly good performance and the model is not as good as
the simplest being modelled i talked about
a while ago
but it contains a lot richer information so
it's able to to tell you a lot more about the scene to deal with
things like inclusions with one count
OK so that's what i'm going to talk about object recognition
o to detection
but there's a whole series of other things you might want to do with images
of people
for example build some model of how they vary
if the person is walking they have characteristic notion
this is changing expression of characteristic things so there's the a whole set of the
learning methods involved in learning some kinds of models for variation articulation or human pose
and things like that have
OK so the simplest ones
everybody knows this linear PCA
i can faces is called vision
so you take a set of
images of faces roughly aligned
varying people living expression varying lighting
treat each image is the vector
you build a principal components analysis of that city vectors
and that captures the main degrees of variation in the set
that's fine it's not really very deep in the visual sense not doing alignment is
not doing a correction for elimination
doesn't really have a strong model
but nevertheless these models because the purely appearance based quite powerful for a number of
things and once you've thought of principal components analysis well as a whole
a lot of other than you
analysis techniques you can use the news fisher linear discriminant to project out
good discrimination directions
between different people for example
you can use independent components analysis to try to to figure out what the things
are the most independent about for example the signals interface
so will typically collapse things like corners of eyes and things like that has been
the most characteristic signals faces there's a whole series of other new techniques that you
can use
this you might not be able to see very here but this a model varying
of the different PCA components
four seasons that wants him OK so that's kind of simple technique
people look down on these days but it does have its uses
and and
standard deviation is forty times larger than the mean of
in the two two dimensional histogram
which has the interesting feature
that there is a slight positive correlation between the two as
which means that either
well they
increase the larger probability the
increased together or decrease together
then the probability that coca-cola increases and i e IBM crazy or by the very
well to the corner of the
the probabilities of these coordinates are
then he is said
almost and the corners
of the histogram
and here is a curve
illustrating the concept of the balance or fall ill
if you put all your money at the very beginning to coca-cola then there is
that it is the twenty two years longer than the bar
then you're return for coca-cola is larger than thirteen
and in IBM just slightly larger than to that
if you
every three
that the portfolio
for people who have that
then the
results of the first flight was that you can achieve
the better
asymptotic average growth
so having no regard hold two
the debut your initial at the very beginning
four all around us he the average growth rate of the better
if you put
in each morning if you apply because the balanced portfolio
then each morning according to to a fixed portfolio you rearrange your money
and in each morning
sixty per cent of your money is invested in google scholar
forty per who IBM
we may have to read the
friday afternoon i will show you that the
that if you use a portfolio
four which the portfolio each morning
b band
on the part of the return vector
you me and she
for the benefit we use along the maybe
it's the of eighteen
so v
the dependent portfolio you may gain much more
every day
but the portfolio vector according to which you make thirty but that is changing
from b to b
i i i give you an example
you may
playing games
we do is they thought that just taking into account IBM and cash
and in each morning
you both some of your money to IBM and either ask for cash
and the
maybe the following simple rules
on that day in the preview they don't IBM increase
then put all your money to the cash
and vice versa
if the preview they
died and bequeathed them with all your money to live here
you may gain out around
if i remember well with these things
yeah but secondly i again use the same rules
so you have to flip flop
obviously you will not make
correct decisions
at each day
so the question was
that for the not memoryless
not memoryless processes markov processes
the whole the
rebel as being is is is made
and the answer was that that in this case
i i make every balancing each morning
by the way of rebalancing portfolio vector or
is there
i strongly depending
on the
preview the big star
people the question
these are some examples i would like to
summarize the the consequences of these
constantly rebalanced portfolios
and in order to avoid that
common misunderstanding get
around this
and mathematical finance of the like very value because there
not a single as trading but you because there are many as the best
the basic math each of
of these
log optimum portfolio
is that the
the real
the amount of capital
because the restart it because at the band portfolio
is not close to
it expectation
i will show you that it is much much less
and at some point idea was very excited to decide the but i was wrong
so if you think oriented lines that these hyperplanes
the VC dimension three that's quite well-known facts get three points
you can find people to consider it in all possible ways
because they're not aligned
you do i love you wouldn't be able to separate
and you can find set
if you take any set of four points
there is the separation
o xo problem of these four points
but not going to be able to separate with linear optics
now if you know the whole thing
well it doesn't actually do
in that case because
it requires that
you can
any set of three point or instead of two points
let let me
if you take a set of three points
also set of three points but the three points line
you cannot separate them
so you can have you can classify
therefore the popper dimension is less than three
but the idea of proof that the
critical this is so institution condition was based on the VC dimension they were very
happy to see what goes wrong
but it's also quite interesting to realise that
but by using
this philosophy
and that means by using mathematics came to very similar conclusions
one of the important things in practice about that need to theory
is the structure of musician twenty
and i've been surprised when i met nick
i was in ninety one
i told him i was very excited excited by cicero's musician was very surprised because
many people read the book
but they were defeated when you go to that point
and that point is the important one
we have this kind of bond
well basically the error you're going to do
on from
in the test set
is going to be less than a or you in the training set
president functions of the number of examples capacity in the confidence
so to minimize the air all you do
on the best that you could just minimize that one
but you can do smart if you minimize both terms
so therefore need to to make edge the capacity control viable and the way to
do it is to say that they
set function that are just like a russian puppet
in each of them you can find it
i mean most of the empirical risk
evaluate this them
and for each of these solutions can
david the sun and pick the best one
and there is something that was proved the
much later in fact by the void
is that this method is strongly universally consistent
i'm not going to explain what strongly universally means
in that case that means
the general idea is that if you do that
using lighting about which are quite losing not very good but you refused that is
one of the
you guarantee
you're going to find the optimal decision boundary
so it's interesting to compare again this all comes results
with the circuitry was musician quincy
o comes with all its is entities should not be multiplied beyond necessity
if the statement about the function you find on this function should have too many
got extra concept
the structure was musicians says that we should explain the observed facts
using the function from the subset with the smallest capacity
explain the observed facts using the theory which is easy to falsify
and you see something about the number of concepts and the theory that is it
nothing really tells you
nothing let's fuzzification and the number of concert use
and in fact
the capacity of the VC dimension this does this problem both entities
so there are cases where this is true
but if you have a linear as apparent OR
the VC dimension is equal to the number of entities plus one of the parameters
i think the indicator function is the sign of the dot product of x and
some parameters the bias
and we know that edge in that case and plus one
but also came with the VC dimension is that is infinity
well in fact there is just one parameter
if you take the indicator which is the sign of the signs of x
well a department
in fact you can make the sun also led so fast that can survive anything
you want
so in that case
the capacity is infinite
but the number of parameters number of entities in the sinus
it is simple functions
and in fact is if you report by again according to common opinion the sine
function is a simple one
but the thing in
to get you into trouble
and there is of course the opposite pole
well if you think and i plan beginning as apparent
but with the constraints on the normal the punishers and assuming your conference from normal
examples well
and the
if you require classification with a margin
then you can find not the VC dimension because of the analogous to simulation theory
where the capacity is bounded
by the ratio
the radius of the points
by the margin you have
and that means that in that case
the capacity is bounded by the number of farming with this about about of than
that can be much smaller
so you can make systems in which you have a very large number of parameters
and yet acceptable capacity
the goal of the three slide is to show that you know the capacity is
not the same as the number of parameters
in general
and this idea
this the coupling to
and that was the beginning of the support vector machines from the efforts to optimize
planes in the sixties
increase the number of parameters
map the input vector in a very high dimensional space
and control of capacity in this high dimensional space
the idea is that by increasing the dimensionality of the space
you can decrease
meant that this ratio
into an acceptable range
i actually should be here
maintenance ratio into an acceptable range
basically make it work
so for instance if you have this
green points in which one from the line
you cannot separate them with a simple hyperplane
but if you mapped them into two-dimensional space switzerland called from the line becomes you
and new square basically you put all points in the problem
you can find as apparently going to survive the right from the green
now we if we work on the margin in this two-dimensional space you can still
make something that's going to learn
at this point the like to come back to the orginal project vladimir
he was saying
he was thinking this
analogy of physical science all the smart people said
if you have too many parameters you cannot make useful reductions
this is a counterexample this is an example where you can have lots of parameters
and still make useful deduction
so there are some technical details that are probably going to say keep because the
mister the slide too incomplete to mark this be
meaningful enough
p nor
falls and just put using a different notation
that's right
if underneath
that's what we know
and now
whereas the contradiction well we have and use this bit what does he say
our assumption was that pino was true everywhere
in particular
it's true here
OK i mean this process you can't just understand them off the top head you've
got to work through the case
that's why i'm trying to draw diagram and hopefully if you sort of copy the
diagram down you can work for
i claim a couple of exercises and again because and pushed to the limit for
time i'm going to let you work through these
all the instances of phi implies sign players phi i k valid
and again the proof is by contradiction
on tree
i'm sorry i just can't i've spent so much time on
on the introduction that i'm just going to have to let you work through these
right so what i'm showing you what i'm trying to say here is that
the shapes somehow
because no matter what
what you substitute into the final size long with the same fine here and here
and then possibly different sign there
you'll find that
no matter what model you choose
this thing is true
same with
this guy
and same with this guy
what's going on well they're all theorems of classical propositional logic
they're all classical tautologies
so i'm not doing anything model there are no boxes in diamonds here that's why
i don't want to go through the details here and there is nothing notable going
OK what about this one
this is what i claimed
this shape
hezbollah it's true
on all models
so let's do
do the same thing again until proof by contradiction
here we are
i claim that
that's for a contradiction assume
let me just get the right
o things sfi one and so i want OK phi one implies i one implies
by one
box size one
so for a contradiction assume that it's not valid
what does it mean it means that there is some model
and some world
here it is
such that
some instances of these
which is
so there some instance of this which is also
i'm not going to bother instantiating i'm just going to take it is indeed what
does it mean for an implication to be false it means that this part is
so this is going to be true
and this
it is false
but the implication is false when this part is true in this part falls
let's just work through it
what does it mean for this thing to befall so it's also an implication so
that means that box by one is true
and books i one
is false
what does it mean for this to be false
this is
every step deposit successor makes i want true
going to do is we want that statement to be false
right every
so i want true
four forces side
that's right that every success
so i
well if that's false then it means some success
forces the negation of size one
so here we are we begin
there some success
which makes i one false
that's what it means
the negation of this is some success
forces not science
this guy is true in our world
so this guy says well every successor has to force if one
well now we have a successor
so we know that phi one is true
in this crisis is
every success
has to force fi one implies i one
we have a success
so if i one implies so one has to be true
we have a problem
just use your truth tables
this is whenever phi one is true so i want this to be true
or phi one is true
so someone has to be true
that's what this implications but we just
what does that
so i one had to be false
so there is a contradiction
so what that says is
no matter what
model you take no matter what valuation take
this shape
is true in all models in our world
this the first model shape we see
it's not
theorem of classical logic is known is
the KX
OK here's some more
i'm trying to tell you properties of logical consequence remember
so the first one is if i is in gamma then phi is a logical
consequence of gamma
why is that
if i is in there than five logical consequence y
because logical consequences
you take
and all the members of gamma true everywhere
if advising the
then of course five straight away
and then what is the right hand say well i to be true everywhere well
surprise surprise
OK so that's trivial
if i is a logical consequence of gamma
then talks five logical consequence of gamma so if i is a logical consequence of
fox five is a logical consequence of gamma
all the members of gamma true everywhere
and phi is a logical consequence of gamma
then phi is true everywhere
you pick a particular point w
and you know it flies to everywhere
you want to know
where the box five true w
if it doesn't have any successes
your home already
because they did in makes a box formula of any form true
if it doesn't have successes so it's got five them four of them
we want to know whether phi is true at these points
but that's what this is if gamma is true everywhere five straight away so we
already know that phi is true everywhere including here
then this guy just said well look i can see those guys and all the
guys that i can see make fighter
there's is an exercise therefore you the bottom
i have
the papers have words in and a topic
sites relationship so the papers cite other papers
and just to make this clearer and actually copying this
paper class over here
it really
is the same one hears of in ER diagram you one it this way and
then maybe
papers have others
so if we set aside
as appear with attribute uncertainty initially we might have things like a simple
the naive bayes flavor
topic model
maybe we also have the
area for the topic
we can say something about the
other institution
anything on their research area
if we want to
get into
the uncertainty that we potentially have
about this relationship so in terms of what papers
which papers
a way of setting this up probabilistically
that may make sense or may not
is too
you can view it like we have
and somehow
downloaded all
the very last part got corrupted
i have the bibliography
and i know the number of entries there
i know that there's three entries but i just don't know
which papers they refer to
and there are a number of natural settings where you know the number of things
that you related to you just don't know who
you related to so reference uncertainty is a way of dealing with that
it explicitly going in and adding an
i dependence model
if you think about it four
the foreign keys
and this relationship
the trick is
i don't want to have
i dependence model that explicitly says well the probability of referring to this
specific papers this the this other specific papers this and so on i want to
be able to generalise in some way across the US and so the trick is
to avoid
doing the naive approach which would be in
multinomial over the primary keys
the related object
stuff is a little too it's going to be
nine contact do not going to be able to learn very well but also
an important thing to keep in mind is it limits your ability to generalize to
in new
situation where you have different papers
and in some domains is an important some domains it's not
the way
to think about this
i'm going to take
and a set of objects that i can refer to
and in some way form a partition
of those objects
in this example
making life easy thing well there's only
topics the papers can be
they can only be a i papers are theory papers and
in this world where i only have
five papers
two of them are AI
papers and three of them
our theory papers
and then what i can do is i can
i have a distribution over the set of paper that says
i'm going to say
a i paper
with probability point three
and so
theory paper with probability points
and then the way the model works is it assumes
uniform distribution
that would mean with probability point one five i will refer to this one point
one five refer to this
OK so this is the way of getting a compact parameterisation
this distribution of over references to objects
but it's actually not that exciting
but the easy thing that you can do is
you can add in something that says
please add
parent to this
and make this
a little bit more interesting to say
of the people are
influences what papers say so
if i a theory paper then i
much more likely to
so a theory papers from
OK i paper
much much much more likely to
so in a i paper and
well only say theory paper with a very small ability so
i can
in the same way that i have the conditional distribution
for any other attribute i can have the conditional distribution
over this attribute that has
reference uncertainty
the place where this gets
a little bit complicated is in making sure that all the sense still being illegal
one way
kind of understanding this is
the bayes net that i'm introducing now has this
structure where
i have
foreign key