generic statements which are generically true about the world now a lot of the power
of unknown come from boring binary ground facts about this particular instance of the world
thinks that just happen to be true
and i think you could even make a point from cognitive science about this a
lot of our intelligence comes not from being smart in general just come from knowing
a lot of stuff
a lot of these big graph
and actually we can be a little bit more precise about the relationship between
the small black circle and the and to be quite graph
so here are
some numbers that some of you may have seen on the screen yesterday
when jacob or by gave his talk about a distributed backward chaining reasoning
and he did the following experiment he took three of the largest datasets that we
so LUBM is a synthetic dataset you can make arbitrarily large
then linked life data
which is about two and a half dozen
the largest life science datasets semantically integrated
and fact forge
which is the PDF plus plus so it's a lot of encyclopedic knowledge to the
pedia plus the internet movie database plus music plus etcetera etcetera and your geography names
and so on
and what you did
it is said OK i'll take the schemas
of those things so that the small black circle and i do the full complete
forward closure
i compute all the inferences and see how long it takes into doing the schema
closure is measured in the order of seconds
or a small number of minutes
in the second experiment was
not only take to the black
the black circle but richard with the big graph and the closure of the whole
and then suddenly the run time is measured in hours
and and by the way notice that we take here somehow the measure of the
size of the circles not just counting the triples but we're taking somehow how complex
it is to do with right so how long does it take to do inference
of i think it's more interesting
of how large the circle should be drawn you see that there is one or
two orders of magnitude in in
the difference in size between
how much it takes to do inference of the white graph or
over the terminological knowledge only
so if we go back to the previous slide
i was like this
these numbers tell us
the slide should really look like this
this is how small terminologies are
compared to our factual knowledge
and it's very easy to imagine that you would blow up the
the factual knowledge that it's very easy to imagine that you make is why draft
but it's much harder to think
and how to arbitrarily make black don't make a right as i was only so
much to acknowledge you could possibly want to write down
so the slogan here is it's a box stupid
that's where the power of our
of our representations are
and again understanding this law
helps us to design artifacts so it's exactly this insight that helps us to do
and distributed reasoning because we can see that
because the closure is so small and the black dot is so small we can
easily replicated across all computing nodes
it's more you can keep it in memory everywhere but at crucial key insight from
this law that you need to know in order to make this informed to design
OK let's look a little bit more this notion of of how complex this terminological
knowledge is
in the next claim is of course to political knowledge is not only small
there's little red
compared to factual knowledge but it's also a very low complexity
what we have
looking at something like how
right OWL is is
it's it's it's strong highly expressive language but depending on where you look now we
either use such as a big expressive language or
and that was of course very often we only use a very small part of
it but somehow there is this unreasonable effectiveness of low expressivity knowledge representation
it is much
more x effective then you would have expected based on on the on the history
of of a research for example
and of course it's nice that we have not only the small language that we
use a lot of the time
it's nice that we also have the expressive language is for the case when we
need it
and there are cases when we need it
so it's not a one zero distribution in the way this is
this is in no way zones if distribution that the vast majority of ontologies are
very lightweight and is a tale of of heavyweight ontologies and it's nice that we
can use these expressive parts if you want to and there's even a bit more
good news there that even though these expressive
languages have very scary complexity measures
in practice though scary complexity measures those worst case complexity measures don't really hit this
in practice
so there was a beautiful talk yesterday by how by student from manchester difficult you
name apologies about how to classify highly expressive ontologies very efficiently i anyway laughing at
the worst case complexity to
the real k the average case complexity is is lower and again this is something
useful to know where you are informing your what something useful to know what you
are designing your defects
know in the worst case complexity bounds are just that worst case
complexity bounds and apparently the information universe is not always worst case
now of course is a key topic in our community is heterogeneity right and then
we know
that originate eighty is unavoidable
it's for good reasons that shows the tower of babel
the metaphor for the vocabulary
that we write
and i think where
something new that we've discovered
column two
OK so this fish that screen
and what is the a correlated equilibrium
it's an equilibrium
it is distribution
or fish which
where you're best off following the fish's advice
so let's say we know the distribution of the fish using
and the fish suggests that
so just to play a role one
now this distribution i've drawn in this picture so what is this game just explain
this so this game would reach choosing
a row and column numbers between one and three
my goal is obviously to match your number if i matching number then i get
your goal is to be one bigger than my number or if it's three wrap
one so your goal is to be off by one from my number and if
you're off by one one bigger
then you get one i get nothing
so this is a very competitive game it's not a zero-sum game
but it's a competitive game where only one of us can win but sometimes need
arose when
OK so now let's say that the fisher suggested has actually picked from this table
according to this distribution which is basically choosing an entry which is not zero zero
making sure that one of us will win at random but not telling us which
and he told me now that i should play a role one
now given that he told me that i should play a role one
knowing how this page works
i see that that probably he told the opponent to play
for sure he told appointed by the column one column two
in fact if he's really being faithful to distribution then it is equally likely that
he's playing column one column two
given that he told me
to play a role one easy and another opponent disposal is equally likely to play
columns one column two
i'm actually best off sticking with his advice
o the point fifty fifty here if i play role one get half if i
play o two are going to have a three again zero so
it is a good idea to follow his advice
this fish is called the correlation device and is helping us play the game and
actually is you see we're getting more money
then we would have had we just
probably if we just play the game regularly to fish the only equilibrium is reached
randomized in the third of the time of us make money so each only make
money third in this case making have
the fish can really help in this cause this idea of a correlation devices really
there in the real world as well like a traffic signal
presume we don't both want to go through the intersection
if there were no traffic signal we would have to sort of
we have to do something else but this traffic signatures that one of us because
and the other doesn't
in this idea is is by
the great game named
it's been around for well it's not quite as popular as nash equilibrium but has many
nice properties that the nash equilibrium
OK so again we have this notion of correlated with many questions about political events
OK so now
this internal regret condition
if you have no internal regret that actually
a statement about you playing a correlated equilibrium which is very surprising to me because
there is no correlation device there's no fish were playing this game we're just playing
a game i'm making actions you make it is officially what to do
so let's think about the game played the sequence of rows and columns who knows
in hindsight we have no internal regret which means that i wouldn't rather
that means i don't regret
changing all my ones two threes or vice versa
any other pair of countries
well you know if you think about this sequence not a sequence but is actually
a distribution over cells in this game if you actually draw from a distribution
need another letter for distribution
now i ran out of letters i just took p
the picture of p p so he's so if you have another distribution p
which is the distribution over the cells in the game that we actually played
and this will be correlated equilibrium if we have no internal regret
because again no internal regret means that the thing about this is the distribution with
mean distribution someone came and chosen random
one of these
random time
between one of our
play around in this game and passes to play according to that
we have no internal regret means when when i'm advised to play
column row two i will play to my best response
and that's exactly the same as this correlated equilibrium
so it turns out that there are very natural algorithms for getting no internal regret
i don't have time to talk about them but you can use the weighted majority
in combination with
some tricks to get a no internal regret algorithm and this means that you end
up playing a game
only found that really is look up
factor two
no i
also question answering in current
can be classified in this category
but of course more and more and we are dealing with information
you can try to acquire the knowledge base knowledge of the
from the from
the kind of unstructured data sources such as text or other
you can try to aggregate to compare
sort of network analyzers you can change
and eventually you can go much more
you can have your system to predict recessions or so
and really really perform intelligence functions like synthesis
discovery predicting
so for crossing
but of course
so far
well we are all the machine
automatic but that we might
maybe i that is also the beginning of the first lecture
why now
this any information that is that
with regard to information extraction and text mining
well what is the claimed
they are both immature information quite a long time also
information extraction
now we can see that might have established technologies
why how can
i think i
it is compatible with it
multimedia when try i also
an object to recognise the information in the data
might be person might be object
might be more categories while some
the classes
it's like being on the other side of the north sea off birthday party
so we
get used
semantically system for and this is also something we could do text why not
also for question
but sometimes it it's today
and next to search
well looking at kind of agenda setting
what we've been looking at
so will try to integrate information extraction
taking into the true model
the careful
if the angle is positive i call this the positive angle
the average velocity is positive
but if i
have negative angle
average velocity would be negative for instance
between t four and t five
if i draw this line
then this angle here
so the average velocity between p four and p five
is now
again if i had to change the zero point
you would have found the same values for the average velocity the only difference would
have been
the position of the curve
in that
there's a very big difference in physics between speed
and velocity
the average velocity between time t one and t five
is zero
with the average speed
is not
the average speed
it is defined
the distance travelled
divided by the time that it takes to travel that distance
one is the distance
that the object travelled between
time t one and time t five
well the object
i started at the position here on these x axis
and then it went up
reach the highest point year
so i make a drawing for you here
which the highest point here
and it went down
and then when it went here
it went up again
comes down again
and its back
in order to find the average speed
you wouldn't have to know exactly what this distances
and at this distance
and at this distance and this this
and if that distance altogether were for instance three hundred metres
and if
the time between
one ninety five
for three seconds
then the average speed would be three hundred metres
divided by three seconds that would be hundred meters per second so the average speed
would be hundred meters per second
yet the average velocity would be
if you look at the location
and t two
and i bring the three closer and closer
then this angle of all five will increase
and i can go to the extreme that i bring t three
almost right at t two
the angle of of fire will then be
to this point
this will then be
my angle of
and now you will understand
how we define
instantaneous velocity
at the time
which is different from
average velocity between two time intervals
and i pick a random time t
equals the limiting case
four x
measured at time t plus delta t
minus x
measured time t
divided by delta t
and i do that for delta t
two zero
think this
think of this as being the three and this as a tool i bring t
closer and closer and closer to t two
and the time between them then goes to zero
and this
is something that you undoubtedly recognise that's the first derivative
after position versus time
and now comes in equation
which is one of the very few
that i want you to remember
in fact in a one
the x dt
this is one
thank you
you must remember not only in a one but for the rest of your time
at MIT
and this could be larger than zero
this could be zero
and this could be smaller than zero
if the angle of o five
the tangential is positive
then it is a positive value if it is negative however
you here then it is negative philosophy
and if the angle of alpha is zero
the velocity is zero
so if we now look at this plot
we can search for the times that the velocity is zero
so you have to look for the derivative being zero that means the
angle of being zero
clearly here
the velocity is zero
right here this turning point
that means many objective here is zero
when the object is here it is again zero at this moment in time
then the angle is zero
and it is again zero here so those are the times
that's the velocity is zero one hundred times that the velocities positive
positive here
it is positive here
still positive positive becomes negative
negative positive zero and negative
that's the definition of the instantaneous
once the instantaneous speed
b is not time-sensitive
suppose that the velocity here
just cycle that v one
suppose that was class thirty meters per second i just grabbed this number
out of the blue
and suppose you somewhere
it was i call that v two
suppose that was minus one hundred meters per second
this is negative
and this is positive then we would have to say in physics whether you like
it or not it's not very pleasing but you would have to say that this
velocity is lower than that one
because minus hundred
is low and employs thirty
what this means of course
is higher here because the speed is the
the magnitude of
velocity and is not signed sensitive so this has the highest bid two hundred meters
per second and this has a lower speed
but this has the lowest velocity it just an algebraic game but very important when
you make your calculations
i have always
i one wondered
what the
average speed only average velocity is of a bullet
now i want you to realize i'm not a fan of guns at all
but it always intrigued me
how can i measure
the average speed
of a
and i've discussed it with some people here
and we came up with
easy way to do
had wire
goes into the blackboards
y one
and we have another wind it goes into the black or white two
and the separation
it is
i mean we have to measure that
set up this year
so this is
why are number one
and this is why are number two
OK let's get started
so welcome back everybody to the second part of my lecture on
machine learning about magic i hope you enjoy the talk they had some might break
out of the paper and now fresh water
OK i would like to start recently
are repeating that what happened lectures that many many things in between just repeatedly
OK so therefore parts we can actually covered the hive introduction to bioinformatics
and i started talking about being can today i'm going to talk about large scale
data structures
to to be used in conjunction with think about it which in data and what
structure of learning so it's quite some
topics covered
OK so i guess the main point for the introduction to bioinformatics was that there
are many different data types and at least four five of them i mentioned that
protein networks
and sequences genomic sequences population they expression data so they come in different data types
depending on the ground
speedy according to the coordinate
in the end we evaluate metric and you would like to inference back to do
in the top
OK so this was
one of the main point
the main point was that something like called the central dogma i hope you remember
something about that being a story told information almost all the information and then this
is called transcription which copies from nineteen eight to them on a and then b
some post postprocessing step of them on a and of like things
and finally the which is called translation that produces the protein the protein are proteins
are the active component in the cell detecting which it with each other
on a projective plane
i mean it acting with
and then were you have to apply things like will in and then introduced
not and and with eighty
OK anybody what these movies
OK me that it can
it so i talked about at the running example recognition of but right
and if you are interested in classifying sequences of this type so we have the
a gene sequence in the middle this boundary between intron exon
always having the ATT here
and then we try to learn rules which can but i think the
which of course by five other retirement i mean like one other appearances of AG
which are not lie
positive and negative
and i guess today you have the introduction into the water pressure and you probably
have seen pictures like this and i think i missed points
first introduced this one two features the sequence and before and after the eighty and
then came up with some non-linear decision boundary but then we discussed several approaches for
more powerful decision boundary maybe not based on who features what features
and we talked about it
which used much more features than just two
and most importantly the spectrum kernel spectrum kernel
it's essentially looking at all puritans came appearing in the sequence OK and became stretch
of sequence
if you look at k nucleotides or
OK i mean the role nancy which combination here in your
what in sequence
and to compute the kernel interested in all the pain
when you the one who has been attributed the to c
another important question would be great degree kernel has the
it is different in the sense that it takes position positional information into account for
the spectrum kernel not take position information it just takes
it just makes it kind of statistics about all the payment which appear in the
sequence but but it doesn't use the the information we have here different for the
weighted degree kernel
so o
but we can out
formulation which i talk about
and then that we become which which allows some
my notion of sequent against each other
OK so i mean i showed you the text
small simulation results where
we compared what life recognition spectrum kernel to compute the area under the policy can
be computed the
four different ringling for up for the kernel and four different if we were to
because of the computer the out
and we've seen of course of the position can become much better than the position
independent code for the
purpose of life
OK so i added to the side the book which i used to generate figure
if we can just play around with that so that actually there is that there
these which are used to generate interest i think that link on the wiki to
some other page and download the data and
so i had something more to play say about
i would like to show you some
i mean what impact any more now
also some scripts which can also download from the wiki page
OK so
this is an artificial dataset i artificially generated hundred sequences each of length two hundred
and if if think a hundred and fifty positive and fifty negative so the negative
see what users actually do
and then based on what we observe try to make additional recommendations try to do
automatic personalisation of certain things you know two things specifically for that user to
you know improved
according to some
measure right i mean of course and recommendation we would like to maybe recommend items
that are valuable to the user in any common setting we might actually want to
recommend things that users wanted to buy and so on and so forth so and
the idea is that the user would not need to actually issuing a query right
like in information retrieval the user wouldn't be
it would be necessary to use as you know i'm looking for this and that
but rather that we can do it somehow implicitly on what what we observe about
that user and that would be good because the user doesn't have to specify it
and also we can make a recommendation even if the user doesn't want them so
that's also good e-commerce setting isn't it
so that's the idea you know what what types types of things we can do
without actually query and instead of using things like building user profiles
so of course you know this is this is done any common setting you know
you look at them as on CD now and so on and so forth in
information retrieval you know we have pushed technology where people are not actively searching but
rather information is brought to them in certain folders are agent technology and so on
and so forth intelligent user interfaces and if you look at it of course you
know and amazon on
you see this in know this year you know hello such-and-such and we have recommendations
for you this is where the recommender systems used or you know you have these
very simple things like customer who bought a particular book prove in this case also
bought some other stuff so these are all types of things
well you haven't actually should query where the system kind of makes recommendations to you
can and so the type of data that we might use for that
i can be of you know different types we can actually use explicit feedback often
so user ratings or user provides even review
or you know
it feels of the questionnaire and so on and so forth all we might also
want to use implicit feedback like you know what the pages visited what have you
purchased whatever you downloaded the we might even go to the level of clickstreams and
so on and so forth
OK and so
if we want to do that there are no two ways that we can go
one is content based filtering k is that somehow we learn about the
we look at the properties of objects
that seem to matter to you it would be more or less standard learning setting
right you know we you have let's say the the things that you buy in
the things that you're not buying and so we would like to find out what
are the things that you buy as opposed to the ones that do not by
and we try to to do that based on the attributes of objects OK based
on the content of things well the problem is often that there might not be
very good predictive attributes OK so we might think of think of movies and things
like that it's very hard you know we might favour certain directors and actors but
you know that might just be very weak predict actually of whether we like it
or not the other idea in in
recommender systems that has been quite successful is the idea of collaborative for social filtering
which means that well look you know if i am is on i have hundreds
of millions of customers right that come to my website
i can not
you know it's it's not just that i could treat every customer individually and try
to learn this but i can use the information have from other customers right to
make recommendations for a particular customer and the idea is that there is some similarity
typically in the way
you know the the types of interest that people have the type preference that people
have that for instance if i would find you know a lot of customers that
are very similar to a particular customer i could use the things that these customers
this is why we are coming to an end
techniques of the only write this
as a learning problem so we have
sometimes is that he takes i call signals x i have some involvement the which
will have the loss function l
which is the solution the last
so what you want to do is to have phoenix finding trendsetters for at the
centre of course
we are in the world
because of having these values
very cheap
like a before you take the picture is that it can i have to admit
it but she so
and then consider the case where n is very large
rules you have like a pool to learn to show you the basis of natural
images you can have
question number of that so what we
might want to instead of these policies
there are two key made the thing because
and this is
something which can be analyzed using unlabelled technique
so indeed when i know can
handle potentially infinite that's
it can also add up with a name change
for instance if you have to do
you might not have the future they may want to optimize dynamically your dictionary
and what is not it's also
in this case from faster than batteries
so i think the
but when was before that also immediately of working in this field
so here is what i want
what we do is we can we do it with a large number of iterations
at each iteration the basic idea is really
for one thing and one of the things which is why you c
then propose
it spent for new elements we compute the space program computing this and that he
and using
the quran which which is here the
team one and that he
the main purpose of
so here
two things to
make decisions the first of all you have to be able to deal with this
but i think that should be so here in case have small
sparsity problem with very high quality
like if
that has like
of size one former
maybe had we can have ten or fifteen until it so in this situation happens
that love is performing very well and what we have is
for the dictionary
it's a bit more tricky because it could look like a bigot easier for the
purpose of each iteration
but one that we had the black hole what we fix all the problems of
the but once
then we can have a closed form for updating the
the kind of be
and it turns out that this
each musician according to the easier to
we know how to
the with this algorithm which is the way the world
the function
the real world
and we see data which guarantees that
so if you want you to say
all this stuff and the said you can last for the
user group which for the we want stop
that minimizes to of the deep sea
these very close to the one produced
the oceans of the solution exhaustivity made one which
it efficiently use the semantic web as well
and then there is also something so can
using the following single
the training set you can make a small evaluation more like fifty eight months
of the training set at each iteration this is the almost
so i began to make a say the function of the nice
when the the
which we call here i t
very nice
so the sense of the word that is the basic poses which we want to
that is there when t tends to infinity with probability one
and then the the second guarantees that
if we consider all the special of the musicians before and that we have beginning
the distance between the seventeenth and the
when t tends to to infinity
and we we
happy with this
so now i going to the extent that
for those who are familiar with the kind of those which can be
finally on his skills as well
so we
there is a from of the problem
and this will be
most important
for the second part when we study a case of instrumental variables because we use
exactly this result and just replace this box and then at minus and by the
instrument regression and the associated
estimation ising contamination
so what they did there is a kind of expansion sympathy expansion
land and at minus lambda which is subject to study is exactly equal to the
difference of these two functions he of men at nine minus and
and the problem is that they don't know is apparent he
so i just
apply this
i just differentiating
this difference
to obtain two parts
the first part
which is which would be much nice to study since it could no part
in the difference and minus and plus the residual term
so the idea that would be to study
the first part and study the rate of convergence of the first part and try
to control this was an attempt to get rid of this residual and the first
result is that these
this linear part can be written as the integral
from zero to ics of the difference between them and that and n
multiply by function
gamma gamma extend i have haven't to explain what is exactly this function it's not
really important the important thing is that doesn't depend on n
so it would change the results are asymptotic results what is important is that
i have i can
right to difference lambda n minus that as an integral part part of an automated
system and the main part of it means that if i can control the residual
then i will be able to prove that i can indeed improve the rate of
convergence since i will improve the regularity of of the initial estimate
an idea of the proof of these results to do
the starting point of all the asymptotic results show
how to transform this
nonlinear problem to me no one was it and exposure to the right of reply
eminently n
so the idea is use
but we have a new place in diffusion of how into parameter lambda operator
and any of them
and we want to express lambda as a function of and so the idea is
to to place the implicit functions so
to derive solution lambda as a function of n
so there is
some of course some assumptions to to check on and around and and and
under these assumptions
we can prove that
there exists an open subset around the true function and
such that ended an open subset around the true function lambda such that f of
ten lambda equal to zero is also satisfied so i can extend the
this relation a and lambda equal to zero to some open subset of one the
two functions and and
and this is
quite nice since i can then use
this result these
a second relation and differentiate this relation in this open since it to obtain to
transform the initial nonlinear differential equations to solve it into a linear differential equation
in a
in the first derivative of ft
played and then at and minus and and the good point in that i can
solve the linear differential equation and then i can obtain an exact form for the
solution of these linear differential equations
so the the idea is that when you have
nonlinear problem to solve is to try to transform it into a linear one to
be able to solve it
to some residual term that has to be controlled and in order to obtain an
exact the exact dependence between a and the solution of the differential equation
the first estimate of enactments and that's the main point
so now using these
this is
the results asymptotic results can derive on the solutions lambda in at manus island
so mainly what do we expect expect to improve the weights of conventions and we
expect to improve the rate of convergence in two
in two directions first
so the differential equation so if assume that n is continuously differentiable all the to
the solution lambda conditioning with b
continuously differentiable of all the three so we haven't yet again in regularity of the
into this parameter and also we have an overview again in dimension since the first
function m was depending on two arguments and my solution and that depends on one
argument so i have
i expect gain in two dimensions and fortunate be able to
check that we obtain these games
is the use cutting plane the strategy that into the mind the parameters are fast
but these properties have to go back to the the
the principal drawback a that they're before the algorithm converges and some quite a lot
of course trains need to be included and to include each of course strength that
is it should be the most violated constraint that they have to compute dynamic programming
and they have to be computed the by dynamic programming second drawback is the use
of slag by was to relax this problem in a real life problem we have
been asked part of what so we use another the main idea behind our approach
is to find a global objective function that anyone can that to in
so that we are able to warm satisfy must if not all the constraints is
beneficial like a number of constraints that what i said before and we think that
the with this approach naked that this approach is more not only adapted for non
separable cases and and our approach basically maximise the discord into the body if i
consider just one sequence a are in the training set that maximize score i have
the of the optimality is marked by the separated of the optimal alignment is maximally
separated for from the markov for correct alignment and in particular the distance between the
sculpted must go on the mean of the story
he is maximized in terms of the standard deviation
then discover it's quite interesting also because it is a measure of ranking so basically
maximizing the discourse we minimize the number of alignments that have score higher than the
given one
since in practical application and the inverse parametric sequence alignment problem we don't have just
one pair of sequence but we have an entire article in fact we should define
the scope of the training set and since
we discourage the linear function and also the sum of the score will be a
linear function also the mean this decide they all overall mean it will be a
linear function similar reasoning can be adopted for the variance if we think that the
contribution of each element in the training set is in that is independent from the
order so we simply compute the overall be vector and all that i see that
there are some you but they that each
each element of
teacher training points to
so the problem is that we are dealing with these maximise of the overall length
and this problem and mister three really can be trivially solved by a quadratic programming
and we see that they are for that we obtain a such that the master
of this potentially many linear constraints are already satisfied the if one wants to
in doing impose that each of them is satisfied one can also include in the
the musician
and again we have a convex optimisation problem and we can develop an iterative algorithms
eventually if we want we can relax constraints for nonseparable problem so basically we have
to approach or we decided to take the the the the and for that we
obtain just maximizing the or we can decide to the other day in the lot
of the constraints basically we see that
this approach has a lot of of ontologies and it works very well in most
of the applications
we need
there were twenty seven approach and we see that basically
and an iterative algorithm can be developed to solve approach and it is based on
four steps in the first step the moment are computed in the second but the
optimal vector five phi either an all day in some solving quadratic programming problem than
we if we want we can entering the main local and for each element in
the training set we can compute the demise violated constraint that is the feature vector
correspond to the optimal alignment for the coordinates of parameters and if the score of
society to read even bigger than the score of the optimal period then we can
impose score of document pages should be big and we can find it in a
new one for solving the quadratic programming problem subject to this constraint we continue with
these until today
effect of course trains does not change
i was so now some experimental results the first experiment i want to show that
with these approaches learning is effectively
she would consider artificial p of random sequences were aligned with random set of parameters
in particular with three parameters and two on the eleventh of this month and the
training set of varying sizes while the past that is fixed to one and the
sequence and we see that learning can converge to the the learning is achieved in
the second
experiments show that the number of constraints and is in the i show that considering
were just one training in the training set to reconstruct the optimise set of parameters
you must have the cases local strains are needed in another experiment i consider to
be discovered optimisation without any constraint e i considered the two hundred eleven parameter model
and compare the performance of the score with a generative model and we today and
substitution matrix are computed by plus and estimates and then i can see that in
the past that is saw with the performance of his car which are always better
than the performance of the generative model
you and he's an example of the
so whenever you see convex functions you should think of a few things you should
think about you get lower bounds from the tension approximation and you get upper bounds
from something like jensen's inequality
so we used the latter
it's member i was
somehow breaking the graph into combinations of trees this is what's going on here is
a special case
so you can imagine this original graph may be i'm trying to solve the quadratic
programme that has
let's make all the node weights zero to make it simple let's say i edge
weights two three four one minus two at a bunch
of of weights
right so those are the weights theta st that are specifying my optimisation problem most
came from your data
one one
yes so it state st for the function access times xt so
in general you can have a whole matrix
but but actually you can always specify with just one number if you do sort
of you discount the degrees of freedom you only need one number per node and
one number per edge this is this is what's called a minimal representation
OK so
those things are the weights on the edges that that's the problem that you're trying
to solve its maximisation problem with these weights
so what the method is doing is saying well i can solve that problem
but it's a future up some edges maybe drop the surgeon you drop this edge
you can put whatever weight you want on those edges i can solve that problem
for you because that's the treaty rights you could run max product on that and
solve it
and i could take some other tree and i could drop some other edges this
one and this one i could put some other weights on those edges i could
also solve that problem very quickly with max product
so that's the intuition you're breaking the problem into things that are easy
in this case we're using trees but you can see the idea is more generally
applicable you could have used other easy structures not just reason that that's indeed what
many people have done in more recent work
OK so how might using these weights what sort of the key property of these
i need to make a convex combination of trees so i'm just going to do
this simple thing i put weight half on each tree
so i need to choose whatever weights i put on the two trees it has
to be the case that one half times this number
when you don't have an edge it's zero by default so one half times this
number plus one half times this number should be that number
so you guys can check me but i think this is sort of valid splitting
of that of the problem into two trees
correct me if i'm wrong
yes it does matter
so his point was in edges where
you know this edges in both this tree industry right this search
i chose to minus six
times one half get minus two
but there many possible splittings i could have done i this is random i just
chose it we're going to see is that this algorithm is actually doing something quite
clever this algorithm for a fixed set of these weights is optimizing over all possible
splittings of trees and it's finding the best splitting
so it's answering your question it's sort of the optimal splitting that we could do
so we'll get to that you're sort of anticipating
which is good
OK so we have this convex combination so
about the label what's really interesting is the author assumes that the reader hasn't taken
309 1 and so the 1st 3 chapters take you through the history of chemistry
starting with the market
and take you through the aristotelian theory after you've had this these lectures will be
a joy to read OK so now let's go inside the let's go inside the
and try to understand what's going on and this is taken from your book Table
1 . 3 and so these are the subatomic particles that we have to
contend with with the electrons it so there's a negative charge in the value of
Y minus 1 . 6 times 10 to the minus 19 coulombs this is the
SI units the system International unit for electric charge that has a mass of 9
. 1 1 times 10 the minus 31 kg so that the charge compensation comes
out of the nucleus with the protons and it's a positive 1 . 6 times
and was lighting cool but its mass is 1800 times that of the electron the
electron just a little map in comparison to the proton and then there's this 3rd
species the neutron which has no charge roughly equal in mass
to that of the of the proton and so on
what we do in order to designate the identity of an atom is to to
the following let this be this is the atomic symbol atomic symbol which was given
by the Brazilian this is the latter wanted to letter character and we began with
the proton number the proton number is in the lower left corner is the proton
number number of protons in the nucleus which in the neutral atom as the number
of protons in the nucleus which in the neutral atom is equal to the number
of electrons
but thank you back
and get the number of neutrons what we do is we go up here the
upper left and this is called the atomic mass atomic mass and that's equal to
the sum of the number of protons across the number of neutrons so we get
the number of neutrons indirect because we know that proton number here this summer protons
and neutrons and we don't put that number of all the mass of the electrons
the so
a light in comparison so this will give us the uh of the sum we
need and at some level we we we really there some redundancy here so we
right sodium for example sodium 23 11 while 11 means of sodium if you've got
11 protons it must be sodium so we can get away with just 23 sodium
if you want to be really really smart you could write sodium like this
just a suggestion now Adams need not be neutral they need not be neutral they
can be show charge deficient or charge excessive and so Faraday Michael Faraday coined the
term iron coined the term iron atoms of net charge atoms and other species sharing
net charge so for example the positive ions positive ions dessert electron-deficient we can't do
anything about getting protons the bearing the nucleus but we can add or subtract electrons
the protein the positive ions are electron deficient and these are known as kappa on
their owners Catalans and you can use mnemonics to try to keep the straight ICT
as sort of like plus sign and you also know that decadic comes from the
fact that you know in electrochemical cell that of the cannons of those a reduced
so you know from catastrophe captors Greek for down catastrophe the downturn so that's a
cat that the negative alliances
the negative ions these are electron rich but they have an excess of electrons and
these are known as the and on the right idea that it's got that on
which which might conjure up negative or on an island and minus both have 5
letters you want to keep those straight away OK nominalism monarchs influence community right now
the last thing is that because the neutron has no net charge we can change
neutron number k neutron has moved charge so this means you can vary you can
vary the neutron number without
without changing the chemical identity because chemical identity is fixed by
the proton
this is you know the charge compensate we can add or subtract of neutrons at
liberty and so you can look for example at the periodic table and if you
look up the atomic mass of carbon you'll see that carbon comes at 12 .
4 0 1 1 4 carbon 12 . 0 1 1 isn't this against Dalton
this expose the whole number here if you look more carefully you'll find that this
is a blend of 3 different forms of carbon we have carbon 12 only believe
office 6 because we already know what's carbon has to have 6 protons so carbon
12 we know that it's got the proton number by definition is sex and the
neutron number of 6 from 12 6 so it's got 6 protons and neutrons and
is the dominant form of carbon so its abundance its abundance in nature is 98
. 8 9 2 % 98 . 9 2 per cent there is a carbon
13 however so it actually matically must be 6 protons and gets 7 neutrons and
this is found in the abundance about 1 . 1 over 80 per cent and
then there's the last 4 carbon 14 which is a radioactive form and we'll talk
about that later 309 1 using radiocarbon dating and carbon 14 6 again and it
has and it is found in the teaching of small amounts to minus 12 or
part per trillion
part per trillion so if you had all these up then you end up with
if i were to follow one
really really want
if you
all i will be
well known
before we have
and both of them
i i
now if you think b
the amount of
i mean
with three really there more
what were
the main
it will be
and then he really
and there are three
and on
well i don't think of
one here
he went
so what want
a u
there are a lot of each one
we were
three right for all three hundred and u
and and what you want
and the
well what
why not
they were
i revised we see her
one the
all my name e
what you want
now of course
o three one
so hold
three we only one
well i mean
one of the
well one of robot
because what the press and role models
o ninety nine million dollars in debt to
OK now what i'm doing my one now so what i want
what here
row three in the morning
in some way
so first of all i wanna acknowledge a student i'm going rising at university of
toronto addition to style it's mainly his work
in unfortunately you know up until last week he was practicing to give this talk
but last week he was selected for a random background checks so
he can get his visa so
in any case
so he's he's a real down here
so i'm gonna talk about multimodal in deep boltzmann machines end
you know data data now this is really coming from a collection of modalities right
we have images text audio
if you're looking at various
the data that's coming to us from social networking that approach product recommendation systems again
we see that is coming in multiple sources of modalities
right robotics applications it's might have multiple senses and by the way i should point
out this was the most exciting acts like in terms of visual presentation so
i hope you enjoy that
in terms of what we try to do to have a mental picture we have
what we call without a full representation so for example he will looking at images
so far
images and text and we wanna get is we're gonna get some notion of a
concept or with commonality free representation right
so how we gonna how gonna do that's well we can learn generative model
joint density model so we're gonna be one generative model of images and text
each here would represent the notion of latent
well hidden
and really we can think about this if used representation and we can use it
for classification or retrieval task you want to use support
now because it a generative model
we can do fun things like generated data from one modality condition about right so
for example for things like image annotation
condition on an image we can generate a distribution over possible
tags or we can go the other way around conditionally
text we can generate a possible distribution images and does things could be useful for
things like image annotation and image retrieval
right but there are several challenges
that we face when we started looking at this problem
the very first challenges that often
different data modalities have very different statistical properties right so be
have very different input representations so for example if you look at images
images are typically represented in terms of real valued ends
if the working attacks typically for using bag of words representation then
it's discrete spas so so you can see that these are very very different data
modalities and really it's very difficult to learn meaningful cross-model features from from these low
level representations
right so so how can we go but at
the second challenge is that
you know we dealing with the data that's often noisy
all missing
right so here's some examples from the flickr dataset you know we have images but
sometimes some of the text that we observe is not very meaningful and sometimes it's
not meaningful sometimes it's amazing sometimes if you look at this last figure here last
picture it's somewhat me meaningful right that tells tells us something that is
picture for nature but is what we actually do seeing the data
in terms of text generated by the model this is the kind of
text that our model can generate just a little bit of a little bit of
a preview so that's capture certain notion of of what you see in in those
right now before i get into specific details about the model in which the model
is let me just show you would demo
so here you can think of this model is a generative model conditionally image
we're going generate a distribution over possible worlds just let the model
decide what what distributions can generate right now what i'm doing here because the a
generative model and running what's called the markov chain monte carlo gibbs sampler here
here you just seeing what it doesn't after every every fifty gives up its
so notice that after about hundred steps it's already generating something meaningful right so you're looking at sea beach island
you know sometimes it generates canadian things cannot be see lake
it only water boat and such so it doesn't go through these
different modes and that's generate
reasonable things right now is how fast it it sort of converges to
what i would
i think it converges right generating meaningful things
now let me
get the specific
definition of what the model is so that i described what that is
the very first building block of our model is is a specific document called restricted boltzmann machines
i mean if you know about this is both which is just a just a
formalise things it's a markov random field you've stochastic binary visible units of stochastic binary
hidden units and you have bipartite connections
i u can
write the joint probability distribution this way and it's a very standard way of of
defining undirected graphical models have pairwise potentials you have
unit potentials
the most important thing here is that you can think of as stochastic hidden variables
is detecting certain patterns that you see in the data
and the conditional distribution here it is again taking a very simple form the product of conditionals which conditional picks
a logistic function
now when dealing with real valued data like
we can
make slight modification to the model and and work with a model called gas in burnley markov random field
right again the structure of the model remains pretty much the same
you have pairwise potentials potentials
and the conditional distributions of the observed data is given by the product of conditionals
wage conditional takes a gas distribution
and these kinds of models have been used fore
modeling images image patches and such
now at the final stage one a model discrete sparse data count data
like in the bag-of-words representation we again make a slight modification to the model and
this is what's called replicated softmax model it's an undirected topic model again
it has the similar structure
the most important thing is that the conditional distribution is given by the softmax distribution so if you think of
the bag of words representation you have a vocabulary of size kate and you have dy
then we can use the model
again the point i was make is is that we have this building block and we can use it
four modeling different kinds of
now one useful thing about this is that most machines is that it's very easy
to infer the states of the latent variables the states of the hidden variables
right and takes a closed form has a closed form solution so it's very important
for things like information retrieval classification wear perception is easy conditionally input i can instantly
tell u
what latent presentations are
and if you look at all of these different models
this essentially all have binary hidden variables and using them to model
different kinds of data
now you can think of a simple model
simple multimodal
model where you just using a joint binary hidden layer
now there are several problems with at a particular model in particular as i mentioned
before inputs have very different statistical properties and it's very difficult to learn meaningful model
i have this five by kind of twenty six or a mysterious past only has
like five five ones
that encodes
my wife
the other part need is now encodings are actually pairs of consecutive pairs
we're going to go with this i'm going to write down the objective function
instead of just in terms of why i'm going to read the terms of disease
because you know we're doing argmax over y
we do now argmaxa risi so one express the objective in terms of disease
so this helps me codes
why in this way
next step is going to care in this
sequence model of pairwise terms
so what i'm going code is well you know this this and this and one
matrix so sold
the pair is a whole baby
right so
there's going to be one position on this matter
so this is this
you can think of it as an indicator variable that says first position is a
in second position is b
and there's you know twenty six about twenty six and so there no
for this
and these four there's only
four wants to know
the discrete y
this is how the maps into this kind of these are one variables e
now we are ready to write down the words in terms of c
so what we do is basically take whatever it was was
whatever objective was hanging on particular
y j
we right now in terms of the j
because it is easier said is the position j
has label and
and so we take the score in
part of the potential that the
talks about and we that's the coefficient
max vision was used so these are when maximizing this is the constant
from me
same thing with the edge variables right so i visited variables atomic
and then these and this is the constant
with this when and they the
OK so now my objective this objective is the same as the objective with the
discrete y
but now
you don't need to actually give the meaning right otherwise this maximization is completely arbitrary
so what i want i mean this is have to be really zero one
if i if i remember zero one as an integer programme
which is you know
now what i want i want something
continuous so it turns out it's not the following it's enough to say the positive
to say that each one sums to one meaning that
you only one position are only one position is set in each
consecutive slots
so that we basically
yeah work including this thing and then we need to ensure that a
z jason case are consistent with each other rights that they they encode the same
right because there's cause decays into scorns sieges and those need to be coordinated
you know otherwise you can just you
maximize the it score separately from the notes core and then you don't have to
consistent while you're talking about
so in order to synchronize with e g t decays thinking was just think
it's enough to do the following terms is basically enforce agreement meaning so
i'm looking in particular jk
and there's some over one side
should get some here
this can marginalized one way
and this on the other way
i should also get the
if you think of this
kind of us in all pairwise presentation that barroso presentation has to agree with the
una representation
so the linear constraints and uneasy
this is sort of linear inequalities right so
we haven't said
we have made disease
the discrete we just mean that still continues
well it turns out that you can you can
that if original network is the chain or tree
the answer yet is always going to be integral
right so so
going from
the picture this is something like this if you have
in fact the learner knows that it can take advantage of it and just learn
one to transition probabilities that can be applied in both of these states and the
state and this state right to states have the same pattern of walls
at two broad hypothesis class would be one that says we don't pay attention to
learn about them separately to know what might be one this is yet the wall
learn from that there were great in this great but you can be there that's
not true and it falls apart
so rule what about a bayesian perspective what about instead of saying there's what's possible
and everything else is impossible what if we say there's likely
and other things might be less likely to things might be very unlikely and that
i think might be impossible OK now you can imagine learning algorithm will put energy
into learning the more likely cases but if they start to break down it's willing
to consider other possibilities as it goes not to mention the probability of the crossword
puzzles stuff but i did and that was really important thing in our past puzzle
work is not to say this would fit in the slot where doesn't but to
say this word is in good faith but not perfect one this one is less
good this was less good and have all the possibilities lying around so the solver
could put them together in other ways
but it's more likely to use the really good answers
so the bayes perspective would give us that kind of
that kind of you we start some kind of prior over the space transition probability
matrices and as we're learning as the ages learning environment it's maintaining a posterior well
here's what i originally thought this was likely but then i saw a bunch of
this data now i think this other thing is likely to
then we optimize
decision making for the probable instead of just possible so we don't have to all
the agent does not take this worst-case view of the rule
something really great under the stage but probably not so
why waste my time
all right
so in this particular case you could say similar states have similar dynamics probably
right the learner should be able to use that
and are faster than if it was using that information so this this kind of
bayesian view can actually drive exploration and result in much faster learning
so what's nice is there's a whole
field of
bayesian reinforcement learning see is very text was one way to get here with a
bayesian representation of models we can plan in the space of posteriors also
i don't want to get into this in detail but the most most of the
way that bayesian
modeling has been used in reinforcement learning is to say you know what this is
really cool if we think about instead of model there's there's you know there's the
one truth and here's what we know about so far but if instead we have
a probability distribution over models we can say
well if i take this step but this time my my distribution of models tells
me what might happen and also what i would learn from that and so i
can in my head start learning about start reasoning about what things i should do
in the world to learn the model and optimize the model the the same time
what's cool about that is races this this possibly artificial distinction between exploring and exploiting
or learning and acting it's just one big planning problem planned to get my information
state to be one where i can get higher reward
this really beautifully elegant from a mathematical standpoint and really hideously intractable in computational view
there are some cases that they can be solved if if there's no states just
there's one stay in actions don't change the state they give you reward or if
the horizon length is actually relatively short then you can actually reason about all possible
reachable belief states
states knowledge and and
optimized for that but in the general case this is actually pretty pretty horrible so
i'm not going to go through this concrete example but it just the idea here
is to showing that when you have a distribution over what the possible models are
sometimes it gets you to take actions that would actually cause it because you learn
like specifically the optimal thing to do here is to learn because that's going to
allow me to get higher reward in the future
so it's very pretty if you really doing this in in the full MDP etc
etc you probability distributions over probability distributions so all the various things that people have
been doing lately in
especially the NIPS community in terms of
displays and nonparametric bayes all fits very nicely into this kind of you
in fact people have made various kinds of approximations to get bayes optimal plans so
the idea of the bayes optimal plan is given you're given the agents uncertainty about
the model space what actions should take to maximize its expected reward expected reward is
over not just uncertain transitions in the probability sorry in the trajectory but also
uncertainty about what the true model is
that the whole expectation and getting high reward maximizing reward with respect to that sort
like search shows research bottom-up learning and so forth
so that's the learning
let me briefly mention the software in which all of this is available
it's called alchemy
it's open source
it allows you to write a new knowledge or captured from somewhere in the form
of a first order formulas
and then all the other things that i just described for learning and inference are
in in addition you have programming language features like you know file inclusion typing
syntactic sugar for the things that are most often is the ability to link in
external functions and predicates and so forth
the URL i'll put up again at the end
it's interesting to compare alchemy with the kinds of things that were available before
on both the logical side and statistical site so comparing alchemy prolog
in prolog the representation has horn clauses
and alchemy it's arbitrary first of the four most welcome is more flexible in that
respect in prolog inference is done by theorem proving which you know back in the
seventies was the fastest for different available
but you know these days you know the fastest inferences by model checking by satisfiability
that's what we do
but of course most importantly in alchemy you've learning and handling of uncertainty right out
of the box and prolog you don't
now comparing alchemy with sort like that
so after that exists out there for doing things like statistical inference in machine learning
is of course many different packages
no single one that's for everything but probably the most popular one by a good
margin is something called bugs
meaning you know the bayesian inference using gibbs sampling
so but these days and that the representation of the muses markov nets involves influences
them by gibbs sampling which we already saw can get very very slow if you
have strong dependencies in community have given sampling in a number of other things including
SAT which is most much faster
in but you can only the parameters in alchemy can also in structure but of
course the most important difference is that alchemy is relational in but there is no
simple general way to handle non IID data in alchemy is just saw this is
very easy
so i can be even looking only as logical erroneous probability is already in many
ways in advance over the state of the art but the nice thing of course
is that it seamlessly combines these two things
you have a problem that has both structured and unstructured aspects you don't have to
put together pieces you don't have to start with a prologue and try to make
a probabilistic or start with bugs and try to handle relational information it's all done
very uniformly smoothly in the language markov logic
so last part of the talk
let me mention some examples of what you can do with markov logic and in
some sense this is the payoff right so far been investing in understanding this representation
in developing the arguments for so what is it that you can do with this
is an awful lot it turns out
so here's here's the sample
some of the things that markov logic and alchemy in some cases other implementations of
markov logic that people have developed things that have been done
information extraction is one it's actually example that i'm going to go over here in
some detail to illustrate things is of course a very important problem
there was a system by reasonable enquiry that actually won the the triple l two
thousand five
information extraction competition using markov logic this was the goal of this was to extract
interactions from from medline abstracts
in two resolution another very important problem link prediction
collective classification things like classifying web pages using the links as well as the content
various kinds of web mining and natural language processing i just came from EMNLP where
we have the paper applying markov logic to natural language processing ontology refinement
another very important problem as i mentioned the best paper award can last year was
a paper by free will and weld
they use markov logic to learn and refine ontologies from from wikipedia and then other
things like on by of social network analysis
and so forth is a couple of examples i think worth mentioning site
which is some of you know is the world's largest knowledge base right but inexact
succeed because of the problems in first order logic the folks it's i caught him
began to transform psyche into into an MLN
by adding weight so therefore it was right to the very straightforward thing to do
and another one is
OK well the largest project in derby history which is trying to build this automated
personal assistant coach manages email and new meetings for you automatically fast things and folders
and what not the main inference engine that killer uses is is based on on
markov logic gates and there's more of these things which hopefully and again you can
go to the alchemy website and there's you know a bunch of pointers to papers
and applications and melons and databases and what not there but you know hopefully this
will precisely that this really is something that you can do state-of-the-art solutions for many
important problems in information and knowledge management today so for concreteness let me as the
last thing in this talk
before conclude just show you
how we can do something like information extraction in markov logic and i think this
is a nice illustration because information extraction is used with essential bridge between the structure
and the instructions right you start out with unstructured it's just text and you populate
database and i can do database inference and logical inference of
i'm going to use as an example the problem of extracting a database of citations
from the reference lists and papers right this is the problem that citeseer and google
scholar have to solve
very problem very popular problem among researchers today
so here's a very small example
and now
you need to do to make things information extraction the first one is what's called
i need to run over the text string and figure out which
fields of my database are
OK so for example proxy england competed ming authors
triple six is very new and so forth
so this is the first part started segmentation
the other part
is into resolution
i need to figure out there
tripoli IL six and the proceedings of the twenty first national conference on artificial intelligence
of the same things
and then i also to figure out that these two papers are the same thing
in this two papers the same and these are the results
otherwise likely my database i'm going to get duplicate results right which should probably seen
happen when you know the we could john mailings to you with different misspellings of
the name and so forth and if i try to do mining on top of
this and that is not properly resolved the results will be garbage so we need
to be able to do these two things
and the state of the art
prior diag
why is that then we could figure out what entry
it's a transpose
now if you remember this is
let's see what it looks like
suppose that was the identity for the moment
and the errors were white noise
you see that a transpose they will be blocked with the block diagonal
let's see what's going to be the shape of a transpose a what's the shape
of this matrix
blocks a three by three right
this is this is five by this is five five three block
five five five
block diagonal
three by five o'clock what counts as
OK so the result is a three by three block matrix
some three by three block matrix
and you know what we can figure out what it what it is but what
i want this block tried glaspie is crucial part is the
is the fact that zero there
why is that while those zero
you see that this role
this column
is perpendicular to the skull
right there is
that that's the point
we were built in total
that that each column has some overlap with the next one
so there's is
there's one diagonal away from the main died but then when we take the
when we take that as the role
into this is the columns
to get
this guy it's zero
so the this structure
of connecting each one the only the only its neighbour
is automatically it's are it's are
the appearing framework that produces try diagonal makers
here blocked right go because each of these is system OK
now then the point is that
blocked right diagonal matrices
as we again what we learn that very first lecture was doing elimination of the
things that the it's
it's a manageable process right i just i just have one step to do i
multiply that role by something to kill this
and then this rose ready to go
and i'm by the the new role by something to kill this
this is the natural recursion
and then what about back substitution
back substitution
remember uses the upper triangular form
to go back
the upper triangular form how many diagonals and the of the when i factor this
in two one l new
what's what's with and this is the l so it's certainly zero there
i don't need to do an elimination here it's zero here
so it's something
something something something something
and the u is the same in the opposite direction
just got
got zero there
because because the zero there never leaves
and it
upper triangular so there is the element there's the block and u
so the forward elimination is just one multiplier and every and every stage the back
substitution is just one substitution every state
and we can create formulas
so this is what the kalman filter has them out
the kalman filter has to amount to inform the formulas
for the
is for these steps forward this is forward this prediction using l
ali and this is important
when i better say what are the outputs one of the inputs and one of
the output
per step
first step OK
OK one of the input
there's a new a
a k
there's a new path
after k
well let me put the first because it kind of comes with the a
so there's the A's and the bees at the new steps
and then
and that's the measurements step but then there's also very
prediction step
is a we've got two kinds of things here
we've got the measurement equations
status quite change of state equations the prediction equation
so we could
and one of the output
i think the best way to do the right thing to do is to break
each step in the into the two pieces
the two pieces
so maybe maybe when i go to the new step
really the f comes before
the a and b the new step so i'm i'm better off if i write
systematically think of the after coming first
as as giving
prediction of the new state
based on the old one
the all
the old our oldest
and then we make some measurements at the new time
and that
this gives us an improved version
so like
then A's and B's
at the new time OK
my that be
i will go here
and my talk a
i will go above it
yeah that's
one unit
and i have a right angle so i can use the pythagorean feeling
to find that
the length a square of equal length
well at least
we are reduced to finding the length of the length of the we can again
find using the ethical and feeling in the x y plane because here
we have a right angle
we have three units and here we have two units
OK so if you do the calculations you will see
well length of b is square root of three square miles to square the thirty
square of thirty
and the length of
is about
length the squared plus one
square you want
it's going to be square root of thirty first one is twelve fourteen
and so on and to which
almost all of you gave
OK so the original formula
you know if you follow it with it in general
if we have
with components a one a two
a a
then the line
a is the square root of a one square loss it was squared
classification with
any questions about that
yes so in general we indeed can consider vectors in abstract spaces that have any
number of coordinates
and then you have more components
in this class will mostly see vectors
with two of three components only because easier to the whole and because a lot
of the method we'll see what exactly the same way with you have three variables
of million volumes
if we had
vector with smart components then we would have a lot of trouble following it
but we could still define its length in the same way
by summing the squares of the components
i'm sorry to say that here
you know
multivariable mostly women mostly to offer
be assured that it was just the same way you have ten thousand i
just calculations some longer
more questions
what else can we do with vector as well i think that i'm sure you
know how to do with vectors
is to add them
to scale
vector addition
so if you have two vectors
a and b
you can from the some some a
how do we do that well first
i tell you that does not have this double life there at the same time
geometric objects that we can like this some pictures
fair also computational objects but we can present by number
so every question about vectors will have two instance one geometric and one numerical
so let's start with the geometry
so let's say that they have two vectors
a and b given to me
let's say that i thought of going the same place to start
well to take this same what they should do is actually move b
so that it starts at the end of it
the head of
OK so this is again the
so so this forms no part of it
so this site is again picked
and now
if we take the diagonal of that dialogue
this is what we call
OK so the idea being that
to move along a plus b it's the same as to move first along a
and then along
but on b then along a plus b equals because
OK now if we do it
new nightly
all you do is you just add the first component of a with the first
component of the
the second with second and the third with the
say that a
it was
in two three
he was one
then you just add this week
so it's pretty straightforward
so for example
you know i say that neither of its components of three two one
so we talked about fitting a line to given a bunch of points
when you're doing that line fitting
you're actually assuming that the number of call it's you have the those excess let's say you have
you know features you are dealing with it
and the number of samples to have in the training set
which is the actual data points ten dimensions
so so u assume that the number of samples you have is larger than the dimensionality of the data
so so you've maybe a hundred samples in ten dimensions
diabetes dataset in see i probably the most widely used has a hundred and fifty
data points each in four dimensions
in those cases
the standard theory that we talked about walks
many of us are getting into problems when the number of samples
it is not only smaller but we're always smaller than the dimensions
so i have a hundred thousand
and i only have a few thousand data points
so climate data is an example i am may be maintaining measuring you know precipitation are cambridgeshire
in the month of june over the last hundred years from inception reanalysis or something
like that so i have a hundred observations over the last hundred years one for
each year
look at the number of features i have this this can easily go into tens of thousands
if you're trying to fit
if you're trying to do ordinary least squares using your favourite tool it break down
if it actually gives you an answer it is line
it has to involve rank-deficient matrix
which cannot be done so ordinary least squares doesn't work in this and
in fact many models don't work in this scenario
i will give you the sort of the keynote example which is in this story
scenario i give you one data point and ask you to draw line
that's what we're talking about
right is complete insanity
if i give you one data point to be
you cannot line when you can fit in finance many lights writes about this you
know you're talking about so so when we talk about the small and heipi regime
this is what are talking about
and i can actually over the next five
maybe ten years
we will hear a lot about this this
class of problems
because in many domains this is showing up we are working on climate data forest
ecology and other places this is the scenario so many of the standard tools have
to be thrown out the window
there is some hope
and i'm going to sort of show you one class of methods and one specific problem
that's you know this is i'm using this as a case study but there's quite
a bit of very interesting what's going on on this
and i think on friday a couple of thoughts which sort of using this flavor
aaron angrily text analysis one is network construction and so on using using sparsity
what we're trying to do
and in this is an illustrative example to make the point
is that we are trying to study the land variable interaction based on climate data
maybe in separate analysis it or something like that
we are using the monthly means and this is available for download anybody can go
on download it you know if you have really seven or eight
and we are looking at responses temperature and precipitation and i locations
i'm gonna show you the pictures so you know
so i'm going to look at implicit in brazil
monthly means
over the last sixty years
and i'm going to try to fix that's why this form that's my wife
and everything everywhere in the ocean
is x
right so
so so
the number of features i'm going to uses going to run into tens of thousands
the number of data points i have samples i have sixty because i'm just looking
at sort of past sixty years of data
and for each such location i'm going to do
i'm going to focus on temperature and i'm going to focus on precipitation precipitation is
always the more difficult ones far on learning in these days
temperature is much more stable
um but can also be case study
and as i said about
this high dimensional regression with a twist
that's we have locations on the oceans
at each location i have hidden variables these variables the sea level pressure precipitation sea
surface temperature relative humidity on the ocean right so
so not i have locations and a bunch of variables at each location
but the total number of sort of dimensionality is is a way higher with higher
then the number of samples i have
i'm not a climate scientist i'm not going to claim anything
about bad but there are considerations that we were asked to sort of put into our model is
not all locations are going to be relevant greenland probably doesn't affect brazil directly
and even if a location is relevant
not all variables in that location is going to be relevant so so maybe
but cambridgeshire land britain maybe sea surface temperature
and maybe you know some wind speeds are important but not pressure maybe something else
right so we don't know but we don't expect all of them to be relevant
at all locations
so what we did
is that we look at ordinary least squares
and we look at that you realize it's not going to work
so this is the location one i mean variables location whatever it was this location
airline babies are ocean locations this is my responsibility
now i i in principle know how to do this optimisation if i actually did
do it in no matter are what they are
are they in principle should complain
these guys are very smart so they'll give you the pseudoinverse and everything will look nice and rosy
i don't believe that answer
right so because in principle the series of audience squares entirely breakdown in this scenario
so what we did we
we basically
border cousin of last so this this past thing
where we want to keep the ordinary least square loss function but we had some regularizers
and there are types some regularizers we added
one his
the group sparsity
what that simply means is back
we know that there is a natural grouping among the variables everything
because latitude longitude i have eight variables
and that's a natural group right this is the sea surface temperature here's he's similar
pressure and so on and so forth so location automatically groups those variables
and this is simply saying
that's why some of those locations are important
this is how you can put in your domain knowledge to the regularizer
so this is what they wanted to regularize are and what they're doing it will make
groups of variables zeal
and the second one is that it usually lasts only the arise are and what
it does is to make some of the features zeal
so together they are this is going to select some locations
and then this is going to select some variables from those locations
and in principle
the schematic if you
one that gets selected audience where will put a non-zero weight it doesn't do feature
those counts
and for this little example that match would have actually given us three point five
so we in general in practice what we find empirically is that these guys will
be quite close
to this we've done a series of experiments where we take these sets of varying
sizes and compute the optimal partial matching between them and are matching score
so you're looking at for each of these points corresponds to
the output of matching like this
the point set sizes varying here from five to one hundred points and these events
sort each of these are sorted according to the optimal measure which is shown in
red and blue is the pyramid match
this is for dimensions ranging from ten to ninety that the dimension of the feature
so it's nicely approximating this measure
we may use of this kernel and a few different scenarios
the pyramid match doesn't actually farmers kernel and we used it with support vector classification
and regression for recognition tasks and pose estimation which i'm going to talk about today
and more recently we've been looking at using this to do some clustering using a
partial match over features to the unsupervised learning of categories from images
but first i would like to this
cover these results today
so for the object recognition tasks we take images and represent them by a set
of features formed using a particular detector that find salient points basically based on corner
texture features within an image
and then we use the descriptor based on
and image gradients and this gives invariance to rotation scale translation
and so the ETH eighty database which contains a different classes
we find that the match will get
competitive performance eighty four percent two
these two existing state-of-the-art set kernels but at a much lower computational cost
we also considered somewhat more challenging database that contains one hundred one categories
and there's a great deal of intra class appearance variation here to deal with
and also the large number of categories is challenging
and you're using a couple of different types of features we get forty three and
fifty two percent performance average over all the test images in this dataset contains about
nine thousand total images we change with about thirty thirty examples per class
so the numbers if you're not familiar with the database might seem
well there are low because of the charge and it in fact are in line
with the state of the art performance here
in fact the measure based on
the exact partial matching using the earthmover distance has reported performance about fifty three percent
so when i with this but much much more efficient takes about twelve seconds to
do a single matching here on average and this is where the feature set sizes
they have about six hundred features and can be as large as two thousand features
and that seconds actually twenty times faster than just the quadratic
suboptimal matching measure
and considering regression an important problem in vision is pose estimation rate estimate articulated pose
of the human and so
we would like to directly when the relationship between the shape of the person in
the image and the underlying posts so here we are taking so let's
and we want to estimate directly through the joint positions
to do this we use support vector regression
and we trained with synthetic dataset used we generated this with a computer graphics package
so we get using now you lots of data quite easily and we can get
precise always the person and very precise right positions as well
and you're constructing this two walking poses only so only walking motion
and the representational use is the shape context histograms
which i mentioned earlier and so this is the descriptor that locally describing the shape
and each of these points
and to test this what we've learned we will use a synthetic tests generated again
with that computer graphics package
to add some difficulty we can insert quarter or simulate clearly these blogs in the
segmentation mask that are going to be very common in practice as you can see
in these real images they get caused by
difficulties in doing this for an extraction and changes in the background and things like
also valid with some real images here we can only eyeball the results into qualitative
so with a separate test set of about three hundred images
here we were training with three thousand of these synthetic examples so now with the
synthetic tests with clean so it's meaning perfect segmentations we look at the performance comparing
our method the pyramid match with a method based on this representation that's been converted
vector by a
counting the number of occurrences of a set of prototype features so if had a
tiny vocabulary of features that are going to occur and then you map your input
features to the prototypes you can count them in the end up with the vector
so here we combine that with gaston RBF kernel
and so basically says that there is
some increase in performance with the pyramid match and was statistically significant using a paired
difference details but
what's really interesting is that when we add some clarity these images like this on
the previous findings these bodies problems in the segmentation pyramid match is better able to
handle that because we are explicitly account for the fact that we
don't need every feature to match some of the feature in the second image
and then we have also had enough application using documents with define task of taking
a research paper in turn ask me what year it was published
so here we are using a bag of words representation
and we're trying to do this with thirteen volumes of newspapers
the word from features
when using latent semantic analysis two
extract semantic space over the words were
with the idea that similar words should have similar vector representations which you find out
by looking at the co occurrence statistics over some corpus of data about which words
occur together
in different documents
so we call is the word meaning features
so now we have a set of these word meaning vectors
we did regression here we're using
testing with about four hundred images in training with about