bad reasons because there are so that other the pieces up again assisted the pieces
that would be the right here you would be
backed to bit OK
so i'm going to my contributors has taken this island is that reason that you
the the because i got to be done here
we get we get them i can also hear about
so we get just point oh that's fine that's fine just just speaking to us
i was going
the like this because we would like to to do a sweep agency
it was saying
you say it compresses the rate at which does compress the range i mean i
mean if you chose
your swing from a to b minor something from the data from the past to
there's some i can arrange is but it's it's it's these these and other reasons
for choosing
the game blue in
it's just that the whole like this point
is that we can be more cohesive power together but it's not
the prime minister
that are
many private so that we can work together to give you
and what
so try to give you a different reason why he's saying he's saying that maybe
maybe some of you in the room might actually care about each other's right i
mean you all know each other and class you will go to the same college
for example if we if we play this game
up and up in the business school and the same is true to say that
i want to write will with a given the business school
i think it's quite likely to get a lot of alpha chosen right but if
we play this game up let's say the divinity school
i'm guessing that i'm guessing that traverses answers reflecting what you guys are going play
in the school you might think that people in the school might care about other
people's rights right there might be ethical reasons perfectly good sensible ethical reasons for choosing
peter in this game might be other reasons well but this fact the the reason
to focus on and perhaps the the lesson learned from this is that right now
this is not the game right now
we have actions that able to take and we know what outcomes are
but we're missing something that will make this again we missing
missing objected missing pales this what people care about
right so
because we start rising again until we know what people care about and we know
the payoffs
and this is the same thing how it operates against other members any other moment
of the cluster today it's relevant
game theory
professors at yale cannot tell you what you'll payoffs should be
you should not have the we can't i can't tell you in useful way
what is that used in your goals in life should be whatever
that's all game was about
however once we know what your payoffs what we know what your goals are
perhaps we can game theory can help you get
so we had two different kind of payoff mentioned here
we had the kind of payoff where
we care about our own great
and travis is mentioned kind of help we might care about other people's grades and
want to do today is how is this game on the both those possible payoffs
the start of
let's put up some possible payoffs of the game
i promise we'll come back and look at some other payoff later we will revisit
the divinity school later
so he once again is also a famous matrix with me and my parents
choosing actions alpha and beta
but this time i'm going to put numbers in here
and some of you
recognise these numbers but that's not
really relevant now
right so what's the idea of the first idea is that these numbers represent
you tiles utilities
that they represent what this what these people trying to maximize the trying to achieve
their goals
the idea is to be
compare this to the outcome matrix
the person is medium
yields the payoff
so if is this box to see you the payoff of three
yields a payoff
of zero and so
towards the interpretation
the first interpretation of the nats interpolation along you jumped straight away
these are people people with these payoffs of people who only care about their own
grades they prefer a to be plastic people have to be minus and the review
minus two c
i all the the great or otherwise run like virginia
these people only care about their rights
really care
from the centre
and i want to know what is here this is little or
so let's first though
the potential
at point p
is an in the world
going from r to infinity if i take the
electric force
divided by
my test charge q
but they are
but this
is the electric field it this
force times distance his work one of his work unit
chart so i take my test charts out
and so this is the integral
in are infinity
you don't feel
we are sorry
and that's very easy grow
because we know what he is
electric field we have done several times
it follows immediately from growers law
so when you
calculate this integral
you get q
divided by
four by
absolutely zero are
it is no surprise because we already had that for a point charge
so this is the situation you are
there are is larger
then capital are
precisely what we had before
we can put in some numbers
if you put in are
he calls are
which is o point three metres
you put in here the ten micro cool and here the
thirty centimetres
you find three hundred thousand volts
you get three
i'm going to the difficult
if you take are equal sixty centimeters doublet
double the distance
potential goes down by a factor of two is one of or
there will be a hundred and fifty kilowatt
and if you go to three leaders
and it is ten times more
then in thirty can afford
so if you go to infinity
which for all practical purposes would be lobby seven
if you go to the lobby seven
then the potential
for all practical purposes
is about zero
because are so large
there's is no potential left
so if i
if i will tell you in march from infinity
to this
the surface of the then graph
and i put a charge q in my pocket
and i marched to defend the graph
by the time i reached that point
i have done work
i multiplied the charge now back to the potential that gives it work again because
potentials work unit charge
and so the work i have done
charted i have in my pocket
find the potential in this case the potential
of the then the graph
i all all the way to the surface which is three hundred thousand volts
if i were strongman output one cornwall in my pocket
that's a lot of charge
then i would have done three hundred thousand rules of work
i just carrying the one school or from lobby seven to defend the graph that's
about the same work i have to do to climb up the empire
state building
famous MGH my mass
times g times
the height have to climb
i know
how the
electric potential
goes was distances one of our relationship now i have arrived at the
then the graph i the surface with my test charge
and now i go inside
and irish slosh around inside i feel no force any more
there's no electric field inside
then this is a nice example of how detailed this vocabulary in psyches is
hall the relationship in
that something is inside something as hollow o
o instruction within the cyc
well this red objects is big and say well that's in the whole of this
is certainly one one possible understanding of the in this this is more than with
this so-called in a monk relationship
then they have different types of
that's a
this type of
inclusion would be een contained completely because the red object is
could contained completely in this
box are in contain partially in contain closed because
the object is closed or in contained opened because it can fall out of
then connectedtoinside sticksinto or screen screwedin and so these are all
this is basically the language hard to describe something his inside some some some something
something else
and business ontologies
our knowledge engineers from cycle using this language to describe
particular situation in the nature so for this one small as they are able to
describe mechanical device
he also with this kind of language but it can be used for anything else
here i just wanted to show the richness of this language an example of this
relationship in
and here is a character slides of one
more which i cannot show life
from site so
psychosis is one of the project one of the project in cyc is also taking
care or more than this
database of terrorism and other stuff
and what
what is
here is a front-end on the top of the site which is called
cyc analytic environment
there are basically we are able to to put
query the natural language
and ask cyc whether the claim is true or not or if whatever we are
interested in now
here's an example of very
and you can read this so the question is the following
who who has a motive for dissemination of what i could cutting
i think that it was labour prime minister visual skills i think two years ago
and it was not clear who killed
but there were
one of the assumptions that
some countries or organisations kind of sust and based on the knowledge which cycads insights
encoded from the public sources
the idea of these demos to show that i can
also come in
provide some answers and explain them is based on the open open information so basically
what we do here is
you type in
in the natural language so who had the motive force this notion of included and
question gets translated in the
first order
the query language is this is just
nicer form of this first order logic query nothing goes and you say OK
and then after a few seconds we get a list of questions list of answers
like this our science you k the united states are these are
possible suspects
if I say anything is rubbish plea please please interupt yeah I mean bayesians don't invent
methods bayesian bayesians build models the models toll
tell us what the method should be whereas frequentist
are happy to consider methods they dream of from anywhere
bayesian's inference is a place always conditional on the method we've got
it doesn't try anything about anything whereas in in frequentist frequentist world the cup
the emphasis is is on giving good answers in repeated use and so on and so on there's are some important
distinctions here and the two can be looked at in parallel
but you know there's not as if there's a competition between the two in which
one clearly wins
except perhaps as we come into the sort of the present day
it's just a few other issues are want to to emphasize
there was a time when I think it was difficult to be bayesian
if you had
clients so you know if you had
end users because there's a lot of needing to defend what you've done I think those days
are rather gone but
perhaps not completely one of the strenghts of bayesian inference is that we can go
directly and report the inferences we want we don't have to twist ourselves into logical
knots thinking about noel hypotheses and you know trying to express everything what's in
in what's often at least for the beginning students are very
counterintuitive way
a very key idea in bayesian inference is borrowing strength this idea that one
thing is always informative about another
you know everything connects if you measure something you'll you're learning not only about the
things that directly influence here but many other things as well and we'll will see that we'll
see that thing we will see that coming up in some of the examples
I think bayesian inference really pays off in complex and high-dimensional problems in in in
small-scale low dimensional problems to be honest we can have different philosophies about how we're gonna do it
but we end up with pretty much the same answers but as
problems get bigger and more complex than there are clear differences and bayesians I put it
to do more
but this one bit even even a committed bayesian will always defend
one aspect of the frequentist idea and that is that we happy typically fall to
use frequentist methods to evaluate performance
so the sort of frequentist consistency or frequentist performance of statistical of bayesian
statistical processes is a perfectly legitimate thing to think about
OK well that's the end of mine sort of opening a motivation trying to go over some of the
key ideas and this is the contents lists for the remainder of this of this
I've only arrived last night I never had a chance to meet any of you yet I
thr first thing I asked when I got to the bar was
you know what are the students like so I don't know anything about you individually but I know a
few things about you in general I know you're very bright I know that
you were very selected to get here
you beat the competition so congratulations but I also know you're pretty diverse in terms of where
you've come from and what you've done before so
that I say that by way of explaining that some of the things I'm gonna
talk about particularly today
will seem really really basic for some of you
but trust me I think it's I think they're worth doing and I suspect that some
of you
here who will appreciate
even the
the elementary things I talk about
let's talk a little about probability I'm not gonna say more about probability in this one
slide so if you don't know about probability you really are going to have
to go and look it up somewhere else
so probabilty is nothing but common sense reduced to calculus somebody said
I think just to recap it measures uncertainty on a zero one scale
zero and one mean what you think they mean
and there's really one property the probability has
and that is if you look at two events and if they can't both happen than the probability
of one or the other is the sum of the two probablities
this extraordinary but that's all you need pretty much that and the same thing generalized to accountable
collection of events
pretty much generates the whole theory of probability so this is remarkably light in terms
of axioms
and of course when we're dealing with data typically the we focus probability not on the general
theory of events but we talk particularly about random variables so almost all of the probabilty
we use will be talking up distributions of random variables discrete or continuous
scalar or vector or linear or all sorts of different bases
rendom variables and their their distributions
and there's only one thing we particularly need from probability theory and that of course
is Bayes theorem
you may
think that maybe that's where the word the name bayesian analysis comes from so here's
a really
small little problem I like puzzles and this this is a version of a puzzle
that appeared in a in a guardian newspaper recently
so these are little little games set in set in a sort of
fictitious context so you really you're now to draw two balls
you can't can't see inside the urns you you know the constitutions of the two but you don't know
which urn is which
and you really need a Red ball
OK and you you choose an urn at random and you pick out a ball and it's blue
OK and you only got one chance left
so the question we're we're asking is
so today we're going to spend a little bit of time on some elementary chemistry
just to develop our language that we use with one another and so when i
say hydrogen bond you don't stare blankly at me and structure heads
many of you have had this already for many of you this is a review
but it's a useful review we believe here at MIT of teaching things
two or three times often the same subject matter but increasing levels of sophistication so
i do this without a very metropolitan
our first issue here is how are atoms and molecules held together
and we are the most familiar way by which atoms and molecules are held together
is of course the covalent bonds
covalent bonds
a an energy of roughly eighty
kilo calories per mole
and that's a rather strong energy to hold together two atoms because
the the energy
the thermal energy
that is the energy it let's body temperature
it is about zero point six killer calories per mole
and therefore if you had a bond if there something holding things together that was
in this range are two or three or four five times higher
then the simple thermal energy at room temperature body temperature would be sufficient to break
apart such
but in fact
this energy the energy of covalent bonds so much higher
that it's highly unlikely the thermal energy
it's going to break apart a it's pre-existing covalent bond and i was just reading
yesterday how people were analyzing
the mitochondrial DNA from more manifold bones
which were dug up from the last neanderthal it around thirty thousand years ago or
or recently timized cousins and they were analysed DNA sequences and they got out of
those analyses stretches of DNA that were
two hundred three hundred nucleotides long
and and that really is stunning testimonial
to the fact that under very
difficult conditions nonetheless the less complex biochemical biological molecules are able to survive over astounding
periods of time
indeed those that are held together by the covalent bonds like this
of course you remember the the film jurassic park where they used
PCR reaction to resurrect the the DNA of dinosaurs that's a bit of a fantasy
since dinosaurs left us i guess about a hundred and fifty million years ago something
like that
there's a big difference between thirty thousand and one hundred fifty
a million years ago
now the fact is if you look at the way the molecules are actually hooked
for instance let's let's look at the water molecule here
ideally there should be no charge on this molecule in fact there is no net
but the the truth of the matter is if one wants to get frank the
oxygen molecule and we always are here the oxygen molecules have a greater affinity for
electrons than two hydrogen atoms i e there electronegative
and and therefore what this means
is it the swarms of electrons that are holding all this together the orbitals are
drawn more closely to the oxygen and the hydrogen atoms i e the protons are
relatively willing to give up
their electrons and what this means
is that there an unequal distribution
and as a consequence there is a fraction of the negative charge
here this and the molecule and the fractions of positive charges here because they it's
not as if they totally given up
the the electrons with electrons are shifted more in this direction and this molecule is
therefore called a polar molecule
by virtue of the fact that here has positive positive pole and here it has
a negative pole
there are other
pairs of molecules which are
relatively equal equally electronegative for example here we have the carbon and hydrogen these two
items are roughly equally matched in terms of their ability to pull electrons away one
from the other and as a consequence there is no net shifting of charge
and keep in mind that this delta i show here is only a fraction of
a an electronic charge is not the entire electronic charge moved over
this has important consequences for the entire biochemistry that were both about to get into
both today and on monday
important because polar molecules
such as water like this are able to dissolve certain compounds and non polar molecules
which can a large arrays of these kinds of bonds or carbon carbon bonds
these are relatively insoluble in water and that has important consequences for the organisation of
biological membranes
we might have a carbonyl one here that the see going to and all the
double bond and here we have once again the situation where the oxygen is far
more evident terms with
willingness and interest in pulling electrons toward itself and therefore the carbon gives up a
little bit of the electron cloud and it becomes slightly electoral positive
whereas the oxygen atom becomes slightly electronegative
and the fact of the matter is that there are also other bonds that are
noncovalent and are much
less energetic for example let's talk from what about hydrogen bond
and it's perhaps easiest to demonstrate hydrogen bond by looking at the structure of two
and the reason is i mean you have here convex function
the squared error and have a convex constraints so we can
jump back and forth from the primal to problem
OK so what does it mean is in this picture here so here on the
left hand side
you see in this picture this kind of l one regularisation l one world so
the contour lines or the residual sum of squares you're square loss and you try
to optimize got minimize that what you see here in the middle of the fifty
ordinary least squares estimator so this is for people to just two dimensions and now
you are saying the l one penalisation
you require
that the solution must be there the l one ball in the l one ball
is this a diamond here so the l one norm ball in two dimensions if
this region here so you require constraint solution to be in this region and that
what's happening here this example what you see is that data hot one
it is exactly zero because you hate the contour line at the age of your
and this is really
what i call one geometry of the problem its parts because the solution to this
in this constellation is forced to be zero and this have to do
because of the geometry of the of the
of the unit ball
now this is vastly different to l two regularisation this is called the ridge regression
sometimes is called taken kind of regularisation there constraint you're solution to live in DL
two ball and this is the standard ball and then it will never be sparse
you see from the picture i mean it never will happen that beta had one
is exactly zero because have very different geometry
so he was again what i said already about the o two world if you
do the regularisation still tool or
you can put in large multiplier for like this this is called the ridge regression
taken of regularisation and it's vastly different from the one norm regularisation because of the
different geometry
so what is actually the l one norm regularisation the loss of doing in the
simplest case the simplest case
is a linear model we ought to normal design so here's my linear models
and the design is or to normal
well you are maybe this is very artificial body packed it maybe not so if
you use for example of wavelet expansion on the regular grid you have an orthonormal
so in this case the loss of the one norm regularisation has an explicit solution
otherwise is just the comics optimisation problem but here it has an explicit solution
and the solution is
the famous soft thresholding estimator so what is it so
you can look at the ordinary least squares estimation
in this problem
and for the j th component is simply what i call vj
this is the least squares estimate
now the last so what doing is a bit
typically in this picture here so on the x axis we have disease the least
squares estimator and the y axis we have debate the beta house
now the last the solution may be hard to see is to find all the
blue line so whenever the ordinary least squares estimator is less than the threshold it
threshold lambda half the lasso zero
and if you do your risk register made an absolute value is bigger than lambda
have you move like this could this blue line here
in contrast the hard threshold estimator is the red dashed line it's OK if it's
listed lambda have zero
and if it's bigger inland have it's the ordinary least squares estimator so you just
truncate the ordinary least squares estimator and if it's kind of hard threshold function and
what you see a bit from this picture is that
the last so really has a bias problem
OK is the one norm regularisation even if the ordinary least squares estimate is huge
is very large and not absolute value if you're way out here way out there
if you would like to estimate just already first because it's unbiased but the loss
so never approaches the red line here so the last actually always inherit bias off
the order of land
and this is something which causes trouble so already in the simplest case even if
you're signal say for the j th component is huge is very large
you end up with the biosift of us
one can see from the picture
so let's just use the last so and then you want to understand a bit
more about some theoretical properties about it so how how do use the loss of
very simple the only thing what you need to do is to choose lambda cases
regularisation parameter and what most people do including myself just rather the cross validation and
choose the best land which optimizes prediction
so in practice
you would choose what you can use some sort of BIC criterion as well most
people just choose lambda via cross validation
that's fine and then you can use again
some sort of cross validation to check overall how good you are this is kind
of what i've shown you at the very beginning and this is induced by the
international classification problem is not that important that you see really i mean the details
here i just want to tell you the last so that's pretty well just
take this
data just stick it into the linear model is not even the logistic model just
linear model to your classification just blindly and you end up with a pretty good
misclassification around saying pretty good in comparison to others it's still not very good classification
accuracy but that's in part due because the problem is very hard
so posting will be better than last year the forward selection algorithm a couple of
OK so this last week and prediction it can invalidate good yard at said that
already and you can also check
which variables are are choosing you know what's happening is if you do don't across
fully in a cross validation setting with every new fall cross validation
will pick a bit different variables so you see already here it's a bit stable
so depending on what actually what your data is you'll always have to be different
variables and average what's happening here in this example you pick about thirteen variables on
average out of more than seven thousand possible genes
OK so
what you can see just exploratory here
the last so yields very sparse model fit
just a doesn't variables out of the more than seven thousand variables
and i will try to explain to people what can we actually expect from from
result like this what are the thirteen variables are these now the real variables and
so on and so forth
OK so i built
bring couple minutes of more theory maybe full of you're more interested in theory never
moved back to methodology bring up in a bit of theory and so on the
OK so the easy part is prediction and estimation but it's actually in particularly estimation
will be important to say something more than about the future in variable selection problem
and the first OK here's the setting i just consider a linear models
theoreticians i assumed fixed design around design is slightly different but it's not a major
difference that look at the fixed design linear model and here is my true underlying
well remember what the weak learning assumption says is it says that
we're assuming that we can always do a a little bit better than random guessing
so what's
assume that all of the gamut he's are at least some positive number gamma
so in that case with this theorem is saying
is that the training area the final combined classifier
is that most e to the minus two times gamma square this constant gamma
times t where t is the number of rounds of boosting
so this is saying that
the training air is going down exponentially fast
as a function of the number of rounds of boosting the training areas dropping very
very quickly
is what this theorem is saying
even if gamma small as long as positive
the training you will go down very quickly
another point about this theorem
and about adaboost in general is that adaboost is an adaptive algorithm that's what he
had to stands for adaptive boosting
what does that mean that it's adaptive means that this algorithm does not need to
know the number of rounds of boosting ahead of time
and it does not need to know lower bound on the gamut years ahead of
either you can just
run the algorithm as it is and the bounds reflect
the fact that you might have a range of different chemicals using some of the
gamma are bigger
than others on some around you're doing better
then you're bound will be that much better
well you can
you can run the algorithm no matter what it
i mean you can run the algorithm
with with anything even if the gamut either zero this year will still hold
u u
if gamma t is are directly measurable is gamma t is
are just the air raid on the training set
so in that respect you can measure them
what's not so easy met to measure is
some the later stuffing and talk about where we're looking at the test theory
and there it's hard to tell what's what's going to happen on the test set
but certainly at this level you can measure the game is yes
so so really definition of we
he able to do
better than random guessing so let's say better than one half minus gamma for some
positive gamma
here i'm only using it slightly
weaker assumption which is that
on any distribution over the training set is you would do better than that
OK so the energy is zero
then all of these will be
zero and you to get to the
you don't want to discard trivial upper bound on the training area
and in fact the algorithm will do anything because alpha t will be zero and
nothing will happen
OK so
i thought i would
try to go through this proof just to show you how simple it is this
the one and only proof i have planned
so let me just try to
go through that had a high level
remember we have this weighted sum of the weak classifiers
and the final combine classifiers just the sign of that same weighted sum so let
me call that weighted sum of that
OK so that's just a tiny bit of notation
if you go back to the algorithm
you go back to this algorithm we've got this nice little recurrence between the distribution
and we can do is you can unravel
that recurrent
OK we can unravel that recurrent
and if you do that by the final i mean just the distribution after the
last round of boosting
if you unravel that we currently get an expression like this
and lo and behold
you have the same weighted sum up here
that we had over here and so the recurring i'm sorry the final distribution can
just be written in this
nice simple forms
just a tiny bit of rewriting using that recurrent
OK the second step
what we do is we can show that the training error
of the final combined classifiers
is at most the productivity is remember the these these normalisation constants
it would seem like just the way of making sure that the distribution
the new distribution would add up to one
divided by three i could have done by heart of course
this is o point one two
and amazing grace
only two percent of less than two percent
now here
o point
one eight six
times to divided by three
o point one two four
i can believe
less than one percent of
so you see in front of your eyes that we were able to create something
that was indeed extremely close
elastic collisions in spite of all the problems that we have a
and that of course there is always some loss
kinetic energy but it so little that it doesn't show up
in these
i want you to have
sleepless nights
i want you to think about the following
and if you can solve before the night is over
i really think
you should lie awake
here is the what
he was a tennis ball that comes in with a certain mass and
and it has a certain velocity v whatever that is
it's in nearly elastic collision and bounces back from the wall
and we all know that is a nearly elastic collision that it comes back with
the same velocity
kinetic energy is conserved all the kinetic energy is indefensible nothing is in the wall
the wall has an infinitely large mass
the momentum of this tennis ball has changed by an amount to envy
that momentum must be in the wall nonnegotiable because momentum must be conserved
so now you see in front of your eyes case that the wall has momentum
but it has no kinetic energy
can you
i understand that can you reconcile that can you show me mathematically that is completely
kosher that the wall
has momentum to MP
non-negotiable must-have moment
and yet
it has no kinetic energy how is that possible
think about it
and if you can solve it
call me three a m
and i'll tell you the solution
OK now let's look
this from
the centre of mass
frame of reference
the centre of mass is very special
and physicist love to work
the centre
of mass for reasons
that you will understand
in the absence of any net external forces
on the system as a whole
as we discussed last time the centre of mass
will always have the same velocity we did demonstration there
we still vibrating object with this spring
but yet the centre of mass was moving with constant velocity
the building now is if you jump into the frame of the centre of mass
that means you move with the same velocity of the centre of mass
the centre of mass standstill in your frame of reference
and if the centre of mass standstill still
the momentum
of the particles in your frame of reference in the centre of mass frame of
reference is zero
it is zero before the collisions
and it is zero after the collision
and this is the centre of mass some amazing properties
that i will discuss with you know
we have a particle
and one
and we have an article two
and this one
in the centre of mass frame
having velocity u one
and this is in the centre of mass frame
as a velocity u two i give it specifically use
so that you can separate useful face these always in your frame of reference use
the frame of reference of the centre of mass
and i take it case
by having completely elastic collisions means q
is zero the kind that we've just discussed
momentum is not only concerned but it is also zero
at all moments in time
before and after the collision
after the collision
let's say
goes back
with velocity
u two prime
and that's a one has a velocity
you want track
that's the situation after the collision
now i know that momentum is zero
so can i can here i i can write down
for the situation after the collision that and one
times you one prime
as and two
times due to prime must be zero
i don't write them down vectors that's not necessary because it's one one-dimensional collision
and the signs will automatically take care of the directions
i told you i chose the case of completely elastic collision q is zero
and so
kinetic energy must be
so i have before the collision
i have one
and one
u one square
as one half
and two
u two square
after the collision i have one half
and one
u one prime squared
was one have
u two times greater kinetic energy before
kinetic energy afterwards
CR one
the creation tool
can solve that cricket and we can
and the result is amazing
the result in the centre of mass
is that
u one prime
equals minus you one
and you two crime
equals minus u two
that is an amazing result when you think about it
it means that in the centre of mass
all that happens is that the speed reverse
directions but the speed the velocities reverse directions with speeds
the same
that is a remarkable
remarkable result
if you ever want to
move yourself to the centre of mass
you will have to know
what the centre of mass velocity is
how do we calculate the velocity of the centre of mass
so we did here
with the centre of mass frame
i'm going back to the
and we know that and total
times the position vector of the centre of mass we defined the last time
he called and one
time the position vector of a particle one
plus and two
position vector of a particle
and so
if you take the derivative of this equation
then the positions become velocities
so the velocity
of the centre of mass
equals one
divided by and one class and two
because that's the total which i bring on the here
and you compute these these
what is called a military or something like that where this is almost the same
matrix as
except that on the diagonal you have minus the sum of plus one on the
of the diagonal
so here you have one one you put to minus two here
here you have one one you put the minus two here the most interesting thing
is when you look at i x five you have one one one and you
put mine three here
and then you do the
exponential the matrix of h
this gives you matrix
of the same size of size five i five
and each entry of these five i five matrix
it gives you the kernel between
x i and x j k
and if you imagine that the your real graphs grows and there are many many
many points and etcetera you can make a connection between these
but you compute like that
and the gaussian kernel the usual gaussian kernel talk to you about
partial conclusions
and then i'll show you something on what's called the representer theorem amount of stuff
is that if you want to do kernels for structures become an idea is to
measure the similarity of objects through the similarities of their parts of their their structures
and lingering question is that the efficiency of the the kernel how how you can
you can compute its actions you can actually compute
and and and knowing that there is a trade between the efficiency and the and
how informative is the kernel
and there are many working solutions for graphs and sequences when i see working
especially for graph ice i mean that there are nice
algorithmic ways to two
tackle problems across i'm not very familiar with the literature on graph classification per se
so i want to say that it's is as as established as the literature for
sequence classification but
i know i think it's it's not that easy to use the graph kernels to
have very good results if you told me you tell me OK let's let's do
this this task and values are one of the kernels that i presented i'm not
sure that you can have a very good results from the start
so there are questions there many questions that says that the kernels for semi structured
data if you want to do is x XML data for instance you have
true structure and each node is labeled by
bye bye unstructured data like text or something like that and you have to deal
with different levels of structure and you have to
to work with that is not very easy to do that
and the idea of learning the kernel that as proposed by alun create for the
airport improved prediction problem is something that is very very
interesting and there are very many different algorithm that that are being developed on the
problem for all of the multiple kernel learning
OK guys were almost done
we're just going to two two to do this part of the representer theorems
and then i'll skip
the parts on the
the theory statistics statistical theory and you will if you want to do that at
with your friends are four for german people have plenty of time the sunday night
you can do that on the sunday nights i don't know
i myself have plenty of time since i've been here since two weeks or three
so the the question of interest so i'm going to talk to you about a
theorem that is very not very difficult to obtain but is and the rise of
a lot of results in kernel kernel methods and it's very
this is something that you have to to to work we then that you have
to have in mind when you work with kernels
so there is a common common features of a a common theme features feature when
you work with
kernels that you you see when you you do kernel ridge regression kernel fisher discriminant
SVM scanner perceptions current principal components component analysis is that you know
training training set s
labeled or unlabeled
then doing your stuff doing your own thing you end up with the function like
so this is why wouldn't call kernel expansion
important thing is that
is expressed in terms of kernel
evaluated on the training points
these extra eyes are those that are in the training points is very important
these were i want you to to see and this is what is very important
we're going to have to break
the magic on why this is so
why is
because the first thing you see that you may you may you may you may
wonder whether whether it's possible to have an x i prime which is not in
the training set
why would you be for this is really an exercise that is in the training
maybe you didn't want but
you might
there's a reason why the x eyes that appear here are precisely those that are
in the training set
and the reason why is explained by his theory
so the theorem states that
if you try to you have occurred
OK so i'm happy to take questions so so
no because i don't know exactly what you and what what you know what you
don't know if we stop me
if things are sounding mysterious
so i'm i'm i'm
i'm trying to stay with the essence of the idea what i try try to
stay away from from complicated pieces of mathematics but unfortunate means that only consider extremely
simple inference problem because they want to stay in the place where we don't have
to worry about how to compute the things they should be trivial to compute
but to tomorrow
you get some more
variations for your money is about what i'm trying to say is that it is
really clear what i'm saying what you really object it's not and even if
of course this is what this is what what's the the talks about right
OK so today so i'll talk a little bit about what is the motivation of
of of thinking about probabilistic models in machine learning why is that why is that
anything framework to do
two machine learning
and then i'll talk about this the distinction between the classical
we can share in and they
talk about how
you do inference in these models what happens when you have some data out there
change your view
view of the world
i have the simple example and i again apologize for having the but extremely simple
example i think is the best way
of thinking about what the concept where are
and then
i talk about
one of the crucial aspect here is the what what i refer to as occam's
this sometimes something in this in the bayesian
in bayesian inference and it's something that sets based for apart from from the from
the simple form the classical in
talking little of model selection
talk about the topic which usually is not considered
very much in
machine learning
which relates testing
but you can test the hypothesis
and i want to talk about that because that really pinpoints a lot of a
lot of the crucial difference
now try summary well also i'll i'll go through a bunch of terms
and we try to define the residue precisely what these terms mean
and the reason i'm going to do that is that a lot of confusion over
or terminology and different
sub part of the community use different terms mean different things use the same terms
mean different things which is very unfortunate
people i have to live with
but i just like to point out the things that might be useful for you
in some of the next lecture by
very careful about
you know what meaning some terms have that really belong in in in talk but
i think it's very useful
later on but i would like
OK i also practically have a ten minute break about halfway through
so it was to be short enough that you
i don't have enough time to
it's not you know
all right so so let's let
but think about motivation so why why would you think about probabilistic models when you're
doing machine learning
there are quite a few reasons
the main one is the probability provides a language for representing uncertainty
and if you do machine learning and the idea is that you're not trying to
you don't have to have a set of rules that that the machine
knows about tries to find a rule that matches in a certain set of circumstances
rather show
the machine some examples and is supposed to extract somehow some regularity from from the
because you only showed a few examples and or the finite
amount of data because it is a great example can be
the noisy like some examples maybe not typical
of the relationship of the data
the the learning systems
can actually be absolutely sure
about things like can say well
but you seem to have the a character recognition system i've seen something that actually
looks a bit like this a couple of times and every time i saw it
i was told that this was two
probably this one is also to write but it's not
i can we be sure i only saw you ten of these things so system
depending on exactly how close they are depending on how
different things that were not to were
you know that this can be some some kind of paid out there and the
are are nice language to express this kind of work they OK and i'm ninety
percent of the two
that that means something very difficult
and again so that the the the the data that we observe can provide evidence
for and against different explanation but might have had two different
different hypotheses about what the world looks like
and then i gather some data and some of the data might favor one of
the happiest more than one and the ability to quantify
how much
this data it's evidence for and against these types of the nation's this seems to
be crucial element of something that's supposed to be learned
relationship from the like
one of the problems you
used for their they used to represent knowledge i can put probability distributions over things
like say well i measure the heights of people and they tend to be
you know one point seven meters minus o point two meters like that
a probability distribution over that thing will actually
and have to my knowledge about that
and also i i i can i can infer new states of knowledge so have
some knowledge and then i make new observation then i some of the my knowledge
i know that know how to be able to do that
i i need to be able to make optimal decisions so if i have
some knowledge about how i think the world works
and you have to make decisions based on the i i mean
is good for us so in connected to yesterday's lecture and that's again a little
bit more technical but it's only a few slides and I think it's nice to
see this so let me first state the theorem and I'll try to keep things as
simple as possible in particular from certain point of view one should actually do this and
not in terms of the standard VC-dimension but in terms of other complexity measures
that I haven't introduced so I'm not gonna do that here but the basic idea
you will also get like this okay so we consider hyperplanes for simplicity
we'll leave out offset where the W is in canonical form with respect
to a given set of points so again this was our canonical form here without
the offset plus B then the set of decision functions induced by these hyperplanes and defined
on this set of points and satisfying the additional constraint that the length of W
is bounded by lambda from above this means that the margin is bounded from below
so the set of decision functions with large margins or margin bounded from below
has a VC-dimension which is bounded like this so it's bounded by this thing
bounding the length of the weight vector and also by their smallest sphere around the origin containing
the the set of data points so this is also a scaling issue and but the
main message here is that this VC-dimension can be can have a small upper
bound even in cases where we work in a high-dimensional or infinite dimensional space so
when principle remember from yesterday the VC-dimension always our upper bound from yesterday was
the number of parameters so it was the dimensionality of the space plus one
or in this case will be dimensionality we don't have an offset so
we might have a very large upper bound trivial of bound VC-dimension which might
even be infinite this tells us in reality it can be a lot smaller and
why is that the case well this is just to give you some intuition if you
have a situation where you here in this here you can still seperate these these
three points in two dimensions in all possible ways using separations of margin gamma
one but if we now require a larger margin of separation gamma two while still requiring
that the points all lie in a ball of certain radius around the origin then you
might no longer be able to seperate three points in all possible ways you might
only be able to do it for two points and if you require a yet larger
gamma allows a margin you might be able to do it at all
okay so the proof works as follows so we assume that we have a
set of point which is shattered by canonic hyperplanes with this constraint on the weight
vector shattered means we can all we can do all possible separations on these
sets of points which in view of the last slides means that for all possible
labels we can satisfy these equalities so remember from before that the positive points are
such that this quantity is larger than one and negative points are such that
this quantity is smaller than one we forget about the B and a compact way of
writing this is just to multiply with label and then both inequalities look the
same way so label times this function is always margin equal to one so
that means we have correctly classified the point XI YI so now let's assume we
can do this so whatever no matter what this set of labels is we
can find some hyperplane that has five C constraint and all these constraints so now we
will prove that the more points so the larger R is the larger a certain
quantity must be and in the second step we will relate this quantity to
this radius and if we put the two things together we'll we will get our bound
okay so the first step will simply consist of taking its inequalities and summing them over
I so from I equals one to R we will get this inequality here on the
right-hand side there's not other one but R we then use the Cauchy-Schwarz inequality so
we upper bound this by the length of this vector and the length of this vector my
assumption this is upper bounded by lambda so we now know that R is smaller
than this smaller than this we divide by lambda we get this inequality here
okay that's the first step of the proof second one is a little bit trickier but also
not really difficult so things always look easy in retrospect but this also took a while
for people to have this nice elegant proof this one is due to Gurvits in
this second part we'll use a probabilistic methods we use so-called Rademacher variables these are
independent random variables values plus minus one equally likely plus minus one so in
that case we look at the expectation of this quantity here so so far we are
allowed to we haven't fixed what other Y values yet so let's look at this quantity here
first of all we can take we can rewrite this thing here like this and
we can take one of the sums so this is like some over I times sum
over J with these thing we move one of the sums are the expectation is linear
to get this quantity now we split this second sum into two parts one is
the part well this so by construction these I mean if these were not
independent then we would have a problem that's right but we are allowed to assume them
independent it's just a calculation when we say let's consider independent randomly we are allowed to
make this assumption we will later fix into some specific value but for now to
prove this we're allowed to assume they're independent because I mean the shattering we're assuming that this
is this way find such a hyperplane that shatters the data which means that we
can solve this problem no matter what the labels are okay so now we
additionally we additionally know that by assumption all points are contained in this ball of radius R
so we use this as well and therefore remember look at the last slide again this
quantity is upper bounded by R times this upper bound on this which is this quantity
now this is a statement that holds for the expectation over this random choices of
algorithm for linear programming you have to
twist the simplex method to make it polynomial but you can do so there is
a polynomial algorithm but most people happy with the simplex method which is polynomial in
all practical cases
so this is this is polynomial actually this is polynomial to it and getting arbitrary
you getting within a given epsilon in polynomial time at the time of mention the
name of the guy who I've got a car market
as opposed to the throughout
bombshell into this well established theory
so by discovering methods that
that he 440 claimed high high efficiency
families in his presentation of his new methods it was being the simplex method by
which I mean there is a serious revolution important scientific subject because this is these
calculations are done a lot of them well much more of course that led to
many discussions as much as much further work to understand the theory behind it and
now uh I think probably in reality most people
most codes would just quickly use the simplex method but the interior methods were definitely
that has always
this'll be better in some problems this will be better another problem
this is
I done everything except explained
the simplex method
I have and I haven't haven't explained this interior point sort of there's a penalty
anyway is a penalty is you get near the
border so you see it stops you short and then you look again I could
try to explain that simplex method since we've got to this point in a few
minutes but still cannot take a few minutes to to describe how the simplex method
and I haven't done duality I haven't looked at the and this is what I
wanted to have a lot of the dual problem
so what's the dual problem in this particular case b
is just the number
there is only 1 y
and what's the constraint in the dual problem a transpose wireless recall seeing a wall
was 1 1 2
so that's not transpose 1 1 2 1 1 2
multiplying y
is less than equal to whatever the cost 5 3 and 8
yeah I'd rather tell you about the dual problem
so that says what
let's recall 5 wireless recalls 3
to wireless recall
and what's the biggest what you could tell me the answer
we could solve the dual problem
I wanna maximize for what
where Y has 3 littoral 5 also was recalls 3 and 2 1 3 weight
so what's the smallest 1
the largest why has largest was possible
there's nobody but the wire to solve all 3 of these conditions the street right
why have 3 layers review 5 the why has the lowest essentially I achieved was
computer compare competing with a PhD for the mother
but he must also compete with a grad student for the money and the grad
because it's cheaper has gone out of the tutor has reduces right because he has
to be
the resistive and he has also be what the computer charge so this
fail alarming use that word is is and say solve the problems for you
if you solve for problems
anyone societies rate as high as they can
but he can't set the rate above what
is competing with
and he's competing among other things with the
so that you can't set his rate per problem
he charges the rate per problem not per hour has just look the answers only
takes into sex
per problem
he has to
that that has to be match like like auto sales he has to match
what the other guys world and the other guys will will solve so many this
it's the computer solves the problem solved charges 4 dollars a problem right
because computer charges 8 dollars an hour but solve 2 problems so the computer is
released solving charging 4 dollars a problem so that Jeter can't charge more than 4
but the grad student is only trading 3 dollars a problem so what's the minimum
and the maximum here what's the what's the White Star
the wise story is how much can the cheetah charge of phrase that maximizes why
posturing and this is the tight constraints
and the maximum is 12 and that's what of course
the grad student
charge the charge
iterative get students hours
where I took the cheetah 4 seconds
but the to do that the cost was the same so that this was 12
equal crops
and we could even see that was optimal you see why it's optimal weight which
of these inequalities why
this stage
lax pair
the difference between e and here is a little bit less clear as you say
then what you're actually doing is sort of the show shoving your time by for
little bit i look away while you try that back in the audience
you don't feel uncomfortable
we have the notion of our reduction
in an unstressed syllable often have reduced vowels
and in english we have at least three of those dipthongs are generally transition in
transitional kind of things are usually a combination of of
static files for example the the i sound in bite is actually a combination of
transition of the eye and the evils
OK rushing through here
no that's that's a static volume the eight
just the
yeah well
oh no you're right that matches a stroke OK you got me
good job
anybody else what they that's true that you got me that is actually
the other
and wilkinson i'm zipping through here because i'm really just trying to define terminology but
stop me if i if i go to far
consonants these are all non sila in other words there are there
it is some sort of obstruction the vocal tract and the
we basically can distinguish consonants by
the distinctive features associated with the place of articulation the and also a manner of
articulation for staff
constant is a complete stoppage of airflow in the vocal tract followed by a release
there is noise from constriction in the vocal tract and four nasals in general the
valve is open and air is flowing through the nasal cavity
so i am an
skip this i'm going to have i think i'm taking a little bit too much
this particular topic
so how how would we apply
distinctive features all i think
one of the way you see them applied most is in
among of foreknowledge is
is we can basically use them to define phonological rules
describing morphologically related words
so the most common example you see
four should given to describe this
this procedure
is pluralisation of english nouns OK in general orthographic orthographically in english we will paralyze
mounds by
adding an answering yes and but for me musically
plurals result in adding one of three different kinds of endings as
fuzzy sound or the is sound
and the actual ending really depends on the last phoneme of the word
so the question is then if i have here i have some examples
of of
a different set of words got three groups of words and the question is
what is the minimum feature set
i would describe the phonemes that proceed these different vowel endings so for example
the first step towards breeze fleece
a i want in english the
the actual ending would choose here is the
there is the the third of the possible plural endings
and so on and so forth
the way i can describe the rule for which of these endings values itself
is all specify the distinctive features associated with the
last phoneme in these words and so for any lexical item then that i can
describe with these distinctive features i could tell you that i'm going to use this
type of
plural ending right and so that i could do the same thing with the next
set of words from up a lot
park leaf and moss well
for all those values the s plural ending and i could say in general that
that the consonantal and vocalic invoice distinctive features are what will describe all you know
for every word out that will describe the last phoneme in the word that for
all those words that would correspond to an as for landing and the last group
all of these and in all the last
phone for all of these words in the last group of our vote basically voiced
and so for all voiced words we would have our nouns anyway all nouns with
the last
phoneme being voiced we would use the plural endings so this gives me a lot
of the
you know i illustrates some of the advantage of using a distinctive features i can
so basically i consider factor
the distinctive features of service of factor representations so i i don't have to know
for each
each item lexicon what the
the plural ending in this example will be i can just if i can specify
the distinctive features associated with that last phone i could tell you what that's going
to be
and so
lots and lots of examples like this and in general that's what that's what distinctive
features are used for by foreknowledge in were released one thing in sort of describing
morphologically related words
right i mentioned before
the notion of
a phoneme is really linguistic quality to map from linguistic quality too
the two acoustic acoustics we use the we generally prefer to
and of
and there are few
o o
but you know
well the rest of his
and it's very easy
show it was all about
or a
one year
great is the
this one the
this whole
it is
well it and
well to be here
it is
it there
particle number two
get minus
because crowded times a two
and a little boring
why omega riskrand
however y here
so i get an h three
which happens to be zero
that's not so relevant
right now
and then i get plus
a one
and the reason why i started off with one and two told now you see
we can put
in the east part
the piece particle now
it's going to be rather easy maybe i forgot the color
omega is created
a b
omega zero credit
lines omega zero credit
now we're going to get
people as well
by one
o zero
also this
because there are also this
well sarah
so now you see
the differential equation
particle number p
so you can go on no
part of the capital and now you have to solve
and differential equation
that's so
it's a terrible thing
we will take a shortcut
which is not very rigid
but it really will save a lot of mass
and that we will use our intuition
something that we know
sort of
from experience
if you have a lot of on
fixed and fixed here
you ask yourself what's going to happen in the lowest possible model
you just know that you get something like this
this is like
and you know that in this second
normal mode the one that follows is has a higher frequency
you expect that this site goes up
this goes down
there also made like this
so we use that experience not very rigid
in order to
the site on
our trial function
this would be
mode one
well log on this would be to
so now i'm going to put it
as a trial
eighty four particle p
which is in involved and nancy this is vote
i want a sinusoid in there
that is always zero here and zero there
and you can have an amplitude of course i can freely choose so
c of and
is the amplitude of the sinusoid
c one
this value is going to be seen to each one
have it's own amplitude
and then i get the sign
one of the
over and was one
let's look together at this
equation so that we have a full understanding
we are trying to put in there
equals zero
that the site is always
it's obvious because we want to that because this point
the zero point
not moving
notice also that if you put in equals and as well
and on
also always zero
forty b and was one
sign of multiple
i'm by is always
zero because
now our model
three seven
that we are
looking for
for instance if we take n equals one
let's take an equals one so we
i have
and they all in mode one
then we get a
the vote
c one which is the amplitude of the sinusoid
and then you would have to sign
of and i
this one
and you can
convince yourself that that is exactly
this sinusoids
with amplitude c one
and you can also convince yourself
it is zero
article and this one
it's again zero of course and if you take an equal two
so they need
you and is the right
thank you very much
that what you're saying
but you're was
thank you very much
is not quite a
that is the p
so for particle number and p zero you see this goes to zero and the
bees and this one is to get close to zero
so you see here the AP
yes no c two
after being
by by by and this one
and that's exactly is this curve
notice that if you put in equal zero you get a zero
if you put in the capital and was one you get a zero
but you will also find that was zero precisely in the middle
when p
its capital and was one
divided by two
so that's the consequence
of this function
and of course
the ratios
all of the individual piece
for a particular mode
take for instance
well number one when the
the system is also like this
the ratios of the
and the church of the individual pages is that i
this site
has its own and two
two has its own two
three has its own and two
one year
two will be there three will be there before we be there and saw
so the amplitude first goes up and the amplitude
goes down again
now comes the question what is omega and
what is the
frequency omega
at these
normal motives and equals one n equals two articles three and four and cannot go
all the way down
and for that
we have to return
two this equation
right now slightly differently
i'm going to take the
eight to one side
i'm going to write down a
first one
the or
they don't
but the
the next thing which
i mean that i don't know
many of you
i have my vote
we can
i mean
i was
you know
the image
but the best way to go
what we have
and with
one to all of the big picture
one of the players
but becomes
it can only make
so you have by the way
was in
why this
and the last one is
but somehow
for them
and the whole to your
sometimes to bring one up
the band
we want to that is the which you want to be
one two
which he was to
by one mission
you can
one of the most efficient
just like
the one
but that
the clothes
so just because like
so you can
no one in which the player
and that these
quite a
problem but we can
which shall
it is the biggest one the
and just to
by the one
more generally
it this is just like
you may not quite
it is also
a lot
and the idea is for k to simply for being directly going to address in
memory and store the information in the data can just pick it up
so no
this linear operators constant cost going into memory and retrieve them the information for the
so look up and up the update operation o one
one of the interesting it's true
compute when f of x i all examples
this takes
both of the data structure and i look in the data structure
if you say a the number of
l is the number of the length of the sequence
OK this is the case the length of the camera
but this is not the time needed to build up the data structure
because we can have at most
u k different came in the training set
size q
and these are the
lookup operation so we can at most n and l k became which look
so if you don't have the data structure then we a a few
you one or and even more so by the point
so this is a very efficient but only only for small k
april nucleotides you can work till maybe order
what may be ordered ten
but not much
another approach is the sorted list approach
it's essentially the approach that i talked about before the spectrum so we
i have a list of came just put
and became a number
and then we sort that this
according to the payment
whenever we have to look into this
we have another list came and we can go down both this thing time
can see which which elements are
then we can take them you know which number
but what we need is we need to support the
that's why the
variation of this this is a bit like you look you
it need much less memory and also works for large because we don't need to
as much memory or more explicitly
get lost
this is an example of tree
this would be particularly automated degree kernel the idea is that
you store tree all the way
point is that the article
for example
a a b a b a b b example edit with you
a a a
eighty eight
you see
in these nodes because store information and the store like the information which
examples have been added work
which are much greater and much of the debate has been added to the knowledge
and then we can later look in the trees and two additional
get i love
i guess i'm going to believe it
we can use this
i'm happy to be here again for the second lectures devoted to nuclear physics
last time i was talking about some features about the nucleus
so i presented the discovery by the front experiment properties of right use
binding energy
the nucleon nucleon interaction lifetime then i finish with some applications
for medical applications are energy
are art archaeology
so then today
is devoted to the modeling of the nucleus
so i will present two types of approaches
macroscopic approaches so then we describe the nucleus in terms of fluids
you will see that it's like a liquid drop
and then i will present to microscopic approaches
so the difference is
you know that you will reiterate the nucleons
and the interaction between them
so these are associated with and mean field approaches
because the last week i just remind you some features important for today
so i remain notation so the proton is made of protons sorry a nucleus is
made of protons and neutrons and we introduce the smartest member
which is the sum of neutral plus
we define it is by adamic numbers e
one consensus it's around ten minus forty meter
more precisely you have these experiments
result concerning right is here in film depending on the web so a entries e
and you see that for all these nuclei i between commonplace to lead to hate
you have these
straight line almost straight line
so you have these little air because one point twenty five
that's a one third
when does it
it means that you have the right use which increases with a one third
and the volume increases with the number of particles
just remember that for
the liquid drop model
concerning the nucleon interaction for free nucleon you have these interactions with you like that
which is very intense and official french
so it is attracting here and you have here is a hard core
what is also important for today that you have the proton neutron interaction which is
bigger neutron neutron and proton proton interaction
also because of the charged protons you have coulomb repulsion between them
last time we have defined many types of nuclear insisted one hand and the unstable
so far stable so it means that their lifetime is infinite so that's why them
is lower than the mass of them of their component
so we define the as given the case like the mass of the components and
times the mass of the neutrons is it terms of protect minors this quantity which
is the binding energy
so first of all can you have to be positive and for unstable
you have this exponential decay here
so during the first course today
then the lecturer introduce this exponential decay
so this is the way we determine life
so there are different types of radioactivity
and finally share neutron proton emission from the weak interaction you have
the the miners and the topless DJ electron capture
these are all the nuclei that are predicted to more than five
doesn't make clear that are predicted to exist and have not been discovered
on earth there are two hundred ninety one here
and more than two thousand have been sent to sites in
different levels factories like here for example
and then finished with that
when we experimentally study indicated so i just remind you have two processes elastic and
inelastic scattering where the that
here's this kind of particles
but you also have gamma spectroscopy here
when there is
photons which are emitted and and then can construct the limits k so you have
the ground state
so the lowest energy state
and then you have all the different excited states correspond to these things which are
the transition between the states here
so this is really a way
it identifies any clues
so now go back to
modeling of the nucleus
i you because of many features
and it has been first interpret as if read as a child we could draw
because of that
you have the volume of the nucleus which is proportional to the number of nucleons
this is similar in the drug
when you have a volume of a drop of blood which is proportional to to
the number of molecules
concerning the interaction among them about interactions
you see that in graph you don't have long range correlations between molecules
it's the same with the features of the experimental features
proved that
can be the same
in any case so that's why
and it is has been for described as a child he could draw
so this is more than one stable about that's a care
first it was used to describe the nuclear fission so
what they have done they have taken the energy of the system that they have
so we
our first example of
linear programming with these generalized inequalities was second order cone programming it the second order
then the next obvious
this would be the a semidefinite cone because we've seen that another
convex cone
that means you have
the ten I's inequality respect to semi definite got
so if you write the normal
mathematics you would have a problem like this you minimize linear function of x
and then you have and a journalist equality respect symmetric
matrix inequality
that means that this been combination of symmetric matrices a i coefficients x i
if there is an b
four different minus the left hand side is positive semi
it's called a semidefinite programme it looks like a a linear programme
except you have made
the and AI i smitten with this
and that's matrix inequality
and actually that's the most of the three so lps can be written as a
source in business to business he has can be written as the
maybe of interest
then for example
the application of this would be
two minimize what you want to minimize the maximum i value symmetric matrix a
and a is a linear function of the optimisation variables x
they have access just constant
six one the constant
that's just another way of saying that have symmetric matrix a of x
and every entry in a
it's a linear function of x
we've seen that that's a convex function follows from this that the example of the
supreme en route
but that doesn't tell you how to actually minimising the the context
could have been solving this is to set up an SDP
and yet that follows so it's a variable t and then you look at this
matrix inequality a very good with the times the identity matrix
and that's equivalent to saying that maximize value of a very
because a is less than t
i in the matrix inequalities since all the bodies of a
you see what i like
i was at this scale
inequality in
but this scattering on the actual function of x
if you minimize here you can
expected in this the very have linear
simple linear functions of x
but you have omitted in the core itself can cause
and you can verify that sinister be because you have the variables are now expressed
this additional table t
minimizing linear function of the variable
and in the constrained to have a symmetric matrix
in fact the in all the elements of this matrix are linear in x
that's why you need
so that gives you a practical way of solving that i value minimisation problem
we can do the same for the matrix on eigenvectors rectangular matrix
and again is linearly dependent on x
you want to minimize the norm for the maximum so you
and there similar trick you can use to write as the matrix inequalities norm of
a president
if it this was a
that's all it i got is present the square
and to show that according to this
and you get this is
so again this is a convex but quite a convex function of x you know
that already because an enormous convex
also that maximizes value norm of a matrix is convex but that doesn't really tell
you how you minimize
by setting it up as an SDP
you get a practical
method for actually solving
then recently one of the reasons why people are interested in semidefinite programming is that
they are used as relaxations or very difficult combinatorial nonconvex problem
so one example would be
this was i haven't discussed problem minimize x minus p two norm
subject to bullying can i say excise could one
so the components of the variables must be plus or minus one
so that in general vary depending on most cases made able to be very difficult
to come for problem
and because you may have to enumerate all possible choices for x
but it's impossible to fix
the relation appears as follows
the first try that n
it could have occurred on the second problem i small c is actually my next
and i would use matrix variable capital c
that's because easy transport
c is actually the original variables
the is capital c is omitted variables and fish
this inequality constraints
so then the rest of the problem can now if you had this equality constraint
can be written as just linear function of
for example saying excites credits one
it is the same as saying that the value of this matrix is one
because he is given by the transpose
on the other hand we have the
these constraints
this policy
i just saying could linear constraints on the
also if you work at the coefficient the objective have the norm of a minus
convex functions of X
but if you're also looking for a method for solving this
then this is not that simple because it's also very non-differentiable
so if you look at the Hessian for example in the points where it's diefferentiable the Hession
is just zero
so it's not easy to solve using newton method or a gradient method
and so on but it's easy solve as an LP
so you
to write this as a linear programming problem we introduce new variable T
and then add an inequality
for each of these components in the maximum that says that A transpose X plus BI
is then T
and we optimize this
linear program over T and X jointly
it's an LP because everything is linear in T the objective and the constraints are all linear
in T
and then it's also not difficult to see that if I minimize over T
and X jointly that's equivalent to solving this problem
and to see that you can just assume that suppose X is fixed in this problem it's not a variable but
you only minimize over T
so if you minimize T is subject to this MM lower bounds on T
then obviously the optimal value of T will be this value the maximum of those lower bounds
so that's if you fix X and optimize over T
and then if you minimize jointly over X and T then the optimal solution will be
the value of X that minimizes this and T will be maximum
so it's equivalent to this and this gives you practical way of solving this
piece-wise linear optimization problem
so an application of this are the one norm or infinity norm
in minimization problems so suppose I want to minimize one norm or the infinity norm
of an function X minus B
so these are we know already that these are convex functions of X
because norms are convex
you can solve them
and practice using linear programming
and the argument or the reason is very similar for example if you look at the
one norm you would introduce a number of variables Y one for
each row in A X minus B
you introduce linear inequalities per lower bounds A minus B and then you minimize the sum of the Y's subject to these
and again it's
easy to see that these are equivalent
so assume again that X is fixed
so AX minus B is just a given vector and then I minimize over Y
so that's a seperal optimization problem you can minimize of every component of Y separately
for each component Y I there are two lower bounds there's a lower bound Y I is greater than
the Ith component of this and greater than the negative of this is greater
than the absolute value
of the Ith component of X minus B
so the optimal value for Y Y I is the absolute value of the Ith component of
A X minus B
so that's if you fix X if you fix X
each component of value would be the absolute value of the corresponding component of A X minus B so the value
some of those will be the one norm of X
of A X minus B
and then if you minimize over X and Y jointly by solving this LP
and X and Y you minimize the one norm
for the infinity norm you have a similar
story except that instead of M
variables you only have one extra variable Y and then you instead of a vector
Y here you have Y times a vector of ones so you impose the same upper bound on
each of the inequalities and that will minimize the maximum of the absolute values of A X
minus B
so this is of course very useful and it's also useful to look at the
distributions you get by norm approximation with different norms
so here I just take a random matrix A of size two hundred by eighty
I minimize the adjusted two norm the discussed problem and the one norm of A X minus B
and this is the distribution of the residual the two hundred residuals in the vector AX minus
B at those two solutions for the two norm and for the one norm
and the green chorus of course are the penalty functions you impose on each
residual for the two norm you have quadratic penalty function for the one norm it's the
absolute value
so then you see that roughly speaking this two problems of course do the same they try to write
B as a linear combination of the columns of A
so roughly speaking I try to do same thing but the distributions you obtain are very different
and there are actually two important differences that are useful
so one is you notice that the of course the high peak at zero if you
use the one norm
and that's explained by the fact that absolute value has this breakpoint or this
breakpoint at one at zero
but as the two norm minimizes the quadratic
penalty function which is flat at the origin
so there's no benne benefit here if you choose X and moving it from something close
to zero to exactly zero
whereas if you use the one norm actually you keep getting a benefit
by making it moving it all the way to zero