it happened first with the aesthetics of the sublime which imposed the radical change
the way people saw the ugly by analyzing our reaction to natural phenomena dominated
by the formless the painful and the terrifying
thus we sense the sublime when seeing
storm rough see rugged clifs glaciers abyss boundless stretches of land caves and waterfalls when
we can appreciate emptiness darkness solitude silence
and the storm only pressure that can prove delightful when we feel horror for something
that cannot possess us and cannot harm us
on his essay on tragic art schiller observed that it is a general
phenomenon of our nature that sad terrible even horrific things
are irresistibly attractive to us
and that scenes of suffering and terror repel and attract us with equal power
and that we greedily devour those stories that make our hair stand on end
it was that spirit that led
a few decades
previously to the Gothic novel which with its ruined castles and monasteries terrifying bones of
bloody crimes diabolical operations and decomposed bodies
thus among the protagonist of the romantic drama we see the damned hero
like in Byron the villains be found in sue balzac emily bronte
but the most ardent romantic eulogy of ugliness came with victor hugo's
preface to his play cromwell
the ugliness that Hugo saw as typical of the new aesthetics was the
grotesque the deformed horrible repellant thing transported with truth and poetry to the
realm of art
and the grotesque was the most fecund of the sources that nature makes available
to artistic creation
as Remo Bodei observed hugo makes beauty turn full circle thus leading it to
coincide with ugliness
see for instance the the description of
quasimodo the hunchback
of notre dame we shall not give to the reader an idea of that tetrahedral
that nose that horse shoe mouth that little left eye obstructed with a red bristling eyebrow
with the right eye disappearing entirely beneath the enormous wart of those
teeth in disarray broken here and there like the embattled parapet of the fortress of that
callous lip upon which one of these teeth encroached like the tusk of an elephant
of that forked chin and above all the expression spread over the whole of
that mixture of malice amazement and sadness and so on and so and so forth
and there is the description of l'homme qui rit the man who laughs gwynplaine
has been prodigal over kindness to gwynplaine she had bestowed on him
a mouth opening to his ears ears holding over to his eyes shapeless nose to support the spectacles
of the grimase maker and the face that no one could look up
without laughing
but was it nature
had she not been assisted
two slits for eyes a hiatus for a mouth a
snub protuberance with two holes for nostrilis
a flattened face all having for the result an appearance of laughter
it is certain that nature never produces such perfection single handed
but is laughter synonym of joy
such a face could never have been created by chance it must have resulted from intention
had Gwynplaine when a child been so worthy of attention that his face
had been subjected to transmutation
why not
industrious manipulators of children had worked upon his face it's inevident
that a mysterious and probably occult science which was to surgery what alchemy
was to chemistry has chiselled that flesh evidently at a very tender age and manufactured his
countenance with premeditation that science clever with the knife skilled in
any the crew
so as do you would want to avoid having several minima
there's no way you're going to your function is going to go up and down
and up and down because if you go up and down then you're going to
have maximise the potential use of minimal
so it looks like
the derivative of your functions then
should have always the same sign
if you can if you go up and down
then the derivative of your of your function is going
it when you go down it's going to be
sorry when you go
and change once
in it is if you think about it the more
then the only way that you have four
to be sure that the function as i only one minimum is to have it
which is
those kinds of functions there
and what's the property of a convex function it's the property that
she would take to any two points
and if you are the segment between f of x in f of y x
and y then this segment is always of above the
the curvature of function
that's the definition of a convex function
and it happens that it's equivalent if you know in advance that f is twice
then being convex is just that the second derivative is is
was it
of comics functions when you find the point where the derivative is zero
then you are guaranteed its minimum
i think pretty much everything that's on this that is what we said about
functions when when we don't know there are convex
except that the only thing we haven't talked about it is
if this continues to grow
so the minimum necessary and sufficient condition for
having only one global minimum for a convex function is is that it is corrosive
which is the definition of their which means basically that if if you have
a continuous function in your sure that in the
when when x goes to minus operators infinity then the function is going to plus
since the function is continuous there's
there's going to be some
some points here
words where there is a minimum
so if you have a continuous function and you know that the infinity goes to
infinity then there's a i fixed one meaning
what this is there
so a minimizer is the point where the derivative is zero
if it's square differentiable then you'd have to have
the gradient being zero and the hessian be non negative semidefinite quantitative metrics again you
can forget about that so i mean this is a positive matrix
so what
here instead of considering only functions
that go to and i have read values are considered functions that maybe you have
a vector values
so your derivative this is is replaced by the gradient and your second derivative is
if i get the signs wrong then will come back and fix
it's about that's my average energy that's the entropy
and what i'm going to do is i'm going to maximise its subject to the
constraint these are marginal song to make every one of them nonnegative that's obvious
and to make them some to one that sort of another obvious constraint
those are not the interesting constraints
interesting constraints are these ones that we've seen before going to make the joint marginals
on the edges though should collapse down to the marginals on the nodes
those are marginalisation constraints that's where the messages are going to pop out
so that's an optimisation problem
fourteen my
energy go
so we sort of remember it's an optimisation problem that involves these two terms
better entropy in an average energy
to constrained optimisation problem
but the constraints are simple and nonnegativity constraints normalisation constraints and have our old friend
the marginalisation constraints
OK so the reason this is an important optimisation problem is because
what the sum product algorithm is doing
we're trying to do
it is it's trying to solve this constrained optimisation problem
so going to drive that are going to see the messages are lagrange multipliers
right so it's trying to solve it because in general as i said that's not
going to be a concave maximisation problem so there could be multiple optima and when
you have multiple optima you can't really say anything about an algorithm that you don't
know if you're getting caught in the valley are not so that's one reason why
some products without reweighting can be problematic
when we make the entropy is concave function then
if we look at the energy the energy is just a linear function
the marginals right it's linear because when you take expectations that linear function
taking expectations linear that sort of an easy part of function
so as long as we choose these weights so we make this a concave function
or concave entropy
then when we add them together concave plus linear is still concave
we're going to get a nice well-behaved optimisation problem
so that's the advantage of choosing the weights in good ways that you you'll get
problems that have unique optimum and there's no issues about
flailing and not not sure which optimum you go to
OK so let's let's try this
any questions before we that's one work through the lagrangian calculations because we haven't seen
it it's not too hard and i think it's it's instructive you have a different
perspective on where the sum product algorithm came from
any questions before we we do that
so e
queries e
right so that's
fix those you're problem parameters
if the marginal every node and you take an expectation of the problem parameters so
it's a linear function of the marginals
i guess
this is why the derivation i'm doing that sort of obscure parts of the bigger
picture so that the bigger picture which is covered more in the slides is that
this function that have defined
where we define it is given in sec
right so this function this is what we're trying to compute the log likelihood that
function is a convex function of the parameters that we use that when i sort
of motivated the upper bound
but whenever you have a convex function
well if you're a convex optimisation kind of person be a convex function one thing
you might do is take its dual
so little even talk about conjugate tools
what i could do is just to give you some sort of intuition where this
is coming from
i'm trying to compute the log likelihood that some function
any function
any convex function closed convex function closed is just a technical condition can be written
as an optimisation problem that involves its
it's a function in some dimension d
it can be written as an optimisation problem that involves
the conjugate dual function
that's probably leaving went through that with you
this is sort of saying that the dual of the dual
under good conditions if you take the dual of the dual you get back the
right cause
that's the dual and i take the dual of it
i get the double tool
under good conditions that's the same thing
good conditions hold here if you take the log likelihood is equal to this
where this is some conjugate function
so the question is what is the conjugate function
the conjugate function in general is an entropy
i for for any graphical model
it's the distribution it has some entropy
and that conjugate function is
it's not the entropy it's the negative entropy because conjugate functions are always convex
so because this guy is the entropy that's why
in our variational problem that's where the better entropy comes from
if i'd done this on the tree if i took the conjugate dual tree i
would have gone tree entropy and it would have been better thing would be exact
so that's why it's coming out because we're doing an approximation on the general graph
actually little let me just let me just walk through this because this kind of
relation what i'm saying here is that this becomes negative entropy
if we do a simple example
a toy example but
it sort of good practice in computing tools and we'll see why entropy pops out
so let's do that because the we see entropy come out in the simple case
then i think it should make a bit more sense you why entropy comes out
in the more complicated case
right so let's some where are we
so i put it she i just had this
kind of
simple thing but it's nice results and what the result well if you think about
so this is actually is you with right you construct this like from the point
clouds from unlabelled actually both labeled and and unlabeled and you get this
she had this
here it's like the sum over all labels class label what
so before we had the represent theorem
and then we also have representer theorems and basically you can think of keeping ghost
you have a sum over all labeled and unlabeled point
of this is this is the solution to to this problem and more of the
interesting thing is you know you get the same
basically the same thing
you have an explicit form for the coefficients so for the case when the loss
is quadratic
this is just the matrix inversion
so you have to to solve the system of linear equations
now of course the typical one sentence labeled unlabeled points
if you want to change was like in SVM
then it's a simple problem the problem words quoted from same
from the problem and support vector machines
but now with this additional controls little bit
so basically we have a support vector machine but we do not
basically where you can sort of look at it works pretty well
so there is some comparisons here but shares interesting to this is the thing that
if you use
there are some of the error is so are some labelled and unlabelled pork
so suppose we just use only labeled points this is there
so that you can ignore this if unlabeled point also
so this is basically a little point should we get a little bit
so this is the difference you can see the difference in some cases very dramatic
twenty four four
so definitely
in all cases with some
so definitely that unlabelled actually tells us the geometry of unlabeled data that's something interesting
there is
there is something
utility which can be captured by using the using this graph
now sort of moving to the next thing and the next thing you have to
theoretical questions surrounding well remember there were two objects so this graph
based things which is
data dependent on there was another thing which is you know and alignment so now
the question is
you know it
construction based on unlabeled
but based on simple how does collective suppose it is really from the manifold suppose
we know that the sample more and more data from with the question is actually
convergence the this
you know that this procedure faithful representation of the object claim to be
it turns out that this is actually true
and in fact what you control
you can show that
so here is the thing
support a simple more and more points from an underlying probability distribution and the constructed
graph as before and i need to choose the parameter remember there was this guy
was in which i need choose this
the width of the gaussians
the function of
in a way that it becomes more and more narrow as the number of questions
so it very important regardless of course you don't get
then i can vectors of
so graph of cluster
converge to again functions as
so that's the problem main
theoretical result
and the previous work there is basically the
there are some results pointwise convergence
so uniform but this is you can actually show that investors themselves
and let me just give you an idea not just an idea of the proof
but also an idea of why this is the right and it turns out that
is it's actually kind of simple
it's basically the heat equation
what is the semantic web
five minutes discussion specifically what is typically
if you questions the phone i let's say this surface for
i have a huge distribution of the surface
in the beginning this is my initial distribution so suppose there is nothing else
and then what happens i just live my run for
and you know
distribution changes as time goes on
and you know so for those of us feel right and there is in the
vacuum because this joke about the physical force in vacuum
then i mean
in the early phase from distribution in the beginning right on this in the and
like twenty goes to infinity for every out to become cost
and i
but in the end it's very short period of time right if i will concede
to be you know zero point zero zero one second this distribution doesn't change well
ten very low
so now how does this work well imagine i just have a few minutes
the source of its support
so i have so everything else is zero here this is my one sort of
what happens to the well
for a short time it become a sort of go
spread out over the
more the result of point of
and there just completely flat
so if it's if anything is going to propose to a xerox if it's surface
and just come
know what happens if i have so many sources of what i to some of
so if have infinitely many sources of how much she would like to him point
and see if i have to integrate over the set of all the points writes
like an integral over all of the point of how much she just point from
all other point
and i know that from each point to its go
well they
the total amount is going to be in convolution to discuss is is biggest from
the point of how much he
so this is the form of
it's actually a very natural right is just group is believed to point to go
normal distributions well this
a large body of work in the statistics literature just about what you can do
with the normal distribution
for instance you could have gauss markov random fields
people have written books on that
actually even very recently
and has a lot to do being with for sparse matrices and so will get
to this in a bit more detail later on
so basically don't underestimate the power of interest the single one of those distributions
you can build a large body of work of statistical inference devices on top of
but what i'm saying is
you know rather than
simeon on this specific one
we can play with all of them
and do it efficiently
all the gotta to do is pick one we read of the corresponding normalisation
we've made life much easier
now why is this useful
well let's just i mean after at the end if they want to perform inference
it's just look at again what we started out so i said well let's consider
all distributions which looked like it within approach between some profits in theta
and these are the sufficient statistics will get to that the later that's normalisation
one of the really good things is that this function g of data
is a nice function
it generates the cumulants
so sometimes people actually use the mechanism very similar to this as
cumulant generating mechanism just to get those for any arbitrary distribution
and the math actually
it does look quite similar
let's recall this is our
g of data
now let's take to the relative with respect to of g of data
and while ignoring
issues of convergence and all of that well all all we do is we just
apply the chain rule and push the narrative through the integral
so the log of an integral
is one of the integral
the derivative pushed into the integral
now e to the
something will be safe i just pulled my father fix out of you
now what get
i get five fixed
he e this expression here
the log of that expression
so basically if i wanted to squeeze then here this in here i would have
to take months to lock
now that
if you recall is exactly to of data
in other words
what i
got sitting here
this entire expression there is p of x parameterized by theta
the integral of four fix
p of express interest by caesar
it's just the expected value for fixed
well that's great
it this is what i've done is i've now once have done the hard work
of looking up in some statistics book the book what your data is
i can compute expected values
o five x
just by taking derivatives
so rather than me having to actually solve this integral here i just take maple
tell it take the derivative with respect to those parameters
another comes with an answer
so now this means that they have an automatic way
of generating all those expectations
so this makes my life really really much easier
let's get ambitious
let's take the second derivative of g theta
you could now go through all the details in
i encourage you to do so at your leisure at some point
you probably want to do that exactly once in your life and the never again
new five but you really should do it once it's it's really really worth it
to the other state here
you have the load your on it means that from this date knowing that you
had this input
i conform to what the transition relation
which is that it's conformed to the behaviour of the automaton OK
that was the definition here
knowing that
labeling of the full binary tree by states of the automaton
of the
you labelled with the initial state
and in our example it was qy should
i have copied it i think my branch here
branch say
this branch
o a q a q and the bottom at the bottom of them
in fact all the colours
so the columns of w the human has got one pascal of zero
so that means if you have a look at this branch and b
one one one and he was he was he was he was he was
you can have branches here
and imagine that you
after this be in this input after the
i have that found is we have like here
an infinite subtree contain
but even this have to complete the full battery with the left branch
always labelled baby
on the left edge
the computation
according to the transition relation
the computational
that's the only
if i have be
so you have to be here to q and q
q bates's OK so the colours
it was one of the leftmost most rush
of this competition
my way to contradiction or to declare
the competition is successful
one of them i might
so what i do is that
and they look at
the current of from
along the branch
so it's
the full binary tree
i choose the branch
this tree
and instead of looking at the states that just because of of the generalisation of
being financed
being an accepting state of being statistic zero one zero would be accepting one would
be accepting
but just to itself
imagine i have now the way
describing our posterior and then we put them into this equation which we can
analytically compute now if we want to be
even a little more robust we might we might want to say well i don't
what these offers were we put a prior on those
and try to integrate over that they would be called the hyper
i per
parameter or hyper hyper prior and you don't need to go at infinitum some people
think of this process never ends that supply of bayesian methods that's completely bogus basically
you u
you only need to consider adding levels of parameters and hyperparameters et cetera it's your
model up to the point where there aren't any two things that you want to
couple together
because then at some point if you have a whole bunch of hyper parameters and
hyper hyper parameters et cetera
then you could collapse the whole hierarchy to just some distribution over
points at some point in the graph
in the hierarchy anyway so
for these models people just usually choose some simple hyperparameters here maybe even all ones
you know like in the lab classes rule the uniform dirichlet distribution they might use
it all to be one and then do inference
and then you can question whether that's good enough
right so the they days question was when you do maximum likelihood
the maximum likelihood for
more complicated models always has a higher likelihood than the maximum likelihood for strictly simpler
whereas when you do the bayesian model averaging
you don't necessarily get that
that's coming in and
so chris bishop kind of already described this in one of his lectures where
really what's happening is when you integrating over the parameters of the model
you're not fitting the model to data in the in the maximisation sensor fitting
so it doesn't matter if that model has more and more parameters it doesn't make
this marginal likelihood higher and higher in fact a more complicated model is just the
model that puts its probability mass
more possible datasets
so i think of any model
class of models as making bets about possible datasets that could be observed and some
simple models will put their bets on some datasets and
not on anything else
the other models will spread their bets out on a wider range of possible datasets
and that's what we usually think of as more complicated models but each model has
this has a unique currency that can spread out unit you know one dollar pound
or euro of probability mass that can spread out over possible datasets
so because of that more complicated models
i will not necessarily have higher marginal likelihood
still have a problem with the next week
three years
it is hard to believe that
yeah so the question was a different way of doing this would be to start
out with the fully connected graph
then do some estimation or learning or something and if some of the parameters are
starting to go to zero in some way then then you could prove them out
and get simpler model out yet there actually are good ways of of using exactly
that intuition that you have in certain cases for example with linear models
like linear calcium models then when the parameter goes to zero something becomes independent of
something else here it's a little more subtle to think about that because these are
conditional probability tables so things are really going to zero they're going towards independence and
as you said yourself one of the problems with
well what you're sort of
thinking about is that it might be computationally costly air and indeed you know it's
it's simpler to start with if you're graph is sparse
you don't want to start with the fully connected graph because then you have a
hell of a big probability distribution to deal with
OK let me just move on
and try to get to some of the sort of fun researching thing at the
end as well
here we can take this score
which was the marginal likelihood we can obviously
i use prior information if we prefer certain graphs to other graphs may be we
have domain knowledge is the biological problem in these genes and we read in the
literature that this gene affects that genes so we want to put that in well
we can put a prior over models are graph structures in here as well
and then the score would just be the log marginal likelihood plus lot prior
a greedy search algorithm we just take graphs and consider operations on the graphs and
try to find one that has the highest score
the bayesian method would try to do
inference over model structures by running markov chain monte carlo for example over the graph
structures so proposing graphs accepting or rejecting exactly in the same way as in mary
four metropolis for example
all right
now what do you do when you have incomplete data so this is kind of
you know the hardest cases in this square
there is an algorithm by near freedman called bayesian structural yeah
is using some of these marginal likelihood computation ideas and the idea behind the EM
algorithm to try to
phil in settings of the hidden variables and then score
structures based on those filled in settings and then move around the space until it
finds a graph with the highest score as possible
let me have a couple of remarks and then let me just give you a
i would like really
this is all
that is the sum fancy mathematics is associated with
it can be seen that sounds
we already have the new function is the same
illustration that shows you
where these two kinds of different
so one one-dimensional regression problems
the difference between here
i have three thousand miles
from here
because of the weights of the posterior
always just run around
three three car right
you get something
if fifty
a few
on new examples posterior the weights and you would imagine the
but i would like to run
right these
the question is
the songs
but we
the question is what happens if you want to make region here
how to make predictions from the model
well we
look what was to
and many more on the weights according to you
what happens here
in addition is always
so we integrate over
the posterior way
we always here
zero maybe not
as for the mean
but it turns us
same again zero with the same model
at the start
that's because
what that does not
if we had just here
and also
our first
and they will tell you
the posterior
the reason why
the model that would be telling
o thing
to worry about
these are the more to worry about whether prior
actually allows you to have
so i'm going to
more than functions so
for most of the rest
like this
actually wish
the we constructed ten
well that's very function
this is year
tell the
inverse square scale
so you you basically just to
gas laws for children functions with different things
and it turns out if you choose the
the distribution of less
and this
gamma distribution
and actually you know it
all the rest
see what looks like
this shows what the actually
the question is all stationary only depend on the distance between
if if you go to infinity
then the
distribution of over the main scale
becomes very high
that means that the
to infinity
you get that calcium is residential
two smaller and smaller you get a mixture which has a different kind of link
let's get real functions
two of
we're not going run
you can see that output is a quite natural in lot
you get a function of the boy
perhaps not structure on was scale
he has
this full-scale destruction cells structure doesn't do it
this exactly what we
the characteristic length scale
by mixing together in functions by
we can get
it gives rise to point
so for example you
so small
skin effect and also artist
small and
this is this is different kind of dimension of different ways
ideas about
one of the characteristic
this example is called the ten commandments
ten growth function
also actually expression
the last of this function
properties are
is similar to
should be
and the next
right there
situation where
from this case
that's why
small values
good functions
all of these cores
process by my brains in such a way
that they think or they well
they actually make you see white light is as real as you can have it
so this raises the subject of
the illusion of course which is what i want to discuss with you
for the remaining part of this lecture
if you ask a physicist
when we see certain colors when we see red when see blue or green
and chances are
that he would give you standard answer
and he would say well
that depends on them
on the wavelength in air if you tell me what wavelengths
you're wrong and i will tell you
what causes you'll see
and i have here a
transparency which
makes the connection between wavelength and these colors
it's also on the web you can also download this
and so if
the wavelength
of light
in areas about
in this range one angstrom is ten to the minus ten meters
you will probably say that's red lights
when the wavelength gets shorter this range you would say i disagree light
and when the wavelength gets even shorter
you would say others blue light
you can see
any wavelength shorter than this you get into the ultraviolet here
you can see any wavelengths longer than this
that's infrared analyse
sensitive for
those wavelengths
so this is all nice and then the
but we still have the problem
of the
the fact that if you mix all the
course together like the rotating disk might looking at the light bulb that our brains
still tell us that we're seeing white light
so maybe that is i'm not really is simple
as we
i think
this scheme
callers has been worked out in
quite some detail already in the seventeenth
and in the eighteenth century
when it was discovered
that there is such a thing as primary colours
maxwell did some research on that
and handles even the
the poet
going to
did work on this
they discover that their primary colours
and when you mix lights
we call these additive mixing
the three primary colours are green violet and red
and where you mix paint
the three primary colours
i yellow blue and red
and the idea behind this
is that if you mix the
the three primary colors in the right proportions
you can make many colors
i want to show you a
color triangle which is the recipe
tells you how you have to make this course
and in order to do that
going to make it dark
all the way dark
you see the color triangle
and the color triangle has in the three colours three corners
the color red
one primary color
and then
here his violence
and then of their it has
it has green
and i'll tell you how this
the recipe has to be used
so i'm going to draw year
color triangle
and we have already here
and we have a green there
and we have here violated
if you know that is called the triangle
you see all the cause that you can imagine sort of
you see yellow
and you see here purple
and you see orange
you can see why
so how do we make these calls now
well suppose i wanna make this call here
so that this color
then you draw three lines
from the three corners
and this is the amount of threads
you have to put in
and this is the amount of green
but you have to put in in the light
and this is the amount of violent like if you do that in the ratio
you would get
the core
which is here
if you want to make very nice yellow
so let's see this makes it very nice yellow which is all the way you
the edge
you don't need any violence you can do to exclusively with green
and with red so let's go to this point here
which is yellow
it would mean then
but i have to put in this much read
and i have to put in
this much ring
and if i had more and more red
i go along this line
and i end up here and i get orange
so i could make audience here
by simply increasing the amount of red o
you should not be violent right
would green
well you should have
well the this is green
i did off on measures of image similarity
so like one
the measurement similarity of is i guess they can make sense of the images in
the same thing not to make sense of this noise
so with correlations
they tend to fail more easily but they tend to suffer from problems with outliers
and things like that
but the big advantage of it is basically in terms of the complexity the the
reason that we kind of tend in vision
to deal with some square difference is all
basically linear classifiers is complexity because all of the time when not just worried about
performance of the accuracy of the classification decision were also worried about how fast we
can do it and so
obviously things like this is the linear classifiers because there's been some kind of signal
processing inland over the years we can do we can evaluate classifiers very quickly now
one exception to this rule going to talk about this is cascaded classifier and classic
cascaded classifier like
boosting can out of this type of topic classifier we got like a stub tree
and instead of having to evaluate that every pixel in an image you might only
have to evaluate small groupings of them such that before you can start making decision
that can actually speed things up a lot so so you can actually come
make your question for complex but generally
we try to adhere to these sort of things
and just to that
this is the linear classifier with weighting matrix by
and here
the quadratic classifier
this is this is a symmetric matrix b then
see the bias and sometimes for i we need to have some constraints and i
again we get into that
so if you can
i have got all these questions now that i will have my sample i've got
go to find the speed
what this implies tutorial is going to be about finding the p so
i know the piece continues so i know that i can settle continuously so
how should i say what's the strategy should have the sample and
the first strategy in the nice strategy i think it's just basically operating on what
what's commonly referred to as the pixel coherence assumption
it essentially the pixel coherence assumption is something really simple
it essentially goes and you have the template at the ground truth the registration point
you move the blue box all around basically every possible x y position in terms
of the temple
and you get what's essentially it's an autocorrelation function into the
this and this
and now the interesting thing and this is where the main knowledge that that's coming
now for any signal to produce is that any kind to the signal
or i could get any sort of behavior you so i might have a big
fight here and everything else flat or for another synthetic sigma whatever i might have
a completely flat all the way through because every other position for every other every
other image but the interesting thing for natural images is that we tend to have
this lovely
graceful degradation
if you actually play with nearly
a natural image by susan
seems whatever
this pixel coherence
this this domain specific knowledge this idea that pixels that are relatively so
it is everyone can understanding what this is representative of basically image shifted with compared
to itself
why translation text translation
and the thing is that with this is i think this is the kind of
inside because you can actually explain a lot of what's going on in computer vision
and image in the image creating count how people were saying jpg images and things
like that based purely on this pixel coherence assumption
in city the coherence assumption is it
is that pixels in close spatial proximity to each other very highly correlated
but that's not something that applies universally so you could have a random signal noise
and things that that doesn't always apply this is something very specific provisions
and the cool thing is is that you can do a lot of great things
with the so if you think about it will touch upon a couple j coding
j coding essentially takes advantage of this
so if the cutting takes advantage that pixels are highly correlated with each other and
so based on this correlation we can have a big inroads in compression and it's
going to change the world people can transfer images very quickly now
and also there also
and we'll touch upon two i could also be something like this x y in
time t
and pixels tend to be quite correlated over time as well which has made big
inroads into safe
the very thing that's recording at the moment makes it possible to record the sort
of image sequences in the in the compressed fashion
and you can do that for any single visual signals the natural natural world of
have this very domain specific knowledge and the cool thing is is that the following
it straight from machine learning perspective not taking into account
all i do a good job but i can do a much better job going
on this programme
yes learner you could which is the which is which is a good which is
a good so it's it's it depends on that's a very good point so so
it depends on how deeply deeply you want to go so like a good general
rule of thumb is say like
natural images things like the discrete cosine transform something so that very representative of town
pixels redundancy in pixels things but you could for specific domains you can learn those
redundancy and that's a very important
now this is like an example of an unnatural image should but actually image up
there but it's essentially got an image and i is
yes yes this is the origin this is basically where where it is in cause
if if there is any information specific and they're never going to get it to
not all the time of the images complete zero flat all the way through but
if there is some sort of specific information to pete heller generated this was that
this actually had to face image and i put into the for duty free domain
and i normalized to the spectral power
talk about that and when you look at these images so i normalized the spectral
energy in the image you look at the image looks extremely edgy looks really unnatural
things like and that's because every frequency spatial frequency in the image is being given
the same amount of power so like edges if everything was in natural images what
tends to happen is that most of the power is concentrated in the lower frequencies
and things so that that's almost the energy use and so on because it's comes
low frequencies that's what we get is graceful degradation
so this is an example of an and a natural image
now you can all be deal that's
that's realise i can i can watch high-definition TV but how does this apply to
computer vision
the reason this is useful is that even though thinking about this pixel elements into
and in in particular you might come across jeffery's priors and reference prior the
another maximum entropy bayes priors so these are all attempts to try and write down
priors that don't particularly quantify anything anybody actually thinks but nevertheless have this property of being
kind of like vanilla they don't they don't sort of
influence inference inference too much and in particular popular to use things like this when
you're trying to compare models for example
but it's still an ongoing quest I mean this this is stock sorry yes
do I have any intuition
well the particular question the jeffery's prior is trying to to deal with is the question mentioned
here if
you know if you and I think the same thing about something let's but you think actually
in terms of the standard deviation of a distribution and I think naturally about the variants
there ought to be a way that you could write down your relative ignorance about sigma
I can write down my
ignorance about sigma squared and it wouldn't matter
you know that the the answer you get in the end would would would be the same you know mines would be the square of
yours and that's a very that's quite a strong condition actually doesn't sound much but it's quite a strong condition of what a prior
could be and that's where jeffery's prior comes from so that's why it uses the the inference the the the information
the problem with all of these things is the pro problem
down at the bottom is that these are all priors that depend on the likelihood
in some way
if we if we want to do think of the prior information
as being what we knew
about theta
before we had any data
OK that's what prior means
surely it also ought to be what we think about theta before we know what
kind of data we're gonna get
the theta is a real thing I think is a better tomorrow today tomorrow I'm going
to find out if I'm gonna have a normally distributed observation minus theta
or a prior distributed observation minus theta I maybe gonna find that out tomorrow but what do I think
today about theta
so these these views of setting priors don't allow you to have a prior in that
situation that's quite
troubling thought so this is this is really an active area particularly we we don't know
how to do
objective priors properly in large emissional problems
it's an active research area and there isn't a clear answer at the moment
that's my understanding of that yeah now these priors are often improper
improper an improper distribution in probability is one that's you know its positive and non-negative
its integral is infinite
not one
like a normal distribution in different variants
are you allowed to use those well
yes you are but be careful
that's what this slide is improper priors are only safe to use if this have this nice property that there
they can be viewed as limits of proper priors
and the the posterior you get there is
correctly the limit of the corresponding it to the posteriors
so this is a this is a bit of advice is not not taken by anybody
but nevertheless I'd give it you know that's the that's the test you have to apply
every time you think about using an improper prior does it does it behave properly in
this sense cause it doesn't always that's not always true
OK I'm gonna use the rest of this first session to talk about some
principles of modelling
how do you model well it's a little difficult to do this in a
kind of generic way right I don't have a particular thing in front of me
a nuclear power station or financial system or something so
but I want to keep it general so what I'm gonna do is talk about
some themes that you see quite a lot
when people think about modelling
so these are quite generic ideas in
in that people use when building models
whether they're statisticians or machine learners I think
and the first of these is to do is called hierarchical modelling
and just in introducing it very informally if you've a bunch of related things
are there rules about how you should think about
modelling them jointly now that's something concrete
so this is a a little sort of medical stats type example
so you've got twelve hospitals carrying out
kind of operation on
it's actually this is based on data on inference cardiac surgery so these little babies
very ill with heart defects
times the expectation
you have to a
so why is that true
so i've done is i've split the ice the expectation of the product
it is the product of the expectations
that's because an independent so what's independent of what
px OK here
random variable
are independent of any of the other partitionings
and the if you will the xnk that would exist for any of the other
recursive calls
so whatever happens in here
is independent of what happened there
OK so we're actually hides have a recurrence
we're using the same we're not partition the same way each time we have a
different one to actually have something going on underneath the mathematics you have to pay
attention to
that the mathematics alone is really showing which is that in t
OK there is actually a set of random choices that are being made
if you were OK
so you have to understand those are independent of those in which case we can
multiply the probabilities of their expectations
OK everybody with me
OK so that was the that's a big one independent of x and k from
other random choices
OK that's equal to
well first of all this is nice
what's expectation of x and k
one already
that's actually doesn't even belong in the summation just pop it outside
OK so i get one over and
times the sum
k equal zero
one minus one
the expectation of the of
i was wondering
summation can zero
expectation of
t of
and minus k minus one
and so should a people's hero
like this one
so that's once again using linearity of explic expectation there this time to split up
these pieces
and just factoring out
the expectation
OK is being one over and
everybody with me still
so all this is elementary just it's one of these things it's hard just because
there are so many steps
it takes that you've seen some of this before
OK so now the next observation is that these two summations are in fact identical
the same information just in a different order this is going
t zero t one t two t three up to t
i mean minus one
this one is going to n minus one t of n minus two t minus
down to
t is there are
so these are in fact equal
so therefore i two of them
and then what's this term equal to
so i want equal to
so but to see why
so the summation of zero
of DNA stadium square
divided by n
or if i want to bring the the an i have one times the summation
of cause one and they don't want
or one
so once again get and in the way of doing it
OK so this is in some sense the so this this is because the summations
of the
identical terms and this is just algebra
so now we're going to do is do something for technical convenience
is it sore
the k equals zero and one terms
into the thing in
four technical convenience
we have a recurrence here
private water and
and if i look at the cases where k equal zero or cables one i
know what the expectation is per year one it's
the expected cost is
the worst case cost most the worst case cost which is constant
OK because it's only
i'm only running at four
ah i'm only solving the problem for constant size and we know that for any
of the boundary cases that are solutions current subsumption constantine
so i can basically just take those two terms out of
models that they don't need high voltage to work and so of course it has
to be
to be there
you went to the scene of first thing to do that you could say all
the good depict octopus don't so i just put it on fire with the input
impedance have single
child detector capacitance and they will look at it
so why not
you will get the voltage which is
a function of the child and the detector capacitance
and again
have to one million people often took also then you can add
but again you wish
the that
you you have to
o five
the i think you know
the opened we also have an input capacitance of which means that you still be
this is to detect octopus capacitance in addition to that the fact that you and
i don't mean that you are more sensitive to course book i will come back
to that
unless you have to do and then we'll have twenty
this is the second best otherwise assisting stay constant
so if we do that we make what is called a child on
and i don't have to fail is shown here
so you have to do that the councils and then you
and all the feedback element is
if the capacitance if you look at
if you saw the equation i mean as as i have done before
for a few minutes ago you will find
what action should between the output and input is just
the change in the voltage output is is
it is a division of the child
by this feedback capacitance also the gain of the system is the feedback capacitance
i'm going to
its feedback capacitance value it will have to be determined by by the amount of
signals that you want to know that you want to to detect so
so a small capacitance high of again but of course the the voltage and so
we get four four new venture
and you have some it's your for you
you if i i suppose impossible i cannot believe among other things and that you
can use it
computer is optimal in the end you can
a very simple thing it turns a short signal into a long one so you
get the idea
and that's what we did before them
this is the end of ninety percent of particle physics detectors
but it's always been by this custom circuits
a lot of parameters after
adapted to this particular
two particular depicted
so that
so if the formulas on in
the game is not find for these is not confined to infinity so you will
films on a with respect to what
to what was which which means that we have a bit of a
of diffuse it's of detector capacitance played a small role
the thing is
you will you have
the don't one is not infinite and so it was designed it holds off
and because
it introduces
the frequency of the pension and and also it makes the input impedance is not
zille was it it should be used
mp fail was
it was perfect
and because of that
the output signal got as good diamonds i stand
it is given by
but by this formula in which the capacitance the picture is introduced and this
jews you will images you also have to deal with the gain of the amplifier
we give you all these frequencies this is doing input impedance of the amplifier
so again if you want to do
on the website you should you should be able to see that it's the way
it's to showing how you compute the input impedance so you would have to
to be
so the
the input impedance for an idea if we have an ideal amplifier will be because
it is just a the user feedback be don't divided by the gain of the
amplifier so this is very i suppose yourself so that's why we call this input
virtual on so it's not on the but in fact the don't solos you could
assume it's it's home
minimizes sensitivity to detector
in don't say
or training during a triangular matrices you just
we need to to know if the product of the day
the diagonal elements is nonzero
and the direction generalisation to that is that is that
let's see for dinner matrix a out two
it's two lines in two columns is a b c
then you can easily take that is invertible if and only if might be seen
as a hero in the universe is the the one that they give you there
in general
if you want to know if there is matrix debating matrix is invertible you know
you have to find to determine which is written this way
the determinant maybe for example defined recursively by saying that
the determinant of a matrix
it is the sum of the determinant of the mine the ninth of
these are some of the smaller determinants
so that's what's written there
thing we think changes equal to one then this formula for the determinant is the
sum of a i one
times these coefficients there
he i one then
is doing the coefficients of the
the first column of the matrix and the coefficient that your input here is actually
the the determinant of the matrix that is obtained from a without the first column
and we without the rule number i
OK so
this thing here is the determinant of a d minus one by d minus one
matrix of that is obtained from a
by subtracting two lines and columns
features affirmative from genes for the inverse of a matrix using the determinants
but you never use it twice a ways that because you have to find all
these these matrices
this matrix of determined there
and it's not really practical
the next thing you want to know is
it is
other ways to find and i will show how to invert the matrix
OK to do so then we look inside the matrix and we try to decompose
it into an easier matrix
or maybe what i should say that when you look for given values
then you would be looking for
an equivalent diagonal matrix to your matrix a
in terms of an open if you think of it in terms of an operator
there is a year dividing matrix is an operator that goes from rd two rd
and you may find nice business were this operator is actually diagonals
if you do so it's really easy to invert the matrix on this basis right
well it's not always possible so the operator is it doesn't necessarily have
diagonal form on some basis but you may want to to get used to get
close to that
so the diagonal values of the matrix or
this carries a message that they are there is a vector
a non-zero vectors and that along the AV
is equal to lambda v
the eigen values are going to be the values that you put on the the
the they are going to all of the equivalent of period after that is diagonal
OK and the
the these
so the eigen vector are going to be the vector that you put in the
in the new basis
on which the operator is local
whole regulate the view yourself on we also have an mid-term which rule which is
scheduled for the this the eighth of november at six PM so please keep that
so please keep that evening free
and so on
let's see
and one more at one one most mysterious thing i want to say is about
a class project on
the goal of this course is so the few well equipped to apply machine learning
algorithms to the problem or to do research in machine learning and so as part
of this scores so asks you to execute a small research projects a small
term projects
and what most of us do for this is easy to apply machine learning to
problem that
you find interesting or investigate some aspects of machine learning on so i don't see
that you are already doing research to those of you who are industry are taking
this different from from the company on one fantastic way to do course project would
be if you apply machine learning algorithms to the problem very interested in onto problem
that you already working on you whether it be in science research problem also the
problem in this you're trying to get the system to work using the learning algorithm
to those of you that are not currently doing research in this space
i one great way to do a project would be if you apply learning algorithms
to just pick problem the care about figure out that you find interesting and apply
the learning outcomes so that the idea is to see what happens
and the goal of the project should really be for you to do a publishable
piece of research in machine learning and take on
and because the course website you actually find a list of the projects that students
had done last year and so all the the semantic and you can go go
later and to look alike but look reading down this list i see that last
year there was that is that some of learning algorithms to control the snake robots
are fewer
projects on improving learning algorithms on desert
project on flying autonomous aircraft there was a project that he done by lt paul
on on this
improving computer vision algorithms using machine learning other cup approaches on netflix rankings using learning
algorithms on a few medical robotics ones and segmenting iota segmenting pieces of the body
using learning algorithms on one the musical instrument detection
another on our in a sequence alignment
few algorithms on understanding the brain neuroscience
actually quite a few approaches neuroscience on projects and understanding FMRI data brain scans on
and so on another project and market making the financial trading project on trying to
use learning algorithms to decide what is it that makes the person's face physically attractive
was the only album optical illusions and so on it goes to fund lots of
fun projects take look on
then you come come of your own ideas but whatever you find cool and interesting
i hope you feel make learning
the machine learning approach to questions
oh yes thank you
so precious to done in groups of up to people
so on as part of forming study groups on your later today is to get
to know cause phase side if we also encourage you to grab to other people
in form group up to three people for project just start brainstorming ideas for analysis
cells on
you can also contact immunity is if you want to bring some ideas with us
one organisation questions
here is how many of you know how many of you know matlab
well call quite a lot
on OK so as part of the
china know octave
i have use after
it was small enough so
as part of the scores on especially in the whole world wants to implement a
few programs a few machine learning algorithms as part of the whole words on and
most of those whole worlds will be done in either matlab or octave which is
sort of and some people call the free version of that allowed which is sort
of it sort of isn't so
because for those who have seen that before
on the intimacy have matlab is programming
here's the proof language that makes it very easy to write code using matrices on
to form new to write code numerical routines to move data around to plot data
on and is an extremely easy to learn tool to use for implementing learning algorithms
and for those of you in case somebody wants to work you know on your
own home computer or something we don't have the matlab licence on for the purposes
of this course there's also
there's also a software package called octave that you can download for free on the
it has some of fewer features and that that but is free and for the
purposes of this class still work for just about everything on
so actually i
so just to psychology for those you have seen that before i guess on one
a colleague of mine and the different university knowledge that they actually teaches teachers and
other machine learning class on
he sort of many years so one day on
he was in his office and posted and to his for about ten years ago
came into his office and he said oh professor professor thank you so much for
machine learning class i learned so much from it on the stuff that i don't
it's the particular
question that
i may ask i have a probabilistic model that relates the weather today
with the temperature today with the pressure during the with all the available for example
what happened yesterday at this time
if you have a bunch of random variables and how they depend on each other
i can ask particular query about one of them
two of them
examples of computing probabilities of particular outcomes
and also i make
particularly interesting
outcomes i mean particularly interesting configurations of my probabilistic model for example
finding the most likely outcome
have a given probabilistic model like for example a noisy remember the example of
of image processing
i have a noisy image
we could ask the following question what's the most likely corrections for his entire image
given how images in general became
and given the pattern of these lights
given the image in terms of service
so an interesting question
solving this problem for example with
in that context would give us a solution to the noise problem
so i mean in graphical models will be concerned with
asking this very same questions that we as with any probabilistic model
it's just that seems to have a particular type of structure given by conditional
independence statements
the way we answer for these different questions
has a particular
i just think
you know
we need to learn specific algorithms to answer for this particular question
well this
another unified problems
answering these questions is much more trivial
for example
you have
it's just univariate gaussian distribution
i want to ask how many people have seen this
well this is something extremely simple
it's the preferred model
for many
for many things in life
let's see how those things happen basically
we have
a unified galson distribution here we have two parameters have the means and if i
and the
the first question to be to estimate the mean and the violence giving
observation right
that's one question you can ask
i mean
very difficult to find this in
solutions for this problem here
i mean you can find them
and the text books have been written more than fifty years ago
you can also sample from the distribution very easy
we have a single viable
i mean
papers written more than fifty years about fifty years ago
he was some nice ways to sample from mcgovern distribution efficiently
and africa
you can compute areas under these
core right
which is compute the probability
also given
given elements of samples
to compute areas
we just need to integrate this quantity
in particular
well you can also find what's the most likely value of this probability distribution
well you can work on
you can compute derivatives for example
if you go out
when the derivative is going to be easier
and you see that the only find value for going zero is exactly this fellow
this morning we looked at
maximum likelihood
and we look at the algorithm for maximizing the likelihood function
what i want to do
in this
lecture is now to look at the bayesian approach
and talk about variational inference in the context of
bayesian learning
so in the bayesian
framework we introduce prior distributions over the parameters
much of the discussion will be very general
but i will again illustrates
the idea is simple examples including things like the gas mixture model
all OK with everybody is a new feature
we're doing user studies at the moment to see
so we introduce prior distributions over all the parameters
and so this is just
this can be represented graphically
by simply adding extra nodes to the graph representing these prior distributions
so just have an expander graph so learning in a bayesian setting of course corresponds
to finding posterior distributions over parameters and then using those posterior distributions to make predictions
for new
test points
because this is an expander graph learning is really just in front
just inference on this expander graph
so we at this rather nice
results that
learning in a bayesian setting is just just inference problem again
and in particular there's no fundamental distinction between
latent variables hidden variables
and parameters
in one sense a sort of the distinction if we have a whole set of
data points we have one latent variable per data point may be a shared parameter
so in that sense they can be a distinction between
latent variables and parameters
fundamentally in this framework there is no difference they just
variables stochastic variables in some big complicated graph
and we're going to observe some of the variables that sort of data
and then what inference two
find posterior distributions of other variables which called trying to predict
so for example we can take the mixture of gaussians model and we can make
it a bayesian model
so this is the structure that we had before
these are the observations
capital and for each observation each observed
data vector
the binary hidden
variable z which is the indicator variable
yes which component generated each of the
data points
so the prior distribution of z is governed by some mixing coefficients
and so we can put a prior distribution
those shown by this node
and this is the a guassian so we have a conjugate prior
over the mean
and the precision of the gas in
and so conjugacy in this model
so p of pi
it is
just to dirichlet which is
products on k
i k and is usually written alpha k minus one
the some
normalisation constant at the front and you can see that conjugate because
recall p of x given pi
it was the products on k
k to set k
so when we multiply this by this
the posterior distribution of pilot can be high
raised to some power
alpha tilde minus one
the posterior distribution has the same form as prior
we can certainly write down the
prior distribution for the mean
and precision which is the inverse covariance
of the garrison
and that's the thing called normal wishart
so we have the prior
on land
which is a wishart distribution
w is governed by matrix and the parameter
it's essentially
the first exact form is something like the
well involves the trace
and some matrix which can write w inverse to w matrix
the parameters of the distribution
and again you can see the controversy structure because the
in the gas in the exponential
of the trade of lambda times something with the something is x minus mu x
minus mu transpose
then he is
new prior for mu depends on lambda in order to have conjugacy
and this is the normal distribution
which is
has some of the
but it's
variant three precision rather
proportional to
the so my notation this is the main the covariance
so the
the inverse covariance the precision to the precision of gas prior is proportional to the
of the original guassian lambda
so again it's sort of an exercise five minutes associated paper to verify that the
product of these which is joint distribution of immune lambda
is the conjugate prior for the gaps in
is an intuition why depends on lambda i don't have an intuition but if you
look through them as you can see that it's you know a few minutes the
and equals two
raise a siouxsie in this example is one one-dimensional one and so
it was later map consists of course disease
and that we use some
so the point is there
and lastly the small was visually that a place along calcium but rather we should
be say
and sample
change of colors
the axis of the maybe that's that that would be a typical sample of the
axis under this model
so how do i fit the parameters of the small
the joint distribution
xeon x
you know is actually calcium what parameters given by some vector they realize meex z
and some covariance matrix sigma
on the right to what those things are
this vector may be as effective zeroes appended to the vector mu
and the matrix a square
is the
partitions made
so what is the last time
so you can also what the distribution of x under this model
and the answer is
well under this model excess calcium
i mean you
and covariance lambda lambda the transposable side it's just the second block the mean vector
and take that law
the the right-hand corner block of the covariance matrix and so this is this is
my formula for computing the marginal distribution of the gaussians that that computing the marginal
distribution of you know the second half of the vector of the first
so this is the marginal distribution of x under my model
and so if you want to learn
let's see here this one writing down the
right this is really specifying the conditional distribution of x given z right so on
the conditional distribution of x given the
this is gaussians
well i mean on
the from the covariance side as well that specified
this is the marginal distribution of x given my training sets of
and unlabelled examples i can actually write down the log likelihood of a training set
right so the likelihood of a training set is actually this right on the likelihood
of the likelihood of my pseudo likelihood of parameters given my training set is the
product and i just want to things i given parameters
and on
i actually write down what others because x i is calcium with random you
and variance lambda lambda transposed times site savings rate is down as you know going
over on the
so i'm going to right the times and minus one
so that's why
for the density of the calcium that has mean mu
and covariance
lambda lambda transpose possi
so this is my likelihood of the parameters given a training set
and one thing you could do is actually take this likelihood and try to maximize
in terms of the parameters to try to find them as likely as the parameters
but if you do that you find that tried you take well to give the
log likelihood to characters that there is a zero you find that you be unable
to solve for the maximum of this
on analytically
so news
you won't be able to solve this by like this patient problem if you take
all right so
we have got until
nine thirty and questions
one copy
so i'm going to start is with the movie
the o thanks
the people in the back and here we have
they ransacked
so i don't know what we've seen is an introduction
to machine learning there was this whirlwind tour markets yesterday
and then there was a good analysis of the different kinds of data
with the rise in practice italics showed you
part of this summer school is going to be more computation
computation first specific kind of models and as as we go for the next few
days will be more clear what kind of model this type of competition is useful
or it's not useful for everything
and so
part of this will be that you get an idea when you can use these
method and when she you shouldn't try
all going to be based on sampling and simulation and so on so quite often
the goal of that do
it's obviously to do machine learning it's obviously to compute parameters
solve integrals compute
this normalisation constants the markers
talking about yesterday
but quite often
it will be just as the simulation device
simulation is important because
if i want to kind of
do it task like
go to sydney
i'm trying to decide what to do this we can kind of simulated my head
how final will be one from the sydney mardi gras and all that
and that kind of gives me that allows me to make decisions
and that's actually how
in fact to come into the sort of thinking
i want to make a decision in the future
i have some prior knowledge my head of state of knowledge in my head and
from that around simulations into the future
so we're going to see a bit of that and that sort of
o be a preamble for worksop is going to talk about later when he
starts talking about reinforcement learning
OK so
a clear indication of we sample
we've seen this before
if you have forced climb
i have a video
it's this tube
pictures in this video for sort of flashing between one and the other
and there is a difference between the two
how many people have seen the difference of and once you see it please don't
and also it
the rest three people
only human
it's quite a lot of number of pixels
respect to the image
how many people have it
it's like a because of waking up
it is that getting up in the morning
that motion seems to be developing
many people
i have it now
for those who haven't seen it
what do airplanes need in order to fly
the end to gives you haven't quite figured out
OK so
this is a phenomenon called change blindness in psychology and its
it happens with images that happens in the visual cortex in the visual field
starts in the visual cortex
but it's it's characteristic of human brain mind and brain how we work
we sample the world
the reason why you don't see it is because we never see this image
this is an illusion we believe we sing it but we don't we sampling
and we only extract from it what we need and we do our reconstruction or
so when you believe using the whole thing
and the same is true for all types of arguments if you're in trouble
unified with your boyfriend on think you write and sign you might just not be
seeing the whole picture
and that's probably more familiar
you know it's some theories of cognition now it's about there being conscious into being
subconscious processes and you just basically covering this
subconscious processes so that
the crisis seems to have
and a good understanding of what's going on
this something mechanism keeping things control
this is again like alex said yesterday please don't take this into projecting that any
of the methods of talk about here described how the brain works it's more
you something is important
it's useful for humans whenever you have limited capacity
to process something we humans don't have
or problems for that matter the capacity to process the whole visual field
focus on certain areas of the space
right so that's the end result
all right so i think this
lastly i kind of thought halfway through the deletion process section so it is just
remind you
dirichlet process is basically a random probability measure that satisfies this conditions for so for
any set partitions
of four space so if it is our space partitioning to us to find the
number of subsets that
it is random because g is random input to measure
and is the vector sum to one and each entry is nonnegative because each entry
here is the mass assigned to each subset
and what we see is that this gene is the dirichlet process if for every
such finite partition this factor here
is distributed according to a dirichlet distribution
with the with the parameters given by
base base measure evaluated the same subset
and as we saw this set of
the set conditions is is consistent or in peter's work is projective right so we
can use common graphs theorem to show that there exists a
a random probability measure over
that satisfies all
all of these conditions
o thing is this
OK so
if we look at say
this set of
distribution problems of probability distributions we have dirichlet alpha and then we take this mess
and then we split into two forward to offer over to take this one split
into two
this one split into two iteration of awful awful awful awful awful and we can
doing this and what we see from here is that this that islam is consistent
the usually of a single parameter alpha is simply going to be
it's just gonna put all its mass and one
this distribution
a draw some of it are random vectors of of length two that sums to
so we can visualize this as count tool
two bars that whose total area sums to one
and similarly for
for this thing can visualize a random draw from it as
four bars was
it was totally has to sum to one
this is the demo to show you so we started with
this one right
so the degree area here is the total area is one
so we split this into two and
that's kind of to that the high some or less the same
this slide is a little different so this is a draw from dirichlet of over
two of over two and we can keep on repeating this beating each each of
these two bus into two
so make this this is draw from a dirichlet alpha alpha before of over four
for over four and a half
and we can keep on doing
doing this with english by the two and having to draw from the corresponding to
and if you do this lot of times
then we see that
the resulting
this basically looks like a random
probability measure
a random distribution that
such that such that
this is a random probability measure such that for any draw
you can look like this is an infinite sum
of of the functions of points passes
we see that it kind looks like the following so g random draw from a
dirichlet process turns out to be always going to be a infinite sum
of point masses this weighted so the case point mass is going to be located
at theta stocky
and has a mass of pikey
of course the pages have to be nonnegative and sum to one
so that this thing actually defines a probability measure
and if a cases atoms
in our
a probability space
so this two questions that we can ask one is
what is that
joint distribution over
of the weights
and over the locations of the atoms
so if we can understand what's the joint is a distribution over both of this
then we
i have a pretty good idea of how does she look like
so these a kind of different representations of dirichlet process that gives us some understanding
what is this strange beast the second thing which we we might do is since
g is a probability measure then we can treat it as
a distribution that we can draw from