so if indeed particles
i ways you should be able to demonstrate that
by having
interference patterns
after particles like the water waves and make it certain locations in space
those particles disappear which turned out to be possible
but that's very nonintuitive
so we think of it two classically when we say well to particles cannot disappear
quantum mechanics you can think in waves if you want to and then you have
no problems with the interference
that and the destructive interference at certain locations
now there are remarkable consequences of quantum mechanics
classical mechanics
you and i are clever enough
you think that we should be able to
determine the position
of an object
for any accuracy that we require
and at the same time
the terminal also its momentum any explicitly we acquire the schematic of how clever we
object is right there
that is its mass and that is its speed
the german
i realized in nineteen twenty seven
the consequence of quantum mechanics is
this is not possible
strange as it may sound to you
i can work stated that the position and momentum
of an object cannot be measured
very accurately at the same time
and i read to you
heisenberg's uncertainty principle the way
we know it says the very concept
of exact position of an object
and it's exact moment together have no meaning in nature
it's a profound non-classical ideas and it is hard for anyone of us
and me included to comprehend
but is consistent
with all experiments that we can do today i want to repeat it because it's
going to be important
of what follows
the very concept of exact position of an object
and it's exact momentum together
i have no meaning
in nature
what does it mean
first let me write down
i books uncertainty principle
delta p which is the uncertainty in the momentum
multiplied by delta x which is in certain positions
of that
or approximately equal
planks constant divided by two pi
from physics
recall that age bar
it's four
is approximately
ten to the minus thirty four
joel sachs
you see eighty six point six
ten to the minus thirty four
if you find it divided by two pi
you get about ten to the minus
thirty four
what does this mean now what it means that if the positions
is known to an accuracy delta x
will give you some examples
that's the momentum
the term is not determined
the amount delta p
larger equal
five i don't
that's what it means
and i'll give you an example
which i chosen from
the book
george kind
come off wrote a book which he called
mister tompkins in wonderland
it's about dreams
mister tomkins
wants to understand the quantum world
and is a professor you'll see a picture of the professor who takes him in
his dreams
remarkable nonintuitive effects of quantum mechanics
any one of these dreams
professor suggests that we make eight four one
the professor takes triangle in the pool table
and he put the triangle
over one billion people
so the billiard ball is constrained
its position
and the delta x
is roughly say ten to thirty centimeters
o point three metres
that means that the
is not determined
not determined to an approximate
value of one
divided by o point three
it's about three
there many use
a second if we give the
a billion more mass of one kilogram
delta p
is and delta v
so if n is one kilogram
the speed of that billiard is undetermined according to
i uncertainty principle
and the first because the centers of the mind
this is point in the k dimensional space
that's the very efficient each dimension is the average value
of all the customers
in the clusters
obviously all customers in the deviation in that cluster have some deviation from the centers
but the otherwise having little division
can be regarded as
as well as more and more
and have high
i have high definition will be regarded as suspicious
that vehicle could customer deviation which is which is the sum of all of it
motivations for customers
but the customers
and then we call the cluster index
which is the
customer deviation divided by the
this customer deviation in the clusters
if the division is to for example
then the if concentrations for that
customer analytics for the right by
a critical to
then the customers started with the monkeys in the killing value of this animal index
and this
the lower part of this list will be one of usual part
and i propose to be taken
aside to the expected one
this is a result from the index for example in the first column you receive
the index
which is five five point nine two is that
and then here's
we see the primary which which made
this customer's unusual is there
internet local knowledge
and it's
its inputs is we see and really contribution measures
which is defined as the minimum deviation divided by the customer deviation
so this means that
if there
total division is regarded as one hundred
sixty two percent of the variation is explained by the
why this very
internet local numbers
then the second very which is responsible
to the end of this custom is the
could come along of icons
in turkish this
for for the second customers
the critical number of transactions division
it's not like experience ninety six percent of them
that means
this is discussed
made enormous
number of the transactions in his car
in the last
this list is a useful tool for
they can go over all the details of the
customer or converts customers
and starting with these very was indicators
they can make this picture
the move to the second phase
which is the inferential data analysis
he here
we would like to use predicted data mining
predict which customers
i are laundering money
in this thing that it would be nice to have it instead
to learn
to the to the model
but unfortunately the monkeys is which i
i have quite a few
they have only seven
confirmed cases which i
one hundred years
this is for real sufficient to form the training set and the local model
then what we have is
it's such as in a
they will ask the help of these pictures
and then will ask them to
to investigate the result of this
and detection face
and we just have to decide which ones they
they want to speak or they seem worth respecting
and using this list
we have an anomaly in the list which is
which is coming from the first phase
ten often working the expected data
they're on the list that
these persons customers should be can be best investigated
then using this list will take this expect list as the first assembled training set
and then we will develop team decision tree or something
predictive model
the one which
should be expected
so if you want to change just click here
and the window opens
like this
you have here all these basic settings you can modify
each of of them
you have online help we can help here
my asking for more information about this
well you see it's it's it's very
easy to use we have just changed here
to use equal frequencies for discretisation
we're going to do this
this afternoon
and apply
the field
when you apply
the filter
to the body of petulance
you see it has been discretized
this is not an histogram is just the collection of categories
the video has been this capacity into
and here you have
they could points
which these filtering voting has has chosen and the counts for each of the modalities
of the categories
you see here that work has changed
the name of this relation
now its name with real name which is i wish
and the name of the field that has been
applied to
you can do this you can do almost everything by clicking immediately after
the on the bottom
we're not going to do it
classify the second
the second big window
well here you can find
everything that you could expect a decision trees decision lists instance based classifiers like these
labels and
so on SVM snow networks
different kinds of regression based on its
and also make the classifier
the these ways of enhancing the classifier
by combining several
instances of the same classifier like bagging boosting stacking
a long list
can be combined with almost everything
if not we can tells you
i can do it
but in principle
it's very flexible
so classified
we just changed
the main window to classify here you have
to choose producer classifiers
we're going to do it quickly
this is
this is a list of some directories because it's ever written in java and you
know the the classes
as of directories two
so you can browse through the different classifiers
like browsing through defensive of directories
so we have here decision trees for example
many of them from the idea three basic two g j forty eight which is
c four five three
and phi trees random forests random trees
let's just this one
c four five
this is again the default parameters this is the confidence factor
it's the level of pruning
you ask
the minimum number of instances leave all the things you can expect right decision trees
if you want to change
again opened the window
change whatever you want if not OK
then it
we have a look here you can see it
then we get to use the whole training set for inducing the decision tree
besides doing this you can specify
a further test set that will be used
and all that after the end of the mall has been created
you can use cross validation with the number of false here
or you can simply use a the holdout technique just use
in this case two thirds
all the training sets for
inducing the them and
then the model and then using the remaining one-third for test whether
in this case we're going to do this last thing
more options
this is just to tell we can what kind of output
you need the model itself
plus statistics
the full confusion matrix
and you can ask we get to store
the whole set of predictions for later visualization
this is nice we
we're going to do it later
anyway start
and this is the result
you can see here
the inputs
four the tree all your settings
and this is the thing
it's because you have to fight
a training level
this is better with less or equal than c o point six then sit also
fifty instances fulfill this condition
you all know what the decision trees
scroll down to see the whole information this is the confusion matrix that we ask
this is the the
performance on test set
which is what we ask it
this is a list of all the models we have induced with the name with
anglican it open it and the sum of things
for example
for the for the specific case of decision trees we can ask tweak to visualize
more nice way
nice way
the same tree
this is our tree
we just
induced of course we can say this figure that i j therefore some other format
we can visualize the classifier errors
which is nice
there was some errors if you remember
these are two errors
two of out-of-town out
of the confusion matrix so if you
i want to see
what instances of these two errors are these two
this is here better alone
on the horizontal axis
against the with
is associated exactly with a radius usually say yes five versus five space in strings
the number of colors and is the same radius but in plant units
so one of the input actions you see as quantum gravity corrections
one of the allowed the corrections string
like what actions
the gauge invariant operators of this conformal field theory which can be written as the
single trace of sum product operators become single string states in just five versus five
this scaling dimensions of this separate we are in the conformal energy scale invariant regime
so the relevant quantities of this scaling normalise dimensions of very very first
become the energies of the string states
renormalisation group flow of the theory if you turn on some relevant must perturbations for
become basically extrapolating solutions between ages five versus five and some other geometry
heavy external probes like quarks become strings stretching to the boundary of radius five and
there are various other elements in this dictionary i want to go through the whole
so there is no sharp precise dictionary and you notice in particular that when we
have two sides here we can contemplate if you think about the string theory side
well the hardest thing to try to compute that quantum gravity effects those are
card because they require loop calculations in string theory
but we can in the sense that north completely those by taking n to be
infinitely large this is called the plane model image
in real to see DNC's three we're not very close to the people in the
limit but still it's well let's take an infinitely large
then the correspondence tells us that the full and equal force prevent means is the
classical theory although it's a classical string theorist
we have to compute string quartets which
now a word about and this if there actually and wanted this if there is
a funny space and you have to
contemplated for a while to get the lead to creation
but here are a couple of relevant comments about it
first of all
it's a space which have an infinite blue shift at the boundary remember all have
at of the throat of the black hole
in nineteen theory or there was this infinite it's safe as you go out there
is a blue shift and these blue shift becomes infinite at that because we kill
yes in the arctic region we have the one if you remember the harmonic function
so now we have an infinite blue shift so things that move out to the
get more and more blue shifted and they have a tendency to fall back in
because otherwise they don't have enough energy to make out
so i this is the space looks like it actually it perhaps particles in the
theory that's consistent with the fact that the energy spectrum is discrete
officials here the correspondence tells you that the energy so various strings there are scaling
dimensions and the spectrum of scaling dimensions should be discrete contin
so that that's why we get the discrete spectrum anomalous dimensions this is the space
is also unusually stable one funny geometric property of it is that if you draw
a barber
born here and you try to expand it out
usually the area of the ball
grows less quickly than the volume of girls like some small power of the volume
was here the area grows like the volume and therefore
this if there is more stable than usual space time
because when you try safer nuclear the barber of
right viking mushrooming during the vacuum this problem may not managed to make it out
since the gain in energy in the video doesn't beat necessarily the surface energy you
have to create the
so it's stable space effects like crap
and finally moving towards the interior of the
looks like changing the energy scale
so in this holographic duality you should think of the theory of the gauge theory
leaving out here
there is indeed the fifth dimension but that's really nothing else than the energy scale
at which you are looking at the system there are no new degrees of freedom
as you move in about and that's how it's called holographic somehow the whole theory
is defined as the bunbury and by moving in you're just changing your energies here
so of course very fascinating for theorists correspondences in the sense gives a very different
way of thinking about energy scales and renormalisation and so on
but you may ask of course
you should always ask what is it really good for
the can we do something with his
so here are the three
things which i think one could say want this question first of all what can
use it to solve the strong coupling large n limit of certain gauge theories
combined with
methods of integrability some very powerful methods of two dimensional integrability one is actually close
almost solving completely for some quantities the larger limit for any type of coupling
four dimensions of seven operators also you transparency for these so far field theorists these
would be an important achievement no we don't know if any
four dimensional gauge theory or field theory at large where can calculate something exactly at
all couplings and it would be of course very interesting for field theories is to
be able to do things
but QCD has any questions three that's far from infinity it also has quarks
force young has no quarks and most importantly as i said it has both strong
and weak coupling energy regime
so it's strongly coupled in the infrared in the interior of the state space a
user strong coupling but it is is weakly coupled asymptotically free in the UV region
which correspond to going on
so what we have is definitely not very similar to UCB and there is i
think still a very long way to go
there are some situations one situation the which is the quark gluon plasma were
even in very rough qualitative model could be of help because there's nothing else you
can use
there is no interference
and the reason is that the lattice gauge theory is basically of very little use
if you want to do out of equilibrium real time calculations one doesn't really know
how to do them by using lattice gauge theory which is in a very
since i came in the field but a lot of the advances that came in
the first ten years of that and i think a lot of what we're doing
is dotting i's and crossing t's at the moment so i worry that we're becoming
a bit too obsessed magical formalisms and this is the reason why that can be
a problem so this is really stupid idea that aerodynamically a bumble bee can't fly
and then the answer is well the bumblebee doesn't know that only he flies through
the force of heart or something like that
obviously that isn't it i mean dynamically bumblebee can fly you can see obama we
flying you can see examples of all the time so what does this mean it
means the mathematical formalism you're using to model what happens aerodynamically does not apply in
these case
it applies to jet aircraft it applies to jumbo jets
it applies to fighter jets but it doesn't apply
two other the bumblebees doing so it's clearly a limitation of the model
rather than the fact now the problem is you can get these two things confused
because the first thing you do is you say well this is the situation in
real life i can't model everything in that sort of mathematical idealisation of study that
but then you can spend so long study that the when you actually look back
at the situation in real life usage itself
the impossible things that things that happen are impossible and we hear examples of that
things like well it's impossible for human vision problem is impossible because of the curse
of dimensionality well problem is impossible because you're doing all the time it's difficult but
we which just doing it wrong when we do
on computers and we see advances in that direction as well so i think it's
very dangerous to get lost in pure mathematical
formalisms because you forget that there are things going on that humans can do for
example that we want to recreate and that's why this link you know i think
that is really
interesting example that it's not good reason so
statisticians will tell you that you can't fool
here's things that also statisticians will say this that you can't infer causality from data
and i think for any statistics it was quite important that this concept existed but
you know
why humans have the a concept of causality then if you can infer from data
mining data is just what we see and doing causality is a really important aspect
of that so you can get a little bit lost if you start proving these
things in demonstrating these things
and lose sight of what's actually really going on and what you really want to
so mathematical foundations are very important though they help us understand the capabilities of our
algorithms and i think the
you know this is why this summer schools important because you have to actually keep
in touch with both of these things
it's really hard now i think to come in machine learning as an undergraduate well
as graduating undergraduate as a graduate student compared to how it was when i came
in so when i came in
the mass you need to know was very complex thing known as the chain rule
and you need to know that to derive an advance algorithm known as back propagation
i still use the chain rule it's still quite useful there
i do an enormous number of other things and you know when i think about
what i'm trying to get my students to do
and what i expect them to know quite quickly and it is far more than
i knew when i came into machine learning in terms of say linear algebra
probability theory
in other areas should be talking about functional analysis is very complicated that makes it
tough because i don't think it's the case that the undergraduate programs pushing people further
than they used to so there is a steep learning curve to come into machine
learning but it's important that people know that
well that's all resentments not point humans give us inspiration to go beyond these mathematical
formalisms so it's important that we don't get lost in the more advanced mathematics that
would you doing i mean sometimes i think some in the computer science department but
sometimes i feel it would be more appropriate to been applied maths problem because you
know i don't see much difference between of applied mathematicians are doing what we do
the main difference is that we consider a broader range of problems and it takes
me a lot longer to work out the mast and some applied mathematicians
OK so
back to this question statistics so any statistics had really what statistics about an early
statistics nothing you have to understand its origins he was different from machine learning and
they had great success with this idea of a statistical proof and i think this
is a really important concept you mustn't forget this concept but one must also ignore
it as well in some sense in terms of looking to the future because there
and it's done so
there's a question i compute the mean of two tables of numbers which is the
statistic right so
that's what baseball statistics like and that's what it's really about studying statistics there are
different does this prove anything does this mean anything and this is what people are
interested in their social scientists early social scientists they were measuring poverty in manchester comparing
to poverty in london and saying is the poverty different they didn't want to use
models they just wanted to sum up numbers compute on
so the answer would depend on what statistics discoveries it depends on how those numbers
are generated with a randomized and what big difference how big the differences between these
these two numbers
that led to hypothesis testing but this is really restrictive because the questions you could
then ask about your data that you can answer the statistical proof are really really
limiting what's really interesting is people actually think that that's not onto what people think
the philosophy of science is so if you work in biology people will tell you
are your
what's your hypothesis but then it's a hypothesis they mean what's your simple question that
you can answer the statistic pop he's not talking about that he talked about hypothesis
is much more complex things that often you could not answer the simple statistics so
that can never really limiting effect on science as well but there were many successes
in this and there are things that we we take
for granted today the fact that we fertilize crops correctly the fact that you can
get consistently brewed beer
right you know they couldn't do that before statistical tests were invented invented statistical test
to do that but there are many open questions we've already mentioned one causality so
that is to say in a given at
OK so each electron has a distinct set of quantum numbers 1st important idea so
you can think of each electron is having its own social security number or IP
address or something so that's important so we once we've chosen a certain mix of
an element as it's used ones for that particular and that's the 1st point the
2nd point of the Aufbau principle is just energetics
electrons will occupy orbitals in order of descending energy
occupy the lowest-energy 1st end up but clearly this an LMS sequence is different from
the energy sequence once we get beyond that to 3 so there's something else going
on so let's talk about the electrons electrons fill orbitals electron electron still orbitals from
the lowest
of energy to
2 highest energy
but there's a there's some there's a wrinkle here and that is that the energy
levels themselves
change with electron occupancy and as you go higher and higher levels those energy levels
as you saw in the case of hydrogen the energy levels work more closely spaced
the differences between those energy levels are becoming smaller and smaller as the end number
rises and what the
2nd point of of is that as the electrons begin to fill those levels the
differences in energy may shift so that an unoccupied states certain levels may be in
the inverse order from how they are in the occupied state so we have to
recognize this lowest energy the highest energy and the function of occupancy seamlessly few examples
of kind so that's the 2nd part of the island of the principle and the
3rd 1 talks about the question of
the generously and it's called the 100 points it talks about
the generous on the final generosity generously areas where you have or orbitals of equivalent
energy how do we put electrons into
such as system orbitals of the equivalent energy we strive to strive for unpaired electrons
strive for unpaired electrons what do I mean by that let's give a simple example
of a simple example is the 1st look at the carbon if we look at
carbon carbon and if you look at the periodic table you'll see this notation x
2 carbon 1 s 2
to ask you 2 p 2 OK so what we learned here this 1st number
here it gives the value of
and so this tells me that this is n equals 1 and S S is
this lowercase notation that the spectroscopy used in place of
the L number so this is an acid so s according to spectroscopy means that
l equals 0 n equals 1 l equals 0 and the superscript 2 is an
indication of the electron occupancy so in plain English this says that there are 2
electrons in the 1 s orbital and then we can continue this is 2 electrons
in the 2 s orbital and there are 2 electrons in the 2 p orbitals
another way of displaying this is a box notation so here's 1
if you like k shall here to ask
L shell and then there's stupidity and we know from over here in the 2
p has the possibility of 3 different about and numbers so as I showed you
last day that this is 1 case where trying on a Cartesian space makes sense
and equals 1 0 minus 1 indicates the 3 principal coordinate directions and the people
refer to these as the 2 p x orbital the 2 p y orbital and
the 2 p z orbital so now let's fill
the orbitals let's occupy the orbitals and we're going to use the palace seclusion principle
and we're going to use the fact that we feel from lower energy to higher
energy so we go 1 go spin up and the other goes spin-down why spin
up and spin down because the 4th quantum number is S and Power says no
we will do that
in a few weeks
ourselves in a two
in nineteen seventy nine which was the year that
maxwell died
the german physicist helmholtz
one of his students hertz
it was twenty two years at the time he was a junior
try to demonstrate that radio waves indeed exists
birds declined because he argued that the
equipment that was available at the time of
not good enough
seven years later when new
equipment had been
developed accepted the challenge
it took in two years
i was able to demonstrate that radio waves
imagine what victory that was
someone like maxwell who predicts
out of nothing that radio waves should exist
you come someone who actually shows that they do exist
died five years after
he was thirty seven years old he was very young
and he live ten more years there's no doubt in my mind
he would have been awarded with the nobel prize for physics with the first nobel
only given in nineteen o one
he died just a little bit too early
next also died very young
h forty eight
why did maxwell call that trains
displacement current
in the presence of the dielectric before the dielectric in there
changing electric fields
real in the course of the current
in between the plates
because the polarisation will change all the time you get to rearrange rearrangements
of these induce charges or indeed
a current
but in vacuum
there shouldn't be any career
any electric field
changing or not changing and of course the current
in vacuum
i believe the vacuum
you know when behaves like any other dielectric just special dielectric happens to be a
dialectic with kappa equals one
and so he really believe
that there was an actual current going
the plates even though we now know of course that is
not the case
so the name displacement current
well perhaps not very
lucky ones
but the term
is a must
and it completes
the theory of electricity and magnetism
the name is obviously of no consequence after all
shakespeare set itself in rome we'll gillette
what's in a name
that which we call a rose by any other name would smell as sweet
those were the words
by shakespeare
i will abandon for now
the displacement current but we will revisit later
when we will be always radio waves
and with the propagation
of electromagnetic radiation
i return out
the good old power
and i will return
generators that ran our economy
we've discussed this at length
and i want to revisit that you
with you
remember that if you
i rotate
conducting look
the magnetic field
you create
induced EMF
and that keeps our economy going
is again
one of those loops
conducting wire
i don't care about the action of the magnetic field that you want to this
way that's fine
what matters is
and we're going to rotate about its axis
every rotate about its axis
we're going to get an induced EMF
and then use the method
which we derive
i think it will last lecture
as a function of time
will be assigned sort of or cosine could sort of curve
and therefore
will look something like this
i call this world number one
so this is the math
produced by the number one
i'm going to add
two more no
which are not
electrically connected
physically separate
if you look from this direction
you will see the following
this would be the number one
because you're looking in this direction you would only see
conducting wire like so
i have now second one which is rotated hundred and twenty degrees
so in this picture
you will see it like so
the number two
and this
on the the twenty degrees
physically on the twenty degree rotation
and then i was one which is again one of the twenty degrees rotated
like so
so this angle
there's also a hundred and twenty degrees
i agree
which is the main classes
of MCMC
agra is
they is i
tried to
in two years yesterday night
is that by using a markov chain
you can do
just as well as
importance sampling or accept reject
if you can produce a markov chain
is that
to the distribution of inter terest
so here it is target distribution f
and you want to book in into for instance all you need to do
is constructing markov chains that is ergodic
and therefore converges
two have and serum
e there to tell you that the empirical approximation
to this integral
in the convergence is to mayor
so again
if you want to have this idea of of of using a markov chain with
stationary distribution f
we can use it in many ways
most naive way
is to say that
we have such a markov chain if we take xt
forty large enough
xt converges to f xt not
fourteen at large
will be roughly
distance from a very bad idea because
we need to have the chain converging
we don't know too large
we should take
and the say and say that even if we can manage
the right to not
we have to do it all over again if you want to say point that
you see me for
so this is that
but on the other hand
most monte carlo
all the point is not
and so we can use the whole change for monte carlo approximation
can we will never
get back to this idea because it is this
about eighty
the that version of it is called perfect sampling
and this is one of the last chapters
in notes but over time
to talk about it
of course you can read
here is the idea we minute to put the idea into practice
the is
to find a way to build
markov chain
which has
the target
distribution as the stationary distributions is of course the point
we need to go over
the idea of the metropolis hastings algorithm to use instead
it's it's a and using the wrong
distribution to get to the right distribution so many years
instead of
f as
the target
distribution we choose
conditional distribution
thirteen of the markov camels
q of y given x that is
almost totally arbitrary
that we have have the choice of
and one is q
so this transition
would simulate from this transition kernel
and because are not using a camel that is a series f
we just picked
whatever can
we wish to
to see it from
i don't think it is
and it
we collect for the wrong choice of kernel
by adding to the simulation
and acceptance step
that is we y from q of y given x but we want to go
two f
as the stationary distribution
and therefore sometimes accept y and sometimes we reject one
and rejecting what it means that the markov chain doesn't change value so x t
plus one
the next step in the markov chain takes the same numerical value as xt
so the markov chain goes from xt two xt plus one by either picking
the new similarity value that has been generated from this
conditional distributions
all staying where it is and the whole
thing that
that make the algorithm works is only the right choice
the acceptance probability
OK if you write the acceptance probabilities that way
that is for y and x values
o f of x the current value divided by q one argument or q x
given y
this choice of acceptance probability
this necessarily
producer markov chain with stationary distribution f of the see in one or two fly
the point is that this is one of the most universal
in the sense that
so far i have no restrictions
on q
and still it produces a markov chain with stationary distribution
so the
a few remarks
on this algorithm
as that is there is
my name is
of this ratio in one
so in this ratio is larger than one
the ability to accept is one and therefore we always move
this new values
if should think that as an exploration agreement of this kind of distribution
for the distribution is always go up here
if this value is larger than this value
this will have meaning in the special case
well i think that if you propose the values that is totally irrelevant for your
target distribution you don't even
you go there because if ever y zero the probability of moving there
and thing that is related to this time the simulation algorithm is that because you
have the ratio
of as
and the ratio of cues
you don't need to know the normalizing constant therefore it is complicated and is missing
the normalizing constant this doesn't matter
for the implementation of this algorithm
the invented that although
we think of xt something that is roughly
coming from the distribution
and the sequence you don't have an i i d sample from after because x
is a markov chain and in particular
because of this stage where we accept or reject
because you can reject means that xtlx plus one can be the same
and you can have sample with identical values
several in a row
the the last point is totally and in the article
it is the fact that y two itself is not
markov chain in most cases
what people thought of this idea of
using actually physical process as the basis of a random physical process is the basis
of the random numbers may be some sort of thermal noise in a resistor or
radioactive decay or what have you you can imagine that if you're going to store
the number in a computer with say thirty two bits
you can say are the first bit toss the coin and if its heads around
one and a half the point again it's tails iwriter zero and you do that
thirty three times and you have your
thirty two bit number
and then if you were to divide that by the maximum possible number that you
could store in thirty two bits
that would give you a random value between zero and one
and that would work that would be fine
that would be very slow and some people don't do it that way so people
use instead are deterministic computer algorithms deterministic in the sense that if you were to
actually run the algorithm over again you would generate exactly the same sequence of random
so you think well that's that's no good that's not random and deterministic but actually
they are just as good as they could it would certainly look random and for
all and to all of the purpose is that we are going to use them
for they behave as if they were random
and in fact there are better than random because you want to be able to
reproduce the sequence because when you're you're doing monte carlo calculation very often you find
some sort of unexpected behavior and you want to be able to try to reproduce
that so it's very convenient in fact to be able to rerun the algorithm and
to reproduce the exact same random looking sequence over again sometimes people call these therefore
pseudo random numbers instead of random but for our purposes there are just as good
as random or better
OK so actually write a computer algorithm that does this efficiently and it produces really
random numbers that
ah behave as if they were truly random that's difficult but it's fairly simple to
to give a sample algorithm that is
almost as good and illustrates all the main points and so there's one called the
multiplicative linear congruence shield generator
so this initial and sub-zero
two n one n two and so forth and so you get a sequence of
numbers and then those
that sequence will have some maximum value and then at the end of the day
divide the numbers in this sequence by the maximum
and that gives you a sequence of numbers distributed between zero and one so here's
the way the the rule works you get there
i plus one element of the sequence from the i th element in the sequence
according to this formula you take and so by a new multiply by
some number a called the multiplier
and then you take that modulo n where
m is is constant called the modulus
right now this
mod operator is the remainder so what you do is you take the integer division
of whatever's before divided by whatever is after and then you take the remainder so
for example twenty seven mod five that would be too
because the remainder is two
so so that's the rule that's the rule that tells you how to get and
i plus one from and survive
and it will produce a sequence of numbers
now there's a catch
and this catches is characteristic of all of these algorithms that are used to produce
a pseudorandom numbers and that that is that the sequence is periodic
so you think periodic how can that be you want these things to behave as
with as if they were random what if they follow some period then that's no
good at all we simply need the period to be very very very long and
you only use a subset of the sequence that lies well within a single period
so here is just to illustrate how that works if you look at the example
from this book i mentioned yesterday by one
a very very nice chapter on how these methods work
now let's just to take for illustrative purposes multiplier of three and the modulus of
normally you would take those numbers to be very very large OK but here just
for illustrative purposes let's pick them small
i think the and zero equal to one
all right so therefore in one is equal to
three times one month seven what's that three months seven three
so then here and two is nine mod seven is two
while the law we get down to some six is fifteen mod seven which is
but that's where we started with so at that point the sequence will simply repeat
right now that's a outrageously short period you would never use a random number generator
that can only generate you know half a dozen random values
so what you need to do is you need to pick something larger which i
think i have in the next overhead
well so first of all as i mentioned before you divide by the maximum value
which are turns out to be essentially equal to the modules and and those with
then uniform between zero and one
and you then have to ask other random
so what you do is you pick the multiplier and the modulus so that these
are so by pass various tests of randomness and there's software packages that you can
use the will detect whether or not the you the distribution is uniform and also
whether or not there are any correlations between pairs of random values so here for
example this in this paper by like we a he suggests using a equals forty
thousand six hundred ninety two and some big number for m is a bit of
black magic involved here but what you get is is a distribution that indeed is
very uniform between zero and one and here is a scatterplot of neighbouring values in
the sequence and here you see this is essentially there is no evidence of any
sort of correlation between the neighbouring pairs that's what you want
now this is a very simple algorithm that in fact is not very very widely
used you know in the root package there's this class called t random and there's
the generator called t random three
which is based on what's called the mayor sent twister algorithm which is an amazing
and it has a period of two to the almost twenty thousand
which is like ten to the six thousand and if you think about it that's
an astronomically that's not even an astronomically large number is only what's an astronomically large
number like ten to the seventy s
protons in the universe
you're talking about ten to the six thousand so there's absolutely no danger you're ever
gonna like run over the period and have repeat just could never happen
so so if you use random number generators you should use to random three you
might ask yourself how can this has had a long period what here
but called
let's call why star that winter here
X star the winter here so I'll sort of introduce the notation starved for that
optimizes the best
then what someone might stop is still get to some X . you don't know
that it's extra yet you look around but everywhere you look is worse
ah yes yes this is the this is the minimum cost so I mean that
that the fact that this is this the the this quantity that you're trying to
maximize when you do it
equals this quantity that in this other problem you're trying to minimise well you're and
actually ask yourself what's the relation between these from
so must be proved right away
weak duality which with what's what's always easy and these problems
it is to show that the maximum
it is always below the minimum
maximum in 1 problem that that looks good the right Max was a real man
but this is the maximum in the dual
is always less regular minimum in the prime we can show that right off the
bat just from taking to to steps along the way
but there was a different problems so as not to surprising and then uh
and mandatory serious duality thing is that actually when you're this quantity you're trying to
maximize hygiene it'll go
and you call this quantity here trying to minimize this cost down as low as
0 they
and then you know you've got the answer
pass each other according to this symbol at the latest through so that the maximum
in the dual for a here so this
thank you xxx
I want to show that this quantity C transpose X is I want to show
that C transpose X is always
less or equal to speak the transforms what for for any for any allowable extra
for this is for any allowable X and Y so the normal yes maybe now
maybe have let's see what is that I'm just gonna reversed here's the thing I'm
maximizing right the key thing I'm maximizing sorry
take that off the OK The is B transpose Y that's the quantity that I
maximize so I
foreshadow up but it doesn't matter
any that's acceptable
will be below 0
In the cost of many exits except thanks and now
that's for for for any acceptable any official I use the right word feasible x
and y
any feasible x and y
this little work OK can we just take it will take that step would say
if if if y is feasible
but the X is the right if x is feasible A X is B right
so I know that is an argument going connect those problems if x is feasible
and a being so this is a taxi transpose Y right
because as a x
now what my
well anytime ICA X transpose like like 1 idea in my head
right it
he started studying the statistical distributions of these patterns
and that didn't go anywhere
but i want to give the talk in the old days of course was overhead
rights like transparency is and so he had a couple of transparency in set one
on the overhead projector and overhead these other transparency one was slightly on top of
the but rotated with respect to it and he noticed that when the when there
was a slight you transformation
some interesting visual effects started to appear
so i kind of simulated that what happened in this experiment were part of the
random dot patterns
as i move my mouse
i'm changing the scaling of
so basically matrix multiply operation on the random dot pattern but i'm doing it with
the scaling or contraction on the x or y axis and rotation some superimposing two
random dot patterns
and one of the things he observed is
you can basically get all of the different flow fields that you see from you
two the left of ordinary differential equations just by changing the scaling and rotation because
it's basically a flow field so this is just a little interactive application here
for doing these kinds of things in this kind of fun to play with
so i just found the
the mouse events here
this transformer class
well i find i can connect to the button press event
and i i register some called axon sort of a standard event handling model we
have a lot of examples like that
but i'll show you
basically the simplest how that would work
one two three
so canonical figure
going define a little function in my hometown show called on press
i said my history so that's going to speed up speeding up a little bit
one of the mouse president gone
the event to tell me what actually event occurred over what the x and y
and display coordinates and what the x and y into indeed according to the connect
to that event
to the motion notify events called on press is probably not the best name basically
when the
i think it detects motion these events are going to fire off
so as you go over through here you can actually your y coordinates in data
you x and y coordinates and display spaces i move out of the axes i
don't have data corner system anymore so i'm only you can see the
the pixel coordinates are still registering but there is no data according
so that's fairly easy to do
um and i'm just going to disconnect that event
what really is cool though is we're using matplotlib is
event handling mechanism so we support
four five six user interface toolkits gtk
city qwx pis on qt qt for cocoa on mac OSX native rendered so all
of these different
back in the math lib support our models they translate go events into our framework
so you can take these
for example here
this transformer class at the very end i call pipe plant
script here
but i can just take these two i have another piece of code here called
class starts
and i have this
wx application
we were very simple double the application
and just
make some simple lines and you can see the wx because we have these two
different figures and had
the environment here
so that there is nothing about pylab app ipod and sister to wx application
what we do is just going to grab this little piece of code here
this transformer bit
the goal my wx
tim played which is the one i just ran for you
i'm going to go to the power plants that line
comment that l
important transformer module that i was just showing you
pace in this little snippet of code is called ax one here right
on the justice instantiate with annexes instances does everything else self
every year on this thing
now just based on this for example
and is fully enabled with user events but president nelson and you can take the
same piece of code and plug it into or QTR so you know give people
the ability to write you know kind of useful little widgets
they don't depend on the underlying really toolkit
so we have some examples in here for last demos and
and the all these years maps of events which many automatically run for you
across a variety of user interface toolkit which is another problem is proliferation of languages
is a professional packages there's also proliferation of user interface toolkit people and developed so
the memory in this case is distributed physically distributed
but logically shared which means what we chose not to the physical memory it's there
we have a single global space
the distributed memory
these are also very popular nowadays
can this
so what happened in the last year that we have gained and scalability
moving the
this was approaches use the in the past and these are approaches used nowadays more
often nowadays
these are possible combination there
architecture classification we described before
but what it's easy to see now it's getting more on the side of distributed
computing cluster using
using distributed memory system
with multiple instruction multiple data
let's keep is OK
and i propose you five
programming model
how do we program part of the system
that as set out by the selected five of them which are
the most useful the most common the use
the first one is the just right out just space
we can think of these
system has a collection of trends
each train has got its own private viable
the prior to just space but there is a shared memory system behind so
we also have public space and these
space is used for communication to exchange information to synchronize
the different rights
programming system like these is exactly the same as programming concurrent to boost concurrent programming
like commodity trading
sequential machine
so if we do market trading
we use the same
program in parallel c so we shared memory space we don't need to go out
anything else
because the system will take care to distribute power treads in different processing
so let's say in this case the parallelism is quite transparent to the programmer
if the programming is using multi trades
message passing
also very popular because
let's say MPI which is the message passing interface is the library now
these freely available
which is the standard
and so on
if you write your code using MPI library your code is portable to any
returning to an systems
these these these programming model is based on a distributed memory
architecture so we have
independent machines
and they
copyright to sort
the problem of exchanging the explicit messages
it's a bit more
a complex than the previous one but this one is there
i is flexibility we can decide has programmers
a piece of the system was called it
seven zero
years ago actually a
he felt that one because of
still as better
features that by
unfortunately in that competition MPI was chosen for understanding
and you will find it for example in global distributions
you know blogs for grid computing MPI is part of the global distribution
data part is another model
these was still used by the disease was very popular for
single supercomputer single system
actually in data parallel
it's very simple
it's very
let's a
elegant and simple because we don't do any explicit programming for them
parallelisation we just
so in that sense the independent components are very well in line with its physiological
and then i will show some results on this
modeling of image and modelling of the visual cortex
so this is something very different from blind source separation
i think people and i see as are certainly not the only ones to develop
models to develop models of the sorry to develop statistical models of image data
because they they are they can be used basically what they very useful for
he's in the most general sense they are used for full bayesian inference
if you know the image is have typically are typically like something that is they
have the same prior distribution then you can use that in different methods of bayesian
inference for example
what you can do is denoising
so assume that you
you have an image and then it is forced to some noise on the image
now if you have a good set is the model of what you need is
really should apply when they have no noise then you can use this in in
bayesian inference actually i can show you what i mean
the formula is actually very simple in this case
so let us assume that we have an image
which is a very high dimensional vector but it's not my
noise and what we assume is only necessary what we all also is only this
so now if we we have
now what you can do is compute the posterior probability
of the original image
and even
distorted image
by the basic probability
the theory of i mean but basically by using the bayesian based formula that will
and probability of
the distorted image
in the original image
times the probability of
the prior probability
of the image
divided by
the probability
well can decide about the probability density so probability so let's say these probabilities
people probability of distorted image
so point is that
well you don't care about this to all
so what you have once you when you know what is the process of
distorted images are nice images from the original images and when you have prior models
of images then you can figure out what is for example the most probable
original image given this distorted image
so this is what image modeling gives you
and this is usually something very simple because for example if we assume that the
noise is an additive gaussian noise then this will be simply the square squared euclidean
distance between the distorted image and the original page so we maximize this you will
be basically
sorry this will be
minus minus
the next exponential
so this will be exponential expansion function of minus the euclidean distance
so you know image is then you want to find
some an image which is as close as possible to the distorted image but at
the same time it has has high a problem prior probability as possible
well basically the sum of the product of maximize
you think
so this this
so this observations of random vectors
the observation so that you can just take the
and that's exactly the same kind of ideas can be used for prediction regression for
example let's say that you have an image and some pieces some missing
for various reasons and you can use the same kind of ideas to infer the
missing pixels
so yes i see and related models are
seems to be quite
useful and i will explain how they are connected to a classical idea what's possible
oh sorry i not expect to get it there
so typically what we typically what people is linear models
all of images using something like a latent variable linear linear latent variable models which
is of course why you easily end up with something like ICA
OK the only obvious when i say these things and you just have to go
along that i actually do really big time right and i have no love for
me and that's why not perfect for teaching this class i had to be erected
more than any other class i taught at stanford in my time here
and that's because each core was that is going to give me a b give
me because there's no better forced to teach programming is just awesome
if you want programming i think there's almost nothing better to do in the world
you have the task trying to get their you're coding you're make stuff happen you're
testing you're already running it comes back around see stuff you build things right you
can when you're done you know works right you know that feeling writing paper like
wasn't good enough the following you could probably go
both run this argument like when you want the works like you know you like
that that was supposed to get the right answer it plays the game solve the
finding and fixing that last part of the body is kind of one of the
aspect of approach we want people moan about i i happen to think that if
you're driven by dividing like most possible detective stories ever right it's like trying to
figure out what happened when you when you do this when you move that y
one this way
and what this effect cause and then they want to make the fake how sexism
staying up late like there and i have stayed up late one night debugging than
anything else in my life and i'm not about that at all
so that means i'm in the right place
hopefully someone that resonate with you
it's a little bit if that only sounds really awful to you hopefully we can
change my little bit but that that is in some ways part of what drives
computer science because this kind of wanting to build things you know we are engineers
right part of the school of engineering right we had this computer science named just
remember any subject name is something science is not science but you know we're trying
to up but but but we do a lot of really great work right and
there are a lot of neat scientific principles and theory that appear what we do
but in the end i think what drives a lot of this is just the
engineering building stuff that is
really need it reminds me that my my happens in mechanical engineering so i used
to be envious because he was building his CVM is a week
total from core you know around the campus people bicycles and stuff like you know
they they build all these things but now having watched all things you don't like
it is really hard actually you know these materials in all these tools millions wavy
hot glue which burns back into fingers touch it and its ability to contribute to
show you need a compiler in a computer he five it's like it's an abstraction
we build our brains and there's is relatively small set of things that you need
to come master and then you can combine them in these very sophisticated interesting ways
to solve all sorts of problems but the kind of the very low overhead and
the range of things you can attack with the same set of skills is huge
like every domain out there can benefit from somebody applying computers and in a useful
way without fail you know there's also the problem for technology is part of the
answer the only answer but certainly something that you can take whatever interest you have
and combine of computer science and construction something call
i think what happened in the second course is amazing that the first cause you
kind of get up to speed and there's a lot of basic material and needs
to get covered and it does kind you on the right path but in this
course actually we really get the blossom beyond the basic things that there's a bunch
of really neat and very successful technique right that second-quarter student can understand and master
and do really cool things with the can learn how to do something like that
created database that has a million entries right and then ask for somebody by name
and be able to instantaneously find that not by looking at a million entries one
by one change the size to make it ten million making billions and still be
able to provide that kind of instantaneous axis you will learn how to do that
right in the technique is not you know some super-human thing is something very clever
admittedly but but it's very accessible taking that's a million thing in we had to
sort it efficiently what if you happen to know things about that's almost sort of
which a little bit of sort other ways you can actually make it even faster
to put in sorted order
there are techniques for example like recursion that take problems that you might not have
any idea when you first look at the problem how to solve but once you
and in matlab code there is only one line change in matlab code for learning
these models going from binary to real value
right and again the conditional probability he's just going is gonna be given by the product of gaussians
right but what you can learn is you can learn these kinds of features a
given you know you're looking at four million unlabelled images
just images random images downloaded from the web
this is the kind of structure that the model is discovering right
and you can see it sort of again and discovers these edges but also discovers interesting things like will colours
and again when i show these things to the neuroscientists they get excited because it
sort of looks will be possible from them
design standpoint
and the way you can think again is again just finds basis find slightly different
basis for four images if i show you a new image
again i can decompose that i can write it as a linear combination of these basis
and these bases again a very useful to have because you can use these basis
to recognize what's going on which is much better than
i just using pixels
now one way to think about these models may be just point this out is if
if you look at the marginal probability probability of the data you can write it as the
this way right
it's the conditional probability times the prior you summing over these latent variables
now what happens is that you can essentially interpret these models as mixture models so
in this case you can interpret them as mixture of gaussians and you're probably familiar
with mixture of gaussians models right
but the beauty of these models you can interpret them as a mixture of exponential number of galaxies
and the way to think about this is that let's say i have
three latent variables
right each one takes value zero one
so if you think about this representation and to the three possible configurations for the eight possible configurations
and it turns out that i can write this model
as a mixture of eight gaussians
right but with the mean and the covariance is gonna be shared across different subsets of hidden variables
so in particular if typically if i have hundreds or thousands of these latent variables
hidden variables there are two thousand possible configurations
right so you can think about is used to do thousand possible mixture components
so these models are you know in general
for a lot of different problems these models work much better than me should gaussians
you can also apply these models to again modeling other kinds of data so here
you're applying it to modeling count data
this very useful for modeling you know things like web pages text
bag-of-words representation
so here you can think of are you know let's say
you have different words in a document and kate is the vocabulary size
so you know in english
might be seventy thousand city might be seventy thousand and its particular web page might
contain let's say a thousand words would be a thousand here
and again it is defining these models as lights
some changes but roughly then you have these pairwise terms and you have these in terms
so there's nothing difficult of extending these models
the conditional distribution is gonna be given by something called softmax distribution is the distribution
of different words that appear in the document
fairly straightforward and these are the kind of our
latent variables the latent topics that the model is discovering right so again if you
apply to the reuters dataset you know it's sort of figures out that they should
be things like
the russians and then you're then the computers and and such
so what i'm showing and again the way to think about this model is that every single web page document
it is given by some linear combination of these topics as sparse linear combination of
these topics a few topics get activated
and that's how
the data is generated
so finds in interesting thing here is that you know when when you apply these
models to images you find these edges when you apply these models to words
it's sort find these
interesting meaningful topics
this is what it doesn't terms reconstructions
so this was trained on the flickr dataset in the second half of the tutorial
i'm gonna show you more of this
so this is if i if i give them all chocolate intake
i called chocolate intake and look at these distribution with hidden variables and then we reconstruct back the data
you know reckons it reckons for you reconstruct things like take chocolates we deserve cupcake
food sugar cream right so obviously captures some semantic similarity between different words
it's also interesting that's you know this guy flower high
and then the japanese sign that flow high japan's according
know what these mean but there was some talk to right so just picks up
you know these kinds of
you know some of multilabel legal things just by looking at correlations
between different between different words
it's very useful you know including text
the other thing is that you can apply these models exact same all you can apply to modeling
social network data
so this was done on the netflix dataset where you have users
and you have movies
and you can think of just in coding each user preference with the rating pattern
has been here
so you can think of these being multinomial random variables that affect all tell you
whether the user liked the movie they like the more you know the user ratings
twenty five
and the interesting thing about this model is that if you look at the latent
representations that the most discovering is sort of discovering these learned genre
you you know horror movies get grouped together
it's interesting michael moore's movies get grouped together
so just by looking at the patterns of how people
rate movies you can basically figure out
the people really like his movies are they really hate his movies and
actually somebody pointed to me that this is not my goal more is more
but it should be very close i guess i'm curious myself
actually watch that movie
exactly the same kind of model slight modification and then you can apply to are
you know social nets or netflix
product recommendation type of problems
so a lot of these different you can model these different modalities and from machine
learning perspective that's very exciting right
because you can apply and a lot of different domains
one of the beauty behind these models is that you get
it's easy to infer the states of the hidden variables right so if you show
me a particular pattern for a user can quickly tell you what movies is what
he's gonna like oficial mean image i quickly tell you the distributional features oral what
topics that you see in the data
right and that's very important for information retrieval four four classification type of problems
way to think about these models is
just give intuition is that you can think of them as product of expert sometimes
people call these models product of experts
and the way to think about these models is that if i look at the marginal distribution
over the data
it can be written as a product of these terms and sometimes people call them as products
right so unlike traditional mixture models
right we have a product of a bunch of things
maybe i can give you an intuition what that really means
let's say i have these different topics that the model discovering right
if i activate topics
like government corruption and oil
you have put in will have very high probability the history books if i'm gonna
tell you that this document is about government corruption and oil
put in should go up
and this is unlike traditional mixture models
right in the mixture model you pick a topic
and then january word like traditional topic models like
latent dirichlet allocation if you've heard about these these kinds of models so he can
make the distributions very precise because you're taking three different distributions you multiplying them together
and as soon as you take distributions and you look at the intersection you can
be very precise about what you're gonna see in document
what you're gonna see the data
and that's precisely what's going on with with
the second part
the solution has to have a zero from component
so let's look at the second part
since omega strictly monotonic we can do the following reasoning we rewrite this quantity
again we use this of problem decomposition
we can now use pythagoras these two things are no
and since the square root a strictly monotonic function and only got a strictly monotonic
function if we set this thing here to zero we actually decrease the value of
inequality because if and only if is a former part is exactly zero therefore the
objective function from theorem must have the property that the of of part is zero
this is the wrong policy or the only thing we left with is this part
which is an expansion in terms of the training points so the solution must have
such an expansion
and all the islands that you've seen so far fit into this scheme
simply by
thinking about how the cost function in that case the for instance for support vector
classifiers the cost function actually only it's just to sum over
terms that depend
on on these quantities are separate for each i
in this form the regularizers to the quadratic one but you can also do support
vector regression you can
based on maximum a posteriori estimates
which can be identified with support vector machines regularisation networks and you can also the
kernel PCA which may or may i may or may not show you below
in this case we need a slightly more complicated cost function
so that's
well a little bit on
to some further kernel algorithms
so now you seem to have seen regression classification and you've seen the representer theorem
and you can probably imagine that one can
construct a lot more different kinds
so the components of these algorithms always similarity measures
you can think of this as a kernel module
and learning modules of the kernel
and some learning algorithms such as classification regression or something else
the interesting thing about the kernel module is
we have now
seen different interpretations we've seen that the kernel place in several different roles in
kernel methods support vector machines
the first one being
when i introduced kernels informally
i call them similarity measures come some kind of similarity measures usually a nonlinear similarity
so one is that the kernel
induces a representation because i told you if you have such a kernel and if
it is positive definite
then will automatically
correspond to the product in some of the space so this can we induce the
reproducing kernel hilbert space and we've shown that the kernel computes the product in that
therefore using this kind of similarity measure
it is equivalent to saying i'm representing my data in such a vector space such
as the product space and and using
standard product
my similarity measures so in the way
the kernel is therefore also gives you the time representation
and finally i just showed you the representer theorem and show you that if you
have any
the general class of objective functions
so if you have a learning problem which can be cast in this form is
minimized such an objective function with regularizer which is for monotonic function of the norm
in a RKHS
then there
class of possible solutions
takes this form so all possible solutions are
expansions in terms of constituent training points
so therefore
if you want to also parameterized function class
which is being used in learning
so all these three issues are
central issues for machine learning
and one of the appealing things have gone machines is that are all these issues
are treated jointly if you like
let's look at a couple of other algorithms
so that's the random walk problem
we can analyze this a little bit more
another way
looking at this is
to make ourselves
the transition probability matrix
we have shown here multiplied by a hundred
so the chain that running in the top twenty one possible states
and the transition probability if
in a particular state at call and shows it
and if you don't want them
o thing where you are on the
we can now
but this not a simple problem we can actually
and the question one
really what precisely we can say well for any particular duration of the probability distribution
where you will have got its start and end zero
the question but any
starting position
and we can what the probability is where you will have a lot the
this is the answer to at the heroes that's what the probability distribution the answer
is what we do in the location ten year in nineteen seventeen weighs about it
and shown in yellow and blue
this mission was starting out with probability one being in the
more about one in seventy
to start finish
and then after one there
new york is
in these
that means yellow places
in the
you would make impressions
okay so the two steps this distribution
the phrase that's
that's a distribution
and you recognise this
on the
one three three one
i think that's
the both that's
is this one
well one
except the distribution
is one
the one got not one but let me just try to get twenty what will be will come back on
about one or one with the right hand one in blue is a little bit which
but that's the next wrote about triangle the right hand side of it
european is happening
after six iteration seven
like this and i'm going to stop every twenty five
twenty five that's
found that very jaguar
in yellow showing you
it is not enough twenty five
still quite likely have it a waterfall and given that you've made and all the
number of this very likely be all locations
then you even
if you have any chance of being
after that iterations
hasn't changed much if started with seventeen years will very likely to be right and i
you are more likely to be in the middle and the edges and very unlikely to be in
nine and eleven
on the next step on when the ones you want you know
what locations nine and eleven you're very unlikely to be like that
the memory at all and even that
only uses on and even memory whenever it on wall
seventy five iterations
one hundred iterations
so instead of being a hundred and up
you might look at this graph now and again
a few one hundred iterations every time other running around iterations but now the and again
from the middle
and another and then we can do no wrong
and that will be a sample what actually
logic and even
you're not gonna get
right action all numbers
one hundred is quite long enough
even if you start in the middle at hand
and definitely not long after the seventeenth before
you've got much lower than in your own opinion but there are around the
dying and
the they
hundred five
two hundred
okay getting
pretty uniform that's the rock
thank you could be pretty much anywhere
after two hundred
or at bottom say four hundred where we really
is becoming fairly the
and we know there
more influence of that same example if you see it again
but very roughly in this is this is what
this is what you can do in the simplest way to compute these weights
and the simple fact that you have you know this weighted sum of the examples
and that generates you know your weight vector makes it that you can
plugging in you know into this of f of x represents things in these two
different ways
this is an important consequence
this is
you can do it you know you can do it the other way around
if you go into the in that direction if you take the perception representation and
going to the kernel representation it's not that interesting right why would you do that
there might be some computational reason why you want to do that but generally
it doesn't buy you much because you've already computed these phi functions
for example you have the pattern recognition problem you have you know images and you
want to extract features like you know edges corners or a small you know arcs
in these all your phi of x
what is more interesting actually needs to go in the other direction
why is that well because you can define now instead of defining features you just
have a simple similarity measure between examples and known
examples that you have in your database
and similarity measures are very flexible features are OK extracting features will will be doing
that in in one of the class that seem nineteen measures are very powerful because
you can define also similarity measures between objects that are not vectors so you can
define similarity measures between say molecules that are of different shapes and or you can
define similarity measures between between
spoken words that the had are different length and i'm not necessarily easy to represent
as vectors
the interesting thing is that once you have the similarity measure like that you can
go back to the second four
and you may think you know why would we want to go back
well because we can find optimisation algorithms that we learned the problem
in this hopes start in this the phi space
and and optimise in some sense you know the
the the the the way the decision was is performed in that space and you
can do that without explicitly
computing the five
just by the mere fact that you know that you can define the k as
the fight and phi can be can remain implicit and find some cases can even
have infinite dimension so this is you know the so-called kernel trick that will be
hearing a lot about i think in
these two weeks in order to derive many kernel method algorithms
so what is the kernel also kernel is a similarity measure it's the dot product
in some space
and sometimes you don't know what the spaces the fire present unknown so here couple
examples of kernels
the gaussian kernel just computes the euclidean distance between two vectors
and the exponentially it's the this the square it so it's what it does is
that if you have an unknown example
it puts kind of the hat around it them
now take take an example to training example
and the key is you see two represents the unknown example
well the known example then the hand axes is and as is the unknown example
then as you go away from the known example
the k of of in t
case so this is what i explained you before that
as you go away
from the centre of the kernel there is the decay so you're going to be
able to use this kernel
two to vote and the voting power of the given pattern is going to be
less and less as you go away from the unknown example
but you have other kernels that i'm not like that not centred and decaying but
you can use the same type of learning algorithm and this is the case of
the put kernel and he because the weird shape you just just for the the
the dot product then you raise it to a given power so without going into
detail because you'll see that in other classes
using this kernel allows you to perform function which instead of being a linear function
is appalling and we'll function for number of with aspect to the inputs
and one last learning machine i would like to mention is the one second last
is not in which you just combine many neurons you put them you stack them
you know in in the structure
well you know there is one layer of neuron that is going to be the
input of another layer of neuron originally the not only are percent from was
designed to solve the so-called chessboard problem in which people showed that people understood that
when you have two classes that are arranged in this chessboard way
you cannot separate them with a single
linear decision boundary but if you have two
you know decision boundary then you can make a perfect separation
which is the how comes in the idea of of stacking several layers of these
well linear decision boundaries
now yet another important class of decision functions comes from tree closely fires
so it's very different from from the rest of what i've been explaining to you
so far but i cannot do without mentioning it
here and in no way representing again the same scalar plots in each box right
and so the way decision classify tree classify as work is that there are going
to try
progressively to
separate examples along
of the feature space so this is one feature one input for example the age
of a patient and here the weight of a patient in the other direction
and the different coloured dots represent two populations
for example you know the healthy and the diseased patients off with for the first
the first threshold threshold on feature f two you can pretty well separate the two
but if you get some things wrong here
in the overall functional class in the villages but actually have to spend a very
long time to figure out what's going on
the questions so far
so for instance protein interaction networks
something that you can overlay
in addition to all of this stuff
what happens then is that you've got
data from different entities of different types we might have missing information because you usually
if you know how to different proteins interact you have a pretty good idea what
they might actually do right
you might actually have this information only in parts
well actually get a little bit later to that in the context of
what you could call data fusion
this is actually one of the most exciting areas
if this is what you want to know about you spot on
this is pretty much
i guess what's happening in
conferences like UAI ICML nips where people actually and i seem be where people actually
worry about bringing start from different types together how to build good models
and a lot of that is
well good engineering it's sometimes a lot of experience
has something to do with statistics but at at the end of the day you
need to make it good
in that case biologically motivated model of how you think those
things interrelated
so for instance here a reasonable model might be that if substrings are similar
probably they do something similar
is that actually means to
similar sequences of proteins
and you can build a fairly good estimators based on that
so here the graph
that would actually be
i guess it actually would be a protein interaction model
another thing that you need to worry about
is missing there
it's not
a lot of data happens to be very well prepared
this is usually what you start out with
once you start working on real problems
you will realize that actually quite often you don't have all the above all the
well why is this so well sometimes in the measurement device fails
for instance if you have a cheap consumer camera
i mean OK you take a picture and you wouldn't notice it but quite often
some of the pixels of
so why don't you notice it because the camera manufacturer has used sneaky trick and
just interpolated the values from the adjacent pixels
into that pixel is missing
well why would they do that will simply because they want to throw away the
so what they've done is actually very very simple algorithm for
estimating missing variables
in an image
another example might be
so you have an microarray analysis experiment
and sometimes actually creating the substance that using analyse it can take years
let's say you will deny right
u for substance substance onto your i
well then just because some may be something went wrong when you wash theory in
which so there may be a few corners where the results are quite that good
well obviously you cannot go back to the biologist and say well sorry we screwed
up in the
in the experiment can use when another you getting that that substance again well
they will come back to you right
so you will have certain
genes whose expression is missing
you actually need to do analysis with that
there are various ways how you can deal with it
OK so the simplest way how you can deal with this is a simple mean
you think this is really tough to know you just take the average over all
the other pixels that you've seen
useful plant been
so actually on the camera people do something slightly smarter they just take the adjacent
not the average pixel value that we would have
it turns out that if you do this
i just try how well estimated forms
very close to being as good as having full
verbal information
so it's really frustrating if you want to design an algorithm which works better on
missing variables because you know
just in the simple mean imputation almost gets you to
the full results and then you know
you design a very complicated algorithm to get a slight improvement this can be extremely
just try simple mean imputation and only if that doesn't work
there's something fancier
the other thing maybe that sometimes measuring things can actually be very expensive
so let's say you're sick you go to see a doctor well what the doctor
is going to do first is he's going to talk to you
why is it going to talk to because that's pretty much the cheapest way of
actually of getting some data
the second thing is going through the is statement take attempt to measure blood pressure
and all that
well why
because these are very cheap measurements there might not be
the most effective measurements in order to diagnose
maybe the most effective way would be to just sticking to come into the cities
but that will cost thousands of dollars
therefore he actually in this case we have a process whereby he would go and
measure things might reformulate you have policies measure again
it has to
that's that actually
consumer more complicated so
maybe in and they will actually be talking about that within in the context of
game theory
are you going to talk about that and
not really OK sorry
so the other thing that could happen is that the bot is simply censor
for instance let's say
you are somebody to
well find information about some product asymmetric wilson and outside of the on the road
and you ask your question there
now the trouble with this is
the type of people who will actually stop and answer the questionnaire are not going
to be a representative sample of the population
so for instance seriously busy managers
well probably not stop
and people might not even give you the right answer
i mean maybe some people would be running around on the street at three PM
so maybe you'll find essentially students and housewives
you will have
the function has shifted in all direction
use your hands
all things in this election
o think it in this direction
but in this direction
so we'll see
also here
was doing
moving with speed v in that direction
now we're going to evaluate website
what happened
we now look
the function
a little less than later in time the length time
it has moved in this direction
it's moving
you can look through the meaning of this equation
you now understand why when i wiggle here
why this string had no choice
it must propagate
function that i generated and must propagate that
with the speed
square would have to define new
we derive the speed of propagation for that string
u is the mass per unit length
these tensions
if i ask you is obvious that the high tension gives you a higher speed
obvious to me
sort of not quite except that
is it obvious if i new large that i make it very thick
very heavy
that the propagation speed is lower
now they know the answer i was so it's quite obvious
but it's not so something
in any case we have derived two things
we had the right that there is such a thing as the speed that we
even have the right
the speed itself schroeder of the overview
so if we had done the experiment again with a high attention
oppose would move fast
something else that we have to explain
why on earth is mountain coming back as value
and why is that the coming back
this amount
that now
is the result of boundary conditions
some people
who have lectured at o three make a very simple state
they say
eight o three is only about two things
this equation
boundary conditions and all the rest follows
by that year
so we have the industry
because our
was the end
that's when he calls
what correctly
and we know that and
must stay a fixed
cannot move
put the line the
what is
this is the
and my post came in
this at the polls
and then evaluate them all the time
that this part of the world
just nicole
ready for that
so this part
and the part that
you to have
i have to make it a little bit to make it look like
little steeper
knows what happened is that
nicole knew very well
but this point cannot move
she very sneakily
without telling you need
oppose that came back to me
we make sure that all moments in time
this points to still so at this very moment in time she must have generated
the polls
which had this
displacement so that this part
exactly the same this sort of
but you must have done that at every moment in time
he must then that when this part arrived with this part arrived in this part
arrive when that part arise
so that means you must have generated
a poll on her side
that is of value
that now looks like this