and different filter designer might come along and say well the filter you want is
what we want
it is not going to be optimal in l two what measure would be
another possible measure use
how can i measure this error one way is to measure its energy l two
but another measure of the areas
it is the max difference right
so the biggest
because triple there is killing us
and the max norm
so the man in the maximum norm
this would be no as we have a much higher
this gives a number which is
known to
actually it's interesting i
gibbs first paper is papers on this on his own phenomena
like the first papers about the page and a half
he gets it wrong
he invested
and then
six months or so later
of course a a correction was published
there has only about ten lines
where he says i just missed it there and then it tells us
that goes up here and tells us what the number is
it's some integral or something we find it
two any number of places
so it's sort of these
you know it's the most famous of the phenomenon in signal processing
in a tiny tiny paper there was a correction to
quite sure
if we looking at the max error
we want to
reduce it there
at the cost of raising there so we can reduce the reduce it there but
but then the report die office for
and what's the optimum
we're looking at max
equally report
so that the optimal
the max norm
frequency is
we report
what is we report
i mean that the graph a polynomial of degree two hundred it's got two hundred
and they all have the same height
i guess in magnitude i can't go below zero here
so that's it we report filter and that
now how would you find the coefficients
for that one
so now this is this page hundred we report
it's not so easy
you're looking for the polynomial that
even automatically clear that there is one that has equal height ripple
all along
of course there's got to be in error here actually take to get anywhere we
really have to allow ourselves a little space
between the end of the past and the start
stop so let me
so if i gave this
these numbers to matlab
matlab would want to numbers the matlab
so what's the matlab command
and as i think because it
it is this guy's algorithm
parameters start and will be the matlab command
which would
so what i do
you would tell
omega p
don't make s
so you inputs would be amazing if he
and omega as
and you could import
one hundred
stop s first stop
what your choice
it some distance here
the more distance you give it
but easier
the design problem
the lower the lower the reports that the closer you can come to ideal if
we fix the degree
if if i if you're asking this polynomial to rebel and then get down like
mad rebel again if you
titan that that will
i don't have
the general solution of the hand
such situations
it is
as of four one one against one
this is a
is why is
OK all so we said something about these people get so you four
for the labelled as this data is really associated with is that you can define
minus levels
in the old days for a lot of other
classifier which is which are related to you
to this day the prediction is random
so we all know these things using this one so when it is put into
these decision function two
then the prediction is somehow like random prediction
so in the end the true case can minus levels
and for all other cases make a k divided by him OK divided by two
something like this
so it is this that can minus one ceased to get true gives correct prediction
that's the way how how this works
this is a
well as this is called
o thing
both the
problem and trying to find a good source of energy
that's why the actually hard quantities this we using this try to
you can use decision as that
but this is more like to of doing that whether or not there those some
research work
how to
how want to list all these kind of things
but in practice you really would like to do prediction this misfolding
already works quite well
what i
this one
o thing
one of the problem that the probability of the positive problem
so here
but as of deletion anything about probability of it's so hard to generate probability of
for is is an
so it's just is a whole other a whole different issue but some research on
the web
OK so the first thing is you
you need to generate the probability of rules for the two classes situation so you
mention that OK so you know i only had two classes how to generate the
probability outputs so was produced the state using the first could as possible probability you
in a second place
of course that must be related to PCA invectives
lin lin that
now we are doing you know for example one against terrorists were one against one
so hopefully combine
those probability values for any four
very two classes yes as soon as a whole estimates for four
for k classes as the average
what is going to be very complicated in this talk about that here
you can see for more information
for more details
support vector machines
we use more complicated forms
so this is one is that
so this is different from one against the rest or one against one
we're trying to directly extend
the SVM optimisation problem
two multi class c
that's the idea
so instead of using only one big about
now we can make a big difference
so we have this summation over from one to k
so each one is for one place in the important part is full of it
this inequality is politics is actually
a whale in one against the rest into an optimisation for
so why
he's true to exactly as well training so we know the true class label of
four this a nice i
and if we multiply we see
the w
as of the true class they should be going
then they use when we multiply it
it we
the about all other labels
so if are using the first past this is w one
so w one times
it i should be with the article about the full extent examples also called w
three six
of things
so this is actually
similar to one against the rest
you want to learn the of the true colours of true class label is greater
or equal to one of a
of using other labels
and we also need bicycle wheels by a large so so that's why we have
these simulations of top transport stop
we also because they variables of suicide it is the penalty parameter
so this looks good
this problem the problem is this is going to be more complicated optimisation problems
OK OK i stress the number of training data
in the case the number of classes
so why is that
is a village feast on
we i then we
so the exciting was just one hundred who one residential until one returning
so that's all the time so that he
quality is for each data instance therefore the number of total quality here is k
so we can also derive the dual optimisation problem because we want to sell to
so we can have
so we can derive b
that's only when we derive the
maybe this is still very off the sizes
it is the number of training data and there is also a member of inequalities
in the primal SVM
one of the interesting range
OK so the question is the overall assumption i made on pretty much
page one of this lecture was that encoding decoding for the error correcting code
around the noisy channel is something we separate
from the system the compression and decompression and i said it is conventional to do
this and the question is is this optimal or could it be better to have
a combined compressor encoder and i can combined decompressor to compressor and decode and
it's very conventional to do things this way to completely separated because people didn't perceive
to be an advantage nevertheless there do exist
some codes of the type that you have in mind so for example if your
source is the bent coin
then there is a single encodings
for distance in the car i neil actually neil's in radford neal who've been hearing
a lot in one calendar things and there is a single decoder that simultaneously effectively
does compression and error correction for the binary symmetric channel so your idea
is conventional tall but there does exist the solution of exactly that for the binary
symmetric channel all the gas in channel a variety of simple channels you can use
the name encodes and
it is possible to make combined systems and you can reach the shannon limit with
with those interiors were
i've shown you several codes and i told you they get within one the three
which might sound really good and i'm showing you how to make it and then
the question is are we done is that
compression is that all you need to know and there's several reasons why this doesn't
wrap up compression
it is
the case so we've got little symbol codes but we've only got optimal symbol codes
and maybe we want something better than a simple code i'm going to show you
that that is the case now by playing the game with you which you probably
some of you come across before
and it's called
the guessing game i'm going to write down on the board
headline but you have to guess every last one of the time
the headlines a little sentence is going to appear on board is going to pair
up here
one time and every time you make an incorrect guess of the next letter which
is drawn from the set
i will write incorrect letters down here in the column until you first one right
then our carry on right and the headline is going to be chosen by the
headline generation
just here
start dancing
so i think be
w l
no there's no quotation mark in alphabet
three pad
is is correct
oh sorry that's correct
so far
space s
the tail
alice gone already
the a
and it's already on
so instead are some
so and
he is OK
we've got
prostitutes is available
right something to notice about this game
the number of guesses it took you to get the next letter
which was lot and in area of the team
chair only for high
one wanted for a long long long long panel on the long one of the
two long long long long long warner in nineteen ninety one
so that it changed sort of right is sometimes it was difficult
and sometimes it difficult often at the beginning of words and sometimes it was really
easy in the middle all in the middle phrase that's often occurs like appeal to
it was the probability distribution of letters the same at every single step in that
process for you the expert expert system will predictions the same at every know you
weren't using that probability distribution from the x-factor which we had that here
you are changing your probability distribution every single step in a way that depend on
the context possibly some quite long way back you know if i started writing in
french headline you would have learned of the french language model and or if you
know french word started learning french because we went through the ahead
and by the end of the headline you would have been using your gradually developing
knowledge of french to make those predictions
what's wrong with optional symbol codes is that just optimal symbol codes and
there examples where the optimal symbol code is actually really lousy let's look at the
typical case in here is a typical case might be
while you're back to predict this thing here
and i asked him what was your probability distribution what would you prediction be any
problem and said well the probability of being the
these are already small point along
lots of very small numbers and point nine nine sitting here
that was your probability distribution and it's often that way and if we were to
use the symbol code
working at the probability distribution on the fly
working at the optimal for that distribution what would happen then well
it might look like this here is an example
of the little alphabet a to k
where c
has a probability of ninety nine percent
and what the optimal simulcast run have algorithm combine these is that
you run huffman algorithm and the very last step you combine the sea
with all the other guys
and the code words you get like this you have one of length one for
probable guy nice and short but it's still one bit long
and the actual entropy the expected information content the idea that we ought to be
compressing down to of this particular distribution here point one one
so the factor by which the huffman algorithm loses compared with all shannon says we
ought to be doing is nine the ratio of this expected language has to be
bigger than one person will code one point something to point one one about nine
so for sources of the time we've just been discussing optimal symbol codes may be
nice and simple but of course you have to change the probability on the fly
and everything else that change probability change the tree and so forth and you still
are only within a factor of nine
of optimal distributions of this time
the real probability distribution
changes the context and simple codes suck when you have probability distributions like this
i the question is what's going on and the answer is
huffman codes give you optimal symbol code but we don't want to simple code
OK so simple cosine
we have the latest stable distribution
with fine line with infinite lives and that's the the best results you can make
use of several
i agree them to estimate the parameters the quantile CFR algorithm due to the colour
guy working in finance
this algorithm
of the middle of of the eighties but you can also occur to maximum likelihood
and since we have a lot of data probably maximum likelihood estimation is the more
formal estimate for this for this result we find that the parameter alpha
is lower than two and significantly so
so prove it if we believe that this type of distribution
comes from
the sum
independent independently idea synchronic shocks independently distributed of synchronic shocks
two several cycles of several firms which are not this interconnected between them
we should end up with something from the lowlands number
so if shocks characterised by finding bias we should have go normality if shocks
not characterized by a finite variance we should have a stable distribution so that the
the main motivation for playing this class of distributions that because here we have a
large number of works
and we found that if we believe that a large number is a good model
to use then we have that this distribution is less stable distribution with alpha lower
than two so we have fat tails
the two days are power law distributed
and the second moment doesn't exist
this is a similar to what
so we have a gaussian and c
and the liver cells
missing data
is good
because in the tails that tend to become more spots
OK but if it is quite good
thank you
OK so
let stable distributions are characterized by instability and the summation
it means that if we start from different models
distributed according to oliver distribution with the given off
was some then we end up
with another level distribution with the same of
if the alphas are all the same
otherwise we end up with a solution with the distribution which is not stable estimation
so it's possible
testing strategy
in order to assess whether i'm on the one on the right
is two
consider that are
in terms of sectors
we have twenty sectors at two-digit
and aggregate
sectors of the four digit level
the level of the digital the digital that sort of the digital level is just
a measure of how does aggregated they industries
so for example in the two sector in the two-digit sector for automotive
you have several for digit sectors regarding two times
sixty years
two in genes
so so you can use aggregate so the first picture that use the new so
was the disaggregated force for these sectors if you aggregated over twenty digits sector you
can estimate
twenty different distributions
since the the the sum of all sector must be the same that is the
entire manufacturing sector of the united states
we can try to assess whether it's sexy it's individual sample of the two digit
is alpha stable distribution we can estimate
the level of of the value of alpha and if the value of alpha this
competition but with available for for the wall set
we should try and you will hear sorry i
OK so
when i got there is the starting point to be
this here
right OK this is an starting with just this part
i'm i'm going
work with that
so you have
so there's that
so the first thing we do is that the suit
one over and
sigma i
h of said i told
one over and
so i minus
one over and some
sigma i h
i said i
and now what i'm going to say is that that is less than or equal
the super
one over and
so CKY
h z i until the
for us
one over and
sigma pi h seven n nine
and then i'm going to say that's less than or equal to
i can choose the suit for
individually this issue age age
so this is
one size but if i can choose the age for this part and for this
separately i'm going to do better still this is less than or equal to suit
h in h
one over and
some sigma i h that i feel that
class c
one of and
some sigma i h
h h
that's just equal to twice suit
sorry expectation that sorry i can't make this stuff up here but since these are
the same you know generated by the same process
the super the expectation of this
and the expectation of this
and so you just get twice the expectation is that
is that OK
i'll run through the steps again just sort of put it all together maybe
if you favour so that then
you know that then separates the south
into one super this into the other side and because he got the expectations
they essentially become independent and you just get twice the expectation over one of them
because they are identical
OK so
now looks quite good we seem to have got quite far
and then you know think well
i've done enough for the day
so i just say
that's rademacher complexity and unfinished OK
so OK
so that's the definition rademacher complexity that is it
OK so
it doesn't seem particularly sensible thing to do this point it just seems like you
run out of steam and you don't know what to do next so just make
a definition
but it amazingly seems a very sensible thing to do in the end you will
see you know that this is actually but OK so if we just make the
definition that is
rademacher complexity
there it is
that's just the definition rademacher complexity
i'll come back to talk about what it means and so on we can we
get this right so let's just go back and see the stages we went through
so if you remember we started by doing this
so we had the that that was the empirical and then we had the same
and we said the same thing was less than or equal to something
plus this so going to have to keep this page
but OK we're just going really replace this by this and and and in
so what was this this was the thing that we essentially got down to the
rademacher complexity in the end
by definition and so we end up with a simply
he all efforts and the expected value of this function is the empirical value plus
the rademacher complexity class this extra term we had one begin again
so that's basically it
maybe now let's just look at this rademacher complexity
maybe just go once more through the steps i mean the the critical step was
i mean the first step was quite easy that was just the rademacher
to get to the expected value once we got to the expected value we could
apply this
nice little
of the sample to estimate p of h within the city
that gave us this
expectation over this guy in place of this kind just inequality
because if you just
work out this average and randomize over the choice of the samples you end up
with the true estimation
then we were able to bring this event outside
and only increase
and then we were able to
that gave us that one
then we were able to introduce the symmetrisation by this sigma five plus minus one
swapping of those two in a very simple way
became very simple
it was listed here
and then
made those steps that i made that more explicit to get to this thing and
then we said we done often that's rademacher complexity that's OK
so that's basically it's
is energy
in the electric fields and there energy in the magnetic field you remember that from
a door two
and the energy density
mind the units in terms of joules per cubic metre
forty electric fields we
right for that you
equals one half
actually non-zero east graphs
there's no such thing as a free lunch
you have to do work to create an electric field you have to assemble charges
and bring them together that means work that creates an electric field
and the same is true
the magnetic field never sort you create a magnetic field inside the solenoid that cost
and the energy
my toward density this per cubic metre for magnetic fields
is squared
divided by
two new zero
now traveling wave traveling electromagnetic wave
so this is now
traveling wave
we know that the magnitude of b
it is the magnitude of e at any moment in time divided by c
so i can write this
as the squared
divided by two museo
c squid
but c square is one of actually non-zero you zero
so this is also one half
absolutely zero these grants
and what you see now is so wonderful
so beautiful is symmetric in electromagnetic waves
it's the same as the other one can not exist without the other and look
at the energy density in the electric field of traveling wave is exactly the same
as the energy density
in the
magnetic field
and so the total
energy density
it is the sum of the two
is absolutely zero
thank you great but you can also write that for that
epsilon zero times e times BC
if you prefer that
this of course
is only true in infection
when the speed of propagation
is c
is traveling wave
and this travelling wave moves and so it carries energy with it
now the question is
how much energy flows through an area which is a one square metre
every year
perpendicular to the direction of propagation
so suppose ever box here
and this site is one square metre
and i want to know
how much radiation comes out of there in one second
so the radiation is flowing in this direction with speed c
so in one second this box
it's quite a large box
three times ten thirty eight meters
and all that energy which is in there
will flow through this one square metre
in the time of one second
and so the
dimensions that we're talking about now
these jewels
per second
per square metre
which is also
what's the square meter
and that now is of course the total
energy density
time c
the speed of light
four which you can ride
absolutely zero
times b
time series squared
if you like that
but you can also right-footed each be divided by museo
c square is one of the apsidal zero mu
this should remind you
of something that
is in your far
distant past
which is what we really have called
in a o to the poynting vector in
and the poynting vector
was the
divided by new zero and the units were watts per square meter which is exactly
what this is
and the reason why the cross disappears here is that the electromagnetic travelling waves he
is always perpendicular to be
so that
takes care of the cross
now both e and b are time variable
and so the poynting vector but obviously also be
time variable
it's going to be proportional
or you can write on you some is zero
times cosine only get t
and b
is some be zero
times cosine omega so in the poynting vector
you get the
cosine square of omega t
but since we never interested in the poynting vector on the time scales smaller than
the period of oscillations we want to know the average
over many oscillations what matters there
is the
the average value of cosines square only getting one from the
and the other one from the b
and that is one half
and so we can conclude that
that the average value of the poynting vector
time everest
is one half that value
one half EB
divided by museo
for which you can also right
one half if you want to kill completely over by the way is is one
he zero
the zero
it's important that you have the zero because the cosine square which is one half
so he idea amplitudes
so you can also write for that one half
he zero scranton and so you're i don't for b
divided by c
and then you get downstairs
and the reason why i write it in this form is that
it tells you
that if you know what the strength of the
if you this that alone
tells you then
what the poynting vector is because b is coupled to e four maxwell's equations
that we're busy over c
and so all that matters then
if you want to calculate what the
the poynting vector is
is is zero
of course the zero would also be fine
so let's take an example
suppose we have an electromagnetic wave
by easier one hundred volts per meter
then i can calculate now
and it isn't traveling electromagnetic wave
i can calculate what the average value of the poynting vector is
so that would become
one half
nine hundred
divided by
museo zero time c
and if you do your homework on that
you will find that it is thirteen watts per square meter
now if you have exposed yourself
thirteen watts per square meter visible light
an infrared light you take all your clothes off
you expose yourself to that your body will absorb that
because we really collect everything from the golden of the
first page
i did before before the lecture so
living in here in the middle so it appears
all these articles and the second most frequent in this
snippets basically creation when the world cup like you and so on so can select
one of them and then we see
this is positioned in the middle of the
the centre of this
and so on the right we see the other all other name entities which are
common to most related to the
the rest of the work is not just the name
what we can do here we can
the problem
OK we can
one on this into context so in the context context means that we on the
world which the most related
which are the most characteristic for the documents were both slovenia and lithuania in this
case appear together are meaning creation so
o thing in creation will be possible your country serbia whatever
and with some other
some other of this countries with some some some other words would be more relevant
but if you were typing creation and then we'll see
how crazy related to other but in this case just countries but injured could be
any kind of name name is
so if turn on this and then we can also wrote to second level of
the sea
interested in the middle
first thirty seconds or so we see the whole context how
these appear
so you have a problem with this resolution otherwise it is a little bit more
but value you've got the idea that you can show this to other functions which
was supported by this itself so
if we select two name entities we see
we see that the graph how
they are related between each other with other name and this
and so one will be just simple
visualisation which i showed before so weak
graph class clustering can be the vision of the topics is graphs that is the
way how
you can pretty easy seem very short time
what kind of topics are in this particular moment relevant for one in three people
george bush probably
so around the world and is not going to work
now we've got it during bush
and the most relevant topics on the name entities
related to the invasion rock america public conversion motion so and so
we could explore some more
so much about this
now just see
so this was this context and last topic is basically visualizing text using
a lot of structure so this is a bit less usual topic ban talking about
that text vision the things we
did some work in this direction so i thought it might be interesting to mention
so first
so what
what is the structure in the
so all the previous patients methods you don't know much about the actual structure so
first we need to form of the documents including that
structure and then we
you are basically relying on this statistical car occurrences within the next next
the moment the approach is expected to
the the structure so it name it's it's pretty cheap to extract that's why it
was kind of useful but now
text has a lot of structure that the question how to extract
of course the structure
is he he's first linguistic structure in the linguistic structure others but on
kind of its related to semantics says the semantics of the
in this work which really it so
you could possibly find can myself which we published this year beginning with a combination
of this
different approaches
in this case
in the case of these were for the purpose of
summarisation of documents but since
kind of side to side result was also musician that that's why i'm i'm showing
OK just two
show you one flight on how we can extract any more
structured information from them
so let me
using microsoft's
parts are called in the evening
which is also in some of the versions used in
microsoft office that he had access to this operation are educating
here's one example so of one input units and michael so we put in on
the input sentence like this
on the output we get part three
which will be something like this is actually the output of the parts
send it the world past and then here we have some other
you they use as an objective third person
singular proper name
in my likely case indirect
think that but i think the proper name market this
a letter is obvious that he was the first singular and
information which we are able to extract out of its in the past basically
take one sentence and gives this kind of part three of them so the question
now i'll be able to use this force
course think what we need to to do is to
OK already in the second example
so this is the whole procedure what we do
so if we have a set of specs attacks the doctor in this case the
document was is from simple example from three sentences on fire and found
he met a friend was that so
with the low capacity
we're giving space as potentially lots of capacity but we've got to leave the controls
and keeps it under control for the particular problem and of course
the amount of capacity we use will depend on the problem was solved
if the problems were easy we may get a very very large margin and we
may have very low capacity effectively and get very very good generalisation
if the problem is harder OK we may have to use more capacity and correspondingly
more data effectively to get the same
level of performance
OK so that's all i can say about why large margin is good
obviously you know if you're interested in that kind of thing
one can look to
more detailed analysis and statistics but there's a lot written about it in various cases
now this very nice connection between what i've said about large margin and and controlling
generalisation and something known as regularisation and i think actually it's probably better to think
regularisation when you're thinking of controlling capacity in kernel methods
so regularisation is
something that has a an old knowledge history
but the connection
with regularisation comes through this observation
and that is that keeping a large margin
for classifier is equivalent to minimising the norm of the weight vector
while keeping the outputs above a fixed value
so if you think about the way that you measure the margin
it's measured by taking the inner product with the
perpendicular weight vector to the
with that weight vector normalized to length one
so if you just compute that inner product project effectively and that direction
which is what you do if you take into product with no one weight vector
that measures the distance from the hyperplane
now if you now imagine that you scalar vector so that the distance of the
two that sort of closest point is this is actually comes out in the product
of one
then the weight vector
now the norm of the weight vector actually measures one over the marginal
the business sort of inverse relation between the margin
and the norm of the weight vector
if you require that the
in the products of the
the weight vector with the training points all have norm because fixed values one
so in other words if we take that as a sort of criterion we fix
show you that you know how this works in the definition
of the
the optimisation but if you take the outputs in the highland have a fixed value
say one
then minimising the norm of the weight vector
while satisfying this criterion
is equivalent to maximizing the margin
so suddenly you know you start to
see that
expanding the marginal controlling the capacity is equivalent to actually
controlling the norm of the
weight vector that you're using in this high dimensional space
so controlling the norm of the weight that is often is also referred to as
and in fact relates back to classical technique in neural networks known as weight decay
so weight decay in neural networks
is the equivalent if you like of
maximizing the margin
provided you
the output separation
at a fixed value which of course
it wasn't always the case in your learning
but often was too
so in the way you want people already had this intuition
the problem was that they're learning algorithms were much harder to
to make effective
i should just say
there is quite a lot of
misinterpretation of
what this
margin maximisation is doing and this
it's written that it's structural risk minimisation
structural risk minimization is where you take a fixed hierarchy of
everything you might want to be screening people for risk of certain disease diagnosing disease
or predicting the outcome of the treatment prognosis
or discovering new drugs
and in security area recently there has been a renewal of interest in machine learning
because of security problems and their face recognition signature fingerprint or iris verification and DNA
fingerprinting have been important applications of machine learning
in the area of computer and the internet people have been using machine learning to
design better computer interfaces including troubleshooting wizards and handwriting recognition interfaces or speech recognition interfaces
and more recently even brainwaves mostly for handicapped people right now to control computers with
their brainpower directly
and india the number of internet applications including hit ranking spam filtering text categorisation text
translation and recombination
as i mentioned when i introduced myself i organise challenges and recently i've i've organised
two changes for nips two-thousand three and two thousand six and for each challenge there
has been five datasets so in total there are now ten datasets that of former
in uniform way
and the that are available to perform experiments and this span the whole spectrum of
the difficulty in terms of number of inputs the number of examples is also a
wide spectrum of types of applications so different types of inputs
and you can see on this slide the variety of difficulty of tests from a
different point of view from the point of view of the performance of the participants
which you see here other he's diagrams of the performance of the participants some on
x is you have the error rate on the test said it's the balanced error
rate that is the average of the error rate of the positive class and of
the negative class for two clusters education problems
since all these problems are too classification problems
and in some some in some cases like on sylva dataset you have
peaked very peaked distribution towards the origin
which indicates that the task is relatively easy everybody's doing well that task
on the other datasets for example the dorothea dataset you see that there is very
widespread distribution so some people are doing very well and some people are doing very
bad on some other datasets you can see that there is a
almost by model distribution
they that most people do well that some people do bad
actually on the metal dataset it's most apparent that you have a by move distribution
so you'll be having the opportunity in the lab class to play with some of
these datasets and compete with you know the best competitors trying to outperform their performance
in class i taught a year ago in zurich i had the students try to
outperform the participants of the first challenge to units thousand three challenge and they all
did very well we only know outperformed or matched closely the performance of the best
participants so this is doable
and this slide i'm showing how different learning machines perform on different datasets
so i'm very coarsely grouped the learning machines in into four categories the linear and
kernel methods the neural that's the decision trees than random forest methods the naive bayes
in these the ten datasets
and as you can see in terms of you know relative balanced error rates these
balanced error rate over the average balanced error rate of all the participants
the best performers are doing very well in general with linear and kernel methods for
the first two datasets but not not better than other methods on the last four
and no networks can do very well in some cases but they have quite a
bit of variance too on some datasets they don't do better than others and the
decision trees well similarly also they have some datasets on which they don't do well
and a bias which is a very simple method making independence assumptions about the inputs
so it's kind of you know the baseline or reference methods for all the machine
learning techniques can do well on on some datasets on which actually other ones do
well also
but generally performs worse so we'll see that you know one of the games in
machine learning is to predict ahead of time which learning machine is going to be
performing well before you've seen data or reserve or chunk of data eyes radiation to
decide between various learning machines which when you think is going to be performing best
in the future
in this class the convention is going to be you that the data are going
to be represented as the matrix the lines of which represent examples and the columns
represent the features or variables
so for example this would be patients in in lines and for each patient you
would have a record of the age of the weight of the number of children
and whatever information is really relevant about this patient
in terms of learning machines a lot of the learning machines they way
the the columns of the lines in order to determine the decision function that they're
are going to be using to make predictions so if you if we're weighting the
columns then we're going to be calling the weights w and if we're weighting the
lines we're going to be calling the weights alpha
and there is one special call at that time here separating from others which is
the target so this is the quantity that you want to predict for example the
health status of the patient is the patient healthy or diseased
you can going i'm showing you know several instances of the same matrix
in so-called unsupervised learning problems we are caring about with the structure of the is
there are not structuring data on the problem being that we don't know what the
target y is in in supervised learning we want to predict an outcome so an
what's the matter computing the related is having an estimate which is good or related
clients OK so the related via being defined essentially by divided by the square of
the expectation OK so in this case what you find what you would find is
that essentially the value store violence would be something which indeed decreasing in one of
the capital and but basically one of pnx is extremely small so they lead to
violence is really really huge so if you want to relate violence of saleable the
ten minus two
it means that essentially in the dimension twenty
you will need like four billion samples OK on four and fourteen you in electing
to the point four twenty sample OK so
with the calorimeters
nice internal rate of convergence but in the scenario
he doesn't break the curse of dimensionality in this case it shouldn't be a kind
of a mystery to you if you saw paul blind in this space when you
try to do the sphere in using sample for that hypercube is really like finding
a needle in a stack in such high dimension on this essentially such blind monte
carlo methods will be a bit stupid so you just a bit of cautionary warning
about semantic elements
so now let's move to the light that's it for the really
g introduction to model the calorimeter so let's move on to do prime trying to
solve the case
what i'm going to be interested in doing is computing essentially just picking coming up
with estimates of expectation of function f with respect to apply distribution pyrex so typically
was your latter point may not be initially posed this way that you have to
write it as an expectation respect appointed distribution i assume for the time being that
you have done the job for me
basically he applies be essentially an arbitrary point p delta function
i assume that were basically rnx but could be any space this knowledge if is
that essentially nothing particularly been working with real numbers
i will introduce some notation
basically we use later on quite lot so i will introduce the delta function
that x not which is basically it integrates with any function f respect to tell
that you are function OK that's not equal to ethics and so i will choose
merge authority notation
in this set of lectures
you could obviously to be completely rigorous obviously should write delta x not dx instead
of using this was not quite rigorous but as the notation abducted not to overload
OK so if you think i want to tell really doing
it's important to give you an sample distributed according to pi
it previously that was my drops that will distributed according to the uniform distribution then
pbgd what you're doing what is the colour corresponds to a correspond to doing an
of the initial distribution of interest approximating it by an empirical measure which is essentially
basically as the re weighted sum of the mass located at the particle at the
one ensembles location OK
so monic element identity y
basically it's not bad if that's stupid despite the fact that if you do things
applies to efficient
simply because essentially you approximate
basically the
target distribution of interest by x by simply so set of one the
points which automatically concentrated then set the norwegian of put that's OK that's why it's
quite clever
so this is a bit funny way of reasoning because whereas when you're doing stuff
the biometric statistics you like samples the data on you try to come up with
function or foundation of your data so you try to approximate that go should have
given me is when you're doing with the calendar year elsewhere you have typically
expression for the target distribution of five on you come up we basically we've
this the multicolour presentation of it from samples because of the kind of we have
way of thinking
OK so this is important for example so this is my mother multicolour approximation of
univariate gaussian
it's in OECD to make such approximation why dimension on it is full dimensional to
element should be precluded but thought i'd mention essentially the concentration of essentially one sample
original by quality mass going be quite actually want
so montecarlo i'm just for doing very quickly
the the
benefits of basically this estimates assume you have evidence on paul this to be according
to buy you want to approximate the expectation of a function f with respect by
what you do very simple you simply substituted by the empirical measure of the sampled
is always HC over lambda right electron is moving at the speed of light you
has to have some other expression for the ratio of the Planck constant to its
momentum and this is just the Newtonian expression of momentum the product of the mass
of the electron times it's some philosopher
actually said
so what are the consequences that how can we go somewhere with their value recalled
in them in
the quantum condition more express the quantum conditioned by the angular momentum quantum condition in
the following manner boss said that the angular momentum and the is quantized where n
is this integer counter h over to apply this is the part proportionality that's multiplied
by the so if if the correct we could then model the electrons in its
orbit not moving as a particle but let's model it is a way
so will come away visit is only 2 kinds of ways this traveling waves and
the standing waves so this is stationary orbit so we need to have a standing
wave so
not to scale so let's imagine this is the electron
in its orbit
it's understanding a standing wave configuration
all right so there's a geometric constraints right so
In order to have an electron in a stationary orbit
electron in stationary orbit
this implies a standing wave a standing wave means there's a geometric constraints which is
what I have to have a whole number of wavelengths to get around the circumference
so the circumference is 2 pi R
it is going to be a standing wave than this must be an integral number
of wavelengths
the boss told us that actually Debreu has told us that the wavelength is related
to the incident velocity through this formula so let's let's substitute that will give us
2 pi are those areas and age over and the I cross multiply here that
will give me and the r equals n h over 2 pi
the client condition of
falls out of three-line derivation if you accept the bride's hypothesis that the electron in
this set of circumstances can be modeled as a way
so he got his PhD thesis and in 1929 he gets a Nobel Prize he's
off to a flying start Einstein right the thesis love the loved what we care
what Einstein says Einstein's only if irritation and Abreu is theoreticians so 1 the retention
propping up another the retention is mutual admiration society we need lot
we need evidence we need experimental evidence
so let's go back to high school for a moment just by way of background
remember these water tanks we could put a vibratory water taken this is top view
of a water taken if you had a motor here that was causing a paddle
to move up and down you could cause waves to form at 1 end of
the tank and moved from left to right
and furthermore you could do little experiment so for example you could put on a
dam in the middle of the tank and if the distance between the wall
In the dam was large in comparison to the wavelength then what happens
if this distance is large in comparison to the wave like this is then simply
casts a shadow
this like like casting a shadow was so part of our approach so this is
simple when D is large in comparison to land they are obstacles obstacles cast shadows
and this is equivalent to modeling the wave as particles this is ray optics
this is the equivalent to ray optics isn't
you don't have to know anything about wave like behaviour you got front coming here
you've got an obstacle
where you can get by it moves through
but in the other case where the gaps
this is the spacing
when the the spacing was small in comparison to the wavelength the obstacles did not
cast a shadow the obstacles did not cast a shadow you see a tiny tiny
little stream coming out of each of these orifices instead you saw this recall
in this case just picking one feature at the time
and if that value of the feature was largely
reject we remove that that with high probability if it was small we kept do
with high probability of vice versa
and what you can see here is the test error
this solid green
dark green line
is what you do if you don't do any great what you get if you
don't do any correction
the mean
the middle bar is what you do
what you get if you actually knew the by some distribution
which in our case meaning you know because we have
explicit bias in one
the right bar is the are the ticket
if you use the moment matching four three waiting
they should be very surprised about the fact
that in all these cases the moment matching model
outperforms the importance sampler
even so for the moment matching and not assume that all that they know what
distribution looks like
not just recover the weighting coefficients
that sounds like magic doesn't it
well the reason why
it outperforms at least believe that this is the reason is because when making use
of the fact that you have you noticed started it explicitly disposition
so basically transduction
by more than what you have to pay for not knowing the distribution
and so you would think OK well that's just one dollar maybe that's just specific
to breast cancer
now actually what happened is that j one so she was the one who did
and it's something where
i initially thought well
stupid and if she had asked me whether this is a good idea would have
really try talking about this experiment
but you did it anyway
and it turned out to be really great
so what it she she thought you know i mean this passing has worked on
the docks
now let's do something that actually would break all of our assumption
namely he had have actually boss the labels
so the distribution
over sick and healthy patient
it would be different on between training and test it
so she basically artificially reweighted to taste it
which doesn't make any sense in the way i mean what the theory shouldn't really
work right
at least at the moment we don't have a good theory for it
but surprising thing was that actually did this
and she is just different degrees of boxing
the method still works really well
so this is probably
this is the big surprise came out of it
the plots he would kind of expect
that's when i was really
very surprised when i saw them
now you can have a look at the big table and we use different datasets
for regression classification what have you and we just
looked at what you do if you don't get
if you don't go to a correction
if you do the correction by knowing the true distribution
if you use the moment matching
in the majority of all cases the moment matching outperforms the importance sampling
in the cases where it doesn't outperform it it's actually fairly close
so for instance i mean
in this case well it's point o to one two point one three likewise here
OK that was maybe not so great but the variance is
a very large anyway but as you can see it actually doesn't really good job
so for practical purposes this is really as good as knowing the poisson distribution
and it's so easy to implement
so the credit program
so this is
basically an affliction number
and now we're going to look at distribution test for independence
now the time for questions
yet showing
is that we will be
close your
however how should we
match those
OK so
you may
you know
derive different matching
according to different background knowledge different countries
so this is another application
where uncertainty material
the next one is about search
for example
if you look at those literature on entity detection digital library so often they use
one example is a you search one chinese name way one which is really very
popular chinese name and then the competition is that how many way one can you
so if you google a while got the right along this of people differently once
you have no clue who is what
and you say because the web is so messy data so if you go to
some clean the data sources b
we may have a better situation in unfortunately
the answer is no because the BLP well to some states of really you know
about the core of better quality than just the rollback right however if you go
to the DBLP is still can find so many we once in that some entries
contain more than one way one
you have an impact in interview individuals
so you can see
if you want to have you know being information to individuals
by search
naturally you have the uncertainty
another example
suppose you want to fill up custom customer form in the web page so often
parties for example you want to apply for continuous bay or you want to apply
for confi lumber
when he
annoying they always as you for actors both a
or this person information and so many customers in they don't want to give the
they just want to go through the form as soon as possible and then
after service
what do you
often do
four b
at least i often quite user asked me for the state in i do not
believe in the united states but i still want to get the service what can
i do and i just get the job at least could the first one alabama
so many people use jennifer's as to their birthdays
when you look at this kind of data in that when you look at the
data you do it if you do not do any analysis you find the data
is screen is also a complete
nothing is missing
the concept really inherently the data is missing
OK so we call these as these guys missing data
and then discuss using a there is a very serious problem because if you do
not analyse the uncertainty of missing values here
you make very wrong business decision for example you find so many customers i in
then this go there for all a lot of sourced there
and there's a lot of money there
you see that was the result right
so this is disguised missing data and it also introduces the uncertainty the uncertainty here
is that was the view URL and more importantly whether these customer these you have
you value or not
this is absurd
then we talk about so many application examples of uncertainty
in and said in our data
and you may ask one question well
uncertainty sounds a very bad thing why do we still want to look at a
certain date
why and data is still useful
in fact all the data could be to some extent uncertain
but even if we can model the uncertainty pop three we still can derive some
useful and useful information from such data
for example for temperature sensor if the difference between the real temperature and sense temperature
follows a normal distribution
then if you have a question is that outside where the temperature is all the
forty degree
but this is uncertain
however if you want to say
what's the probability
this is
if you want to have situation where
therefore you as you can see when we analyse uncertain data one important thing we
need to do is that when we
the questions
but when we asked the questions the answers could should be probabilistic
and the answers should be
at some some sort of aggregate level
this is important
for example
these kind of questions how we can estimate the percentage of married vote voters supporting
obama from the way data these kind of questions is so popular so frequent in
these days
i guess and you know when verview see all kinds of such questions every week
given such answers and the answer has to come with some confidence
some quantity measures of the answer
you have to ask another question about uncertainty is somewhat look
can we
i removed and sent by some way
well there's something called the clinic
which may help
OK and when we just apply data cleaning to no remove all the uncertainty and
then we have cleaned and sorted data
just some serious problem the first problem is
how do i remove this uncertain data
one thing you can do is that well you can remove all the uncertain actually
and you can remove all the uncertain records
the problem here is that in fact you reduce the available data
for some applications you have you know enough data
band is so you could be OK
but for some application
you only have one of the very small amount of data
and the data
has the inherent concur that uncertainty then it is a problem let me give you
one example
medical even if metrics of health informatics
there's so many
kind of disease
in the whole world only collect very small number of cases
and for each case you may have hundreds of attributes
but only
but only few of them a complete most of them in that contain a lot
of uncertainties
then you can also just say i know audience the matters because in such a
if you do that you lose all the cases
OK so this is one
we review removing unsourced entries may not be
may not work
and we
you think about is the uncertainty in fact to some extent is related to data
generated by
for example if you don't tell me exactly which at the street edges of
of your home but you tell me the city or the state
how about we raise
the data and it is
to the level
things are certain
then we have we have a beautiful work
when you raise the analyse level
basically you have to do the same stuff as in normal mixture models you introduce
a hidden variable which year is one if the density at this point in space
x is explained by a certain component which is currently
well basically kernel offered offer certain data point and their else rising and indeed you
do the normal
am stuff
and you come up with this
e step
if you plug causes tetanus into the m step we get a nice from of
i've shown you before
so this shows that although many of maximizing
the complete light duty also maximizes the data likelihood which is basically in this case
the kernel density estimate and when starting the EM with
well the data points
you do the hill climbing for that data point
and so we we got nice formulation
four our dental organisms
and how much faster hit climbing procedure and then slide problems come into play and
now we have to identify the local maxima slightly differently as we did before the
EM algorithm iterates and iterate into and sometimes and from one point it converges
two two point detectors usually by this kind of this form you put threshold epsilon
if the target function doesn't change much then you stop
and because the end points reached by this iteration
x star t and we also recorded the size of the last step
if you converge to the to the fixed point here
steps to become closer to become smaller
and so you have a kind of sense of scale what you're dealing at sons
assumption we are taking to identify local maxima is that true local maxima is in
a ball around x star
and the ball has radius of st
we associate to point to be in the same cluster there
and point
if the distance between the endpoints smaller than the sun
between t and t prime and then we say the towards overlaps in the same
belong to the same maximum this
may create in some cases non unique assignment in this case which we rarely happens
you just to write a few
steps for them and then you're
x star converges to a bit closer to the local maximum and and then you
can resolve these non unique assignments
so far for the growth
the organisms still needs
in each iteration a sum over all data points which is quite expensive
so we look for some more general methods to speed up and one thing is
to do this piracy and this is the paper by neal and hinton
ninety nine
quite general paper and basically they say update only p percent of the point is
the largest posterior basically those point which has the largest kernel values
which produce large kind of a
with in one iteration
and this saves the rest of canada competition of the after the first iteration you
you need to do one iteration two to sort by the priors
but by the posterior and then you can
safe it and we did it in the following that we just identified a few
points which really contribute to the local maxima and then the
basically wanted the point is not we did not have the point this slide over
the deviation from the origin of approach but the intent and they also also update
this set but since they converge so fast it wasn't really necessary
to update the points in the set l
which is not so much contribute
and the other approach is much more cross we just we use dataset first step
very simplest two by random sampling
if you have an point to just simple p percent of as representative points or
you run k means on these points and take the centroids as the representative points
takes account of was also representative points so experiments
basically confirmed our search assumption that we need much less iterations number of iterations is
shown here four point if you have this
the prior previous approach of england one point this and here you have probably put
different base for epsilon we stop the EM iteration he put zero there
well it's not useful but you see it and how much more work but if
you put a reasonable value like this
you do much less iterations
and just to identify the correct clustering
this was artificial data here show you read it in a moment
to compare this to acceleration methods
ten in terms of speed this
sparsity and a bit more expensive since you have to do one full iteration then
you can reduce the problem reduces costs and here sampling approaches doesn't
what was the big differences in speech
suspect equality in this still artificial data measured graph clustering quality the suspect anomalous mutual
the few on the x axis
sample size so here we take full sample was not shown here eighty percent of
the data get twenty percent of the data and you see here for low dimensional
you need a identifier clustering with small error
but but you only twenty percent of your point
this is low dimensional data technique for sixteen
and if you make the higher
i give you one hundred twenty eight
this album is not so nicely shown more and you also need larger small things
for real data we compared it to k means and there is not a direct
methods which is here
provided this is a bit like self
step by step for suggesting
this has
similar based k means a bit better in terms of as which information
here are shown here
the size of the sample size and here's the standard deviation is i was
standard deviation
and you see here the sampling cost something
but not too much on real data
he also can compare but basically the cells that
that's all
and that's a law about
this bound becomes tight
becomes equality if and only if
your q distribution here matches peaked distribution
so if you're approximation is really really good that matches your true
then the bound becomes tight
right so now why do we have this bond well it turns out
that you can write it this way
and this term the log probabilities
is just linear in
this hidden variables and this is known as official about
so why is this
an interesting thing
the reason why this is interesting because if you look at these guys here this
is the normalizing constant is the partition function that we can compute that's where all
exponential computation goes into
everything else we can compute
and the beauty of this algorithm is that now i'm gonna try to say well
finding the distribution q such that this bound is despite this possible maximizes about
so try to me to be less close as possible to the true he but
not is that terms that depend on q they don't really
interact with this intractable partition function
so that's the beauty of the algorithm that basically says we don't really need to
find what the normalizing constant and what this partition function is we can actually solve
this problem without
using exponential
then we can view this thing is that you can actually write it as a
low probability minus something that's called tail divergence
cool but lieber divergence divergence between two distribution and he
and the tail that is essential measures the distance between two and
so it's kind of like saying by maximizing the bound you've basically trying to find
two such that it's as close as possible to the true
true posterior distribution
in terms of detail divergence sense
so now we have the initial about what we can do is we can choose
a fully factorized distribution that's the easiest thing to do is called mean field you're
basically saying all the links in my model are gonna be broken
and what the variational inference in this case is trying to do
is essentially trying to find a single mode in the posterior distribution
okay so if you have you know a few modes
additional inference will just find one mode and say that's my explanation of the data
and end it comes down to a set of nonlinear equations which are very easy to
so four you just iterating through these non linear set of
the question of deletion a fixed point
and that's gonna be your best to distribution
that that that you get
again it's
you know it's it's a little bit complex if you've never heard about variational inference
but it's sort of the idea that you have in mind is that you try
to approximate your complex distribution with a simpler distribution and there is subjective that you're
trying to make it as close as possible to the true
conditional distribution here
so now the way you want these models is that's you're doing variational inference
to estimate the first data and expectations and then you're running in same see stochastic approximation to estimate these
model's expected sufficient statistics
you can sort of show you know properly
show that you have all show convergence guarantees asymptotically stable point official about
you know basically it says that you know when you talk to you guys they're
happy with out because it says asymptotically everything is okay
right so now let's see
how it works in practice
now in general inference he is fast because we using mean field approximation so it
takes fraction of a second to infer
approximately the states of the latent variables
and learning she can scale to millions of examples
this is because we using stochastic approximation which doesn't depend on the data so you
can really make it make it very scalable
so one question is does it actually work
you know i think the article should be working is good but doesn't actually work
in practice so what i'm gonna do is i'm gonna let you judge whether it
works or not
so what i'm gonna show is i'm gonna show you two panels
on one panel i'm gonna show you the real data
on another initially simulated data
and you have to tell me which one is which
so again one panel shows real data data about shows simulated data
how many of you this was you know whether this was real
all right hand but this was real this was simulated
alright as i have and have perfect
so that's
that's good i'm always worried about you know
if you
if you get it right when you get right right
so if you look at
the data
this is simulated this is real
so a couple of things to notice the real data is much more diverse
right if you look at these handwritten characters across these different alphabets
you know this is all a bit more structure to the real data and now
has to do with the inability of the model to explore this exponential space
of all possible handwritten characters
if you also look at
you know something like this
right you can basically see that people probably wouldn't
draw this image this way right it's just you know they're like
pixel hanging out here in one pixel hang out here so if you actually steer
these images for quite some time
you'll see
but this is simulated this is the only method captures a lot of structure handwritten characters right
sort captures how how
what's the underlying structure
now if i look at some other datasets so for example if i look at the e
data set of handwritten digits
now there's another this is a commonly used is a simple dataset how many of
you think this is really simulated
right a few how many of you think this is real and this simulated
so that's a much easier test
this is indeed simulated so if you look at something like five over here right
the kind of the thickness or if the about average
solutions will probably survived the higher the fitness about the average to high the probability
of survival and of course the below average probably die out
OK i mentioned that this is done
that one way of implementing it is
the so-called roulette wheel
you can imagine the rule
and dr
the idea is
the following
this is the rule that then
the sections
correspond to the individuals
in such a way that
the larger this
i mean the higher the fitness the larger sections section belongs to one individual so
if you now
do this rule selections
if you turn this real and of course if you select
one thing that there is a high probability of selecting the larger one
so after doing this selection procedure and times
n is the number of these sections or individuals you get what
a certain way and copies
out of this population
where the most
it is the individual will probably be represented
a higher number high number of times then maybe the second one and so so
on but this is very bad individuals will probably never come
out of this selection procedure so this is one traditional approach of implementing this selection
that is called fitness proportionate
there are also alternative selection schemes now there's more popular like rank based when we
do not take
fitness values into core into considerations but simply their ranks to serve as witness then
there is
l selections when a certain number of
the best
solutions to go
into the next populations tournament selection when a certain subset
of solutions compete against each other and so on
these models are known to have certain properties which so some of these are more
convenient and there's about this is a very specific so
maybe we can mention some extensions of these algorithms and then show some additional examples
to know what is actually
what it can produce in practice
we said that
bit strings
are the most traditional way of encoding the solutions genetic algorithms later this is this
improved in the way that we are not that strict anymore it depends on the
problem is we are solving let's say
i don't know travelling salesman problem then
presenting solutions as
permutations will be the most natural way so we can do this with the genetic
algorithms also just needs to
some tailoring of these operators
then it can be also real vectors as we the evolution strategies arrays
it depends on the problem
the crossover operator is
also something that is implemented in twenty different ways of what we saw
with the simple crossover region is the most straightforward implementation
o variety of other implementations like multiple point cross-over which is cutting the strings at
several points and then exchange every second
a pair of
then it is uniform cross-over when
for each pair of components we decide separately by the two exchange them or not
then there is arithmetic crossover for real vectors when new components are calculated based on
the original ones and so on
four permutation problems we have specific operators and so on
as we did
evolution strategies we also how
advanced techniques genetic algorithms
like meta GA's which is a tuning
one of the problem or of the data on the high level and solving the
problem itself on on
lower level
then these algorithms can be paralyzed
that is implemented on parallel computers because of population based search
this is particularly
this is calculated by these microscopic approach the distance between the fragments so
and you can have this line here which are the prediction that we can make
if you compare with experimental data here
you see
but you have a global agreement with experimental data
these people and p here can be explained by the formation of the fragments so
with the hand when you have two different fragments
the distance between the centre of mass of these fragments is quite large
so then if the distance is lot
total kinetic energy
is small
so you you have the spherical here's the distances less
so it's a big east and say sorry
it's more dispensary small distance and then total kinetic energy
big and so on
the information can explain this by down here
so we have an overestimation to six percent so
as we don't have introduced a new phenomenological parameters
this is quite a good news
so we can calculate the quadrupole deformation of the fission fragments that solution
so this is what we have done for different fissioning system from diamond family
this is this information depending on the mass of the fraction of the fragments
and you see this sort of structure which is really do to be shell effects
for eighty two fifty so
we have these match minima for a eighty two
and one hundred thirty beats maximum here
what you can see also that this fragment deformation do not strongly depend upon the
fissioning system that you are looking at
when you have this information you can easily calculate the deformation energy
and then you can constitute can calculate the emission of neutrons so first when you
have excited fragmented we first meet some neutrons
so when you have the deformation energy you can calculate the emission of neutrons because
you just have to divide by the energy of the neutrons what is the energy
of the emitted neutrons
if the kinetic energy of the neutrons blows
the binding energy of the neutrons when he was in the
so that in this formula
number of neutrons emitted in the exhibition energy divided by the energy of the neutrons
which is the sum of the kinetic energy of the neutrons the separation energy of
the neutrons in the nucleus
so all it has been calculated by the previous calculations and then you see that
can compare with experimental data this is the neutron multiplicity depending on the mass of
the fragments
so open symbols are for experiment and this one black symbols from theory
so you see that the
we had good qualitative agreement so we have
i found these structure here the so structure
you see that there are some discrepancies
some can be explained by experiments
which are very difficult to obtain and some can be explained by different assumptions that
we have made one of the assumption that here
we had this
after approximation where we consider here
at that
energy of the fragment is only due to the information
but you can have all that kind of exciting action due to promotion of some
intrinsic citation indices neglected here
so that
is the way progress can be made now to better
i understand the process better describe their experimental results
so now the time dependent propagation so how do we do so with the hand
what we do in that need with an initial state here which represent the company
placed a new trying new stations of initial state here and then we have this
schrodinger equations time dependent so we propagate everywhere
it's quantum mechanical but you can imagine that what what somewhere and then you are
looking whereas the winters training
and then you can that flex along all station configurations and then you can have
time dependent territories so
even if it's the same effect with water
that and then it where
comes here and then calculate the different probabilities to have
what are here
different depending on the configuration
so and then we can calculate different properties like the mass distribution for example
and these are the results of value evaluation can consider experiments and are you experienced
and here
so this is a unit of fragments depending on one that
you have a static results so you can calculate from no dynamics no time evolution
you can
calculate is what we call one-dimensional results in right
and the new results out the blue
here here
so you see different points of first you have the same location of the maxima
so it means that in these
nucleus which is fissionable uranium two hundred thirty eight
this does not depend
too much on the national that really depend on the energy
but you see that you really improve here
we want to be able to
to build a company gener generalizations like that every metal has solvent
for every fish there's a bigger fish
every student is brighter than someone but we
we need to be able to say things like
and the technique that's
standard for
as you
i will be away
is to introduce
in the syntax variables look like names
so they begin with x something which means to
so they they they behave just just as though they were naming things
but they don't name any particular thing that's the intended semantics
variability over the domain
we consider
the sets of
when we when we look at the variable
and think about what it takes out well we consider
the set evaluations of that we get by letting it began different things like range
over variable well at the very
over the domain
variables in themselves are not that useful
to say things to to generalize they have to be bound
and they get bound by quantifiers
are expressions that say
what quantity of things
in the domain
satisfy some description
again in natural languages there are quite a lot of quantifiers
most of which don't have any very interesting logic
we consider expression like
most days of these
this is
quantifier it says
consider the things in here that satisfy the description i
most of them satisfy this other description b
and the way we see that in
logical notation will be something like for most
such that
but text justifies a
x satisfies b
and this
stuff here
like most quantifiers in natural language this is a binary
operation it takes two
predicates here
the variable standing here
in the places
the names of these objects are going to go on
and this kind of notation is capable of representing
first order logic
again we not
concerned to formalize
all of these we restrict ourselves to
to just a couple of the
namely a universal
but says everything in the domain satisfies
for all
and for that we
i'm going to use
this inverted a
with the very
and then
this formula here with
in the interesting case the variable occurs in it
and the existential quantifier
he says that something in the domain at least one thing
satisfies the condition
and actually right to reverse e
in the standard way
to represent that
so as is familiar
the logic was
with this vocabulary we can say things like all
by peds
otherwise they look ridiculous
take anything in the domain
this is the question in natural language so we can put any other questions so
with a simple interface we can form
this question in tool
query before the knowledge base which is already first order
kerry in this
much with the like this give the values of
the o station and
five such that the following is true so is a couple of
constraints which we provide in in the text
and the president
but then
we would get an answer so that
function five so this argument would be
the governor detection of an outlets
five rockets
and so on and the station is something west stations so this is now
taken straight from the knowledge base so there are obviously plenty of
a set of documents which had this pieces of
on information inside which were in one of the other way as large showing before
transferring to the first into knowledge base and now we can ask
about these facts which appeared in the knowledge base
so what's so
we came from the natural language
the first or the query
so the answer now we can also say well justified
justify this answer
and now this would be a justification
so up here
we have very which we
three with the beginning
the question here is of there
you see there are two two variables station in funk type so the answer was
this station something was stationed functi type is
whatever of it
and now this is justification for the answer it's a long one but this is
really the trace of cyc
it's like doing reasoning can connecting small pieces and very specific knowledge
and very generic knowledge now if let's see you try to come focus to be
from this justification so
this would be
this rule here is very specific
knowledge about these rockets
which again won gold much into the details but it if
facility cessation of that and that type and some type of situation and so on
we can conclude this and this so this would be very domain specific knowledge was
down here
using this reasoning car whether specific domain knowledge would be triggered as well as a
very generic knowledge so
it's a it's simple common sense rule in this particular case would be divide devices
cannot perform their primary function when they are broken so this is part of the
we a justification
for that particular relatively complex complex
this interface allows really cool for typically four
expert user or analyst to ask relatively complicated queries and then get this kind of
justification and especially in this kind of very
montreal domains so this kind of justification so very
helpful because
they are far from complete especially if the person is not very knowledgeable in the
so the second example which i have is an example of abductive reasoning which doesn't
work in general but works well in this particular case this is
i hope you know how much can you see this question so the question is
who has a motive for this is the nation of life and i think it
is a couple of years ago there was because the prime minister of lebanon which
got killed in some
now the question we're still i think but today is not clear who
who was the perpetrator of this event now
we can ask
so what's eichner about
terrorism so it knows a lot of facts
collected from if public sources
so i think this was one of the projects from sites so some other people
were day-by-day collecting pieces of information from public sources about the terrorist activities
now we can ask so
what who has a motive for this is the notion of but i think
so this question gets transferred of their into
the first order form so we would like to instantiate this variable who
so who has a motive for this is the national accrediting
and then the press this button for getting an answer we get the list so
it's much sort city OK the united states
so the difference is that we allow cycle in this particular case
and not only everybody right everybody right by a good amount by l one margin
a difference between this and the rest of point two
so that tells us least the thing that posting is searching for example
we don't tell us how to get the only access we have this matrix by
the weak learning algorithm
that you find data but lisa tells us that this weighted vote system there exists
a good way of a nice linear separation really defined over these hypotheses has a
l one margin alomar this means that this weighted by the weights
sum up their sum up to one
and the gap there's point
so this means the thing it was searching for we know it exists and of
course it was great because it gives you a way of getting at if the
only act if we don't so if you had with this thing is if we
had explicitly listed always hypothesis we would need to use a
we can define a linear separation
but if this is a huge set of hypotheses and the only access have is
by this algorithm a that goes to find one and it was just way of
doing that
this is just like adding an interesting way of thinking about what it was to
OK so now
a little bit about what happens if everyone's adapting
so what if
so we start by talking about algorithms that
you know the world is changing traffic is changing every you know an actual traffic
is likewise trafficking
because everybody else is changing the way they're acting based on what's going themselves and
you know so everybody's changing so what happens so the changing cost function we're experiencing
traffic is due to other players in the system optimizing for themselves using some i
regret minimising procedure
if you think about this idea of having lower right it can be viewed as
a nice definition of what it means to be acting reasonably of interest one right
so here you are you figure out how to drive to work and if some
other way to go much better than what you've been taking
you know you're not doing great job acting in the nicely self-interest away
but suppose everybody is able to have regret going to zero
it was to say about the overall system
so one thing is we saw the zero sum games
the empirical frequencies so if you have
zero sum game two players zero sum game and they're both minimizing regret then their
behaviors are going approach minimax optimal
OK so there are both minimizing regret and they they play you you look at
how many times they played to their options those distributions apply how many times they
played this first that is that those things are going for minimax optimal and you
can see that because if your empirical distribution of play wasn't
going towards minimax optimal if it was was far too was
very non optimal
minimax optimality guarantees you get released the value of the game is if you're quite
far from that if you only
you are praying distribution and only guarantees you so much lower numbers the opponent with
the will take advantage of that they would have to take advantage of your they're
running minimizing our
OK so i'm just arguing here is the two regret minimising i'm going to play
against each other they have to have the distributions approaching minimax optimality because if you
want approaching that would mean that there be some choice the other player could make
that would do much better than the value of the game v
they would have to do that because are minimizing regret and then you will have
so really they both have to be approach next
that's so we can understand two player zero-sum game
the natural thing to ask is in general sum games you start playing these guys
against each other will the behavior quickly or even all approach to nash equilibrium
i mean if you think about a nash equilibrium is exactly a set of distributions
have no regret with respect to each other
given the other guys doing this
there's nothing you read it or find there's no particular strategy that does much better
given what you're doing is no particular strategy guide your for your both feeling no
regret happy
in general sum games will these adaptive algorithms guarantee approach
unfortunately the answer is no
just to give an example
here's an example of the EM where they don't
it's one that
now they officially called this but i like to call rock paper scissors was born
there in the first part
so the first three rows and columns this game are what's called the shapley game
which is rock paper scissors ceremonies rock paper scissors beats
paper beats rock scissors paper
rock beats
what happens if you both play the same thing
and i mean high right
but in the shapley game you both
OK so
if the row player plays plays rock
tumblr page paper
OK then
paper wins so the row player plays
pays the fact that
the column player dollar
the other way around the money goes the other way if they both the same
thing about me and all of they both
so that the shapley game the sadly game is losing proposition
OK in the shapley game here
i have left the future slides
anyway so the shapley game got these three
places here many men the best that equilibrium is still one thirty one one just
like rock paper scissors
that's the best you can really do
but when you lose
we we we don't just change the battle to be the flu and so
actually you're expected
expected loss of one-third in this game because
one third chance to do the same thing in the guy that new
you lose two thirds chance
so we start with that will have a fourth action which is played foosball
in this fourth action
but the man slightly negative if the other papers players doing rock paper scissors but
positive person joined the and played football with you
so we have the fourth option there here
but it's going to be a plus
for about but this online says
up here in other players doing anything
so if you set this up right i'll go through the exact values you need
you can make it so the only nash equilibrium is to help both players playing
OK and the reason is that
this part is a losing proposition
so if you're instead having some probability and playing foosball and some probably rock paper