so this is this is pure covalency
this is pure covalency this is polar covalent see what call a polar covalent because
if you look at this molecule you say that well the electrons are a little
bit closer to the right and the left so the charges and uniformly distributed its
net neutral molecules that neutral but this right and there's a little bit more negative
and the left hand is a little bit more positive and physics when fizzes was
a little bit of citizens rights case delta that's physics talked for a little bit
so this is a little bit negative this a little bit positive
which means I could model this by
a dipole
this is a dipole
it's got negative and the positive and and it has certain properties if we put
a dipole that has the freedom to move we put the dipole in an electric
field it will align itself with the field lines so because this is a dipole
he chose the Pol part of dipole to give us polar covalent C and what's
the ultimate what's the what's the extreme of of unequal sharing its its electron transfer
so this is a perfect sharing unequal sharing and here
the electrons are not actually donated so this becomes f minus this is the of
an electron it's an a plus and so this 1 here I going say let's
very than the longest 1 OK this is
this is the ultimate in unequal sharing and this is ironic and this is ionic
so you can see that polar covalent C is tendency towards ionic bonding and that's
why pollen call this partial ionic character and universally quantified the quantified by this formula
he said that the % ionic character and this is within a bond of a
compound this is cent ionic character for
a covalent bond
for covalent bond he said that's going to equal one minus
the exponential this is just basic natural logarithms e to the power of minus 1
quarter times the difference in electronegativities squared so it's this thing again this universe electronegativity
squaring multiplied by a quarter
and raise that to the power of E subtract that from 1 multiplied by a
hundred and you have something between 0 and 100 and
I think there's some evidence of that here
so this is right out of your periodic table if you look up in the
corner your periodic table in 1 of the sides that they've actually tabulated this for
so I've rewritten the formula here and these are the 2 different scales of ionic
character 1 by piling actually there's more than 2 but in they show these 2
there's polymers 1 Hannes Meyer and so here's pollen and
we could we could do this for a
or compound here HF for HF just for grins and chuckles let's do it the
electronegativity of chlorine is 3 . 9 8 and electronegativity of H is 2 .
2 all on this scale and so if you plug these values into this formula
that will give you that the percentage of ionic character for the bond and see
and I want to make sure that you don't think that this is the cent
of character of the compounds on 1 of the really festivities here and indicate that
I'm talking about the age of bond if you plug into this formula here you
end up with a
of about 50 60 % and that's already been tabulated up there in the normal
graph see Figure that I think delta heroes of 1 . 5 7 8 which
is roughly 1 . 0 in the using 56 now how does that just to
give you a sense of what that means if the 264 figures pure covalency and
the 344 as partial ionic character what fraction of the 608 344
344 which is partial ionic character divided by 6 0 wait times 100 is 57
% so it makes sense that makes sense
that's good we can do all sorts of things the same site I indicated the
molecule there's another of orthography that's used to indicate dipole you can use delta minus
delta plus some people like to use an error and the arrow points in the
direction of the more electronegative
and when I remember that is little across here and I think that the pluses
and you you can have your own mnemonic device to figure that out anyway so
let's what's going to look at another 1 I think last professor Belanger did this
only just hybridisation method right so there's nothing nothing looks like this with the SP
three hybridization so let's let's look at that we see here we've got a dipole
we only have 1 bond so the actual H. F. molecules HF molecule is polar
HF molecule was polar hasn't died whereas H
2 is non polar
H 2 nonpolar how I know its charge distributions perfectly symmetric the electrons here are
shared equally
so that's non polar and likewise for fluorine F 2 so let's look at thing
so methane we can draw it looks like this get carbon SP three hybridization right
CH 4 years as 3 carbon hybridisation allows for monster form who has Sinaga hydrogens
at the 4 corners of the tetrahedra
so I wanna ask what's the nature the carbon hydrogen bonds
was each carbon hydrogen bond and I look up and I see that the electronegativity
of carbon is 2 . 5 5 and electronegativity of hydrogen and we already know
is 2 . 2 0 so there's difference electronegativity since carbons electronegativity is higher than
that of hydrogen which you'd expect from where carbon lies on the periodic table think
about it and see if you know the periodic table then you know where relative
elements where elements are relative to 1 another so at any moment you know in
any bond which is the more electropositive
electropositive is down to the left because that's where the metals
so carbons right hydrogen this is more electronegative so let's look at this carbon hydrogen
i mean was the forward
the result will depend on the world but if we want to approximate
the things
o model
you'll waste
and that's it
the importance of twenty one
the assumption in the rich which is required to make the best of all is
that you can compute
you want
in the simplest
from this
is the
genetic sequence of points
this is the way
and sequence of approximate solutions to sort out point is generated
they fought
you can build this point this
that might come about only by
multiply by the
and the problem of
that intermediate points
that in the same
you take it do exactly the same but the
the value of your data for five what the point is that in minus one
of the
OK but again you approximate the centre of this process like this in the u
well you also
oppose thomas is the best way
OK that's it your search warrants
well this is out that
you've said that she's out
some sort of
and here is that all the results of the full
assume that you're
the gradient is called the continuous peninsula
OK how do we measure the mass of in the distance between the
the long
and the distance between them
because it was
if you will
sort of the wisdom of all of the with the problem is the last all
i believe
this is
it is the maximum of during linear form the universe
the normal operating
it's where the nature of the phi actually world
all right
what is the evidence
one of
a of
and that's what the explicit space policy differs according to the rate of convergence depends
on boastful but only one
this the need to be what you get
most cases seem is the idea of the means
say a the
so what
well known
you're telling what you want to see what might
what the problem of finding the right spot
now as you may also want it means that your right
OK and then you get this sort of components one two with both is one
you get the convergence
on the way the by biting
this all forms that of the
right course
one is independent of the data and use it out that this is one of
the first world war fall
and you see how the world depends
and also how it depends on the distance generate
the goal was put out
now can come up with just straight some of the best possible
you know how to approximate this
it was several situations where
so what i did for the so-called untouchables what
a point x is the same label
it's good about
seven gas
and that's not the point of the opposite
and this gap gamma right here defines wilderness survival given enough function
this an example of a notion of
so for instance said that the similarity between and two
positive examples of police point two
the similarity between and to negative that and examples still is o point on the
dissimilarity between a positive example another example is the random number reminds one of
on the left-hand side you need to point to the right hand side to be
so this is satisfy notion flats along c and i don't want to just
a simple example
and actually if you think about it
in space is large enough is known to get chances be similarity function will another
so this looks like a very reasonable notion of what to ask
but what about the function
moreover if you had a similarity function satisfying these are very condition then also have
a very
efficient learning i
so what all have to do in this case is to just throw a bunch
of positive examples of of negative examples and then steamed out the classification rule
that classifies an example x is positive
on average
most similar examples in this class
this negative otherwise so this is not the definition is not good enough to get
to what kind of functions are not just the simplest spot point
OK so let me
i'll come to the main notion beat
i'm not claiming that we have this is
not just kind of functions to see an example in sec
so in that case so if we had a similarity function satisfying this condition
there and we had to have
we can use a simple and they start
we draw a bunch of positive examples about negative examples and the classification rule that
classifies an example x
if it's an average more similar examples in this class the money and that he
otherwise on the ground we get is that if set s plus in this minus
has size at least one of them are square loss one the concepts of time
then had privately someone that the classification with output has at most epsilon last at
some time
it's not easy to get an array to choose arbitrary close
two the fraction of the examples it failed to satisfy this requirement
that is more similar to examples of level that examples of it was OK this
is the perfection is not very complicated and we go free
it's actually very simple so first let's take a quick example at solar six an
example that satisfies this condition here
the band imagine something the census plus and minus
then can show that the probability of error respect or even
good example x is at most times sort of prime and this follows from the
a simple application of standard station acquired like hoeffding inequality
now since this is true for any given fixed it's a good example x but
then is the expected error of our procedure the set of good examples that most
of the times
and so
it means that the markov inequality together there is at most of the chance
but the error rate
over the set of with examples is greater than absolute right
and then by adding back the fraction of examples
failing to satisfy this inequality we get them to decide
the error the classification of the output is at most epsilon
that's it
so if we had the same semantic funds signed this condition then you have to
be able to learn that was
however it turns out is you might expect that not all what kind of functions
are going to satisfy this condition
he would and
to be hard to imagine what kind of functions satisfy this condition because otherwise it
would be really interesting learning that was like is just use is trivial and does
not one
but here is the concrete examples showing that strange but not all what kind of
functions are good similarity functions
it is
for this example imagine that the point without examples of point in the two dimensional
euclidean space
and that the similarity function but they can see that the kernel function to can
that exist on the product is two-dimensional
in space
and imagine that there are distributions looks like this one here so the
positive examples as being equally among upper left and upper right
and the negative examples lie on here
just for simplicity imagine that distribution is sixty feet so
other examples have also been found examples and
now if we
consider an appropriate bank right here and particularly if to get an angle of thirty
then clearly these kind of function similarity function can have a very large margins the
margin going to be a constant going to be
you can easily verify that this similarity function fails to satisfy this condition over here
and it does so even before
so long of course even for that long they one
a large fraction of examples of the positive examples namely all the positive examples like
however hard productive
then the negative examples
and they have on with the example particle the product of
and the negative example is we can verify to half whether product or know
a positive example of your half sample as a whole
band hot water
OK so
this is an example where
it was similarity function
link function what kind of functions what kind of functions as the with large margin
but if it fails to satisfy all symbols notion of was not much
it is it is in this simple example right here we simply ignore all the
positive examples here in the upper left
where and competing expectations
that's fine
as of these that suggests trying to broaden the definition as follows
we're going to say that all similarity function is what similarity function problem problem
if exists a large enough set off
reasonable points
sergeant most of the examples acts on average more similar to reasonable points of overall
labels then that resemble point of the opposite label
OK now that you don't even need to
no is set in advance
we seem to have two
i hope but it exists
for services besides the our main definition does alter the protein have so
for money
we say that k
assessment or similarity function is an absolute garment how
good similarity function if there exists a set r of reasonable points
so i most of examples x
one is the fraction of examples x satisfy the property but the expected stimuli reasonable
point of wrong labels
is going to buy lease to certain get
which if you think about it is a very strange thing right in your probability
of smoking depends on the difference small
you're probability of having the flu
is not just a function of your symptoms it's also function of you know whether
the flu epidemic going around and you have been in contact with somebody who has
the full
this is very easy to fix this is very difficult to express in this kind
of models but very easy to express in markov logic as we just saw
so this is sort of like the statistical site
what about logical side
well it's probably fairly intuitive there
infinite weights give first order logic is a special case of markov logic civil at
all no it's good infinity
then you pay infinite penalty for violating formula and you retrieve back the first of
the case and we have the theorem that says you can answer all entailment quiz
in first order logic by computing conditional probabilities on the markov logic network that you
get by taking the formulas and giving them infinite weights
so this is nice though we first order logic is a special case but of
course we really interested in the case where the weights are finite
so what can we say there
well if the knowledge base is satisfiable
meaning it's possible to make all the formula is true at the same time
and although it's are positive
which you can always ensured by flipping by negating formulas and their weights
the satisfying assignments are the most of the distribution
which means that even in the finite noisy case
the world that first-order logic likes this feeling that the modes of the distribution
OK and we're gonna make very good use of this when it comes time to
do inference
but of course the most important thing about markov logic is that unlike in logic
where if you have a contradiction in the in the knowledge base now pigs fly
and anything can happen markov logic has no problem with contradictions between four
if there is a contradiction markov logic just where the evidence on each side and
produces the probability for the formula
so now it's actually easy to build large knowledge bases because you have to look
at least in this respect of course because you don't have to make sure that
there no consistent anymore
and more importantly it's easy to do things like the semantic web
well you have contributions from many different people and there is no hope of ever
making them more consistent but you still want to be able to reason with those
contributions OK so markov logic it was at this level this this becomes pretty straightforward
OK so let me talk a little bit about the inference and learning algorithms now
of course
this will be only of theoretical interest if we didn't have such efficient inference and
learning algorithms enough
you know it's a long way to go and make them more efficient but we've
also come a very long way already and we can definitely handle a lot of
rule real problems with what we have today so let's look at that a little
let's start by looking at inference
one of the most frequent and most useful types of inference that people want to
is what's called MEP maximum upper styria or it or MP
most probable explanation inference
and this consists of a given some evidence
what's called the next
finding the most likely state of the world
i e the most likely values of another set of variables y
you can think of this as finding the most probable explanation for what you see
here are the symptoms what is the most probable disease that explains the
for those of you know for example by hmm this is what the viterbi algorithm
is doing
so what does this mean in markov logic well let's replace this p of y
given x by the expression that we saw before right so we thought we want
to find the white
that maximizes this
this is constant this is monotonically increasing function so to maximize this all have to
maximize is what's inside here
what you what are we doing here
we were trying to find the assignment of values to the variables
that maximizes the sum of the weights of the ground
one was that you
surprise surprise this is just the weighted maxsat problem
right the satisfiability problem which is try to satisfy all formulas in a liquid essential
NP complete problem the max that problem is trying to satisfy as many as possible
the weighted next SAT problem is winning formula has the weight
and you want to maximize the weight of satisfied formulas
and the reason this is very nice us is that
we don't have to invent anything new to do inference in markov logic we can
just use an off-the-shelf which SAT
like for example maxwalksat
and we can take advantage of the last fifty years of intensive research on SAT
but is sets of us can handle problems with millions of variables in minutes or
seconds and are going to take advantage of that in all the future improvements of
the continuing research on the subject
and the number
like very surprising and i think that falls out of this is that we start
going in
if you think about first order logic inference is not renowned for being fast
and neither is probabilistic inference if you combine the two
you probably have really be near the surprising thing is that it turns out that
using this scheme
we can actually do inference in markov logic faster
then inference in first order logic
and the reason i can do it faster is that as we will see shortly
maxwalksat it's pretty much the exact same algorithm with very minor change as well you
we is know process liability point one but owing to the
if i did some of the constraints that were previously hard which should have been
and make them soft and i have an easy problem to solve and therefore can
solve it in a few
fewer steps
such systems are often when we make the first knowledge-based soft the inference on that
we actually save time interest and in the process
so for those of you not familiar with satisfiability solvers is is it actually is
easy to explain something like walks in just one slide
it's incredible how powerful it is given how simple it is so the goal of
the walksat
is to find an assignment of truth values to billion
the labels
it stays in this interval until t four
and said OK
let's say that the function is between two f one three at line
over a region of size t two minus t one which is the size interval
plus t four minus thirty three which is the size
and instead of saying size
he said size gets too confusing so i call measure instead
and that was the beginning in measure theory essentially that other people talked about matter
before the bag there are a lot of famous mathematicians who were all involved in
doing this
but but anyway
so that's the basic idea
what matters concerned with now for this curve here
it's a nice smooth curve
and you can almost see intuitively that you're going to get the same thing as
looking at it this way
and in fact you do
and anyway what he finally wound up with this after saying what the matter was
on each one of those little slices how much of the functional a in each
one of those intervals would just add them all up
he would add up how much of the function was any flies he would multiply
how much the function within the slice
but how high the place was up
and then you get an answer
one difference between what he did
and what reminded
was that he was going to lower bound and doing it this way if he
was dealing with the non negative functions
his approximation was always a little less than what the function was because anything that
lay between two epsilon three excellent he would approximated this to work the line which
is a little less
then numbers between two epsilon three long so this is the lower bound
whereas this is is whatever happens to be a however you decide to approximate the
function here
there are lots of ways of doing it
OK i will prove any of these things i just want to point them out
so that when you get frustrated with this
you can always rely on this
which says whenever they reminded the rule exists in other words whenever the integral if
you're used to
namely whenever it has meaning
the integral gives you the same value
OK in other words if you haven't lost anything
by going from remind integration to the bank integration you can only gain you can't
the familiar rules for calculating reminded of rules also apply for the bacon across
OK remember what all those rules are you probably know all of them better
better even fundamental definition of an integral which is split up the function at the
time tiny little
little increments because throughout
all of the courses that you've taken learning about integration learning about differentiation learning about
all of these things what you've done for the most part
it's the go through exercises using these various rules
so you know how how to integrate lots of lots of traditional functions you memorize
what the role of many of them is
you have many ways of combining them to find out what the in rule of
many other functions is
if you program a computer to calculate these integrals are computer can do it both
you can either use all the rules to find out what the value of the
integral is or can shop things that finally find out that way
and as i said before
if you
if you think that being able to calculate integrals is what engineering is about think
again i told you before you can be replaced by a digital computer
it's worse than that
you could be replaced by year by year handheld palm palm whatever it's called OK
you can be replaced by anything
after a while we're little things embedded in our body will tell us when we're
second things like this you can be replaced by those things even
OK so
so you really want to learn more than just that
OK for some very weird functions built by general exist but rely april doesn't exist
why do we want to worry about weird functions
i want to tell you two reasons for i told you about it last time
one thing is
awful lot of communication theory
is concerned
we're going back and forth between the time domain
in the frequency domain
when you talk about things which are
straightforward in the time domain
often they become very very weird in the frequency domain and vice versa
i'm going to give you beautiful example of that
probably the next probably class you can look at it
it is in it is in in the appendix
you see this absolutely weird functions
which has the perfectly well-defined fourier transform
and therefore the inverse fourier transform this nice looking thing is absolutely we're
the other reason is even more important we have to deal with random processes we
have to deal with noise functions
which are continuously varying functions of time
we have to deal with what we transmit which is continuously varying functions of time
and just like when we were dealing with sources
he said if we want to compress the source
it's not enough to think about what one source sequences we have to think about
namely we have to model
these functions
as as sample values
what we call
a stochastic process or random process
originally start talking about that these functions which already look complicated just become sample points
and this much bigger space
we're dealing with random processes
now when you're dealing with sample points of these random processes
we are in this just crops up as a necessary part of all of this
you can define a random process which consists of only non weird things
if you do you get something that doesn't work very well it doesn't do much
for more
people do that all the time but you run out of steam with a very
very quickly
OK so for both reasons we have to be able to deal with where things
the most ideal thing is to be able to deal with the weird things and
get rid of them without even thinking about them
what's the nice thing about the big theory
it lets you get rid of all we're in this without even thinking about it
but in order to understand to start with so we get rid of all that
weird stuff
we have to understand just a little bit about what it's about to start with
OK so that's
that's where we're going
in this picture
but the picture back out again
i sort of left something very nice well-behaved function
it's easy to find out what the
what to measure
of a the function is namely what what the measure is the set of values
where you're in some tiny little interval
and that's straightforward it was just the summary
just the some of the bunch of intervals
but now we come to the to the clincher which is we want to be
knowledge based systems era
which takes us up to about
nineteen seventy nine
we made into
period where
expert systems actually my people money
so i guess the most famous one
from from that period consistent with the deck which is
dexter around this computer digital equipment corporation probably change something now something else now
but they had an expert system they used to configure ordered that computers
it was estimated that it was saying the company that forty million dollars a year
there are they're related stories in the kind of things
american military got similar kinds of stories that i i technology saving
very large amounts of money
so that was good
in that same period there was a project started in japan called the fifth generation
why fifth-generation while somehow the fall before the nodes of quite work that
just what they were counting but anyway
it was the fifth generation projects
because in almost all the time
started about nineteen eighty
one also
went into the nineties
ten is one of the longer than that
and it was
it caused quite a stir because it was
didn't follow the american style
artificial intelligence which was based on this
it is
more european language prolog
public based on logic
this is based on a different kind of
mathematical foundation
this was the way americans did i i and they could imagine
the other way
and when the japanese chose problog
the tracking of attention
the first generation project was attempt to jump ahead
and build
they don't exactly talk about i have talked about solving
i kinds of problems with new kinds of computers
based on
logical foundations
and highly parallel
so we went for
about ten years ago but longer
in fact i personally had a connection with i spent six weeks at tree in
turkey which was
an amazing experience
the project itself
on the whole
it was an incredibly successful there remember now
so at the beginning was better than the end
in the end
the a little less than other people which is that it's very hard to beat
general purpose
so the idea here is to build special purpose hardware
does logical inference very rapidly and problem incredibly fast and power
OK so the standard part meanwhile into was making making the general purpose
o processors faster and faster
by the end until we find just as fast as which is that the better
so in fact trying to build special purpose troops
this turned out not to be successful thing to do
and forcing the japanese politics of that
on the other hand many this got jobs fifth-generation project because a lot of money
in the last round
in the UK
the project was started
lots of jobs created
and we shared some of that and the MCC which is the microelectronics and computer
corporation was started in the US
so called all the countries are very
i guess
motivated to try and match the fifth generation project
and lots of
it had lots of good side effects one of them was to get people to
a i and to
what programming and related areas
OK so the next is
the period of the nineteen eighties into the early nineteen nineties
and members to about neurons before the very beginning mcculloch and pitts
and then there was a period where
it somehow
funding died because it was some theorems prove said
you know was could do certain things in fact it was pretty clear that this
was not good objection anyway
in the early eighties the number of people
discovered what's called the backpropagation algorithm for neural networks so neural network is a collection
of neurons
and signals come in
and the computer results
the y
and these things have to be trained
and the training is in terms of weights between the different neurons
so there's a whole bunch of parameters
they can be hundreds and hundreds of parameters which these weights
and you want to write weights
the computed result
so things how to train
and the backpropagation algorithm was independently discovered by a whole bunch of people
basically it's a way of
pushing data through the neural network and then back propagating it to upgrade upgrade the
and you do this ten thousand times you get a neural network that learns what
you want to learn
so that was anomalies enormously successful technology and very very widely used as to what
is today the neural networks as
probably still
the most widely used machine learning technology
so you're networks made a recovery point
and then moving from the eighties into them say the early nineties
and that's the forces
the euclidean space is an example of symmetric positive definite by linear form semantic because
if there's a competitiveness involves
all rights
so many men involved in the manifold is a differentiable manifold can reach each tangent
space has an inner product so this is important we can define an inner product
metric inducing in norm for the tangent vector so now we know which means that
i can go to compute distances in that
it's possible to define different metrics so
are you end up
the difference between different many manifolds
this talk about to do this do is more
curve that joins the points along the shortest spread on the manifold
the way to do this is important because it use it as the minimum distance
between two points on the manifold so you know there's a twice the shortest frying
from boston to istanbul is not can conform the metadata
line but it's kind of they opened this curve is the geodesic
this measurement is not explored and shows great
in the
the together numbers it is what define now the explanation that the next the vector
in the tangent space
to the point on the manifold so the defining a mapping from the tangent spaces
to back to the manifold
and it is the property that a geodesic e
reaches all of two units are for instance of
the value that it
i have
o point is a point on the on y is equal to one of the
by the victors velocities piecewise constant for geophysics but it's not going to give you
that i mean to commodities arm
under the exponential map to each of the zero zero tangent vector is the point
it means that you are defining these explanations only for a specific point on the
manifold which means that if i moved to another point when don't change
of the four not change but can affect the result is going to change so
these operators are defined point specific
since the best stone to do do this it is constant length of the geodesic
is given by the norm of the initial velocity and this is the kind norm
on this issue
all right for each point on the manifold we the exponential map is a diffeomorphism
which means one old and differentiable mappings in both directions by the inverse mapping x
is only defined in the neighborhood points and think about negative a real or complex
numbers of
one is kind of mapping contains the other one is only defined only on the
neighborhood this like the one in small neighborhood are assumptions are going to be that
this is kind of an illustration showing the geodesic between two points
and a mapping from manifold to
tangent space and i just remember this thing this still if you want to talk
about manifold learning having to go from meaningful to tangent space
because to complicated space between euclidean space which is just the logarithm operation
and your application is what you need to look at spatial morgan i'm gonna can
talk about the thing and it is also a
making to go back to the manifold because you might be interested in the origin
of this could like that this a structure of an object are so this
these are the two things you may want to kind of keep in mind
that is a couple more slides before the brain stars by the formal definition of
duties against the explanation that the distance between two points on a manifold can be
computed as the distance between the point on the manifold and kind of a is
ten just space correspondence on the manifold a but as i mentioned the and it
can be found in all
and by on the tangent space and this makes sense from that point on the
tangent space and two here is the same thing written because this is an inner
product and this the thing i showed you before
for many many false than during an inverse mapping can dive right these things
which means that i'm gonna multiply left multiply
one of the points on the manifold commercial the one of the points
there are one this can be defined in distance
all right well about these local and explanation thing right
the talk has two parts
the first part
i will be by are to set
another an introduction before and so to to kind of create to set up for
people haven't seen this before
i know will basically be talking about
particle filtering for state space models and we will discuss some algorithms that we need
a lot of us are very familiar with in this community
but then he will introduce some
recent new development that he's been working on with colleagues where he's looking at asia's
of parameter learning not just filtering in state estimation but trying to go beyond due
to tackle problems like smoothing
and learning
after that we
this tutorial kind of log so we're going to have a short break
and then i will look into particle filtering
but i will consider the type of problems that we don't often
the deal with
things like igon value problems protein folding problems control problems
and static distributions
and so on and also some very interesting ways of learning ABC ABC is like
this really cool
bayesian technique where you can learn if you can imagine as basic so
only these four topics were covered basically the end of the twentieth century
and most of what we're going to talk about
will be new things
many many people in this community have worked in this problem
and many communities to have attacked this problem
people in control people in signal processing people and statistics
physics and so on and they'll give them method different names and slightly different methodologies
and we'll try to
bring to your attention some of these
in machine learning the method became popular with andrew blake michael is the computer vision
applications a sort of those show you some examples
many people have contributed to the method and now i have listed some here
without mentioning
just so already known face he's done a lot of work on this too and
i'm sure i'm missing some of you in the audience
so what's particle filtering so it's a technique for approximating
and that evolve over time that have some sort of dynamics
but it can also be used for static distributions is out of
about the DNA full for now let's consider dynamic distributions
the idea is we want to approximate the distribution
and the way we do it is we draw samples from this thread distribution
and then if we just count how many samples full image then we get histogram
is approximation of this
and we can give weight to these
different samples which is what we call particles as well
and that allows us to get a good representation of this
and here we can see how these particles propagate over time
and if they are doing well
they get bigger weight
so this sort of the survival of the fittest
aspect to this
and yet another
picture of the same thing we you showed this to how the distribution is evolving
over time
you're able to in this case tracker target that actually has two
possible hypotheses of what could be god
and so you have to maintain a hypothesis
so here's an example
how you can use
particles here just you trying to estimate the probability distribution over the location of these
play is being tracked
and each of these little boxes like in this layers of particles
and then when you take the average of sort of ketamine
track these things in video on the TV
we then project them to the world using some basic geometry
and then you have sort of trajectories you know what the person was doing
in this case in the game
OK i have added question
for the first part
here are some bigger
the first is
or coca cola
during the forty four years fields
in the from the need to be these aren't heal
almost now
here is the one over and times longer than which is the average growth rate
you could see that the
the average growth rate
goldberg is fairly quickly
plus number
we which is about all all all
o five or something like that
that's a very small number
and also one may ask that there
the conditions on friday the eighth of the ideal assume that the
the classes of three there is stationary stationary but it brought which means that the
all the multidimensional distributions are invariant under the time changes
so the distribution of the segment
today is the same as the distribution of the segment of the same length
three years later
these figure
does not contradict the
could be the function
and here is the histogram
it is
here you can see the
fifty the normal that it would be his ograms
it is it has the mean
or or all peaks
and the standard deviation of the group of the area
twenty five times larger than these small holes the wall
because it has a mean very close
who who who won
if scale is on the return and the
in the region up on the log
so the the mean is very very close to to one
and interesting point is that it is not symmetric distribution
so that the probability that is likely to be crazy
is larger than the probability of life increase
of the SS
and the base sequence of three
along and as that either very hard to predict essentially impossible to predict
because of the
very few large standard deviation because of the very large red area of
back to the mean of the
and feel
using such read the sequence
we we'll be very successful or
the log optimum
portfolio selection four and the goal of optimal portfolio selection
this is one the
property what i can extract from the the the good i don't know who much
about the reasoning behind the cart
on what
we haven't made such
this is the
same for IBM
and here the histogram has similar shape
they are they
the derivative of the probability that the problem
so this parameter actually
one when is sequence position is
so that
so essentially we replace i mean poor
we have this
during metric so the number of letters by the number of positions
so there the derivative of that one is going to be all of europe except
except the position where we have a letter in policy is just like a binary
representation of secret
and if you know take the perspective i mean take this magic make it
and take this kind of approach this is going to be identical with the baby
you can just
one of the competition this year
OK i there
right the locked up here and then this
in the summer right
and then
this mistake
you should
the log p and then the product becomes
and then we get the new one
thank you
so it should be so
questions but i always replace the fisher information metric with the like the identity matrix
anything that i do
i guess when i learn a linear classifier on top of this i mean the
fisher information metric only like stretching dimensions and rotating in it's way for a kernel
classifier doesn't really matter whether you rotate data maybe it matters whether stretch
but rotating at least doesn't change your life
so for when you when you learn SVM based on the future already
make a big difference
but i will usually ignore them because it's quite expensive to efficiently
OK so
this was one kernel which was
pine based on probabilistic models and i give you two examples
where we use similarity measure
to define
so this is one which is called the pairwise comparison
so the general idea is that the
program for computing similarity score between two sequence so this is an alignment program
OK called block and that gives us a score for each
possible health bring
how can we use this string for this these alignments
so we cannot directly use the similarity between the because that's not going to be
what you can do it so we can take
all the sequences but we have in the training set and compare all the examples
each other
then take
like one goal of
as the vector of features
the problem is that we have to compare all sequences with each other and then
you have to compute scalar product quite long only this leads to fight high computational
costs in the u n is the number of training
slightly better kernel is the local alignment kernel
he is some more definitions
OK so
the idea of the local alignment is that you define
based on the substitution method and and based on can be used to find score
for certain alignment
think like with you
and sequence that the left image quite well
i l i e
this works as long as
the speed
is much smaller than
the speed of light
if that's no longer the case
then we have to apply
special relativity
and that is not part of this course
but i would like to briefly touched upon that today
i can show you
how things go sour
because suppose we have a
five hundred
you know
of electron
four that means that in this equation here
is five hundred thousand
q is the charge of the electron
and is now the mass of the electron
and if i applied that equation
i find that v is four point two
times ten thirty eight
beta the second
and that is larger
and the speed of light that's clearly not possible
the actual speed if you make relativistic corrections
is two point six
ten thirty eight
meters per second
and although i don't expect you to be able to make those relativistic corrections
i will make them today
you will see why i have two
and i want to show you
that in fact
this is not all that difficult
even though i will not hold you responsible
forty equations
so what i have here
is now
kinetic energy
again qv
that's not changing
it is no longer one half MV squared
this gonna minus one times MC squared and gamma
defined their called to lawrence factor
so if you know now for the electron
that capital these five hundred thousand
you can calculate what organised from the first equation
and then you go to the second equation you find speed is you'll see that
that you never find this being larger
the speed of light
and so
we now have to make a correction also
forty eighty i
and those corrections become
relatively easy
this now requires effective come and see that
on the upper blackboard there
and these two now
it has to be replaced by government was one and then everything
is OK
so i don't expect you to know this
but i don't want you to think that all these relative the corrections come out
of the blue
nor do i want you to think that is very difficult really is
in equations are extremely straightforward
i want to show you now the
some of the results that we just
the one MTV proton
and the five hundred kv
this is on the web
you can click on lectures supplement and you can make yourself
hard copy
so you see the kinetic energy
one of the proton
notice the speed that we calculated their non relativistic government very close to one you
don't have to make corrections
and in one thousand light field
you get a radius of fifteen centimetres
we just calculated
if you go to a fifty and the proton
sort of on the borderline between relativistic and non relativistic
still non relativistic enough
and it is non relativistic
you can clearly see here
that's the radius
goes with the square root of capitol hill
and for fifty mv
capital fierce fifty million
and for one in the capital is one million
and since it goes with the square root of the you expect roughly the radius
to be square root of fifty times larger which is seven
and indeed you see that
that's my information
in fact extraction so we continue with machinery
towards the end will also speak somehow about future research things well
research we would like to do
which we are not aliens
to execute but i think it is just
because it might also like this for you to
for doing research in this area
we we thought that so yes
somehow all
the problem that
when you communicate through text
there are many many
variables that are interdependent
so actually
what we see in a text what we see and what right
of depends on the context so the words are not used in isolation
the used
in this system configuration in this country is in the
it supported the examples
if you are looking for
named entities
so you want to classify words such as persons locations
and you have to you
well it could be
a location but new york times text is an organisation
so how
well it's actually from the context from the rest of the round
new york
that you can infer from this that there is mounting location station
to summarize
communication that language has some structure and
exploring the structure also when using machine learning techniques for instance we have sequences
a sentence has worked in a certain sequence
and in some language is the position of the words in the sentence can make
a big difference between the two
i'd like see
but in english for instance
the subject is used
one of the first word the first nouns sentence followed by
and it follows that i object to that
so this
but also s communication is kind of
i structure
and this is more when we look into scores
let's just look at the table of contents in the book
it's structure you have some topics through topics which
find more detail topics as well by the search
so maybe we can exploit also this hierarchical structure
i mean
thank you
so we decided to
this course
it is the word
fact extraction so most of what we are
this course is in fact extraction fact extraction as i mentioned already is something you
be able to to do so we can extract facts certain from sentences
so we
this fact extraction
it could benefit from modeling in this context at least some slack
but i think it's fixed line should move beyond such fact extraction
remind you might be to
this is not substantial support from
so just write
but you can mention especially fields like
like this
especially for instance in LA
you seem many abstract concepts and maybe you also to
just maybe not only to expect certain facts
maybe along with you might have occurred in fact
the number of people can for instance
this can do it you might want to go beyond extracts
system concepts
hi level concepts from
the text the
and we want to integrate this context
and this is the actual fruitful life
on the first try to get right
first of all let's get
what turns have
the so
article as
there is a function of about
in fact the
i trust you
o of
one of the four
are around
part of lot of
in terms of
of the
one year on what you want to have
it not hard
thank you
the fact that he
for the rest
who are different
all right well
o to right
one of the structure of
the problem
on the average IQ
like the other half distance so you will definitely bring them
it is more many more
is that
what for example what is not good it's more and more
is this the right so here i have degree distribution right and i was just
showing you that it's the power right and this is not a power right
so what is so the thing is people usually just like go for four they
will discover something and then they would try to find the model that would explain
that so profoundly probability distributions and they said OK preferential then they found clustering this
triangles and they were saying oh how can we model that all here is the
small world model
the small world model won't get you won't get to power law degree distribution so
if you want one if you want more difficult one the other hand the other
OK this is an obviously would get about something a property that is the model
but get to that property but there is that was very few say what if
i want to all of them were can i find the generated throughout the can
all of them
and this is what i show
three days
so what
so what is the question
the question is this
maybe try
because we are talking about small world one
otherwise there is no
the clustering coefficient is defined by the clustering coefficient is calculated so it should be
defined not it's not of the clustering coefficient is that is the right you have
your clustering coefficient of of what it takes to be the case right
should be one or
right to exclude the k then you want to ask how many possible triangles that
which means which this is the number of possible triangles right
and here i call i say number of triangles
so what what he says if i have over six
like this
and i know something like this then i say how many possible triangles are that
it's cages to
so thank need to select two this is this is the total number of one
thank could you could be here here here here and so on
and i say OK there are two up the two out of whatever
five just OK
so this is clustering coefficient and then what you can do actually i should say
i should say this so this is what a particular x now ck just the
average over all its vertices where the of that particular degree
and this is now you can plot this called this distribution of the clustering coefficient
and then if you want to see
this is a single c that going again average or what right so there are
this is this is what
i think the important is that we do not
it it is connected component
i don't understand
i mean what it says right which makes sense is if that's me and i
have two friends and there is a higher probability of of the of the two
people knowing each other right and this is something that definitely true or real for
social networks like let's go back
OK the other thing for which
i don't know
i want to go into too much detail is that
there are also because study spectral properties of graphs which means that you can take
your graph adjacency matrix right where where you have one there an edge and you
have zero if there's no edge right and i can do if the graph is
undirected and you can look like a principal component analysis or you can do SVD
so that you get basically get arguments and i connect and if you plot the
distribution of this you'll find that it's cute
one interpretation is that they call it the spectral gap in the spectral gap measures
the the difference between first and second i can value and then that you how
how how nice the graph with cost which means home ice communities are there in
the cluster OK but that's
let's go on
so for example in them so this what this is all for static graphs for
temporal graph for temporal patterns that are too that one is
basic question but you want to ask what is the relation between the number of
nodes and the number of edges over time
right and
right so he would say n is the number of nodes at time t is
the number of edges at time t five w the number of nodes with the
number of edges also w
OK and
it turns out it will
it will more than doubled and
how you can reason about this is if you plotted on log so here the
number of nodes at time t
number of edges at time t and you blocked both on log log scale
and you will see it follows pretty much like right and if the relation with
thing many this line should have slope one
if the graph is fully connected or if it's core every node has like links
to the prove to the constant cost
part of the network then this should be to right so the
the exponent
this is a this slope should be between one and two one means you have
the linear growth of the number of edges right here
or you can have quadratic growth of the number of features OK so this is
what what has been found for foreground that evolve over time so that they are
basically getting down
OK and so this is what i also explained that if you
if you have a close one then you have the growth which
because the average degree the in the in the graph is constant and if you
have any questions that you then you have growth which means that
you're getting ready dense graphs right
because everyone is like connected to the constant fraction of the of the network
and this i will skip
and the other thing that is also surprising for evolving networks is a few
if you ask how the distances increase of my network gets louder and
no conventional wisdom or results in existing models tell you i would say that this
is slowly increase like log n log log n and things like that so if
the the and the number of nodes gets larger the
the diameter will slowly
this is what happens if you if you measure these things over time right so
here for example this is a citation after that from nineteen ninety two to two
thousand three
and diameter decreases right now the question is so i showed you all these
and so
this is just just a short list of
well of types of networks where these patterns of these properties can be found so
we would like when you have webpages hyper links online communities would be i know
friends and things like that who calls who is like and from making tea
you have four numbers in who course home of autonomous systems that are you can
think of them
you can think of them as the out or like IBM dot com is an
autonomous systems and make it is an autonomous systems all this autonomous systems like like
about packages between each other you can do the actual out
for the second one you can like bipartite graph like movie stock actors you can
system where we have some input on this thing called and
the output is determined by
weighting the input
this is very similar to the situation so that's what we have is when you're
in the perceptron and that's what we have
so what i did before which i
an output
as the principal component
and we're looking for it to have this property so so we can
david so that
these weights actually corresponds to this this
then we would have no network that was producing
the principal components for that will be the principal component score of x
it is one so
so it's obvious if we combine that w nicholson
then vehicle to one this was and sort
what we trying to do
here is
if i do the normalizing trade i did above
or just justice entering the of it
it turns out that the variance of y
just the one j squares of
divided by minus one
and also onto shared the top of the tree
so if i want to get your network to play principal components analysis then what
should be doing is making the squared output
the y
it was about and what the variance to maximize so this
so the output must once upon a time i y two
that i want to have the property that this is because it could be
but it still has to be worked out from
time the white
so g
is the obvious if i just by what is to just a double w
this just get bigger and bigger and bigger might double trouble and so on copenhagen
or not because it's quantity
so i just the by the way if technology is replaced with rule by three
then that once will be big
just keep getting higher high so so
i have to do something to stop the big big enough to choose the weights
in of the constraints of
so what do is
is this constraint
make the length of w is the vector w equal to one
so what's the squared length
it's the same
so that we together what was saying is this
maximize the squared outputs
so you see the whites
mean that constraint and we will get the first from school on the output
i don't know how to do this i don't think that's what i do try
to solve this by standard optimisation methods are on the ground in particular objective function
it is there
around the plane of one minus
the lead to one of
so that's the lagrangian and then if i can differentiate the find maximum then
but given the right answer because because self-justification to spread self-justification to try and it
was great this problem so that's we do try
to optimise this
first thing do is differentiation
then we set the derivative sequences it
so if it's necessary zero it turns out one of the most people two
i can't see their
that's just after all handwaving jogging
it is that what you do is you multiply
everything in sight by the way
what we see from the w three c from the
w transpose that is o
so that from
that becomes two lambda w c w w is one of
so i just end with lambda is equal to
OK quite sure that came from
so again and then also this back into the ground
by end up with half the derivatives of the lagrangian with respect to w is
if you look at the
no network
things in chapter eight
what you find is that they
hebbian learning says firstly
taking steps changing the w
five steps that x
minus one
some zones so what this is doing
what they don't work is doing is solving this problem
why gradient descent
but both density because that's so it is just like
so so you taking
iterations that's on you
this is talking about the gradients and you so far down the the gradient on
that's three components but seem fanciful so the stuff was going this is
why learning is related to principal component analysis can show but first analysis is about
solving that problem and this
is a gradient descent approach to find an optimum my problem
so that's what people going on about one so there's a link between principal components
analysis and know that OK
transc in correspondence analysis is the same idea as principal components analysis exception is thinking
of your observations is the rows or columns of the table so this is this
classical dataset from the book by one acres
it's about employees in south africa my and whether this meant how many of them
to do so
the idea in this is that we can simplify well
so far this instead of having five
all four
dimensions which are way you think about it i was being then you can simplify
into to one or two and
balls and two
the transformation of
and then
essentially just a principal component analysis fact mathematically doing principal component analysis of this so
which is in this for the memory free in this position he plays often deal
with places
and you can show that
the idea to come back here
o to come back here
the priority you always the priority zero
asian is the in the game matches the parity
of the state
you in so here
top thirty zero
he's qq had pretty easy and so on so just one of a number of
what concerns
possible transit transitions the end the game can be quite big it has
the possible labels a b that you can degrade with so you can think of
the size
there is that the
as i can
the winning strategy in this game
it means that whatever and tree
the trust will make
as the player zero
if i mean be i would choose the triangle which corresponds to one position with
it depends on the on the kernel in
so it make
the choice of the same triangle here
whatever and the tree
provided response to
i mean position in the game which is the same
so if you think of what i mean what is the consequence of this
so i think
similar choice
what i am in the tree
well i mean which two
i mean the current state of my automata which is the same transition from n
it may be true to what it means to be here is regular
so it means that the but the but this entry here
and the subtree here
this is isomorphic
same because
i mean QA always true because of one and q eight a shows i mean
the transition that i showed you here
and here are editors here so
that's what i've chosen here
if i change the values of course and and if i come back to here
i mean that we should and here i was which was the same transition CNT
here so the trophic
so what does that mean it means that
i can exhibit the tree which is the true is regular again represented with a
finite state object
i mean is that
so this is the claim here
when i say that
on top of the head the model
it means that if players he has a winning strategy
which is
you can also enforce the strategy to be memoryless
because you always have minor strategy
if you have
there were less winning strategy stages which means that you can build
model which is regular regularity in finite mathematics is the same
OK it's i skip but as you can imagine
i skipped because
they transform it into this input three transformation is polynomial
you build get the size of a prime and you saw the game
and solving the game is so this is the price to pay
to cheque non emptiness is the same price as the one you have to pay
to solve parity game
the parity games it's not really
very expensive is putting up
right so now membership
membership is open
the game is very easy
i show you
it's so i try to explain it
so what is given
four membership
the tree
and they give you a lot about the security of the math
so what
is that i would be
you're more than when i started with
the input tree t
and on the other side grow
of a
so what i did was that edition relations telling me look
when when i mean the node which is w
address the tree
in the binary tree when i mean no w
consider what
i consider
the late
in the state
and there are two problems with the first one is the node labeling right so
he if i have to grow
right they are the same i just labeled nodes different right so here i get
this is not number one two three four or five this way
OK i get two different ideas instrumentation
OK and now if i would just go and all that
this would be different in general
so this is one problem so i don't know
i don't know the node label right i don't know how to map the nodes
of this graph to the or how to make this adjacency matrix this adjacency matrix
so what i need to do in principle idea to consider or all node labelings
sigma OK so she might just the permutation basic how to label how to label
these nodes so that i can then
take this matrix they take that one can calculate that equation shown before OK so
the problem here is so what i would like to do is i would like
to average over all over all labelings
i mean
the number of permutations is like and victorian right so this will explode for more
than a graph of final note if you like and
the other assumption i'm making is that all labelings are a priori have the same
probability that they just something that comes at the end when the graph is created
and what they believe that is how to map
the rows and columns of here
two here so in principle
this is very bad news
OK the other
so let's see now that right so what i really calculating this very probability of
a graph the parameters that should be say sorry in this this is some notation
somebody told me how to do this map and right now i'm going to go
ahead just but i'm i'm i'm i know them around so this means that in
the u the the element that position you of this this permutation this work this
mapping and this is what i'm doing right and
the one problem with this equation is this again takes and and time ordered and
square because they have to go into the woods
every cell of this of this matrix
so i have to go so this this is the adjacency matrix of a graph
right and the adjacency matrix of a graph so what i need to do is
now the every cell of this matrix which means if i have a graph of
final size one hundred thousand this would never fit into memory or
the complexity of just evaluating
evaluating the probability for us in the data and the single mutation
we take and square brackets never
i mean they never able to calculate
so i can solutions for both OK this is good news so basically the bad
news is that if you need to create is then you have to average over
all permutations and you have to
the police every cell of your graph adjacency matrix or get the complexity would be
like in victoria land
and worst right and on
we can do this in linear time so we all in time for the right
time proportional to the number of features and there are two
two things will be using that we won't be able consider
all labelings but we do some like statistical simulation techniques like MCMC to sample permutations
from this distribution rights all now i know i think the graph and i think
the parameters and i want to say to sample
distribution are mutations of these so how you can think about this is that once
i think the graph in the
so let us be like the space of all permutations that so here you can
like think of them like i love being in some some lexical lexicographical order something
that so here is the permutation that like one two three four
and he's like and minus one and so
you can you think the distribution of the difference about some limitations that would that
but there was no really good and that would be a lot of bad permutations
so what we you want to do is we want to sample permutations from distribution
what we hope is that if we were to take a lot of samples
it won't have to consider everyone
but just sample many many times and this one and the other thing that using
since real graphs are sparse what i mean by that is that
right so i have to use the number of edges n is the number of
nodes in
in one was right in the worst case would
he could go like
and square right so is the number of cells
and these grows quadratically with which is the size of the matrix
but the the real graphs are sparse which means that majority
all elements in the in the matrix which is you know so what i can
do is i can quickly calculate probability that the graph is empty but the the
parameters i did not observe not even a single edge and now only going to
correct this for the edges that actually observed that we should be using
and now and this and this will now so creating this
and using some approximation will take
constantine so i will only go and have to correct
this probability for the edges that that really then OK now i'm going to be
what so what you really doing but
is we do
we've been doing gradient descent right so i want to have
the even q of the log likelihood with respect to my parameters to be some
kind of matrix of the which for every parameter so for every element of my
middle initial matrix and to calculate this
if you are to be clever you get something you get an expression that i
saw him again
averaging over all the permutations but it says
here is the probability of a permutation
and i think
what's have
i think i think the
the derivative of the likelihood but what is convenient now here is that i can
sample these
i can then evaluate these changes
output output which OK
so here here's here's what you're doing great so you want to
we want to sample permutations from distribution and what we are doing this
we started something with some limitations right let's just want to end and then the
two supporting this limitation
we solve the elements OK now
what i'm doing is just evaluating the ratio right so this this says if the
if the new one so this is the new to the new permutation i got
when we have
going through a wire like so
and we look at the magnetic field in the vicinity of the wire
and we know from experiment
if you put pieces of magnetite
round wire
they line up
in a circle
around like this
that circle
radius is are
then the magnetic field
that's an experimental fact
is proportional to the current
i is inversely proportional
with the radius of that circle
by convention
direction of the magnetic fields
given by the right-hand corkscrew
i rotate this way
current goes up
you've seen before
which electric charges
when you have a a wire which is uniformly distributed
so was positive charge
you've also seen
electric fields in the vicinity of that straight wire
four of us one of them are
for the direction is different than the magnetic field
but also falls off as one of or
and the reason is that
electric monopole individual charges
the electric field falls off as one of four square
so when you integrate out over straight you get the one of our fields
so by analogy
it would be it's
very plausible
if you took magnetic monopole
that the magnetic field would also fall off is one of four square
but the magnetic monopole as far as we know don't exist
in principle they could exist but we've never seen one
and if anyone of you ever find one
that would certainly be
the nobel prize it's by no means impossible
so the simple fact that the
the magnetic fields
around the current of all office
one of four our
it sort of suggests
if you carve this
why rob in the elements dl
at each one of those elements contributes to the magnetic fields
inverse are scramble
by integrating out over the whole wire
you don't get to one of our field
and this is behind the ideas
the formalism by the
so far
we introduce the idea here
if you have a little current element dl
the current is in this direction
and you want to know
what the magnetic field is a small contribution be
that little
current elements
and the distances are
and the unit vector
from the element bl to the point where you want to know the magnetic field
is i rules
the idea was that the b
current little bit of magnetic fields in this case it will be in the blackboards
because of the right hand corkscrew rule
currently in this direction so these elements
contribute to magnetic field in this direction perpendicular to the blackboard
is some constant
proportional to
current no doubt
and then
is proportional to the length of the element dl
if it's longer than
that you is larger
in order to get the direction right perpendicular to blackboard
we take the cross product
there is a unit vector are
the unit vector are
has length one
so you only do that in order to get the direction
and this
and that is inversely proportional to our script of course
and this is
the formalism by biau survive
and you can do experiments
and measure the magnetic fields in the vicinity of wires
in this formalism or works
so you can calculate the individual contributions of all these elements l
and then you
and integration
and this formalism works
you can then also
national c is
and as i units
these tend to remind seven
but we write for c
something quite peculiar
we write for c
museo divided by four by
we call these new zero
the permeability of free space
seen earlier
the school law
that this constant nine times ten to the ninth we call that one of four
pi actually non-zero what's in a name
so here
we call these museo
divided by
four pi
so now you can
apply the also fires law
and you can go to straight wire
you have a current i
suppose you want to know what to
magnetic field at that location is
and this in capitol are
so what you now have to do
if you carbon is up
in an infinite number of small
elements dl
and this
distances are
and the unit vector
like so
and you calculate the small amount of
semantic field due to this little element
you integrate is over the whole why mathematics
you've done it you've done it before
where we have uniformly
electric charge on the wire
so i'm not going to do this again for you very straightforward
is of mathematics
the magnetic field by the way
in this case will come out of the blackboard
the right-hand court school
what you find when you do this
you will find that the
was new zero
times i
divided by two pi are
this being are
so you need to see that the
inverse one of our
comes out
and so if you for instance take a radius
o point one metres
ten centimetres
and you have the current
why over one hundred and years
you would end up with b field
uses equations
OK so the similarity function so forgive sort of data given by documents i might
want them different similarity function and you
my one if we have different notions of the way
cluster numbers how u
and then given a certain property you what kind of algorithms that suggest that that's
the kind of question we're going to be looking at
so let's start with something simple here which is supposed by similarity function has the
the property that for any two
documents of the same topic there are similarities bigger than zero
and and for any two are topic document to different topic this similarity is less
than zero
i claim this to be a really easy thing to do
you give me you give me that
my algorithm
i came
what would you do your an algorithm given a similarity function with this property
when you do
it's just a character who thinks and acts although either begins zero that that's its
the side pick another x although i think that cluster very
right that's a bit much
unfortunately one problem is that we have no labeled data we get the following issue
the of its k clustering easy so let's try to weaken this little bit will
see something interesting happens
and then we have to deal with this thing in order to be able to
develop an interest in the theory
so i when we can just a little bit in the following way let's imagine
a similarity function has the property that all the examples are strictly more similar to
all the
other examples of their own topic then any example of the other
so all documents
are strictly more similar to other documents of their topic than any document so before
we had
zero as a fixed number bigger than year for your own last year for the
health now realize that fly
for any given example x if you're just sort all the others by similarity or
saying is that the more similar ones come first meets are the course sort we
sort them by similarity the ones in its own topic come first and then the
ones of the different topic come with that these
but still pretty strong condition
unfortunately the following thing can happen
there's a very strong condition but here's something could happen so
this is again USA century
in terms of the sports news but OK so the same similarity function could satisfy
this condition for two very different clusterings of the same for this is an example
imagine a document about four topics your baseball basketball math and physics
and let's imagine similarity function is some reasonable thing so that baseball documents are all
very similar to each other basketball is are all similar to each other the map
for each of the connection with each other and there's medium similarity between baseball and
basketball is medium similarity between metaphysics very low similarity
you have a physics based about it follows similarity
that should be good enough right big the problem is
the given information
it could be it could be that the clustering the person is thinking
it is in fact the clustering baseball basketball math physics that would be very nice
natural for clusters clustering
but it could also be
that the clustering the person is thinking of is that you know and i really
into sports
sports documents have math physics
so maybe the right answer is three clusters is mapped the physics in this work
or are
maybe the right answer
if you ask somebody outside of this room is the other way
the right answer is baseball
basketball and stuff with like we are the math symbols and
that's also a perfectly reasonable clustering and
the problem is
the same similarity functions satisfy
this property
all x are more similar to y in their own cluster than any
why primary other cluster
four above
this and this
OK so for instance here
here is strictly is more similar everybody in their own cluster than anybody
and these guys are more similar to
right so satisfies the properties so maybe they are thinking of the question
or maybe they are thinking of this clustering and they're both perfectly consistent with this
property so have my arguments will be able to figure out
so you have to somehow deal with
and so
there are several things one can do with the way women purpose of dealing with
is that so we can't even tell what someone this week and the goal
so how do we deal with we change the problem so so but we do
this in a way that i think is very weak and the goal building
so let's say that our algorithm rather than actually opening cost
it's allowed to produce a hierarchy
OK such that the correct answer is approximately some pruning of the tree
so what i mean is given this example
our algorithm could output the following three we could say that high-level is one big
cluster like this called dark and then i would support for society and also with
support from baseball basketball for science and the math first so instead of actually have
clustering my algorithm is going to help with the tree
and i'm going to say that this tree is going to define the error rate
say this tree is good if the cluster you're thinking of is approximately some pruning
of the tree so if you're thinking of the clustering
four math physics and this is a good tree thinking of this clustering baseball basketball
science good tree the area to my tree is going to be the error rate
with respect to the best proof
OK so i mean this defined based on whether we can our goal by things
that having to produce the right answer
the approximation to the right answer
and allow my producer tree and then
leave it up to the user to decide how specific they want to be
OK so let me the users job decide they they want to be
the claim is the reasonably natural thing
so so kind of a high-level picture here is if you try doing clustering you
can potentially
do better if you allow your algorithm to do this say if you're in a
and you put labels on here
and you say i will encode ayer zero
can be as one is not wonderful it's an optimal symbol code
it's expected length
it is one
and that is indeed
close to the entropy
it is
point zero eight
it's within one bit of entropy
but it's actually
that's about a factor of twelve bigger than the entropy
and it's not compressing it of course it's just taking a binary alphabet and encoding it directly
in the binary with no encoding
so that's a trivial example where symbol codes clearly aren't getting us where we really
want to go shannon says we should be able to achieve more than ten fold
compression about then calling file
so i'd like to now play a game with you
the situations in which we might be dissatisfied about this plus one
that's lurking in this
the game is called the guessing game
and what we're not going to do
is i'm going to write on the board
the headline
from a newspaper and i have a headline
written here
in front of me
and i'm going to write it with your help
because you're going to guess each letter a headline as we go along
and if you guess the first character letter correctly i'll write it down and i
will tell you it's correct and then we can move on the ground getting the
second letter
all the headline and me alphabet legal characters for this headline
is on the board data z
and space
when we finish the headline now i'll let you know so i'll supply
the full stop
in the the headline
you can start getting the first letter and i'll write it underneath this line all the guesses
that you've made that are not correct and when i right above the line it
tells you that you've got the right letter
guessing time
not to be
not i
this is not right
and is right
next letter
is wrong
do you say hey you
i is correct
next lecture
not tests
not take
it's not well
and i
so again
it's not you
i would say anything about ministers
not they
it's not less
not to
not really
not enough
not see
property like you
now it
not not to
not only
no i
not then
not pay
not see
not be
thank you
it's not
no i
not w
is there
so again
not at
not you