maybe the internet web various
auctions and so forth they involvement multiple agents interacting who each have their own interests
and so when you design the system you can't just design it is if you
have some central control the side however been we talk to each other they all
there are going to do things based on what's what their own motivations and so
when you we keep when you have a problem where you have to keep in
mind people's motivations that brings it into the context game theory a lot of interest
and i would say the last five
six seven years maybe a little older but but really the
mostly most of the work is the last five or six years in connection think
pure science and game theory to this book each chapter is by an expert in
different area
chapter four the chapter that i wrote together with another researcher you shine mansoor
on learning regret minimisation and equilibria so from the things of the talking about it
on my webpage
but you can also
by the book
i don't get any money
there's a nice book of prediction learning and games by nicholas just beyond and government
also on
similar topics to will be talking about
it's it's pretty mathematical and
well i'm really mathematical it
many mathematical for me but
but unlike you know it depends we're coming from it
i think it's quite nice
so we sent also have course notes there on the web so
i happened to
by the domain name machine learning that come out available and not the company back
to look at my course notes to it
sure but the tunnels but anyway
OK so our first office online learning
minimizing regret combining expert advice so let me tell you
what these mean OK so something to start actually with with the kind of motivating
sense so imagine that every morning you need to pick one and possible routes to
drive to work
OK so
for me i live in
the suburbs and try to drive to work each day and there are various ways
i could you
find you know from a computer science perspective
that's why you tell me the lengths of the edges and i can solve for
the shortest path problem we've got plenty of algorithms for solving the shortest path
right the problem is that traffic is different each day
it's not clear after your which is going to be that because these the cost
of the edges the amount of time it takes to go from one place depends
on traffic and i don't know in advance what that's going to be so i
to make a decision before i get to see what the drawings
so i think a path to imagine here you are you going to typically away
to go to work choose the path and you find out how long it took
you need to be thirty two minutes to get from home to work
and perhaps i also find out by asking my friends how
along other rows would have taken
or maybe not maybe i just get the information i just get feedback from the
we can consider
these two scenarios
goods that was day one and then
then the next day i think a different maybe i'll take a different path that
takes me
twenty seven minutes now to take twenty seven minutes because it was because of the
past thing different or maybe just because there was less traffic that a
next another out next week another next to pick every day gonna take away to
go to work
and a natural question to ask here is is there a strategy that i can
use for choosing around with the following properties but in the long run as i
every day going to work
whatever the sequence of traffic patterns happens to be so i don't want to make
an assumption that you know
days are drawn from some distribution or something just everyday there's some traffic and whatever
the sequence happens to be
i'd like to know who have the property that i've done nearly as well as
the best fixed around hindsight so nobody can tell me oh i always go this
way and hide much better than you do i would like to have the property
that i'm doing
released nearly as well as the best fixed throughout i could have chosen in hindsight
newsletter at every day
OK so
basically integrate over the whole parameter space
so we're saying
we're taking all the lines that we
i mean that we know that
potentially including every single line in the possible space of of lines that could be
we're looking at how likely
that line is given the the training data we've already received
without looking at how likely
well that particular part of the test data
that class that
that c that x the the label and that position
how likely would both of those b
given some particular line and we integrate that over every possible lines
so in our example the parameters
what lines are the w and b
and the data is the input position which was to die in our speech example
and see which is either yes or no
and in that example
OK that's a bit confusing
let's let's look an example OK to questions as to give
we're looking at the density of different parameters
so the data is something that's that's fixed we've got some
we've got some data we've seen we seem that we know where the data points
are so we can have no one identity is and we're interested in
where's where's the good points in parameter space seem to represent data
density of the data exactly but the
the density of
good parameters our how likely are all different possible and
the the question is more
is it
right that's a great question OK so the distribution of the data again is something
that we
we already know i'm more interested in is where where should we put the best
we're interested in
you know going back to
going back to the
the input data we've got let's remind ourselves the task is going on here we
want to know
if we take a new recording of someone saying
something which could either be a yes or no
and it arrives at some point in this space we want to know if that's
a yes or no
the way that we're
choosing to distinguish between that is with the line
so the the fundamental goal here is to work out
where the lines are going with which places to guidelines
so that's why we're interested in the distribution
of possible lines
given the data
so given that we seen these things was the
how likely to think different different mind
this is exactly what you got
what yeah
so is
five years
nine it
sure so i
OK great questions the
well we've already got a way of specifying the likelihood so we can take a
whole bunch of lines and we can say
we can say
here's a bunch of lines which had equally high likelihood all these have likelihood one
so so far were saying all of these lines are equally
equally likely and there's whole the punchlines which we don't care about we're not whole
interest them
because they have likelihood zero
OK so we're trying to work out
kind of which lines are better than other lines and at the moment we have
a whole bunch of lines that we think are equally likely
we sampled each of those
so we're trying to get a bit further
looking at the combination of all these lines
we're trying to see
which kind of areas are covered by
by all of these so for a particular point here
really interested in what should we think about the
what should we infer about the class of the point which we receive here someone
make some some noise recorded the microphone
we calculate these features and its projected here in the studio space then
what do we do with here on some lines it's on the
the red side on some of the lines on the blue side
so what we do
and so
what bayes rule is trying to
to do is to look at some
combination over whole input space
and give us some probability not just to zero or one
point here being yes or no
or for or for any other point
let's look at
what the what the result is when we do when we run through
this inference here
so for each data point will try and we'll try and integrate this over all
the possible lines and we'll see what the output is and then maybe they will
become more clear to me why we would have
OK what i've done here
the state is i've sampled ten thousand lines
given each likelihood of one again if it's but categories and the way we want
and likely to zero if it doesn't
i drawn this contour plot
and this is drawn
looking out for each point
what proportion of the lines
is it on the
the red side and what proportion of lines on the blue side so it's very
easy to calculate this we have our
we have our
are in space
next to
and if i have
align with
likelihood of one
then on the posterior
a way that
so you can have shade in this colour as
area saying that given this
setting the parameter here
inputs i receive in this space low will think that the red class that's gonna
be me saying yes
here is going to be in both places me saying no
OK that's what we can do first single
a single line
now we're integrating up over many lines
so let's take another one say
that line there also has
the likelihood of one
stated beliefs
we're seeing some important some new information
but according to black
and now i want to change my set of beliefs and i want to try
figure out what the new state belief is so the question is given initial state
in the late
new piece of information what does the new state of belief
now as with most things were not interested in all the possible ways of changing
this state
but we are only interested in looking at the ones that we might call interesting
for us interesting means rational the this some rational reason
all behavior that took me from the initial belief state new information to the new
OK let's try lay down some rationality criteria organism online you can use tools
OK now the first one is the principal of categorial matching and basically what it
says is whatever my belief state looks like initially should end up with something that
looks like that the end
so if i just as well as in propositional logic to start with
should end up with another set of propositional logic from the not the same formulas
but they still to propositional forms
if the formulas are closed under sum
consequence operator then the resulting so will be closed the consequence
if the initial set is the set of formulas with probabilities attached then i'm going
to end up with another set of forms with probabilities attached
might be different probabilities but they're still going to be
so whatever the initial state looks like the resulting state look like that too
where possible the beliefs and the beliefs they should be consistent
why do we want consistency particularly when we're dealing with propositional logic
what we work what what we worried about consistency
perfect so you know it's the whole that sort of form that was on the
board with hagar cut right
once you have an inconsistent set of formulas you can prove everything
so we've got one of these paradoxes of material implication and when you know that
point when we believe everything we know nothing
one is
consistency is an issue for us
deductive closure so if the
this is a pretty strong one if
if you know the sentences that i currently believe entail some for sentence and i
also believe the sentence
this third one essentially means that the system that we're going to come up with
a sense what is trying to model is not so much what the reason i
i realize
what they can effectively do
but really just describes the commitment what they committed to believe
so you can think of these polices
the belief that they committed to believing regardless of whether they have an inference mechanism
that could actually realistically allow them to
to conclude the story OK so it's sort of theory of commitment problem the theory
of realization
and these first properties what we might call study properties because they only talk about
the beliefs they told me nothing about transitioning from one belief state to the next
OK so here are my or additional two properties on that i want to add
the first one is the principal of informational economy
and in a sense it talks about when you give up information
assuming that the information that you have to believe that you have acquired at this
point of the line
you know you sacrifice allowed to
to get them in
it took a lot of resources to
you know come to all these conclusions you don't want just want to give them
easily willy-nilly so
the idea would be that whenever you have to give something up give up as
little as possible
when you have to change from one state to the next trying to change the
state as little as possible
OK the last one sets is that
if you consider
one belief more important than another one then retain the more important ones in the
list over the last
that's a good question so you would not because we're just talking about you know
the logical sort of relationships between these formulas may not be quite so simple to
work out you know why
able to to estimate this expression here then in some sense i could search over
all possible graphs and find the most likely one ensure that and say hey here
is my OK so that's generally the idea the way we go about this is
the following so the first thing we need to define is how likely is no
due to infect right to say i have a particular
cascade a particular piece of information see how likely was that node u
transfer this piece of information to OK so that the first sort of in the
expression that need to define this be basically we need to define a model of
how information diffuses through the network was even have that we will say hard so
now if i know how likely it was used to transmit information to be or
how likely was used to in fact be the question be OK how likely is
is the is the whole
information to spread in now in particular cascade or a better than b so that
sort of the next expression we have to estimate and then the last the last
election we have to estimate or be able to compute to her son of a
given graph
how likely was this set was set with this set of infections to occur in
the graph and because they have no more deeply infections in the graph at the
same time also what is the probability of all these or likelihood of all these
infections in the graph here i have OK so
of course what would be the problem in the first problem will be how to
estimate the likelihood so how how to estimate the probability of cascades given the graph
and the second thing would be if i can estimate this expression how to efficiently
find the graph that maximizes that expression of the hallways decision to search over all
these graphs
so that would be that would be the
outline of what we are trying to OK so i would start at the beginning
and start talking about alcohol how can we model how information diffuses through the network
so the way do this is the following to say have a single cascade a
single piece of information and this piece of information wants to spread through the network
now we are assuming you know the network so the way we think about this
is the following had like step so the the first node gets infected let's say
a mention the information and that no information can spread to see it will spread
to some other nodes with probability because of that is going to sleep and then
after if the information decides to transmit then he will also sample what call incubation
time to write so some time of how long did it take for that information
to transmit so the way we will say we will say we will think about
this is the following so if i have two nodes u and v and they
both mention the same piece of content then i would say the probability that it
transmitted from u to v is is in some sense let's proportional to the to
this to the distance in time that both sites mentioned the piece of information so
i can say the longer time the difference in time the less likely was the
information to spread from u to v
and that's basically the basic premise of intrusion so the intuition to be more closely
with them to mention information the more likely will used to influence OK and here
is of course you have much more complicated expressions okay so that's the first and
the second thing now is given a set of infection times and let's say that
i have now this cascade the infected nodes a time once you find to be
applied any time for and let's assume that i know that it went from a
to b from a to c and from between so the way
now what i need to know how to estimate is what's the probability that that
this kind of event occurs that was the probability that this cascade this set of
infection times happen in pattern like this and i'm still assuming that have the graph
so the way i do this is basically saying i started a
then my infection propagated to CMB when it came to see it didn't propagate to
be because it came from a so really what i need to do is to
say here is the set of edges these information propagated that are sort of the
blue edges and this is the set of edges where the information is not properly
it's sort of this is the positive evidence that the positive evidence is each replication
of probability big and then there's this time lag between the infections that i have
here and then the information propagates that's that's that's a factor of one minus better
that happens with probability one minus and what do is
in the in the model going to ignore this for this fact this loss vector
so you say the probability that a particular cascade propagated in a particular better in
a particular pattern is simply the product of over the edges of the history and
the infection times here OK so that's the that
the first piece
the second question is is really how likely is the information not spread in a
particular pattern but over the graph right because we don't know how the information spread
there may be different ways but that of of that of how the how our
contagion could have spread that are all consistent with my infection times
right so
here i'm showing like three different pieces that are all consistent with the striking although
there is a gets infected first see gets infected secondly gets infected and for me
it's not clear whether you've got infected from a already got infected from from c
as a show here
right so
if i would want to compute now the probability of a particular set of infection
times over the graph i would need to sum over all
over all the all the trees that could all all the ways that this information
could have spread through the graph and again
that is it feasible to do so
what i i do here is just a the most likely to be right so
instead of going here and saying let's sum over all of these events only some
forward i will only consider the most likely to so the most likely way how
the information could have spread over the so now
now i told you how to how to compute how likely is a particular set
of infection times to occur on a particular graph g OK so now because they
have multiple infections i will assume they are independent so i will be multiply them
together so now i have this i take the logarithm so this is not the
likelihood is not the log likelihood so what i really want to do is i
want to optimize this expression i want to find the graphs
but the that best explains how information spreads over these graphs right that's that's basically
my god my goal is to find the graph k edges such that it is
all electorates so
that's one of observation vision and that's not observation
and each line corresponds to one
and if you notice
the first tree
right so this at all the little like you see
how have similar shape
and the idea is if they have similar shape and probably by from the same
new neurons
and if you
in an electrode into
the real amount that you actually
we by multiple neuron and you need to figure out which by belong to which
in this case maybe you might think that
the first response belong to one neuron and then maybe the next or belong to
the second neurons
and then the next three belong to with the neuron
so again the question is how many neurons there
in the vicinity of
let's put you can receive back
so this is basically like clustering that they are much more high dimensional
so in fact that's what people do people just take
the high dimensional data and it is the and then each cluster c belong to
corresponds to the by
corresponding to one
one unique neuron
another example is hoping modelling so here the idea is that
you are given a set of documents
decompose the
each document into a mixture of topics so you you use
describe each document is a mixture of topics
and then there will be a set of topics which is quite all documents with
the new copper
again the question then is how many topics
activities within a particular corpus of documents and again we need to answer the question
and we need to
two models that you know everything
it looks
like this
o five
so another example is in grammar induction
the idea is you want to learn a proper context a probabilistic context free grammar
paul language they singly
that's cool
now possible questions you you can
as the first one is given a lot a lot of that the the english
from english
figure out a grammar of english
and at the same time hard each sentence
in in the grammar
people familiar with the band
they become
will OK
i the out going to what i think that but basically they look like this
so in this case
that said that she heard the noise
and what you to do is to parse sentence
in terms of
in this case you have a sentence and there might be now every year
that's about right and appropriate to the nine
and then the
great in
hearts into cool
i think this bbb
but i think the
i'm not going to be about the fact that
the one that and this is again an operation
so once you heart the sentence
you have you can kind of see that you have
and this that and to some extent
so the question now is
given lots of english sentences and you learn a grammar for english
as part of the the
in the grammar
the second question you could ask
let's say that we have the grammar
and this is the apostrophe in in the family
maybe you might think that OK multiple types of phrases that goes
along with multiple now great
but of course the grammar you even if you only hope is based on the
right and what you want to learn it
how many of the truth the home many of not with the other
and you can learn all over again from
that the was of english
so again this is a model selection action because
you know you don't really know how many parts of
not with the other to begin with you need to figure that out
so another example is visual analysis in which
even things like pictures you want to decompose the c
in two objects and object into parts and then put into
again you
you don't really know how many objects there are any object types
how many
part then within each object
and this of questions is given model selection question because
if you
have really which model
and you
so would be the thing is to maximize likelihood
then of course you would say that
you know
you have
you have many many different objects and object corresponds to
a whole image
the those that cannot the be applications of dirichlet processes and so the process pretty
ways to solve all the problems
so much for so light
how to be create the definition of there's a process so let's start with the
a finite mixture model people familiar with mixture model
we are
you know something
in know
very small
you know
call it off
o lord
they are all
one month
one of the things
no no
one one
from all
one of more
so what
so the were OK so i'm going to be i'm going to be talking about
quite a number of
quite a number of projects actually put together in the in the context of an
overview of all the methods of machine learning that have been applied for the for
the task of doing acoustic signal processing and by acoustic signal processing i mean things
like speech recognition
tracking the source location
detection of non speech audio events and answering questions about human speech perceptual capability and
an audio perceptual capability so in you know they're going to be maybe ten or
fifteen applications touched on briefly and and for that reason the the outline of my
talk looks more or less like an outline of the field of machine learning so
i'm going to talk about different criteria that you can choose in order to that
you can use in order to decide what kind of pattern recognizer to apply to
which particular problem in in statistical acoustics
i'm going to talk about this ancient division of the the the methods in machine
learning into discriminative and bayesian methods were discriminative method is essentially one is trained in
order to do as well as possible in a specific application a bayesian method is
one in which you pay attention to stochastic normalisation of all the of functions estimated
so that they become probabilities so that you can string them together in relatively complicated
graphical structures in order to
in order to model more and more complicated problems and then a technique that's been
particularly useful for me is to is to take those two methods combine them that
is to create a sense and a neural network in which the hidden nodes are
trained for specific tasks and then the output of those hidden nodes are then fed
into a bayesian inference engine
in general when i talk to active stations they're interested in answering a particular question
about the nature of the universe or about the nature of the human animal and
the way in which we answer questions about the nature of the human animal is
this is this little method that was developed by by francis bacon called the scientific
method namely hypothesise observe and test that is before you actually observed any of the
data you construct the hypothesis about what might be happening in the real world based
on your understanding of reality and then you collect data is necessary to test the
hypothesis to determine whether the hypothesis or the null hypothesis is more likely machine learning
turns that on its head of of course
in pattern recognition application we first we first collect the data and then we test
the hypothesis in and then we form the hypothesis more specifically we start out with
an infinite set of hypotheses
the hypothesis space some kind of parameterized universal approximator that is a space of functions
with which given adequate complexity is able to approximate any
function is able to learn any function and then we train that space of functions
using the training set and we test we do something finally a little bit similar
to the to a scientific hypothesis tests by using a separate testing database in order
to determine whether
whether that went with hypothesis for the form of what's going on in the real
world actually matches
what we observe in the real world so here's an example of of the way
in which pattern recognition techniques can be combined with the scientific method this is an
ongoing set of experiments that are going on in my lab we have a whole
bunch of both of undergraduates naive listeners listening to this thing to arbitrary mixtures of
speech and non speech audio in this case is that it's actually meeting room audio
so people talking about a particular topic and they they type on their computers and
a closed doors and they make a discrete their chairs and they dropped books on
the table and things like that we the subjects to tell us
when something happens that attracts their attention and this is some of you may recognise
that the bottom up versus top down division of attention this has been very finely
developed in the visual processing community and has not received much attention in the auditory
processing community we want to know is there something other than just loudness that attracts
one's attention to particular acoustic event so we have we have two hypotheses here number
one we we we hypothesise that particular signal model for what makes an acoustic event
perceptually salient in this case we look at we look at attributes of the centre
surround difference in loudness and in features like tony city and frequency contrast in temporal
contrast and the second hypothesis is that those same subjects were asked to detect events
like lectures squeaking footsteps will be easier more easily able to detect events that they've
previously marked being salient or that somebody else is marked as being perceptually salient that
is the ability to recognise an acoustic event is correlated with the bottom up
on the bottom up attention-grabbing features of that that event
in the first part of this talk i simply introduces easy technique linear technique for
the study that by stuff classification dimensionality reduction aggression and finding a relationship between that
i don't know about
the technique that has been i think everybody knows ahead but are very powerful and
i believe that for three reasons first of all that very intuitive
because sometimes we need to be able to visualise solution but dramatically
they were many often because
must of the natural function of small we can
you can also
long small not so much
and the
with the news is also that
they are very fast and easy to solve because simply involves math operations usually
this is the last part of the talk that when i do before lunch and
after lunch when i was i would say more into thinking he bought new first
i want to i ask myself what do we do if we have a non
linear function and i will introduce the notion of care so i we learned
kenneth our use when want to mark one that in some high dimensional feature space
where you can still use the linear technique after the mapping
and the best part of the task
and i think
maybe the more
you know the most interesting is what
what do we do if we don't
simple data but we have structure data like sequences graphs images and we good these
into vectors which i got it and can we use to
we felt like before last we will talk about the nest technique for the analysis
some technique for regression let linear regression and the nice discrete aggression into aggression
i mean introduce fisher discriminant nine
and we talk about some problem that can be solved as again by the problem
principal component analysis of squares and canonical correlation analysis
and then i'll talk about how we start to talk about support vector machine
the task was to introduce going that i was going to do about the machine
but introduce all the cannon metal like can read the connection cannot component analysis kernel
canonical correlation analysis
the last part of the are discussed recent trend in machine learning the learning in
structured output spaces that i like and i also what
in the eyes which may be used in the last two years i will discuss
some applications more computer vision of you but you already know that or
technical and very powerful widely used and people from
many feel like so
OK let's talk about you know thinking about that
let's start with the least squares problems
in case of regression brief attention
we have data points represented
three dimensional spaces and we have labels each label is associated with that point labels
come from either skylar deleon
each level
want to find a linear decision function
that means you get what you want to use the bottom there make sure that
vector w that but i think that our species function
i will for regression is to find a linear function that was made the able
that assume that the label i did by rather well we have a gaussian noise
covariance matrix and and the expected value the what to the when we look for
the best of the best my life is to make sure that
and what we want to
we want to get w by solving these the problems
once we get that we can be able to sort of to give the optimal
label y
two when you just point x
in order to do some work that suggests he in the story is about the
function i think you see i'm not doing any assumptions for example of the capacity
and not this
but this is what i'm trying to
i mean my
some other thing on w and this is the function
just as well and we should know what we are doing is likely to lead
we describe regression
we have for each data point one hand predictions and we measure for each training
point there received well so what we have summing up of the have
in the beginning to our cost function so
minimizing this cost function
OK if
we're minimizing the cost function that is the sum of squares
why did the corresponds to the likelihood it's quite straightforward to see that we can
try to live in that way
the product of its actions we can put the
that's right side
that's what just want to
which is a
and the right
only one
one of the
there's a correct rule
so just write down things everybody can
all other even simpler
but way
so i will be taken only one element
so because we said that this has to be true
i mean we know is a positive definite kernel therefore this question here is true
no matter what coefficients in what points we take so i will only take one
point for simplicity because i know in particular in that case also i this inequality
so i will only use something like this
a one a one well i don't have some a one a one
and then here i have
k of x one
x one
so i know by definition
positive definite kernel
therefore this thing here is nonnegative and i know that it's negative no matter what
i choose for a in x
let's just call it a and x
so this is the same
squared OK of x x
this is supposed to be true i know this is true for all and x
we just put a equal to one
and they're not directly have the result i want to talk about
this is the same
so we've got the second one
let's look at the first one
so cushy schwartz inequality
anyone like to see how that is being proved
so this one
so you're trying to prove it by using the feature map right but i guess
that it would be possible but the only problem is we have to prove that
we we have to prove that
if k is positive definite
then there exists a feature mapping such pages is the product
in the representation
we prove that if the feature map
and like up here we prove the for example if the feature map then we
can construct company but we don't know yet
strictly speaking but if we have a positive definite we have a future we're actually
going to prove that in the next slide we want to use the results so
we use the knowledge here then
we would be making
some are
so it i mean would be possible to prove it like that but i would
prefer to prove it without using that
so the way i would like to prove it
by looking at the determinant of the the gram matrix and using some facts of
linear algebra
so i told you that positive definite kernels definition of the kernel is exactly the
same as saying that the gram matrix is positive definite so i would actually consider
a particular gram matrix that i get for having to training points only if i
have to training points micron matrix looks like this
now i know that this matrix is positive definite because i'm assuming that the kernel
is positive definite
so what if i know that this grammar is positive definite i know in particular
that its determinant is nonnegative
so if you don't know that you just have to believe me so
this is a symmetric matrix actually it's it's determinant will be the product of the
tag values and since the matrix is positive definite there would be no negative i
can values of the product of the values will be nonnegative so the determinant of
this thing here will be
nonnegative and that's just work on the determinant determinant is the product of these two
minus the product of these two
product of these two i can simplify because by assumption
k is positive definite and therefore symmetric so is actually just k x one x
this is basically the result i wanted to prove
i just have to
this thing to bring it to the other side
OK and i have a proven it without using the the feature map
OK finding vanishing diagonals
so how do we prove that any suggestions
using the one
so we can directly
applied to the results
so by the results
we know that k of ex prime
squared is upper bounded by
a x x
OK of ex-prime ex-prime
if i'm
assuming that the dying nonzero by which i mean that's up to do the same
thing twice the diagonal this is zero then
this is zero
and this is zero
and therefore
this square is zero for any x x from the public and is zero everywhere
OK so these are some
some simple properties of kernels and even if you haven't worked them out all that
useful that you work with the definition of because even the definition of simple you
need to
play around with it a little bit too to really understand it
i mention that
was i think
the water and some ice
this is zero
the ice is it's a minus forty
what is simplicity
but let me make that also applies for
i bring them together and ask you what happened
now this is a certain problem it
if we had two
if you want to the party
and yet what twenty
you can easily guess that will end up somewhere in between you can calculate
that was more such
what forty
you got i said minus forty
you bring them together and that's what happened
well the answer will depend on how much of the stuff you have
if they want to know what you mean
the atlantic ocean
and by assuming a couple of ways q we know what's going to happen
these guys are going to get clobbered going to melt
you will end up somewhere here
and you can easily calculate the final temperature by saying
this felt that the for water
in magnitude
it's going to be
the heat given to this argument this is the incident that you to come here
in the heat to melt someone otherwise
and he to raise the someone to watch the final temperature
we can solve for the final temperature
if you want to solve this problem and i give you some as with his
of water and give you some as with the eyes
you can first make the optimistic assumption that you will end up as water
but the unknown temperature
the unknown temperature t
this is the t one is the key two
right you're equations
except that one more time there that's the heat it takes to melt the ice
you saw forty to get a positive answer
you can use
because his assumption that ended up on what meant
you heat up the ice to melt the ice into water then heated up
water from zero to the final water
but if you do the calculation got negative value of t
the answer cannot be blindly used
because the assumption that you're on the other side of ice is wrong
then you can try something else
you can assume you down here
if you think it down here
then you simply
he to the ice
from here to here this what you brought down to zero
so i told mc delta t from that
then you've taken out
now the latent heat of melting you take out heat when you freeze
and then you
they can even more
come down here
and all those losses of the original water is equal to gain a precise
we can assume he can solve the city when you start with the city
we've got a negative number
you're OK
that would be good at something if i say i sprinkled two drops of water
on the big iceberg
we know it's going to end up with size and that's a good starting point
but if they give you numbers which are kind of wishy washy when i don't
this one winner that will win
that's the third possibility
the possibilities of the end of the day
you end up here with some of water and someone applies to zero degrees
so that the adoption you may have to consider
if neither of them works
the question is not what is the final temperature
what's the best in them
what do you want to know in that
how much is ice and how much is one
that's the best
and there are several ways
figure that out
let me just say in words i don't want to do this
because for you this should be fairly easy
if it's the question i suppose what the
thing said try fail
i took a possibility
assume them up here and i assume the ice melted
and get a negative answer that struck down
i think negative and assume everybody frozen that doesn't work then i'm don't this option
with somewhat of water and someone applies
the question is how much is left
you solve that by doing the following
you say all these ice
went from here
it does that by absorbing that mc delta t
possibly a system specifically advised them felt that maybe plus minus forty
felt that these plus four
you give that you that this guy you that you sort out of the sky
and it's like that of this guy first to bring this to zero
and you still have some what he can extract from you use that
to convert water into ice at the price of eighty
calories per gram
maybe you can freeze
five grams of five kilograms of the water
that is bx tries this maybe whatever water you start
the total mass will be the same
but if you got sixty grams of water
you've been the sixty grammes zero and you still have some more heat to be
maybe you can work ten grams to rise and fifty minutes what
so the final answer will be
fifty grams of water
n grams of ice plus whatever them supplies you start
that's what the most
complex heat
and we're going to deal with graphs we know how to
take a graph and figure out what the central ones are
in fact this case it comes out that this one here
is the central point of this graph and that is a good choice as the
canonical image
OK so that's the way of combining
a little bit of image data from extracting features from the images and then a
lot of information from the web of what's connected to each other and what's important
and here we will not just the portion of its
and we can see how this one in the middle
and these ones are on the periphery
and that's pretty important because people are easily distracted when they are searching for images
and you know the task was really to find this one
but if we show them a variety gonna get distracted and say well you know
maybe this one and this one is different and more interesting graph look at that
this one shown some scans so you would have we click on that one
and we've got to have a way to combat that and say
we don't want to show is the number one result
something that's
more interesting or novel
they want to show that somewhere in the results but we want to show the
canonical one first in this kind of technique allows us to do that
OK and another similar example for starbucks were able to get that
lower right in the middle
and then this is just an example of what the features are so at each
point there's is a vector
for that point is is the so-called SIFT features and so it's abstract representation of
what the images but is
it works well of across rotations and scaling and so on so it's easy to
compare between images
and is just one more example
showing this is for the lincoln monument how they cluster into multiple different clusters so
there isn't necessarily model is so there was over one canonical here it turns out
that there's three canonical hours inside during the day and inside during night and exterior
shot can cluster together
OK one more piece of work by an islamic at google
on learning people annotations
so here we have an image and the notation
says george bush americal barrel of hearing photograph by herbert proper
so if you're searching for merkel bush this
picture could potentially be retrieved by you wouldn't really know
which one was
bush and which was mercola which was very
then you would know that herbert roper is represented in the picture that he was
just the photographer because all those words are differentiated
so we'd like to be able to do is similar to what we're doing in
translation here's the spaces for him
you need to get this model for alan alda and here's the spaces for him
and notice that like with the lincoln monument we don't have to map everything into
a single model we can have multiple clusters and so you get the
young alan alda from matchdays with dark hair and the older one although with folding
classes and so on
and that's OK for these types of data driven models we don't have fit everything
into one
in conclusion
code is liability is this guy is to be really good programmer and doesn't happen
to stop coding but he said measuring programming progress by lines of code is like
measuring aircraft building progress by weight
right and so
you don't really want to know if you're building airplane it's everything is going great
is getting heavier and heavier
rather what you want to say is you know would be nice if it was
getting lighter and lighter that could fly
and it's the same thing with lines of codes for you know each line of
code makes your project heavier and harder to change so the period have
the better
and this data driven approaches one way of getting to that ideal of having less
code more flexible more
i think it's time for to
o thing
this is the standard approach for four
learning on those
image databases i think that image is part
the image so it is important applications a
has been using the text to search the images it's possible to do the opposite
to use this
although we learn all on those graphs is all this
this compilation
that you do on those discussed this creates some knowledge that can be used to
retrieve the next to the concepts and the text is is this possible to explore
on the opposite way information so you want to go up
put in an image and get back text no i mean you do users searching
for the text for the cost for the web page and the text seems to
have the although this beautiful
also map the
classic and you can your profit from from this information to give him the
right web pages
yes is so i mean certainly we we try to do that
so we have
if i'm not quite sure if you're asking what what what types of queries and
how the text images his work but in all cases we want to integrate all
of the knowledge we have very few if we know
synonyms for words we want to be able to add those and we know relationships
between them
which we should add that and so far we
i have kept the the web search image search separately although we think they probably
should be
integrated together more and we'd like to be able to do that more in the
and with local image that was kind of a community causing with people just because
they and their
rewarding when people just take it and so it was right or wrong i want
to find it really interesting
do is we do not happening
two mapping
concentration into some function of concentration
map that
into some function of depth such that i'll get a straight line
and then i can with the naked eye say i've got it i know what's
going on here
so therefore the model
transformed c and f of c x into g x then
underlies the whole
and so the mathematical formulation of diffusion we all
someone by the name of that of fig
out of that
he was a physician
but a lot mathematics
and if you do
two diffusion
obama did
two spectroscopy recalled
study the measurements that were made by strong and was born for instance data to
that equation that ultimately we
i want to be
in concert with the rydberg equation what effect did he looked at thomas graham
thomas graham the published some diffusion data
for the rate of ingress of
materials in aqueous media
and i think was the one who is able to fit thomas screams data and
give us
a model and here is
through here this is the
cover page this is the first page of the paper this was published in an
islander physique me
leipzig eighteen fifty five and here we are page fifty nine
on diffusion by doctor at offic
from zurich
it starts off as you've seen before there's a little bit of background there's references
to the antecedent literature and where we go
eighteen fifty five
what did he tell us in this important papers
let's take a look at his representation of what's going on in this process
he was able to quantify this gives a measure that has predictive capacity
what he said was that the rate of ingress expressed why
a term called phlox phlox measures the rate
it's the mass flow rate
so clearly it must have
some kind of units of mass
per unit time so i'm going to use as i units kilograms per second but
is quantified on the basis of unit cross sectional area so it's the mass flow
species i
i'm going to make it in one direction in the x direction we set things
up in the previous sketch so it's kilograms per second on a unit area basis
so flux is mass flow rate per unit area
so the flux of species i
what he observed was is
it's related to the concentration gradient
in species
is the concentration gradient that
it dictates the rate of progress gradient in
concentration of i
in the x direction
later on you can generalize this in three dimensions you can replace the derivative the
with the dell
two in three dimensions simultaneously
the constant of proportionality
the the diffusion coefficient or diffusivity
diffusion coefficient diffusivity
and finally there's a minus sign why because
species move from high concentration to low concentration
so if i look at the
the curve above
i expect that since the concentration
is high
at the free surface
that the flux is moving from
left to right we would expect
jason five move from high concentration to low concentration but look at the slow
the here is
negative so in order to have a positive flux with the negative slope we fix
it no problem
that is easy to put their minus so that's
genesis of the
one is assigned to make the
coordinates come up properly and units well we know the units on concentration concentration must
be in kilograms per
cubic meter so we got that
by the tax
the DX this acts actually calls for units so that's one over meter
and if i'm going to have kilograms per square meter per second on the left
and these are the units of d by the axon that follows the diffusivity
must have units of length squared per time
so diffusivities expressed in
metre squared per second
concentration kilograms per cubic metre
the derivative one over and then the flux
in the following you
but there's more
in this paper
it was so visionaire
he said
you know
this describes diffusion
of matter into matter
but he says this also bears resemblance to ready for this i said there are
some parallels between heat transfer and mass transport cigarette canonized
in his paper that you know
this is similar to fourier first law
four years first law
conduction he said
then is i get there i go around as many times as i want i
keep decreasing the way because that is negative to it by some fixed amount and
then i can go to v so as long as there is a negative weight
cycle reachable from you can also reach me
you know there's no
shortest path
because if i take any particular path i can make it shorter by going around
a couple more times
so in some sense this is not really
a minimum it's more like an infinite
for those who
like to get fancy about such things but what say that delta of UV is
minus infinity in this case there's a negative weight cycle
from u to v
so that's one case we have to
i worry about something but is longer as there are no negative weight cycles delta
hu v will be some
something bigger than minus infinity some finite bounded below by some finite value even if
you could have negative weights but still no negative weight cycle
for example there might not be any cycles in your graph
that's still interesting
and i guess it's useful to know that you can get from a to b
in negative and infinite time creates time travel
if if the weights happen to correspond to time
but when else might shortest paths not exist so this is one
but there's another
a simpler case
it's not connected there might not be any path from u to v this this
might be empty there may be no path from
you do the here we have to define what happens here will will say
it's infinity
if there is no
used to be so
there these exceptional cases plus infinity minus infinity which are pretty intuitive because i mean
takes a really long time to get from u to v if there's no path
you can't get there from here
OK but that's
that's the definition
most of the time this is the case we care about course
usually this is of finite set
OK so that's the definition now let me tell you
we're going to get a few basic
structural properties about shortest paths that will allow us to obtain good algorithms for finding
these plants when they exist
and in particular we want to use ideas from dynamic programming
i want to use dynamic programming to solve shortest path
what do i need to establish was like the first thing i should check
all implemented dynamic programming by now so it should make complete sense of is more
sensitive to a couple weeks ago and
last week on the learned
dynamic programming something that goes on every year i think i understand better than the
previous year
but in particular
when you learn
dynamic programming in this class
this is nice key property should check
optimal substructure
this is the reason why we should keep in mind
this is not really enough for dynamic programming to be
useful and efficient way but at least tells you that it should
should be able to try to apply
it's pretty weak statement
something you should check defined pretty much a necessary condition for dynamic programming to make
and so optimal substructure here means that if i take some shortest path i welcome
subpath of that shortest path i claim that too
is a shortest path
with its respect to points obviously not between the same points but if if i
have some shortest path between two endpoints to take any surpass that's also the shortest
path this is one
version of optimal substructure this one turns out to be true to this
and how should i improve an optimal substructure property
that we're here to mean this is not always true but it's a good technique
so we're going to think about and to essentially provide picture here
so suppose you have
some some path of some shortest path so let's say
path is x to y
the path goes from u to v
so we assume that u v is the shortest path we want to prove the
x y is the shortest
suppose x y is the shortest path then there's some shorter path
figures from x to y
but if you have some shorter path from x to y then then this one
then i should just erase
this part of the shortest path from u to v
and replaced it with the shorter ones of this this is some hypothetical
shorter path
so suppose this existed
if that existed then i should just cut that the all path from x to
y and paste in this new one from x to y is strictly shorter they're
strictly shorter path from u to v but i simply immutable was the shortest path
OK so there is no shorter path and that proves
we have this sum has the shortest paths are shortest path
you should now be if familiar
proof technique but there's yet another instance of cut and
so that's a good sign
for computing shortest paths i mean in terms of dynamic programming will look directly dynamic
programming here because we're going to infer greedy which is even stronger
and the next monday will see some dynamic programming approach is intuitively there's some pretty
natural some problems here i mean going from u to v
i want to find what's for sparse community well that's a particular problem maybe involves
computing shortest path from u to some intermediate point x and then from x to
you something like that that feels
good that's like quadratically many some problems in school of the square subproblems
so it sounds like that would lead to tighter program you can make it work
out sister the little bit tricky
we'll see you next monday
but thinking about this intermediate point we get something called the triangle inequality
so you've probably heard some form of the triangle inequality for it holds in all
sorts of geometric spaces and also called for sparse is slightly
more obvious sanchez depending on your
information so if you have any
triple of vertices
the shortest path from u to v is at most the shortest path from u
to x
one of the shortest path
next week
course interest perhaps weight from u accent shortest path weight from x to be
by infinity there could be kernels
in fact and so so this is just basically
a and
times v
many times in the discrete case
the way we're going to do this is
we're going to construct our f function to be the product of the initial function
and the transition transitions the multiplications by the success of matrix of the initial factor
that is a stochastic function
times transition matrix and if we do that
then it's clear that if integrate over x one ten minus one
over here on the right
on the left-hand side what i have is any
of xn
and on the other side i have zn
and of xn
and z
c one
the one
so that allows me to get an estimate again by taking ratios of two successive
an estimate of lambda
can now
it's the same algorithm it's exactly this is what we had full state space models
the only thing is my f is now the success of multiplications or or kernel
the proposal could be
anything you want engineer like
matrix there's different ways
generating proposals for this kind of two about it later
and again you just draw samples from this q
and then you successively compute these weights
and you're essentially reiterating
the power method that is really a monte carlo matrix vector multiplication of success successive
so the second example
and this is more related to the problem of
blowing up stuff
you have some particles start somewhere
and this part of sort of diffuse and if they touch
a lot of boundary to get killed
and so you kind of want to estimate
for the particles that survive what is the distribution
at the end
and you also want to estimate what is the probability
some particles will survive some critical
time steps
the transition here's is the actual evolution of the particle in the physical system
and then there's the probability
of the particle being
kilowatts which which is given by known functions say one minus g
and others your thoughts there
neither i nor many people know the middle step
again it's the same setup if you want to estimate a particular time
survival time
you have an integral of the probability of the particle whatever being killed in other
ways that survives at each time step
and it's easy to see that once again we have the success of integration
we have what's called the path integral
and in this path integral game with this would be our ap
we again have five being just f of then
and zn is really just the idea and integral which is the partition function
application of these techniques that has been used a lot in the literature is self
avoiding random walks
in the self avoiding random walk you start at some point in the discrete lattice
you can take a step but you're not allowed to visit
you know sort of the wrapping yourself so you if you've been here you can't
five been
so from here and i go here i'm not allowed to go back to the
same place i have to keep avoiding going to where i am
and that turns out to actually be useful for many things
one of which
some models from
how polymers fall
and some people studied this for very sort of
simplified models of protein folding especially peter grassberger
some other people rosenbluth of the
metropolis algorithm
has also worked on this and
then the typical approaches again you particle filtering this year after this assumes that
and so you build the sequence you basically sample
as you go
and you might have more interesting models and a simple self avoiding random walk you
might have different types of potentials between these nodes
but the goal is to try to come up with these configurations it try to
that sort of more plausible
and because of proteins
another example the kind of again rehashed that all we're doing his solving path integrals
and that the method can really be applied to many more problems
other than state space models
is the example of stochastic control
so in stochastic control
we have an equation recurrent equation that many of us are familiar with
bellman equation
or is also known as
fredholm equation of the second kind
and it's possible to iterate this question is
two unfold this equation by means of of expanding it in time
in some sort of like mixture
o of path integrals
and again we can choose whatever should be
and then in order to solve to approximate the value function
we just need to again run particle called you this is sort of an additional
step is is that for some
and so you need to do some extra things and these guys are here are
now let's
they discuss the way of doing that efficiently
now part integrals for control something that many people have been using recently
i know per capita and a lot of work on this
and it's also been used in what's called inference approach for mdps and pomdps piece
so people like
one the guys to do this he and did some work on this
this marked assigned
there there's
there's lots of people full of this approach to look at mater science paper and
all the people that cited you'll get the literature from scholar
and they also began formulate these things as mixtures and once you have this sort
of mission you have to estimate
policies and you have to the forward backward
message passing and you can do this with particle methods
finds work on applied this to
dirichlet processes where you have tables and
people get killed
and from there with this
and then the new guy comes in tables small and this is the standard chinese
five dimensional joint distribution called the query you want to find more
you want to go back one
compute the joint distribution over all queries
good news and the good news is not completely missing
i'm going tell you how to compute the joint distribution
group that is not how you
it's quite possible to compute the distances between nodes in the tree
just a simple case the distribution
each node has changed
you can compute the joint pairwise posteriors distribution for any pair of connected science fiction
and i simply
the product all the messages
coming into i
he said the message from the change
all messages coming in j
except the message from i
in the case of the late so these are
o functions and the potential to be
the happens and this year
this situation the joint posterior over x i x j given the this is proportional
to the product of all messages arrive at no i
so all messages arriving
one is this
all right i know i except message
right i j
except for the first time to take solve problem in the product potential between i
and j which is the original walls either you have not two
and evidence
why am i
focusing on this case the joint distribution between two connected like here
i what i just told you you know
on the street and you can compute the marginal over one these four or incomplete
disjoint over x one x two
over the next three
and extracts four
to compute the joint
for x one x four
o or one of these particles
so this is why i care more these articles are
well these are exactly the marginal distributions are going to be funded work
so remember two sources queries actually what is query comes from what you read
in some parts europe which has i'm saying
one of the first round
OK and involves conditioning they are completely positive in the remaining crew
but no query is trying to do
i would be returned
so remember that the algorithm
called the inferencing society
three he's in the basically called the inference engine
and the kinds of queries we we know exactly what happened
for the queries during learning were only to be the marginal distributions between two adjacent
because all parameters wherever he they are parameters virtually no parent
because that's the only
parameters of the trees are all
so only marginal distribution
but the individual articles on the marginals p
note that we ever these particles
x to that's why focused on
you have to
now uh
the story once told me that they all the maximal cliques in the tree so
that all need do work it turn inference other pairwise or higher order or series
is possible using
messages on entire path
so i think i x separated
the from all messages at o potential
so answer
that's not
in last year
i want to tell you
so do maximisation sensation so belief propagation summed over all possible values of the martyrs
that's not appearing on
but want to maximize over non occurring on its
what want
the probability of the single best-selling variables consistent with the evidence
so one way to you
probabilistic models say well
summing over all possible sets of nodes
log ten how likely is it that so many times
use of this is the single joint exploitation
there are cases where and case instead of some not very
you want to maximize and locally
is a lot like
solution in search of
plus so just basically here you can see the maximum over x one x two
x three is the same from our model
the maximum overall product is just
this one which is
and in doing so this is maximum posterior mass immigration law and the law of
the sum product algorithm is called the max product algorithm use this so on trees
using exactly the propagation were replace citation by mathematicians and that allows you to compute
the man saying for
forty years
so that
four case not government in very much detail about
if you are interested in this
good of the papers that the time
this interesting that
so this is not the only operational you
as it happens also
OK so
the question that message passing belief propagation or four
so that's the way
the o nature insurance this idea
it's like this
that's all
yes i mentioned above
the above
in the case of observation
so far as is easy to learn
so here
to here what i mean is you have a delta function
on the observed value x j j changed
so the only
so there are people who try to find support vectors in the brain actually do
intelligent people tried that
there are people who
try to find deep belief networks in the brain who tried to find will of
course whatever the road network connection in the right so it's gone either way but
it's just like saying well because the plane has jet engine therefore birth must fly
using jet engines
OK so
do not fall into the trap
there are structures that work well in
in both areas but that's
more locked in anything else
i think i'm probably at the very extreme point here and some people might argue
the opposite but OK
at least for those sixty minutes i'm going to argue the point
OK now
you can read for this later on
or if you follow the max just fire up
escape x doctor
and you can try out eliza
it's quite scary
how easily people are full for at least two three phrases
into thinking that we over the interacting with
actually has intelligence
that's what people in the nineteenth century thought how the brain works
there are various regions
which had
you'll enjoy
what can we do well we could extract structure
we could actually do novelty detection of according to supervised learning unsupervised learning actually has
a lot more questions
they actually
the final is usually coming up with a really good question
in supervised learning it's more coming up with a really good algorithm for a given
depending on
which of those things you enjoy more
the question of finding good answer you might choose one of those three areas
and of course it's not that clear-cut
this is where we are going to see some equations so
it get a little bit more time but not very much now
well essentially what i'm going to do now is to talk about the language that
we need in order to to
specify our analysis
so i'm going to go a little bit over time now
and will
so we start to live life after the break
so what we need to do is we need to deal with uncertainty being cm
measuring some doctor my measurement device might be love with
and in some mathematical tools
quite convenient is probability theory in this case
i want to
make a statement will give this image of some greenish objects well what are the
chances that this is an apple and orange after all it could be an unripe
i might want to find out whether things happen at the same time with have
unusual events like low density events
might want to condition things
given this apple given this image what are the chances that this is an at
large that's the conditional statements
what we have is
we take have some space of possible outcomes
then p of x tells how likely that is actually people usually will start introducing
sigma algebras here but we're not going to worry about it
so that
these are very basic axioms
namely the probability of an event is somewhere between zero and one
the problem is that something happened is one
if i have disjoint
and the probability that
any of those events is going to happen is just the sum of those probabilities
and you can infer from that the probability
the union between x and y
it's just the probability of x
possible y
one is the chance that both things happen at the same time
so here's the proof
probability of both events
for the first time in one of the second
the thing to fix
the thing you might have is multiple very
we might have some product space
x and y
same classification relation with a we always have those pairs
well i might want to say something about y given x or about excuse why
the simplest thing that could actually happen is that x and y have nothing to
do with each other
in other words x y bin
this happens if the probability of x and y happening is just the product of
the probabilities
a simple example
so i
well you want to find out what it's going to be a boy or a
you go to an astrologer
the story goes into the backroom case the crystal ball tosses the coin depending on
whether it comes up heads tails it will tell you it's going to be a
boy girl
yes some money
you pay
well as you can see in half of all the cases this rose gets it
that's when you tell your neighbor i which is just resident she's going to tell
you that it's right
this case still be ashamed and not tell anybody
that's how this strongest keeps on making money
you he
we only talk about these cases right
you could be a little bit more scientific you go to some physicians
probably you get it right most of the time maybe sometimes you know the sound
quite that good
but usually
you get it right
this is when you tell you never
now the bayes rule
i can write the joint probability of x and y
and data in their nature
how long these analyses we remove uncertainty
so you to listen to
and you're using tools in the toolbox
that is that is sensitive to the
you have to
it's not worth
so this is what title is
our contributions toward national news muslims
forty five
one of my
so what does it should be
but you should
this talk
are you trying to do
so on
this one
right is of the square also
much less common sense
so what i want is also wanted to see if some instances these notions of
the nineteen from two thousand
so using a
well my slides
this is the nature of things
yes know describe process images should be
this is rather than getting
rather than a single
we have decision
the is all
and then were most people
and we get rho
get life
and mention
this is this is in the row space
on this
in this position is used
it's system
so this is two examples date
two these security
you may
we use these points to
what is really happening decision
and more also
not something else
more also served point using
it easy see
that is
so please again
this this line is it's one thing that
now i i want to thank you for and your as you can see green
you might start with this one was
call me call
now is not the one one
and that's the
corresponding long
a very simple things that certain point one
to do these applications
so you need to have a good implementations of memory
because there is no learning without memory so there could be
the entire subset of what we did
we would collect the research would cannot that would be around the city memory another
theme could be
so i
staging them you know in in order of what is the the most basic function
that living systems have so even living system needs to have learning functionality it needs
for us to have some way of storing information if you don't have memory you
can't have any other form of learning
so to me at least the next stage if you if you can do some
learning is to be able to to the simple control tasks within the least elaborate
living systems that are capable of learning and can do these are like the warms
the can you know crawl and died themselves so they can seem so some simple
control tasks
then more elaborate living systems the they get into a planning and so they have
to do forecasting and decision-making so this is more elaborate type of learning
and finally
language to me would be
even get know a higher level in terms of cognition of types of
a body of tools that you need to solve learning problems of course i realize
you know there are many ways of of of
creating a classification of the types of research and learning and this is just you
know suggestion but what i'm trying to do here is an tightest to find one
way of having a relatively small number
of paul's around which all these exhibits all this research could be regrouped so that
the general public could understand well learning has to do with memory was call in
robotics with you know the statistics forecasting
and this is making and also with the
language learning or
because this kind of applications
and so within each category we can of course three google lot of of different
things and this could be of course we can replace you know if you have
other ideas we can replace each box by something else but then you should start
thinking about organizing laying out an exhibition in an exhibit hall you could have done
with different
seems that correspond to
different locations in the public could walk school for that and at the centre of
the application
seems to survival creation
would be fueled by these building the right building blocks
i came up with with that and i can elaborate a little bit about it
in the discussion if you want i was thinking of both
learning machines and teaching machines
because i think the learning and teaching have to walk hand-to-hand and we can present
learning so computers that can learn and also computers that can teach in this case
it's a lot of opportunities for you know attracting interesting
demonstrations so making people think what is learning how do we learn and when we
learn about learning so when we understand how learning works how we can benefit from
it in teaching applications
one such attempts is these challenges so
you know that pascal has been organizing a lot of
challenges in machine learning and challenge in machine learning our also tool for teaching so
so how do we compute we stop
watson of this idea
you've contraction
we are interested in knowing the fixed point of the fraction of the
now assume that we start you come to the greedy policy about how they want
that is because of the
well i fixed point here right
o that that first two cookies
hungary for
sorry i
OK so these are getting called value iteration
so you start this as you said just this some initial value function
apply t three you get the next iterate
it is indefinitely
and this process is converging to restart
one thing that we study just gone through the greedy policy
should be easy
if you have the more the knowledge of surfacing
so this sounds pretty nice and the rate of convergence is metric which is also
pretty good
but then the question is how do we really want to do this indefinitely or
do we want to stop at a certain stage
so this is not really an argument right so if you see that something has
to be repeated infinitely
many times and that's not
so we want to
to stop some but there are some then
there is a theorem that says that
OK so what would happen if you started if you stop
what would you do you would still constitute the greedy policy i would guess because
you you have no other
no no better gas
of what the good policy might be
c hold that if
let's stop this article still be spot than the greedy policy
with respect to that saying is going to be nearly optimal
and so this is again some concrete arguments and locative because of this nice contractions
you can really have
that property
and this is what many would understand so to say that
well in particular imagine that you stop there is some value function v
w option value function be militarized it doesn't have to be auctioned by conduction by
and then you're interested in the
and you you take policy pi with greatest respect to guy
and you are interested in the difference between them
the platform and stopped performance and the performance under policy pi
luckily can conclude that performance can be bonded
by what's called the ban that are
the value function v so
this is what
the next iterate would be if we continue the process
so we subtract that from what we got right now
we compute the supply on r and we divided by one minus come
and multiply by two and that bonds the expressing their
so one thing to notice here is that this is a pointwise long so this
is shown as an unborn
but the pi
there's no larger than we start right
so the
the start of acts
could be
larger than the pie
but the difference between the two guys any acts cannot be larger than than this
so that means that if you stop this
function to such that
TV minus the the norm that is sort of this morning after
they should be safe
the next question is
if that is going to happen
if if you
iterate this process a long long time and that's very easy to see that that's
going to happen because
so let's we have k
the the case iterates over fk is just
to the power of k applied to be zero
let's take
the FK minus the k
the difference between these two guys was the so this is just a t to
the power of k
times TV
minus theta the path can applied to be zero difference between the two guys and
even more
so you know that if apply this contraction key times
then you've got to gain the contraction is contraction coefficient of government to the power
of k
right because we had this rule that says that if you have two lipschitz operators
and you take the composite operator
then the league constant for the composite operator is just the product of the lipschitz
constant of the operators
for all these operators delicious constant just come up
so you have to multiply got lucky and got government to the power of k
so then this can be bounded
but property government to the part of k
he the zero minus resale
so this is converging to zero
at the tumour great
if you can measure the initial
this stands between TV zero and these in all
then you get the bond
the performance rights just like in the case here is that we
you get about
you know how many trees you have to it if you have three strikes
creativity and then and then you can just need them by solving this for k
and it happens that in the finite MDP
for this reason you can stop after a certain number of iterations because you only
so many policies and the performance gap between
and the policy that the second best and the best policy is positive number and
then you can stop of the rise this is that the is so interesting
what's interesting is that to some people at least that you can get the pursuit
of complex polynomial complexity result of this
so that was one are given and
that's the basis of many many learning target insects as well
so this is why the learning abilities or faster
so the the other good news goes by the name of hard
this is called the policy
iteration are getting
and the basic design
goes like this
so if you
have some policy pi
you have a and that policy you get its value function v
and then you take a greedy policy is suspected that phi functions so that's why
i prior
what is saying is it any better this policy or not so the the great
inside of hard was that this policy should be
really better
then the addition of policy that started this and this is very easy to to
see and the following theorem also if you do this
the value function of the new policy is is never smaller than the value function
of the policy
and in particular
if it happens
then when you come to these maxims
you do this one step lookahead so this ban operator does want to look at
it takes imitative art
and then
the future the words
and there
as a kind of context variable
and so i'm not making a random variable and is now i've actually gone way
where i explicitly made things random variables in the bayes net to have the context
so it depends on the
scenario you're under but
the way
this work is you can have a separate context predicate
in the body of the rule
and he only backward chaining it
it's true
the center for this
is we can change
ph be context predicate
and we can say that
bob is author
p one
we can make the assumption that it
a fact is and
the background knowledge base
you can be
prove it
ten one
at all
then the way something like this would work
when he
i don't actually add an explicit variable here
and i can deal with the fact that
basically the context very well is
in a certain way handling kind of negation because it's dealing with the negation as
failure for
not being
after t one
and so you get a kind of simpler structure here
is the way
being able to have a deterministic
structure that everything's conditioned on
it's not included as part of the model
and you actually see an analogy with this
and some of the other approaches
but then to cycle question so
one of the things is
they made an assumption
there's no cycles
the resulting bayes
and so
if there are cycles travel
i think this was
some of the
so in a certain way the semantics here
the knowledge based model construction are kind of procedural semantics and you go through this
procedure building a base that if
you get a bayes net then you have the semantic
it's not really
expressed declaratively
in terms of the program but instead of this constructed network
can have
some of the other issues they come up
are things like
the brown random variables and i talked about so far have been
bland random variables
but obviously
you get into some
difficulties here so
if i want to have
lead author
p one alice lead out there
p one bob
for all possible values
that's gonna blow up
so that
kind of unappealing
and on top of that
i did not encoding the constraint
that well there should only be one
lead after