which means that the maximum number of distinct rows is no more than
which means the right most
so clearly an MDP with n states
cannot produce the system dynamics matrix was rank is more than
yes because
the only way be n distinct rows
in every row every history that and in the same state where the same future
the prediction yes
the park
the whole
we have the highest might not want to use an MDP
cannot produce even states can produce is made that one
i'm going to show you my model
two minutes
but having
so i just wanted to say
one hundred years of pompey NDP except you don't get to see the states so
if you ignore the last
these these nodes you look at things about this as an MDP state at time
state at time t plus one depends on the last state and the action you
chose the conditional probability table to the transition matrix determines the distribution of the next
state given the last state and the action so if i didn't have the edges
coming out there will be a markov decision process is a graphical model representation of
a markov decision process upon BP is just we don't get to see the state
instead you get to see some other thing which is the observation
which is determined stochastically from the state to make mark to make it upon the
pond these are hugely richer class that MDP in fact most real world situations you
have publicly because you never really get to see the state
OK so you never get the states
is the underlying hidden things like chairs and tables and things that generally get to
observe what you get observe visual images or
auditory signals things that's all
right so
all worlds are really pompey things
OK well actually you know what i proved you now
any palm TV with an underlying hidden states
cannot produce a ceramics matrix of rank more than n and then i'll show you
my model
and this proof of i'm not going to hopefully only hopefully some of you get
i don't think all of you here because be very fast over to how to
pompey's work how HMM is one way to men's work is you don't get to
see the state so what do you do instead
instead what you do is you take your observations and compute posteriors over the underlying
bayes rule basically by using the obvious bayesian updating procedure to say i don't get
to see the state i can see observations so i'm just going to maintain the
distribution over the underlying states and that's going to be my representation of state distribution
over states
the called belief states often in the in the punjabi literature groups of belief states
are you representation of state in hmm upon
the key
he said need which to be
and got very fast is the following
if i want to make predictions about any possible future and upon DP give me
the belief state it turns out the prediction for any future is a linear function
of the belief state
so if you give me any possible test and that's make predictions it turns out
that the prediction for a test p of the given age is the belief state
by age and history the belief state captures the history
find some
a linear linear weights like
so what does that mean
OK the proof of this is actually very straightforward is you know upon you're a
tremendous sort of that mean that means the following if i consider
and rose
in this the belief states are unit basis vectors meets means in which the belief
is that you and one specific state underlying state
right so you basis vectors meaning one zero zero zero zero one zero zero zero
zero zero ones are those just
with all the probability mass in a particular state that underlying states and such belief
factors consider rose
in general corresponding to the end
you can prove quite easily that any row
is a linear combination of those and rose with the linear combination is exactly the
linear content is exactly the belief
that the corresponding history we said again
support as how compute destroy the find this history this is really the corresponding belief
so it assigns some probability of state one somebody state to somebody state three to
then this row is that same linear combination
the other rows that correspond to unit basis police station
despite linear linear algebra
which means
the maximum rank maximum number of linearly independent rows is an
hence the rank that
so what
i won't go to the point very much more
let me now
show you my representation now my alternative representation called predictive state representations you should be
you know
why this interesting cell come back in titus that explain why this might be might
be interesting so here's my model here's my representation predictive state representation of this class
of systems and it looks like this
these core tests
q one qn
my state representation is going to be the predictions forties core tests
the point is that of course given any history h these and numbers are sufficient
statistics of history meaning i can make prediction for any test from the numbers
so if i gave you need a number of my state
and then i take an action a
and get observation o so my new histories h a o
the question to answer is how do i update my in numbers so that have
these numbers
if i can answer that question how models
because i can maintain my state that know that from my state i can make
any prediction i one
are actually
you understand the point i'm making so what i'm going to show you now is
the following
if you give me the numbers for my current history
if i take an action a scene observation of
and we show you how to compute it
the this
these are numbers
if i could do that but i can maintain their numbers as i take action
the observations and i know that one to have been a number that can predict
anything you want
four that seems yes
that's my goal to show you how to update the numbers
that's not to be quite straightforward
so let's look at one particular number here
corresponding to the past q survive
let me show you update that
the prediction fortescue survive in the new one step long history
it's just by classic probability
is the prediction of one step along the past in the old history
divided by
the probability of the one step past in old history
good probabilistic model of document and we can plug in any
probabilistic model of document in here and in principle be able to compute this kind
of score
OK if are items are images again we can go and buy a good model
of features of images and plug in whatever that
good model features of images is in the model
the important thing is that whatever the model is that we're putting in has the
three parameters
that allows it to
model different kinds of images or different kinds of documents etcetera
that engendered work with
well do that in a minute
it's it's it looks alike mutual information except that
it's not averaging with respect to x
OK it's that some people have called
such things pointwise mutual information
but that is a kind of termites are occasionally
yeah that's a very good question
ideally what you might want to do is
you might want to consider from our universe of items
possible subsets
you know in theory all possible subsets and see which one is best with our
concept or category
that's just much more computationally expensive
so the cheapest thing to do is to rank the items but if you can
afford a little bit more computation time
then you might want to consider whether
list of ranked items is actually cohen in with a single concept or not
but i'm thinking
here about a realistic information retrieval applications in which
you send the query and you expect the answer back you know
after your link
so let's elaborate a little more on this criterion
so we can write the score for items as the ratio
of the probability of x
given the query that divided by the probability of x
now the probability of x given the query that we can decompose into
the probability of x and the query that
divided by the probability of the query that this makes it look even more like
a mutual pointwise mutual information
and now what we see is that the score is actually a ratio
involving three marginal likelihood
in the
the numerator what we have
is the probability of the item x and the queries
which is a particular marginal likelihood where both the item and the queries that were
generated from the parameters data
and then in the denominator we have two terms one of them is that the
marginal likelihood
or the ACT and the other one is the marginal likelihood for the query
but it turns out the computer core
the only thing we need is to be able to compute marginal likelihoods for arbitrary
from our model and given our prior
and this is another perspective on this score
which can be expressed through a graphical models
what the score actually does
it is the following
it compares
two hypotheses
the data was generated
in the numerator
we have the hypothesis
query set
and the idea that we're trying to score
were generated
from a single setting of the parameters of our generative model
but given that
parameter is unknown we have integrate over possible
adding that parameter could
this is the generative model where
r v
queries that any item or scoring were generated from the same but unknown parameters data
we're going to change
to talk to you about
so it's
i also that added pressure
barometric pressure
if for now we
forget gravity
and i would have a
closed off
and filled with fluid gas so it could be
a liquid
has every a year
and i apply force on it
and i apply pressure
pressure is defined
force divided by area
has units newton's discrimina
it is also called
of course
one of the first i mean there's one
in the absence of gravity
is everywhere
in this special
the same
and that's what's called
articles principle
cost principle says that the pressure applied to to an enclosed fluid
is transmitted undiminished
to every point in the fluid
into the walls
of the container
keep in mind pressure is the scalar
it has no direction
has direction
and the force exerted by the fluid
on anything therefore also on the wall
must be everywhere perpendicular to the wall
because if there were any tangential component
then the fluid would start to move
actually equals minus reaction so it starts to move
and we are talking about
static fluid
so if i take any
element i take one year at the surface
little element delta a
and the force must be perpendicular to that surface
delta s
so delta have
by delta a
in the limiting case
delta a goes to zero
it is then that pressure
has some truly amazing
consequences which are by no means
so intuitive
this is the idea of an hydraulic
i have here
that's always has very
curious shape
and let be here
based on on it
area a one
for every eight
it's filled with liquid
and i apply here force
f one
before after
so the pressure that i apply here
is f one
divided by a one according to pass call everywhere in the fluid
that pressure must be the same
for now
i just assume that the effect of gravity which i will discuss shortly
doesn't change
the situation
very significantly
i will address the gravity very shortly
so the pressure then will be the same everywhere
the pressure due to this site is f two divided by a two
so too must be the same
if the liquid is not moving
so what that means is that is a two
of a one
there were one hundred
it would means that this force
three hundred times less than that one
in other words i could put on here the weights
the last ten kilograms
and he i could put a thousand kilograms
and it will be completing an equally well
that's not so intuitive
this is using
all the garages
what they do is they put on top of this
i believe that up here
so this is this platform
there's around here
and on top of it is car
and someone pushes here
and then
this goes up
the cargo so
if i push here
with a four-cylinder with more than ten kilograms so that would be hundred newtons
this level will go up
so your first thought maybe g
isn't that a violation of the conservation of energy
isn't it time and i'm not going to be getting something for nothing
well not really
suppose i push this down over the distance d one
then the amount of fluid that i place is the volume
it's a one times the one
that through its ends up here
so this one will go up
over the distance d two
but the same amount of through the
these here
and there
in other words
a one b one
must be a true
the two
if the force here
hundred times
less than the force there
the work
i'm doing on the left side
f one
times the one
if the force he was hundred times less than that
distance that i move
is hundred times larger than the two
because a two over a one is one hundred
so f one the one
it will be the same
as f two d two
a hundred times
lower force
but over one hundred times larger distance
it is maximizing the edge
and depending on that we kind of smaller or larger much
OK and that's actually a wide range i mean
so it can be small can aligned
however when you choose this parameter role
you see
this region becomes very small so i mean when you choose wrote i mean let's
say the maximum margin is zero point four individuals role close to resume point four
then this difference between the performance of the best in the worst
case performance becomes really small
so we can ensure that the most might not converge because essentially the base learner
if it's really so it can go like first this i mean first be corporate
if later
b i mean performed first then goes back and forth between these two
case so and the
the function does not converge
OK so
OK so here's some
results of how to get to the full of adaboost stop but thinking about it
in the material
i skip limit here
just show you the final version of
OK so
that is again just a slight modification of adaboost so
the main difference is that we don't have to specify this parameter role in the
beginning but now this parameter always adapted during the iterations
so essentially the look at the edge of the base learners so these gamma t
take the minimum of all those actions
subtract the limit
and you see that in in that are of computation
OK so the difference to all i did was throw is just that the adaptively
choose this committee
OK so now you might ask does large margin help
and here is one example that helps so
it really depends on the dataset
OK so this is a hundred dimensional data set
and we have only to discover that features and these two discriminative features look like
and all the other dimensions are essentially noise
so you see that there are separated they are not very well separated but they
and then we used c four point five
adaboost and precursor version of this article started by this
doing essentially the same
so when we run c four point five we measure the generalisation error seven point
four percent
the average in two hundred runs
when you're on adaboost with c four point five then you get a generalisation error
four percent
the margin is as you point three which was achieved
and when you run this extended better version of articles which achieves the larger margin
and the at the margin of viewpoint point pi eight
and we find that the genes asian error
goes down to three point six percent is not a very big difference but it's
so the large margin can improve the generalisation performance
however many have noisy data
then might not so empirically it i mean many if noisy data then you might
do something else might want to do something else
OK it essentially what what i was doing so this is tries to solve this
this optimisation problem so we try to maximize this variable role such that the margin
of all the examples
are larger than role
we have these the some of the output is this one and they critical because
so this is the linear optimisation problem
so this is
some which goes over all hypotheses posts so here i assumed it's just fine the
number of courses and as i said it's just j
OK so this is normal linear programme
so the dual optimisation problem just looks like this so we try to find some
excellent such that the edge of all hypotheses is smaller than epsilon and we have
to find the distribution d which is critical zero and the sum to one
OK so this the dual optimisation problem
you can compute this from this
and we have a solution to this one then you get a solution
so this is for finding fuzzy sets so you can generalize this now to infinite
process it's adaboost stuff star and i actually be they all solve this
even when the number of crosses
it is infinite
so here we have infinite sums
so we can just use adaboost and other will actually be and all these other
things we can use force holding such a linear programs
so these seamy infinite linear programs because there infinitely many constraints or he has infinitely
many constraints or infinitely many variables
OK so this is just something interesting in itself
so adaboost did not depend on the number of did not depend on the size
of the force sent
i really didn't care about about that is infinitely many constraints so the just go
through everything works
so this is a solution method for solving this optimisation problems
so when you consider that most are so converges to the solution of this linear
so what this does is that it gradually expands the network out from the query
nodes until it bumps into evidence
and of course in the worst case you know this will reduce the whole world
but more often you know there will be something boundary evidence that separates the query
from you know the vast majority of atoms out there and you get a big
efficiency gains
there no however in this case as well
and the snake is the following
is we want to be able to subsume both probabilistic and logical inference which means
we have to be able to deal with deterministic dependencies
and i was like MCMC and belief propagation can handle deterministic dependencies
for example in the case of gibbs sampling is easy to see why it breaks
if i deterministic dependencies what that means is that there are some possible worlds over
and there some possible worlds over here but they don't communicate
so i can start if i stuck my markov chain over here else sample over
here forever and ever jump over there and it into their get the wrong probabilities
even if all i have is very strong dependencies
what that means is that yes i could go from here to here but i
have to take on a bunch of unlikely steps to go from one to the
you know the more steps i have to take the exponential less likely exponentially longer
time to go from one to the other side in practice what happened
and this is in fact what makes probabilistic inference five minutes long-standing problem
and here again there's something that we can do
by combining ideas from probability and logic which is to have an MCMC algorithm where
the the next step is actually obtained by running a SAT solver
sets of are very good at finding isolated you know non-zero probability regions of space
that's what they're for
so you can use the sets of and very quickly jump between modes whereas give
sampling with basically take forever
course there's some details in making this work correctly but they can be figured out
so this the so called MC SAT that experimentally is just many orders of magnitude
faster than gives an even you know more sophisticated MCMC algorithms designed to deal with
this problem of multiple isolated nodes
i won't go into the details of it here
but it's certainly not itself with things like and cystatin said basically underlie our ability
to do this type of modelling in domains of realistic size today
OK what about learning
well learning for learning in our data instead of the single relation is going to
be a relational database with an arbitrary number of
relations in
i'm going to keep making the assumption that there is no missing data which you
know here in this case what this means is that i'm going to make a
closed world assumption
on the database that i'm using for learning meaning any atom that is not in
that it was assumed to be false
in many cases this is inappropriate assumption one it's not that i need to use
the and versions of these algorithms and again they are available but in this tutorial
going ignore decision
and of course there's going to be again learning parameters i e weights learning structure
i e formulas as before
so how do the weight learning
just as we did for markov networks
we have the same gradient descent procedure another the
the gradient is just the difference between the number of times the clauses true in
the data and the expected number of closed times it's true according to the MLE
it is exactly the same way as before
we're just doing it now on a non IID world forwarding it on an IB
world but the beautiful thing is that the masterworks of the same
so can actually handle this complicated dependencies with at some level no extra work conceptually
of course computationally it could be a lot more expensive
and not to the generative learning we can use the likelihood as before
into the discriminative learning we can use conditional likelihood as before
and now for inference
we can use
MC SAT
to compute these expectations or
we can use maxwalksat to compute the most likely state and then to the counts
in there
so very straightforward extension of the algorithms for markov networks what about structure learning
well again this is a very straightforward the extension of feature
induction for markov networks
and it it's really kind of inductive logic programming like we're trying to learn clauses
x so in principle you could use any for this
except for a couple of things
one is that
most at the other end up for learning horn clauses and he won induce any
clauses not just horn clauses
so we need something a bit more general and the other one is that
p with a simple have something like accuracy coverage
no information gain is evaluation measure
and that's not appropriate here
because you are trying to model the probability distribution if you do if you use
those criteria you get results
so we actually one is something like the likelihood or you know some posterior probability
as the evaluation function
now this as
so conceptually can take an LP with within generalize it to handle you know any
clauses user likely because the russian function and you have an organ for learning alliance
the problem though is that this is going to be hideously slow
there's is going to be hideously slow
is that
as before
we can little we need to learn weights for each candidate clauses any time i
what is that
that's sophie fy x that's right depends only on the variables in x of s
what can we say about this guy here
the term indexed by a
right you can only depend on things in a and s
right that's again using
part of the cutset property
right there cannot be any connection between a and b so there's no way that
be term will somehow pull me and this guy can only depend on
much of these different names this is as
this is a s and this is fee
so that depends only on bns
OK so
you can tell me why that's useful so what we sort of done is we've
just taken our factorisation we've collapsed it into three terms
one for a one for b and one for the overlap there
right so if you remember what we're trying to prove right what we're trying to
prove is this guy right here we're trying to prove that when we condition on
x of s
then it becomes the product of two terms
so i won't
right out the algebra leave that for you guys but essentially the proof is done
because what happens now is if you take this new condition you're going fix
this this become some constant that you don't care about
you fix some of these variables in
fix these variables here
but after conditioning what you have is just to separate product of a
in terms indexed by b so you can see exactly the splitting of factors conditioning
you get exactly the splitting that you wanted to somehow that decomposition that was the
key in this particular argument and of course the decomposition that was using this claim
that but you should verify that we did in fact have disjoint union that was
using the fact that we had a vertex cut set
OK so that some
that's all it shows is one direction that shows us the factorisation property
implies markov so summarizing
if we
what you'll see is that px
a x b if we condition on x of s
i right
proportional to number snowdrop things that
depend only
on as because those
conditioning those are fixed i'm to get something that's basically proportional to
fy a s
x a
put bar because we're conditioning on it and
and vx p access
i to be some constants floating around but we don't care about those
that's enough to show is that this system breaks into the product we wanted
OK so any questions about that
OK so that actually was the
the easier direction as you might have thought
probably just in the interest of time i won't prove the other direction because it
would take a fair bit of work but i can sort of tell you how
it works
the other direction is is a bit harder so if you look at the assumption
the assumption of the theorem include that you have a strictly positive distribution
but this argument
i mean you might worry a little bit about dividing by zero when i condition
but if you look carefully at this argument it actually holds for any distribution can
you hold for distributions that might assign zero probability to some
on configurations but the reverse that if you have a markov you have the markov
this factorisation property doesn't always hold unless the distribution is strictly positive
so if you look in the book by lawrence and it's book called graphical models
you can find all these sort of weird kind of examples
what the proof uses it uses
something called the mobius inversion formula
so this is what i said it certainly needs this assumption that p of x
is bigger than zero
it's it's a nice proof it's kind of combinatorial uses something called obvious inversion
and i won't go into details on it here
you can now
you can read it in the proof of this
and so in the
the directory that i set up for this course on the first page of slides
the web address i left a set of introductory lectures that actual go well
review this proof that i just did but also
state them obvious inversion and go for the backward direction too
so if you're interested you can have a look at that if you have never
seen it i i think it's worth looking at just once because
while historically it's interesting and it's nice argument it's it's nice to understand why these
two things are are equivalent
OK so any questions
OK so
what i'd like to start talking about now and what will spend a lot of
tomorrow morning talking about is
more the the kinds of computational questions that arise when you apply a graphical model
right we've already seen some instances of the kinds of computational problems that you'd like
to solve
one of them you'd like to solve is is basically a sort of simply stated
it's basically just a giant summation or a giant in general
i haven't said much so far about what this mysterious c quantity is
the state space with the same size for example
the complexity of computing this thing will be basically
s times at times times at times s
o two n
we have asked again
i mean there's no way
in practice we were talking this thing the images and you have millions of
or these things may be next
all these things maybe
speech signal
particles of physical system there's no way you can actually compute anything
if you
just one
every element of your sample space from your original representation k
just giving an example
if you wanted to
ask both types of queries like some probabilistic calculations
in the model
in any realistic
you be able to do it
so you we need some type of compact representation for p
right because if you going to compute these
is not practical we need some
some type of compact representation for in what graphical models is gives you is precisely
that some of these you
nice structure for p
that allows you to perform this calculation
in nice inefficient man ac
OK for many types of graphical
that's the critical observation again
when the
compactness of the model or when the structure of the model
arises from conditional independence statements involving the viable
graphical models
these what you need
to for the screen
and and this is an important point
graphical models have been used for many types of applications
and they are extremely helpful extremely important
but we need to understand their limitations as well
i mean
they are not the right model for any type of the probabilistic structure
so graphical models are used
in these types of cases
when the structure of your probabilistic space is given by conditional independencies among the online
there's not mean
that's the only
interesting structure that you may have and you probably
for example you may have
structure our probabilistic space that i
probably six space maybe structural according to
patterns between the limitations of the body
she does not have to do with a particular
viable stem cells but we
all the valuables at the same time
immediately graphical models but they don't seem
to be
the right tools to study these things in the present study
o situation
so i mean we should understand that
graphical models basically really talking about structural problems structured probabilistic models when these
structure arises from
conditional independence
of course been talking alot about conditional independence so had to convince you that
this is a useful concept that actually realized the real problem
many of them
on the idea of
conditional independence
this is
the shortest possible introduction i i could
prepare for what's going to come
i will start
already before the break because we still have about twenty minutes before the first
made some
approximations and what was the approximation we use just the
the class approximation
someone as long the question
but multiple classes had support vector machines deal with multiple classes
and i'm sure you've all been wondering the same about this how do we deal
with multiple classes and this sort of setting
so what i'm going to do is i'm going to
a way of doing gaussian process
over multiple classes
and i will introduce you to a couple of new concepts which hopefully should
prove interesting
so now we're going to do is we're going to
the classification
the target values when they take on
values from one to k keeping the number of
classes that you could be considering
let's make some modelling assumptions here
let's assume
so for each class
we want to discriminate we need to find the function which somehow or other
describes it discriminates that class from all of others
so what we will do is really soon
that we have no real importance
a gaussian process prior
each class
right so there's going to be a function for each class
so that means that our prior
is not going to be
on the function values for class one
the function values for class two the function values of two
class k
the covariance function parameters
the GP for class one up to
class k
and given
a set of attributes of covariates
now also
and impose the restriction that p on
each of these gaussian processes for each class
is independent
and that's perfectly reasonable because quite well we haven't seen what the dependencies between the
yeah it
we'll see
that posterior only the posterior over functions will be dependent
so we can just assume
statistical independence of each of these goes in processes
so we take a product form over k
all of our gaussian process priors
for each class
still with me
are about thirty percent of
what about the likelihood function
what was the likelihood function is just to the for binary classification
when you're always asking questions you should remember this was
what was the the the likelihood function to be used
for binary classification
two classes
it was a binomial and the function that we used was the logistic function sigmoid
function remember
so now we need to
look at what the
likelihood is going to be over two classes
so over two classes we had a binomial function a binomial distribution
over k classes
we have a multinomial distribution might so we have to keep possible choices
and this is for those of you who done
so someone pick me up last night for was fitting to schoolboy algebra so and
if anyone has done some schoolboy statistics
and will recognise the
multinomial distribution
which is basically OK we'll see just short
but if and
if the class label for the instigator of point
corresponds to the case class
then this delta function returns of one
why do that
i'm just to show you that i can do right i'm just demonstrated that i
can stick any denied any DNA
remember the DNA doesn't want to have a piece of DNA it doesn't know whether
it came from human or zebra it's just the molecule you can stick the molecules
right but what i really want to attach my human DNA two
i want to attach to to some other DNA
that has the ability to grow on its own
within bacteria
i need to make
here's what i would really like
i would like to have a piece of DNA
it has some sequences
the recognition sites
four replication
i'd like have some replication initiation sites here
so piece of DNA
one of the bacterial chromosome itself
here's my bacteria
the bacteria is on chromosome
replicates itself
and it has
the ability to start DNA replication at multiple sites
called origins
but what i would really like
is to be able to construct in the laboratory
a synthetic piece of DNA
that also would function
as an origin
a replication
because then what i could do
is in vitro
take my piece of DNA
attach it to this effect
it would now
we have the ability to grow bacteria
how like make
a piece of DNA what kind of engineering tricks can do
to create a small piece of DNA that has all the machinery
to be able to be copied replicated just like bacterial chromosomes
that's a pretty fancy feat of engineering
i can do that
risk because so we're ask
if you want to do this you ask the experts who are the experts
viruses or
four or bacteriophage basically if you want to do anything the place to ask
is the folks who have the most experience folks have the most experience are almost
prokaryotic out organisms
because they are by far the most evolved things on this planet anything that can
replicate itself and grow every twenty minutes or something like that somewhat more generations of
evolution and you have and therefore they are much more optimise than we are to
go asking say
has a bacteria worked out how to do this
students had better in order to do this just fine
in fact
most bacteria
least many bacteria
contained within
in addition to their own chromosome
small circles of DNA
these are called
happy so
this is the chromosome
that means on top of or in addition to
so in addition to the chromosome there's an episode
the episode
is in fact an autonomously replicating piece of DNA
it has a large
and markets
why bacteria have episodes
it turns out that the songs
often contain genes
one of the genes they contain
or some of the types of genes they contain are resistance to
there might be for example
a penicillin
resistance gene
contains on episode
or streptomyces reserve resistance
it turns out the bacteria
i have these episodes containing resistance genes
they're not in the chromosome set
why would they do that
it turns out
one a bacterium dies in the cell cracks open
the DNA spills out
the next door neighbour bacteria
has mechanisms to suck up DNA from the environment
never know might find something interesting out there
it turns out that bacteria are rather promiscuously exchanging pieces of DNA
all the time
and so i bacteria that has a
episode the has the penicillin resistance genes
can spread it
two other bacteria and and it's very nice it's compact on its own little episode
autonomously replicating piece of DNA
we are more likely to be in
that are available at
being laid down by a little bit you really haven't an initial conditions keep on going
three hundred eighty five
i know of of four hundred set
you can hardly see on screen that
the yellow and blue
in absence
almost all of your initial condition was in one hundred
one day
and that is that
all and all
five hundred in the fall
i you it into them and the fact that the relation with it and that's where i think when we
thank you
any questions about
so the general message we've got it
you make that's all size at all
and it the distribution in dealing with the characteristic length scale
or al in the same units
a random walk methods is going at least
element belongs where
to get around it may be worth because there might be other properties you know
the registration might not be canyon in like that will get across
then you have to write the even longer
so this
number we've got three years
one on where
is bound lower bound on how long you might have run
and will be what
everything i've shown here as in one dimension let's make clear how it relates to
high-dimensional problems in the typical
it they an inference problem that you're working on
and if all of these
things called acts are unknown parameters that are being determined by data
in the real world typically you have quite a lot of data and you have quite a lot
and so
and we read distribution
they look more like this
maybe two dimensional maybe even two thousand dimensional
and it will have some long lengthscale some lengthscale that are
that's a bit shorter
in general you might have
this is again a cup to
the real situation
might be gamma dimensions gamma could yield good
even well determined dimensions
gamma dimensions
where the length scale is less al
and then there might be very minor gamma other dimensions
in which the length scale is much larger
and would be wholly determined relative the total number of grammar the damage you at the page
minus gamma dimension that will be determined by the data you have
and then you
and gamma world determined by the data
so this is your effective number of parameters the only number freedom
number well parameters
you know give yourself a step size
that's long
you could imagine all
small out
all smaller they could use just like problem
something that
finally let
why can use
are you something
thank you
even when you're designing a metropolis
i think have a long
he any size you want to know it back
around what's gonna happen now well
all in all your there are accepted and you don't do a random walk
then it still the case
at the typical distance u we'll gone
he that's is going as the square root
it's going to take you
at least element belongs where
get around from one independent points in to another
and then what they need at least
one of with that's
you get
pressure independent points
so that's pushes you say well i want i want to be really big van allen at all
small of this
bacteria with group
let's make it on unambiguously had
if made at already beginning motivated alpha example
then what actually happened
well if you are interested in you make proposal
and the green there
which remember
gamma dimensional effectively the whole place is a dimensional
and gamma vote dimensions of the kind that in fact with with a little help
and in so many the government will not and
what about mean is the probability of making and accept the move it at one day
it can be the ratio of
the following
and that's bad news
and i think the metrics
which is not symmetric the proposed an algorithm for performing grouping which is actually spectral
and also are already already so that using mean field new for finding
groupings using this method
so we compared our results
with the with those obtained using the original
and then we also compare the results using the symmetrized version we wanted to see
what happens if symmetrized that
so we perform the few experiments on synthetic data
we had
for example circle here
and a lot of nice
this is what happens
bias algorithms
ours is
this one
williamson former USSR
this is using the that mation
for example compare with the original williams former of which is exactly the same similarity
but using the spectral form
so what happens is that the big picture which emerges actually that
the replicator dynamics with the semantic matches
provides a good compromise between false positive and false negative rate
for example what happens is that usually
williamson form
very low
false positive rate
it's very conservative
yes very greatly
for example here you can see
there is no false negative
but you know the problem
to capture all a very significant part of shape
this is what we did
of course we incorporate knowledge as well
so we
when measurements
the big picture is that
using our algorithm against the original outcomes
is a good compromise between false positive rate false negative for example here we have
some problems with your original argument your original answer mathematics very low false positive rate
very low because it is a set this very conservative
field of false false negative rate is very high
while ours
the larger false positive rate and much more
false negative this is the big picture the
we also have to experiments in the early nineties
in this case the difference between
and we have some form
and even against against the symmetry this is what we got
i symmetrizing metrics so we got the radio asymmetric symmetrizing the replicator dynamics and you
can see the results are much worse
well actually
this confirms the intuition if i have
and regionalism that matters in this in the dry
just just using a lot of information
OK so let me go to the finals
part of this lecture
how can we use game theory
an interesting fact
the classical strategy you here for performing a partition of the input data is
belongs strategy
so i just
finding dominant sets remove it from graph theory applied research and so on
this is two problems
first this is not necessary for some months
it forces the hard partition
hard bound
the second problem that by
in this way
we are implicitly introducing
a change in this case
we're not change in the metrics using exactly the same edits four
but by removing
these are the ground right change this case
the data
so we can use game theory
perform an enumeration of the dominant set
to perform a partition of the data
which allows for overlapping last
this can be
can find some interesting application for example
consider the situation where
so there's is a transparent surface
that surface
makes perfect sense
it is classified
two different clusters
suppose case where we have
a very simple case
two clusters this is one cluster is another class
this point belongs both there's no way there's no sense to say this belongs to
this and not
are situations actually where it it is important to be able
get overlapping last
so let me show you the basic idea with a very simple case where we
don't have weights of edges
so we are working on
and directed undirected unweighted graphs
suppose that i found
these two dominant sets are to maximum clique
ABC on one side and a view
i want to
these two dominant set in the future so what i want to do is that
they want to run again the replicator dynamics
and i want to be sure that i will not get
these two guys here again how can i do that
OK to take is the following
for each maximum clique that you want to avoid just add an extra vertex
we are
but it's one here which is related to
and we have products to which is related to the
the greek
and you create new edges you could actually new
in this graph will be a directed one
so we are transforming an undirected graph the
you have directed edges
and the structure is the following
take for example this which is associated with this click here
to to right one
then you have edges which
you can mean edges and outgoing
you can't just start from that x one is doesn't one
and we reach all the vertices within
click associated two
all this just start from one to d
c into it
this is the parliament doesn't belong to directly
so you will have only just started from these
but this and ending up this
you do the same with this you have create new world
right so this is a lgn minus
the minimum
over virgin of energy
so if i take the minimum out then it becomes the maximum because there's a
minus sign so
n minus the minimum is the same as the maximum because of the difference between
a lgn lg
he's just comes from the definition of this quantity here
and this is called the estimation error i i like
to call it
better the maximum regret because it's the quantity that you can define even if you
don't have
this i framework even if you are not in the statistical framework and estimation is
a term that is usually used in the statistical for
OK and what did what it
it tells you is how much does the data
mislead you in
making you believe that gn is good while the the good function is g underscore
and this quantity of course depends on on the training data that you have
and the point is you can
quantify like get
upper bounds on this quantity
even if you don't make any assumptions about
you distribution
sorry about your target function
what is interesting when you do this decomposition is that you get term that
you cannot say anything about
and then another term
which you can control so the eighties now OK let's forget about this
let's say we will never be able to say anything about this
the party we make assumptions
so let's focus
on this term here
and we know anyway that the sum of those terms can be made arbitrarily large
because of the insurance and so let's see how small this can be a how
to control these these quantities here
because of
again rephrasing
so we want to focus on the estimation error or the maximum regret
somehow the message is that the
this learning theory will not tell you
how to justify your assumptions but it can tell you only
once you have put these assumptions what's once you've have made these restrictions
whether or not you believe that they are true is another problem but once you've
made them what can you do
to best exploit them
so now do a little bit of
mathematics finally
and i will introduce
selection bias variance decomposition
yes yes you can see that as a kind of a generalisation of the bias
variance decomposition sometimes
although it's not
always correct but sometimes people call these by using these different
but it's the same spirit
one is deterministic the other ones
so that's three
the main ingredient where you want to think about this quantity is maximum we wanted
one is deviation inequality
which are the basic probability inequalities about how
random variables deviates from verification
other one is called them
wiki so
i don't want
so which dates
the quantity we want to bound
something that we know how to do
so this estimation error can be related to the quantity that can be handled by
probability theory
and the
the gradient of interest actually
in my opinion this is the most important one is the union bound so it
how to
relates the deviation of a collection of random variables
once you know
each random variable
you see i mean flight
this is
i would say
the quantity of interest in this way
it is around one
so when you
so it's on the right
one of the random variable what can you i mean the kind of mathematical statement
you want to make about this from the variable is to characterize
how it actually right
the first thing can say is you want to compute the expectation of this from
the so again here expectation is with respect to the sampling of the training data
so showing you where to get repeated training samples of size n
and you have to compute
the average
error that that you make this these expectations in the
that's one quantity of interest
but sometimes people refer to quantify
one of the probabilities of the deviations
tell you what is the probability that these quantities larger than some
value epsilon
and why why is better it's because from this you can recover
all the properties of random variables with this is the distribution function of toronto bible
so it's completely characterize that characterizes it
quantity that some people
could be interested in is the worst case value of this from the bible
the maximum over all the possible training sample of this difference
OK this is usually not done in the framework and it's done more in the
on line framework but is just to tell you that
it's also something that you can get
a handle on
so so we will focus mainly on
the probability
what is a bit confusing here is that we have two layers of expectation one
layer is with respect to the training sample so we have the first kind of
random variable that we have is the training sample and then we have another random
variable which is the test data
so that's why
the loss
of the function was defined in the society setting as the expected value of the
the expectation of
the residual given the price and income is equal to zero so that means you
are in the case of the unity of the prices of course
so you have to to introduce some instrumental variables to solve and that leads to
the second case what happens when you the initial estimate of ten is no longer
estimation of the the conditional expectation the destination of instrument that regulation
and what happens then to the solution of the differential equation depending on the form
of the first estimate of
as the conditional expectation of something more complicated
what i'm going to do do this us focus on
this is more than where n is the conditional expectation derive some results for the
solution of the differential equation and using the same kind of methodology the same framework
we place the show
the conditional expectation by something complicated and see what happens
the solution
so in this
in this setting
i consider that this random vector x y z and they assume that my function
in which appears to be a functional equations
is exactly the conditional expectation is easy
even it's in
and i consider
both systems
lambda prime equal to m of explained
and london prime equal to an active pixel lambda and in or what follows i
will use some nonparametric can estimation to estimate the conditional expectation
and at so i will introduce some
cannot function capital gay and someone responded to each
two billion is basically
in the presentation
so the first step of
the methodology is to study the existence and uniqueness of both systems are true and
estimated one so the question the issues of identification of identification
and to study the issues i will i will i very well know
mathematical CERN about existence and uniqueness of solutions of ordinary differential equations it is the
because she she
and this year and there that you know
the neighborhood of the initial conditions so in the neighborhood of
nine point he was you will under some regularity property
on the functions
and in and
and if they satisfy in particular the kids conditions then i can define a unique
lambda and some associated based in london that
so if i assume
and satisfy
she condition that and then it also satisfies the conditions inside and able deal what
i can find
unique solutions formal systems
and then the second step to check
in this inverse problems mister the you are the solutions stable
that means if when i will replace a by and then we have the perturbation
involving is the solution to be confirmed as initial perturbations
and under
some regularity properties on the conventions of an actor and we have the stability of
the problem since the distance between london at
and then there is controlled
by distance between them and i
so i'm facing
well posed inverse problems there exists a unique solution to both systems
and the next step will be what kind of property can i prove ninety right
for the convergence of land at lambda i only have
you know with the consistency
what can i do what i can tell about the rate of convergence
so apt
what has been proved that the estimator
i consider
that means that i can in particular
right lambda as a function
he of n
and london at the function field an act
and the kind of assumptions
very roughly i will assume in the next
and what we what follows that
and will be more than it should satisfy the condition because since i will assume
that any continuous function of all the two
but to be effective helpful to derive some data expansions for the
i mean squared error
in this come in the neighborhood of he was you're going to combine neighborhood
i denoted by d is compact as was
i we assume that m and it is also continuously differentiable of all the two
in the same neighborhood and to have the ability of the solution i need to
assume that the derivative of
and then
the estimation of
the conditional expectation is that he respect the second arguement
converge uniformly to civility respect the content and
so that's the main the main assumption i need both on both function and that
now i know
i can write exactly lambda and london and at using this function and the next
step is
to study
rates of convergence of this function
lambda n two lambda and that leads to the following question
we know
one the weight of convergence of the estimation of the conditional expectation to the true
conditional expectation what happens when we apply some transformation he physicists nations and what kind
of information that we apply we have we can already have some intrusions of the
results we have defined lambda as the solution of differential equations that means you know
way that
what we have done is invest invest in with
differential operator so apply
very roughly some kind of internal world
later on the function and then at so we expect to prove that the convergence
of land and two lambda
is improved compared to the convergence and
that's the idea of what we
what to expect things
so now
study these conventions since we have a non linear
problems prevents we on the phone
of these the great he so
we have to realize
this system
to study the convention of london at london
so this is an intermediate
a very small step of the methodology
i think a you
any any prediction i make is likely to be wrong so it's better not to
predict but in terms of vision
i think it's useful to have a few guiding principles
four main areas of research
those include
prime guiding principles would be
number one
is understanding relevant so
for a company like you yahoo know how can we make it
so that are advertising
which is the product of actually drives money to the company
is as relevant to the user and the content they are consuming on the whole
another important principle is actually understanding a lot of these new phenomena that are emerging
on the web things that are enabled by web two point o like social media
sharing sites like you know photos on flickr and so forth all of these because
social media is understanding what the the appropriate dynamics appropriate incentives what makes these communities
grow and what sustains them
what is the equivalent of reputation online a lot of i would say
mapping a lot of the familiar online content offline concepts that we have evolved over
the last few thousand years
to have the equivalent online network
and make it into more secure and more reliable
safer for people
those are important guiding principles within them are
very deep open scientific problem i think is a lot of attention a in lot
of understanding
OK and first
so why research what what made me
one of the social when i was younger
on the personal side
probably two things i always wanted to be an engineer i think i was born
that way
my father happen to have a phd in engineering so there was a lot of
family pressure that you know one way or another graduate school is definitely something you
want to do
along the way
i discovered
passion for
four mathematics and more
modeling the world in an abstract language of mathematics
so realizing that you can actually theoretically model something
derive consequences of your model
and then actually see them
i realized when you make predictions about the real world
was a huge factor in turning me on to the whole world of research and
digging deeper beyond that i also had the good fortune of getting a couple of
summer internships during my
graduate career which really opened up my eyes one was with general motors research labs
where we worked on database of car repairs
millions of court cases that are difficult to solve and the idea was to mine
all this data and figure out the rules for
you know what causes some of these problems
that actually allowed me to discover that a lot of these things we do in
machine learning and induction in data mining actually have very practical
the other was GPL
we're realizing that these
machine learning and data mining techniques and actually solve problems that are very
very difficult to solve for
highly specialized groups of people like astronomers in very specialized scientists that was a big
eye-opening finding this is an area it's almost like
you know the analogy would be an car engine you know makes the cargo much
faster than any human can possibly run
with these algorithms you can actually extend intellect and inference capability over datasets that the
mind cannot fathom
so those those other things that sort of really influenced me in a big way
and after that you
you get you get addicted to learning in
figuring out things in
the joy of discovery in
good stuff
we do this
intuitively and very quickly and call it almost becomes second nature to make good moves
it seems to be intimately tied to the human visual system you when your experience
and you look at the borders immediately kind of points coming up to one to
be played they look like very natural moves now
the question is how how could the computer learned about this in one idea is
there exists a large databases of i guess today even millions of records of games
one idea is could we use these data
because it constitutes a very competent play
and could be somehow use this data to make the computer understand
so if you like to learn how to play go well
and that's the idea basically of applying machine learning
to go
in two tasks may come to mind in this context
one idea is
why don't we learn an evaluation function
so could be somehow learn
a mapping from a given position
two in number and the numbers somewhat indicates how good that position is for us
there would be a very natural units for that right this unit of one point
of territory and in those terms we would like to know how good position is
for example what's might expect that
winning score for example
and the interesting thing is that at the end of the game in fact we
know for every point on the board if it is black or if it is
why so we have a very detailed information at the end of the game that's
different from backgammon
wherever we only know that in the end we win or lose or points different
from chess where we only get this one bit of information here in goal we
have essentially three hundred sixty one bits of information that's something i learned from a
paper by nic schraudolph
the guy with the computer there
because he had realized that in the early nineties and i think that's a very
key thing for computer go i think
so another thing you might want to learn is how to select moves so evaluation
function learning was learn function that takes the position and see number that indicates the
position is now this would be for a given position
and all the possible moves to me how good each move is
and that's a different problem and of course here it might be more appropriate not
to look at the and positions but rather to look at the move actually made
by people and those we can get from the database and that's very interesting directions
forward i think
so the classical problem when approaching any learning problem is that of representation
and what we essentially requires that we have a certain degree of the and generality
in the representation because only then we can hope to generalize to larger
learn something more than just learning by heart the positions that we observe
yet we need sufficient information to actually draw the right conclusions
and of course we need learning algorithms that are able to
work on those representations
here's an example of a very recent work
by frank to grow out and this is actually a product that he's going to
commercialize and something i think would be a very good product it's called OIL and
frank's idea is
yes this huge
database of games half a million games i think he's working with a very strong
players and his idea is
to look at every single move made in within these games you can imagine this
kind of two hundred games
two and move per game and a half million games it's quite a few
quite a few moves and he looks at the surrounding patron of each of these
a bit like this in this diamond shape so to speak for this particular move
india's diamond shapes of different sizes of eight different sizes
so a small diamond shapes for
and those patterns that he would probably observe rather frequently
and he big diamond shapes that almost spend the entire board
and those would not be not be observed as frequently but if you observe them
then you have a very good idea that you may want to play there are
to play there and he's in this way he learning the value of different moves
and the amazing thing is this is not
really published the scientific results but he illustrate this on the game
he tried the system on the game that he wasn't in the database or that
he had used for training and he was able to achieve prediction of professional moves
of about forty five percent
shannon is is absolutely correct in i want to digitize everything to two he bandwidth
need for b and samples per second but that's assuming that i'm about to see
benjamin white noise
but in practice that's not what we see
in practice if you go into five to seven gigahertz band you can see little
pulses and things like this is not know is that all
so this seems to be about two requires actually extremely structure and extremely compressible and
that's where compressed sensing comes in and says if you're about to digitize things have
depend on the number of degrees of freedom which is much smaller
and what the shannon rate implies then you should be able in principle to sample
of a much reduced
without information loss
that's exactly what compressed sensing says and so we've seen an example of this would
say that the signal
has a sparse frequency spectrum
for example the GSM signaling if you know GSM protocols but GSM is allocating certain
bands for communications but what he does also that if you looking abandon next to
bands must be free
there must be emptied to avoid interferences and things like this and so when you
see GSM signal at any given time pretty sparse in the frequency domain lots of
signals are sparse in the frequency domain and just as an example of the toy
suppose we have a signal that has the spatial frequency spectrum well compressed sensing sense
the following it says if it has its consequences spectrum sample in a nonuniform locations
in time
we construct using
and linear programming
and what is guaranteed is that if the number of samples is above
the spectral occupancy times love factor then this reconstruction is
probably exact and so what you have by compressed sensing is that the shannon weight
is irrelevant what matters is information rate the amount of information contained per unit involved
and not the total bandwidth
OK so now
the US government agency has actually
created many
the US government has created many programs to actually leverage
compressed sensing in real hardware there's one associated with which is and that up two
and so is a circuit designers as the time me and others JPL we actually
new ABC's that will actually is sampled way below the shannon raids with hopefully without
much information loss
and so we are proposing to architecture going to propose show you most ambitious one
that does something like this so the incoming wave is coming i cannot sample it
that the shannon right it's just too high
it's three gigahertz there's no circuits that will let me sample signal six billion tons
per second what's interesting though is that i can change the polarity of the six
wave additional rate second multiplies single by plus or minus one additionally this i can
do because it has to do is changing the polarisation of the way so the
wave comes into its
it's the way as a function of time comes in
and enters a bank of channels
and each channel is actually essentially multiplying
incoming freak wave by random sequences of plus and minus once they're all difference
and of course i can digitize is the shannon way so what i'm doing is
integrating and i'm digitizing at a very slow rate
right so this is gets multiply the shannon rate then it gets integrated and then
we digitize the output at the shannon right
i do have a very slow rate is mathematically what one of these channels is
is essentially
taking an inner product between the incoming frequency with radio frequency wave and a random
sequence of plus and minus one
OK we actually spend an enormous amount of time designing this chip
and finally we have manufactured so now we're testing it
and so we have to build the ship was as time out be bright students
u two and u i must say that most of this work is by as
it and one and migrants steven bakker well we have actually put everything on the
chip it's very complex chip that has is a channel that you can see
one two three four five six seven eight
the uses little power at the moment six hundred twenty million watts
that is we believe can have an operation range of digitizing signal
in three gigahertz band it's a tiny chip to be made about to the minimum
and the dynamic range we hope to get about signals is about fifty db
OK so
problem actually going to think about now pretty much most of the time for the
rest of you know today and tomorrow is the problem of segmentation
some people believe that
a necessary precursor to making progress with
analyzing images you know try to build a general image processing system that could identify
components of images and was john winn would say explain every part of the everybody
in fact he takes it to an extreme and would say that the problem of
understanding images to explain the role of every pixel in an image of all humans
can do it by point topic so you know i choose one random you can
tell me what that pixel is doing you know it's part of the sky is
part of such so you know that i rather like that way of thinking about
the image understanding task explain every pixel and so as i say some people believe
the necessary precursor for that is to do some kind of segmentation
of the image into chunks that break the problem down without too much loss of
so there's been a program for some r one release ten years in berkeley two
both make this business of segmentation
but i have to say i'm skeptical because
what they do
to make progress on this problem is they get bank panel of humans to do
segmentations of images and and kind to use those as ground truth for evaluating the
the performance than of machine machine inference programs going to segmentation and
this annotated image is a map of all
what some some body of users said so bright line is the line that many
users selected the demo line is aligned only if you use the same brightness is
proportional to the number of years and what you see the as anything to me
anyway is the degree of disagreement amongst users and actually it may be an illusion
that you can come up to an image treated as a signal and say what
are the important politicians in the in the image to me this is going back
to that example i shown the beginning of the hand you know i said what
you would ideally like if you're naive easy is for the outline of the hand
just to come out but what you get with a good signal processing is something
much more arguable and ambiguous where actually a whole family of lines we you could
actually say that the lines in that in that piece signal processing are wrong it's
not the wrong is that there in some sense not fit for purpose and the
purpose is something that you have in your head it's not really something that you
can design define having been you know as as part of the problem spec
and here's another one in doing the same thing i suppose if you if you
came in with a very specific problem it may be you could do better and
define a low-level process that would pull out controls which were put into that process
and people are trying to do that kind of thing and definitely works but so
i i just want to say
i'm skeptical about segmentation the value of segmentation as a kind of module that you
can design build and test and then you forget about the the image after that
because you've you've simplify
on the other hand there are some
some less ambitious versions of the segmentation problem like the one that i mentioned before
which i think makes sense and you know they may not be the precursor for
vision vision systems that perform the level of animal vision
you can sell them
i'm gonna show
so here's the problem i'd like to be able to take this this foreground objects
and segmented here's the ground truth that segmentation and you know he is the kind
of evidence that i'm going to use all of a lot of foreground color and
background colour and it's well distinguished in this particular image so you can imagine that
in this particular case the job might not be that difficult although you know it's
not trivial because this is not this is not the kind of poster paint image
i mean if this was the blue star on a red background then we would
agree with trivial and you can all imagine the trivial matlab program that would do
the separation but here you know there's more interesting
the population of colours in the foreground and open the population in the background there
might be some overlap but i don't know what would you do you know what
you people are highly highly trained fighting unit now for a whole week plus the
additional years that you already spending a phd something i'd be interested in what people
you know your first reaction be if you want to make a separation program that
you know we use the colours to separate foreground from the background
in this image any
begun by gradient streams so then what property gradients would help people
and of course
o screen
do you think a straighter in the foreground and background by separation or background because
you mean that the gradients around there on the boundary yesterday i was not about
idea at all i think that would pull out the boundary of the star
i mean in the nature of things you know there are a few bumps here
so you know i worry that you might get a few leaks and that would
make it difficult for you i you're remember we're going to try and explain every
pixel all foreground pixels or the background is again a few leaks and then you
do flood filling or something to define the interior you're going to be in trouble
so i don't know if you have a good suggestion but i anybody got any
other any other ideas that would help characterize the interior
you know maybe just point to an interior pixel maybe the little clump of interior
to be used at all
so in
what we need to
that's a great answer that basically the rest of my lecture and tomorrow
this result take take
examples that require high things like the use of the link
two major
good idea so you know somehow biased towards the
colours are predominant in the foreground and away from the colours that from the background
i might get a bit of overlap between the colour palettes with your
your methods still be working
you know the purples i think is it's violence seem to be the foreground background
is going to cause trouble you think
cause the trouble
more speculation
so these are
i think it's a great suggestion when you take a photograph certain if it's sort
of you know deliberate photograph foreground object you try and get them focused on you
in the background is likely to be less focus so if you could somehow distinguish
you know the smoothness or lack of smoothness
the of you get all those on the test plus a couple more than what
do you want to those of basic formulas will plus transform it but if you
need anything else on
so I'm building those on board the basic task today is to see how will
plus transform so used to solve linear differential equation with constant coefficients
had to do
we're going to take the will plus transform of the derivative
In order to make sense of that procedure
will go laughter and I apologize if that's what it's slightly theoretical question namely we
have to have some guarantee in advance that the will plus transform is going to
exist now how people plus transform failed exist
can always calculate this and the answer is no you can't always calculate because it's
an improper integral
I'm integrating all the way up to infinity
and you know that improper integrals don't always converge
you know with the underground for example were just didn't have the exponential factor there
was we tdt that
it might look like it made sense but the integral of convergence infinity anyway there's
no value
so I mean conditions in advance which guarantees that people plus transforms will exist
only under those circumstances will formulas make any sense
there is a standard conditions in your book of a chance to talk about last
time so I thought I'd better than the 1st few minutes to talking about that
condition because that's what we're going to need in order to be able to solve
differential equations
the condition that makes plus transform
definitely exist for a function is that activity should grow to rapidly it can grow
rapidly on
because they can grow world because the minus st is pulling it down trying hard
to go down to 0 and the integral converges all we have to do is
to guarantee that it doesn't grow so rapidly that e the minus st is powerless
to pull it down
now the conditioned its growth what's called the growth conditions
this is a very important applications and this is the most important it's not always
it's always on 1801 but it's not always taught in high school calculus and
it's a question of how fast the function is allowed to grow and that the
condition is universally said this way should be of exponential types
so what I'm defining is the phrase all put quotation marks for that reason what
does this mean
it's a condition of growth condition on functions how fast the candidate of it said
activity inside synset team I get negatively very large that would hurt to make the
integral part to converge but not like the convergence of use the absolute value of
I'm getting is going up or going down very well
whichever way it goes it's you should not be bigger than
all rapidly growing exponentially and here a rapidly growing exponentially
of the
is some positive constants
for some positive constants and so
positive constant
and should be true for all values of the
greater equal to 0 I don't have to worry about negative values of because the
integral doesn't contain doesn't care about them into I'm only the integration as the runs
from 0 to infinity in other words activity could have been extremely while function of
the of levels so whatever functions of the negative values of T and we don't
it's only what's happening from now from time 0 onto effect of you know it
as long as it is now from now on it's OK alright so the way
to behave as by being an exponential
the charges some feeling for what this means these functions for example if K is
a hundred years and you with plot of the 100 looks like those straight of
on every computer plot on 180 go like that
unless of course you make the scale t equals 0 2 over here is 1
well you not to OK
so these functions really can go quite rapidly
but let's take an example and see what's of exponential type and then perhaps even
more interestingly what is it
so for instance the function of society is that of exponential time will
it's absolute value is always less than or equal to
so all right falls in this paradigm if takes equal to 1 of which I
think be
they can be 0 C equals 1 fact signed the basic conditions is 1 is
more interesting team
they get to power
is smaller than some exponential with maybe a constant out
well to 100 power go straight up also
well we feel that if we make the exponential big enough maybe you went out
in fact
you have to make the exponential big k equals 1 is good
in other words I say I don't have to put absolute value signs around the
deviance because I'm only thinking about the being a positive number anyway
I say that that's less than or equal to some constant and positive constant times
E to the T will be
for something
and 2 and that
the way you think of them so what this proves is that there for 2
years of exponential type which we could get because after all we were able to
calculate will plus transform
is no longer clear which haven't put down to be promised corner yet put down
a beeper
right and if we say that puppy often we close this often does so we
know that it's in fact running
to do we run our little program
and rock on
all right
no more of by one by life is good so any questions about the whole
of by one by
that's another common thing that the common couple common things i want to show you
so you know and if they come up in your program you don't feel like
all you're out there drift all along like these have been done millions of times
by other very qualified programmers don't worry it happens to every are some one of
things i just mentioned is this thing called the comments this thing up here in
green what's that all about
so as i mentioned last time one of the key software engineering principles is to
write programs that are understandable by people not just by machines and so what comment
is is always being able to put something in the program that another human being
reading your program can actually read and understand that actually has no impact on the
execution of the program at all
so the way the common works is it starts off with the splash star and
now everything you put
the main span multiple lines until you pointed star and slash is the commons it's
there just for the person to read it doesn't affect the program at all
and so what i would encourage you to do is part of good programming styles
all your programs up at the top should have a comment that says what the
name of the file is and has a little bit of an explanation about what
your program actually does and if you wonder how much of an explanation around at
the beginning be the end up as you want but in the hand that you've
got you see examples of major programs and they're all commented so you can see
examples of comments and that there's also short and you can do there's a comment
that's just
slash slash that means everything on the remainder of this line is the comment so
it actually has no close in some sense for the comment like this does explicitly
everything else the rest the line when you hit return that's how it was done
for comments sometimes if you want to have a one line comment somewhere you can
just put a slash slash question
yeah when you get assigned to a different section leader you'll actually put your assignments
in with your name and your section leader and that's how we get differentiated so
wait until you get your first action and you'll see how
all the submissions that works
well you when you write like other methods
yeah you should comment those as well so methods should also be commented on show
an example of that they actually so you can see an example of how we
do that so that's actually and i love what everyone just you know i like
it like you in the audience leading into the next topic and that's a perfect
example the say hey let's actually looking looking to program that we did last time
which was the steeplechase program now with comments OK so up at the top sometimes
you need to click this little plus sign to expand the common because the eclipse
has the tendency to try to minimize the comments automatically so just click the plus
sign will spend about steeplechaser we have and i still comment here at the top
of our programmes notice this is a job files i mentioned before and with job
because carols actually implemented in java but you shouldn't use no features of java other
than what is it in the carol book and if you like a and i
don't know job enough for you to unlearn you're good to go because you just
know carol right
the other thing that's going on here is you'll notice that inside the program we
have comments as well so this method to run method it has to run the
race that's nine avenues long we need to move forward john e
articles eight times and that makes it explicit that person right if we didn't have
a common someone come along and say hey the rate nine avenues wiry you only
iterating this eight times right that's a natural question to ask and they put in
comments to clarify things in the programme which are not obvious to a another thing
related to that is which refer to as preconditions and postconditions what did you expect
to be true before you call the particular method or before particular method is invoked
and what's going to be true afterwards storefront jump here remember jumper from last time
we ascend portal which means we go up we moved cross over the top of
the island we decentralised come back down the other side well what we needed for
that to be true
for this to actually work right is the precondition is you're facing east at the
bottom of the herd which means the was right in front of you and you're
facing east in front of it that way we know which way to turn on
how to ascend the model and how to get over it and when you're done
you're going to be facing east again so you can assume after this method is
done that you're facing east again and you're at the bottom of the world in
the next avenue after the so makes clear right because we don't know what all
stuff is going on inside on inside central in the central but programmer now designated
trace through the execution of your program to figure out what's going on this tells
them what needs to be true before and what needs to be trapped it helps
need for my specific applications and here is the clustering that will have those properties
the thing that we know from kleinberg is that you want to have the clustering
that satisfies all the possible properties
you know the same for many things in life
you can get the car which is beautiful and fast and convenient and cheap or
this is the ideal period i would like to say so here i have
lists of
things that are called axioms
and here we have a list of possible clustering paradigms and then can ask which
clustering power and satisfies which requirement now
the axioms should be satisfied by all clustering paradigms
the things which are properties like kind consistency clambers richness
satisfied by some paradigms but not by others and that should have been somehow
taxonomies the class different clustering methods by which properties are satisfied
two each clustering method will have a profile of which properties it's fine we should
the axioms should be satisfied all of them and if i have a function which
is not a clustering function it should at least fail one of those
the all clustering functions to satisfy all the the properties they call axioms
other properties distinguish between different clustering methods and
functions which are not clustering to each police force if i one of those
accept that
the idea deity only the and now i'm not going to give you such a
theory because
the they had difficulty here is that we don't have a clear definition of what
is not clustering i mean
i have this requirement every function which is not the clustering should forty five one
of the axioms but it's clear how should i defined it is not the clustering
by showing that it doesn't satisfy one of the properties that they want to do
so i i get into a side here but i can still come up with
some properties which are more natural to be axioms than others and is satisfied by
all the reasonable common clustering
i want to give you some example of such properties so it in general we
can say that
at that some of the requirements of the really partition into two types of
properties region it's properties
so one of the most the kind which is another one who became richness the
range of your partitioning is all possible partitioning into k that so
so we need some which is requirement and we need that answering back this
like saying scale invariance if you change the scale
the clustering were not change so these are two different
types of properties and for each of them we can come up with relaxations that
i really meant by all really common popular clustering paradigms
and so i'll just give you one example of
the relaxation of the property of clans that what you do this relaxation
you really
and i have it in all reasonable clustering functions so
the problem with the clan because it's so let me remind you what causes the
was because it was the requirements that if i pull together points in the same
cluster important class different clusters apart then
apply my
clustering function again and get the same partition
but the problem is this it could be that may be drawn picture here the
problem is this could be that assumed they have
this might
initially looks like this
so my clustering function would say
well here is my clustering
and now
i'm pulling together points in the same cluster and i get something like
so i just took some of the point in this class and put them together
and i don't touch the other or pull away
the other class
so i screamed this cluster
a little bit away half of those points will shrink to here and the other
half here so this is consistent change inside this class only
reduce the distances between the clusters i only increased distances but if i give you
this clustering you're probably give me not this clustering but something like this
you know you your wallet about the fact that i didn't fix scale again i'm
talking about and i would to find the correct number of clusters and then class
so i'm saying is that consistency requirements although it
on the first glance it looks much it has problems because the natural examples where
you want to refute it
because i don't know how to draw but i i could do it without increasing
any internal distances i could do it can i mean it doesn't even have to
be embedded in in say that all the distances here in the x y
equals one for every x and y
and between those two two
the x y
it was then if we pick point from here point from here
and now i make all the difference here
the x y here it was pointwise
and here the x y
it was point one
and between those two
i still have distance two
so i didn't extend any inside
i can it one
good to know the people of poland
so i still have distance one between these two groups but inside the group restricted
this is the point
and i'll get to stimuli and when i try to draw it of course i
i don't do precisely but you can easily
formalise such a situation
suggested remedy for this problem is to say that the consistency
should be not allow you to change the proportions which i within each class so
you have
a list of constant
a lambda i for every cluster
and the new
distance function should be
if a and b are in the same cluster is the oldest distance times the
constant lambda
and if they are in different clusters if the old distance times some london you
so i p
constants for every cluster have a shrinking constant
and for all the between distances i have some expansion constant
and if i now
do my shrinking and expansion
i'm running out of kind of counter examples and i can show