OK so
but let's use the chain rule to understand how
F depends on the C 1 y is held constant
so that 1st Fibre Chernobyl locally and then when I corners what's going on so
you can just use the version that they have a fair as a template to
see what's going on with the job that I'm going to explain it
not just for
but but but but but but but but but but but but but but but
but but but but but but but but that's OK so that's the most
mechanical and
mindless way of life and number and the same here let's say that conveying z
keeping why constant may want to know how I've changes as well as might change
because x might change what might why might change and z might know how quickly
does exchange and well the rate of change of X in this situation is partial
expert z with white constant
so if I change x at this rate than if will change at that time
now otherwise might change
so the rate of change of why would be like the change of life perspective
z according white constant that wait a 2nd if y is held constant then why
doesn't change so it going is evil and the didn't really have to write that
but I voted just to be systematic OK if wife had been somehow able to
change something like that but we have closed after to change at it because it
is held constant so if y is held constant then nothing happens here
and finally where z is changing something of a perspective this 1
and that causes after change at that time and then we add the effects to
this seeds nothing but we would all channel just put these extra substrates to tell
us what is held constant and what is
OK now of course we can simplify to the small because here how quickly does
change differentiating this is where the weight of tendency with respect to itself is just
1 OK
so in fact that really
mysterious part of this is the 1 here which is the rate of change of
x with respect to and to find that we have to understand the constant
so how can we find the rate of change of expert perspectives z where we
could use different forms liquid in here but we can also keep using the change
it but it it it thank you
going do that when I can just look at how gene would change with respect
to the delays has so I just do the same thing relations between genes that
but before I do it so let's ask ourselves 1st what this report well if
G is held constant then when we very easy keeping why constant unchanging xxx well
just the doesn't change its held constant but but but also in the fact that
it doesn't give it if we just say that when again when and where to
get vector so let's see how we can compute factors interchangeable where the Chernobyl tells
us in g changes because x y and z change
OK how does it change because of x y and the possibility of X times
the rate of change of expression that how does it change because of the wide
where the authority for wife but thanks to the rate of change of wine but
of course it just not then you don't need to actually find this 1 because
ways has constant
the convention because the rate of change because the changes and how quickly z changes
here of course is what you get
so out of this you get that when entail of I think pathology dutiful experimenters
white a piece of text and partial expert so this is a white constant press
genes and and this and now we found however dependency in the case of lexical
from the with white has constant is negative the gist of the scene of the
adjacent access
no we plug this into that and we get
this goes on the way here
OK and then we get the answer but I'm not going to work in a
2nd but
so there will support X times this value in the case of the probabilities of
X plus a cover letter from and you can observe that this is exactly the
same formula that we had over in fact let's compare this to statements
I claim with exactly the same thing just with different notation
amazing customer service thank you
OK OK big screen isn't working today there can be things smaller species there actually
because i i think in this room just got a new project that
someone sent an exciting email
was it just on friday saying which is a new project in this the set
of four thousand to one something rather brightness ratio and some some was very excited
about the new project in this room you will see that we see that in
operation on wednesday
stop it or what machine learning is on one this one this machine learning
she has a
she can we can we detect up raise your hand if if the text on
the small spines is legible
OK call mostly there so just read out on so
what is machine learning
way back in about nineteen fifty nine after samuel
this is a defined machine learning informally as the the study that gives computers to
learn on the this study tickets computers the ability to learn without being explicitly programmed
so obvious tamil
so we that history machine learning actually
this is something
very cool which was on
he really checkers program
which would take into checkers against itself
and so because
computer can play thousands of games since his itself rather quickly on office and has
program thousands of games against itself and over time we start to learn to recognise
patterns which led to wins and patterns which led to losses over time and things
like that you know g if i get a lot of my pieces taken by
the opponent then are more likely to use and when you a my piece instances
the position the especially likely to win rather
so over time the sanyo
the checkers for and they will actually learn
to play checkers by learning whether the support positions that tend to be associated with
what the board positions tend to be associated losses on
and way back in nineteen around nineteen fifty nine the amazing thing about this was
that on his program actually learned to play checkers much better than arthur samuel himself
even today there are some people that say you know what computers can't do anything
that are not explicitly programmed two and after samuel's checkers program was on may be
the first
i think really convincing refutation direct refutation of this claim are mainly on other sami
manager at checkers program they could play checkers much better than he personally and as
an instance of the computers learning to do things that they really were not problem
here the more
the reason the more modern more formal definition of machine learning due to tom mitchell
who says that will pose learning problems on this is defined as follows she says
a computer programme is said to learn from experience e with respect to some tossed
and some performance measure p
if this performance on t as measured by p improves with experience e so not
only is the definition of rhymes on
so for example in the case of chequers on the experience he e that the
program has would be on the experience of playing once against attackers against itself say
the toasty were is is the task of playing checkers and performance measure p will
be something like you know the fraction games wins against certain set of human opponents
and by this definition will say that after samuels on
check this program has learned to play checkers
as an overview of what we're going to
doing discourse on this process of organised into four major sections on one
o point four major topics and this class the first of which is
on supervisor
we give an example of that
suppose you collect a dataset holding prices and quality is that ramesh actually collected the
data set last week to to use an example later on this suppose that are
good to go to collected collect
of statistics about how much houses cost is a certain geographic area and that the
t collected data from housing prices in portland oregon
so what you can do is that's a part
you know the square footage of the holes
against the
this price the whole space
so you get the bit data back to this
the second dataset like this poses different sizes that you know this different amounts of
now let's say that i'm trying to sell holes in
the same areas portland organism with the data comes from the on this i have
the whole you know the size in square footage
and i want an album to tell me about how much should i expect my
whole the cell for
so the loss away to do this
so in summary you may have seen elements of what i'm about to say before
so what you can do is look at the data and the history ninety eight
and then you know this is my whole
made an industry i think
my house is going to go for damage
and other decisions committee which which we'll talk about later which is
well whether i don't want to straight line maybe actually shoot the quadratic function to
be that data little bit better
you notice if you do that depends school so that is
and this sort the learning problem of learning to predict housing prices is an example
of what's called the supervised learning problem
on and the reason is called supervised learning is because we're providing the algorithm a
data set
a bunch of square footage in the budget housing sizes and as well as the
right answer what the actual prizes
of the number of houses were
it is called the supervised learning because was supervising the album when the words were
giving the album on the quote right answer
well i think it's very different
from things like web two point o websites which can be built in six months
and can achieve notoriety
o fame notoriety or whatever and in eighteen months there in bringing lots of money
and be sold to somebody so that's the sort of the venture capitalist dream who
looking for a short return on investment i think that in fact they're not used
so certainly off the dotcom bust when it became very because very reasonably very careful
not used to look at something where we're putting down every two years we make
a new building block now i think what we've got the building blocks and i
think sparql actually which is now coming to fruition i think sparql is really important
building blocks of this query language suddenly you know now we have systematically recruited language
using databases without without sequel
so it's really is almost unthinkable so now we move to a situation where whoever
has a large amount of data computer sparql endpoint on it and they can be
queried with with this new sparql language
that makes a huge step so that the semantic web really is not something that
the venture capitalist investor themselves they'll investing in people who use it and more and
more i think we'll see semantic web technology creep into web two point their applications
creep into desktop applications creep into
enterprise and applications particularly
this would be kind of one side but later dataset would be the big companies
like google microsoft yahoo
maybe some other like documents
my impression is but let's say this is still a question my impression is that
it's a cool what's change landscape of semantic web for the semantic technologies a couple
of relatively simple decisions a lot but still some
they're not to act like
microsoft the other so cannot comment on this
of course the triple-a i conference to peter norvig was actively questioning the semantic web
suggesting that people
wouldn't have time for it various arguments against it so we cannot ask even though
there are people with google people what google interest in the semantic web we can
ask what the attitude so why what is it that is this possible that peter
in a i person really
it's still thinks of ontologies as being like cyclic huge monolithic things doesn't and he
doesn't understand the fractal nature of the semantic web and how many interconnected many on
ontologies indicated the edges or or maybe working can only i didn't get a lot
of time to talk to about wales questions so we can only wonder perhaps is
that google really makes that what they do well is they make
by making order out of chaos
they've got this algorithm which looks at the castle links on the web and to
produces sort finds young vectors and
while there is chaos out there then you have a business model
if if in fact the web there was a lot of data out there which
was reliable we're all from reliable sources and the assistance of finding for finding which
sources were reliable for difference of data with the provenance this stuff that we have
and then
and the systems that which across much more complicated queries and get a really sophisticated
answers which relevant queries which is is so the google engine just really will work
for toll which involves relationships between people and so on and maybe the this would
be a threat to current business model perhaps that's what company and like most accomplished
looking at alternative ways of looking at ways in which they can use the data
and i've got a and i think they make
they may find it very useful to have metadata about how different pages relate on
the web for example they may start with that and then moved to i think
what question just as he thought that he said well what is it is because
it's metadata metadata that can never be trusted but in fact the spider webs but
data and only some of the data and metadata the large amounts of data out
there maybe google want one detector while
and maybe so it will be weakness and maybe there will be other companies will
come in index the data and provide you and due to the semantic web but
google it to the web who knows who can say semantic web would be kind
of interplay between the state of the art technologies and so what i wanted to
be one step so but it's very much biased stopped so i remember two years
so tell me what you got was what's the matter with plans to talk to
because it's the e
logic so machine learning the mining technologies wouldn't have so much place it it should
have guess my make this thing by top-down and bottom-up so of would be letting
my my perspective logic based on our style ontologies
which are mainly manual called it one of the three would be this
emergent semantics one
semantics search would come out of the data and only one with
check the conference i well there's not much from this
although the whole of the talk in the corridors about mapping databases industry track about
how you
take a relational database and information and put it on the semantic web
so when you do that you end up with default ontology which is the first
which is what was in the database to mind when he decided that he or
she decided it was so you have to then
you can look at that and
take a look at random
programme over the design of schema that which will try and work out what the
database and was thinking of certain extent you can do quite a good job of
that and then you can elaborate that an end up building up what you call
bottom-up ontology there are so many databases out there with valuable information and the enterprise
is obviously lots of lots of data and with some so we've done this for
we know
we were
this site
he goes
or we can
very few people
you're in for her
all right
you can
we will be
you are
when we the
and the whole or
you all
because you
well you know
he call
it's not really
all right
no one
i mean there is a lot people
i mean
who is it
i i
i told you about one
for example
he is
in britain
he was
i care
i would also
estimates on
or whatever
what we call
you are
in the
one right one
he he
two destroying previously created en
to use MIT phrase the reversibility is intuitively obvious because if you are able to
i would still use that we use in the
well i don't know so
by contraction must be reversible because for example this polymerization were irreversible
and all the protein that was ever size of the surface of the planet over
the last three years would accumulate progressively and obviously that doesn't happen in there for
all macromolecular synthesis
proceed forward obviously must go in the other direction as well
and the resulting concentration of complete protein is known as for its steady state
so we might make the protein
one rate and break down at the same rate and its steady-state concentrations
represents a compromise between these two i knew the concentration of protein
so we might observe at any one point in time
indeed the term
could be expanded due to any process in which is in
so this is and is the breakdown of something
and the equilibrium concentration which results is once again called the steady state of that
now let's go down to the nitty gritty which is
something which we can avoid for very long which is to say they are i
side chains
once again here we see an arbitrary artifact of very early
evolution in the biosphere
because there are in fact twenty different side chains creating set twenty distinct amino acid
which are used to proteins by organisms on this planet
again there are rare exceptions
certain funky in certain bacteria are able to make unusual amino acid
these are the basic building blocks of virtually all life forms on the planet
ninety nine point nine nine percent of all the protein drug
he site for the liberalisation of these twenty amino acids
and by the way i wanted the amino acids lysine
over here you see right here
violates this rule of chirality
and in you recall before i said because there are four distinct amino acid
for sightings around the central carbon
sometimes called the alpha carbon you always have handedness of amino acids
but indicated this kind of this notion can not be respected in the things of
not here
simply because we don't have four distinct carbon run according with the red
and here these two hydrogens or
equivalent to one another not for distinct changes only three distinct surprising violates this rule
chirality of left and right
here by the way
side chain
which all of these cases is depicted as extending off to the right of each
amino acid
so i think we need proton hydrogen
in fact what we see about these
amino acid is is that the side chains have quite distinct biochemical properties
and that begins to impress us with the notion of proteins
and their biochemical attributes
can be extended
the identities of the amino acids are used to construct the
we can talk about the notion of non polar
versus polar amino acids i
i mean i which have four affinity for water
they don't have a separation plus and minus charges
and as a consequence
there are little bit or quite a bit hydrophobic
now you see how can they be hydrophobic because here they are this charge and
here this i mean this
i thought that would make it highly hydrophilic
keep in mind when talking about amino acid
i'm not talking about them when they in a single amino acid form i'm talking
about the properties once they have been polymerize interesting
and once their collaboration with things like this
the NH two and COOH charge
that is the charge here and the charge you become irrelevant
because this oxygen and this means movable type of covalent bonds
and the acquisition of the proton
in this setting of of proton over here
not occur because both of these o and and are involved in covalent bonds
so therefore we talk about
nine four and four minutes
keep in mind we're focusing on the biochemical properties of the side chains because the
central backbone of the of the polypeptide
and this article is defined quite clearly areas central backbone using
quite repeating structure
NCC NCC NCC this is invariant
what what changes what defines the biochemical
attributes of this all the time
or a polypeptide are the identities of the which again are are plotted on this
particular graph to have a different version in your book
to the right
you see we have the proton metal group vale
lucene and isoleucine
and the differences between this suggests these are all quite
quite similar to the propane and and the that we talked about last time relaxing
then say these are quite hydrophobic side
and as such
if were polypeptide
we can imagine
it's an adventure start let's hope the presentation will be smoother
i'd like to thank the organisers for inviting me like talk about the recent work
on polyhedral approximation is convex optimisation we're basically we have perhaps difficult optimisation problem and
we make polyhedral approximations piecewise linear approximations to solve the cost functions with some of
the constraints so as to get an easier problem and then have to get the
solution to these problems
we define the approximation and in the end we converge to the solution
so my
i'd like to talk about a flexible and unified framework for polyhedral approximation
which includes the classical methods that i'm sure you know the cutting plane method which
involves out linear decision from below and simplicity composition
which involves in real linear innovation from within
so these methods can classical methods are part of this framework
but there are new methods that included in new verges or extensions of the old
of the old methods
and the vehicle for this is duality
and conjugacy
it's well known that in the in other linear station are connected by conjugacy
if you cover function
convex and you consider an outer linear decision by subgradients
r and consider the conjugate function of this which i call h
conjugate of the outer linear decision is an intermediate station
for the break points correspond to the subgradients here
and anniversary from one innovation we obtain an outer linear position
where the
the the slopes here determine the points of of contact
so this is known but how exactly in and out of the notation is connected
not make clear i'm going to explain that in in my talk
the vehicle
is a form of
i a flexible and brought form of convex programming called extended one traffic programming
here the vector x of optimisation involves components x one x two x m
in the cost function is additive involves components and each component depends of f
depends on the corresponding component of x
in the f i here extended real valued convex functions
and s is the subspace
now this problem has
a dual that has the same form
because this form here
the valuable so why
otherwise leave in the orthogonal subspace to s
and the edges are
the conjugate functions of the full symmetry between the two dual problems
the primal and the dual
and the algorithmic idea which my framework is based
two in the linear i some of these functions that are linear in some of
these functions leave some other functions
some other terms
and then
so the corresponding
polyhedral approximated extended monodromy programming problem
and we find the linear decision by using duality and the interplay between these two
now the features of it out station in this framework is their first of combine
the same algorithm
these may involve some that in some of the other simultaneously
their roles are reversed in the dual problem because of the conjugacy involved here
i was thinking be apply to the prime or the book but
the two algorithms are mathematically equivalent and basically to do all faces of the same
i published a paper recently on the duality aspects of the EMP formulation
the material is going to be in the text because i'm very
in this work was motivated
by an application machine learning some colleagues at the university of helsinki
jane you and you will see
it's still in progress
in that application so that you can make the connection to machine learning
we have a cost function that's of this form
as of x x is the optimisation variables
are so that is the regularisation term
and here we have a set of functions
each one
depends on x
in corresponds to
a block of data about of data so we have lots and lots of data
this functions here not application of polyhedral but very complicated because they correspond to complicated
batches of data and they are very difficult to deal with
so there are amenable to simplification
by outer or inner approximation
so this components below the point where they some regularisation function which is not linear
ice or linear
and that's the problem that we had
and we look at the the
do all of this problem and apply
simplicial decomposition which is in early initiation do correspond to other linear decision of the
primal and the
it's a challenging problem in the results have been promising so far
i'll come back to this sum to this attitude cost functions a later
so here is the outline of my talk like to talk about what kind of
approximation in general give some terminology
review existing methodologies particularly in the area of cutting plane its implicit decomposition methods
then i'm going to introduce extended when proper programming
the duality theory in biology this is the central point of the story and then
we discuss special cases of the algorithm
how the classical methods are obtained from it and how you can also obtain new
methods in this way
OK let me remind you the definition of subgradient of an extended
real valued convex function is a vector y my subgradients are going to be wise
and my primal variables are going to be ex
so for a point x is a subgradient is one for which
this is a linear function of z lies below
f four rosie
and the set of all subgradients is called the subdifferential is denoted by the partial
f of x
in the graphic interpretation is that the subgradient can be identified with unknown vertical supporting
hyperplane to the epigraph
of this convex functions
so you have a slow why i call them slopes even though they are subgradients
and you fit a hyper plane that slope to the epigraph and
any slope like this the substrate of the corresponding point of contact
so the subgradient why the subgradient at the point x where the hyperplane that should
be happy
now the linear decision
corresponds to approximating the epigraph of functions
subgradients the maximum of linear
a function is defined by subgradients
so we have a number of points x zero
up to xk
and we have a subgradient at these points otherwise
in each one of those is the function like that
and we take the maximum of those in that defines
o point here that all that's the general idea of to linear section
and then you should corresponds to approximation by subgradient in a linear decision corresponds to
approximation by convex hulls
the convex hull
four points that in an approximate
is the sum of all that
we might
so after time capital city
this the wrong at the time
is a similar need
plus one
well minus one or it could be zero if we do reject any where we are
let's start with
in the middle and were not doing any
let's actually neglect wall made life
easy and the of
and then there are only the first one one variables
and we're interested in
the variance developed at
well there is
polytunnel are interested in
how wide
the region is look the very x
average about red
the fact that the sum of independent random variables and so at so
the bank at the sum of the variances
i that's
take a single step is performed by one that means the value
one when was all these things i want
also the variance
is he
if you want
the typical distance you've got
be elsewhere
then you need
to run the chain time
that's a long square root and i want show you how this scaling in general
in general
in that case one one
you get what i want know what the mean squared what he at once
the equal
the key element of
all right but not you scaling
it's getting quadratically with the ratio of five they live there
and so
it's not that this example
but think is a hundred or a hundred or something like that to be the answer question
the question right
and now the first one is maybe
one of those not quite clear
so let's be running things
so what iterations are the
six iterations
eighty iterations
after a hundred iterations
we have three wall so in that particular run hundred was very good yes
i keep on going
non-blocking again when everybody again was made in
o them
right we weren't allowed
if you going to the right
reported it directly back hitting the same ball
three hundred
four hundred
four hundred forty
and then we got a proposal
at the four hundred iterations
it unreasonably in agreement with what you said and the reason that one four hundred
three notable
that's rule from back-of-the-envelope methods as
what looks like that
we keep on running
come back again and again and again
and maybe
four hundred iterations later was still available and then we have a around
program the outside
nine hundred of the four hundred iterations
five hundred
well but the thing that this will
so that's what happens when you run the same
so it takes
thousands of iterations
you get good independent points
what other way visualizing this is to imagine that histogram where we have been during the simulation
so here's the histogram what iterations
eighty hundred and no
this is the simulation we just did
so at all hundred iterations by the man hit the wall still histogram where we being
it's quite
it will be it'll be and i'm even
so this is the point at which you might say i've actually got one independent samples from this
about five hundred iterations what
so that's the wrong i'm not saying
that when you run a metropolis like this you should throw away all the point
while one is the where we collect the points
effective number independent we've got running along with the operation is probably only one of
just one pass
what i found that
comparison in the degree distribution
so suppose we had a graph that then we know that the average degree is
around three point three and we want to be able to pick pick another random
and guess what this degree was well we might say that
we might assume that it follows some surplus on gaussians distribution and that the
at that the average degree is equivalent to the motor
the mode of the degree distribution but this is actually not the case in real
graphs the the motives one most
most nodes have very small small degree
and so the mean is meaningless and because we have a very skewed distribution
but what exact pattern degreed is the real graphs follow
we find that
most real graphs to display power law degree
the degree distribution and we can measure this with the rank exponent are if we
took the if we rank the degree of of all nodes in the network like
the top the one with
pies can activity is ranked
rank one and so on in the
then we would follow power law with
with in this case an exponent minus
o point eight two in this in internet domains they find the highest
the highest can connected one is eighty in teaneck is IBM and so on and
while most
most have very very low conductivity
this is this is all in log log scale of course
so does does have the power of hold over time and
do they hold on
the graphs and domains
the answer to both these questions is yes
for that siganos et all showed
showed that on the internet domain this rank exponent hold constant and
this is also o so also shown on other graphs in domains that they other
graphs also displayed power laws
so here's here's applauded the rank exponent are over time it remains confident about point
point eight two
this is over
over series of several months
this is somewhat surprising
because we might expect that
but the
hubs made has made change in
how they attract links but is actually pretty consistent power law
and this is also shown in the peer-to-peer topology topology joe jovanovic and all showed
the degree of the gnutella network also follow a power law
and richardson and domingos showed the epinions com also
also had the power law degree distribution and out degree
so next going to look at the
the patterns and connect components in real graphs
so the basic graph generator is an artist and graph which means that for and
we we pick n vertices and we just decided to draw to connect any two
nodes in the network with probability p this is some of the first study on
the probably be for a random graphs
and they had it
this editor new renyi random graph has many provable properties including including the emergence of
and that the giant connected component
the degree distribution does not
it does not reflect that of real graphs but this property of giant connected component
that is that we find that nearly all networks have a giant connected component emerge
and it was also shown in some recent work by
kumar et al
the social media graphs often have middle region they did some experiments with flickr and
with the other three sixty groups and they show that there is the middle region
not not giant but
it's component sizes larger than one
this the behaviour of this was that they rarely have really connected to each other
to form a larger components they would usually connect into the gigantic connected component or
take on singletons
so now now introduce some properties of static graphs and but in an active research
area is looking at the evolution of graphs over time and it's very useful for
some the applications that will talk talk about later
so how do graphs of graphs evolve and we know that the degree exponent seems
constant we show have constant rank exponent
for degree distribution
but are there any other consistent patterns so we can identify
so what about the evolution of diameter we have the
so some prior analysis some parallel like graphs hence the diameter slowly increases with time
that if you if they took random graphs that would generate power laws with the
diameter would also tend to tend to increase with log n log log n and
i'm using citations as an example but of course you could do this with with
anything else and then you have the infield predicates this is the predicate that does
the segmentation
it says this position in the citation is in this field
like so you know this piece here is arthur or or whatever
announcing field and some citation to the into resolution
these formulas of the HMM
what do they say
well if you have this talk and in this position this positions in this field
so this is the observation matrix word tokens are observations and fields
i states
now here's my transition matrix it says that if i'm in this field in this
position then i'm in this field in the next position
in fact in practice we actually don't need to build a complete matrix here we
just want to capture the regularity that usually stay in the same field as you
go along and that's what i'm actually doing it but because just as easily have
put on the full hmm
now notice
in most information extraction problems
most places in the source don't correspond to any field
and what people do for that is they create this artificial other state
that's not the field
but then you have to model the correlations between the various things and you know
this is very messy because is a pile of stuff
in alchemy you actually need to do that
only the only need to do is you actually allow
the notice i put no exclamation mark you
which means the position might not be in any field
position to not be in any field and what i'm doing here is just understanding
of a rule that says well you can be more than one field once
so if you are you not then you
and so forth
so this system does information extraction
no sorry these three forms of the HMM for information extraction and this one was
here i just the form that we saw before to the resolution except that they
now start from this predicates instead of the predicates that had before
so this the complete information extraction system in just you know seven short formulas that
fit on the slide
as i said the introduction part is actually fairly state-of-the-art
the information extraction part is actually not that great
and the reason why it's not that great is is that it's not very good
at detecting field boundaries
it's very propagating fields and identifying correlations between woods and fields but placing the boundaries
exactly is one of the challenge
and people know this information extraction what it is like to define rules explicitly to
predict field boundaries
but combining this with an HMM is not you know very straightforward
alchemy however you can do that very easily
for example in citations
there's a very good predictor of the field band which is the period
most few in citation separated by periods so i can just add this one precondition
to this rule
it says that nearby positions like to be in the same field as long as
one of the of money is not the case that one of them is the
so if i have appeared that stops the propagation of fields this one change very
easy to make it makes a big difference in the accuracy in fact with this
one change you actually get something that is a fairly state-of-the-art into resolution system sorry
citation matching system
like what's very
the good question so
what happens in your citations right is that
periods appears separators between fields but they also appear as abbreviations of
well this is why we need a weighted rule as opposed to the tremendous decline
because i'm going to learn the wait for the rule that a function of how
often you get each case
so what's going to happen is that it's going to
ten down propagation but not to zero because it could be and often
but what you what you really want to do is you want to put in
that knowledge right that this thing that appears in are you know letters within the
with full stops are probably initials you can model that says that
but in that case
it is actually an exception to this rule
in fact this is one of the things that we do in this paper that
just came out in tripoli two thousand seven you know we actually wrote a bunch
of stuff like this that we know about you know citations then again there's a
lot of the fun of working with something like companies that you can just right
the things you know about the domain and that you know sort of like of
which translates into better models
and this is the state-of-the-art a model
the full one that we have in this paper citation matching and like the standard
datasets and it's still pretty simple MLN we've only about you know a couple dozen
formulas for
so see how the information extraction
not really because you don't have to wait until the fields and so on and
in order to me
well right now but let me clarify
this because this is the complete information extraction system but like an information extraction system
it needs the data to learn the ways some sort
raise so we need for to to actually made that clearer right so
in order to train this right any the database
on the database
is going to be groundings of these predicates that this is basically going to be
like these datasets are
you have at the base of like you know citations and then you know this
was after this was you know then you these two authors with the same in
these to fields with the same from that you learn the weights for the samoan
and then this similarly come up with a new database and like the standard machine
learning so
so in love this information extraction
so you try to go the weights on these particular one right
there are some new
we entities that
the CIA
the biggest i'm doing it myself one of the biggest another because i've seen the
biggest as
so this is any that is that sort of a different schools here as well
as the learning machine learning now specifically the thing is that there is
good question and the answer is it's up to you what you wanted to go
on and not the way you make it go on is that you include your
original things like you know the thing this is not in your new inference
and that's a known fact and you can infer from that
for example certain records of the set
and you know in general you want to use them
there is also this tricky issues that when you have you know non IID data
your training in your tests may not be independent
so for england although actually have to be careful but i do that but for
practical purposes yes you one include information and you know you probably get a lot
of mileage out of it
OK so
let's get even more ambitious
you know why i just do segmentation right let's actually do passing of the input
because to really doing in real
two to quickly would find at least a fixed percentage of negative
throw them away
and then everything else is just passes on to the next next states to look
so all the time if you go down the change rejecting some things which are
initially relatively easy
things and and further down the classifiers tend to be more complex and you have
to do more things
the features here again is how wavelets in fact these ones are rectangular so there's
this fact many different rectangular
aspirations positions that can have so there's a very large set of features things trained
in each of those features is treated as an individual weak classifiers
for the for the think tank based weak classifier in each stage adaboost
so a
you can see the detections they can see the first two features the pulls this
is very characteristic faced section kind of dark region around the eyes
and the fact that the bright
but are in the middle you know this is
the most characteristic signal
the faces
and faces are actually relatively easy cluster take
because of that frontal faces
so all detectors whatever the features use basically have those could those two things the
but as said yes i did was that it was good here
well it's able to select the best of the large weekly which features
and basically
although the algorithm seems somewhat
ad hoc or
if you're not sure that the features are selected in the in the world to
the classifier
just select also features nevertheless does link to run small set of features which were
relatively well so you can think of it more as feature selection method
and is a classifier trained were equally is a feature selection method across the training
and then you can do the same thing for pedestrian detection
mister tate also involves no motion derivative
i wanted the video that i can find the videos
you can
OK onto another type detector
so this is a new orleans inspired detector
the dates
from the early nineties
with standard eighteen t with support vector machines came out because they were doing it
were well aware
we're doing support vector machines well aware of this and these guys well aware of
what machines but they kept the neural approach and the reason is that it works
quite hard to train because the complex
mister back propagation and things need to know what doing
this approach is still giving
competitive detectors with anything else
we know about
so the way that works says it's a neural network the new network the spatial
which is convolutional so in fact what happens you take your image u
run a bank filters of a given size it
what you're going to learn
and then you rectify those filters you run the second bank filters on the output
again which is
so on third fourth bank etcetera
so this mimics the simple cell complex cell structure list of the v one
part of the visual cortex
is that the inspiration for it turns out that this actually works very well the
conductivity changes as you go up so first of all it's rather local
it tends to spread out so the final few stages of the global
and we'll give you a class the class classification
p and so here it's digital sensors ten different classes will output
he trained by gradient descent one thing this thing needs very big training sets
so this was trained on i think fifty thousand or something digits
but in terms of an actual applications machine learning it's one of the earliest and
still one of the most successful the system actually reads about ten percent of objects
the persians united states
it doesn't make too many mistakes so you can see here
the kind of resistance to perturbations of noise
changes in position and scale
the system has you probably can't read the figures here
which is the output of the system
but it's getting things mostly right despite very very severe perturbations
OK so
another neuron detector
kind of inspired by the previous one
and this one trying to build an some rotation invariance to face detection
and the way they did
so this equals minus ng
h two
this is zero
and so you see what you see here
is exactly what you see here
the two are identical
so you could use work energy theorem
or you can use the conservation of mechanical energy that makes no difference
and so you know can calculate the maximum
and for those of you who want some numbers i found that the maximum
was lots minus seven
o point four degrees
you always get two angles
and in radiance that because the mind is o point one three ratings
you know the cosine of the angle is so always get away
nothing you can do about it
so now you can ask yourself the question
what is phi
if i is always a bit of a pain in the neck and is really
not all that much physics five
but i was sort of curious
with these
initial conditions what if i would be
so that
just take a quick look at that
so if we want to know what
we have to look at the initial condition that
t equals zero
velocity at point p is
o point three
in this direction
and we know to fatah equals
data zero and we know what data series that was the five degrees at point
o nine
radiance and so i'm going to substitute that
in my solution
so i don't equals zero
i noticed they're equal status zero
fatah zero i know the data zero is
we just calculated with data maxis
times the cosine
t equals zero
so our pop
two angles of phi
plus and minus five one
always find the plus and minus sign because the cosine of the angle is the
same as the cosine minus
so now we have to find out which of the two it is
by the way
when you find
data maximum
because plaza mine o point one three iranians
you could have picked a plus or minus
i pick the plus
if you want to pick the minus you would have found different facing
but you can pick minus
i just want to remind you that i picked plus whatever follows
so now i have to take into account the
the fact that at equals zero
that i know the
out of that committee but i take the
relative of that equation
there are so i get that
the fate of the two
which is the angular velocity in radians per second at any moment in time that
we're going to evaluate it equal zero
because miners omega
the sign
omega t
let's fly
we will evaluate it equal zero
one of the fate of the t
well the theory t is v divided by l
this is to divided by l
and is therefore
plus o point three
this plus because a zero angle is increasing
so it is plus
how do we know to be overwhelmed
well remember we discussed before
your changes
angle by an amount p theta and if these are here
i call that the
and if the length is l
and the definition of the data
and in radiance is as divided by l
if we divide both sides by dt which mathematicians cannot do physicists can
then you get the theta DT
equals the
and that is the velocity divided by l so you see the theta DT
is he divided by l
so we now have the second equation
we now
console for sin phi
give you again to angles
the viewing angle phi two
and gives you hundred eighty degrees minus fights
they have the same value for sin phi
but only one of these
will be the same
as one of these
and that's the one that you pick
and in my case
before my value of o point one three
i find then
that's fine
equals minus o point eight
two radios
it is about minus forty seven degrees
there's not much physics in the facing
what is interesting perhaps is to mention that if we had chosen
the speed at time t equals zero if we had given speech in this direction
o point three
meters per second
they maximum wouldn't have changed of course not
but the phi would have changed
so maybe we can start
it is a small example before going to the next slide that should clear up
some of the concept that we are talking about
so this is showing the litter box
that has this navigation task and this is kind of the standard environment in
reinforcement learning the point my mind that people you like
you seem you imagine that the robot is into the space
and it has actions that can go
two as the composite actions like you the the agent can say that i want
to go on mars
but what happens is that agent saying i want to go to mars
sometime it goes to the other direction so zero point
percent of the time it goes really but in the rest of the time just
randomly goes in the direction of the other compress
and so the task of the agent is to get to
two somebody were state and so maybe
four or transitions
the reward is going to to be zero
except when they finally some whole gets to the their state
and then somehow it it tries to
to stay there let let's say and
what's happening leaves that forever
so the disk that all of these counting here by the way
is that when this happens
if you didn't have discounting that the sun would be infinite right so if you
do this discounting saying
the sun is always finite because konami smaller than one
so you know that this is the geometric theory
if you just saw all these numbers
what you get
you get one of one minus come
so we receive our minds come a lot of
in the talk
so this defines the transition probability
i was criticized for saying cut by
the kernel is just you know what your argument function and
and that's what you want you want to sink when you hear the word co
so the transition probability
could be a matrix if you have a finite state space but if you have
an infinite state space is just the function for this defines that the thing
and and this defines the rewards for
so then everything is pretty much defined here and
how do you
design a controller in this case
well what the content should do is is that it should try to use some
actions that go to the action that brings the agent closer to the goal
some of
and what makes this difficult is the reward is
so no no one this is
the control problem specification this is very simple
that you want to take this action is right
because this is defined in terms of the rewards
and the immediate reward at every time step i just zero
so this is
this makes the problem
the figure
but this makes the problem i suspect
so i hope that that i know these concepts are
easier to understand
so again policies of the behaving so the robot decides to
that it looks at the state and then
it seems that well into the forests and on into the
was that there is the best
so maybe i should take the action that brings me to to use
so that's the policy so places and they have of defining the behavior
it could depend on the full blast
but it doesn't necessarily have to depend on
and given your policy
what is the value of the policy it could be good policies are about but
this is you start region from some states
and then you start to execute the policy so that really stuck in some random
going somebody
and then use on
the rewards that i received along this pass
OK you do the discarding as well you take the expectations and
but you're taking the expectation what happens is that you are basically summing over all
this possible future trajectories right so some of the actors are going to hit the
goal some of the trajectory is to missing in
and you take the expectation we suspect all this trajectory
it's good
so that the
the value for state tax and the policy pi
and have a function again it's just we're taking the maximum of this was just
all possible policies
an optimal policy
would get this value in every possible state and you can buy that if such
an optimal policy would exist at all
so what's missing
so given that you know about the problem so far
let's assume that everything is fine and the states finite actions are finite
does an optimal policy as the still not
of many optimal policies
OK why
so talking about this specific problem but i'm really asking more generally
that the church is given a finite MDP and and the question is if there
exists an optimal policy
if i write
the actual words which make up the joke of the information bearing thing for the
so telling and then we have a whole range of strokes about is it's about
six about christmas those
this things so about
all sorts of
all sorts of things are never mind but not to about slovenians were talks about
potatoes or jokes about civilians potatoes but that will be created solely
i'm trying to get
twenty million
i can never going to talk
want to
so find mutual funds china
all right
the second suspect that the product and this one one of the argument restrictions on
the front
o think right you matrix about anything according to size so right so that these
jokes but the
ones which are listed where things someone made a decision at some stage about jokes
about those things so that title john has been reified so it so the concept
of jokes about
austrians was the homeless here because it just about austrian is in the knowledge base
so every time someone made some assertion about possibly the the offensive
no i'm not so we have to the full KB defined can you see world
with the decision on to the austrians
or to money
any other
so coverage
it was it's only deep brain wouldn't it has a number of predict is countable
on the fingers and the figures are now on your toes as well
so we've got thousands and thousands of so it's in the sun
no it's
the difference is mostly that's more suited for inference
right but
wouldn't it loses
has more
has more uniform coverage
and it in some cases more fine grained
perhaps i global even in reality
that that they have very
different purposes and you can use them together because we have these links to win
if you can actually find some german wouldn't have go up wouldn't some two we're
gonna correspondence and then you can start reasoning about
four drawn random to from the sort of list of good ingrams and see whether
they those are perfectly
the different games and they give you some information about coverage which might give you
some information about utility i think it's
important to realize what sort of game that you're playing the idea of playing a
game of sampling in a knowledge inferentially productive knowledge base so don't
compare to what the coverage again wouldn't it
is was would be what you do the things you should compare it to serve
as a feature compared to something in a in
knowledge bases which it should have been used for inference
so here's the key
rather than because he was
is says you
yes and no
and i very much want to i sort of produced infrastructure which is all the
wikipedia articles sorted by the council including the list and i want to go through
one by one and in the end to cyc i want cite from them one
by one element to itself and i want you guys to do it to show
you how we're going to make you do that at the end of the talk
of three hopefully will likely
so there's a lot of things the
a lot of data about the
that they all
on the basis of that
the things he
because he it was that
don't know
what does that mean if you look at the relationship like that where i was
showing you the container completely and so on we have
large numbers of meanings for war i mentioned then wouldn't it
wouldn't it is
meanings for
this is
contextual variants on the meanings of reasonably narrowly applied words we tend to have large
numbers of
variants on common words we
g one
i give you one
you know
you know all
so what
all this
the average
you know
so you can
the second
it's not
what is the
it here is that
we can read them
it the
we use
its mission
it seems to the
so it was really is
it is
is it
so this
so you
the new
what we really need
with my
the discrete
this is not
it is
so the story
at the same time hilbert was openly disparaging and skeptical of philosophy and the belief
the ability of philosophy to to solve problems on its own terms so
for help
the only way to make philosophical prior progress was to translate philosophical questions into properly
mathematical questions
and then you do mathematics is the mathematical method ties the philosophical questions and then
and then you can make
you can make progress
no good of course did that ended that to great effect
so he was remarkably good at using formal methods to address epistemological problems but at
the same time is very sensitive to
to the limitations of the former methods and largely
as a consequence of his incompleteness theorems and so
while recognizing and feeling very strongly these limitations he looked too
philosophy of these falls out of a certain type of philosophical method to fill the
gap and so here's another quote from from from conversations with how long so kernel
is says that the analysis of concepts is central to philosophy
science only combines concepts is and does not analyse concepts it contributes the analysis of
concepts by being stimulating from real analysis analysis is to arrive at what thinking is
based on the inborn intuitions and so the idea is to science we basically work
with the concepts were given me we can take them apart and put them together
in different ways and apply new concepts from the old ones but it doesn't give
us the initial concept to start with for that i mean that's what that's we
you need this kind of
big philosophical method that no one discussed this morning that you that's where you have
to rely on one
this mysterious method of analysis to give you the concepts to work with
and this i take it is explained his disdain for many mathematicians met mathematicians and
philosophers who expect to get
too much from syntactic methods
so they're the ones who expect to derive something from nothing you know in
from that quote while avoiding the appearance of philosophy
i take that to be some drama here or there this this this this tension
between a girl and hope it to be a poignant one i mean girl had
inherited the powerful
from from help at
any shared gilbert strong desire to see mathematics from describe the destructive skeptical
attitudes but in the end he concluded that an overly narrow reading of the metamathematical
tradition left skepticism with the upper hand
and there's you know some historical irony here as well so this
as far as i know there is no evidence that hilbert and kernel ever meant
but they once came close
so in in nineteen
thirty one
hilbert gave a lecture in can expert called not to can logic so the knowledge
ninety three
thank you
where the use cases of logic and and and and the rational sciences and a
and you natural sciences with great optimism
so for minute excerpt of that speech was excerpted
and so her girl
albert read on the radio and i'm pretty sure you can still find it online
today so if you google or if not sending email send it if you can
actually you know you get an MP MP three files with with you know talbot's
voice just reading the
a snippet of this lecture lecture that ends with the words famous in this in
very and so we must know
we will
and the historical irony is that that at the same time kernel was the conference
on epistemology and exact sciences in that very same city
and that was the
the conference where google announced the incomplete the first incompleteness theorem just the day before
public lecture
and of course that the inputs a is true it shows that there are limitations
to the knowledge and former methods
OK so let me sort of now jump to the present and
how to extract some what i mean so what good is history unless you to
learn something from it so they i take
from these considerations
so first of all
i think it's undeniable that the metamathematical approach which involves syntactic formal methods modelling mathematical
methods provide a powerful means of understanding mathematics i mean i think it's undeniable that
work in the hope at school as well as girls work tells us something about
the nature mathematical we understand mathematics better than we did a hundred years ago
as a result
but at the same time the mathematical modeling should be complemented by a properly philosophical
on the subject matter so we should always be
mindful of
what it is we're trying to understand you know formal systems these days are a
dime a dozen you really have to think long and hard about what it is
you're trying to capture and whether or not your formal modelling is is actually doing
what you think it is
at least for me in my view mathematical logic is often most compelling
and satisfying these two strands come together so that is when you get
mathematical results that contribute to a deeper philosophical understanding
so another from the mathematics is informed by and informs our philosophical or philosophical understanding
and so
so the landmine like to tell you give you a quick overview of some things
are going on and metamathematics today
and i mean happily i don't have to spend too much time on any of
them because you been hearing them all along in the conference and i don't have
what would be how much longer life
sounds good
so yes i'm going to talk about quickly proof mining automated reasoning and formal verification
combinatorial independences dependences in history and philosophy of mathematics in fifteen minutes
and if it doesn't
only logarithmic
so that's quite dramatically dozens and dozens grow
and we
grows logarithmically so much much weaker
and then
this fine
precision takes place is an important consequence is a mention
tells you
that you have an issue with this and dimension
yes it's a motivations
that are
no more than the dimension
and this is the machine looks maximally complexity can realize all possible separations on such
training sets of size
characterized by the dimension
and once we got past that we see image what you want
training examples and mention the
machine yourself in the regime
with the machine
can i realize everything anymore so are some things that you can do
which means that suddenly
an inductive bias suddenly
prior knowledge or whatever we want you have to see function class will
after that point sandy
you can hope to
to generalize
and nothing in between
no because it's possible
there is an example of that is the dimension
we take half spaces in our two
so they are
can be written like this
functions taking values plus or minus one
two different space
you know this is how anyone can reach
and if we
three points
which can
can be to to the poll three
three points
so we can have it possible separation
place the points in general position it turns out we can actually realize all these eight possible separations
so we can show all
three points in general position
and how it
it turns out that true
that we should never shuffle four points so if you take four ones no matter place them
you will not be able to separate in
sixteen possible ways to do put the
using functions from the class of functions
or in this case you mention is three
and it turns out this case the of equal number
and the number rounds of both of these users
some kind of complexity concept in statistics
from the point of view
statistical learning theory is
sometimes makes sense
but not always because it turns out there are cases where
can be very different cases
learning machines which is one parameter with dimension is infinite
and the cases
when you have
infinitely many parameters implicitly in the present to find out
anyway somehow things it's so clear to everybody that just counting the number of parameters
doesn't make sense as long as you don't have some sense of scale also people in because
with one parameter which is a real number you end
as much as you want you can including many parameters
our accuracy in one real numbers so discounting real numbers that make sense that's clear
a lot of this has been done
many approaches
this is
one example of this examining
and the
like this into a typical bones that when i showed you before
basically the same kind of thing stream arguments before
we get
well i
well now we have the test error training error
here we have a quantity that
depends on the species are mentioned age
today depends on the ratio between these dimension
and the number training stations
and then
we can also look at this
respond and discuss it bit
when i first saw this kind of was quite
something like this is possible
we know about the induction
a which are and going work
at a canadian university
and the university of massachusetts of the the UK systems is
designed for being able to define some complex queries about evolution
a stock information stock price
we had a look
what's the data stream
main applications some models
what data stream management systems are
process spend too much time on this
subject but i think that the management of data is very important
and i think that these systems we represent the future of data management
in real applications in the next lecture
now let's turn to
data stream mining
so the outline in the following so first i'm going to give the definition
and context of the data stream mining
and then i'm going to focus on
three different methods
decision tree
and clustering
the goal
it's important
apply data mining algorithms to
once we more to several weeks
the constraints
are the same as before limited memory
limited CPU
one possible
o PM
as well
we want to introduce
what's windowing in the data mining process
windowing is that if we consider a stream
so we have here at the beginning of the stream
at each
we have
some elements arriving in the stream
here is the current day
and windowing
it is to define to which portion of the stream we want to apply
data mining algorithm
i've we want to apply it to the whole stream
so i mean from the beginning to the current day date
or two is sliding window
i want to build the model
for the last three hours and maintain the model for the last three hours
all too
any portion of the
any portion of the past of schools but not defined
in order to
let's have a look at these different requirements
if we want
to apply the algorithm to the whole stream
we need
the algorithm to be incremental
why because we don't want we want to be
one possible origin we want to have only one pass for each element and we
don't want to memorize
all in
incremental algorithms are sufficient to do
if we want to
apply it on sliding window
last day
last three hours for instance
we need an incremental algorithm
the ability to forget the past
when some elements
died from window
get out of the window
we have we need to remove them from the model
if we want to apply on any past portion not defined in advance
we need incremental algorithms
we need to to keep from summaries
history of the host tree
not the whole stream
but a summary of
what are we going to
i see no
but the whole stream
well one meant for which is already
applicable to stream
if is no own network
we can
at the beginning of the stream
with the neural network
and then we wait
it's not that easy
the question is actually on this slide during the break
the first one is
yes there's a mistake here
for example some examples of images and that our semi definite positive include diagonal matrix
only if the diagonal elements are
positive nonnegative
so you're mean you're missing here and a diagonal matrix with nonnegative elements inherent in
the diagonal matrix with nonnegative elements
and the results zeros on the diagonal then is semi definite positive
so why
is the transpose b always the semi definite positive matrix
the reason is that you want to know if
this dot product is is always nonnegative and it turns out that the end is
the domain of the matrix which is the transpose of the matrix has this property
then you can
transfer it to the left of the dot product
by by just transposing a matrix
this means that the product is exactly this one and obviously it's the norm of
the x squared so it's got to be
and then get it right that's the reason why be transposed b
all the transpose is always symmetric semi definite positive matrix
so again i would be switching rather quickly enough from linear algebra to probability so
if you have
a few questions then
now is the time
all right
this issue probabilities
so again i'm not planning to go into these areas into the very
very complicated concepts in probability so we start to with was really the basics let's
say you have
according to new to sit and you look at is if the the outcome is
to use our heads
and you do that several times
and you wonder if you've done that and sometimes what is the probability to have
and two s exactly
that would be a fair coin right
if you want
to study the problem the
the outcome of random events
then you have to formalize that in mathematics with a random space
we're all media is actually the space of random events the set of random events
a year is the
the set of measurable collections of events
and these are probability we should go from
eighty two you one so if in my
in my car in in my car experiments
the set of random even for it if if
sorry is that even the
even so i want to study is just does one calling and i look at
the outcome of of of
disney these
this thing and then the
he said on omega is the set containing only add and k is the set
of measurable collections of even is
is made of four minutes that is that are
was all omega and the empty set and the
the set that contains only adds or sitcom that contains only three years
and so you will be able to measure the probability of any elements in e
so the probability of the empty set is you know the probability of the whole
set omega is exactly one
and if you have a occurred which is maybe not for but
which is a little bit biased then the probability of heads and may be p
and the one of these maybe one p
so there
let's properties of or of the probability are that the probabilities between zero and one
the empty set as the probability the full set as one of probability one if
you have if you consider to is to measure random events
that there are
OK but there's a there's a mistake there if you consider two random even for
which means that there section is empty and their union
the other is the intersection is empty then the probability of the union of
the evans is the sum of the two probabilities
so you can easily imagine that he is you have and
we'll see what the rules are women
that's quite different from what must of this might try to to do
today was certainly pretty
revolutionary i think in nineteen thirty
which was
an idea of having a little abstract or ideal idealise machine which is going to
carry out computations for you
and there are a couple of different approaches to that
the first one is called turing machine
in all around during
i guess not
and coincidentally actually was responsible for
taking for the concept of digital computer
at least in
during the war in england
so the the second world war
and in
and the true machine is what i call the state machine
it's like a little engine remembers what it up to
and remember that by saying i mean state forty four
and it looks up the title of what's best to do it in state forty
four something else
maybe that changes the state of ideas
changes some storage being written from
there's the third approach called abacus machines
and that's machines are can't just intermediary device really make it easier to prove some
because machines are really more like what we think of computer
you imagine that there is a bunch of
containers and each contain has a numbering
and so we call the registers
as time goes by
there's some operations which can affect the
values of numbers in registers and the operations are controlled
by little thing it remarkable program i guess
so that actually have a machine is
really closer to conception of computer
o by the
computer like things
so it's kind of interesting as three different approaches to computability
and what will mainly be trying to do is just push forward to showing both
particular ones
or equivalent
there was a
this problem that
there might be ways of computing that we somehow or having captured yet
but we can see it every time we come up with a new way of
figuring out whether something far artistically
computable victory so far we have tried to do this
it always turns out to be
we can prove mathematics and science some some something else someone else already thought of
the mathematician working at the time when the church symbolic logician
propose the thesis
as as a formal statement to control
discussion in this area
culture to status
OK and just read that because i think it's can isolate just the they self
this is there's no end to the possible variations in detailed characterizations of the notions
of computability
and effectiveness
being able to tell whether really done the job not
you have to finally accept or reject the thesis
that the set of functions computable in any one senses someone comes up with
is the same as another way to do it
to us when we're thinking about this
so think
OK it's but
in the light of the problem space that we're dealing with it's really important
we're really trying to capture
whether or not they could be
one of gilbert's little as could really be a call
a little lower others got
effective computability that's the why of
ensuring that we haven't gone wrong don't always idealised stack
the importance of is around that maybe we left something out maybe there is a
way that humans think about calculations
so we haven't yet
teased out of
apparently attempts to do this
just to be completely crazily skeptical speculative
just as
in a sense the greeks didn't want to see real numbers
i run up against them all the time
but they kept on the will way we have been dealing with numbers all other
integers or rationals
you can see this this problem here the edge looking at diagnosis of
five squares and so on
but will figure that one out
really it was that they had teased at the following locations and come up with
strong theories
the church's this is about that you might be the problem here is some figured
out enough about what it means to compute
i don't know if it's possible
but the faces we have
they're all it's always all sign
so we can define the
because functions
you start with the thing actually called primitive recursive functions by
got two sets of introduction so i don't know
the simplest sort of calculable functions are the ones that either
if for every argument these are functions on non so
not not stuff just not
can indeed side to
so the function that for every
input document number
it is zero
easy to compute one step can be the number to give you the answer you
know the number here
this the
it's clearly
so is the successor function in a number of one two
and so is the function that says taking projections
if we've got a whole bunch of arguments will take the attack
this is a list of accolades
we can find the odd because now given to us is always to stop this
through the list
the things are called recursive functions because of this the next
axioms around composition recursion k so the composition function
and says we can make up more complicated functions from
from others self we have a bunch of functions
h one is there
h one
through a chance
we can somehow the take the result loss functions
apply new function g
and we call that a new function
that's a lie creating new functions from old
is to compose
we want to have a way of creating
functions by starting from
what the function does when it's even
zero an argument
and then what we should do
if we are given the number of nonzero
and the answer is
i will do it like this
it's to be some particular function for zero
and for the successor case the case we are dealing with anything other than zero
it's going to work out some composition
of simple things
so we know how to
we didn't know how to calculate the value of f when we have expressed one
so that's three express one's car three
we don't know how to do it for zero
we worked our way after knowing how to do it for two
given that we know how to do it for two
in no
this expression here
as you look like that
taking logs and matching terms
initially depends on all the random variables at once
and these are functions just in the last couple weeks
this has to hold for all distributions
and that's the constant was as easy
so we just decompose
state in terms of orthonormal basis
and we just take care of those synergy
well then this expression here
can be written as such
because of this
the times the corresponding coefficients theta i has to match the right hand side
and this only works if f individual terms which depend on the maximal cliques
this has sold for all size and data
then you just
collect all those terms depending on the maximal cliques together
it is defined as as just feature maps on the maximal cliques themselves
then we can get this inner product
so it's really just
straightforward linear algebra
it is but
not deep
now let's take an example
normal distribution
so this is actually something that
martin already had on slides we didn't
discuss that we will show the same example but will just see it was probably
slightly different numbers but other than that same
so mean that for normal distribution of topics was just six and a six transpose
the only thing that kind of stuff passes now
all the sudden those excess of vector valued
everybody knows how to write it to write normal distribution
we would also see that will have to express first inverse covariance matrix it's time
for a normal distribution
now we know
that's how far must decompose into the subsets involving on undergraduates from each maximal clique
so i know that have normal distribution with certain conditional independence properties
sometimes this is called a gauss markov random field
so if you see somebody writing this
you know this is code for saying something very simple namely have a normal distribution
and have conditional independence properties
now for the linear term well that's just fine
it decomposes very nicely so the only really happen in terms of the excited state
and they correspond to an nation this graph
now we know that for a normal distribution we have x transpose inverse covariance matrix
we must not have any coupling terms between vertices that don't have any age
what this means is that the inverse covariance matrix has to be sparse
seven look
this is my normal distribution
at some coefficients theta here
and these must be zero
whenever this knowledge
they can just write eta two is the inverse covariance matrix
and then
well it's just leave off
so it's between one and two
so i can have those terms
and actually i made a mistake here
this should be too and this should be answers what does the numbers you
and there is an edge between the two and three
and then three four and five fully connected
remember sometimes you would actually right across
through it's adjacency matrix
and i've told you in addition to all that that
this actually makes some of the scenes this this really corresponds to gauss markov random
i don't it means that they have some dependence
so we solve large sparse linear systems before
they quite well
at least three four people
the use this if you do that
from a really good idea if you don't use just the standard matlab routine for
solving a linear system but use
eight specific sparse linear solver
is the sparseness cells actually much faster
was exploiting the fact that the linear system has lots of zero
system proceed this by eliminating one variable after the
as it so happens is exactly the same procedure
as the message passing algorithm
and we'll will get to that a little bit
the point
here is
the inference procedures that we've talked about in graphical models last week
we just
in the next one after the other we wanted to ensure doesn't cover was too
much else
that is the same problem that you will get if you solve linear system
because if you remove the wrong variable all the other variables that depends on a
and then you will get to really dance to
and it takes a long time to solve
and you can use the very same techniques
for finding a good action order
on the graphical model
and on the sparse linear system
so here
OK well
so let's see how we do is actually
really simple
markov chain
so the data and they had to law
of the some of my entire domain
now here in the markov chain have expressions which depend only on adjacent land
five pxtxt the first one is something
so this is some in of x plus one
have to some or all this one sixty
of the product over all those intuitionistic one