choice trials in which is a certain stimulus was chewed was chosen
and all the forced trials of that same stimulus in aligned one on the other
side of magic responses and they look
this is for that
one hundred percent seventy five percent fifty percent twenty five percent for each one of
them they aligned
very well on each other
so the bottom line here is
it seems like
the prediction errors in different trajectories look like a star so prediction error not like
a critic
prediction error state value prediction urban action value q value prediction error
i think i'm not going to go through this in detail
but just to say that in a different study
there have been only two studies on this the second study for rho should always
in rats and they
they had this somewhat different design where they had always predicting
immediate reward delayed rewards large reward small rewards et cetera and we won't go
through all this now but when they looked at their responses it looked more like
they saw they thought they were c
q learning rather than star so so they were seeing
in of four-stroke trial where the rat had to get
let's look at this level
i there are rewarded with a short delay or with the long delay rewards with
long delays are discounted by time right so they had more fiery called the firing
here this is already the time the reward
more firing four
the short delay rewards it for the long delayed rewards and the same or firing
for high for large reward for small reward
but when they got a choice
in both cases they saw the same fiery whether they are going to choose the
short or the long delay
they first saw the same kind of q value of the best possible option so
this fits this
regardless of whether they are going to choose the best what we're going to choose
the second one
the long delay one
in the same year
so this some of the summary of the story here is that the jury is
still out on starts versus q learning or even science versus q learning versus actor
critic there
are a small handful of studies looking at this directly and what really needs to
be done is
more neuroscientists to do more experiments recording from dopamine neurons especially in
i wrote here telltale tasks tasks that are designed especially for this purpose could really
tease apart these different models
and the reason
we want them to do that is that
as i said this is one area where the brain can for reinforcement learning because
the brain actually learns in task it's much harder than normal reinforcement learning task write
it learns in real time with real noise in real problems and if you look
at these signals sorry
you see there
very very noisy and
kind of you know not
what we expect from a nice prediction error signal but the brain is noisy the
world is noisy
it's true that also are specific measurement devices putting electrodes into the brain don't give
us the nice signal in the world and it could be that the brain itself
see the cleaner signal
that we're seeing here
but in general
since the brain learns so well it would be interesting to know what algorithm it
uses to do that learning and that could maybe help the debate between these different
algorithms in reinforcement learning
they have half an hour left
which means that will probably not get arrested sitiv ity in the brain but will
do these two so that's good
so until now i've talked about three algorithms for model free learning
but one question is
do animals really only learn model free trial and error prediction errors you you you
know run around the world blindly and see what happens or is it or is
there also model based reinforcement learning in the brain
and it turns out that
way before reinforcement learning came into the picture neuroscientists are at that point psychologists had
fierce debates on this
where some
psychologists like thorndike thought that everything was stimulus response see stimulus you learn response to
basically learn a policy for this
model free and some people like torment thoughts about that
rats were much smarter than that
so what experimenter told did
to show this
with this experiment so in this experiment
there are starting from here
i ran into this big arena to find this
the second pathway running down the pathway and got food over here
do this again and again over several days
so the nineteen forty six i don't have a video to show you
and then in the test phase changes situation
this saying
table was now connected to a bunch of different
array of of pathways the main pathway this pathway was blocked
and he asked himself were with the rats go which passed what they choose
and so
you can probably see that this is where the goal is to be before
so the question is will they know to go down pathway number six
and indeed
most of the rats chose pathway six cells and chose one something went right
which is kind of
the policy here the policy closest to the food
but many of the
a completely new policy that they'd never been trained on before
which can which basically showed told
in his words
all his words are humble rat he said even the humble rat can learn spatial
structure and use it to plan flexibly so the right just learned
straight left right right food they learned
something about the world they learned what he called the cognitive map
of the environment which is what we call a transition function between states
model of the world
a more modern way
of getting the same thing
which actually looks at the other half now transitions between states but the reward function
to get a probabilistic representation of these hidden causes and hidden states that all levels
in the model
noting that they are all subject these random fluctuations
both on they
on the emotional the flow of the hidden states here
and the scheme you get from the predictive coding formulation in terms the prediction errors
is very very simple all you're doing is going from sort causes consequences
these bayesian inversion basically maps from consequences sensory consequences to courses replacing these structures these random fluctuations here
with prediction errors
just inverting the direction of these arrows so
you just be inversion scheme has the same architecture
as a generative model
all we're doing now
is basically informing
conditional on the posterior
expectations sale averages
way informing them in terms of by giving them the prediction error
using forward
prediction errors passing into deep into the hierarchy
i found these prediction errors are simply formed by passing predictions down or outputs to the periphery of the hierarchy
i've written down the equations in the previous slide district for those people interested at
intuition is is is quite simple here is just about
the form of they e
and the internal brain states and how they talk to each other should somehow recapitulate
architectural the form of the generative process itself
and once you've got the form it's quite simple to see
one could interpret message passing in the real brain conform to the sort of hierarchical
architecture and i this cartoon that's here
in terms of
different brain systems and different
parts of the
cortico-subcortical of the brain
distinguishing between the representation predictions
prediction errors
which i thought particularly efficient posed by david mumford here too
be encoded by
deep and superficial pyramidal cells because cell population in the brain respectively so the red triangles correspond these prediction errors
and the black black triangles corresponds to these posters predictions are expectations
and you get the same sort of message passing that described in the previous
exactly in the brain
and you get this sort of
for example we have this approach presented there coming from the eye muscles and the
visual information coming from the retina
that's passed up it's compared with top-down predictions to love its prediction error
the prediction errors and sent forward to improve the predictions and this process continues hierarchically
until some higher consensus is achieved whereby pictures minimize all levels in the hierarchy and
you have an increasingly abstract representation
of the causes of your visual
using that you want know
no okay i'll give you examples of that's a very good point and sometimes the
performance process in the real world doesn't correspond to the form of the generative model
and you get some interesting mismatches in the world and what the world out here
but i have about
the model the world is brain in but the real world that you want in presentation
will bring
o yes sorry yes so the model of the world is completely within the brain you
have enormous hierarchical depth and separation temporal scales so for example in in the final
part of the brain that could be structure representations
provide context which could be some minutes hours and days
whereas representations and low levels of the cortex usually condition poster beliefs expectations about hidden
states fluctuate over time scales millisecond of tens or hundreds of milliseconds and all hierarchy
compose and optimize with this
message for parallel message passing
to minimize
talk about is
bayesian discriminative learning and the reason for that is
in machine learning
we have certain terminology in their effects
the way we think about different kinds of models so one particular
kinda terminology is this
generative versus discriminative model
so let's look at classification
when you have some inputs x and some class labels why
the generative model
models so you can think of is the generative process more
objects out there in the world if you are trying to classify
cats versus dogs
what you do
is the state's images of cats versus dogs to be more precise
you have some
prior proportions o
you know
how many cats versus dogs images you expect sea
and then you have
it class conditional density
which gives you for each of your class is a probability distribution over
we observed features of the class
so this will be the probability distribution over
image features assuming your cat another one assuming your dog or turkey or whatever
in discriminative modeling what you do is you try to directly models the conditional distribution
which would be say the probability of the label given the class or it could be building a decision
system that just simply outputs this hard decision
about a label
sorry given me input feature there
it is often the case that's
a lot of machine learning is based on discriminative models
the bayesian bits of machine learning often talking about generative models probability distributions over the whole data
and so it is only natural that this sort of
conception has emerged there
the bayesian
ah frequentist maps onto the generative discriminative divide
and that's not really accurate
it is perfectly possible
to be bayesian about discriminative
similarly expressed perfectly possible
to build
generative models in eighty frequentist way for example you could do something like
kernel density estimation
or feed a mixture model using maximum likelihood or something like that
in particular i think it's very may be useful to look at the example of linear classification this is something
we are all extremely familiar with
so imagine we have a few data points
let's say these two blue data points and this one red data points
and we want to build a linear classifier
and clearly
all these great lines
are consistent with
this data set of three data points
all these
great lines
perfectly separate the blue class from the red class
so how do we choose one of these
to make predictions
well if you could be
let's call it the maximum margin principle for choosing these it would say
choose this
blue line here this blue dashed line that's what the support vector machine will give you
it is a line that maximizes the margin
the distance to points in either of these two classes in this noise free classification problem
now let's contrast there
you know some people have called the bayes point machine
sort of you know used to be
restaurants and things like that's it was all about machines a while ago so
you know the support vector machine kicked out of it
a revolution in naming
love machine learning methods to different kinds machine so the bayes point machine corresponds to this very very simple idea
which is
take a distribution over a linear classifiers for example in this case the uniform distribution
as your prior
so uniform over all possible orientations
and then
conditioned on your noise free data here
your distribution over classifiers looks like this
great thing i've sampled a few hundred points from the distribution
and the bayes point machine just says
find the meaning parameters space
all the posterior distribution over europe classifiers
okay and that's what this red curve gives you
so what is the
what does that do for us
it says
well first of all the answers different from the
maximum margin classifier and the difference comes from the fact that we have this data point
which essentially eliminates
makes the problem is symmetric it eliminates a bunch of classifiers on this side so it tools
the base point classifiers in in the
right direction
if we had
one another data point here i course chosen pathological examples shoyu u
the difference is to exaggerated differences but if i had one extra datapoint here and
one extra datapoint here that's a maximum margin doesn't change at all
but the basic point shifts further in this direction
which is what you get from just averaging over over these
guys here
similarly if i add cluster of points here and the costs are points here not which are actually support vectors
right there are further away from this smooth line these two points but they act in the opposite direction repelling
the classifier in the in
in the
leftward direction
so any questions about that
the termites
the right
the difference between the
right so this is
this is not about hard versus soft classification is not about noise models are what i would call likelihood functions
it's about
the averaging
but bayesian
methods are all about averaging
that's the core idea that the core idea is
given this small dataset i have uncertainty about these classifier
end i need to average the predictions of these classifiers
this is not an exact bayesian solution what we do here
is slightly incorrect which is where averaging in parameter space
the pick any classifier
more formally
we can write the problem as i have on the slide which is minimized the
differential relative entropy between the gas parameters by a not in the guessing parameterized by
a subject to the constraints similarity and dissimilarity constraints and we also require that a
be a positive definite
now if you look at this it's a little bit a little bit nasty so
it's not clear
immediately how you might go about solving it so what we do is we appeal
result which which shows that if we fix the means of two multivariate gaussians we
can actually rewrite the differential relative entropy as
one half times the log determinant divergence between a and and not where the log
determinant divergence is matrix divergences defined at the bottom of the slide
so we can we can just directly map from that the relative entropy formulation of
the KL formulation
two what i call the log determinant formulation
the objective is just rewritten and the constraints
the distance constraints i just turned into standard form so it's clear that there are
linear constraints on a so
so we map it over to this equivalent formulation the log determinant formulation
now we can try to solve this problem
now if you look at what the definition of the log determinant divergence is it's
it looks almost like an SDP has got has this trace term but then there's
this this log that determine actually
that will mean that we can't we can't quite use semidefinite programming
so we need to develop an algorithm for solving this
and i want to go into too much detail but we use the method of
bregman projections which are very
briefly is dual coordinate descent method
essentially what you do is you have on the whole of this matrix at each
and you project
that that the whole of this matrix onto a single constraint features the constraint you
projected and then and then you do some correction and you do this iteratively and
as it turns out that the update this projection can be done
and a very simple way it turns out to be a rank one
update so that
the cost of doing a single projection is ordered the squared
d is the dimensionality
of the data
and briefly some of the nice things about this algorithm first it's it's very scalable
since we have these simple projections and we we don't have to worry about
enforcing the positive definiteness constraint because
the projection does that for us automatically
and there's no
there's no line surgery it's all closed form and no i can vector computation is
very simple
at the beginning of the talk i mentioned
two two nice aspects of the of the of our approach one was this connection
to kernel learning and one was a connection to online metric learning
so i'd like to talk about that now for for a couple of slides
on the left i have the log determinant formulation
i did mention it before but we also can add slack variables two to to
the formulation is to guarantee the existence of a solution which we do
in general so OK so on the left with the log determinant formulation which is
over d by d matrices
it might be the case that the that the dimensionality of the data is very
high in which case maybe it's not feasible to work with a directly
so on the right here is is what i call the kernel formulation which is
over now and by n matrices
where n is the number of
data points in your training set and the constraints are slightly different
but it turns out that if
OK star is the optimal solution here to this kernel problem and it's k stars
the optimal solution to the kernel problem and a stars the optimal solution to the
log determinant problem
then k star equals x transpose a star x where x is your
input data
the input data vectors
so what what this will allow us to do
his work with the kernel formulation when the dimensionality of the data is very high
so so to make them a little bit more clear if if we want to
if we want to learn a metric in kernel space
so say we have some kernel function
phi x transpose y and now we want to learn we want to learn some
DNA of phoenix come you why
now if you expand that just using the definition of the mahalanobis distance
what it's equivalent to
is learning a kernel function of the form
px transpose a few y
so the question is how can we learn given the fact that we can compute
the extras few why how do we compute px transpose a fee one
and if you solve this kernel formulation
you can actually do this and what we show is that the learned kernel
has this form so it's it's the original kernel plus a quadratic
term which is
based on the x i and x j are are are
data points that are part of your constraints
so another another aspect of the algorithm of this of this formulation which is which
is nice is that we can also do
metric learning
in an online manner
we can we can
we can
two variant of this projection method that i talked about a few slides ago
the amount of discount will vary with the action so you have continuous time
the discrete events
events we get to choose actions and interval dependent
so the idea of options is exactly that we're going to start with an MDP
now we can overlay on top
these higher-level actions
that give me variable temporal resolution allows me plan and whatever the right temporal scale
one of the problem is
so you can think of this seminar composite process as overlaid on the underlying primitive
level markov decision process yes
OK good let me let me make sure this point is being it being understood
what's the goal
again the goal is to think of actions much more flexibly than the primitive actions
uniform discrete time muscle twitch simple actions right so what we want we want actions
to be things like
the library
the airport
the door
and so on policies
that can react to
the noisy situation that you're in and yes you have a finite number discrete number
of options
but you want to plan in terms of
right and within it when you choose not been you choose to go to the
then you are doing these all these little action that you're doing underneath right
the point is that you can now thinking reasoning planning learn in terms of these
higher-level things call options
that doesn't answer your question what was question
for example
yes so we have very formal definition of options you write an option is to
stop given
you could start set of initiation sets initiation state you follow a fixed policy
until you tell me go to these conditions
and the point is
if you want to build an option that picture library by the coffee shop you
could do that but you have a policy that
that that competition i'm not sure exactly what you're trying to you trying to say
the core content of
is conditional on its conditional in the sense that
all of the official policy that in some states to actions
now learned policy that maps states of
so the conditional in the sense
after a mapping from states to actions might say i want to
and then execute a particular policy
oh i see what you might say you might encounter and consistency
why would door
like can't copy of you all i want coffee
you see how
so you can you can try that option
and do something different because somehow randomly into a state that make something more yes
but i will make sure the semantics of not is is
make sure that that's the case
OK so let's go
here the
here is the
powerful results
basically it is the
this is probably holes from the problem all is also we have been so far
markov processes are reported or case law
that's what he said well you might want any options this graph shows the office
at each iteration
i mean that in a sense of loss
and as a a result
there are many ways
programme all stand to the case not so let's work through that
let me show you now how all the results have been talking about a markov
decision process is applied to the settings i'm is going to work to some notation
so we're going to learn policies over options that you learn mappings
then assigned to each state distribution or option so in our policies very mapping some
distribution two options
value function is going to be of value functions
four options so this is the value functions for options policy in state s
this is the q value function for policy new
four state option
state and option
the optimal values are defined this way
we can talk about models in this way we talk about planning methods this way
and really all the resources available obtain so let's let's build built towards that so
long as to find the first principal definition of value functions for options
thanks for the introduction
so first before i start i would like to give a very special thanks to
students in both those who have help me
brains slide particular although not always MRI
and the human obozinski
also so what i will try to do today is to give you an overview
of the these hard to pick of sparse methods for machine learning and trying as
much as i can to work to talk about the work of others
but as the and as i said something that is hard to do so and
you always try to snippets some of your own work which we do what was
limited amounts
so i've been doing a lot of reading in in the last two or three
weeks but i may have forgotten someone so if you don't see yourself as
yourself on the slides
don't get mad at me
and it does not mean that you don't do good work on sparse methods
so let me start by giving an overview before i go more into the details
so this is very usual sitting in machine learning at least for supervised learning you
have input data x belonging to some input space capital x
so i'm not used to manipulating this little hands it so
i would try to point towards the screen with an
so this is the capital x being a kind of input space and you want
to predict
a function y value y
and half
machine learning is considering this empirical risk minimisation framework when you minimize the objective function
which will try to so you want to optimize with respect to a function from
x to y in x to predict y
and you have that the fitting term along the points which is the sum of
all the points of the loss
between your true value y i your prediction for x i
and the regularisation term
which is you know or square
but a lot of issues
associated with this framework and the men to issues which loss should you choose for
which type of wine
and this i want to consider these two matches this tutorial
will make use of this is sold other if you use least squares regression if
y i is the only number of users support vector machine logistic if you use
why i being
the discrete
just can value the number
so we mainly focus on this and the choice of the function space and the
now we consider the various types of non
and here
you have to the goal of adding an norm of course is to avoid overfitting
and now you have two main lines of work is in this setting we have
two camps first came in the one of on so bash norms
and this is essentially the camp of kernel methods
and the good thing is it it allows you to do
not enough data and also the theory at least as far as i'm concerned is
well developed and you have a lot of algorithms which are available for this type
of of regularized
the second camp the camp of sparsity
in using norms so here are usually as a start is restricted to only about
the task you want to predict
from x as a linear function of x and of course the main example is
the one on which is just the sun
of the absolute value so here's the cool thing in that it does two things
at the same time
it was both to avoid overfitting and also create something goes into URI estimator estimator
for w
so it does both model selection and regularisation and here
this is a matter because the tutorial
the theory the theoretical part and i don't make work is in progress and this
is the topic of this tutorial
so the first aspect of recovery
if the aspect of algorithms so which one which one is fast it and two
so here this is
picture taken from the statistics and kindly given to me by stefan can
this is the gas here again the laplace and of those
so gauss in favour and two
in the lab class in favour of of one
and since one is not differentiable would see that it might look it is hard
to optimize this is the president of toys
and since and two usually it's too nice smooth convex optimisation problems where if you
would square loss to get just enough system is supposed to be easier this is
goals in here and of course we which
which one wins this is not always OK and then we will see
so first is nice for two things because laplace french
and even better lab class professor article value so you see that it's going to
be important to pick school
and this will be achieved by essentially first order methods with which we will see
the same
for anyone have two
and also i think also to be methods which can use the fact that you're
going to get a sparse solution
get that into the details we get into the details of the
then we got a bit of the article was is associated with with this type
of regularisation
and then we mainly focus on two types of results the first result to be
support recovery and this is in this setting things that we was kind of late
with respect to to applications people have been using one of four
and the problem is that it does two things it will prevent overfitting and select
good zero
and it has been only recently that people have to analyse how which zeros are
we actually getting do we get the correct and whatever show you that you get
this is a sufficient condition for the exact support recovery and it involves the covariance
matrix of the covariance
and essentially if you remove the this parts in says that to get the correct
you q to have low correlation between variables
we see that this is both the positive result
in would tell you when you don't get a good support
both so to me very negative one in the sense that
c to data often call eighty
this shows that we never get good support
then would get to the second aspect which is the high dimensional inference where people
try to derive results we say that
you can still predict well if the number of features p
it is at most exponential in the number of observations throughout this tutorial people the
number of features
and be the number of observations
then we go around trying to go beyond that so because i
that's the only thing that apply in the last directly is almost never useful
in a sense that you well you only have a few lineup problems in machine
learning and you really want to be
but to go beyond that and i will consider first nonlinearities through adding kernels
then trying to see if you can actually do is exponentially many features can you
really or an algorithm where the peak was an
so the definition of convexity
is exactly that statement but where n equals two
alpha one alpha two alpha and beta
this is just the statement for general and
and you can interpret this in some
year way which i will
and into
sure when i j
this is saying take several points on this curve
take the polygon they
these are straight line segments you take the interior
if you take an affine combination like that you will get point
inside the polygon possibly on the boundary
the claim is that all those points are above the curve
again intuitively true from if you draw nice canonical convex
but in fact it's true
algebraically to always a good thing
any suggestions how we might prove this theorem this is this lemma pretty easy
so what technique might we use
one more
induction always a good answer
induction should out
you here because we already know that this is true by definition of convexity for
n equals two
the base case is clear
in fact there an even simpler base case which is when
because one
if n equals one
you have one number that sums to one so alpha one and so one and
nothing's going on here this is just saying
as of
one times x one
is it most
one times fx one so not
really exciting
those that hold with equality
so we don't even need any close to this case
so the interesting part of the still not terribly interesting is the induction step
this is good
in practice and induction
so what we care about
is this the sum
this linear combination of this linear combination f one combination xk xk some over k
now what i would like to do
his apply induction what i know about inductively
it's a of this some if it's some only up to n minus one instead
of all the way up to
any smaller some i can deal with by induction
so i'm going to try and get rid of the terminal well separated out
and this is
only natural
if you play with my combinations before
was just some algebra
so i want to separate out the output and x
and turn
i'd also like to make an apple in combination this is the trick
if you
if i just removed the last term the alpha case from one of n minus
one wouldn't sum to one anymore some something smaller so i can't just take out
this term i'm going to have to do some
trickery here
you should see why this is true because the one myself and cancel
and then i'm just going to some alpha kxk
OK equal one to n minus one
plus the alpha an eccentric i haven't done anything here these are
but now
this nifty feature that on the one hand these two numbers alpha one myself and
sum to one
and on the other hand if i didn't write these numbers should sum up to
just going from one up to k one of two n minus one
one of the sum of two
one well these numbers summed up to one minus alpha
and so on dividing everything by one minus and so they will sum to one
so now i have to have one combinations
i just apply the two things that i know
i know this
the sampling combination will work
why can i say this is alpha and xn
one myself
of this crazy
two possible answers one is correct in one is incorrect
so which would be
on the board to consider
so i'm treating this is just one big x value
i have some x and i have some
one after the fly combination of those two x values is at most the combinations
of the those
x values
this is
by which i mean there
and here's some pseudocode for this is actually slightly different from the book
the book has one in fact there's a nice problem in the book that has
even a different one
OK so
but there are all the basically the same
patricia AP q
we're looking at at the depth of the recursion is the from p q
basically we pick up pivot which were not just because the first element of the
array a page
and book justin for your information uses a few
i use a p
doesn't really matter
and then we set index
to pay
now we have a little
OK so this is the code so basically a
the structure is a for loop with an if statement in the middle
so the
the structure of the algorithm best partitioning step
it looks as far as we set the pivot
to be the first element so here's p
here's q
OK so this is going to be are invariant
any time during the execution of loop
i essentially have
some values up to i which already less equal to x
and then some values
that and the j minus one
that are greater than equal to x
and then i don't know about the rest
so we start out with i equal to p
and j equal to p plus one
that said he plus one
OK so that everything is unknown except for
x here
the idea is that is going to preserve the invariant and the way it does
it is as we go through the loop is it looks at a GA and
it says is the greater than or equal to x
so is less than or equal to x
OK if it's greater than or equal to x it does nothing
OK because what can happen if this is great and called axon essentially just go
to the next iteration loop which moved this boundary
on the invariant satisfied the receiver
but it is less or equal to some kind of problem
if i want to maintain the invariant this next element is less than or equal
to x
so what it does then is it says i'll
let me just move this boundary
and swap this element here which is greater than equal to x with this one
here this less than or equal to x
thereby by
increasing the size of this
subarray and then the invariant satisfied again
so it's fairly simple
it's actually very tight and easy algorithm you so that that's one reason that this
is such a great piece of code
is very efficient
now in principle also this basically the running time for this on n elements
is or and
and basically just going through the n elements and is doing cost amount of work
and then just the cost amount of work outside
so this is a clever piece of code in fact in principle partition is easy
OK thank you were worrying about doing it in place it's really pretty easy thing
to do i take an element
just compare every other element with that
from one to one then one into the other
it's clearly linear time
OK but off and
what you find is that just because you can do it that way theoretically doesn't
mean that that's going to end up giving you
good code and this is a nice piece of code allows you to do it
in place
OK and that's one reason why this is a particularly good album is the constants
are good
OK so yes it when we do asymptotic analysis we tend to ignore the constants
for actually building codes you care about the constants
but first you care much more than just about the constants is whether overall it's
going to be a fast algorithm
OK let's go through an example of this
so there over here
just so we get to get the gist
so here's a
re that i've
created out of whole cloth
here we set x the pivot to be
to be
OK so let's look to see how this algorithm works
so i starts out here
and j starts out here
OK we
what we do is we start scanning right
century that code scanning right until it gets something which is less than or equal
to the pivot so keep going until it finds jake heaps incrementing until you find
something that's less than or equal to the pivot and in that case it's
number five
and it says well swap these two things
does that
so we get six
o five thirteen ten
two eleven
OK and meanwhile now i gets incrementally
j continues where it left off
so now we keep scanning right until we get something that's less than or equal
to the pivot
in this case it's three
was one three and five
we get
sixty three
and now
this step we we increment i we increment starchy out here
in this case right off the bat
we have something
which is
which is less than or equal to x is we swap these two
were nine
groups what i do
that's what the wrong thing to here
it's why i'm not a computer
guys what you would
we have all these guys essentially
it means that all this weight are very very close to zero
on this one here
basically dominate so very very close to one
so essentially what it means that you approximating highdimensional probability distribution
by simple that that you like mass because essentially one of the particle as all
the the weight very close to one on all the others are very close to
zero OK so that doesn't work
so that's why it's important sampling of basically
it's importance sampling on a notable something doesn't scale in i mentioned so what could
i do
two kind of try to
minimize essentially
the visionary c
let me take the degeneracy
of the importance sampling technique so i want to come up with a method is
going to try to reduce the violence of this topic alice teammates so all well
you basically what i've presented here are only degree of freedom i have currently to
deal with this problem too limited the violence and most may consist of these conditional
it is going to show the solution is the only degree of freedom the algorithm
OK so
is there way so long
to pick it
so as assume essentially
meanwhile the violence of my important something is to
OK so that's
so the question i tried to team essentially the only degree of freedom i have
in the important something
so let's look basically
basically to pick to find out what's essentially the best thing i could do
entails selecting the
contain part of the solution to any time well let's come back to the expression
of the weight
importance weights
at time and starting partners with time and i tell you what it is essentially
well this is the
normalized target distribution
divided essentially by the importance distribution which is remember structure that's full of OK
by construction
so nice to play a little bit that this expression
uses include components components waiting time is what they basically you
this down here
which is essentially a function
of the n minus one feels component x one x two x minus one
time basically
this term which is the conditional distribution of xn given all remaining company and the
current target distribution divided by basically
the importance distribution at time
when it comes time you've already essentially sample the company x one x two xn
minus one so the only thing to do
you can do is try to minimize the violence of these guys with respect to
q and all of this is the best thing to do
so as to minimize the violence of this guy respect to qn is to pick
basically two and a quarter pi and so that it is very simple reason
there's nothing really can do
yes so that's basically what this is somewhat the kind of locally
o two more in city at time and if i want to minimize the violence
and the importance weight okay then and only then can do essentially is ph
in part of the solution
as the conditional distribution of x then under the target distribution in which case basically
what you observe is that the resulting importance it is actually independent of the current
sample of it
that's a bit you will have
OK so
that makes sense this thing is a kind of intuitive so let's come back to
the example where you're dealing with the case of the state space model so that
essentially the joint
target distribution you're trying to sample from is the posterior distribution of the infield state
of the state space model given the first salvation where in this case basically
because of the
the should have been making all state space model that is the underlying underlying essentially
state processes markov process on the observation processes such that the observation are conditionally independent
given the states process of physically acceleration density g one given x and then you
can easily show
that in these very specific case the are similar some are locally optimal importance distribution
you can use is the posterior distribution of xn given the cold acceleration of the
previous state stages sample x n minus one so some are you can think of
it this is was basically proportional to the point where the state space with time
because the likelihood of the observed nationwide so some kind of optimal tradeoff between the
dynamic of the state space model on the salvation equation
so you can play with that so essentially if you have to use this kind
it's like importance sampling type algorithm to do estimation in state space models this the
kind of persona the the kind of sampling distribution you should try to
to some poor form so as to compute sequentially to state
in chased where basically your own algorithm to solve all five
these conditional distribution because my not be the case that you can sample exactly from
this guy
o even you might be able to solve all
from this conditional distribution using cell rejection sampling but your own ball two so important
to compute the associated importance weights because essentially it involved into this tale of x
and then never mind basically what you can do is essentially a footpath basically
come with the analytic approximation
of these distributions on proposed use sample from it's OK
so you could use a extended kalman filter unscented chemistry to any like violation without
techniques all basically you will cry for the discrepancy anyway between the target distribution on
the proposal density using importance sampling OK so
the second big
advantage of basically kind of of the calorimeter you can reuse or your factory it's
less almost deterministic approximation technique also used in the context so second possibly as an
important distribution to propose some fourteen one of and part of the space on you
correct for
the discrepancy by simply reweighting use important according to the all of the components which
that's kind of the nice thing about this kind of the techniques
so you can do that
OK you can do all those things OK so for example
assume that you're going to do inference in state space models
corollary of the definition the negative border is the set of many for of the
complement of the sets in the positive more
we call these
well i already said action
we can use this in a so-called willis and an the sort person computing some
maximum frequency using randomized algorithm going up
that is
then compute the minimum frequency very find them against database
and continued this until no more
users are all and this actually at least in some
five days of this works pretty well that we get them that's representation of
the collection of all frequent items
how important that in the end is
i don't really know
OK o
OK yet another more very small theoretical results
i suppose
somebody now in the back row which is misbehaving badly today
the back somebody in the back row is is telling me that OK yeah
this is exactly the set of frequent
set in
in the data
how many questions do i have
to verify
this claim
actually it's pretty easy to so that you need to to exactly
the things in the water
both in the negative and in in the positive more
so it
again in our example a
somebody claims that this is exactly the collection of sequence that we have to cheque
exactly the same
these are frequent and this unknown when it goes on for all you don't have
to anything else
alright that was just a glimpse into
it certain theoretical aspects related to to the borders of on
frequent collections of frequent patterns now i moved to the next part
which is
basically about inclusion exclusion principle and maximum entropy
and the goal here
find out how we can use the frequency
to infer something about the underlying distribution
so early on i said that there is smoke modelling and global modelling
and i'm talking about local modelling
that's what fans still talking about but now i'm thinking about how
information about frequent sets how we could do use that to tell something of the
whole distribution
to recap what we know about treatments that can be an exponential number of them
into the in the number of
they are down supposed called collection under some subset relation we can find them many
in the number of innovations variables algorithm is very simple
and also finding frequently true positive conjunctions
so now the basic question is what do these frequent set was about the underlying
so we are given
a data set of n rows and m columns
and the distribution is
the reason overall you don't one vectors of length n
so the basic question is OK we know these things frequencies which we happen to
be able to compute quite quickly
what do they tell us about the underlying distribution
simple observation is that the case we wouldn't know the zero frequency sets
so basically the frequency of all conjunctions
then we will know
you know everything about the data
just a very simple example suppose
we would have
two variables and you
and if we have a frequency of a so
how many times we have a one
the frequency of blue
the frequency of eighty which is the frequency of the conjunction was one of the
because one
then we can put express
the probability of each variable combinations
as they a
some combination of all these terms
one one of the user well that's a new one zero and a mindset a
b and so on
so if we would not zero frequency says we will know the whole distribution
OK that's completely
in a way that's useless observation because you're all frequencies will be an exponential number
so that's basically saying that the just the description of the distribution
what is a little bit more interesting is suppose we would like to
find out that say the frequency of the d stands
so how many
rose satisfy at least one of the variables a high
as mistakes are made
the the the set x year
continuous variables AI goes from one
we want to find out how many arrows
in the data have at least one of the variables they are equal to one
previously we had been talking about content conjunction now we try to estimate the frequency
of roles satisfying this time
and the idea that what one wants to do is find
eight rank something approximation to the data and the optimal solutions in the case of
gaussian noise is given by the singular value decomposition
but one could think probably more general distributions and in the case that the noise
is any member of the exponential family
finding the basis for the subspace
it's actually an optimisation problem and rather than being purely problems before it's actually nonlinear
optimization problems but fortunately it's been shown recently that the problem is
and so it admits a unique global
and therefore one can just run any optimisation algorithms will converge to the optimal
so this this extension of PCA is is being known as probabilistic PCA
but there have been other type of extensions of PCA to different domains in one
of them has to do with well what happens if this space rather than just
being a linear subspace is instead a nonlinear manifold
in that case the tradition with being to think well
maybe i can just take my data points
it certain nonlinear and betting
and after applying the embedding
the data that we will live in a subspace
and so i could just apply PCA in the high dimensional space
and therefore get my set of principal components
of course that is not very efficient because these high dimensional space can be very
unfortunately there is a beautiful theory developed by
including alex smola which is present here
call kernel PCA
that allows you to do the computation of these principal components just by looking at
both products of the original data rather than looking at the actually
the embedding of the day
the problem is well
if i have no idea what the manifold looks like
then really i have no idea what embedding actually use in these
the idea of the embedding at least finite dimensional spaces
well what inventing should use if the manifold is of type a maybe i could
use embedding a and so in the end is just a model assumption i think
my data and i believe that this embedding will map it into a linear subspace
and not be true
the the embedding i choose may not be the correct one
learning what type of embedding to use is is an active problem today in the
machine learning community
and the problem is well what happens if rather than having a very small and
a single manifold now i have a mixture of manifold and in this particular case
is a mixture of subspaces
of course is no longer a smooth manifold there is no singularity particle the intersection
in this case the difficulty is that i not know which points belong to which
and so
it's not a problem of estimating some model for my data that is just the
smooth manifold but also is the problem of segmentation because i need to simultaneously estimate
basis for the subspaces as well as which point belongs to which subspaces
and this can be solved within a probabilistic framework using techniques such as the expectation
maximisation algorithm and in nineteen nine tipping and bishop
presented a solution to this problem based on expectation maximisation
so this is precisely the problem would be talking today but rather than taking a
probabilistic approach it will be a purely algebraic approach
this type of techniques or how to solve this problem is actually fundamental to many
and in particular in computer vision
it can be applied to the problem of computing vanishing points this is in a
sense if you have a set of parallel lines in an image
parallel three d space the projection is not parallel so they actually converge and they
intersect a point that point is called the vanishing point
and in this case for instance one might be interested in clustering which lines are
parallel to each other
by precisely finding which lines intersect in which vanishing point
that can be cast as the problem of clustering
better living in
place in history
compression one of the most popular techniques for compression
is to find basis
describe the image that is exactly the principal component analysis problems
and one could think of maybe getting richer description of a major even better compression
by using multiple principal components of possibly slower dimensions
segmentation i'll show examples on how to apply
these techniques to segmentation of images based on intensity or segmentation of images based on
i'll spend the entire second lecture talking about how to do motion segmentation based on
these type techniques where one has a camera that's possibly moving and an object moving
and how it is possible to take that
the sequence and converted to problem of how the car is moving one subspace and
the camera is moving in another subspace and so it is to be seeing april
talk about the type segmentation problems here there is somebody who is speaking
it is host and the guest and they're both of them is impossible to separate
these video sequence into three groups mtime each corresponding to each one of the shots
in this video sequence
just briefly mention one example and face recognition
essentially the key underlying idea is the basis of one single person under different illumination
conditions in a subspace
and so
u one could attempt to cluster different faces by clustering subspace
i will not talk about this but their ideas on
given a video sequence of the person that's walking and imagine that i could track
the joints of the person
then the trajectories that the joint of the person described as a function of time
live in some subspace
when the person is walking
and even different subspaces when the person is running and so one could attempt to
do recognition of activities by clustering subspaces
in this case apply to human data
in an absolutely similar fashion there is very recent
in computer vision to model
complicated dynamics in video sequences and these are called dynamic textures
in which one has to understand preserve water
or you can notice but the
the big this mostly in the middle is actually a toilet flushing
and both of them can be considered a different types of dynamic textures so in
this case one would be interested in segmenting the video sequence into different regions each
region corresponding to a different dynamic textures
and we have been recently working on applications on this in biomedical imaging
these i don't know how well you can see i can see very well on
my screen but i guess you can hardly see
that's an image of the heart
so what you can see
in here is the chest of the person
and here you have the heart beating
and what we're trying to do is essentially
the text
different type of arrhythmias by looking at the evolution of the heart as a function
of time and of course the test is just going to moving only according to
the breeding but the heart is moving complexlly according to a certain dynamic texture so
by applying essentially the same techniques for separating water
first small
one cannot separate the heart versus the rest and then by analyzing how they move
the term in certain
i read his
then i will talk about this editor but for those of you
finished around this
learning algorithms
you mention this perceptron
which i said that
quite simple
on one side but on the other side is very efficient
and then we saw these them all
support vector machines
going to the results of this learning curve maybe just briefly mention
so part of every scientific
work or even commercial work is also the revelation and also in text mining and
related fields we have a couple of very standard evaluation measures like probably you had
already for this name so precision recall accuracy and f f measure so they would
normally appearing
of scientific papers and instead of going out to the formula maybe just the intuition
behind this
formulas so precision is basically
measuring the truth while recall is measuring the whole truth so
michael mccord whole truth the hotels and physically
precision recall means how much the through so how much
of everything what's out there through
right recover accuracy
it's very simple
measure so
just the proportion of right stuff versus everything as it's not used often and f
measure is just a combination due general geometric mean between through some the whole truth
between precision and recall so
we one go here too much into the details but these are four standard measures
and the higher they are the better they are
OK not not just think you're more words about the learning so
very standard datasets of india evaluating
machine learning algorithms on taxes is this so-called writers dataset we are categorizing that documents
set of hundred twenty that categories and so these are some of these categories or
acquire corn and so on and these are just so we have two datasets one
something over twenty thousand documents beak and the other one is a kind of thirty
thousand documents and business leads document has zero one or several of these labels and
machine learning task is to
make model which
science this labels back the documents
so that was the message here so here i want to show
three algorithms which we mention so support vector machine perceptron small algorithm which showed before
and we know which is equally small and very efficient algorithm which is used also
by many companies section instead of SVM where we try to
categorize text
on this small writers domain
here we see
so SVM perceptron and winnow and here we use different representations of the document so
the message here is seated between SVM is the most advanced methods and let's say
perceptron which is just a small town lines of code is very small and we
know is a little bit less if you apply
a couple of very small improvements on the perceptron and know then they practically equal
and this is this is what is the message for machine learners and they all
use linear so SVM
this linear linear kernel
a rather simple scenario which is
as i said quite efficient
in other categorisation task which is similar to the one we chose just showed this
categorization IN tool
in two
subject higher here we don't have just the
least of categories into which we would like to see
categorized document but we have a large hierarchy of
categories and so i will
actually i will make them all here is keep a couple of slides
so if
you might be aware of this the most higher here the moss is the largest
higher he on the that which was made more less in these two point zero
point zero partial but it's all it has over six hundred thousand categories so this
is the three
which has six hundred thousand categories top-level you have something like twenty categories but then
when you go into these categories but if you go into a science
then we would get another new categories and if get to agriculture then this will
be further on so on
OK so what's important is that we have six hundred thousand categories not just like
hundred twenty years before and fuel
million websites which are mainly categorized into this six hundred thousand competitors now what we
would like to do
here is to build a classifier
which with the new which would take taken new document and classified
into the right spot to this
make huge three
and basically
we did this we use just
the nearest neighbour nothing special
and it works quite well and i will demonstrate how this works
i have it here on the local machine
hope still works so
here we based represen documents into this small window and press submit and then we
get categories here i prepared so
and coming from this
joseph stefan institute slovenia
and let's say we can take the
english description of our institute
small argument
this is just a few lines of text
and we try to categorize categorize this
in two d moss into the most science park because it wouldn't fit the whole
classified fit this notable press submit
and you get the categories from the moss
are apparently the most relevant ones so this is science science society academic departments or
science institutions research institute so which is exactly what we actually want to happen
environmental organisations research institutes and so on and so these are the actual categories that
test point
but of course this
cannot be computed because we don't know the distribution we can only approximated then usually
natural way to approximate this quantity is
given your training sample compute the average
on this training sample
so you have the x i y i compute these for i from one to
n the average and this is called the empirical
so the eighty will be true
this quantity
its empirical estimate
and of course we know
i mean it's a simple fact that the expected value
this empirical error
is equal to the loss
but here
becareful we'll see in a minute why this is dangerous statement it
this is true when g
is if fixed function
so it will no longer be true when g
it depends on the sample so when you have if you put here you classifiers
the function output by your training algorithms
this will no longer be true
OK so now
i have put here in the in these two slides
a couple of
kind of a very basic but
useful tools
are inequalities that come from basic probability theory
what i can
propose you is too
try to think about how you would prove these results
most of them can be proved quite directly
so if you want i can lead to some say five minutes to think about
it and then i can i give you the
the answer to just
because then in paper in
try to prove the things
OK this this does not require proof and we
this one but those two and this one
and i recall what we know about probabilities are
probability of something larger than zero
the probability of
so at each event is a subset
of this
everything and you know it
this is one
and the probability of the union
the sum minus the intersection
OK maybe a bit trivial
so if we look at the first one is of course from what i've written
well usually
this is not
fatalities so when you write it like this direct
it will be these combining these and non negativity
for this one
so anyone has
the proof
OK so inclusion sorry
the implication here is synonymous for inclusion so it means
eight is the subset of b
the four
and the thing and then i'm going to this picture which talks about the types
of learning techniques that have been used in the learning problems that have been looked
at and i was going to spend a lot more large one of them learning
such control
then talk about learning domain models and then finally talk about learning strategies
i i think i missed the flight here but i want you to remember in
your head that slide that i showed you earlier which said that basically mention this
point earlier it said that as impressive as the domain independent learners one and in
fact you know what our discussion i just complicated now
explain how we got from sorry looking graphs too much happier looking graphs in that
no importance like video having munich airport and then i also said that from the
munich airport graph you also have planners if you allow people to write
the main knowledge as to extract the in knowledge about fundamental physics this seems to
be good at writing all sorts of nifty knowledge
this the plan is that it will be used to
in competitions
even with even bigger margins than the very best domain specific domain independent and so
now if you're learning
that's good news to you because all you interested in is eliminating humans from the
without respect and so if people are writing this externality we want to lobotomized them
and stuff like that so that we don't need them anymore and you know so
they give you
the problems that the learning can
i basically getting into that by first talking to you about knowledge based planning track
and what kinds of knowledge people rule for these plants
that gives you an idea as to what being successful so you know those are
the kinds of things you might want
OK one thing ali told you for example you know figuring out many a heuristic
is actually underestimating and remembering of learning what it is it looks like a nice
idea i sort of thought that actually that works quite well so there are other
types of
a hand according to my knowledge which seems to work even better so i want
to give you some
i feel but how these sorts of knowledge
OK and then we can spend time talking to learn
OK so this whole thing sort of comes from the point of view of a
but looking at these two pictures which is the acme of what was planned which
are little requires is domain physics a bunch of actions schemas
and that's all it requires and it takes the initial state of problem articles another
problem spew of solutions this is domain independent planning so i think it's about is
the physics of the domain and make up the lands
the other extreme is sort of writing it separates the program for each possible landing
would you have so if your life depends on your bosses you know you're in
your cell is completely dependent on how fast you can do blocks planning i would
recommend that you don't planning just try to see program you know that that in
fact i don't know there are people who have look exactly at this point in
john slaney has looked at how fast can you do blocks planning if you want
to write
the best seat following
OK it's an interesting thing to do and so these would be
unabashedly domain specific so each time you get to the main you write c program
OK that's not very very obviously
in the community i'm planning somehow
you are much more interested in the domain independent in all but if the problem
i think is the program somewhere doesn't have anything FEEIT
OK it turns out that there is a happy middle ground village easiness innocence given
a domain and given a plan and a new domain
OK rather than sport
looking at the domain and spotlighting useit program what i was our what you could
do is you start with a customizable plan which is a domain independent planning
it would work even if you don't give it an extra knowledge
the island acquired system in physics
if you give it more and more static knowledge about how to find plans
then they could do better
so think of it as in expertise solution
OK so
this is sort of any expertise solution if you have more expertise i'll give you
plans faster if you know what expertise than just the main physics i still do
the best we can withstand domain independent
OK so
in many thinking about knowledge base plan is this is the picture you have in
mind the real question is very the domain specific knowledge coming
OK it could come
but from humans
which is what we talk about fast because the knowledge planning track people actually wrote
OK and you could actually combine only you look at you analyse the plans in
this domain and then you figure out what's the best
what's the kind of knowledge to learn and add to your customers
OK so i was talking about this and then we'll talk about
OK so it's customers and almost in the beginning of repeating what i said earlier
so that movie itself customizing one is given by humans humans will customize the planners
and it turns out that they tend to customize in all sorts of interesting reflecting
different kinds of extra knowledge and it's just what looking at the types of money
doing the right
and in particular see that they might extract the collective knowledge
which is just specific domain and has nothing to do with the planet they can
write procedural knowledge which is sort of
almost going to the extreme of writing and that the program acceptance of i didn't
see light and some high-level language
OK so
that's basically much more of a procedural control for that domain and people have done
both of these
OK and then we'll see how about the possibility of doing it is through machine
learning and we can learn how many of these sorts of things and i likely
to give you an idea of some of them which are the ones with
and which if you are interested you can go on
and if in a couple of all
OK so this is a more recent development
and that has shown to improve generalisation performance of the models one
OK this some work that you can look at you
kid to download my presentation point
the which
OK so i'm doing time was
the rest is really no so
it doesn't take that much of the time what i'd like to show you now
different variations around this idea so the first thing is
well if you extract these concepts right shouldn't these concepts some also help you in
supervised learning task for instance in text categorisation
and here most text categorisation algorithms like
k nearest neighbors and also adaboost text system whereas the end
they usually are based on the just the term based representation right
but the question is if i can extract these nice concept somehow can i can
exploit this also to improve text categorisation and what we do here this is the
next was the people
basically combine adaboost
two different versions of that
where we use weak learners
you know the set of all hypotheses
consisted of two different type of simple hypothesis one is just an indicator function for
term features
so it's whatever minus one the terms not present in document otherwise it's one
and the other one what we did is we would run
this problem probabilistic latent semantic analysis
over the over the whole document collection
and that would give us these
concept probabilities for every document
right and we would take that as a kind of representation for the document that
and we just
you know you very simple
the indicator function here we have some threshold that we also optimize over
beta where we said well the probability is below that right and some of the
document is not on the concepts of minus one
so we have these very simple functions
and what we do now is we combine them using out
it's just standard
just show you that experimentally
you know you can
can gain by doing that so this is on the
i don't want to get too much into the details of the
the experimental setup the the
well known writers twenty one thousand something
dataset and you know
census taker paper you know reduced
one thousand different metrics and thousand different set of what but this is just showing
improvement in terms of
f one measure in the average precision
four you know micro and macro averaged depends on how you treat the different ways
to different categories and you see that you get some improvement
very consistent that's not what i mean
it's not revolutionary
but it's it's solid improvement across the board and also we looked at more interesting
data datasets this now is the subset of the medline collection
fifty thousand something edits datasets the ottoman
dataset and and we see here improvement in average precision around relative improvement of about
to get an estimate good enough to get a certain accuracy of the expectation
of random variables the number of samples is completely independent of the number of values
and variable can take
and it's just an idea
exploited industry
and that's that's how it's it's speeding cars to measure
OK and the and the current state of the art algorithms are inspired by UCT
which are much cleverer than this the foundational idea they decide much more cleverly which
actions to explore which one's not
but but but the underlying idea is this
so i'm going to talk lots of
lots of nice results and applications available reinforcement learning but
all of them
you know the state space you know the action space you know the reward space
what i'm interested in
what what drives my interest these days has been for a while but for the
near future is
trying to build flexible intelligent
i systems
that's how it connects to cognitive science because the the example of the flexible intelligence
are animals and human things
if you're doing narrow and you're doing now is a pejorative work now just means
you particular problem you want to make a helicopter flight you want to schedule you
know the trucking companies
she you know trucks you want to solve a specific engineering problem you know the
state space because thousands of person is referred to as input into figuring out what's
good state is one of the good representation of actions forty objectives were the reward
you know
great we have good methods for not off the shelf but
pretty good methods for solving that class
those types of problems if on the other hand if you are interested in flexibly
i these are rarely given
right now
so if on the other hand you are you magically get hardware for android
you log deal with amazon com any or a household robot that is going to
be a companion in
what is going to be state space
how to represent his actions what reward function should have was on the program into
into that robot
maybe i was on the reward function should be don't come back but you know
come back to that
OK so back that brought these questions are much trickier now
and those are the questions i want to give you one
the basic idea of our
three to those questions for the for the rest of the rest
so this is my tutorial if anybody has questions about this part
along with that tag twenty five
a question about sport yes
o thing
right so having defined flexible AI what that means exactly in opposition to
classical engineering look up control where they were very well defined problem and you can
take flexible AI in many different directions i'm define except the we're motivating these questions
or what the state space should be what the action space to be with reward
adjustable economy is an interesting approach that
agent people have
make progress on but
let me come back to that if in the end talk about what i'm not
much of the system so let's
let's hold off that maybe this time at the end we can we can improve
on this OK so
let's see i already said this is what should be
the state space for dog person what state space is not very clear like what
we know what perceptions are
we don't know what state spaces
in a way that's all symmetrisation is doing is formalising independence assumption
i mean just saying that the likelihood of
all of these things happening in the second half is well
but it's it's just four right
sounds good
so how many people have
succeeded in this
slide just put up
derivation here to show you how it works
so basically your setting that
two to minus epsilon and over two equal to delta over two BH and
take logs to base two on both sides
and through life through by minus and you get epsilon over to here
and log of the
inverse ratio here two bhm delta that's because of the minus going through the log
then you put epsilon is two over
and substituting in so should be to ensure that should be too
should be too
and then substituting in cellars lemon
well firstly separating this is the logo of the product into the sum of the
two logd log two over delta and log ph brand and then subst
substituting in the cell bound which is the
two EMI over del over data the taking log that the d comes down and
you get d log
two you and over d
so again it's just to manipulation of the
of the formulae
as everyone happy with that
OK i just want to give you a chance to
chosen because around so there it is
so what that tells you this is if you like the
central result of learning theory in some sense
so i
there doesn't hurt
it says
we have
but the formulas we so with probability at least one minus delta
if you the generalisation error of a function h in the class h
with these dimension d
which has zero training error is bounded by the following quantity
two over and
d the VC dimension log two you know the delta plus log two delta
so no it is again the same form we've been seeing coming out repeatedly
the inverse
dependence on n
so as the training set size goes up you're getting decrease in the training error
the log two of the delta the
delta coming in very benignly under the log
in this case is locked the base to science natural others i remember
not much in it
and now this complexity term which if you remember before we had logged one over
and where we chose this prior sort of
weightings of the
the functions
has is replaced by this uniform turn
which is equal for all functions
and it's d log two m over d
so you can think of d in some sense measuring the complexity of the function
so the VC dimension is some nice measure the function class
and notice that the
polynomial growth we had directly translates into this logarithmic growth here
in in the sample size and we're setting that against the inverse and which is
what is controlling
generalisation error so provided we
take a sufficiently large sample
this is going to be
dominated by this and this is already quite small
and we're going to get a good bounds on the generalization
if on the other hand we deployed
result where
we still had exponential growth
in the
growth function
then this would have been log of two to be
two and
take the log of that and you just have to and and you get the
ems cancel and you get a trivial bound
seem to need that
significant decay of the growth function below the exponential growth in order to get
and effective
so this is you know say was was heralded as a very sort of
key result and it it's very nice in the sense that characterizes learning in the
following sense that there are lower bounds
again i'm not going to go into the process these but there are lower bounds
that say that
given a class of VC dimension d
there exist distributions
such that with probability at least delta over m random examples the error of h
is at least this quantity
so it's it's sort of like
in inverse in the sense that it says
you know there are cases in which you can do is roughly is bad i
mean OK there's a lot of factor missing here but in a lot of factors
between learning theorists don't count for much
so there is the the log to anybody here
and here this is the cover and
but the constants are a bit different and st
but apart from that i mean this is very very close
so in a sense what this is telling us is that the VC dimension is
the right characterisation of learning in this in this classification sense
so it's a very nice close theory in that sense it all looks very beautiful
the corresponding results for non zero training which again i mean the techniques are very
are very short millisecond in the case of the
one that bounces back one millisecond indicates that once that one clunk
and the average
it's about five hundred fifty times
their normal weight
i'd like to show you
fast photography
on not these very same ball with on another one that we did
let me take this
this out
that is the ball that comes down
with the speed of four meters per second
and each train is one millisecond
so you will see a rule
and the ruler indicates has marked in centimetres
so you will see it going for
seconds it will go one centimetre
so it has the speed of two and a half meters per second it will
hit the floor and then we can count the number of milli seconds that it
takes contact
and going back up again it's not going to be too many second it's a
bit longer but again impressively short
all right we're going to make it rather dark in order to get
decent quality
i'm going to turn
five of these off
and i'm going to set the TV two
and now i will start to this
there we go
let's hope that that will go
OK that comfortable down
these marks are
in centimetres
so it is a rule in centimetres
this is one centimeter
a reminder little
because we
well little too late
let's start again
so what
when it passes this mark one
see for many seconds for about one centimeter
two and a half meters per second novel count the number of seconds
and in fact
and it's of about six maybe seventy seconds
this no special ball
these impact times are
amazingly short
now have something
very special
something really special
something that has kept me awake a lot of things keep me awake physics and
not only in physics
but this
but this is very special
this is very special
i have here a basketball
not completely elastic but not bad
tennis ball
not completely elastic not bad
now i'm going to drop them together
vertically down
and then
this ball
will bounce up somehow
and so the question that i have for you is
so you think if i drop it from this height
that this tennis ball
well sort of come up at most to this high to do you think it
will be lower
think it will be
so usually intuition in the worst case it can be wrong is already pushing this
so what do you think
well the tennis ball reach about the same height who is in favor of that
was in favor of
while i was in favor of a lot time
OK yeah i'll try it now
i cannot guarantee that this ball will go straight up after the impact because clearly
it's impossible that has zero chance of probably go off at some direction
but you will see
the fact that i had in mind
so there we go
you see that indeed tennis ball
goes way i tried once more to see what i can get it
go up a little bit more vertically with that is very difficult
it goes way high
and this is something that you should be able to calculate
you can you will
believe this part of the simon number sixty haven't seen it yet
there we go
what does matter
and you know anyone of you know approximately how much higher it goes invisible is
way higher mass than this one because the mass ratio comes into it
any ideas
prices high
you'll be surprised when he resigned six
what's hard
OK for thank you could even see if he always there was quite a bit
higher than twice
great great experiment in something you can do
the self geometry
now i want to discuss the remaining time about rockets
a rocket
experience an impulse
from the engine
and that changes the momentum
the rocket
before we go into the details of the rocket
think about gandhi's ideas of throwing objects on the floor
and that's turned to tomatoes
i want to made because i want to complete inelastic collisions
so tomatoes hit the floor
it's not that i not only going to throw one made on the floor but
i'm very angry today i'm going to a lot of these tomatoes on the floor
and as in nancy tomatoes on the floor
if one of the major hits the floor
the change in momentum is envy if m is the mass of the tomato
but i'm going to throw and on the floor
so to change of momentum
is an as in nancy
times the mass of the
you may know
and this
is the number of kilograms per second
after may know that i throw on the floor
so this is
the change of momentum
so this is called delta p
dividing by delta t
and that's an average force
real experience
the force in down direction
of course that was also the case here when the ball experience
four supt
which we calculated here
the from our experience of course the same force in down direction actually act action
equals minus reaction newton's third law
so the force experiences the different experiences a force in down direction
and i can write it down
in a somewhat more civilized four
f equals
the NDT
times the velocity
if the velocity of the tomatoes it hit the floor
o is constant
and we're going to apply these rockets were by exhaust out of rockets as relative
to the rock at constant speed
and this is then
number of kilograms per second
i threw on the floor
this is very real
i can throw his tomatoes on a bathroom scale
and if i through four kilogrammes per second on a bathroom scale
and it's the bathroom scale was five meters per second you better believe it you
will see
see also we can we can solve problems like this one so here's that means
that i that i showed before
we gave a chinese restaurant process prior over the MDP so we basically said that
states can cluster we don't know exactly how many clusters there are there may be
one as many clusters are states in the environment but that's unlikely to probably clustering
together and we let it run environment we don't see the wall switches but see
what i mean this state here's what i was what happened when i was there
and i was this takeover happened i was there they may be the same so
the chinese restaurant prior let's those kind of cluster together empirically
and ends up four outperforming algorithm that
streets of state separately and outperforms an algorithm that assumes all states have the same
cluster which is incorrect assumption so caustic can do well but it basically it figures
out the number of clusters that are there learned about
and better about the states this it's often you can if you the colors to
represent the state question you can see some of them are not quite the right
color but enough the right column
OK it's it's enough right color that
that the behaviour that comes out of this is what you what you hope
that's kind of cute
we're still working on that there's various difficulties in in using big complicated bayesian reasoning
algorithms in the context of the sort of thing
OK so next change gears is to talk a little bit about the fact that
computation matters so
what talk about so far is that in the in the model based setting if
you have the right model class for the environment we have various kinds of you
know quickly found type algorithms that can quickly acquired transition models
and then we hit with the planning systematic planning stack
and then we behave nearly optimal the thing is that the magic planning stack is
much heavier than you might think when you first see it lying on the ground
this is even planning is just a computational problem it's not a learning problem you
we're treating it as an oracle actually leads to
solutions to problems that we've looked at that you can't really run it just is
too slow to do the planning
especially the more powerful the german generalization is in the learning the bigger the model
is that we can learn the less likely it is that we can plan and
so we've got to do something about these large models otherwise these great things that
we're learning our users we can use them to make decisions in the world
what does the bunch ways people are doing this i'm going really not do it
justice and i apologize by
but i give you the high level view see is a highly i talked about
three different classes of reinforcement learning approaches policy search research policy value function search try
q function and model based we learn the model and then playing with the model
what turns out that this plan with the model things really expensive so what can
you do what thing you can do is say well model
it's kind of like an environment
and so
we could just make use any reinforcement or we want as a learner for that
now it's a fake environments learning environment but you know if we can learn them
efficiently and we can learn to accurately then that's OK
so if learning if reinforcement learning is more efficient than planning
then we can put a policy search algorithm inside model based algorithms to learn the
model and then playing with it by pretending its environment and reinforcement learning we can
put a value function methods inside model based method to learn the model
and then pretend the models environment and use value function learner to actually decide what
to do
it seems so crazy just might work right so in cases where we can do
efficient policy search value function search with the kinds of models we learned this can
work really well one thing i didn't put up here is you learn the model
and then inside user model based learner for the reinforcement learner that somehow seems like
an infinite regress that that's meaningful haven't seen anybody do that in the literature that
i wouldn't be surprised now somebody
because it does that just to screw up my figure
so that's the basic idea and this is a very natural way for cannot see
ideas to fit with model based reinforcement learning is just use your favourite regression algorithm
to represent the transition function used the transition function the simulator and run your favourite
reinforcement learning algorithm on that to decide what to do
so this is the idea that actually goes way back i think it's in many
ways but under explored but i found in the first place i ever saw it
was in a paper by markets in charlotte that instance based models for control where
they say we can learn this problem which we now know as mountain car but
at that time they called bead on a wire
but i think they created the problem in that paper where you have to exert
force to get your car to go up to the top of the hill but
it's really high hill so you actually have to drive backwards get some momentum going
on and then come up to the top and a show that you can actually
k times t even now compare that with the general way the general equation as
follows at that yellow boxes over the standard linear form
how are they going to compare well
this is about 30 general function this is general a general function of the you
know I can make the external temperature
I can suppose it behaves in any way I like steadily rising decaying exponentially maybe
oscillating back and forth for some reason
the only way which is not general is that if K is a constant so
I will ask you to
we it let's imagine the conductivity is changing over time so this is usually constant
but there is no which says it has to be
how good conductivity change over time well we could suppose for example that the
so we can suppose that this was made of slowly congealing jails for instance you
know starts out as liquid that gets solid in the jell-o gel doesn't transmitting a
I believe quite as well as as a liquid diet as liquid is jealous solid
or liquid oxygen and once you about that
so with this understanding but so let's not necessarily
but not necessarily all I can think of this therefore by allowing can vary with
time and the external temperature vary with time I can think of it as a
general linear equation
so these models are not special shared fairly general
I did promise you won't solve an equation that this lecture I still have not
solved any equations OK
time to start temporizing and solve so I'm going to in order not to play
favorites with these 2 models all go back to and to get used to thinking
of new variables all the time that is not uh the eclectic switching from one
variable to another according to which a particular lecture you happened to be sitting here
and so let's take our equation in the form of why prime plus P of
X Y with general form using the old variables equal to Q of X solve
me well there are different ways of describing the solution process no matter how you
do it amounts to the same amount of work and there's always a trick involved
in each 1 of them since you can suppress the trick by doing the problem
some other way
the way I'm going to do it I think this is the best that's why
I'm giving it to you at least 2 it's easiest remember the least word but
by and colleagues who would fight with me on that point so since they are
not fight with me I am free to do whatever I like
1 of the main reasons is that
of doing it the way I'm going to do is because I want you to
get 1 lowered into your conscience attach consciousness and that's the word or 2 words
integrating factor
I'm going to solve this equation by finding an integrating factor of the form U
of X
was integrating factor well
show you the not by writing elaborate definition on the board which show you what
its function is it's a certain function of X I don't know what it is
but here's what I wanted to do I want to
multiplying under drop the axes of just so that the thing looks less complicated so
what I wanna do is multiply this equation ruled by U of X that's why
it's called the factor because you're going to multiply everything through by it so it's
gonna look like you why prime plus p
equals Q U
right now
this thing is so far it's just a fact what makes it integrating factor is
that this after I do that I want this to turn out to be the