when when when I have a regular network
my clustering coefficient is lar large, for example
in things like this, right, there are there are there are the triangles
and as the network gets gets a more random, the triangles disappear and this gives you a nice way, how to interpo interpolate between something really
regular and something really random
so this is
what I want to show, but there is a but to this model and the but is are
the power-law degree distributions, right, so the heavy tail degree distribution we know that
here all the nodes have the same degree distribution on this side again
the degree distribution is concentrated at the mean, right, here we have a
a poisson degree distribution end, but what we saw before is that in real life they are power-laws
so how do we get to power-laws
and I guess
that you all heard
of the of the first model that
sort of started it all, it was called preferential attachment
by barabasi
and the idea was that
so if you think how how how
say how do people behave how cita how how are citations added to the papers, right, it turns out that
I don't know you start and you want to write a paper then what turns out is that the probability that you're yo that some paper will get a new citation is proportional to the number of citations is it already has, right, so this is something that is called rich get richer, so the more citations you have, the more li the more likely you are to get a new citation, so so this is here is what we mean by that, right, and you know a new node will come and it will create M out-links
and now
all we say is what is the probability of linking to a node with particular degree is just proportional to the degree, right, I'm just like normalizing the sum of all the all the degrees, right, and this is based on a herbert simon's result where he called this cumulative advantage or rich get richer and the whole thing was observed in nineteen sixty-five where where they
where people measured that that the number of new citations the paper gets it is proportional to the number it already has, right, and this is this is exactly what what the formula says so and what turns out is that this
rich get richer
preferential attachment type of process will give you power-law degree distributions with exponent minus three
so there is still a problem with this mo this model that all the nodes have been constant out degree, right, because the way the model specifies it says a node comes
and it will create M edges, now it needs to find targets for these edges and the way it finds the targets is that every node the probability of being selected is proportional to the number of edges it has
but what is nice is that just this simple process
gives you gi gives us the way that this large-scale property like the the the the power-law degree distribution emerges
again there's, so as I said, in in preferential attachment all the all the nodes have the same out degree, so here is a way
to to create power-law in degree and out degree distributions and also a way how to generate communities, right, as we said in in graphs, there's usually at least in social networks alright there is this notion of communities where communities are more densily linked
inside the and they are sparsely linked to the rest of the graph, right, and
a way, how to think about this
is the edge copying model
by kleinberg from ninety-nine
and the idea is the, again, we have a network and a new node comes to it
and so the
that's just group is big
we have this
i see
you might see
and was a semiring
might seem like
season one
the some
see what was
so that
so your
you seem like this
my see
this formulation
again going from the the US right
and i'm going to show
then you get something that's
this expression
we we're going to
it might seem like
this is
the humility right down the line and then we'll discuss it in
so let me rephrase it so what you see is that if you use
if you
x minus to plus and you subtract x minus the mind think about when is
this function positive with eventually this part is bigger than the other one which means
if the point is further away from the positive and then from the negative zone
so maybe it's not the other way around
so i
that's right
up to you
this section on the talk about whatever
what of the
design changes
so i
and the difference between
c one
minus one
i that's
i think of this is in boldface x that is using
which at the top of the site is used as the
shorthand by it's a little bit confusing so all these vectors are already living in
the feature space that is using
it right first
does was my
and we have to
one year
here we
see what does it mean to see my doctor
in this this
as this
the was
darcy true
and plus
and then some ideas
so we can
it is the sequel
so what
i see my thoughts in mind
the signs again i just one
thank you very much
different from what i expected but it also shows that the two formulations are the
so it counts solution
yes he's using some linear algebra just to show that the one formulation that i
was suggesting originally
here with the dot product in the distance formulations of the same of course i
guess some of you may have just
use this formula the starting point in directly plugging things
and then
that so we get to the solution here
so maybe
maybe i'll just briefly into it so that those people can also double checked that
i did things correctly but
meanwhile maybe right down to solve the the problem
for name
OK so one point for patrick
maybe also one point for the guy who notice the sign change
and so
will be wearing the yellow jersey tonight
OK so that the discrete do it the other way
so if we if we directly use this formulation
so just ignore all this in between
and directly plug it in
so this is the dot product between
this vector and itself OK
c minus
the sum of all my negative points very and one over and two
OK so
if d is measured in very large units
then the size of the neighborhood is essentially k equals one and if t is
measured very small units and averaging over one
but it will never be of course equivalent to k nearest neighbour
so now the idea is to learn the metric by adjusting these these to maximize
its expected performance
and having done the simplest thing that could possibly do for the objective function i'm
now going to do the simplest thing i could possibly do for the model
so the simplest thing you could possibly do is just measure the distance between two
points x i and x j
by putting a positive semi definite matrix in
so just go gaussians or quadratic metric
q is some symmetric
positive semi definite matrix and we're going to rewrite this distance using the square root
of q
so i just replaced q with eight transpose a there's many ways to do this
they are unique
any the square root of q will make the point here what is the distance
turn out to be the distance turns out to just be euclidean distance
in some transformed space
so you can imagine is that i just found the transformation a
after which
the right distance metric to use is just euclidean distance
so you can summarize everything i told you so far by the following find me
a linear transformation of the original data
so that when i look in that linear transformation and i do the euclidean k
nearest neighbour things worked out well
as estimated by
leave one out cross validation or soft versions
OK the questions
with me
that's bust-up
this in regression this would be very close to parzen window
with the exception of this normalisation is sort of point
in the
so you can think of this as sort of stealing the bandwidth trick from density
estimation and trying to make it work for classification
OK so
this is probably
too many equations on one slide but i just want to make a point here
because you on touched on i think it's very very crucial if you just do
what i told you
you're going to end up with an algorithm is quadratic in the number of data
and that's probably gonna make you unhappy
so i'm going to try and tell you a little bit about how to approximate
or sample to get around so here it is this is the expected classification performance
so this is the average over all data points of the chance of getting that
data point correct and the leave one out scheme
OK so we take the derivative of this with respect to the distances
where the distances are defined like this what we're really taking the derivative with respect
to the transformation so adjusting the linear transformation
so that the expected performance is
now if you write down this expression for the gradient the exact expression it sort
of quadratic
you have to some of all the data points because each data point contribute to
gradient term and in order to compute the gradient term of that data point exactly
you need to consider the other datapoints first the ones in your class and then
the ones not in your class
OK so it would be quadratic if you did
there's two observations here why this is just gradient descent
so we don't really care about the exact gradient right it's not a holy artifact
it's just the gradient we're just going to take it and adjust their parameters and
drop it on the floor
so we don't really need the gradient to be right we just need to be
sort of right in fact we don't even need to be sort of right which
is not needed to be not ninety degrees wrong
OK so just subsample here just grab a few data points used to estimate the
gradient nature parameters and started that would be fine
i want to
stochastic gradient optimisation perfectly legit OK the observation is that in these interiors sometimes you're
weighting the other data points so
it appeared back here on the screen
OK good
i guess
the penalty for spending too long in the slide
so you're weighting the other data points and there waiting no by
neighborhood selection probability and most of these probabilities are almost zero
right i have my little neighborhood my friends were around me and the probability of
picking someone all the way over there is basically zero so you don't need to
go through all these painful calculations you can keep inactive list of who's really ineffective
neighborhood domain and then update that active list every few hundred iterations when you return
to the premier so there are some tricks for approximation you don't want to get
into them but if you just write down this equation it looks pretty nasty
so this is the the algorithm the first one that i want to tell you
about it called neighbourhood components analysis so was in a couple of years ago
it learns a linear transformation of the input space after which nearest neighbour performs well
so the transformation intuitively scales up directions which are useful for discrimination and tries to
project out dimensions which are not informative about class
and the algorithm is very simple
right down this objective function
and optimize that kind of
and then you are you take this that you want a new project training set
into that
new feature space so for every training point exile you create a new training point
why i by multiplying by this transformation and then you put the line rises as
the training data a four-year-old k nearest neighbour code
and at test time when you get a new test point you also multiplied by
eight to get into the right test space and then you present that y test
here consider really even have to write any new code for test
so if you have kd trees and fancy data structures LSH that does you no
retrieval for the neighbours and stuff you can
using maximum likelihood
parameter on the inverse covariance matrix with an l one penalty
on the on the inverse covariance there it is of the year
so this is
this is a p by p covariance matrix and we put in our one penalty
on all the
all the parameters and the covariance matrix
and this is just
the partially maximise log likelihood for the gas in models
and it turns out
if you do blockwise coordinate descent
you've got to p by the covariance matrix solving for
a whole column of coefficients at the time it turns out
solving that amounts to a kind of
let's two regularisation problem
so it's like a lasso regression problem and you can exploit coordinate descent so this
too many details to go into
but again we can do that very efficiently
and we can compute the whole path
as we vary lambda
so for example
we can solve moderately sparse graphs
with a thousand nodes in under a minute
and i'll give an example now
this is a small problem eleven proteins
measured on seven thousand
training observations
and so you know the graphical models you see the land is written about the
when lambda zero
land easier over the it's and and
every year
it's unregularized fit so there is an edge between every protein
and then as you ramp up lambda
the graph gets more sparse sparser and sparser
so we can compute the whole path of solutions very efficiently
the group lasso that's
one and may invent again
two different groups
and others have worked on it too
so each in that case each of the terms
the penalty is referred to sets of parameters
and you don't have one norm have some of our two norms
and so this term over year is actually the l two norm of the vector
of coefficients so that the variables are arranged in groups and each group has a
set of linear coefficients
and we we penalize
the vector of coefficients for each group with an l two norm
no it is not l two squared it's just too
and what that does is it tends to select the whole group of variables or
leave it out
and if they in the or nonzeros
and that's useful for example if you fit in linear models with categorical predictors
with multiple levels and you represent each of those
by dummy variable saliency of a group of coefficients you want at home
categorical variables in or out of the model
with all of its coefficients
and coordinate ascent very useful for solving that problem
something that we worked on a few years ago
stands for comparative genome hybridisation modelling
and we use we introduced well to and colleagues introduced something called the fused lasso
so there
in this particular example
the coefficients actually former time series so they arranged a lot of time series series
in genome order
so these enabling this notion two coefficients
so we've got a penalty that patients take the coefficients to zero
and also constraints
neighboring coefficients to be the same
so trying to encourage piecewise
in fact
and yes the solution to get out
again we use a coordinate descent method to solve the problem
in this paper
the website on that
so finished
so in summary then l one regularisation variance has become a powerful tool with with
the advent of wide data
infinitely down to try and make it work but never works
but if you do the outer apply this and you find that when using in
zero one
then you get this nice function here
so does anyone recognise this function here
someone said entropy
and that is entropy that's entropy for bernoulli random variables
it's actually negative entropy to be to be exact
so it could be a general relation will see this what happens is entropy comes
out here
and in some other cases you get plus infinity
there's another thing you should think about this is going to be relevant later
if you think about mu belonging to zero one
right that's exactly the sort of set of possible probabilities that a coin flip can
the probability that the coin is heads can be anywhere between zero and one
but it can't be outside that interval
and that's not a coincidence the fact that this guy is is nicely behaved where
the coin flipping makes sense that mu is between zero and one it makes sense
and the fact that plus infinity if the coin flip doesn't make sense
that's not a coincidence that's going to come up with a bit more generally later
OK so any questions about
this basic concept is to duality as we discussed analytically here
and we looked at it geometrically
and now we've just on this particular example to a simple example would actually captures
a lot of the intuition of the general case
sure you all how
and yes
how do i feel all
right so i didn't say that i said that that is always convex
with no restrictions on that
but when f is well behaved
and well behaved means convex and lower semi continuous
you're correct if i start with the non convex function
i can't somehow
take the dual twice and get a convex function back that's the that's the same
so it's sort of key
we're going to be applying this always one f is convex to start with
this is just a somewhat technical condition that they're interesting behave well the boundary we
won't worry about that here but that's a good question
any other questions
OK so
so this example we did
actually illustrates a lot of the general principles
the more general of
for the general case exponential families
so let's go about doing this a bit more generally let's imagine that we have
an exponential family
and we're going to compute the dual of
cumulant generating function here
so this i already did a special case here i did the simple newly
and i did the cumulant generating function not going to do it for
any exponential family
but the principles are going to be the same if you understand the case what
i'm doing is destroying it with more abstract notation
so i definition tells us to go off and solve this optimisation problem
and we follow the same steps we take derivatives
in order to try and find stationary point we get new
and the derivative of this guy should be equal to zero this is a sort
of key equation
OK so
he is a very useful fact
the fact is that the function a it's actually what's known as the cumulant generating
how many people have heard about moment generating functions and cumulant generating functions
OK so very few
how many people have heard of cumulants
again roughly the same number that called not heard of cumulants
OK so you understand
how many people moment
you all know moments are OK so humans are various combinations of moments
well go into details now but there are just two different sets of combinations of
and they have nice properties
for certain functions
what's important here is that this guy all we need to know is when you
take one derivative of it
what happens is is that you get what are known as mean parameters
and what these mean parameters are remember this guy
specified in terms of the sufficient statistics
so the main parameters are the expectations
of the sufficient statistic with respect to the distribution
so these are very important things like let me just jump back to our earlier
so we can see what what it means in this special case with bernoulli
just describe this the bernoulli case here because
so it's good concrete example to keep your
keep your mind on a special case we can think about is this for newly
and we saw that it's just the coin flipping random variable
x here was just zero and one
and we saw that this was the log normalisation constant had this form
and what we computed before
is we compute the gradient of this function
it was equal to this
even today over one policy to the data
but all i'm saying now is the following that
the only new thing i've said there is that in fact that derivative of the
until another critical voltage and falls again another tube going even brighter and this is
6 . 7 volts
I just for your information you look on the periodic table today and it turns
out that the ionisation voltage for mercury is about 10 . 4 10 . 4
is the ionisation energy so this is below the ionization energy
so what's going on here what they reason was that
they were exciting bound electrons with this mercury and furthermore
that there are critical voltages associated with critical energies conclusions there are quantized energy levels
within mercury which is to say that the war postulate of quantization applies not only
a 1 electron atom but it applies to multi electron atoms would have applies to
multi electron atoms does not mean applies to everything so they concluded from this experiment
quantization quantization of energy so quantization of energies of electrons in multi electron atoms
thank you
or model doesn't apply to multi electron atoms but the assumption that energy is quantizing
multielectron atoms is
the assumption of energy quantization extends to multi electron atoms so this is really really
good war was writing very very high but all the things come to an end
there are problems with the boar model to so now let's look at limitations wanna
look at limitations of the boar model limitations of more OK 1st of all there's
data out there there's data out there already 1st 1887 1887 Michaelson morally Michaelson morally
This work was distinguished by the fact that was done in the United States you
notice most of everything I've shown you up until now was done in Europe with
1 exception the Milliken experiment in Chicago everything else is European science but Michael had
immigrated to the United States and it was really really clever use a brilliant inventor
was doing military research for the Navy's back in the early 18 eighties he invented
the interferometry and he was the 1st to make accurate measurements of the speed of
light Michaelson interferometry and he was I hear eventually worked at the case School of
Applied Science in Cleveland which ultimately became Case Western Reserve University after a number of
transitions and he was working at case in Cleveland and
doing very very high and
Precision spectroscopy that was his 48 he was a brilliant experimentalists knew how to make
equipment that was highly accurate and what he found was that 1 of Armstrong's lines
the line the line associated with the transition 3 2
if you look really really carefully
angstrom made the measurements by looking at like hitting a photographic plate and that like
doesn't come down license shop there's a little bit of of
scattering the data so you get this
fact line but the positions of center-to-center underlines follow that set of 4
the numbers that we were looking at yesterday now and Michaelson did the work member
on stranded is experiments in 1853 Michaelson looks very very carefully and sees that it's
not 1 line but it's 2 lines to lines very close together
so the 3 2 line is in fact Dublin
it's a double that is to say 2 lines very very close together but from
a distance it looks like a line and then if you got really accurate instrumentation
discover that it's a double
that's a problem that's a problem because if you look at this term scheme here
if we got a Dublin it means that you got to different transitions so the
model was a goal from n equals 2 up to n equals 3 when you
fall from 3 back down to 2 you give off a photon and that photon
has a unique value of wavelength but they're measuring to but they're very close so
what that suggests is that maybe there are 2 levels they're really really close together
and sometimes the electron falls from the higher level and sometimes it falls from the
lower level but in any event there must be more than 1 level but very
close together sober is silent on the now the other possibility is that you know
to is the problem we don't know maybe there maybe there maybe this is got
to lies and this has what
so that's the point 1st of all by the way I'm Michaelson was awarded the
don't know
all right
you know
know it
at the time
nine thousand five
all aspects
for example
all right
the consequences of this
well the
on the other
this is
consequently the soccer ball the company
some of these are
because of the way
o who
if you are you
those who is the level world
the problem
what we
tomorrow the world
one of the problem
we have
the match
we're actually what are four
the knowledge that
our use of the the underlying yes one
everything except one
the world
we don't always
what is otherwise be resolved information
is not very
we are
and that verification
so we
one of them
o four one
but what
what i will say well the question was
i like
the you what to do or what or
there are three major
one is come on
transfer database
that is pretty fine
want to be able to
also known as
is something
the rest was really
u example
for example
you might ask
written like
in the beginning
for a long
if you like
the loss
what was
like like
all right
four to be able to around
if you ask what is the
number three
what want
or low-balled
if you are
there is something one can
the characteristics of war
we don't know that
the you know about it
you might might be able to learn
the number of players in the last five years
the first was
she was born
four were
born on player
well one
they don't want to be able to do something like the one
were four
because of its peculiar geometry
only one explanation
so to cyc recall
if you haven't found one
yourself here
let me first
come to is simple conclusion
and all of you must have come to that conclusion
that top when i showed it to you during my exam review
was spending for more than an hour
in fact it was spending the next day
energy has to come from somewhere
and so the only conclusion that you could have drawn that the energy came from
inside the box
there must be something inside the box clearly there must be a battery in that
and there is
it doesn't tell you how it works here
and i can assure you i can admit that it took me quite a while
before i fully understand
how it works
and i want to explain that to you
and then i will demonstrate it to you again
what it looks like
in the top itself
is a magnet
he was the top
north and south
and this is that pop
we rotating it was spending
inside the box
right at the centre of the box
is the solenoid
nine volt battery
inside the solenoid is also a little bit of irony
we have not
discuss that in our course it's not important forty explanation
related understand why there is also
so my review makes the magnetic field build from
this is right at the centre of the
of the little platform on which i was running this
concave platform
here is a little
best ignored so when the
but that's it
bonds is all
imagine for now that is rotating in such a way
at the north pole
is approaching
that's all i coming in from above
what's going to happen now
in this
so know it in this court
you're changing the magnetic flux through the surface of this course
and so
you're introducing
induced EMF
an induced currents
and this current
is sense by transistor which i have not reported here
and the transistor
throw the switch
and now
folks energy out of the battery
and runs current very high current through this
such that the top
the south pole
remember if you have a cordial
you're on current through here
you get the magnetic field
like so
in this case is the north pole
this because if you reverse the current
this is cells and this is more
the magnetic field that comes out there
is fanning out in all the erection three-dimensional
it's going like this
fanning out like this
so when it approaches
coral there is the change in
magnetic flux and this becomes itself
the north pole is being attracted
by the south pole and make you look at this from above now
the top scene from above spending in this direction
and that's a year is this coral
this is the north pole
this is the south pole
and i just discussed issue
the current is going to flow
from the battery
will make this is south of the current can only flow
in that call in one direction and that's just the way to design
one of the current goes it's always this becomes the south pole
the north pole is being attracted by the south pole
notice is going to be talked up
so far
so good
later in time
looking from above
the north pole of the year
and the south pole will be there is rotated a little bit further
and the
coral is here
now on the north pole is
o thing
it's receiving it's not approaching its receiving
this work remain the south pole
it would be disastrous because i was born in north pole that attracted to don't
want that
the transistor senses
the EMF
in the corals
it reverses direction it has to reverse direction
if the north pole comes then you may have is in one direction but when
the north pole of the EMF course goes into action
kind of reverse
so the transistor that it opens the switch
so there is no north pole here and there is no cycles
so thing starts to
go around further
what happens now in the south pole
OK here is the situation
at the south pole
is now approaching
OK so
can you hear me
OK so it's not exactly by compressed sensing this
lectures is more about an one minimisation and compressed sensing part of this
a much bigger story
so i'm going to try to give you an overview of an one minimisation
and its connections of course with compressed sensing and and sparse signal recovery in statistics
and so
before i begin i just want to start with very simple things just to show
that the l one norm is very different from the two norm and so
in many problems that we have to deal with in an applied science we wish
to solve x equals b
approximately so in many problems of course we have made a data matrix a which
is an by an
we can assume for example that we have more observations and variables so that we
have more columns and rows in this picture so that the system is what we
call overdetermined
and so on and so x equals b of course traditionally there's no solution there's
no solution except that x equals b because it's overdetermined
and so the way we approach this is by no minimisation and so of course
everybody is familiar with least squares and the squares we're going to try to fit
this kind of
model with is by finding that x that minimizes such that minimizes the distance to
be in l two sense
and i'm sure as you are and when you learn in regression least squares puts
a large weights on this
on on a very small weight on small residual says whenever b-minus axis small
you pay a very small way
and when the miners x is large up a very large
and i'm sure you've taken introductory classes in in in your question
which you know that the least squares line for example is very sensitive to outliers
because you you really do not want to see large residual
so the first idea to fit
data is to just minimize the least squares to solve the discrete problems and minimize
the distance between b and x in l two
something that happens actually is more natural would be to actually not minimize the sum
of squared residuals but rather the some
of the absolute values of the residual
and that would be minimizing the l one norm i assume that everybody is familiar
with the l one norm that is very important that you are
if not i will write it on the board so are the people who don't
know what is the one norm
everybody knows OK so you may want to minimize the
distance between b and the one sense now
so now you would want to minimize the sum of absolute values of the residual
and so this puts a much larger weight on small residuals and less weight on
the on larger residuals because now they are not squared anymore
OK so we have two proposals and it's
i'm using to note that historically
galson that class had long discussions about whether you should use l two and one
and since the nineteenth century at least gulls prevail
but what i want to show you in that they can read lead to very
different solutions qualitatively so here i'm going to make a random problems were enemies
five hundred so i have five hundred measurements and is one fifty some trying to
fit a hundred and fifty dimensional parameters and i'm going to make a random problem
and whether x minimizes scores
l two
the residual sum of squares of just the sum of the absolute values of the
residual i get very different results
so here's what i get if i minimize e
l two norm and here is what i get if i minimise the one norm
and you can see that it's not a question of whether we prefer l one
l two four physical philosophical reason it's just like the lead to very different answers
one particular aspect of the l one norm it that you see an enormous spike
had zero
which means that a lot of the residuals actually exactly zero
and so this is kind of
going back to thing that
the l one norm puts
a much very large weight on small residual is so large that it forces us
a lot of residuals to be actually
and you can prove it is not difficult that if you minimize your one
a lot of the residuals will actually be exactly
OK so but for the moment i want to is that we observe very different
and so
and they are both valid down on
philosophical ground and not sure why we should minimize l two norm another one or
perhaps because we have linear algebra
but other than that
here's another set another problem which we're going to be extremely concerned about in these
lectures which is it's a slightly different problems in the sense that now is the
system of linear equations is underdetermined so i wish to solve a x equals b
but now it has fewer rows and columns so there are many solutions in general
to the system
so i need to solve x equals b
but now i have fewer rows and columns of the matrix is is that
and so i have many solutions
and so we can discuss well if there's many solution we need to we're going
to need to pick one and so if you open the literature of people would
for example in the literature on inverse problems or even in statistics one with the
ridge regression and that we should pick the solution that has minimum to no minimum
so among all this
candidates x feelings the data be
the proposal would be to find that was minimum l two energy
another related proposal would be a very similar it says OK models this solution
satisfying aka x equals b
pick the one with minimum l one norm instead
right so this would say
minimize energy and this would say minimize it one norm
and again if we do this on the random problems
we get
very very different pictures so here is an underdetermined system of equations would have
two hundred fifty equations but an unknown vector of dimension one hundred i want to
make a random problems and when i look at the minimum energy solution and look
and how did i draw these well
guassian process is actually an infinite you know to prior on this infinite dimensional space
right but i just discretize this
between minus two into
i drew
but discretized into hundred bins and i drew one sample from hundred dimensional gaussians
which has one a hundred by hundred covariance matrix
this is one sample from a hundred dimensional guessing there's another sample another sample per
it's the vector is one hundred dimensional vector and i just want the elements of
the a hundred dimensional vector instead of labeling my
access to go from one two hundred and labeling my access to go from minus
the two
guassian process should not be harder to understand than multivariate calcium distribution
it's infinity in that
a it's a process
which means that
the it's
it's implicitly
it's sort of the limit of the gas in distribution as you take the dimensionality
to infinity if you now
sample in any finite number of points you get a multivariate gaussians
OK but i could have drawn the same thing
you know
grid that you know
discretizing this with a million
little steps right in with the look the same so imagine trying this discretizing with
a million with a billion and so on in the limit where you get is
a natural function
OK that's sort of what
the basic idea here is
you wouldn't really be able to sample from that because computationally would be really hard
to do
but it because you know you can
take determinant of and million by million matrix or something like that
i mean we can draw anything on the discrete digital computer we can try anything
continuous anyway
we always have discretised but the beauty of it is that all those other
million dimensions can be integrated out analytically
so how do we use this for classification
so here's our user for classification i hope you can see this this sort of
red and blue island here OK
imagine we have a binary classification problem
so we given a data set d
points in some input space x and then
binary class labels plus or minus one
and y space
and our goal is to infer class probabilities
that the data points
so here's how we're going to do it
we're going to have
take our guassian process which is the prior on functions
we're going to turn into prior on
how do we do this we say
every time i drive function
in the inputs
areas where the function is positive i'm going to call it the class plus one
in the input areas where the function is negative i'm going to call class minus
for example this function represents
the idea that the
positive class is this interval
in this interval
the negative class is this interval in this interval
this is the one the picture in two d we might look like this
this is under the prior before observed the data
this is a typical sample of what i believe
class boundaries would look like
you know we have
blue mountains in the red sea
and zero is like sea level
and wherever
the function this is a draw from the function
by the way this is a draw from the function
in two dimensional space so this is
we call it x one x two color why should be called one
x one x two two dimensions of this function
and then
every time the function is greater than zero
i think a priority that's in the positive class and if the function is less
than zero we think that's in the negative class
it's a weird way of thinking right we have been observed any data yet
but we have beliefs about what we think are class boundaries are going to look
like the class boundaries are going to look like a nice and smooth sort of
regions like this
so what happens when you observe sorry
when you observe data
then you have to do inference is about what you're underlying function is so let's
let's say i observed data that said
you know i observed a bunch of data points that were in the positive class
and a bunch of the players so when the negative class here
and clearly this function is not a good
function because it would have predicted negative
class data points here
so essentially i would have to come up with a distribution over functions that are
consistent with
positive data here and negative data here so i would get a distribution over functions
that locally
like what i'm trying here you know
used to build background palette but you know it's not that
pleasing because that's quite a lot of work on the part of the user we
were trying to get closer towards the idea of
waving the magic wand
and we know we can't get to
so this is a kind of half-way house where all the user
has to do with this interactive graphics system is to drag the blue rectangle around
the object and and guaranteed
the object in some way
inside that's very much less work than
drawing with a greasy pencil but what does that do in terms of
providing training data
we've lost now they
the initial provision of training data that is implied by the greasy pencil happen
well not entirely
because you still have some material which is definitely in the background so that the
thing has become asymmetrical now so outside the blue rectangle you've got material which is
definitely the background we can build a background colour palettes from that material inside now
kind of a bit ambiguous
initially we don't have any so that we can point to and say that is
definitely in the foreground so we're going to be a little bit messed up for
building the foreground colour power but the solution to that is to
use expectation maximisation station to build the colour palette iteratively and what you're seeing here
it is a series of iterations in which the colour palette the foreground is initially
crude polluted with background elements but gradually refined until
we reach a good segmentation now we can play with this a little bit
see that
one i prepared earlier
alright doing computer graphics and this angle is seriously because i can tell you
OK so now
back again
now this is my colleague antonio criminisi
and we're going to
four in
you can be segmented
c so now i drawn my rectangle as the use i'm gonna release
the mouse button and as soon as the math gets released some optimisation over that
markov random field is going to get unleashed
it is
doing it
it's done
and i wasn't bad was we didn't quite get what we were
hoping for
so the poor guy has lost his head but
we can put that right quickly before
before you see any issues are also a little bit
missing publishers back
now we are
a little bit of editing work here and when more back
i could now
copy and paste that that's the
should be funding
now there is another of my goodness
he has a ghastly holding easier because somebody shot
you guys really should have spotted that
i think we can
we can minimize the damage by
by making him small is now only a very small hole no one really noticed
there we are
now that was actually
and optimisation
that works in in real time
and so the rest of the lecture i'm just going to tell you what
optimisation is
this is the graph cut
risation talking about before
so there are as i said there are lots of ways potentially of solving this
kind of problem and people have been looking at this year for you know
what's that two decades we can say if we exclude simulated annealing which was really
designed for nuking the world not solving computer vision problems
metropolis rosenbluth rosenbluth teller and teller you know this paper
this is a simulated annealing you know about this
algorithm you know where you sort of simulate lowering the temperature
in an optimisation problem
the reason that it's rosenbluth rosenbluth teller and teller is because some of the work
on this paper was done dinner party and the wives were present so they decided
i want add them into the paper
very very generous approach to science which you know we rarely seen at
and that
his brothers
so people have been trying to do this for
quite quite awhile i guess starting with
b sag
iterated conditional modes is a little bit like hill climbing on these rather complex posterior
distributions that are not really sufficiently
straightforward to help time on but you know you can do something i'll show results
right at the end compares some of these classic methods with the method i'm going
describe now loopy belief propagation i was referring to early on is the a kind
of extension to belief propagation that you were you hearing about
don't overlook the force but do appreciate the fact
they don't do any work
so now
i'm going to show you
which i find one of the most
mind-boggling demonstrations
i've ever seen we do have
a circular track
you have right in front of you
that's circles although you may not think it is but it is
and that circles
has radius
which according to many to the manufacturer
is a hundred fifteen metres
was an uncertainty
of about
i think it's about five meters sixteen difficult to measure and eventually transport you think
it could change
we tried to clean this a little better
and so the radius of this
the radius of curvature of our
arc which is also in track record hundred fifty
plus and minus five metres
so we can calculate now
what the period of oscillation is this
the whole track is five meters long
so half the track
is about
two and half metres
so the angle theta maximum
is approximately
two and a half metres which is half the length of the track
divided by hundred fifty
and that is an extremely small angle
that is about one point two degrees
so this is in radiance and this is in degrees
so the angle
it's very small
so we should be able to make a perfect prediction
the period and i'm going to do that
i take two pi times the square root of our over g and r is
hundred fifteen
hundred fifteen i divided by g
i take the square root
i multiply by two
i multiply by pi
and i get twenty one
o point
and this is the prediction
he calls
twenty one point five
uncertainty in our
is about four point three percent
since we have this career of our
that becomes two point two percent
so if i multiply that by point o two two
i get an uncertainty of about o point four seven that's called is o point
five seconds
so this is a hard prediction
what the period of oscillation
should be twenty one and a half
plus and minus one half
now i'm going to observe it
i'm going to see
we're going to
how this compares
i don't know what i don't oscillate ten times that will take three four five
minutes that's too long
it's not really necessary because my reaction time
is o point one second so even if i did only one oscillation
there will be enough to see whether it
it's coincident with that
consistent with that number however it is such a beautiful experiment it's so much fun
to see that object go back and forth in twenty one seconds that i will
go for your pleasure and for my own pleasure i will go three oscillations not
that it is necessary but i will do it pretty is going to be something
closer minus and this is my reaction time
which is o point one second and then we can call
divided by three
and then of course the error will go down by a factor of three
we'll see whether this number agrees
with this one
all right you imagine someone making a track like this
air traffic
with a radius of one hundred fifty meters one is this
this may be a ctmeter hundred fifty meters
that is something like ten times higher
more fifteen times higher than this year
amazing that
people were able to do that in fact
nowadays you can even buy this anymore
this is probably some fifty years old if not all
i have to get the
air flowing
out of all these holes there are many many small holes in here
you can also see
areas is now blowing
this object
going report on here
and just because of gravity
it will go
that's all it is only gravity
we'll do work
he the time
and we're going to time i'll start off first
and then when it comes back to stop
i will start to time because that's for me very sharp criterion when object comes
i can still hold here it's very easy for me
start the timing
you may notice as you watch that some of the amplitude
will decrease because there is all the old
because there is of course a little bit of friction is very little
but it is not zero
i do it
just look at it is incredible
just goes simply by gravity
it's like a pendulum
I'm gonna be talking about inference and in particular bayesian inference
inference is different from data analysis inference is about learning about
not just the data you got but the data you will have or you might
have so it inevitably involves modeling it involves assumption
so inference is the process of discovering from the data something about tipically about mechanisms
that are they did might have caused the data or generated the data or if that's too much
at least mechanisms that might explain the data the goals of
doing this acquire can be quite varied and there's not one simple single thing we're
trying to do we may simply be trying to predict future data in many
commercial applications that's the main thing you want to do I guess but in
scientific applications is usually a little more we typically want to try and something
truth that's a bit of a overblown word but something about the scientific truth something
about scientific laws something about how society works whatever it is
if you're an applied mathematician you naturally think of that as an inverse problem
instead of going from assumptions towards data in inference we're going in the opposite direction we're
going from data back towards assumptions and trying to learn something and the
idea in bayesian inference is simply that we use probability to do all of that
OK we absolutely rigorously stick to the laws of probability and that's pretty much the
only thing we use to conduct all of our inferential processes
I'm gonna spend some minutes in these opening slides talking about the implications of
this but a key strength essentially is that all sources of uncertainty are simultaneously and coherently
accounted for
I in the in the old days of small data problems that wasn't terribly important
because it probably was and it was once source of uncertainty but nowadays we're dealing with
complex systems with many different sources of variation and is crucial to be able to properly
integrate all of those uncertainties and all of that randomness and the laws of probability make
that easy and possible and is about the best game in town for doing that
in my opinion
is model-based and in I think in the machine learning language we would call this
the generative models this are models that are capable of generating the data
a further strength of the bayesian approach is that models are not of course models have to be
assumed and and and so on and our analyses are conditional
on the on the truth of those models but also we can use bayesian methods
themselves to criticize those models so if you like it's internally self-criticizing which is which is quite important
OK so over the three talks today and the two tomorrow I'm gonna
cover various different things
and I'll tell you a little bit later about the actual program today's
lecture is quite introductory but we'll get on to some more difficult things
everything connects everything does connect the three other themes that at this summer
school that particulary connect with
my talks are these three here you've been hearing about
monte carlo methods from from arnold and he'll continue today the bayesian
non-parametrics theme on Monday and Tuesday is also very relevant and at the
end of next week the the graphical models theme from Martin von Wainwright is
also very important now if if they weren't I will probably be talking about
all of those things
in less detail so I'm gonna deliberately try and downplay those particular issues and relying on them
I'm sure they did it a lot better than I would but relying on them to cover those
those areas
now I'm not as you know I'm not a machine learner of any
so I was a little bit nervous coming here and I spent a little time browsing on the
way to find out what other people have done so and in doing so
I decided to steal two slides from two people I admire a lot I think they're very highly esteemed
both in the statistics and the machine learning community
I thought they might have an interesting perspective on
perhaps the connections between the subjects if they are indeed different discussed and also on
the role of bayesian methods
in them so this first one is Michael Jordan
and you can see what he says here he was trying to explain what machine
learning was to a statistician
you may disagree of course of what he says but what he says is this that's a
loose fede confederation of themes in statistical inference is a focus on prediction and
exploratory data analysis
a focus on computational methodologies and in particulary empirical evaluation
and sometimes frequentist and sometimes bayesian
let's say sigma is fixed they can also put a prior over sigma let's put
a prior over music only
and when i take the prior over mu as the calcium then everything becomes simple
if they don't do that everything is not so simple
that's why people have taken in priors over music
for simplicity so i want to know what
let's say i need a prior over new because mu is not known it's the
try to estimate so i just say well look here from you should be something
like e to the minus mu minus mu not squared over two
sigma naught squared and there's a constant i don't want
he that concern is just the the the normal
a couple of pies that you have
one is carried to hide things like that so it means well i believe somehow
what i'm looking for this mu is
in the vicinity of you not which i have to specify and
well known sort of more or less certain about this with sigma naught
so this is the prior it comes with two hyperparameters so high power
mu nought and sigma is i hyperparameters i have to supply
i just want to estimate one thing and i have to come up with two
well OK so what's the p of mu given the new given d according to
this it's the given mute times p speed mu divided by p fifty
don't calculate everything that p of the given mu is just the likelihood
of the data so it's
it's the product to fly
one of the spirit of two pi e to the minus
x y
minus new square
over two sigma was called was that of the introduce it's across
it was right
let's forget about it
too much right
so this is the likelihood
and i have to multiply by e to the minus mu minus mu nor critical
over to see my notes
and then divide by something
p of d the first of all we see
because he an exponent there's an exponent and everything i mean it goes up to
second order in mu in the exponent so it's going to be a galson as
right so let's just find out what the mean and the variance of the scouts
is and then the rest will be just follow from normalisation
i have to
get these two guys together
let's take the exponent so this is proportional to x
minus one over two
so what do i have i have first of all
because this product
goes into is something get about the eyes here
minutes of this product goes into some right
so if i multiply
i found collecting all the terms that go with mu square
i get the following i get new square i get
there's some here that some would give me probably and
because i have to sum up in terms from multiply to get
this is the a size clear minus two new
x y
new square in his
right so this some of this constant gives me an n times
new square and then i'll have this guy here which is a plus
plus one over sigma not square
now i have to collect all the terms that are linear in mu
everything that is linear in me was the following thing there is this mute times
x y so there's mu MUN a sum over high
this will be coming from that with this to those away
there will be this is another term linear here
and it's a plus
mu nought
divided by new node divided by
sigma not squared
listen to the details of the later lectures
so you start with a little problem from probabilities which is
which is the following you've got a red box in the blue box and inside
each box we've got some apples and oranges
depicted by some of the basic graphics i'm afraid that's left box we've got six
oranges and apples and i got both rappers one orange
and imagine the process by which somebody picks one of these boxes randomly with some
and then reaches into the box and select the piece of fruit
again random with equal probability of choosing any of those pieces of fruit
we can
ask the following question suppose that we don't know which box was chosen but we
do know a piece of fruit was an orange we can ask what's the probability
that the box was blue
so we're actually doing here is typical of what we're doing in machine learning problems
with sort of going in the opposite direction to
the physical process the physical processes you first which is the box and then you
choose the piece of fruit we want to sort of reverse that process we know
the piece of fruit if we want to infer the probability that we chose the
blue box
so because we do that using the rules of probability and it's very beautiful theory
just described by these two simple rules are really most of what we're gonna be
talking about just the consistent application of these these two very simple rules does anybody
would anyone seeking to derive the rules of probability or
mean everybody very happy with these i imagine from the the applicants we have this
summer school everybody is very comfortable with the OK and properties of course satisfy the
probably property properties be nonnegative and sum to one
and from the from the sum rule
from the product rule of probability
we can write the conditional probability of y given x
in terms of the ratio of the the joint the marginal we can write the
joint is the product of the conditional and the other marginal
which gives bayes theorem to bayes theorem provides way
the conditional probability of y given x in terms of the reverse conditional p of
x given y
from the product and some rule we can express the denominator in bayes theorem in
terms of the summation over the terms which appear
in the numerator
so if you look are apples and oranges then
and let's suppose that the probability of choosing the red boxes two-fifths so it's more
likely that we choose the blue box the the red box
and we
somebody shows box we don't know which one is chosen piece of afraid it's an
we first compute the denominator in bayes theorem which is the probability that the fruit
was orange that's
the fruit is orange given the boxes red well that's just the
fraction of pieces of fruit in the box to oranges times the probability that the
box red
which is two-fifths
and similarly for this
in this case the probability of the boxes blue is just one minus this was
in nineteen twenty s
and then use bayes theorem
to compute
the probability
boxer trade given the food was that comes out to be two-thirds which is bigger
than half
sort of the called with our intuition observing a piece of fruit and oranges some
that's stays is more towards the red box the the blue box because the proportion
of oranges is higher in the red box that is in the blue box
OK very comfortable with that
any questions and show
why did they pick two-fifths
it's just to tutorial examples i just wanted to achieve
well i chose the number basis of the numbers cannot simply and also because this
is this is less than half the saying that a priority
it was more likely that it shows the blue box but once i saw a
piece of fruit was an orange it becomes more likely that in fact it was
red box
was that slightly bigger than half that
there's nothing nothing deep and mysterious and of course we can also talk about probabilities
with respect to continuous variables x
is a continuous variable we can define a probability density shown by the red curve
here there ex
so the probability that x will lie in this little interval with delta x is
just equal to that the area
which is the product of delta x times the height of this curve
and so the probability that x will
lie within an interval a to b is the integral of the density over that
and if we integrate from minus infinity up to point z that density get something
called the the cumulative probability which is shown that the blue curve that starts zero
on the left and ends up the one on the right
and again these are nonnegative in this case the probability density integrates to one
so bayesian inference this is one of the the first of those three ingredients in
this sort of third generation framework that i'm talking about and
the idea of bayesian inference is really a consistent use of probability to quantify
uncertainty sources extending probability beyond the notion of frequencies repeatable events and using probability theory
the way we have uncertainty
of your friends have an ipod and then you can change your mind going by
OK so the question is
can reach which ones
and i think that allowed
you need lots of observations to be able to distinguish between
so if i show in the results for example for the DVD recommendations
when we had a point two million
recombination events
it's it's nice diminishing returns right so i'm blocking the number of recommendations received on
a particular DVD what's the probability of purchasing
and you can see that
probability and i think reason and saturates at around fifteen and what you can also
see that overall the the the probability basically the infection probabilities whitelaw a best it's
around five percent
and interesting
this this also holds for other types of behavior so for example for group membership
for the probability of communicating you make it some
so last part that i want to that here is basically the question of
if we know how things probably the question is how to find out the most
sort of inferential knowledge of how to do that these cascades as quickly as possible
and this comes
in many different flavours so for example on the blog for information cascades you can
ask one of the most influential or infectious blogs so which blocks should so that
i most up-to-date so that i know
the stories that happening
in the blood
environ marketing
the same question question can be asked
that is what the trendsetters who are the influentials people who should i given free
free products so they create cascades and everyone goes by
what spreading you can ask whether workplace by monitoring stations were replaced place sensors to
detect these epidemics as quickly as possible right even though these are different pressures these
are the and the same question
so here's here's here's the problem if i if i had network
i want want to detect epidemics as quickly as possible so the idea is if
we don't start here and spread over time this particular way
and there could be some other the start and spread this particular way the question
is whether i my sense my monitoring station
these epidemics as quickly as possible
and that would be like two parts to the problem so the first part is
the cost right so
monitoring of advertising to particular node in the network have we have a particular cost
just because there's some the
and then will also be only one
and for example for for detecting diseases
the one that makes lots of that is that we want to minimize the number
of affected nodes so you see that is a particular disease spread particular way
and these are the two
sense of monitoring stations the people
and what we get is basically the number of people safe from infection and infections
that can spread easily
we were detected here so this would be the people that will get infected because
there is lot
and there are also other reward functions are also makes sense which would mean like
you want to minimize time to detection or just say i want to do that
but i don't care how holland and so on
just to be a bit more formal way what the problem we are given a
graph in the budget and we have data on how cascades
propagate through the network rights of these data can be obtained from the blogosphere by
calling what you can have
someone or something related to the user's data on how what is possible propagation effects
events could spread through the network
and we want to
select the set of nodes
for maximizing the one right so i want to maximize expected reward subject to costa
and so i mean this is is hard
if you exploit the the problem structure that show in the next slide then you
can try to to the body to call itself
which is basically two independent runs of a light
well basically in the first round we just ignore and greedily optimize reward
in the second in the second independent i'm we optimize reward cost ratios
and then pick the best of the solution
and we can we can show that the following what function has disappointed that property
that i've shown in the next slide
our like neural
so what is now
the problem structure are trying to explain something to me the idea is the following
so if i have some
on some networks and i already
i mean
right but i want
i don't know who the role was wrong
that's why the
so no
part one three
roman five of going from memory and so on
o lord god
now we were not below
from her
OK so this is the
now to make it more or less
i mean
what are
i think one
same thing with
if you want to roll one
and now all over
or so
so the idea is a
they are
i mean to them
and the role of our
o o o
one one
and what
but rather
three or o
there all
one of the
and then mind
and in one go away
because you
but here
the main road
well you
what mean
he a new
where n is
i mean there's no more
the the
four fifty
so who don't
one hundred or one thousand
the above
i know
a lot more
and the so
in the
what want
the number of
and that the
and what we know
you go
early i the
you know your role
if you think of
through the calculation so you see the problem
first second and then
i have a
a break
yes so what what what would have to do for doing nothing like likelihood in
this case
right so maximum likelihood we go like that
so let's take two gaussians
and for simplicity
let's say all the segments are one
so just to simplify
and so i take the negative log likelihood so i take minus long
p d
well all the parameters theta and the parameters are now the two means the two
mixing coefficients
these are the unknowns
we don't know how
how strongly each component is mixed
in the set
so this would be
again since we have independent data
and then we would take the longer
and we would have
p one
of two pi so this is
this goes back to the
o thing
so i just
six months
two one e to the minus
why i minus mu one squared
over two
now comes the contribution from the second one
p two over scary to too high
e to the minus one i
minus two
question this is the object he would have to minimize
so for instance we are doing let's call this the
so if we do e
he mu one and set this equal to zero which is get
a minus
i from one to n
the figure
i want to see it would get
if you take the derivative of this
you would get the two
period two pi
e to the minus
once screened over two
mean two squared two and here you would actually differentiate only with respect to this
let's get rid of all these
here is too high
you have
p one
times e to the minus
you i minus one square
well if you take the derivative this
minus you get a y
i minus mu
one so this is actually what you would have to do
and set this equal to zero and then solve
you get a similar equation for the derivative with respect to two mu two
and yes if doesn't look so
it doesn't look so nice so
just let me write in a little
a different way
you know it's
it's not for me be the first time here
but you know after a while it's not funny anymore
you know it's it's deadly
it's very
what do you mean you teach which you don't believe
but i mean you know believe textbooks you use of this
this is shocking
but i believe all of its that's different
every single thing that i told you that these four disciplines
sir i believe all
this is the
there are only partially true
so at any rate
and by the way if you look at an introductory textbook in cognitive psychology
decision and how people make decisions
how people make choices usually chapter thirteen or fourteen
which means you never get
it's invariant anime news i mean always
and it always says that people allows decision makers and it shows you what the
rational actor model is wrong
and that it gives you some examples from common first and the story
every single one of
now if you look at a special course in psychology and cognitive decision on decision
like barons book
on decision making special course then you get a lot of very good
social theory and very
nuanced and careful work
but it's not part of the tacit knowledge in the profession
it specialized in that area
if you study
decision making
the second is what can be assumed in a disciplinary journal articles
what can you say
if you submit an article to journal looking say without some reviewer freaking out
OK in economics you can say
we're going to find some game perfect nash equilibria
this game
nobody for example
only need only i
or in sociology and mean you can imagine every field is all these things which
if you said in another field to push the button
and you get rejected
so when you work with other people on a paper from different disciplines
there's two things the other disciplines has to tell you because the guy tells you
what is what references you have to put in
because if you don't have the reference in
there's no way that publishes art
and the second is what words you have to take out
say because if a see this were going to go in and
OK this is the sound funny but it's actually quite distressing
this will not happen in the natural sciences
o physicists and chemists don't disagree about the nature of you know
the structure of proteins
can don't have their own rules
alternately they don't say what quantum mechanics is obviously wrong we have our own little
mechanics we
i mean this country
can therefore
at least three of them are wrong
and i argue that they are all wrong in the sense that they all include
fundamental insights
that must be incorporated into a unified basic model of human choice and strategic interaction
this may sound obvious but if you take an economics textbook go look in the
appendix goal the
table mountain cable car to go look in the
you know
but index
and see if you can find more like
or would like
you know even more like
this missile
it's missing workers not even the corruption
and conversely in biology
they don't actually things you
but the first time i ever do i get an article in the journal of
theoretical biology in in two thousand three
called the hitchhiker's guide to alter
and it was mostly you know genetics deployed that you know
my article is an
but the basic idea was that people are socialized and they have a certain genetic
structure that more makes some more or less open to being socialized to be to
internalizing norms
internalizing norms at the heart of sociological model
the active role models
well i showed this to my best friends and mike of the people i work
they actually
i got from biology side of this is just pop psychology there's no such thing
as internalisation this is just pop psychology
or we already captured this in
the grande coefficient the third order of you know some maximisation
and it took me a year to convince people what i want
that they could actually use this concept technologies here given some literature on to read
the literature is a huge literature and sociology on the internalisation of norms
it's very impressive
go read
they were convinced
my point is that
the discipline and by the way when you mention the sociologist the rational actor model
they go for their guns mostly
i mean
that some people here
but you know what if i wanted to care about the rational actor model i
want to become an economist what you need it
this is very general
now i can finally the monk of full copy OK
i want to give five principles for the
of the behavioral science
and what i mean by this is the following i don't mean that these five
principles the most important thing
i mean it
with the use of these
we can create a situation in which wherever two disciplines overlap in the sense that
they are describing the same phenomenon
the great
or if they do not agree
they have to fight it out
so you know you might have some of the most important things in economics are
not going to be and what i'm saying
or any other view but there what you need to
to bring them together
fitting together
here that the
so picky picky applications
2nd is an artifact and that is related to the heart each time the started
beating the subject is moving availability and because of this movement the amount of flux
which is sketched so wire that changes and you know that it's actually quite remarkable
because you are in a very very strong magnetic field movements are very small but
if you multiply this large magnetic fields this is very small and moving movements than
that for somewhere or another you you get the potential difference which is in the
same order of EEG so there there the top 10 times bigger and then you
can use it to which it's very very clearly
I not what you what we do to work to get rid of the year
of these artifacts we also report the
the EKG particles from finger
well then we get the
exact positions of the heartbeats heartbeats are and are not extremely regular they also vary
a little bit of time and that's the reason why we have to report the
signals that we know the events of the heartbeat weekend
what we can if the if you have these artifacts we can compute the average
artefact triggered by the
. ecology and you can and then the kind of President EEG signal which looks
that's so that we can start here at the equator think this experienced because they
relation all this happened because of they of think about what is more
at each year out that some of the
so the pulses of the recorded from the from the finger for this a cable
from here to here but it is not so much influenced by the magnetic field
inside a board ecology is recorded to here from the from the rest so that
this over much more the structure by also by the canadian fields and that's I
think the reason why signals that recorded from something are emerged much cleaner and much
more appropriate to to get to EKG triggers from ECG so much so that he
she wants us to believe it must be stated he is all the more
nowadays they have the media
the ecology and EEG there are almost the same amplitude so if you look here
at the at the signals
so this this is this is the ballistic artefact reduce these strings that are caused
by the emotional disappeared but that a bit surprising is that it is indeed of
the same order of magnitude of of the unit itself because of of the
this is
that is the name of the
what something happens yeah OK that's exactly what