were sent today a the hundreds if not thousands of email messages right waiting for
us since we've seen that it's k so it would be great to also address
that and my thought about what to do that is to build substantially more sophisticated
systems than the ones we use today
so today we have the web
or other sources of text and we systems like google that i think of as
information or before state graze over the web and then they regurgitate what they find
in an indexable form
and my suggestion is that we move up the information food chain and build information
carnivores if you will more sophisticated engine so this is are not all icon so
some kind of node we can ask questions about how is the ipad two in
and get answers like well i found twenty eight thousand reviews eighty seven percent of
which are positive the key features that people talk about our this that and the
other thing is an electronics them and that's what
decide outcome does in part but the show them and the second in the in
the restaurant domain but but you see the idea right if we're able to operate
at this high level then the interaction is much more satisfying of course to be
able to
analyse the text and summarize it this level we need much more sophisticated
so let me show you this rather minor project which is something we've put together
recently and by the way all the demos and going to show you today are
available on the web so
don't rush to try them as i'm doing it will probably slow them down these
are research prototypes but feel free to try them after resistance etc that are of
minor dot com and what it does is it extracts key attributes and opinions anything
this review by what yelled in seattle so barber shops hotels restaurants and is based
on the system which was done by maria myself way back when but now we're
at a much larger scale and what really emphasise what i want to show you
here is how an interface based on extraction
can summarise information for you much more succinctly and easily then if you're having to
do search and this is the point that was made extremely well by a tiny
at all in the best paper attractors that they want to best paper award for
an extractive interfaces just in this year's HCI
so let's see what this looks like
pacific in
to my them so
here's a reminder
and i tell you that i'm looking for
good sushi in seattle
i will ignore the optimal resolution notification
he gives me a bunch of restaurants where there's good sushi but interpreted the
query for good sushi that literally basically it says i have a set of opinion
words that have extracted from the reviews and i've rank them right from the darkest
green is the most positive to read dhaka's roads is the most negative black is
somewhere in the middle and
i'm going to interpret good so she is good suger better so so
excellent so she is going to be included as well and you see that it's
providing us with something that according to the old reviews is probably the best sushi
in seattle
and it's also extracted a wide variety of other
attributes and what people said about about those summarizes the reviews and we should probably
cut down the number of adjectives but you can add this article going get a
sense of how is the service in this place and if you say
you know really interested in what people say about service one only go places where
the service is i don't know amazing that might click on that and i'll see
places where the service amazing and then i could go amigo two
taste of india
and see what people say say about that so you get a sense here right
about how
we're operating that at the level of reading reviews after reviews but at the level
of this concise summary
now again the the interface i showed you
it is not
optimized for mobile devices but again you can imagine how on a mobile device like
this one right reader reviews and i think we've all had that experience become very
tedious you could imagine looking in this and quickly at a glance seeing what people
about about this issue about the service et cetera because we're extracting these with negative
what have i done so far in the talk
i hopefully motivated for two reasons information extraction right one is to solve the knowledge
acquisition bottleneck and the other one is as a basis for new paradigm of search
and interaction based on extractions what i'm going to do now is tell you more
about machine reading and specifically focus on how we do information extraction so i'm going
to get into some more detail here definitely not the level of detail for an
NLP person but all refer to the papers for that so machine reading is really
going to be
information extraction or i e and inference give quick overview of that with the focus
on the question of how do we scale
i e to operate over the web
all talk specifically about our approach which is called open a and i'll give you
the second m
and then the next part of the talk is all show you how much
we're able to compute inferences over the extractions from from from the web
and all all end up with some speculative remarks
OK so so what is a basically think of it as a function that maps
a sentence to relation instance and the probabilities of the sentences anderson was the inventor
of the light bulb then
i might come up with the relation invented events in the life ball with the
probability of point nine that's that's what we're trying to do here and how do
we do that well we go back to the fifties with the
harris's distributional hypothesis first put it really really said you shall know word by the
identifying candidates systems that will have this type of phase diagram and then they're very
simple anybody three online one would come up with these rules
if you
i thought about it before you write everybody beat you to it so you can
get the glory anymore but let's think about what would have to be the situation
if the two metals a and b are going to mix in all proportions
then they must be very similar so
they must have similar crystal structures
crystal structures that way
you get a simple substitutional solid solutions
and furthermore if they're going to substitute solid for solid they should have similar atomic
dimensions right there no good to have two fcc metals mixing where one has
a atomic radius that is so large that it has the force fed into the
lattice of the other similar atomic
similar atomic volumes
and lastly bring in some chemistry we want them to mix and not chemically react
so they should have a small
in electronegativity difference if they're both the same size both crystal structure but they have
a high electronegativity difference they're going to
engaged in electron transfer so that's no good but i i think this set him
robbery rules is nice to reflect upon the light everything else we've learned three o
nine one because the phase diagrams have as i said earlier they have embedded in
them a lot of basic chemistry which goes back to the electronic structure of the
constituents so let's draw a schematic
and the diagram for
one such system called type one so plotting a versus b
this is temperature on the vertical axis horizontal axis compositions on the left side have
here a right side have here b
and looking at solid liquid equilibrium so
at this extreme pur
this and member must be the melting point of pure a
and the other extreme is pure b
so this the melting point of pure b and i've drawn just arbitrarily well melting
point of b
happens to be higher than the melting point of a book
it doesn't matter one has to be larger than the other
and so now this is what the phase and going to answer the question how
does melting point vary as a function of composition
various like this it's not a straight line for two reasons
the first one being that if when you take thermodynamics subsequently if you choose to
do so you'll understand
physical chemistry behind i want to tell you let me just stated without proof that
if c is greater than one
in other words if you're not in the pure material
if you're in a multicomponent system if c is greater than one it's impossible to
go from
phase one
to phase two
cannot go from phase one to phase two
a two phase
region in between
so we can go from all liquid to all solid memory said these mix in
all proportions down here so solid you can mix any mix any ratio of a
and b as solid any max
of a and b is liquids but
because we must go through two phases regime this opens up
to give a two phase regime so up here this is all liquid down here
this is all solid and in between these two phase regime of liquid and solid
we can call it slush
slash we've seen slash before we've seen ice
slash in water
two phase equilibrium for pyramids here this is now liquid plus solid and a multicomponent
up here we have single phase
liquid because the mixing in all proportions so this is the solution
down here these are solid solutions
and here we have
there has to be a period because the formula is not symmetric
the formula does not treat F and G equally
and therefore this is not obvious
that's not that's at least not obvious if you look at it that way
but it is obvious if you look at it that way y
In other words F star Energy
is the guy whose will plus transform is f of x times here well what
would start
that would be the guys plus transform is g times that that have left times
capital G is the same as capital g and capital
so it's because all plus transform mutative ordinary multiplication is computed it follows that this
has to be computed community to so I'll write that down since at times g
incompetent G and and you have to understand that here I mean weasel plus transform
of those guys
but it's not obvious from the formula
OK let's calculate all plus transform of sorry the convolution the let's do it by
the formula
by the formula I calculate integral 0 T I take the first function by changes
variable to the dummy variable you so that you square
take a 2nd function and replace its variable by you
minus T so this is time
the minus you start OK
you see that this calculated this is where I have to write down that's what
the formula becomes
a request is anything wrong
0 sorry that the integrations respect your point of view
because there was a lot so it is
use integral you squared members integrated perspective you so it's you Q over 3
the rest of it is the integral of you Q which is uniform over for
all this has to be evaluated between 0 and seek at the upper limit so
I put you equal T I get even for over 3
my to you before over 4
Of course at the lower limit you is 0 so both of these are terms
0 there's nothing there and the answer is therefore to you look for avoided or
a 3rd my supporters 12
so let's doing it from the formula but of course there's an easier way to
do it and we can cheat and will plus transform instead of if I will
plus transform it will plus transform t squared is what is
2 factorial divided by sq
will plus transform of 2 years
1 divided by squared
and so because this is the convolution of these should correspond to the product will
plus transform which is to over estimate power
not the same as this what will plus transform in other words what's the universal
plus transform of to overestimate fish
well the universal plus transform of 4 factorial over X the 5th is how much
the 4th right
now how does this differ well to turn that into that I should divide by
4 times 3 so there should be 1 12
moral 4 times 3 because this is 24 that's too
so divided by 12 inches what constant
so works at least in that case
in one classifier is a linear classifier
i have bounds for both of them
if i take the best of of them then what they lose in my balance
is a factor flock to
so it's not much you know it
and it also tells you how to trade
sample size was size of the cluster for so if you lose this factor flocked
to it means to get the same
performance if you want
you need to have
an increase of the sample size
that is equivalent to this factor
it tells you how to trade sample size with complexity or at least complexity as
measured by the club cardinality of the classes
it happens that we can improve
quite significantly these results so the first thing was
as we said before
these have things inequality may be losing certain cases
in particular we used only the fact that the valuable is bounded but we do
not use
all the properties of the random bible for example the variance
but with this we can already improved a little bit is this inequality
said second most important point is that when we do this union bounds we do
not care about what the functions where we just knew that we had
capital and functions no matter what they are we said we just the problem by
the sun
overall probabilities and we got this factor log and
and another
direction into which you can improve this these kind of result is
when you look at this quantity it's a bit crude two
upper bound
remember the supremum or coming from a poor bounding
these differences which were the difference of pain for
the the function returned by our algorithm and we replace that by the worst
the difference in the class but maybe
this does not always have things the worst difference
by using this fact we can get all sorts of refined bounds
but the main objective will be
to refine the union bound
it happens that for refining the union bound we first have to introduce
the other refinement i was mentioning the refinement on the deviations
so let's come back to
what are random variables look like
empirical average of
the loss
is what is called the binomial
random variables
and what does it mean it means that
a sense of random bible that can add value zero one
and there are n of them and they have value one with probability small p
which is exactly
the probability of their probability that we have
that we make an error
we know completely the distribution at least in the special case where we have binary
classification we know completely the distribution of
this one i
and we can actually compute exactly the kind of inequality here
the deviations
of our
random bible of interest again for a fixed function
and it's equal to this quantity here
it's essentially tells you that
you have this you have these n
you have zero one for each example you
zero with probability one minus p and one with probability
if you have k ones
this happens with probability p to the k one minus p to n minus
and there are
n choose k
two up k ones among
an example
and you do the sum for all values
such that
the sum of the once divided by n is less sorry is larger than g
which is why we have this system
and this is not always very convenient to work with
so there are a bunch of
approximations or actually there are upper bounds on this quantity
that's simplified
the simplest one is of things inequality
and the important thing here is that it does not depend on
the value of p
so it's independent on the distribution which is nice in certain cases but which can
be a bit clues in order to cases when we have information
now if we
go back this way
bernstein inequality is already taking into account that the variance
because actually
p is a small pe is the expectation of the random variable and small p
times one minus p
is the variance
of the random variable of interest
actually in this special case again with binary random variables it doesn't matter really when
you whether you talk about expectation or variance because they are more less related directly
OK and then they are more refined bounds but which are a bit less easy
to work with
so we concentrate on on this or this
if we look at
bernstein's inequality for example
we see that
force small maltese
this will be small here
so we will have a term which is more or less
of the same type as having
which is e to the minus the square
which is
typical of
states of gulshan random variables
it to
mean small b from the right yes yes
you can but it it seems that
p you need to be to know people to live in a way it is
but we see that there is a trick
to actually use this
for estimating p
so OK so forced multi
these behaves like a gulshan tail
like the
four large t
this term becomes dominant and we have e to the minus
constant times t
which means
exponential data like west all random variables
i mean if everything were gulshan it would be
be simpler but it's not the case for change
so that's what is said here
gulshan behaviour
where the
variants of the gaussians more is the violence
of the random bible
i mean the tail of for the gaussians is exactly
e to the minus the square divided by twice the violence that standard of on
gulshan right so this is exactly the same as if we had the gumption
variable with variance p one million
but in addition to that we have also these
heavy tail behaviour
and the maximum
the worst case if you want
for this quantity
will you know mostly already know how to do
so is that there i do have some slides
you know again that for those who want to see
he later
and the b in the upper don't slide to be on the conference so thank
you very much
so i think that after eleven years of semantic web industry
industrial and service activities self-assessment is very well known from the far
funding agencies but also has the responsibility interface for young researchers active in these domains
and in that respect
let's say
levis that's the picture
the layers
OK you just presented also they correspond to the vision of the semantic web
of the first
so i think that this is more or less the question of what our vision
tenacity picture
that you discuss under the new light and i can
after a
three months
how is to my mind
i think that for the semantic web is the with that so the semantic and
not the other way around
OK as you pointed out
the semantic web essentially
became an issue on the web when he we forget all the stuff
this is the success of the linked data
and this is it's a profound changes on the way we perceive the whole world
in addition to the standard
that's been
let's say design by researchers by a space space station
well the formal semantics it is the case with essentially
this so my
in the semantic web and semantic web stack
the results of the semantics which is the key is to start with
of the four real use
and even
i would say that when i started editing here the university of
by this entity relationship model
at that time it was one
still incapable of course but also have parts of some value
that's what happens today with students
it's in semantic web
so this is because other people have be allowed
the question is the vision of a particularly good well i mean it was sort
do we have the right stuff in the standard which i'm going still say yes
to some degree but it would take a long time so what i am saying
yes and i have also criticized other aspects of that but the key thing i
want to say is that anything that starts with we have to teach people to
right fail on the web
so you yourself said it was accepting the web
but the web work with entity relationship models better than it will work with anything
right into we fought until until the end users have that
but we as an academic community which is what this talk was directed at remember
it was
i said lots of good things about the semantic web making money for people and
being useful on the web and succeeding the we is an academic community
i have lost some of the core
and i think it's the finding the core to have the web stuff and have
representation that and i'm very open to other things you are being part
but the question becomes not we pretty much know there is no existing model that
has solved this
we have these communities start exploring these models again saying what we're really trying to
and how these models help us so that really was my point is i'm not
disagreeing with anything that
i think the key is that
anyone who wants to stand up and tell me
technology access the right one including the technologies i felt men
i'm not telling you i think we have to think are
so sorry because as long as the question to you but then i'd really like
to reply also took it produces
i know we were the last statement that i mean students who are i mean
that we are teaching them semantic web or ontology engineering are not is capable
of models i think they are they are really comparable and we're teaching them i
mean we are doing ontology and getting well
we teaching them to reduce models which is something that normally you don't eat when
you're doing entity relationship models only i think that i mean that there are many
aspects there i mean i i really we fully with dl hybridize in trying to
find ways where we can represent real problems and solve them i mean i think
that's the most important thing that we have to to think of i mean that's
that's as well you're right don't forget we're research community service where we're picking low
hanging fruit
we're competing with the growing startup world that we help create
right so again it no longer needs needs everyone in this room
to be helping to figure out how you let some other company and back in
nineteen eighty six someone said something really changed my thinking is the expert system world
you know the first guy to act build the expert system
you know frameworks and things like that
has publishable results
the second guy
so does it gets published will result in a further validating one for sky
the first guy to do it in some new domain different in the first it
has published results because they help show that except
the DNA of the same is independent because all the information you already
we're going to study this case
you have a different situation because
well yes the question are e being the then you not observed
we are not conditionally on
we're not conditionals using
b c
we not going to condition on c
but still we ask the question in the independent
and then if you do this your surprisingly ten yes the i the
so how do we do that we we write this feel free use
this is called
o five musicals over time you be
so we have you a b
is equal to the marginalisation over c and p of c
which is the model of the forces of these factorizations
there are
we just feel free
times of be
times p of the given maybe
these factors
and the spectre go outside because you to do logical dependency
and you only have some overseas of p of the given name
how much is this
we've seen these already there
this is equal to one
because we never have conditional probability and a sum over the first five
because this is the distribution on
this is the probability distribution
it is a function of general functional c of e and b
with so you probability function of c the
by then a and b we are not going to go into the normalisation with
fixed in the history normalize y
by varying c
now let's conditional on c let's assume condition c
we use
represents fact the conditional on c
all its conditional on c
then obtain the interesting
if we we condition on c
don't become independent anymore
then they become the
so basically this conditional independence will
four of the five position this graph from the
so essentially what you
what we what we learn he is the this let's try to look at technology
assumed to find
this is a chart
if i don't tell you anything
the graph
so you don't have so far they observed the child you don't have some of
i the father and the mother independent
well the independent because any
father can can be a anyone the mother
i don't know
all right so actually is independent
of the
but if i observe the child
let's assume
they observed
you know
let's assume i i also the child
who has brown eyes
so the child the child has grown
they are the parents of ten
they are not enough in particular i know they can not all the lies
because it will have a wide range child like
by the very fact that they will serve as a child i know something about
the parents
the connected
are for example if a observed that the child is cocaine
i don't know anything about the band but he felt that the child is OK
it's very likely that the parents
i'm going to be
so i know something about that
tell you what happened
look at any one of you know i know a lot about
well i mean there's defense between them
yes exactly exactly
i know that there is a dependence between this i know that knowledge from one
thing would be morally on
OK so
this interesting things here
seeing that
of k
score of
y one
to y k
is a
his my i equals one
why i minus one
why i
my so
for any particular
sequence of tags y one through y k
which is starting at the beginning of the input sequence but not going all the
way to the end of the input sequence i can talk about the score of
a sequence of tags
my goal
is to
find the
the best sequence of tags
so far
find the tag sequence with the best score
sequence y one
july and
with max school
to find
you OK
one of the best sequence
y one to y k
and the value of k column b
is the school
test sequence
y one
who i k
where is it
y k
he calls the
and so this UK AV is just a special case of UK around adding the
on the last time
and my actually my goal
is to find
u n plus one
and then
and so
a lot
going to
i mentioned this before
for convenience are going to extend my set of tags
to include two special attacks called start and and then i'm going to
just assert that the that the zero tag why zero is start and the n
plus one tag y n plus one and
now my goal is to find
this the best sequence of tags
the goes after tagging plus one way tagging plus one equals and
so been to here
just we defined
just got different notation for the goal of the algorithm
because remember the goal is to find the argmax
over all sequences of
well you have a good question so it is only as the last set up
it leads me to think well can i find you want then you to then
new three
and the answer is that i can do that in the guaranteed way by using
an idea called dynamic programming
max o y one
to y
OK minus one
some from i corps one
g i
why i minus one y i
why i whatever y is
and then
which is fixed because these the argument UK the
and so now comes the interesting part
i'm going to have a recurrence
u KV
is the
max of y
OK minus one
common like a minus one
like a minus one
so here
let we just go back here and write correctly
here is the definition of UK v
it's the score the best sequence y one to y k with like equals b
it's actually a maximal y one to y k minus one
the sum of the g functions for all four
i was one of the k minus one
and then
cluster g function for y k minus one and
this is the definition of the UK the function
with this definition of the UK v function i can
i can write down a recursive way too
evaluate new cave
it's the
so the macs here of the y one to y k minus one
i get if we had some actual y one to y k minus two
and then
ending in like a minus one
so here i have gk like it was one v that's the same so this
approximately right
he was about to report
university of reinforcement
thank you so
my talk is going to have three parts one is about dynamic programming
so we started that and i hope that will be able to finish
and so
let's start
so first first of all what reinforcement learning
and what i'm talking about dynamic programming is the of reinforcement learning
the first place
well reinforcement learning according to a
to reach is also in the
university of reinforcement learning
every method that uses samples to solve optimal control problems can be considered very first
so we take this is the definition and so therefore we are going to study
first dynamic programming
which is sort of the basis forms the basis for
the solutions for optimal control problems
so by the way
OK again this is your chance to learn about reinforcement learning
please stop me and b
to ask questions
i don't care
as someone has also said
there are no stupid questions
the only maybe stupid answers
so don't feel embarrassed if you don't understand something
some people
and and they told me that
they don't have enough time to understand during lectures all this stuff and they want
to look after lots of the slides
they i want to study is the saying and that's not a good approach
we are here to learn
and this is your seeing the chance to learn it
maybe if it if you're not asking those questions maybe this chance begun
because you will be busy this other things and you will have time to
a study in the test for this
different fields
just please stop me maybe one get to the end but
but at least you will have a better foundation
i hope it's clear
then we can start
so first of all
why do we talk about reinforcement learning what's the excitement about reinforcement learning by why
do i care about reinforcement learning so that's the first thing that i like to
talk about and that the godfather the type of defining a i
then we
deal with some specifics which go under the name of MDP is funny programming and
we do a little bit of approximate dynamic programming
so far so good i i believe
so we got in the literature there are basically two books
which are a little dated this time
so one book is by its southern and andy barto
you can see the book over there
and these are the guys who committed it
so this is an introductory book target to the genetic code interns and doesn't require
much of mathematical background
the other book is is more like a devoted to the theory five
and the title is neuro dynamic programming
and you know this is just the start of this is really really reinforcement learning
without talking about
and those are assigned image back to and joins the thickness the the in theory
of reinforcement learning
and in particular choice image about across
has worked on dynamic programming then or since
many many years
it's probably not born
was already working
so regarding journals and conferences the main channels such email IM she chair and the
idea knows also
i relevant but maybe a little bit less relevant
regarding conferences visu shows that
and that's it
from those three axioms you can
get everything all the normal part of properties of the probability function
can be derived from those three axioms for example
the probability that the
the property that the probability of the null set is equal to zero or the
the probability of the eigenvalue and the union of a and the complement of a
is equal to one and so forth let's just take a quick look at this
final one
suppose i have
two subsets a and b
but i don't make any statement as to whether or not they are disjoint these
are just any two subsets a and b
then the probability that i associate with the union
of a and b
is equal to the probability of a plus the probability of the
one minus the probability of the intersection of a and b
so that that's that also holds the notice that that's not quite the same thing
is this third axes
the third axiom appears kind of is a special case of that
when that term is zero
i hope i'm not going to use that theory in any sort of sophisticated way
i hope this notation is more or less clear
we're not going to be using that too much i just wanted to impress upon
you that there is an axiomatic definition
of probability
which may be a little bit different from the notion of probability that you normally
carry around
there's one more
type of probability that not actually follow from those three axioms and that's what's called
conditional probability
sometimes what we want to do is to regard to say the set of possible
outcomes of measurements as being some subset of the originally specified sample space
right so i want to constrain the outcome to be in some
subset b
and i defined then the probability of a given b
as the probability
the intersection of a and b
divided by the probability of b
that doesn't follow from the three color of axioms that has to be taken effectively
is the fourth axiom
so here's what i mean by that suppose i want to know
what is the probability when you when you rolling a die
what's the probability to have the number that comes up less than three
given that somebody has peaked and told you that it's an even number
i suppose so the probability of rolling and less than three given that n is
all right so what's the intersection of in less than three
even well that can only be
right so the probability of rolling a two
the other six possibilities and therefore that's one six
and then here in the denominator we have to have the probability
of rolling even number so that's two four six out of six to three six
so therefore you would get one thirty for the probability of and less than three
given n is even
OK so that's conditional probability that's a very important concept that we will continue to
that is closely related to important property that will also
the meeting and that is the property of independence
so two subsets a and b
are said to be independent
if the probability for the intersection of a and b that is to say a
and b
it is equal to the probability of a times the probability of b
so that's just the definition
why should that be called independent the what's what's that have to do with independence
you could call it i don't factorize ability or something
but it's easy to see why
what that has to do with independence
if you look at for example
what the probability of a given b is
in the case when a and b are independent
right so
let's see from the definition of the conditional probability the probability of a given b
that's just that expression here
but if a and b are independent
then that probability in the numerator
is simply the product p of a times p of
and the p of these cancelled and this is just p of a
so what does that mean that means the imposing the condition of b
has no effect on the probability
and so that somehow motivates why one would call that independence
and similarly you can show that py of given a would simply be equal to
p of
so don't confuse independent subsets with disjoint subsets that's that's completely different to subsets means
that their intersection is is the null set
OK so that's that's conditional probability
so that's all very abstract and we didn't even really have to insist on what
the elements of the sample space represented but in order to
give some sort of meaning to what to probability and to to specify
a prescription according to which we can assign numerical values to the probability i have
to interpret it in some way
and there are two
commonly used interpretations
probability so let's go through that quickly
one is
that the elements of the sample space are outcomes of some repeatable experiment
and i say that the probability of a is interpreted as the fraction of times
that the outcome is a
in the limit that i repeat the experiment
some very large number of times
so i'm assuming here that this experiment can be repeated some arbitrarily large number of
and i think mathematicians probably last when i write this the slim and ghost because
this is not a well-defined limiting these any sort of mathematical sense
but nevertheless we have this notion that if you if somehow you could repeat an
experiment an infinite number of times the fraction of a certain outcome might just converge
just to switch to a certain value
that is the idea that we have in mind
in the usual sort of copenhagen interpretation of quantum mechanics
and it's certainly very appropriate for the type of work that we do
because when we collide together protons we for one thing we do an awful lot
of time to write ten to eleven protons in each bunch the LHC so we're
certainly repeating that
pp collisions a large number of times and there doesn't seem to be any fundamental
limit to the number of times that we could do that so this frequency interpretation
of probability seems very appropriate
on the other hand there's certainly we others
types of situations
where you want to talk about the degree of uncertainty
vision you might want to search over all pairs of images to find the one
that best matches the debt between the two
so those are more search problems when you have maximisation
OK so
both sets of problems are hard in general
this one is hard because you have
again an exponential number of summations or you have a very high dimensional integrals
right intervals are very easy if there in one dimension or two but they rapidly
become very hard if if you have a higher dimensional ones
right so these are generalizations of the problems that i think are notable to spoken
about he's probably spoke about the problem of filtering in the other sequence something like
the time series evolving over time
anyone who
computer approximate the marginal distribution given all the data up to time t
that would be this problem here this marginalization problem if you on the markov chain
would be interested in it from more general graphs
if i go back to this example so that that demo that i showed you
what was i doing what was the approximately doing
really there extra notes here you're observing noisy versions right you had to clean image
that was sitting there you didn't see that
you saw a noisy image to be some
shaded nodes there that show what you observe and what that algorithm was doing was
it was approximately something very quickly over all codewords
that are
and for every node it was finding out is more likely to be o one
or to be zero
right so is computing the marginal at every node
and it was more likely to be one then declare one
and vice versa
so that's what that alan was doing it wasn't doing it exactly because somebody mentioned
this this graph actually has cycles but if it had been tree the algorithm that
would represent will do it exactly into it very efficiently
OK so the problems would like to solve
let me come back to this tomorrow
about variational methods and we just started
talking about the max product algorithm
OK so the max product algorithm how many people know about the viterbi algorithm
OK so to be of them as a special case of the max product algorithm
one reason graphical models are useful is because they essentially generalize many classical algorithms there
is listed at least ten to fifteen algorithms that are special cases of what we're
gonna do now
so if you've heard of the term be that's a special case forward backward is
a special case alphabet beta a special case common filtering is a special case fast
fourier transform is a special case you can essentially go down the name you know
many influential algorithms are all to a special case of what we're gonna do now
that's part of the utility of graphical models they somehow allowed you see what the
key ideas in all of these problems are
OK so max product
what is it's an algorithm for trying to solve problem number three
it's trying to solve this maximization problems we have what we like to do is
to maximize overall the nodes of the graph this product of terms
that's where it gets its name you'll see in a minute because it has the
maximum product and
the algorithm all it does is play games with those two terms
OK so let's let me do this concrete examples
OK so max product
right so the simple example i'm showing you have got three nodes
one two and three
so that's three variables
and so i know that i have a factorizations
over these three variables on the right in certain way because it's useful to me
later on the right is proportional to the product of three terms
one for every node
it should be necessary
well are you
issue here
the right
and you are
and you
you have
and you it
and here i
and how
the have
we can see the
you you
you just
in this in the
thank you very much and will
what you
you can the
i think
he said well
this question
you use
so how do you
and you
i think
we can
you get
you want to more
and was he would teach me how human
i think ready
y is male or female
so this is a a call arms unfortunately in english there's no
gender free version of this as far as i know
parent child now
uncle aren't showing you come up with one
and i'm going to try
it's going to sound that
why do we care about why because i want to see if i can do
is recovering step three coloring idea was well the grandparents let's say it's black if
i can push
the blackness of the pair the grandparent down into the two children
then if both of these are read in other words then i'd be happy that
push the problem of this guy is now read skies black sinister alright this one
may violate the
great-grandparents but will just keep going up and that
if we're lucky
why is red
then we can just to recurrent
if the color y
was red
and the
we will recall color and i'm going to differ
this took pictures
called case one
OK let me first time you how cases
and then we'll see how they work
for non in case one
so this else should be aligned with that
then are either in case two or three here is that the dichotomy
it turns out we've actually seen all the cases
maybe not a versus b
we've seen the case in the very beginning we're just recall that's case one
the next thing we saw is what well it's kind of annoying the grandparent and
ten seven and ten were not straight there is exactly
so case two is when there is exact
so that's
if x is the right of the page you x is the right child of
its parent
and the parent is the left child of the grandparents of the same so far
that is case two
OK the other case if x is the left child of its parent so
then we have left chain expert of x grandparents
that's case three
i not write else here
because what case two does is it reduces the case three
so in case two are going to do this stuff that's here and and then
we're going do stuff here very case we just do this stuff here or in
case one we just in the stuff here
and then that finishes three cases on the a-side
then back to this if we say else
this is case b
which is the same as a
by reversing the notions
left and right
in the natural
natural way every time we write something we instead write or something and vice versa
so this is really just looking everything over
just focus on case on
category a and let's see what we do in each of the three cases were
seen in the example
let's do it generically
so there's little there's one more line to the graph
aligned with here
there's a chance when you do all of this the road becomes red we always
wanted to be black
if it's red we set to black at the very end of the algorithm
this does not change
the black eyed property
everything will still be fine causes
i mean every path either goes the record doesn't
every x to leave
changing the route from red to black is no problem
it will increase the black everyone but they all say
all the paths will still have the same value just it'll be one large
let's look at the three cases
and i'm going to use some notation remember we have triangles in order to denote
arbitrary subtrees and we define retention
i'm going to use triangle with the dot on top
so to say
this node the subtree
has a black
so this what i feel something like it means black because i'm on the blackboard
and i also have the property that each of these triangles
i have the same black i
so this will let me
make sure the black black-eyed property property for
is being preserved
generations of search which by conventional standards now it worthless like things like altavista anybody
remembers that was this idea of pagerank where you rank web search it's not just
based on the match the words on the page to the words in the courage
but to some sense of how important the web pages how central it is in
the greater conductivity network of the web and google shows that you can compute a
sensible in very efficient notion of
authoritativeness centrality by taking basically the first principal component of the web conductivity matrix so
PCA and related techniques
massively influential
what's missing well again you've seen some of this in all the talks here and
i want to give you my take on what the serious study of cognition learning
and cognition more generally tells us how to go beyond this
this paradigm but also what kind of insights can we take from this paradigm and
what other stuff do we have to add we want we don't just want to
throw this out because this such a successful paradigm like in in physics or any
other successful science we want success paradigms to build on what was valuable and write
about alternate so the premise of this
summer school it's pretty clearly is that
there is some sense in which cognition is heavily dependent on learning and learning should
be described as a kind of statistical inference but the question is what kind of
statistics and how does it interact with the other important
pieces of the picture and cognition the kinds of symbolic representations for example the nyquist
OK so the outline for for this talk will be three parts of give you
my take on the big problems of cognitive science which may cause already hinted at
a course it's this is a personal view but it's one that's widely shared also
it's not the only problem though just to be clear then talk about how machine
learning in its modern form can help address this problem and then a very brief
introduction to cognition viewed through the lens of statistical inference and learning like what's an
example of the sort of experiment we might do
just give some insight into how
into your why we might want to view cognition as a kind of statistical inference
so here's the big question from my point of view you could put it like
this how does the mind get so much from so little all across cognition we
see the mind taking in data as a the senses and making generalizations abstractions going
beyond the data
given building models doing things that by saying some conventional standard in in statistics maybe
by the standard that earlier paradigm should be possible to get it and we want
to understand how that works
so we can illustrate this from starting from visual perception
the the i think it's
but again widely acknowledged that taking out even learning the study of vision is where
we made the most progress in understanding how the brain and the mind work how
cognition spans all these different levels this is a slide from david marr's books on
mars are not remembered famous these days for a number of reasons including these this
way to think about how cognitive system works at different levels of analysis is talked
about but he was also probably this is the main legacy one of the founders
of the field of computational vision a field which has also a long history of
interactions between the human and engineering side
and in his book that based on research program developed over brief time he died
tragically early from cancer
this research was mostly done in the nineteen seventies and the book was published around
nineteen eighty laid out of view of how the visual system might work it was
mostly speculation he didn't have time to really work it all out
but there's a lot we can learn by looking at
now this is this figure here is just meant to illustrate what makes the problem
of vision heart how in the in this context vision is the mind going beyond
the data that's given
so here's an image again this is you know circa nineteen eighty digital image very
low resolution low contrast but we can still see what it is right so what
is this
look at the plant life heard somebody else it's leaf
is that one only four how many leaves either
four what else is there
this is standing right there you can you can put put a number of words
on this but you can also talk about the geometry right like use your hands
to describe the shape of this plant these leads sort of like this one can
leave club folding over another one passing behind another one over here so just from
this image very low quality images is you can extract semantic context enriched services process
but what does it look like coming into your eye looks like this this is
just zoom in in that box there of the
pixel brightness is on a scale of zero to two fifty five roughly like what
might be coming into your the retinal ganglion cells you pulling inputs from photoreceptors in
your retina and you just yes have numbers here right where there are the surfaces
or the leaves or stems of the plant
that's the problem and this particular human is an interesting one because this is a
region here one leaf crosses over the other and perceptually we see abound between surfaces
there but there's no actual
or a sharp change the image brightness is here it's all numbers around in ohio
one sixty slow one seventy so that's
that's interpolated based on of course other data that's here but also rich knowledge about
the world and and that indeed the processes of image formation like works
as as sonic pointed out or showed some great illustrations of the study of visual
illusions places where our minds plays tricks on a city like has long been used
by cognitive scientists to understand how the problem or what makes it hard and what
kind of assumptions are constraints might enable the solution
so here's my favorite visual illusion it's a close second perhaps to the brighton solutions
that make showed this one is by roger shepherd who is one of the founders
of cognitive psychology one of the most important figures in cognitive science he is also
a very good artist besides being very creative scientists and so he drew number of
it's the whole universe so no further restrictions on the object on the right hand
and this
concept description then describes all those things
which appear which show up
on the left-hand side
of top of the head of relation
and what we're saying here is that
of objects on the left side
of head of tupels
are a subset of
the professors
now if you
take a minute and have a look at the chair
the concept x here
and then we see that
we know
chairs show up on the left-hand side of the head of tupels right because is
the restriction that we impose on all chairs
and since they impose they show up
as objects on the left-hand side ahead of
all chairs must be professor so all of a sudden
sub concept of professor and not only if you want all
first and then the rest is pretty much the same
you add an axiom and you introduce
concept subsumption relationship between concept names that are you see not directly related to the
extent that you have in your window
right that you know
it's apparent that you need reasoning techniques to find this out as you have seen
before you will be informed
about new subsumption relationships
which might be unexpected which might be unwanted even
so if it turns out that you don't want chairs to be professor you have
to somehow revise the model
and later on you will see how this can repair could be supported using reasoning
o thing
might be a very common modelling
take you technique and it is known as the domain restriction
for the head of
relation and so probably
you will
use an ontology language that provides a dedicated syntax to to make it more apparent
what you do right
impose the domain restriction on the
relation head off
but you see
concerning the semantics that we adopt this introduces implicit subsumption relationship no matter how you
this kind of restriction
the just two
i understand what is going on here we might use the
but how how do i reduce the
scale here the idea
so if this is new to me and from getting lost
OK thanks alot that's great and this is the point
great call no
been using this machine for quite some time know that but it's nodes not
i noted the
into this
raise the reason here and as you can see there are
this this is the
taxonomy that the system computes
you can using the interface you can
inspect the
concept definitions here and so on and so forth you can just interactively deal with
your concept either using proce or other tools
and you can select the
notes here
and you might then use these concepts for checking out whether there are instances of
chair so this will be dealt with later on now we focus on the class
we we might
just introduce a new concept work can do this year so you might just introduce
a person taking
for which there exists something that they take in this something that must be a
i will
increased the
so the idea is that
we might be tempted to introduce a new name person taking lectures into our model
and we define this name so we see this concept description person some takescourse chair
course sorry
some takescourse course
some that we would like to call
the person taking lectures
and that's okay for the system and i hope you can show this
then we should probably see this
you know it
in the
so this one plot on the x axis it plots sort of the levels of
the cascade right so this cascade here has four levels of c one two three
four right and what i'm blocking here is sort of the information gets farther away
from the source i'm i'm blocking them for example the black line here is objectivity
right and what this is trying to say is that cascades sort of usually they
started the relatively my sort of without any sort of this that the baseline sentiment
and then very quickly the opinions polarizer activities there is this increase in in
or decreasing objectivity which means people start using sick sentiment sentiment words more and more
and then and then the cascade cools off and sort of big gets more objective
so what seems to suggest that in the first two steps of information propagation there
is this let's a polarization that occurs and then as information gets older and propagate
even for the
opinions start to cool off and actually the language gets more objective than what was
the baseline of the
of the of the of the blogs that mentioning the things right so it's interesting
that you get this sort of good this could heating up of the cascade and
then sort of cooling off effects as the information gets for these are just two
examples what can be done with information flow and sentiment i think there are like
parts of others
interesting questions here that the
i haven't yet been answered by the the way the the enabling thing here is
to trace have blog blog posts place hyperlink so that we can see how it
for the the better which information flows and i'll start analyzing the sentiment as a
function of the shape of the cascade or the distance from the initiator of the
cascade and so on so
this is this is the first way how we can information through hyperlinks what is
so what is good about sort of right abstract up and see what is good
about this and what is not so good about so
exactly the color correlation gets to get so exactly so here is the
with the relation is positive and and sort of the slope is more than one
so here it seems that if the parent is subjective children are getting even more
right but then when you go high off sort of the correlation since the turn
around and says children get less objective than the pattern OK good so to say
to say some thoughts about this right so the first thing is why is why
slicing hyperlinks could for the thing is the first thing is it's very it's unambiguous
precise and explicit way to trace information to trace information flow right i we obtained
above the timing information that someone and we also painted the place of information so
we obtain the ground we obtain the cascade so we can start analyzing discussed what
is not so good about this is the basic idea making this assumption that whenever
someone creates link somewhere else there are some information from their transferred to me right
so there are many things that do not transmit information particular navigational links templates and
things like that the other important point is that for example mainstream media sites do
not create links to one another right so there are no links between washington post
the new york times even though they may be stealing stories from one another right
so the problem is
that sort of these database very let's to a very high high precision but low
recall right similar happens with bloggers who sort of forget to add the link to
the source right and this this this problem that people don't create hyperlinks so that
we often in online media given at who had implicit networks will motivate the the
later part of the of the story that was asking me for the networks of
image information spreads OK so this is this is the one important point the important
point that i want to more skin through the going to do this is really
the basically because we have a complete data when we collect this information flows especially
if you go online on the blogosphere the the problem becomes that our cascades will
become fun so what i mean by that is imagine that this is this is
a particular cascade truck is just a theory of how information spreads started red mullet
then it touched or this not so but then the problem is because i'm calling
online data may be a crawler somehow i missed the blocked both that here showing
great right so the problem is that
my data i have missing data some of my cascade being this kind of nice
binary tree or near a nearly binary tree it really really be some some strange
thing it would be like chain here and then sort of two more separated components
and so on right so the important thing here is fight let's have some at
and i have something propagating through the network some cascade this chain of length two
right and then for some reason maybe i didn't crawler somehow i'm missing data that
nodes are also mention this piece of information that might escape instead of looking like
this as it should look like just just as two isolated nodes in the finals
asking OK what are the properties of this thing was the properties of that thing
of course it's very different right so here i can say what is the depth
or one plus the depth of this cascade here and say three here and see
here and say sorry what is the size here is say three right i have
three notes here and say i have two nodes or if i start asking what
is the depth of the cascade here i would say that there is still here
and say that the zero right so that one problem is if i have a
few missing pieces in the in the case of information flow in the cascade microscope
can get disconnected and i have no clue how to what to do about so
here is here is what what one can do actually that it is possible to
correct for the effects of missing data on cascades right so the way you can
think about this is to say OK i want to find some properties of the
complete cascade c and property can mean what is the that what is the number
of nodes what is the number of leaf nodes and things like that so that's
what i'd like to do the problem is that i have missing data so i
don't get to see this real cascade but i just get to see some kind
of cascaded missing in right and it under the assumption that each node is missing
uniformly at random with some small probability that we can sort of have a paper
there is a paper whose main messages the following the first thing is that the
method that we put in the paper is because the effective about when more than
so i can represent my my graph is the matrix
now what is
special about this matrix
compared to the user like the general because problem first of all the input matrix
is symmetric because here we have the same label in both directions is an undirected
secondly the output of the clustering of the rows should equal the output of the
clustering of the columns is very similar
two what we required in the problem of classifying antibiotics
so i want to have a partitioning of the graph
so partitioning of the nodes will have the same here is here so i want
to have the same partitioning of the columns and the rows
and finally the requirements that
members of the same
block should have plus between them and of
different blocks to the minus one translates into the requirements when i look at this
it's not just that they want the block to be homogeneous but they wanted to
be a plus one
a lot
not because the one thousand eight those two
but this is come from the same block
so i want to have plus one
o minus one
so this gives us
a version of by clustering in which
we not only require homogeneity of each block but we also dictate
what is going to be the pattern of labels of the plot
in this case the patterns of the labels of the block should be
plus one along the diagonal and minus one
on block which of diagonal
so specific case of the clustering and you can think of it is not very
different because
then the total number of potential patterns of blocks is small we suspect the size
of the matrix
it's two to the l times k but that's very small compared to
we can consider we can view the
correlation clustering problem as
some twist on the biclustering problem and indeed the algorithm that we have phone
the biclustering problem also of
any problem like this and hardness results they also go both ways
let me get to the results
so that the is the
that i
the first one to describe the computational complexity results
and we could show for the minority buy myself
actually for all three
types of objective functions for the minority cost for the maximum cover mogeneous blocks and
for the minimum weighted by and we could show all these problems are NP hard
actually not only NP hard that you can show that there is no
the test but i mean it's even hard to approximate in some precise fence
and on the other hand we can have an approximation algorithm for those problems with
guaranteed approximations
success so
what we show here is that this is an approximation algorithm that finds in time
which is same
i want to get to for let's ignore this for a second so in this
time it computer clustering with because is no more than the optimal cost cost plus
the running time ten need is linear in the size of the matrix
but exponential in one of absence square
in the number of blocks
and in that it's a probabilistic algorithm in their probability of success
so we get an algorithm which is linear in the size
of the matrix by the exponential in the precision and accuracy
parameters and in the numbers of blogs and columns
and in fact i mean one could ask
this is
a quite satisfactory results it's almost matches the lower about we can prove in terms
of hardness one could that
is this
exponential depend on the exponential dependence of epsilon is the inevitable and we can show
to the hardness results but exponential dependence can analyse that is it really needed and
we could in fact show
it is the case that if you consider
so the
from the point of view of computational complexity
the two basic cases we can consider one is that it is
so case one
is that what i consider him OK in part
the input
the second case is knl
what we saw what we show here is the hardness of both cases so if
ten l a part of the input we can show how this of bi clustering
if you do not allow permutations of the rows and columns
i don't allow for the for the columns might task is very simple so i
keep the rules in the same order i keep the columns in the same order
i just want to know when to and my first block and start my second
well they can show is that this is already
np p hard if five you can tell us about this is i can not
be polynomial in k in
on the other hand if i you can and is fixed
then without computing the blocks just pounding to stop is of course
an easy task when windows of fixed
i mean it takes time and and to the k times and to help but
if k l are considered constant then this is one of the time and
if i don't allow limitations
but if i do allow limitations that's the hardness is unlikely
get here that if there are constants then it becomes NP hard
when you want to find the best permutation of the rows and columns
which is the kind of problem to consider is considered as viable
then even if you don't allow limitations is NP hard which means that
we cannot hope to get rid of this exponential dependence
on can
so we we have a hardness results for all those three
types of objective cost functions and we have an approximation algorithm
and what do you want to do now is to discuss little bit
idea behind the formation of so i hope that you are still
life and be interested
so here is
and not having spirit
this is
the last they're replying to
does not apply to become
in particular
this can be done the zero by good choice of classifier
that means that this can be done zero
could user classifier
another thing which is interesting about this is that a lot of people designing individual
learning our limbs
like for example support vector seems to
you have failed to generalize the multiclass case correctly
and says that there is a black box technique
generalizing the multiclass case
which always works
for any
good binary classification error
and there are things people to keep track of like consistency and so forth is
but i can see implies multiclass consistency
so also
so the square root is not great but
we subtract off this
this minimum
he says that
my we something pretty non-trivial
even when the and binary is point two five right so
it is point two five
twenty five
and this is zero mean is you must be doing
as well as anything
OK so
that's the same
in the course traditional try to prove it
the way to prove it is using the hadamard matrix
one way to prevent using hadamard matrix
the hadamard matrix has this property that
the distance between any two
is half of the number of rows
keep going
here i fast and so the recursive definition of the hadamard matrix
the way that it works recursively to take
in this game
stick and here and here and here and inverted sick here
and then take this guy
put it here and here and here in birds taken here
crazy last night
you gotta see this
it has patterns into it's it's very nice pattern
i i think i've actually seen this and drugs
never repeats
it's pretty cool
we could try everything he says
and it is using the software maybe lower learned
but i have little bits of it
i'm thinking that maybe very wary like this
here the hadamard matrix distance between any two columns is half the number of errors
let's let b be the number of rows over binary problems
the distance between any two codewords be over two
exactly b over two
that equality by the way is why reason hadamard
it it's actually quality
and then
we analyse this
OK so we're going to analysis
assuming that the
one in classifiers are perfect first
will do
imperfect case next
OK so assuming that are perfect
l one distance
by problems
of of of intelligence
the probability of a set containing here label
right probing is estimating the probability the labels in one set of the other
and if you know what that is
the only bits probabilistic estimate of that set
and that's thing that
this is actually pretty
you there
this some
for every label
the set containing
the probability that they will
and there's some sort of fancy switching of something going on here
you say look
whatever what reliable elder care about
it's going to my definition appearing every set
were were measuring the probability of
there's b
the set so we have b times the probability of that particular label
and every other label
appears half the time
because the difference between
comm does have
so the first half the time which means that
it happens half
the some of the other labels
the problem that label
and multiplying from the left that's why I call it the left nullspace
by making and putting it on the left I had to make it into a
instead of a column vector
my convention is I usually don't do that I usually stay with A transpose Y
OK and you might ask
how do we get a basis
or I might ask how do we get a basis for this for space this
left null space
OK under the example
as always I that
all right
the left null space is not jumping out at the hero
than I know which is a free for protect free variables the special solutions but
those special solutions to a x equals 0 and now I'm looking at A transpose
and I'm not saying here
but somehow you feel that the work that you did which simplified 82 art should
have revealed
the left null space to
and slightly less
immediate but it's there
from a to R
I took some steps
and I guess I'm interested in what were those steps
or what we call them together I don't I'm not interested in what
particular ones they were I'm interested in what was the whole matrix that took me
from 8 to
how would you find that
you remember gals Jordan
where attack on the identity matrix
that's do that again although it above here
so this is now
this is now this idea of
I take the matrix a
which is
In gas Jordan when we saw before a with a square invertible matrix and we
were finding its inverse
now the matrix is an square it's probably rectangular
I'll still tacked on the identity matrix and of course
since have length and it better be M by M
and now do
the reduced role echelon form of this
what I get back
the reduced row echelon form starts with these columns starts with the 1st columns works
like mad and produces are
Of course still the same size environment and we did before
and then
whatever it did to get our something else is going to show up here
and we call it the
in Miami
it's whatever you do you see that he just gonna contain a record of what
we did
we did whatever it took to get a need to become
and at the same time we were doing it to the identity
so we started with the identity matrix we buzzed along
so we took this is something
it all these roll reduce reduction amounted to multiplying on the left by some matrix
some series of elementary matrices that altogether gave us 1 matrix and that matrix is
so all reduction step
amounted to multiplying by how do I know that
it certainly amounted multiply by something
and that's something took on
so that something was
now look at the 1st part
e a is ah
no big deal
all I've said is
that v
role reduction steps that we all know well
taking data are
in some matrix and I can find out what that matrix is by just taking
ions and see what comes up
what comes out is the
but just review
the invertible square case
what happened there
because I was interested in chapter 2 also
when was square invertible
I took a I I did row elimination what what was the came out it
was I
so in chapter 2 in chapter 2
all our was not
the road with the reduced row echelon form of a nice invertible square matrix is
the identity
so if ah was Iike in that case then he was than he was
because he is
that's that was good and easy
what I'm saying is that there still is
it's not a inverse anymore because there is a rectangular hasn't gotten
but there is still some matrix eat
that this to this
0 I should have figured out in advance what it was
I didn't I did those steps in sort of erases I went
and the
I should have done them to the identity to accommodate the
can I do that cannot keep the identity matrix like I'm supposed to do and
at the level of what was delta y
minus the pressure
levelwise divided by delta y
it's that around so i bring this to the other side
equals minus
i was doing
and if i take the limiting case of this
for delta y goes to zero
then we will call this
and this tells you
when you go to increasing values of y
the pressure will go down to minus sign
very natural to go with decreasing values of y
the pressure
will go up and we call this
hi was static pressure
so it due to the fact that there is gravity
without gravity there is no hypothetical
almost fluids
most liquids
practically incompressible
in other words the density of
liquid cannot really change
so therefore
you could remove this
and simply always use the same density is exceedingly difficult takes renders the forces
pressures to change the density
over liquid unlike
the of gas gas is compressible
you can very easily change
the density of gas
so liquid
if i have here
this then and i have here
and i put in force on here
it would be impossible for me
make that
volume smaller even
by the fraction of a percent
it would be impossible if this however were gas
and will be very nice
for me to push that in
and two
change the volume of the small volume small and thereby
make the density of the gas go up
if i took a sledgehammer
and i would hit
plastic below
just saying that was fulfilled his heir
acts like a cushion
i could squeeze it
if i had the sledgehammer on the marble floor
i couldn't squeeze and the force
on the marble floor of the hammer will be way higher
because i don't have this caution action
if i take a break
we have one here
we have to
and this pain is fell to the brain
with water
and the other one
it's filled with air
and it was this last hammer
these acts like a caution
this one however
doesn't want the volume will decrease sort of force
like on the marble floor will be way higher
but remember
that force divided by area
expression and according to paul goal
the pressure
propagates on the minister in the whole through it
and so if i would
so the but still here
i get a huge force
extremely small area of the bullet
so the pressure inside the liquid will go up enormously
and the can might explode
provided that it's really filled to the brim with water because if there is an
left then you have this question action
i don't remember whether there's every year where this area in there
i'll leave you to decide
o five bought from this site
and then we'll see which can
and which does not
and the one that doesn't is the one that has ever in it
and the one that explodes
the water and it provided that we really feel that the brim
so something in the
i did something wrong it's OK
all right
because the bullet
OK ready for this
you tell me which can is filled with and which can is filled with
four three two one zero
this one is closest
as an ice hole i still there
this one has a whole year and hold a about
so sort of what we know which one
what i mean by the way
still there
these things are not so
i will assume from now on
i completely incompressible
in other words i can now use
this law that we have there
and they were very simple integration
i have now the
i can integrate
some value p one to p two
y two
what one
question one
in the liquid
and that equals now
minus rho g
and y one
right now it trivial the role because rho is constant rho is not a function
of y
with the atmosphere of the earth
that's more difficult because rho is a function of altitude the atmosphere not
with liquids
so we get the two
minus one
equals minus rho g
times y two
mine is why what is the scope of cultural
i prefer
right it's slightly differently
but it's the same thing i like sign your i which is around
and y two
why my one sort of means is i see immediately that if y two minus
one one
positive higher than this the pressure one is larger than the pressure to cause they
identical so this is the high dose radiation pressure
this has quite bizarre consequences
suppose i had a
the vessel that i filled with a liquid
how run change shape
like so
what is strange
i would feel it
we liquid this level
and the level years
so next time i give this talk it'll be in the right place and remember
we talked about all this stuff and we saw that we've got these things out
that looks sort of like topics human genome DNA genetic evolution evolutionary and so on
and we start with another article we had the the topic of high probability had
different words that co occur
so then i ask you to think about
why this happens
so does anybody think about that
the one person think about that
i am OK
it's not very well well-formed question
what i did these words come out that look like topics when we impose
these generative model this model
the first model
she why when we were in the vedas do we do we get this
these kinds of things out
he said co occurrence
within twenty min
yeah that's true
so this this has a lot to do with co occurrence why why would
why would the posterior distribution of the latent variables in this model
one place with high probability words that co occur
because say who who's talking i can see
OK that's
that's hopefully true
but we're just fitting this model to observed data
where have we
the what the question is that the simple question is
this is our model
and we've specified all of the distributions remember the dirichlet distribution here let's say that
there are dirichlet distributions here although don't worry about yet so much this is a
multinomial with parameter theta and this comes from looking up the
xe or z a topic in data
and drawing the word from that and so the question is why look at the
posterior of the latent variable, specifically the betas, why do co-occurring words have high probability
and so we're really just looking at the posterior we're at we have no future
data in our hands one would when we're making this computation
so maybe can you flesh out what what you mean
that's right that's right this of my higher point here my higher level point
it is
when you when you know i said the topic modeling really is just
case study of bayesian modeling with text
OK and when you're when you're engaging in the practice of bayesian modeling it's worth
thinking a little bit about
what you expect from the posterior or understanding why something is happening
trying to understand the least so
it's true that the bayesian machinery is working as expected and giving us the right
the things these these distributions over words but
i want to thank
again a little longer about why co occurring words come out of it
and i don't by the way i don't have an answer to i like my
answer but it's not i don't know three OK
OK so that so it has to do with word dependence
and that i see so that if two words come from the same topic then
they are dependent on each other and and co occurrence independence are somehow
are somehow linked
which they are
going from prior to
this is one of
this is not a power of one hundred
you this is too i missed last part i want to write down here thank
you said the last part again
so i
it was around this OK
i like are