little bit of fraud
in fact i can give you a number of examples of this are just singled
out one which is the lesser
which was written to the times in london just a month or so ago this
said sir i was recently the victim of an internet fraud the sum involved was
several hundred pounds my local police refused to investigate stating that their policy was to
only for sums of over five thousand pounds about ten thousand dollars it's less than
that they don't bother
this has all sorts of implications i think it has an implication
suggesting that society is changing it means that small
and less than ten thousand dollars fraud are regarded as in some sense except to
certain about places
i don't feel it's worth investigating they're sort of of interesting sociological consequences of that
secondly there's something there's sort of version of the preta principle
in general in fraud detection first fifty percent these numbers don't really mean anything you
know just of indicate is the first fifty percent of fraud
it is easy to stop
relatively easy
you know many forces are pretty stupid
but some clever the first fifty percent is easy to stop the next twenty five
takes the same amount of effort next twelve office percent takes the same amount of
effort again
and then you can see that
you'll never stop it all
at the top and presumably there are some very successful fraud as process not detected
and the search point
the resources available for fraud detection always limited was to come from the british bankers'
association conference a few weeks ago
and the figure of
around three percent of police resources are spent on detecting and preventing fraud
just three percent police have lots of other things to spend money on
and what's clear what is very clear
it was that that's three percent isn't going to be increased
they're not going to switch money out of stopping burglars or muggings on the street
or whatever
to put it into fraud detection
consequences of these
these things are the if we come out in the process we go out think
that means we've got to bring sophisticated advanced technologies to better stop them which is
the sort of thing we've been talking about this meeting
there are a number of general problems in fraud detection and i'm going to look
at some of these in detail as we as we go on
four datasets may be huge in both both in terms of numbers of if you
think flat file both in terms of number of variables and in terms of the
number of cases but also in terms of complexity
the relationships between these things i'm talking about flat file here but as we will
see things can be much more complicated
most of these the variables
the only way
most of these the variables to be relevant
and also
and this is really a problem here
most cases will be fraud is the classic data mining
anomaly detection type problem if you like
we really are looking for a needle in a haystack and i'll give you some
figures on those in a moment
there is an evolutionary arms race
i'm going to talk in detail about this
basically what i mean by that is the forces on standing still i don't just
have one method they used when that stopped it stop as we have seen
there's a leapfrog of prevention and detection the banks
telecoms agencies or whatever
put in place a a method for stopping a certain kind of fraud
that they build a nest for detecting a certain kind of fraud and put in
place a method for detecting
and then cycles round and i'll illustrate that the examples there's also a leapfrog of
operations and exploration
you have accumulated database from the past two years
to enable you to construct advanced detection
algorithms you put them into
and then
that collects you collect more data through that cycle around again
and i've already referred to the fact that fraud may involve complex data types most
of the data but i'm going to be talking about a simple numerical data are
mostly i'm going to be talking about flat files but
if if i get to the scientific fraud part will see images and other kinds
of data as well being used in fraud
a little comment about the role of data fusion data fusion integrating data from multiple
there are all sorts of issues associated with this which are not really going to
talk about just a little bit on this slide which they fusion complicates disclosure risk
we had
doesn't matter interactions here
these are conditionally independent given the data which is very important
it's very important for these to be conditionally independent given the data so you can
get the right distribution is much less important together i distribution here
we get the content ourselves with settling towards equilibrium distribution here the free state here
would like the true
conditional distribution here
he learns these
four hundred times
about a million connections here
and then he learns these amazing connections here
and then learns these half half-million connections here
when he learns the second
level connections he puts in latin int
the interconnections among the units that are not visible
OK he didn't do any fine-tuning just degree learning like this
once he's learned
he can i generate it very very slowly
but we just want to see a few samples by generating correctly
so generate correctly this guy needs to go up and down a lot of times
between these two sets of units and each time it comes down
in this study these units one at the time
that's the correct question really needs going to generate stochastically
you know these units one at the time
get all of them
and then you can go back up again
and then you get again and again you lot of times
then the final step
you only have to go down once
that is with the top down input coming from here
you go through all these many times to reach an equilibrium sample given this and
then with an equilibrium sample you got here
if this were connected to go through these many times but they're not so you
just get on it
so it's really the top on third pick because you have to go and down
many times time come down you have to go through units sequentially
that's why we don't use it for learning
but now you can look at how well it doesn't generating natural image patches
these are real natural image patches from manhattan's database
and if you're trying to model just like the one i showed you but without
the lateral interactions
so generating talk to
but you train like in normal
deep belief nett with no
lateral interactions within
you get get clouds basically these have the same second order statistics is the data
but they
a lot
a lot of the structure images which is
forty speaking images nothing happens and then suddenly stuff happens
and then nothing times something most of this stuff like edges
so you sort of see here there's not much of an analog
you see in this one percent nothing then something something interesting thing
these don't really look like that
OK so what happens if we just train the same model with these latter interactions
it takes longer to train is called more parameters because the actual interactions gives you
qualitatively different models
right now it has the property
not is not as well as natural images but much much better than the previous
think of
you know there's not much of making this stuff happening here and here
and you know this looks much more like get in natural images than what you
get if you don't use lateral interactions
now i want to emphasise this is very funny way of using markov random fields
remember says that the vision people
because all vision people
i believe the following
so dangerous statement
they believe that if you use the markov random field and you can do inference
the way it's going to work is this
you can have a markov random field between your hidden variables line show you some
data and you are going have to do inference to figure out
what the what a correct sample from your hidden variables is given you got this
markov random field
that's not what we're going do
well we're going to do is
if i give you some data
even though you learn this model with all these lateral interactions
when you do inference
you're just going to go through these the transpose this way matrix and you can
ignore these latter interactions to for the states of the units
the lateral interactions just don't come into it in doing inference
what happens in your brain is yours in your visual cortex they get initial activity
and then we'll actually interacts and they settled that
and they change what they do
and everybody interprets that as they get a better model of the world
i think they're getting worse model of the world i think what they get in
an initial state is the best model of the world
and then there corrupting it with what they believe so they can do learning so
they get a better signal from learning
well that's what i believe sometimes when i'm doing diebold's machines ability of the story
if you think about
so that some enforcing constraints when you do generations
but how they helping the inference and learning
if you ask why do people want date
people wanting data to get rid of the pairwise correlations so they can concentrate on
higher order correlations because the pairwise correlations to have nearly all the power
any system this modelling the powers correlations if it sort of try to change parameters
to model the higher correlation slightly better
but in doing that it's slightly messes up his model the pairwise correlations it among
want to make that change because so much more power in the power was correlations
those are the most important things to right so if you want to sort of
see those
low-power higher order correlations which of the interesting things
through this sort of a lot of these strong pair wise correlations you better get
rid of the pairwise correlations
and that's what you want in data
so we try to remove the statistics
so the natural way to think about learning multilevel models is to say
OK let's learn hidden
once we have learned that the the pairwise correlations
so let's remove those before find higher order correlations
and in a sense that's what we're doing
but we're doing it in a way this much faster than actually removing
because we cannot allow inference to go much faster than you could if you actually
have to remove the pairwise correlations before you go to the next step
so we're going to do
it is
we can wind the learning signal that is we're going to get the same learning
so we will explain
again as i said earlier u
the don't physics because that's clearly outside are
i think satisfy
neurophysiological explanations is not available today although
it's quite a bit published
on this the literature
i've tried to read up on it
and it comes down to it
stimulation of these
brains in a special way
flickering the lights
on the cells of the retina
and then the brains just tell you that you see color
what can we do about this is is not
i don't speak too fast they wanted cause
and if you go too slowly then you don't seem very rarely the optimum around seven hrs
five ten hertz you one is fine
so in the morning we always play a little bit with that
get it right the twenty words it fades away
the electorate try to challenge my audience
and i am
always make them longer perhaps these in a little bit
and at the same time trying to teach them from physics
students like that
and i see no reason why should make an exception for u
and last two six questions
six questions about three miles
and i know that all you've looked at rainbows
but looking at something is very different from seeing it
and i'm not going to test to
she whether you've never seen rainbows
now that i like u
because when i teach
my freshman about this i ask them fifteen questions about
only six liu
what is the radius of the rainbow
and some of you in the audience may say rabies was how can you talk about the radius
well when you see a rainbow
then it looks like an arc in the sky
like so
you may be horizon
and since it is argued that is a circle somewhere in the mid point
the midpoint could be below right and of course stay here
and so you have a distance here
that you can express in terms of an angle
and that angle can be expressed in terms of so many degrees
now i don't expect you to know the exact answer
is it and degrees
so ninety degrees is a twenty degrees
what is approximately so that's what i mean by angle
in terms of angle
because sequence
is the readout sites
what is already inside or that depend maybe on the time of the day
maybe the time of the year
have you ever noticed that there is a huge difference in brightness
of this guy
when you see a rainbow
this guy
is much brighter in certain areas than it is in other areas and i can ask new
whereas it very bright and whereas it very dark
all relative to the rainbow
and then comes the question is there more than one well maybe there is a
second well maybe there is a third one
and if there is a second one was its colour sequence is a red outside
the real outside
now comes the question number six either both polarized already gave it away didn't i
in my introduction i said we all know
should know
that the both polarized
so you think you're going to get away
which question number six but there is no such thing as a free lunch here
so i'm going to change this question into
why i the
that's a hard question
one of the answer to all six
only models
raise your hands
physics professor and my two
my page my personal physician
michael zero
on this man
one of the few and the mighty
well as this expressions only data five
on more workers just expired
visual sensor so this is some input from the retina and then you whatever the
size of its input the model of the neuron is that your summing up these
imports and then your firing
when that some reaches a certain threshold and you i think you would write this
threshold here b that was
not rose let's model of a neuron it with mcculloch and pitts but it's mcculloch
and pitts in nineteen forty three
so it's quite an old model
you know
i actually was quite excited by this type of model and the major innovation for
the multilayer perceptron was instead of this being a threshold we turn this into a
smooth function
which meant you could do differentiation and you can make multiple they versions of this
so you would have another important here
and basically put the whole thing together so you've got some important you would feed
forward through make your classification and very much i was inspired to come into
machine learning because of these models i think a big disappointment for me
was some
i actually worked out so there was a problem with this
multilayer perceptron idea
because if you go multi-layered versions turned on
this one move away
so if the multi-layered versions of or maybe should
you can hear me OK good if you do multi-layered versions of this if you've
got threshold units there was this problem of how you work out what the
responsibility for the error here is because you your objective function was discontinuous you can
compute gradients and i think it's it's published in a i that in nineteen ninety
i want to an algorithm for doing that i was very excited because it was
written as a big open problems in machine learning how you do the multilayer networks
of these linear threshold units
and when i published it no one cared because it wasn't an interesting problem because
we've moved beyond that
that model in two ways one no one thought of as a realistic model of
the brain and to
no of course it is practically useful way of doing classification so in some sense
we can see that now
but i think we go back to say the early fifties and we look at
rosales work with early computers what you see is he's got
an extremely
fast way of doing classification
that was published this based on the model of a neuron that was published in
less than a decade ago
as the way the brain works i think that would be
at the time would be considered very exciting things so
now we can look back and say
not really how the brain works but it's not some interesting aspects and the reason
i wanted to talk about it here is because it's this interesting aspects of learning
of the you've got something that you need to adapt so in that case
these weights here
and what you adapting those weights according to is what you observe to be the
class we'll talk what your supervision signal is and what your input signal is right
so in the world i think examples of
similar models that were based on very simple learning rules hebbian learning time rules which
you know again i don't know much about but i understand one point it was
taken very seriously in cognitive science see reinforce connections where you see things on together
in same time and those sort of models include things like the hopfield network and
bolss machines which are making a big comeback at the moment
OK so
i don't want to talk much more about that learning rule or what the objective
function is but what i want to do is to talk about something i spend
more time working on which is regression
so that's less connected to the brain but i'm going to follow a similar path
of trying to show you regression we know how to do regression
regression was invented
by sort of physicists around the turn of the nineteenth century for fitting a physical
models the universe two
observations of whether planets were it was reinvented by golden he called regression statistician inside
of the turn of the twentieth century
and it's basically the same a different type of supervised learning but the
the target now has a real value given some set of inputs
one of my favorite data sets on this is predicting the quality of meat given
spectral measurements is take it or data so you've got some sort of set spectral
measurements and you want to predict they measure to meet you want to predict what
the quality of that meat was
that means we have similar structures
but the interesting thing is the whole concept in that has where
you need to be
the structure and global media finds for for
in one of four pass what is
this is the shortest distance
from this no
well spread
you want to find the supposed
for about this
we are
the structure of
i find it
hard to get very efficient index
which is why simple is
and why
and of course many many pass
so all these formation
but the shortest path is very
it is the last one short novels
those reasons why
there's one small
five percent that's only one
well that's all
so you already know that this is really five v five stories and this one
one year
so thank you get this one is
want to give you
the shortest path
he or also showed vast majority that can
well i think about this
that's it because of
but i feel more interesting similarity
sir is a structure
so for example
five crystals follows is going to or or speech innovation or speech
it was most
this is
this is a hard question
just because
actually and all
full what this
for example the
the christmas
he said you're looking for authors
using this
there like his phd students long-term collaborator where we also
the black last
but what about the conferences wall
nine people see set of conferences
like this
five different set of land use
different parts
their research which
you got
you can see also different as good
do sense
so we
the what is the author or a
is of
this the key
or a
the other
one final reasons because he
the only goal
you get a couple answers
is called the similarity
she was
almost majority were his phd students
he said no no no don't know
i think they are do you see
but the interesting thing is
it follows is most cell
in order to try out
the reason is even the authors papers
an image basically yeah typically is used only as a particularly convenient
representation for inference in this H DPN and hierarchical Pitman Yor process type of models okay  so for both
the nested CRP and the Chinese restaurant franchise we see that we get trees which
are not not necessarily binary trees right so we could for example
have it that this three tables get merged into one table up here so they could
be like more than one no that could be coagulations involving more than two clusters
at the same time okay we could also construct hierarchy random trees where
each node of the tree will split into exactly two children okay and you could do that
by actually taking kind of a continuum limit of this partition valued Markov chain sorry
recall that for both this process and this process we get this rand this random
this sequence of either random fragmentations or random coagulations and they are
both Markov chains of partitions and we can take this Markov chain and take
a continuum time limit where we get kind of like a continuous time Markov jump process over over a
random partitions and that it turns out that in that case you could actually derive that the
trees that you get are will all be binary I guess I'm kind
of running out of time so I won't really describe it but you could do that in
the case of the nested CRP the continuum  time limit model called
the Dirichlet diffusion tree and this is a model that was proposed by
Neal  actually even before the nested CRP by Redford Neal who used it
for doing  density estimation and is basically the continuum time time limit of the
of the nested CRP and more recently there has been generalization of
the the Dirichlet diffusion tree to Pitman Yor diffusion trees where Knowles and Ghahramani took the
basically the continuum time limit of a nested chinese restaurant process
where the Chinese restaurant process is what two parameter Chinese restaurant processes  similarly you
can take the continuum time limit of the Chinese restaurant franchise and you can show
that that corresponds to a model that came from genetics long time ago called
Kingman's coalescent which is a basically a standard model for modelling genealogies in population genetics
there're also generalizations called the called the lambda coalescent  I guess I'll skip this
bit okay and and both the Dirichlet diffusion tree and the and the kingman's
coalescence produce random trees which are binary trees so every internal node of the
tree  will always produce two children there are ultrametric trees in the sense that
the leaves are all the same distance away from from the root and
they're random right okay so this are what's called ultrametric trees there are  in fact more
other constructions for random trees and which have been people in probability theory have explored
and these are things like Gibbs fragmentation trees continuum random trees and standard additive coalescent
and so forth so I guess these are kind of things which people who do
modelling of data hasn't really explored that much okay any questions about trees
yes I don't think
there is actually a particular reason for choosing fragmentation over coagulation or vice-versa it seems
that they're all just different trees and if you you can actually generate from these trees
and they'd look quite different okay but in general I don't think there's a particular
reason to choose one over the other you know it's up to your fancy really okay yes
how do you evaluate the trees arm in quantitatively
okay so in the topic models I think it really depends on your application right
so they have used it for things like topic modelling and they have evaluated topic
models quantitatively using perplexity scores like how perplexity is  this score which basically
measures how well it is predicting words that is not seen before and I guess I
think they did find that it  works  somewhat better than than LDA I think more
recently people in the topic modelling literature have been also more interested in how the
issue with perplexity is that it's a quantitative measure but it's not neccessarily
a measure that actually corresponds to what people do with with topic models the way people use
topic models is as a way of summarizing a document corpus so they've been looking
at kind of different ways in which you could evaluate topic models in terms of how
well are they summarizing a document corpus and also how well how well they actually
describe topics which are perceptually coherent okay you have question or
yes yes so we have actually used Kingman's coalescent
this sort of a random trees as a model for doing hierarchical clustering and you can
actually evaluate it we actually evaluated it in a few way one way
is to kind of look at what's called purity scores basically scores which relate the
true underlying clustering to the tree that you have and they do seem to work
a lot better than all of the all of the linkage algorithms you can use
it for things like filling in basically if the data at each leaf
of your tree is partially observed so there might be a few entries that
you do observe few entries which you didn't observe right then you can build this tree and
then you can use the other data items to help you fill in the entries in
your in in your data vectors which you did not observe and then you can
look at how well they did it do that fill that filling in it's basically a
predictive type of process and again you can see that that actually works much better than
but first
remember so this is just a recap from
yes it comes from the commission's in fact she said that there exist for the
system itself
OK there is such kind of it that he
they don't suppose we want to do is human beings also there in the data
for a between vector of body cavities prime you can show that it is positive
semidefinite cases it is symmetric of course and if you compute like the
the metrics of inner product spaces
we also saw some the kind of this that we can all the question
the RBF kernel is also all symmetric positive definite kernels
so there exists
one of the curvature that is that in fact
giving a positive definite kernel
in a sense is equivalent to
giving the structure to you by the structure of a hilbert space about space
that's what that's like hilbert space with an inner product
let's forget about the
other properties so that he was start from space where there is no stranger to
a set of points five point five b
the reason for that is that the set
but positive and you can also function k
two those similarities for me then we will think about that
two defining
prior to finding a space on the right which is a vector space is what
are also some because the space is that can do mitigation but can i can
in fact the it
following form of the most prominent in the nineteen fifties is that
a function k is on this space basis is positive definite
if and only if so there is an equivalence
if you think about space age so this space
with some you know for that
and mapping phi
that goes from the initial state to the hilbert space
so that the value of the can also k of six prime
is equal
so the inner product in the space
between the images
your point by
because we find these things for every spring
so the picture on the beach here really shows that is that you have
initial space without any structure as long as you give me a function k that
is positive it as is
you gave me but the right you can function from its points here to the
and then we can also the synapse between two points here is exactly the inner
products of the product
so the
between the images of the points
OK so that's a very strong so this is one of the reasons why we
focus on that that as long as give me such a search function you give
me a lot of things in fact is beginning and ending of your space into
a vector space
so we just spend few minutes to try to give some ideas on how to
prove that because this will make some interesting things first so here o you want
to prove their existence a there is an argument between two things there is one
direction to prove which is easy
the notion that if
if you define a function k as the inner product space
it is easy to prove that this thing is positive semidefinite why is it the
case just for this line symmetry because inability symmetry and this was different because they
never that is being
this is the easy part
now the other mission is
i suppose you give me a positive definite kernel
how can we prove that
it can be written in a product space
so in fact he took what he is not so easy and find was actually
you could you could prove it is in the US you going to find basis
for a finite set of points that can just be metrics which is positive semidefinite
and the problem there are simply means that you can asymmetric actually so this is
very very traditional
now if you want to use any of the organisation you need you can do
it only on this is set of can and but they can also called mass
of kernels which are defined as continuous functions on compact spaces so it seems a
bit technical just for those of you interested in but so is if you if
you function k is continues in your space is compact then you can extend to
provide the information because you have come back to writers and so on and this
was done in nineteen five by third example accounts
but this is still a bit restricted because for instance if you take the question
on on our
it's not the massacre
so it's continues with the space are not compact OK so you cannot apply
this proves that he doesn't the mission consisted in
in fact the way present before nineteen fifty announced and chance paper that was formed
in the general case that whatever the space k
so whatever the space ace combat or not
what the function k continuous and that's the term is true in the sense that
for any
but if you can no longer any space that is the human space so that
k of crime is equal to the inner product between the images
and the way to prove that was
was introduced space which i want to describe how quickly
because we're gonna use it later on we can thought this space is called the
reproducing kernel hilbert space
so it's a bit
i'm in my name
current name usually so this is simply called rkhs RKHS you think of the RKHS
a space of functions
OK so functions of functions that go from your space
it is
to the real numbers
and in fact as soon as you so not describe everything about architecture rules but
the idea is that as soon as you have account all
then together we can overcome one
OK yes
well start no
with the second part of this
the tar so i'm going to build on what proper talked about
i mean particularly going to
in this part of the talk we're going to try to understand what can active
learning do for us
when need help much does it help
what are its draws and so on so we already saw the main idea is
closing the loop between the data collection process the observations and sampling
and we saw that
you can
possibly by lot but also curiosity can kill the cat if you are focusing too
much on something
you might miss the world so if you look trying to learn about the forest
and if you're looking only at one tree you'll miss forest
so these are going to focus on the very simple problems are very simple
problems maybe
some would say contrived settings but this is what is going to give us a
good idea
what can be done
in particular i'm going to be very interesting
answering this second question how much can be gained
and of course in answering this question rule
also learning
ways of taking advantage of the sampling feedback
and hopefully get some insight about
ways of constructing algorithms that
that do this and will actually part three will talk a little bit about some
of those are reasons
for that session
a little outline here we're going to talk about this
very simple binary classification problems it's going to be one dimensional threshold estimation problems
i'm going to review
the probabilistic classification framework rather
and under this framework was going to quantify
the active learning gains for this
simple setting and also
show what active learning can do
what are the lower bound for the fundamental limitations
generalizes this to multiple and mentions in the
so what happens next
let's consider a very simple problem so you're trying to
learned threshold say the transition between dark and light is
forested areas shaded areas like then you're trying to learn
we're just like the tree canopy and the prairie starts
and more abstractly say function like this it's zero two point in n one and
you're just trying to learn that function
figure out what data studies
and let's say you do this from noisy observations this so you say
so what's the value of the function at this point zero point eight and use
cases that one but it could be something noise it could be
could be zero with some probability could be something different than one like one point
five one three that's like that so
but to make a point samples of observations of this function
so the goal here is to learn this threshold status as accurately as possible
OK so if you're doing passive learning
you cannot use this feedback between
observations on the sampling so if you have to ask
and questions about this function
o point samples to learn about a just are
what where when you ask the questions
if you don't know
it already is
the only reasonable thing to do
especially as this and question somewhat uniformly distributed over the entire domain between zero and
so just put your and samples over there
and let's say there was nice
it collects observations
and you see this and immediately get
they just are must be between this application this application
your error is going to be on the order of one over so it's going
one you and sample space using samples is on europe one of around so your
error in estimating the research
it's going to be
rather like one around but if you look at this to see that you are
wasting too many samples once you've so observations of all the samples are collected here
are completely useless
all these two really matter so you're
we think a lot of
information here
so if you're doing passive active learning what you do well you do binary binarisation
everyone knows about this
now take a sample right in the middle point one half see also wants status
must be to the left
data to support the last
that must be to the right of that point
OK now which it which corner does win
the grad student right because the 3 corners are I could figure out the cost
is here the PhD is doing all the work solving all 4 problems working for
hours for 20 got
here a grad student is doing all the work working for hours 3 dollars an
hour for 12
yeah the computer's doing all the work
only has to work 2 hours but it's clusters 8 dollars an hour so this
is 16 dollars pulse so 68
is that right
yeah 16 28
or 12 so the winner is
the optimum is there gratitude
but that was this was a small problem where we could check all corners and
my point was can't do that usually so now I speak about the simplex method
started some corner
but I need some preliminary method to find the corners suppose I start at corner
cornerpiece so start and the idea of the simplex method will be
to move to another corner and neighbouring corner
what's and neighbouring corner on on on a 1 of these high-dimensional deals
and neighbouring corner means
1 of the axes
1 of the axes that 1 0 well look at the area it the x
at this point
what happens if I moved to the court
1 some drops to 0
and some other X you could say
X 1 leaves the basis is when I travel appear
and x 2
3 rather enters base
I'm using word basis for the free X 1 and 2 it leaves the leaves
the solution becomes 0 and a different 1 x 3 enters a solution
becomes non-zero
and the cost is reduced
went from 20 dollars down to 60
OK then I look around from this course
which way shall I go
I go along an edge to the next 1
so I could go along this edge
or along this edge
so I compute
which way is the best way to go
when I go this way my computations to show on worst costs more
when I go this way it costs less and reducing the cost so course go
that way until I can't go any further because I'm reducing reducing the more work
the grad student does at the more work that's taken away from the computer and
given the the grad student much cheaper
more as I travel down here I'm giving more and more work the grad student
until I reached that point
when I can't take away any more work from the computer and the computer is
is no longer doing anything dropped 0
but in this case the entering variable was the grad student number 2
and the leaving variable was a computer 3 and it left the point of dropping
a 0 the grad student moved up from 0 to something whatever it for whatever
something it took just
to satisfy the constraint and I have added new corn
now I look around from that corners and
the simplex method of courses and know it's got to x so it would look
around it would say there are 2 ways I can move from here
but they both
mean cost increase so I must be at the winner
so that's
that's the idea of the simplex method start somewhere started some corner
move travel along edges
reducing the cost every time
and until you get to edge where you can
because cannot be reduced and that's that's the text the winners
so that's the simplex method now I have to tell you
how the simplex method chooses the age to travel
well not quite
how many
now could
the two
in fact
i i i
i that
and i am i
in that period time
now it
i mean that
so how can
so i can
you have
my life
that that
i field
you can
we are not
for change
there at all the functions
and he signed by
thank you
but i find
and that true
and i
i trying
three years
i mean
so much
if you think that
having at least
a question
i present
thank you
this is my true
o soviet strictly OK in this kind of games you don't need to have been
done so far
to find
this strategy can be so-called memoryless
in the study
he said in which position what you're going to play
it doesn't depend on the history
two and so why is it important
there's also very important if you want to compute
so this is part of your question on the reserve and it's just
if i give you mission
not so if i gave you pretty game
with the starting
now we're not with the start position on the political i give you an arena
with colours
it's a copy with well defined game how to play
so parity games
i want to compute positions
so that players you'll have extracted from this position
can become
to thank you see said
and if you are familiar with the you can compute it
can you can compute
copy of winning position
and this will cost you
like you know and people
yes it's NP into clint PY because as it is that mines issued warnings
so it's as easy to
so i with the other one
its dual system it is hard to see that you losers of the two
well because one win so you just exchange the wall of the players
and the argument very quickly
and then the damage but
you get strategy it's easy
it's so small object because you're so you guessed which outgoing transition you choose from
your position
basically here
popular zero
these rules
and here can guess one
so we start from we start from here
have to get this
both rules so it's wonderful
for this one because we're not go there
you choose not going out
that is your strategy which is with one
and now that know that
you can have
the take
and you check that in the remaining graph
and this is infinitely often
black position
and say
you do it for the first position and the it's things like this position you
guess arrows rules for this position gives you for its position you guess if there
are the guests
if they do you put it in the winning region and to check whether
in a given graph hidden things from something this is pulling them
and you it
this is just so you guess the road to real time that they are really
so this gives you an MP
and then p algorithm
what to do next time
the time
one the two things
i would say that in that very
very simple
they can be
i think
my priority is non deterministic parity tree automata
this is this QA on top and everything
take one
i do right from it
so what they came in way
i will
enable me to
from the initial state
will be in charge of
choosing the transition
you have to guess the computation which is accepting
so sitting in fourth
i want to answer whether my automaton accepts so
so players e
will play in the arena where players zero
the current label will be
this is not too big because finding many inputs on my note
good guesses
the label
it should be put on the model if
and it's also guesses
will be chosen
would be in this current states and there would be this label given to
my automaton nondeterministic
given some
state and
label of the input tree
so i have to choose the there
of states
going to
my run
in the full binary tree
so low here
i have to choose
see that
this one
you're over
what i mean is set q a a
i have to guess whether my computation goal
keep going using
this is like it will make you a right by
by topic or vice versa
so i guess i have to choose
the two brains automaton will be look
would be
i mean state q
form mean some positions
this might have information about the current state of the automaton i have to choose
what i put here
and knowing what they could hear what the truth
you have to guess
nor can i talk about existence constraints so i want to say that all instances
of paper must have an awful
OK so must have an awful which is the person
all papers must have at least three reviewers
i can represent any that using RDF schema disappears and language learning to do that
nor can i say things about properties of the relationship can be characterized the relationship
to say that there transitive perhaps they have inverses
it's also although this is kind of rather weak on this is also a rather
strong as well kind of in almost paradoxically that because there are many things i
can say with RDF i can do some quite sophisticated metamodelling OK so i can
say things about classes are treated as individuals and so on so we can actually
quite hard for me to provide
reasoning support for the kind of RDF inference
so i have this problem the RDF is kind of in some ways week in
a language that allows me to express kind of isn't rich enough to capture some
of the relationships among capture my domain but also it's actually quite strong in other
so the proposed solution was to extend RDF schema with a language which has a
number of desirable characteristics should extend existing web standards to ensure that we can sit
within this space we can interoperating can make tools
it should be easy to understand and use this is of course a kind of
subjective terms
it should have adequate expressive power OK so again this is subjective based on the
context of application that you have
it should be formally specified so that we can provide some reasoning support and this
is the proposed that language that was out there with me he's these requirements
there some insights on the history of volcanic already covered some of this so all
i'll skip over these again these are in the slide so you can you can
read them
so essentially what we have
this we have
a number of different languages
and i say something more about the details of what's actually in the language later
on but i always was constructed to have what was called layer and this allowed
us to basically provides languages which had a very limited expressivity
OK so depending on the application that we had the requirements that you had you
could choose a language with different layer of
so for example we have all fall
which is the union of
the OWL syntax is all the operator's dl language and vocabulary with RDF with little
restrictions on them
there's a language called OWL DL talk talk about more about later
which was the restrict the restriction of the use of all two language which corresponds
to a fragment of first-order logic and reason why this was chosen because this that
allows us to do some reasoning OK so this allows us to have an inference
based on existing algorithms which we know has kind of nice characteristics
there is also a language called OWL lite which is simply a subset of OWL
and these languages are layered so we have what we call syntactic layering so essentially
a light ontology that i can write down is also an DL ontology and any
OWL DL ontologies also now full ontology and certainly as semantic layering whereby any inferences
that we can draw using these languages will correspond case any inference we can do
in OWL lite should correspond to inference which is done in algeria
so powerful
with an awful there is no restriction on the use of the OWL vocabulary OK
so i can i can essentially produce our RDF graphs make use of OWL vocabulary
and there's no restriction on what i can do i can say anything
and this is
the semantic here given in terms of the RDF style model theory i'm not going
to talk about the details of this kind of if you interested in looking up
looking at some of the details of this that i continue around
so the URL is kind of the presentation so you can go and look at
the information here it is on the w three c site in the documentation
associated RDF
so i bl
here we have the use of vocabulary is being restricted in some way
so that we can do some of the things we can do now
and now falls so for example we can modify the vocabulary itself so we're not
allowed to say things about language itself we have some restrictions on the math modelling
that we can perform here
and we have what we call that we have a model theory which is based
on some first order logic description logic model theory so there's some direct correspondence here
between the subset and subset of first-order logic which will will see more about a
and one of the benefits here was the
we were able to kind of leverage off so a number of years of research
into the representation languages so we had some well defined semantics we have known properties
of how we could reason with these languages have known properties but the behaviour of
reasoning with these languages in terms of the complexity the decidability and so on
OWL lite was enough for the subset here with with a few constructs now in
practice i think with hindsight the
the experience seems to be the OWL lite not really the kind of particularly picked
up there the fragments which kind of sit somewhere around like the people are actually
really using in practice
OK so all goal
OK so this is this is probably quite important here
the semantics of the OWL DL fragment given using a model theoretic approach
OK so i have
i have an interpretation
OK which describes
the semantics in terms of a collection of objects and some functions that map my
classes to sets of objects i'm really kind of thinking of the classes in my
ontology as collections of objects in my domain can
and also my properties to pairs of objects properties are relating pairs of objects together
the classes of describing sets of objects in the domain
in this in this approach
class descriptions and characterisation of the individuals that are members of that class
so what we have now is we have
vocabulary that allows us to describe
classes of individuals OK and we have operators to allow kind of form together combine
those those those
classes into composite descriptions
so i have a number of operators for constructing class expressions
so basically we can we can talk about
underlying classes
so here i have an example which is a basic class which is the class
of humans case so these are
this this the interpretation here would be a collection of individuals in my domain which
at time t
the acceleration took place at an earlier time
because the radiation has to reach me
so t prime
it is then t
minors are divided by c is always the time delay
that's the reason
why we write down these equations
so i right now than in all weights
its glory weighted you would find it in most books
so this is not a e vector
due to an accelerated charged
you may choose the direction are
and is a function of time
and that now becomes
minus i'll get back to the minus sign
then i get a perpendicular at time t prime
whereas this is at time t
that is the connection between the two
proportion the charge
divided by c squared
four pi
epsilon zero and just one hour
you have the privilege
to convert not conferred
right down for me or for yourself
what is associated be feel this
it's very easy of course the strength of the b field is see times smaller
you must make sure that the crosby is in the direction of propagation
so i'll leave you with that
and then we get
that the poynting vector
as a function
of rt
is then e crosby
divided by new zero
and there you have the entire set
tells me
what electric field is
due to the acceleration but the magnetic field is to tune acceleration and now
what the
the poynting vector is
how many joules per second for
square meter flow out
a perpendicular
is different for different directions
if i call this angle theta
a perpendicular is zero
if i am looking down here because then A's taught me there is no perpendicular
if i am
in this direction than a perpendicular is the same as a
so you see
that the strength of the electric field
is a strong function of that angle theta
so what you're going to see is that a spherical we're going out from this
accelerated charge
but the electric field strength in that spherical wave going on all directions is the
strongest in this plane here perpendicular to a and is zero
in that direction
and so i would like to make is somewhat different
somewhat simplified
picture for you
to stress the connection
and to also address the minus sign
so if this is the direction
of the acceleration in a
so i put a vector in here
then this is a perpendicular let's first choose the direction of or
these are
you can show that any way you want to sort and this would be a
and if the charge is positive
which i have chosen here because look the field lines go away
then the vector perpendicular is in this direction
it's like so
and that is the reason for the minus sign
if q is positive
he is in the opposite direction of a perpendicular if q is negative then it
is in the same direction
and then
you get that is angle theta is very important
the vector
is proportional to sign of failure
because a perpendicular
is of course eight times the sign of theta
and so the vector in the the vector have signs of theta in the
and the poynting vector cosine square data in the
because this as a sign of data and this as a sign of data
so the poynting vector s
is proportional
two designs scroll fader
and so sort spherical waves going in all their actions
the poynting vector is very different for the different directions
the amount of energy per second that flows out
per square metre in the plane perpendicular to the arbitration is very high
and it is zero in this direction if you look here you would see nothing
if you look here
what's the maximum and anything in between
you would see
less than the maximum at more than zero
so this is really
a plane wave
infinitely in all its if anything is more spherical
and that is the plane wave
however if you very far away from the origin
you can probably locally approximated by
a plane wave solution
so now i want to summarize for you
basically what i want you to remember and which is all that i remember
and that is how do you find the vector
if you know the acceleration
and you know where you are in space
we accelerate q
and we do not in the direction a
and you are
some position in space are
they you observe an electromagnetic wave
but you observe time delay
which i'm not further
expand on
now comes the key thing that the field
this the approach
and a
you can confirm that was
this picture there
so what are you choose you may choose any are you want to also outside
the blackboard of course this is just for simplicity
e vector
must be in that plane
but the factory
must be perpendicular to or
maxwell's equations the man that e vectors perpendicular to the direction of propagation for a
traveling wave
the magnitude of the vector
is proportional
two the magnitude
of the a perpendicular
and the magnitude of e
is proportional to one of our
and if q is positive
then e is in that direction
mine is a perpendicular if q is negative then it is in the direction
of a perpendicular
there's another paper we
employed a similar strategy
but where we still have this markov chain idea although it's not necessary for marketing make during training
so now the black box is a bit more complicated sequence like boxes
is the same box we use all right all again
and the box has
in addition to
the random numbers going in the parameters coming in
it has a previous state coming in and out of the next state
so so now
you take the previous state from the
preview the output the the next day the previous application of this red box
this is the next paper was previously for the next one
and basically what doing here is is a markov chain
it turns out that it's possible to train the markov chain
using as a training criterion
the reconstruction error criterion we find autoencoders
come back to that later
something very very simple you can find by backdrop
so what are the things that has happened recently is that we realize that we can
we can avoid this these
these markov chains are an essentially use backprop
train these generative models
it is also how we try be
be deep and very deep
generative industrial needs
there is
a set of related approaches
which avoid again these these
these markov chains
at unit during training
i have come up in the last nine months roughly
well so there's much more the
called helmholtz machines from the mid nineties
game geoff hinton was part of the gang
in the since starting about
last december review papers are starting to come out
more coming out
ways to build what's called a directed graphical models
but avoids some of these
intractability that have been associated with these kinds of models in the past
in the first these
which i think is gonna have a lot of impact
is a paper was presented i cleared doesn't fourteen but
tech report came out in december two thousand thirteen
kingman dwelling
which is about what i call variational autoencoders the title their paper something about bayesian variational something autoencoders but it's
the world is different but it's the same idea
and the idea is
he realized was already in house machine paper from ninety five
you can have you are
generative network which is just a sequenceof
you are stochastic or deterministic
at the top level you inject something that looks like noise and output generators samples
so that's the thing picture i showed before but now has multiple layers
that's the key
so that's
your model
at the joint distribution between
the visible
some latent variables
visible and latent period age
but you're gonna learn another perhaps cuba
which has associated joint distribution
which is driven by the training data so that when it comes from the bottom
in predicts what the latent variables should be through multiple layers which could be stochastic or not
this kind of setup
there has been a lot of work recently
and the target propagation thing i mentioned
earlier as part of the thing as well
so you notice that
there's a kind of falling water here if you've faulty
you start from the one which is
example from the dataset you will
you get a representation
and that's what
the output of an encoder basically
but stochastic one
then you go back down from the people at the decoder
and you're trying to make
examples are generated very close to
your original input
that's reconstruction air so the way these are trying actually is very similar to
we're trying to autoencoders
but there are a few bells and whistles are different which
seem to be important actually
what is an autoencoder is just
a particular kind of neural net
in which is decomposed into functions then called an equal
and there's something in between which is a representation in computing
the encoder and the decoder trying to be inverses eachother but
are not just arbitrary inverse otherwise you could just identity function
you're trying to
encoder decoder to work well the ones to have low reconstruction error
only for the training examples
but potentially give
hi reconstruction error elsewhere far from examples
well the all way of doing this is to make me
he later small
smaller than the input
one special case of this of course is principal components analysis if the encoder is linear inequalities in here
and the reconstruction error squared here like like in this line
and then you get peace you essentially
but if you introduce nonlinearities now you can learn
much more interesting things
one thing you might know is that you see is is equivalent to modeling
he input with eh
guassian in multivariate calcium
one autoencoders nonlinearities allow you to do is the model more complicated distributions than the gas in
indeed reconstruction doesn't have to be square area could be
any kind of like actually so you can use the usual cross entropy
which is just the log conditional like you
you can think of the reconstruction error is just minus log
he of x given age in other words you have representation age
from fact that the output of the encoder
and from its you're trying to predict
the probability
be original input and you want the probability to be as large as possible
all right
now there is he
there's been a number of different
types of what call have been proposed in the literature in the last saw
eight years
there's one
on which there has been a lot more
mathematical work and anything be understanding of what they do
has reached a point where r on
it helps to draw a much clearer picture
what would and quarters are doing
they allow for repetitions of nodes could be of infinite length
so you similarity score would be infinity which is not what you want
two here this problem you don't wait longer walks
by using
a lambda
smaller than one
then you compute
this geometric series here
for values of k from zero to infinity
you obtain
as limit of this series
and then you add up over all entries
of the matrix
which is
one scalar and that's your similarity score
your kernel value for the two given graphs g and g-prime
but then we look at that
on the following slides
these random walk comments have their own
the runtime problem as we will see
these random walk kernels as they were defined in two thousand and two thousand three
required runtime of O of n to the six
and that's
are you trying time effort if you're working with large graphs
the second problem
cause tottering we also have a look at this problem
later on
it means
because you allow for repetitions of nodes in your walks
your walks
may visit
the same
set of nodes all over again
they may visit the same cycle over again or even in an undirected graph they
may go back and forth
between the same two nodes a and b all the time
thereby creating
a long common walk
in your two input graphs and thereby creating a huge similarity score just
because of one common edge
between the two input graphs
that's too
the phenomenon of tottering
there's another phenomenon that i observe which is
the problem of halting
let me go back to slides to show this
you have to choose
you're decaying factor lambda
so small
in order to make this
geometric series converge that you completely downweight any walk is longer than
ten of them
so basically
often you have to
choose your lambda so small that in the end of the day
you just comparing walks of length one
you two graphs and that
just a simple similarity measure between two graphs that compares all at all pairs of
of two input graphs G and G prime
so for example
if lambda is one over ten thousand then walks
of length one
get ten thousand times more weight in the kernel similarity score then walks of length
these again ten thousand times more than walks of length three and you can
imagine at the end of the day
the only thing that you're comparing all walks of length one
which means edges
that's the problem of quality
and these problems have inspired a lot of work in the machine learning community
especially in the community of common machines
and this research try to heal these
three problems the runtime problems the problem of tottering and the problem of halting. we will
have a closer look
of these approaches
we have look at
the method
achieved to
compute these random walk kernels much faster than was possible before
we'll have
closer look
the technique by my head out from ICML two thousand four
where they
propose to ways
of preventing tottering
and speeding up
graph kernel computation
and then this work
based on the idea here
rather compare shortest path into graphs
then walks thereby getting rid
after problem of torturing and halting
we start
by this approach by
vishwanathan et al from nips two thousand six
why is the
direct computation
after random
walk kernel
you know of n to the six
so they they they were using as a vertical control
just the
the addition of the activities of these two electrodes
and the horizontal control the subject it
so they have it's it's just two linear equations
then they
there some some gain parameter that they have to
control and that's it
let me
let me show
so so these are some
some pictures of of some
different users for different users and you see that first of all you see the
speed like
the paradigms such you have the ball in the centre
and then
in the periphery
there's some classes some boxes lighting up and you you're supposed to move to the
fall into these boxes
although the break
it says
they can this trajectory to point seven seconds
this one
this whole task i mean for example is going to longer twenty seven seconds so
you see from these these plots already that
the speed with which certain subjects can perform this task is very quite
but you can see also that there are some very good subjects and of course
i'm showing a video from the very good subject
i have some
i'm just watching it so peaceful
so in fact
if this
o point you the the block actually hits the target first
if you were there
i mean
it i think is a very impressive results because it's the first time that noninvasively
somebody did some some two d control
and it's very hard task and and you actually need to do some learning this
we have started to do some t two d work
a couple
in between years ago but it didn't work so well
but recently we've we've found
also some very good well working
strategy but you see that they can
even without training
OK so i i think
go to the plantation again
OK so
so with the new neural them training
you use
the sum and difference for controlled horizontal and vertical movements and you can see you
can see in the video how controlled is
let's talk about the invasive and and non-invasive side
in contrast so
i think
in in noninvasive world like from the application point of view that some
some patients like the eleven a-list patients from the obama
and they using this system
and i think there's lots of potential applications around which are not medical but which
are in the
human machine interface think side and will come to that later
if you think about visions in this in this invasive world there's very nice
nature inside article by nicholas where he's
so to say dreaming about the future of the series
and i think it's it's it's really a very interesting and worthwhile trying direction that
you just
so for example
the idea would be
in epilepsy
you could
when you have been planted areas you could actually
provide with some micro problems medication
if you
three u ary
i realize that there some seizure that is coming up
this is so this is a very very
interesting applications and of course the question is whether you can do this reliably with
pricey products also have help maybe this is also the reason because we had these incentives
for people to buy and recommend and rating so rating that is on the website
and comments it seems it doesn't play much role
so what do we want to say for for the future it seems like decision is
like more complex than just threshold or or simple diminishing returns curve right so I
hope like that after I showed you those those measurements now you saw that there are many other different factors that are
going on I don't know viral marketing or diffusion that you would like or that one has to
think about or at least would like to model and what also turns out that this for
viral marketing is that this context like so how how how expensive is the
item and what what area the item comes from right whether it's like some profess
professional organizational type of thing or it's more like leisure type of product so
what we can do now is ask how do cascades look like what I mean
by that is we would like to see what are the information propagation graphs right or something
so for example this is a cascade of medical guidebooks and again so the red edges
that I think you should be able to see are the ones that were successful
recommendations right you can see that most recommendations are not successful but this would mean that this person
made the recommendation here and they they followed the recommendation so again and
we have some something where where the thing propagated and the rest is just disconnected and similarly for
some DVD that is these giant piece where there was some propagation and the rest is just
a purchase and a recommendation to a single node and nothing happens so now the question is how
how do these structures look like if you go and count them alright so we basically want to
do count graphs and what I want to say is this right so how how do I
define it so let's let's have some social network and now we have some process that spreads
over the network and as it spreads it creates a graph right so we
start and then this thing spreads and it creates a cascade right so a cascade is just this
graph that is induced on the social network as the as the information or some
some adoption of something spreads over it and now we we'd like to go
and count these guys and see see what they are so for so this is for viral marketing right
this is the most common cascade where just somebody purchases a product and makes a recommendation nothing
happens and this is like in terms of the counts or the frequency in the counts
for seventy-five percent for books and CD's and so on while only twelve
percent for DVD's and then for example also what is going on is for
is that the split of recommendations or a purchase and and a recommendation is six
times or one point two times for DVD's more frequent than collision  of two recommendations but for
example for DVD's a collision collision of three is more frequent than a split on three
and then like chains are more frequent than collisions and this types of graphs are again
more frequent than collisions even though like collision is has less edges right has two edges versus
versus three edges or for example here a late split which means propagation and a split is more frequent than
a split and a propagation so just to show more examples right so here
this  this ones are have very like nice social interpretation right this would mean
somebody buys makes recommendations and nothing happens right then we have this sort of bipartite
cores were there are two friends who or two people who don't know each other or
known don't recommend to each other but they recommend to the same set of people
they have a same set of friends or if now one one of the
people here buys and recommends on then we get structures like this right this is the first
purchaser and he recommends to all these people now one of them decides to buy and makes recommendations
to everyone below them right and most of the times this is how cascades look like but there are
also examples of more complicated cascades where where the purchasing behavior propagates farther
so this were cascades for viral marketing now if you go back to the
to the cascades in blogs where we have these blog posts and  information propagating and here
the influence propagates in the reverse direction of the edges this is like a direction of
the hyperlink so the influence goes from top to down and these are these are just
that's what i want to say about morality but i want you to keep in
mind when we discuss
different claims about what's involved in what
hasn't what about inevitability here i want to turn to richard dawkins
richard dawkins writes
the trial had bad teaching mathematics it is accepted the resulting efficiency can be remedied
by extra good teaching the following year
but any suggestion that the child's efficiency might have genetic origins is likely to be
greeted with something approaching despair if it's in the genes is determined
and nothing can be done about it
this is pernicious nonsense on almost astrological scale
genetic causes environmental causes are in principle no different from each other some may be
hard to to reverse others may be using
why genes what it means to to deserve their sinister drug not like reputation
why you thought to be so much more fix an inescapable and their effects on
television nuns books
i like the nuns
the point here is
what causes something
is logically separate
from what can reverse it
you think of clear cases where something is plainly genetic
but it's fairly easily reversed and where something is cultural and it's very difficult to
reverse there's an example
my eyesight is quite poor
the reason why my site is quite four is not too
two to patriarchy
television culture of the map
my eyesight is quite poor due to the crappy teams mum and dad gave me
genetically determined if anything is it also fairly easy to fix thirties machines which put
panes of glass in front of your eyes
and help you to see better
more advanced machines known as contact lenses actually stick the thing into your eyes and
at the cost of occasional infections euro two you come to see that it is
biologically cars
but fairly easy defects
on the other hand take an example of society's treatment of the bees
it turns out when we and we will get this little bit we talk about
sexual attractiveness
how thin somebody is
or how that they are what you think of that is actually not critically hardwired
there is often called the culture
the ones in our culture it is almost impossible to shake
so the point here is just that genetic does not mean inevitable
cultural doesn't mean easy to fix
that's general background let's start with the basics xn
what's the difference between males and females
i don't even think
penis and vagina
there's a lot of animals that have neither one
and the actually runs deeper
by definition
when biologists talk about this
animals that are males have a little sex cells
which carries genes and nothing else
sperm cells
animals that are females have sex
which has genes
but also food into protective cover and all sorts of other stuff
the little sex cell is much lower than the big six so this is the
only erotic picture i'm going to show you today
it's a bunch little sperm circling around the egg
it's strawman
but this raises the puzzle
i just described male and female roughly in terms of the size difference
males are smaller
sex cells females are bigger why is it then that for so many animals
are bigger ones
physically and more aggressive ones
this is a puzzle lands occupied scientists for a long time
we predict that is no
a pretty clear answer to it
and answer goes like this
it is based on idea
by robert rivers
call parental investment
and what parental investment is
is defined here as
any investment
that's going to increase the offspring's chance of survival
at the cost of the parents
the ability to invest in other offspring
so for example
suppose an animal can cream offspring by blinking an eye
and then after the run-off
that would be extremely little investment
suppose another animal had to work for ten years
and during those ten years could not create another offspring
that is be a huge investment
troopers points l
that was in this species females typically have much higher parental investment than males
because females have these big sex cells they typically incubate them internally
they carry the
if there is might have to sit on the
and hence each potential trials
is a huge cost
for males which have the smallest xl
you don't have the same thing for males it might just be a few moments
of of copulation
and that's it
if you could ask yourself for humans each one of you in the room what
is the minimum effort you could do
to create a child
those happier genes
and it's apparent that the male investment on average is lower
then the female investment males can choose
or might do better off in some circumstances by putting a lot of investment in
their offspring
but females don't have a choice
females barring technological advance
so now i want to
first so you to magnetic field configuration
one of the very loosely one loop
seven windings
and i will do that by
sprinkling magnetite cis ion file
in the vicinity
we've done this before
for the current configuration now i do it
for this
so it was seven windings
and i'm going to run a few hundred MP's
first get this
car battery
so we put some iron filings here
what i want you to see now is that the magnetic field inside even though
it's very loosely one
nicely uniform
and there is almost no
like and magnetic field outside look at it
that incredible
you see how the five line themselves up very nicely horizontally inside the loop
and when you look outside the loop
well there where we assume the magnetic field was above zero
you don't see the island file being more we and many preferred direction
which indicates that the magnetic field
is very low
i want to show you
what magnetic field we can get
with his baby
which is exactly what you on the record
has twenty eight on the windings
and we're going to run the current which is something like four point five mps
but i'm going to tell you what that could this
because i haven't
currently there for you
and i also have a
i mean which indicates the
is the current leader
and the maximum
current that you see there are three will be six and
and the upper one
calibrated in such a way that if is full scale
we have three on the gulf three three on the go
and i can i have approach
probe we never discussed how that works called the whole problem
and this whole probe
allows me to measure the magnetic field in the vicinity of the solenoid
it's even signed sensitive if the magnetic field is like this
we go the right the magnetic field is like this go to the left
so this allows us then to be actually quite quantitative
and evaluates the
magnetic field
near the opening of the solenoid
then we can go in there and we can also probe
so i'm running now
the current let's look at the bottom meter
so there's about four point eight and
i saw was four or five it's higher
and here comes this probe
and i now about food away from the entrance
you see nothing
and i come close to the entrance
and the magnetic field begins to show
no and nearly constant yet i'm now entering
on the gauss
i'm going to work
one out
even deeper
and the four
now we have about two hundred forty gauss
and notice as i go going further
it doesn't increases more or less constant
is more or less constant
when i come out here i moved back and forth about twenty centimetres
if i came in from the other side
it would simply see reversal in the sign which is not so interesting
he two hundred forty dollars in the other direction because this proper science sensitive
i can also show you if i come on the outside
the solenoid
you see nothing
so indeed our assumption that the magnetic field is very low outside tightly one solenoid
was a very good assumption
very well
you've been asked
the deadline is friday four PM
to explain
the behaviour
the kelvin water dropper
and i decided to give you a little bit of help that most of you
may already have figured it out
those who haven't
probably one figure without between now and friday any
so i might as well tell you
one of proper called the kelvin water dropper is an amazing battery
we've seen it before we know
what it's doing but i will
i'm going to find this itself to be a matrix
so the derivative of f with respect to a
is itself a matrix and matrix contains
all the partial derivatives of f
respect to the elements of a
one more definition is on
there is a square matrix a
n by n matrix number equals number of columns then we define the trace of
a to be equal to the sum of its diagonal elements
so this is just some
of AI i
o for those who don't have seen this sort operator notation before you can think
of trees a no trace operator applied to the square matrix a but is more
commonly written without the parentheses are usually right trace is this just means someone that
here are some facts about the trace operator in about derivatives and i was right
is proof you can also here is to prove some of them at the discussion
section on the or you can actually go home and sober by the prince of
all these
it turns out that on
given two mattresses
a and b
the trace of the matrix a times b is equal to
the trace of p a k another proved this but you should be able to
go home improved this yourself on
without too much difficulty
on and similarly
the trace of the product of three matrices is that we can take the matrix
at the end you cyclically permuted to the front street it becomes the case that
to take the matrix you back in the front
and this is also equal to the chase
BC take the matrix being the to the
suppose you have a function
f of a which is defined as the trace of a b
so this is right the traces of real numbers so the trace of a b
is a function that takes as input matrix a and outputs a real number
so then the derivative with respect to the matrix a
this function is the
going to be transposed is just another fact that you can
prepare yourself by going back referring to definitions of cases images there so i'm not
going to do
you left
i lost the cup was on
difficult to the case because the pace is just the sum of diagonal elements and
so suppose matrix the documents change
and so on
it located a real numbers you know the space overall numbers just itself so i
think the real numbers one by one matrix so the trace the one by one
matrix is just whatever
whatever the real numbers
and lastly
this is somewhat tricky one on
the derivative respect to the matrix a matrix the ABA transfer c
this is a plus the transport
the transport and i want prove value either the soldiers out your work yourself
and so
i guess key equations
the key facts i'm going to use the game
about racism matrix derivatives are all these five
ten minutes
on these things i'm going to go on
figure out
let's list
the outcome of a quick derivation for how to minimize gf theater in as a
function of theta in closed form without needing to use an iterative alpha
to work this out then we define the matrix x is called the design matrix
on to be matrix containing all the input from a training set
so the one was was was the vector of inputs is the vector of features
for first training example so i'm going to
set x one to be the first row of
this matrix x
set my second training examples was to be the second row and so we can
have training example and so on
that's going to be my on
the design matrix and this is defined as matrix kappa x as follows
and so on
now we take the matrix x multiplied by my parameter vector data starvation just two
of these steps so x data
on remand the whole matrix vector multiplications skills right you take this factory multiplied by
the rows of the matrix
so x times theater is going to be just x one both data
that don't