so we can assume that estimate of the transition is really the correct
transition process
some error term
know make some assumptions about these are terms resumed the additive model for both the
transition in the observation will assume the noise in this case is unbiased and the
noise and correlated between the transition and observation and that we can estimate the covariance
terms from data
so the question is really asking is what is the
variance in the value function and if i have estimation of variance in the value
function and then i can tell apart to policies
so there's a little bit of math that goes on in how you do this
but it turns out you can approximate this reasonably well this is just the
bellman equation that i showed a little bit earlier
and i can substitute the model area so instead of having my model estimates in
here with the true
and the error term
and this is where we need to start approximating things you can approximate this using
taylor's expansion it turns out
and there's a lot of technical details in the paper which i want to go
into today but the point is to that you can get in a second order
taylor approximation for that particular equation
that gives you a good estimate
the variance in your value function
and once you have that you can actually ask
what's the bit what's the bias is my estimate of the value function with the
variance and not with the covariance and you can get
closed form expressions for this
for the case
where you have about data finite samples that were you've estimated these things
and so using this
we can actually
apply this in the context of the simple
i like example and the way we usually apply this is we assume we fix
the true models in order to test this
get some data it's a little bit of bootstrapping kind of estimate we fix the
true models and then we generate a set of test cases each containing a fixed
number of sample for each test case we get an estimate of the value function
and we calculate the standard deviation using the method i just described
and you can measure how often
the true value function
which calculated with the true model is up from estimate
in terms of one or two standard deviations and see how that relates
to estimate
that variance
so the first step is to validating
a better estimate is actually pretty good we did this second order taylor expansion approximation
to estimate the variance so we first want to check whether that variance estimation is
reasonably good
and what we find out is in fact
gives us a pretty good accuracy in terms of our estimate this is
for standard deviation one standard deviation to standard deviation as a function of the number
of samples but even with the smallest number of sample
i think there are reasonably good
these are not tiny samples mind you you need a reasonably enough data but when
you do
the accuracy of the variance estimate is actually quite good
so once you do that you can start asking interesting questions
such as
what is a good strategy
from my wheelchair in terms of confirming information
have three strategies here
if the ask once
where the person wants to go
ask twice
ask three times
and remember that we don't have any notion
of what are the observation probabilities to what's that noise in terms of the response
rate that noise usually comes from the speech recognizer
these results show is that as twice is definitely
the better strategy to take if you compare ask one or three times
in expectation
ask once
it's better than as three times but when you take the variance into account
there's not much difference really quite overlapping and here i think it
one standard deviation interval for the three different policies but you can actually compare these
strategies and if for some reason eighty TNT decide asking twice cannot be deployed
and you can only ask once asked three times
the reason may be
then you have good grounds to decide which of the two you may want to
if you want variance minimizing kind of system so that people are very familiar with
the system is going to do every time everyone has the same experience then maybe
you want to ask three times
if you're willing to make a lot more mistakes on a few subjects but not
everyone then you can ask only once
so you have a way to talk about
how we can compare these
now if we apply the same framework
in the case of treatment strategies
you also get some interesting results
this is not using the epilepsy data that they talked about briefly earlier this is
using data from a random clinical trial of people with depression
we had four thousand patients registered in this trial
i say we in fact researchers some of the university of pittsburgh and a number
of other centers
collected the state over five years
and an interesting question we can ask is
there is something called the minimum norm solution OK
so this is one of x transpose x is not full rank that is not
invertible so w star is no longer unique
h is the set of all w's
where w is the minimizer
so all the solutions
the problem x transpose x w is equal to extract suppose y
you need to check for yourself that actually not an empty set
but h is well the OK anyway
h is this class
and so the minimum norm solution was simply minimize www
over this class that's the minimum norm solution x transpose x is
not invertible
so when will extract x not be invertible
it may not be invertible for sure
if the number of data points and
actually less than
the dimension k
of the space in which we are working
because this matrix then
we'll have rank n
and it's less than k six transpose x will not be invertible
so if you have a few data points than the dimension of the space we
are working
that will be not invertible you will have to actually do something to find a
unique solution and one very standard thing to do with the minimum norm solution
now you may say that this is not very canonical into the pathology because usually
are going to be working in the finite dimensional space with k parameter that everyone
knows we should at least have one data point five parameter
OK so we should at least have
larger than k
and this problem seems to disappear
however what is pathological in this setting
will become canonical once you apply kernel
because what you want to apply common
we will see that essentially solving this problem but in an infinite dimensional space
once solving this problem in an infinite dimensional space
and the number of data points is always finite and therefore less than infinity
so what is pathological here will be canonical with kernels and so we will have
to deal with this issue
then again as the minimum norm solution that will
let's deal with this issue for least squares in our simple setting right away
what would you do
you would actually do what's called regularized least squares
so you would actually minimize over w
this one over summation over IY minor axis when the gamma
times www
and then you do the same thing
that show now that you actually have a unique minimizer
and this unique minimizer is given by w stars the full text of expressiveness
this is done by differentiating with respect to w and setting this equal to zero
now you can see the i can values of this matrix is always positive because
you've added the gamma times i
and so this is guaranteed now to be strictly positive definite
and you have this invertible
this is what is called ridge regression
so this i think at least goes back to the seventies
maybe no further than that i think seventy the statistics is motivation
so if you do this with the corner
you will actually get regularized least squares
so there are two different ways somehow to regularize if you're extract for that is
not invertible wanted to take the minimum norm solution
which would actually correspond to the more penrose pseudo inverse when you
when you do it in a hilbert space
and this is the other
the minimum norm solution
well actually not very good
so now what support vector machines support vector machines is more or less the the
as regularized least squares
but with a different loss function
so we have some asian i put the one to n
the of w dot excite plus b
that would be and you don't really need to
but this is just to ensure that your hyperplane so now what are you doing
with support vector machines have a number of data points x i y i which
are trying to separate
using a linear classifier
and you want this linear classifier not always pass through the origin so you had
this be which is an offset to make it
so where the
is the hinge loss
given by this object zero if y fx is greater than equal to one and
this otherwise
you can actually draw picture which looks something like this
with this is the value of y fx
is green better
is it better
so this is why times fx
which is
positive if f and why should have the same sign
so that's often called the margin actually in the margin literature
if that is positive that means effects correctly classified the point x if that is
negative that means affecting correctly classifies the point x so this is the misclassification loss
this is positive zero and this is negative it's one
and the hinge loss goes basically like this
and this is the last one
you can like this
a slightly different way
this is the way in which some of you have seen this will be familiar
and that is to right
it as www
actually i made a mistake that gamma i should be on www who have exact
correspondence with
the previous slide
and some asian i i
where this II's are
and this
so there two constraints there's one constraint per data point OK
if i six i equal to zero
that means every data point is correctly classified by my function
with a positive margin
OK so welcome to decision and we are very pleased to have stefan miller
it's this
thanks very much so like to thank you and all the organiser for this
really wonderful summer school i'm enjoying it lot i suppose many of you as well
and would like to try to do is
behind this talk is to try to give a bit of perspective on sparsity techniques
dictionaries what is behind and the
how far it can go and in some sense also what are the limitations and
i must say that this perspective is very much influenced by the fact that
i did something a bit crazy the last six years which is going out of
academia and discover the outside world and
i found it with your others company
and the worst of it is that we ended up in one of the most
brutal market which is consumer electronics was very naive idea this idea that we could
completely change image processing wastes two tools enhance sparsity and geometry
and that gave me of course a lot of perspective on these two tools because
you can come to people and say have wonderful orthogonal basis and so on why
don't you get my product they don't care about the article basis they wanted to
work now
i realized that
the problem was a bit more complicated than just writing a paper yet i also
realize something is that mathematics is incredibly powerful to survive
even in such an environment even for doing developments and so well basically
going into this world for these last six years forced me to
re-evaluated little bit the effectiveness of this kind of technique
what is
the main idea of sparsity so basically sparsity is about
dimension reduction you have a signal
and you have a dictionary that call here now for that i'll explain why and
the idea is that basically you're going to extract out of this
alphabet dictionary the basic vectors you need to best approximate your signal
with as few of them that so you think of them
and what you want is to minimize the error epsilon which remains
and the idea which is behind is that the elements that you're going to extract
from your dictionary are the essential features
a few signal
and therefore out of that should be able to do classification compression and
OK i said that
normally it's called the dictionary i called it an alphabet here i'd like to to
explain why so in the early nineties there was a lot of work of many
of us to construct a new water gonna bases frames wavelengths and and at one
point she because came out with this idea of building a library of orthogonal basis
with so-called with that back and the point was at that point was you can
was working on the idea of saying well
let's try to build a big bag of many functions and completely freely out of
this function try to approximate the original signal and that's where we worked on these
matching pursuit ideas and we had to find a name for this big bag and
we decided to call it
a dictionary so why did we could decided to call it a dictionary the words
have the importance the idea was basically that's
these vectors will be the basic words
and then once you have the the word you just put a classification problem is
so to kind of analysis view of the world to decompose into functions then you
look at what functions you had and the problem is nearly so and what i'd
like to try to show today is that the problem in fact is much more
complicated and now if i had to find a name for this big bag of
function i will call it rather than alphabet than in dictionary we are very far
from words and many other steps are needed before we can get to anything which
resembled to the notion of so that's will be one of the point
i like to do so of course one of the questions which comes and we
had some very nice talk yesterday on that is how to construct this alphabet or
dictionary how to optimise it and as i said this kind of technique have very
nice applications of course to compression denoising
i'm going to speak a lot about inverse problem because as you will see inverse
problem and pattern recognition are really working hand in hand and also of course i
be speaking about
in recognition now one of the big difficulties of which comes sparsity within these
alphabet or dictionary is the instability and these instabilities are key to try to understand
the limitations also that kind of thing
now the next question is also how much dimensionality reduction can you get out of
sparsity where are you going to stop
the overview of the talk is the following first going to try to give the
kind of really fast review of these non-linear sparse representations
and then i'm going to focus on inverse problems and on super resolution so super
resolution is about increasing the resolution of the data and what i'm show is that
basically the super resolution ideas are very close
two pattern recognition problem
and then we'll go
into this issue of instability and what i'd like to explain here is that
rather than working on vectors very often
one should rather work on more rigid structures such as vector spaces and in the
case of
inverse problem rather than having a full nonlinear approach try for example to work out
of piecewise linear representations and i'll speak about this block spaces
and the last part of the talk algo in techniques which are which have been
developed in computer vision i think they're are very nice thing coming out of computer
vision in the last few words and try to do a link with these techniques
of manifold still related to these
space approximation
OK so sparse representation now
if you're lucky enough to have a dictionary which is not gonna basis then basically
everything is very simple everything is very simple because to approximate it out of that
sea and vectors the only thing that you have to do is to decompose it
in your to basis
and of course the decomposition coefficients are just inner products and one of those appointed
so what you see there
and what are the best
and vectors that basically the largest eigenvectors was in your basis the reason being that
you have in india she conservation which gives you the air as the sum square
of all the coefficients you haven't picked
so if you do that for example over wavelet orthonormal basis to do it rush
holding and basically you get the coefficients in the neighborhood of the edges or textures
and out of let's say ten percent of the coefficients you can indeed we construct
a very good quality image
OK now
so weights
of the different worlds
you can see
it's exactly equivalent
it is and then
so look at this formula
so here
if i developed these
this is completely equivalent
use of opinion
all of the transformation of x by
if you apply p
two weeks as a linear transformation
OK to have explanation minus
my ex-prime
and you have to know the square no
OK because we are just changing the in fact we're changing the references recommendations space
in order to capture
the semantic relation between
this is just an idea it's we simple and you can use the full of
objects in fact
and what i can say to you is in fact it increases
it increases the accuracy
of support vector machines and you can see you can imagine what what's the
in fact you it uses
so the following picture for instance
so black one
so look if you have a documents where somewhere
do not up and
but is if in these documents you have
that are close to the work we are going with this matrix p we're going
to make it kind of semantics missing so we are we going between produced work
that we're not
in the original document
which as you know only which are closed
two the world's heaviest
so of course if you look really sure you want to make something very precisely
we create for instance if you want to
to find specific but then to make translation from your document will have to make
it a more sophisticated approach but but for categorisation between improve
so for instance
you have
you have rights
you have country
you have party
as and the worlds that have been
in fact
reweighting state
country nation
because it's just an example two
to make you think about it very easy way
two were to define candidates who
and to engineer
then for your for that we have to ask
sorry of course but
oh yes sorry so in fact we took the distance between two nodes
in the lattice of wordnet
and we normalize it
so the idea was to work to capture
the semantic inside one met
so you can
in fact in many applications
you have some ontology or you have some late is a new data and you
capture this is the
so and you don't want to go into the details but
OK this is good for documents about
we are we are aware that it's for
simple task
well the task what you want to do is need to define the semantics try
to extract the semantics yourself so you don't want to
to use an a priori metrics p you want to find funds the cluster four
so what i'm going to show to to you
morning is the use of fish cannot swim going to explain what is ship fish
can then then going to use them for the gain document representation
and you will see that
is also general approach that you can use for a very
there were large number of fish
it's just an introduction to fish again and so the idea is
you want to build cameras
the data
and you are you are going to consider their unity
and you're going to be done
parametric more than
pervasive political culture data
to more than you distribution
i would say
any graphical with then in principle but of course
so much the more complex graphical there's a more complex
maybe be there is
the computation for getting there
so if you can remember
maybe some selection bias selection will be useful so once you have your wendell p
also some it somebody theta
so it's specious car is defined as the following picture
you are going to take the the gradient
of the log of the probability of x
given t theta
so you have to tell you what am i going have to take you to
derry team
you're on
after the probability
with respect to the different
parameters of your
so let's
just stop and think about this is this computation
you have one x
which is given
what you want to do
with this competition you want to compute
how much
each primates
if you were then contribute
two the value
the probability of x
OK it's means that a
if some parameter of human there
is not very useful
as a there's a will be here
you will see that for many data
as you understand already
we need to define a monotonic function say we want to talk about the least
set of nodes
which is
if it's point of this
o thing
five also right
expression of this kind
and z would be the viable
so i have already said
so so let me just make comments here
so this is also kind of typo actually it's not really but i always would
have rather actually two right i mean to use capital letters
because it's it's you know sitting
it could be
a set
of note
and they you remember the little thing i told you about MSO
we better use capital letters
two quantify to talk about sets
instead of lowercase to talk about individuals individuals would be just
one particular no
but we don't need them
can we don't talk about that particular note we talk about
just sets
to some
so this is what is written here with hope so with people
viable as the
i meant to
to denote set
and here the formula so nothing particular
like here it means my child
left sun
o my zero child
so this it done
if you want to put it this way
and here my
left right child satisfies beta
was an identity
it's important that the go down the tree
and this will be the most difficult thing that they need to
explain more
using this
know how we have now with his
this is the negation this is
and reached
so here we have always come back to it we have to execute restrictions because
everything syntactic here
and so on
the things that i defined
to correspond to something to nick
in the set of nodes of my military
so let's forget about it now
and then we come back to it
this is syntactic restriction that
i mean i want is some monotonicity
in the objective a built in the objects i will give you semantic of now
so he will
so here i have the formula very standard
and i'm going to give you the semantics of these forms
and the semantics will be give you will be given to you
inductive method we define the formula
in terms of
when the meaning of formula in terms of the meaning of its forms
of course i have i mean
elements of my
my formulas that are not in the article inductively defined this
so what is the mother
i tree
it means
binary tree
which nodes
i label
elements of my set of information
so a b c d
and also
i would have i was in my formula
it's very stubborn and also to give you a way to interpret the
the virus
on top of of
i mean
you know the to interpret my
new categories formulas i need a tree
and then it also away
to tell you
if i take a set
like i said
i have to give to tell you what it means this thing
it's supposed to denote the set so i had to give you explicitly which set
it corresponds to in matrix
what we have is that we need some way to
five hz
as a subset of nodes
senator interpretation
one of them
if this is the needed more installations is used up here
so z here is taken as proposition where is it
what is it
so i need to tell you what is it so i give you
for each viable
for the moment
what it corresponds to
that is very
what is the what is
in the tree it's given
in this particular trail
but actually even with a house military might resemble a tree and only need to
give you the positions in history
z hold
o but i will interpret is viable
which is supposed to be a formula
how would put this this viable
in the tree simply give you here this mapping in which nodes
this particular viable z hold
and this is what is stored here i mean
if i take
what is well men in which nodes
z holes
well simply take the set of nodes is given by the relation
so let me
let me
tell the story in a very rigorous manner so i give you treat
and for each viable that is in this sets fire go back to this is
the set which is fixed
it can be taken
infinity if you want it doesn't matter
the set of eyeballs for each viable
i tell you
to each set of nodes correspond
this is fixed
and this is called the model
this tree press and rotation of survival
now they have this model
i'm going to
what i want to do is to interpret my mu calculus formulae
in this model
so this is
forget all this line for the moment
sort of unusual or maybe slightly surprising because it means if you take two we
have two positive definite matrices which have the same size and you take the pointwise
product so
each elem element wise product you get a positive definite matrix again not everybody knows
that and it's surprising nontrivial results that translates into the pointwise product of kernel functions
so they are also positive definite
and various other operations and this is just a very short list of people now
spend a lot of time constructing his quest for one way which is why position
the procedure
i was told
why is what was the whitening procedure good year
what you
so you are if the question is
i think you are referring to this thing here why is widening a good thing
i wouldn't generalizes it's a good thing it depends what with the kernel is good
so if you can always good in the sense that working
with the feature map associated with the kernel gives you a good representation of the
then whitening
data in this representation a good thing because it just makes the case equivalent to
the previous case
this is like making an empirical kernel which
gives you the same results is restricted to the subspace as the kernel you start
with if the company began with was not very good kernels
then it's possible that using the square root might be better so i wouldn't say
generally whitening is a good thing is it depends
we we
make all four of them but it's interesting question is that you have a slide
about that that may be scary even more so
he said well we let me taking the square is good maybe taking part three
or four is that you can do all sorts of operations and comes actually the
fact that kernels are symmetric functions gives you rich
arsenal of of transformations that you can do because you can
construct people because he started to cry
of functions on the kernel
on the kernel matrices which is as rich as the sister started about continuous functions
on the spectrum of the columns and you can do all sorts of transformations so
not just square root but any any non-linear transformations
on the kernel matrix
and sometimes that's useful if you have committees that have properties that you don't like
for instance the dynamic range is not good to so sometimes it's difficult to construct
good similarity measures and you want to do some custom transformations of things in that
case something that he can be handy but it hasn't been that much it's something
it's quite powerful from mathematical point of view but people don't
two is much
so let me see
actually is so let's let's move on to
this example of
the kernel grew from yesterday
so i got a question after the
after the talk which actually already points in this direction that i'm not going to
go into so that was quite interesting because it's something that we didn't have observe
initially so so i showed you this
simple classification rules
well you have a set of positive points in the set of negative points over
you compute the mean of the positive points
you the negative points
you have some test point and then you're taking whether you closer to this one
close this one and you are working dogs to do that in the feature space
and you right in terms of kernels get some complicated expressions
let's see if we can find it
so you get this thing here
and if you look at it so this is the parzen window density is still
can be for special cases of counterparts windows density estimate of the positive class this
can be density estimate of the negative class
and here we have this term in i think the lady who asked the question
she was referring to this time she said well it looks like you already have
information about variants of the class so she was trying to intuitively understand why is
this sometimes a good classification procedure so you're comparing the points within the negative class
to look into a difference is if you have a gaussian curve you look how
close are they to each other here you have something similar for the positive class
so so it seems like this simple classification procedure which is
looking at the means and checking whether you're closer to mean on not it already
contains information about the structure of these clusters
which is kinda surprising that i thought it was very nice nice very nice observations
so that's exactly how you should try to understand arguments you always trying to get
an intuition for what they're doing because sometimes that leads to other interesting things and
what it leads to in this case i'm going to
do you for the next half hour
so this observation was we have some the means contain some information about the structure
of the clusters and of course so this was
probably with the intuition of using a gaussian kernel may be will depend on the
will tell me some of the ways how is it different now than my
boyhood with just the saturday morning cartoons
even realise how much marketing you're exposed to
what forms does a come in
go ahead
so you have a variety you have athletes movie stars
music celebrities and people like that who get associated with food and of course very
powerful for kids so the list of athletes that have endorsed some of the food
companies are done marketing for them
so the williams sisters the great tennis players have done fast food companies michael jordan
fast food companies kobe bryant and then you go of course get all the the
cartoon characters like spongebob and other things that over the years have been associated with
the number of these products so that so that those attachments are very important
so real real people endorsing these sort of things that's right well and i am
michael phelps now there's one of those gold medals i theories on we and
somebody said frosted flakes panels that's true but
OK so there are lots of OK the the these things get couple like your
saying so these are very interesting things but think about your marketing landscape and how
different was so it's on television all the time but television used to be almost
one hundred percent of the marketing
and its share of the overall marketing
burden if you call it that has is going down
but other things have taken its place
so you have billboards you know when you guys were in high school how many
of you had high schools was was suffering machines and
OK almost everybody well you know when you walk past offering machine you're being marketed
to even if you don't buy it because it's the big colorful thing that stands
that's the form of marketing
what about product placement
in television shows and movies
and there's hardly a movie that goes by now that doesn't have products in certain
that's all bought-and-paid-for
so in general if you're watching an action movie and there's a car chase in
the trucks and cars crashing all over the place and let's say about wiser truck
shows up in the scene somehow well people are very likely painfully
and every time a product shows up its bought-and-paid-for for the most part
lot of people don't recognise this is marketing but there are many other forms will
talk about in the class some of which you probably don't even know about
in some of which you probably see but don't code is marketing and so you're
natural defenses
that might provide some kind of a buffer
between a commercial message in your behavior
you have a filter screen that helps you interpret these messages the opportunity of people
the control that is going down and down and down and the opportunity for parents
to control is being eroded day after day after day
so the amount of marketing the total marketing burden has gone way up
over the years
and of course if you think about what's being marketed
it's not the quiche it's not the total through
it's the high calorie
high fat high sugar foods for the most part
so we'll talk a lot about marketing
it's very important for thinking about food to take a global view
we have to think about the whole world here
why is that important of course
it's an important value to have in general that in order to be good neighbors
in the world we need to understand it
we need to if we're going to be good citizens in the world we have
to know what other people are doing what's affecting us but even if you're totally
nation centric
and even if you're only concerned with the united states and you still have to
know what's going on around the world why is that well one is because we
a food environment
we export food but we also
export norms
we export
the economics of food and a number of things that affect the world and that
comes back to affect us
so the most recent example as i mentioned before is the huge spike in food
prices around the world which is created what rioting starvation
major crises in various countries some of that is being forced by the united states
and the corn ethanol
conversion program that has pushed up the price of corn a great deal pushed down
the world supply of corn for eating and pushed up world prices there are other
factors involved two like high energy prices but certainly US policy is affecting that
but we're also affected by the rest of the world
agriculture subsidies
in the european union affect the politics of subsidies here and that affects the cost
of food and what we pay for them in the market so these things are
all very important drivers of the diet so we need to know what's happening globally
but also the world died is changing to look like that of america
and you see these headlines from scientific journals and this is just a small sample
hi and take advantage sugar among norwegian children and adolescents
obesity rising alarming rate in china refined sugar intake and australian children
i mean we could i could show these for the next three weeks non-stop because
there are so many papers like this
and as i said when the health minister of china says that over nutrition is
a bigger problem and undernutrition
we're seeing the change in the world so the global view is extremely interesting as
we look around the world
here's a slide that shows the projected increase in diabetes
in the next twenty five years
now there are two types of diabetes you may know there's type one diabetes
i have
they were going to talk about waveguides and by residents cavities
last thursday
i discussed the boundary conditions of electromagnetic waves
on the surface of an ideal
conductor in vacuum
we will see some of the
amazing consequences
and i will return to something that
i have discussed with you before but never fully explained
and that's the
setup up whereby we have
metal plate
this is my coordinate system
this is the direction
and then i have here
number plate
the parallel plates
and this will be the x direction
i call this actually equals zero
and this axial age
and this then
is the wider
that's the seven
you see there
i'm going to try to send electromagnetic radiation through gap
and what holds always
now consult always
it's always kx
x rules
was KY
so why move
let's cases
and the roof
case the direction then of
also land
close to pi
divided by that k
and the magnitude of that k
is the square root
of k x squared
k KY squared
plus cases grant
o we got
equals casey
if this is
in fact
i'm going to
sent through this gap
linearly polarized radiation in the y direction so that's the choice that i made i
don't have to do that
but that's the choice to make
and think about the y direction and the same direction
very very large infinitely large or in practice many many many times the wavelength of
the radiation
so to meet the boundary conditions
electric field which is only in the y direction
must become
zero here and must become zero there
the electric field cannot be in the plane
remember he of team which lost the tangential component
at the surface of the conductor must be zero
so e of why must vanish here and it must
vanish there
so for this case whereby we only have radiations
linearly polarized light direction so y
must become zero
four x equals a
and for x
equals zero
since there is no dependence of the field in the y direction
will be zero you will see that
come back many times in
in this problem
so now i would like to take a look
at this geometry from above
looking down on the
x z plane
so here
is is the direction
and this
is the x direction
and the y direction it's coming straight out of the blackboard
pointing new directions and looking down on the plane from above
so let the
vector b this
the factory
so discounting factor has a component
in the x direction
just k of x
and it has a component in the z direction
which is scale free
but it does not have a component in the white
KY zero
the waves and think of them as waterways as far as i'm concerned so this
is the direction of propagation in the gap
the water waves
would be perpendicular
two direction of propagation
wichita planes with constant fields i'm going to put one in here
this is ninety degrees
and i'm going to put another one in here
so this is not propagating
with speed c
in this direction
and the separation between these two crests
is land that is my definition of land
o point the
in the one
and if you to
if you are going to make the
OK so from that you
can do
that automatic get i
and not convex function died
but long
convex function on the data that
you have
thank you that
so it that
in that case you for use the
three months
convex function it does not satisfy the a
and angry man you're making is not this kind of the fisher information can be
so in
specifies something that structure
convex function
he then i know about the case of the nation are the as it is
clear from p
it doesn't appear
it seeks
OK i
so is that all
p i
OK so called
we use another important just just
p and
in the convex front
what i
i p
the mind i get it to the local function because
but how to rip p
we have a convex
and the context actually and i had a bad things automatically
so in that
the idea that it
youngster both
she can't a diver
and so it sixteen you've seen today
OK so
time coming
OK so if they there are all the questions about the the geometric
didn't make
from my point of view
and i presume it to be
so it
the point if you make
can you say
OK and here
if the
we p
you could be making
on the probability that we count the underlying meaning
OK now what is the potential that can keep it longer and p
this is the data
so xs
and also one content
formation people
talking about something called the come back
they use
OK this is not and not
convex functions p c
but the
something in the
we're pretty sure
he has
i can think of
the land
o thing in that all the the people the the matrix p
the many and all also that to
and to think about some convex function on the family
he did
just if you could use
we have to
if you want to use we look
if we introduce idea
we have
we find that it is not p
he was a
in the war of the hand
twenty four at the end the next
so he
what do you make
having the
many images
so i find called
not to
and again so you can ask question like was alan turing born in england and
the first thing it says well
i don't have any direct evidence for the zero piece of evidence in the corpus
but it it instantiates milan and it comes to conclusion well with some probability i
do believe that he was born in england if i click on the number i
can see
the again this chain of reasoning that that led to that conclusion and is doing
some probabilistic computation over that
and again this can be optimized further so we're seeing here really
over hundreds of millions of assertions some very simple inference to get beyond what is
explicitly stated in the text and again everything here
the probability values they're in green and the different modes of reasoning everything can be
refined just
i urge stuff to put something together just so i could show you show you
something brand and this is i would refer to the paper and the six that
we haven't written it yet so
i can't quite do that
excuse me
the family tree
different systems that i talked about here are in green some systems the rebuilt found
that i didn't talk about are in red
we were influenced to start this knowitall project by three systems that i should mention
one is tom mitchells project at CMU that the web KB project which again very
much shares this motivation of trying to get knowledge from text or in a lens
terminology crossing the structure chasm of you know very important challenge for for this kind
of work also by turning spam i our algorithm and then also by
we had one of the early question answering systems from the web system back in
two thousand one was called mulder you would ask you to question it would go
through the search engines and get your answer and this is one of system and
we realize instead of doing this kind of question answering thing one at the time
why don't we just go and apply the kind of extraction machine we can too
every sentence on the web and something that in fact were
very excited about is exactly that scaling textrunner from one hundred twenty million pages to
the full web corpus and we believe that if you do that as you often
see with these things with two orders of magnitude more data the quality of what
you get will go up
what i want to acknowledge the team a number of people there
that down his name is in red aside from his great contributions is also on
the job market today so if people are interested they should contact him directly is
a great guy
and let me just i want to leave time for questions so let me just
end with again that the high level conclusion so what i'm asking you to think
about is
search systems that operate over a much more semantic space than today's search systems instead
of key words and documents we can have these kinds of extractions instead of TFIDF
and pagerank we can have these from relational models like the one i showed you
the resolver was using instead of web pages and hyperlinks we can think of entities
and the relationships between them and i guess i shouldn't even say instead of right
i mean these
two spaces can co-exist side-by-side right you could ask could we use extractions relational models
help build a better ranking function could we use them to do better spam detection
could we use them alongside imagine some model were somebody show me start this trying
to do this recently where you have the pages but the different entities are highlighted
on the side and you can click the same we can click show me similar
pages you can click on the entity and say show me more pages about this
entity right so these are not opposing but complementary and what i hope i persuaded
use this is not a dream or even a long-term super ambitious vision like tim
berners-lee vision of the semantic web this is something that we are prototypes of today
and other people are building even even more advanced ones as we speak so this
the probability of x given
some evidence e some data e that we observed
so we might want to compute the probability of a given c
like we did before
the good news about singly connected graphs is that
information gets split up very nicely
so every node x in the graph divides the evidence into upstream and downstream evidence
so for example c
divide the
observed stuff into the stuff that's observed upstream from c
in other words with arrows pointing to see and downstream from c
in other words arrows pointing from c
now also every edge divides the evidence into upstream and downstream parts
the edge between
c and e divides the graph into
this part of the downstream and this part that's upstream
and you can think of it you know even if it's downstream of upstream is
still upstream
so imagine if you introduced
you know contaminant this is the reverse system and introduce some contaminant indeed it would
arrive at this
a branch of the river
from upstream so that's what it means to be
upstream versus downstream OK so
so in singly connected graphs stuff gets divided up into upstream and downstream components
and now belief propagation makes use of
three basic ideas put them together
it's nothing magical is just the application of bayes rule two graphs that satisfy conditional
independence relationships
but it turns out that you can
right it efficiently
if you
the use of these ideas
so the first idea is that the probability of the variable x can be found
by combining upstream and downstream evidence
so the probability of x given some observed data e
we can write that is the probability of x and e
divided by the probability e
which we can write is the probability of x given
upstream and downstream evidence
divided by the joint probability upstream and downstream evidence
so i'm imagining that i the big graph but i observed variables all over the
place so observed this variable here in that variable here in that very well here
somewhere upstream somewhere downstream
if we're interested in
the distribution of x
that we don't care about things that are constants
with respect to the values that x can take so
this denominator here is just
up to proportionality we can ignore this constant and then renormalize afterwards
so then we take the joint distribution of x
the upstream and downstream
and we divide it up into the distribution of x given upstream
stuff coming up from above
times the distribution of the downstream stuff given x and the upstream stuff
now because x separates
the downstream from the upstream
the distribution of the stuff is downstream from x
given x in the upstream stopped
only depends on
x it is independent of the stuff that substrate is blocked by
this gets copied here
and this distribution is independent of the upstream evidence
so it becomes the probability the downstream evidence given x
no need
it is sorry he can be a set of nodes is the observed values of
many different nodes some of which can be upstream and some of which can be
downstream from x
the way you can think about this is that there's is
if you want to find the probability distribution over x
how many regions that you get
four how many examples
we're trying to learn a function in if the number of regions that we can distinguish is is large then
the function
can be more complicated if you remember the very beginning of the story are told you that what really mattered
in termsof
the statistical
issues with the curse-of-dimensionality and so on was
the number of ups and downs
the function you will learn if you're trying to learn a function is very complicated
what does that mean it means the function that has many many ups and downs
many regions you want distinguish
distinguishes sense that you get a different answer in different neighbouring regions
right so so
to get statistical power would like to have a function
that's can distinguish a large number of regions
and yet doesn't require too many examples to learn
so here with all these organisms
you need at least one example per region to tell you where the region is
and what the output should be for the region
so we get a linear relationship between the number of regions that we can distinguish the number of examples
that's clear we can move to the next slide
which is what we get with
what we call distributed representations that's things like we do in deep learning
and are be absolutely and that's and factor models
sparse coding and so on
what we do here is we're also gonna define regions but the way we can define them
it is very very different it's by composing simpler regions
so the simplest possible case is
illustrated here you have your own opinion
where's you have a two-dimensional input and you have three
units and so these are actually binary units so each of is a linear classifier
so linear classifier breaks the input space into two regions with a hyperplane
so each of these units is going be on
when the input is on one side of the hyperplane
and of when the input is on the other side of the hyperplane that's a
very very simple set up to understand what's going on
so now we can count how many regions that we get we get all of
these intersections of these have all these hyperplanes
and how many intersections that get well we can get up to an exponential number
of intersections
are we get an exponential number region
even though we have a linear number
i've units and parameters
and examples to defined
so now we can have
eighty function
that's gonna answer different things in
different regions where the number of regions is exponentially large compared to the number of parameters number examples that we
so it seems that we gained something exponentially large compared to the previous case
as usual in machine learning there's not really any free lunch there's a reason why this might work
it's assuming something about input even though
learn very complicated function that's function has some kind of structure
and we are assuming something about the data
and that's something may not be applicable
so it's a prior so remember at the beginning i said it all starts with
priors so here there's a prior
the priors one
it says the world is composed
all these different attributes each other breaks the input space into different regions
end we particular objective is
you know
deciding for each attribute whether it's on a lot of what value is
and furthermore the pryr underlying this is not we can learn about each of these atoms each of these features
without having to see
all of the values all the configurations of other attributes
that's what allows us to learn about region
in which we have never seen any data
simply because
we've seen enough examples for each of the hyperplane we can generalize to some
configurations of on and off
we have never seen so many give you an example let's say that
the first bit indicates the city images image a person in the first get indicates start
this person is tall
we are at war are small
and the second that tells us whether this person is
is a male or female and third
tells us that the person
is right-handed or left-handed
there are
there are actually seventy input that no one could extract in order to detect these
things and you don't need to
to see all the configurations of other attributes in order to learn each other and
not larger to generalize to new configurations of these attributes that you've never seen
with only three would make a big difference that you have a hundred of them
now you can start seeing the power of generalization that you're getting
all right so that's that's very very important and that's what distinguishes
what we do in deep learning from
a lot of more
machine learning
so i i promised a little bit earlier to tell you about
something new that has been added to be toolbox of neural nets and planning in the last couple of years
that's helps to regularize the helps them generalize better
and it's called dropped out
so that's that's
very simple thing really it's basically about injecting noise it turns out that if you
inject noise during training of neural nets you can get them to generalize a lot
and end
here it's done in a particular way
half of these hidden units of view deep net to zero
randomly on each examples of reach example randomly choose each bit
each hidden unit whether it should be zero
we are not if it's not it's the value had computed
and you have to correction for it because
numbers can be smaller
so so that's it's a very very simple trick
and there's an explanation as to why it works
which is quite nice
if you know something about bagging
it's it's it's a very special kind of bagging so the idea bagging is u have multiple predictors
and you train them separately and at the end of the day
you'd take your vote that you take the average of the outputs
we have an exponentially large number of predictors each other's predictors corresponds to one neural
net wear a particular set of units is activated and the other is always of
and for every particular example we see we get should randomly what whatever these that's
this is what happens when you send those bits are wrong
and we can train the weights of network
of course because the exponentially large of
elements in the back you never gonna be have a chance to visit all the
but the good news is because they all share parameters when you train one
that informs happen we are roughly
and so
number of indices depending on the number of parents
this is just laying out a graphical model with some parameters now the question we're
interested in
it is
well this machine learning summer school
we want to be able to learn this stuff from data
so imagine we knew that the structure of the graph
but we didn't know these parameters
but we had a data set of observations
configurations of these variables
how would we learn the parameters data from the data
that's the question that we're going to try to start
answer so this to be clear about the data set is this bold vector x
is a configuration of these four variables
so for example of the four variables were binary
this would be
a particular observed bit string of length four
right and we're going to summer dataset of
and observations began observations that were drawn
independently from the model with this structure and we're gonna
trying to learn the parameters theta
of the whole graph from the data
questions about this
so what i'm going to do is i'm going to start this problem
simpler and more
classical ways of doing this learning and then move on to more sophisticated ways of
doing it
so the simplest most classical way of doing this learning is to do maximum likelihood
estimation for the parameters theta
from the data
i just
recap some of the stuff here so we have a data set d of these
how to learn the parameters from data
maximum likelihood learning
it is based on computing the likelihood function
and trying to maximize the function of the parameters so we need to be able
to write down what is the likelihood
so the likelihood
for the parameters theta
it is the probability of the observed data set given the parameters
if we have assumed that our data came independently and identically from this graph
then that is the product over all n data points
of the probability
of that little and data points
the parameters of the model
all right
here's where it gets a little more interesting
we're going to try to maximize this likelihood as a function of the parameters equivalently
we can maximize the log about likelihood
because the maximum of that are exactly the same locations as
the maximum of the likelihood so generally we do maximisation of log like this causes
numerically nice are more stable
so the log likelihood that has this product turning into summation
and now for each data point
because we had
this graphical model structure
we know that the probability of that data point configuration of all the variables
factors into a product of each variable given its parents
and so
we get in the log likelihood second summation which is over each variable
in the model
the log of the probability of
variable taking on the configuration that it took in the end data points
the setting of the parameters
so the setting of the parents of that variable
in the data point
and all that is the function of
the parameters theta i
now this is a function of parameters
and we want to maximize this function
with respect to the parameters
and what we can do to do that is to take the derivatives of this
function with respect to the parameters
and solve for the optimum
by setting those rivers equal to zero
now do we have any do we have to worry about any constraints on this
there any constraints on the parameters
i see some people nodding so you're not
that the some row wise to one
so when we do maximisation here we're maximizing likelihood subject to the constraint that the
parameters sum to one
there are also supposed to be nonnegative
generally will get that answer to the next station
now the summary of what results if you do this maximization is that the because
log likelihood decomposes into sum of functions of the parameters
of each variable given its parents
then each of those parameters can be optimized separately
and the result that we're going to get is that the maximum likelihood setting of
the parameters
for the i th variable
where the
take on value k in the child takes on value k prime
that thing is just equal to
the number of times in the dataset
can see
you if you
and you this
and he
i also
you all
do you
should be
all right
thank you
so what
thank you very much
want to be
and you can
there are these are
i will
he is all
o point
well you
and what we
and the
he is
and on the radio
and stay
i remember the
we were trained human
all of
three hours
and the
during the day
he was
the work
the common approach
and something similar
and by the only
shortly after
all right
so you think you can think of
and again
you you
and so
is the sum of the probability of error
of making an error to this
the possibility of making an error to this
the thing that we're going to add here
let me try to explain it from this picture
i'm sending this point here
i can find
the probability of their over that point which is the probability of going over that
i can talk about the probability of their to over here
which is the probability of going over that threshold
these are not orthogonal to each other
in fact they have a common component to
and the common company
is what happens in this first direction here
OK in other words if if you send one zero zero
and the noise
and your own always variable clobbers you in other words what you receive
is something
in this coordinate which is way down here
and sort of arbitrary everywhere else
conditional on the noise here being very very large
you're probably going to make an error
now you can imagine having a million orthogonal signals
and the noise clobbering you your own voice variable
you're going to have a million ways to make errors
and they're all going to be kind likely
if i go far enough down here suppose what i received in this coordinate is
is the probability of one half
each one of these
things is going to be greater than zero
if i use the union bound
adding up the probabilities of each of these i'm going to add up to a
million one that's
which is five hundred thousand
as the as an upper bound to a probability
and that's gonna clobber
my band pretty badly
which says the thing i want to do here
when i'm sending this i want to condition my whole argument on what the noises
in this direction
and given what the noise is in this direction
i will then try to evaluate the error probability
conditional on this
conditional on received value here
in fact the noise in the direction w two
is independent noise and direction w three independent of the noise in the direction w
four and so forth so at that point condition on w one i'm dealing with
n minus one independent random variables
i can deal with independent random variables you can deal with independent random variables
maybe some of you can integrate over these complex poly cards
i can i don't want to
i don't want to write a programme that does it
i don't want to be close to anybody who writes the program that does
OK so
so here we go
where am i
so the first thing i want to which i didn't tell you
because only a scalar problem a little bit
i tried to say that here
going to normalize the whole problem
by calling my output b so i instead of wives and j
one normalized by multiplying why subject a by the square root of the noise variance
OK in other words i'm going to scale and noise down so the noise has
unit variance
and by scaling the noise down so it has unit variance the signal will be
scaled down in the same way
so the signal now instead of being the square root of a which is the
energy i have available
it's going to be the square root of the
square root of two a divided by n zero
somehow this thing keeps creeping up everywhere
too over n here well of course it's the
it's the
it's the difference between a which is the energy we have to send the signal
and and zero over two which is the noise energy in each degree of freedom
so it's not surprising
it is sort of a fundamental quantity and as soon as we normalize to make
the noise variance equal to one that's what the signal is
someone to call out for this so i don't have to write this all the
because it gets kinda messy on the slide
OK so given
given that i'm going to send input one
he received the variable w one
it's going to be normal
with the mean alpha which is this where the two way over and zero
and with the variance of one
all the other random variables are going to be normal random variables mean zero and
variance one
i'm gonna make an error
if any one of these other random variables
happens to rise up and exceed w one
so the thing we have here is w one is doing some crazy thing i
have this enormous e
by the code about the code words in other directions
and then the question we ask you can always
which is usually very small all over the place
but it might rise up someplace
and it rises up someplace
that should be good estimates of of the action by association independence addition right
so one very simple metal that's used very often in reinforcement learning is the absolute
freedom at all
so in this matter what you do is that you choose this high probability the
optimal action and this is much smaller probability
some other action
so let's have some great
and so
biosphere simplicity
and the performance shown here so
and some testbeds so if you don't
two and exploration this is the average reward so you can compute the average one
out on what
so that's the average reward is received after a certain number of places and you
see that if you increase exploration of of it
this is little a bit more rewards so exploration is good
but is it good to explore indefinitely
can you suggest an improvement of the basic abseiling PVR given
in some way
that would
increase the performance
changes all the time how increase decrease
you want to because it to have zero so what would be the right rate
what you get
asking too much
one thing that you want to
and sure
that you try trial elections indefinitely
so if you are decreasing as along too fast two hours at all
OK maybe want to decrease
so the first time you use that sonic was one half second time use absolute
it was one of those are sort zero
that's too fast right
so that the degrees but too fast and from that and it's a
so you want to limit the rate of the trees so
it's quite tough but were scrapped
half an hour t
that the work
one our log t
that would work
that's very slow
well respected it is better than mean
so far
forget what the
something happened to the microphone
well as the
can tested this first
thank you
is good
the same thing
again approved so
any other gases
that's along
could be
so these are the best ideas
i don't know that
OK so
my guess would be just one where t
and then you can turn the constant that modifies that
that should work with about it if you are able to tune the nicholson
but maybe some of these other ideas for his first one problem though is that
this is insensitive to devices as you're still not is
it might be better to feed back the
in particular
it was the use after exploring
in the friendly of the value of their values right so
we said in epsilon greedy that is hard pretty cheesy
the action that looks optimum and in the rest of the cases is uniformly at
random to some other action
but this might not be idealists so might be better to use those actions and
a bit off more often
was value so they look a little bit better
so one way of achieving that is to use what's called botswana exploitation
sometimes it keeps action selection or using exponentially so this has been used many times
and so that's the problem over there
and what you want to do here
is that
you have the temperature parameter that you are going to
after yourself and i can value problem so that's really bad assumption here that every
class is again seen with the same variance that terrible assumption
and if you do PCA
well you ignore the labels
and you just find the principal directions of jackson's most variance then of course you
also get a jumbled because there's lots of high variance noise directions and all PCA
cares about his noise images go all variants it just goes and finds the
but all the skip over that of a little bit better example is some simple
face classification task so these are sort of law the data is raw images taken
off a really low res camera
and there's eighteen people in the data set whose identity of the class labels
and so again here this is fisher's discriminant this is principal components and this is
what you get if you do neighborhood component analysis so this is just literally a
five hundred and sixty by two matrix
in which i multiply each of the raw frames by
that matrix give me two dimensions and i just want to point here and i
column according to the labels so that there is a linear projection which is a
very good job at separating things here
and then you can convince yourself that this also helps by measuring the test error
so this plot shows you mixture of training and test points but you might be
worried that over fitting in at least in this case the air sorry that it's
really not
so i want to move on to are sort of related objective function that amir
globerson had the idea of optimizing which i think is very interesting in its own
right so let's look at the original NCA objective and i'm just going to put
a lot in front of it which should disturb anyone OK so the original NCA
objective was this it was the expected number of correct
classifications that you would get a new data set under this randomizer
so maximizing that is the same as maximizing the log
OK and here i just wrote an expanded this probability of getting data point i
correctly in terms of the probability of landing on any of the other datapoints j
there's a couple of things you could do one thing is you could take this
log you could pushing inside here
what does that do that is the chance of labeling the data dataset exactly right
so might be a bit worried that this objective function
you can make confident errors
and that's true right if there is one data point it's really irritating
doesn't matter it just get that data point wrong it's only one out of and
of the data points right so who cares
it just puts it in the deep zone of class labels which have nothing to
do with it and it gets it wrong it just suffers loss
but if you have a domain where you think your data is very noisy
three training data and you really don't want your classifier confidently giving you wrong answers
at test time then this my concern you so that you can put large inside
which case you're not maximizing the
expected number of correct labels you maximizing the chance of getting every label exactly right
and then what message as it is
you know why stop there let's push the log inside one more time
so then this is the objective function
and this objective function has a very interesting geometrical
so here's the geometrical interpretation it's collapsing classes
so this objective function is only good if each class is just one unit modal
distribution doesn't have to be guessing but some kind of you to model blob
and in that case what a good metric two
well good metric would be one under which all the points of the same class
got squashed together in infinitely close
and all the other ones got spread infinitely far away
so a perfect metric would collapse a for the green class it would collapse all
the green points together and send all the other points very very far away
assuming each class is just a single
a lot
OK so in order to kind of get from that geometric intuition to to that
objective function that i showed you
here's what what united
we said well let's call this distribution the ideal distribution
over the neighbours possible neighbours j
for each class
for each data point so the ideal distribution over neighbours for data point xi is
some constant value
if the class of i in the class of share equal
so you put some constant mass on all of the your friends who are in
the same class as you and you put zero
probability of landing on anyone who isn't in your class of that would be very
nice right if we could get this distribution then are we've only one out estimate
would be perfect we estimate that would be getting everything labelled
so here's the idea that we're going to find the metric or the transformation by
minimizing the average KL divergence from this ideal distribution to the actual distribution induced by
so each metric that we pick induces some distribution over neighbours
and there's the ideal distribution which puts
constant probability on the correct class and zero probability also we just measure the KL
divergence so for each data point i i ask what distribution of other datapoints j
is being induced by the metric that's sky i said what would you like to
have other distribution that this guy just penalize the distribution of average or some data
points and which is minimized
so if you size this function you would see that it comes back to the
and in some of those areas there's they really are they really believe in evolution
is really happening something like that something like evolutionary adaptation is really happening in market
or really happening in a language in other areas they just believe it's kind of
a handy way of talking so if you look at the journal of evolutionary economics
they you know ninety percent of what gets published there is nothing to do with
evolution it seems like economists it's such a radical idea for economists that things might
change but that they're prepared to do anything any situation where they consider system changes
they're willing to say that's kind of
wacky evolutionary sort of ideas
so this so that's really powerful organising principle here
and that's kind of reaching out and touching many many different disciplines
and in some cases that's a good thing in some cases it's this still debatable
for most of them i guess because it's so it's early days for evolutionary linguistics
it's early days for evolutionary psychology
i've overrun slightly
throughout this whole lecture the height the idea has been to take kind of gobsmacking
biological complexity and hint at the kinds of ways that that can be can can
lead to new engineering paradigms really
but you need that there's a sort of word of caution that needs to be
a note of caution that needs to be sounded at this point there has been
a tendency or there's this kind of slight confusion
about the relationship between evolution and up to amounted then it's it's not really news
there's something in philosophy called the is bought problems
which were the the the idea is that just because something is doesn't mean that
it ought to be that way
so just because it's the case that many
desert their families doesn't make that the right thing to do it doesn't make it
and that's it
it's also sometimes is related to the naturalistic fallacy which is the same idea
just because things are a certain way in nature doesn't make them good or defensible
or right
but you know you should remember when people try to tell you that you shouldn't
do that because it's not it's not natural for people to do that
it's not natural for physicists to you know enjoy
conceptual art
so what does matter it doesn't matter whether that's what happened in nature
evolved systems were not designed to do the jobs we need done
evolution was the process of
of optimising creating optimal solutions they would be optimal solutions to our problems
they would be optimal solutions to the problem of getting reproduced
certain so
within within AI
where there's there's a kind of little cottage industry of taking biological system that it
looks pretty neat idealise in it so you have an algorithm and then claiming that
are algorithm is a really good way of solving anyone's problems well is the kind
fallacious reasoning there
OK so ants are very good at doing ant stuff doesn't mean that they can
run a telecoms network necessarily they haven't evolved to run a telecoms network
of course if you can argue that there is a strong analogy or the idealise
in from ants you've captured exactly those properties that would help run a telecoms network
will then you know that i i can carry on talking to you know time
to make sense but there's some laziness in the move from biological systems to the
to the idealised versions they inspire
on sometimes asked to just take it on faith that genetic algorithms are good because
they're kind of there were inspired by real evolution and real evolution has evolved us
well maybe tapping search and hill climbing is also good news even if it's less
on the other hand you have people arguing the opposite direction they're like well you
know makes it all the messy it's all the nasty and dirty and untrustworthy and
you never you don't understand it so i don't want anything to do with it
these are
i think it would be
let's see if you have any energy left by now
this if i have any energy left
OK a little system supposed to introduce myself and try to that
i studied telecommunications engineering in madrid
a while ago
i then did my phd in denmark and the danish technical university then i was
at the max planck institute for almost three years working with karl rasmussen and cultural
after that i was in berlin briefly with klaus robert miller and then now and
as you can see at microsoft research in cambridge
now the group is is called applied games group does anyone of you have an
only one x in the wrong
and i
there's there's any one of you have a playstation
dammit i
there's one of you know the name of the game halo
alright alright
so i don't want to make you jealous but i've been playing halo three for
six months
it's coming out so in september it's an amazing it's amazing game
OK so as supposed is mentioned he he sort of there was a little bit
of a struggle to see who was going to cover what and as you can
guess a more research and then the number of an academic right now
and you is the a contradiction between two i don't spend so much time giving
lectures really site you know there's a couple of things that i sort of know
about and i was a bit reluctant to to go down and you start working
on preparing some lectures that i don't really have right side
what i what i'm going to try and cover is today i'm going to try
and give a little bit of
on an overview on probability against i heard me can did some of that then
i'm going to try and guide you through a little bit of information theory and
then and then tell you something about something about bayesian inference which is the topic
that's very close to my heart somehow
who of you knows about bayesian inference
sort of about
very good the other thing is
before coming here i went to the
the mark on so the mark is marketing and communications department
and they give me all these postcards
microsoft so we have internships we have postdoc positions and all this kind of thing
and so i'm going to i'm going to leave them lying around here
you have to do that if you want to collect point six so
this is the company so you are evaluated and
you have to write this annual report saying it on this have done that and
all right
now we can get down to the
to the actual there to the actual work
so i
i had a couple of slides introducing machine learning and the different types of machine
learning and so on but then as i was listening to
use of this lecture i realize that you already know everything about machine learning so
i'm going
i have actually removed the slides so now i'm the only slight of left and
was this one which actually asked the question
so why do you want to use probabilistic models for for learning
OK so
one thing you can do is
you can you can use probabilities as as a language
to express how much knowledge or information
you've gained from your data are right so there is that that's one advantage
the other thing is once you've expressed
your models
in a probabilistic way
you have probability theory behind you
to tell you what to do so you don't you don't have to thank you
can sort of switch off and
and just do all right
what what can we do
with the probabilistic model where one thing we can do is we make we can
make predictions with with an indication of uncertainty all right
so it's not the same
if i'm doing regression and i want to know what the value of the stock
is going to be is not the same to know forty three
then to no
forty three
plus minus ten with ninety five percent confidence or something like that around right
so that's uncertainty
it is actually
crucial concept another thing is when you're going to make a decision right should i
press on the nuclear
button or not should i operate this patient yes or no
if you really want to know
whether the diagnosis system
it is certain about what it's saying or not right
it's not the same as you're going to perform an operation on a young patient
is you know fit and strong you might sort of thing
yeah i'm not very sure whether there really is no cancer now but since the
patient is strong and fit
let's just go and and and cut is going to be fine if you have
a if you have an old person who's who's maybe a lot already
then you really want to make sure that the operation is necessary because you might
just give the patient and there was actually nothing
probabilistic models also allow you to
try and and and guess things about missing inputs missing data you might you might
and you can also fantasize data so for example if you were to build a
probabilistic model of digits or of handwritten characters or something like that
basically if you basically were to build a probability distribution over those things you could
actually samples from them and generate new
unseen sort of images that are conformant with what you've seen so far
and there's there's a lot of links between
probabilistic modeling and other things
there's obvious relations to information theory and i will i will talk about
a bit of information theory today
and actually
if you
if you go and read machine learning papers you can really see that you could
do some sort of clustering on the background that people have right to have all
these people that are
engineers design things that work they don't write to many proofs
but you know they know what they're doing you have these people that come from
physics all they know is about energy right and whenever they going write the probability
distribution is the exponential of minus some energy and stuff like that
but indeed this these are just sort of variations on the same on the same
OK so let's go through this go through a couple of boring slides before we
have to
going to some interesting stuff
OK so we need we need some definitions
you are
the local gradient based optimization is kind doomed
so maybe we can
actually fix this by
doing something different which i call target problem this is a very recent tech report
from just a few weeks ago
the idea is that
we can generalize the notion of a back problem with it
so consider
deep with composition of functions f one f two three and so on going up
computing more and more nonlinear function of the input
and imagine someone told u how
some later
should change a little bit
some delta other delta doesn't have to be
infinitesimal it could be
the discrete change maybe
maybe the
each held hidden
directories is a bit vector i'm getting you target
each have al which
it's another bit vector which is a few minutes and hamming distance away from the original
so let's imagine that someone gave u
target give details until you could make a small change
but not necessarily infinitesimal
we'll blow air
hagen view take the information
in order to
compute target for the lower layer
so we're trying to generalize the notion of backprop because backprop doesn't
if the target is an absolute away
from sacha
the thinking behind this is well
if we knew how to invert at all the functions that's
the layer and minus one two layer out
then can do the right we just about target player al
that would target later and minus one
if we were to apply
after to this low-level target
and we would get thee
target for el chapelle
and we know about one gives a low cost so now we know that
each have their own minus one which is the application of this approximate inverse j
it's a good time so what it says is that if you have ways to approximate inverse
your functions going up
then you should be able to do target propagation
and in
guess what autoencoders without for you
all quarters
learn how to invert
transformation so if in addition to training regular
you're in there
you make each layer view good autoencoder
then you can do target propagation because that's what i'm claiming
we haven't tried it yet
but we're working on it
so which brings me to
the last chapter of my presentation
which has to do with
bringing all these advances to unsupervised learning in structured output learning
so what do we care about unsupervised learning
as i told you at the beginning most of these
industrial applications of deep learning in the last couple of years have been with supervised learning wear
are you take a problem like
speech recognition and we have
hundreds of millions of labelled examples where we know for each frame with the fourteen should be
more object-recognition
where we have millions
of images that have been labeled by humans
and we know this is a car this cat this is
house and so on
and this is great
there's a lot lot more data out there
which is unlabelled end
we don't want wait for humans to label of data
so that's one reason but there's also for some more fundamental reasons why we're interested in
unsupervised learning
and supplies learning
really allows us to
and further
questions about the data
but the new new questions not necessarily the same question
o the same question so
if you think about the problem of
predicting why given x
it's always the same question the question is x
and the answer is i mean the question is given x predict why
but sometimes like to predict some subset of variables given other variables for example if somebody
for example question answering right somebody asked a question that computer
you can think of it is
somebody writes a sentence and there's a missing part the sentence is the question that
you have to fill in the missing
subject missing object in in the sentence
an unsupervised learning that's that's for you it says it's got learned
the joint distribution between all the variables you observe
and from that's you should be able to answer any question of the form
i tell you some variables in
please give me
plausible values about the variables
okay so that's one reason or another reason we've seen already is that's
unsupervised learning
helps us to
provide better
john isation we can use it as a regularizer end
we've seen and i'll give you an example next slide about
it helps to do