at the time which happened to be his own program
this was essentially done by having observing experts play in doing supervised learning with regard
to the moves you then have
you know examples of good play really
and the other thing was that this that special became specific input features were used
so in what i had previously described the input features very very generic you didn't
have to know much about how to play the game in in order to create
this input representation now here that was different
so this suggests that we may also use in the TD approach special features that
are depend on our common knowledge and the other thing that we can do in
addition is to search
through a game tree
the government specific features in this case are
for example in which stage the game has become an
proceeds through different stages depending on what happens when for example is the running game
you if these two parties right
towards each other each is trying to reach the goal and of course there's a
clash happening but sometimes it happens or
almost always the and it happens that they overcome each other
and then
it's just running towards the goal this particular that that requires particular ways of moving
so that's very interesting information for an agent that plays backgammon in other situation is
the back game
suppose you during the game you fall behind because you throws are not so good
or the opponent hits you what you can now do is you keep your checkers
at the very back and wait
well you have you have to play of course but you leave these checkers there
and you know opponent runs towards you and i hope that these checkers will force
the opponent to be blocked some work and hit
at the same time you had built up a big block on your own side
of the board so that if the opponent is hit
to go to the bar used to enter and ends up behind this big block
thank you had created for that's another game type that require specific kinds of play
and that would also be very interesting in the future
other features of course just the people count how far is it from me to
go home with my stones there are other things like the cross over can't or
how many
how many throws it would take me until i can do bear of you can
count how many blocks blocks you have because the more blocks you have the greatest
danger of being hit and so on there's also the point that certain
certain points on the board of great strategic value and blocking them for you will
be very valuable so that could also be specific knowledge that enter and in fact
this has been injured and makes for even stronger play
another interesting thing of course search
it's an old idea generation and how he suggested how to approach computer chess by
having an evaluation function and combine that with search and the idea is that you're
evaluation function well in some ways be faulty you cannot have the perfect evaluation function
for complex games but if you search down the game tree then that can in
some ways to compensate for this problem
we just give you an example how such a game tree what's game tree looks
like so this is a given position and now one party can make different moves
in this case i just indicated too
and then from there on the other party can make a number of moves and
from there on the first part i can make moves again and
it's associated with each note
there's number here and the idea is that you pretty much enumerate
all the possible numbers on the possible states to certain death
and you evaluate them using your heuristic evaluation function and then you apply a minimax
search that means that
you try to find what is called the principle of variations
which emerges from maximizing in this layer minimizing in this layer maximizing this layer which
reflects that one of the players always wants to maximize
his score and the other player wants to minimize the opponent's goal
so that's the basic idea and this works fairly well in chess but in backgammon
of course you have additional complications and the complication is that you have facts
there are twenty one different dice combinations
for two days and suppose you start with given bought state and the first thing
is you have to roll the dice
this kind of unfolds already and then for the for the for the given discrimination
you have to make a move which can lead to different positions and now comes
the problem now in these positions again dice thrown which leads to further fanned out
so it's much harder to search deeply in backgammon because in between the dice always
give so many possible
possible variations
so effectively
search in backgammon is usually limited to three life because then the number of different
positions already grows quite a bit
is the kind of the career of TD gammon there were different versions with varying
number of of hidden units in the end there there were trained on one point
five million training games and it had quite an influence in the sense that professional
players after analyzing their games with a TD gammon actually changed the way of playing
is most noticeable in the in the opening for the starting positions always the same
and you can really just look at for the twenty one different combinations which moves
are being made and professional players actually took up quite a few suggestions from TD
gammon here and change the way of playing so nowadays
what we know
so it
they are
so it's
that year
you want
the way we see
feelings OK six
well the
so we may be
of course
he e
we can
well at least it need
and if you don't really
when he was done with very
one one
more you know
a special way
so what you're going to end up with this
let's go over the here sodium and chloride the keep attaching and detaching and attaching
but we've got two sizes modelling was hard spheres and so they're going to fit
together in a regular array
so this means that they will form
a crystal
so we're going to have solids and and we're going to have crystalline crystal crystal
and ordered solid
as opposed to the disordered solid will we'll talk about both a little bit
right so now i want to show you that this this comes necessarily from energetics
it's really it's a really cool derivation i want to compare two situations
here's an iron gas
this is my humble drawing to indicate the discrete sodium chlorine pairs
so this is one of these pairs that have shown up here it's got negative
we see that we get the negative energy by attaching the chloride to the sodium
and i'm saying suppose these four as they have to initially in the gas phase
and they remain two ions sees me two atoms per ion pair
discreetly bombing around the gas phase
so that's
situation number one situation number two is i take the same number
and i make
a role
they're all in one row
so what happens if this is
i've only drawn three but now let's
let's pump up the volume here let's get together
so i have ever get number of these things in a long line
you can that is going to be solid it's can be one-dimensional crystal
so the question is can i show you from an energetics standpoint that the crystal
is favoured over having the discrete set of
of pairs
and you know the answer is yes because i would set myself up for failure
to switch so let's let's take a look first of all situation number one when
you know how to do that because you know the energy of one pair so
let's just multiply that by a vigorous numbers so e
one will simply equal
and never get times
the energy of the ion pair
articles are not which we can
substitute whenever get role
i'm doing this for one one
plus one minus one like sodium chloride
we can come to make more complex later
and you have to get and from experimental evidence you can pull that of theory
so this is born exponent is determined experimentally
there are people that
all right so now let's get the energy for the line
so for that one
what to draw
line of the song to start with
get the color charges
doctor says is good for
right so here's the here's the
and the chloride on each side
and then we'll go for another
and then
another chloride
on each side
so now what i want to do is i want to start here at the
centre and i want to count the energetics
i what we do is i'm going say start with this science and of the
energy associated with the interactions between that i and everybody else in the role and
then multiplied by
ever get some is that the number of atoms are also the source for the
goose is sauce for the gander so what about edge effects i could ever get
number these things what do you think the air is going to be by failing
to recognise that at the end of six times ten to the twenty third i've
over counted some energy is vanishingly small
so no longer preoccupied by the end work were the big medal in the middle
is is everything here so
we can start this distance here is are not so i know the
the energy in this first
in the first pair
the energy in the first pair with equal
that's just gonna equal
where over four pi
that's one zero are not that's just
what we've seen before
but in addition
the field is continuing to radiate so it's unsaturated and it's omnidirectional so this canine
feels the repulsive force of the
cation over here
this can ionize is attracting the chloride next to it and it's repelling
the sodium
as the next nearest neighbour so that's repulsive term i got add up
i put that because that that's repulsive energy that's going to decrease the energy of
the system so i've got distance here two
are not
two are not an edit distance of two are not i have a positive repulsive
term i just plug into the
the coulombs law
and so that's going to be plus the square
over four pi epsilon zero
two are not
now what happens let's keep counting now the the the next one is the chloride
it's of opposite charge it exerts an influence only that's minus to plus so that's
going to give me this term here that's four pi epsilon zero
three are not
and so on and so i think you can see the way this is going
to her what about the born term forget the board turn important term is going
to be felt except in this first one so i'm going to forget now patch
the end
no only boring born repulsion to or not
that's always
all right and then we're going to do all going to do this i'm only
come in one direction so i gotta multiply this whole thing by two because i'm
come come both directions
so now i'm going to come back to this and again minus the squared over
four pi epsilon zero or not
times this series one minus half
plus the third
minus the quarter
its centre
so what we've got is this series is broken into two terms that are conveniently
representing two physical ideas this is electrostatics right here
the pre factor
embodies all the electrostatics
and what's all this stuff why is one half of thirty this is the instant
or the animals this is that is to say the instance adam arrangements
the instant adam range
in this case it's
now i do this is often just the that one central
canine so now let's do it for all the and so what we do now
is multiplied by an and then add
born repulsion
we put all that together here's what it looks like
it looks like this
equal to lines
and having natural
the square over four quite epsilon zero
are not one minus one over and i want to call this whole geometric factor
this whole geometric factor i'm going to put it into one
number and i'm going note that the madelon constant
the madelon constant
the madelon constant is simply the geometric factor that's enough
so let's put that here
with case
normally teach pointwise humanity
for to
and i don't and some schmoozing assumptions
assumptions on the rate of convergence of the bandwith parameter
we have
asymptotic normality following and at at the square root of n kind of scrambled of
n sigma in with the invention
with an asymptotic variance
which was approved before which is of the following form was defined peaks
and you can just model that it's exactly
mean world from zero
he it's of some functions that means in particular number that lambda is solution of
i differential equation and the initial condition is that lambda zero
equal to zero
you see clearly that
the mall
the closer i am
to the initial ponzi was you will so small business entity clients that's quite natural
because i would know even better the function and estimating and if i get
more and more far from this from this initial condition imposed in the problem i
have a bigger and bigger variance is entity variance
from my symptoms
here is
you are the main results
i can show you for the initial problems
well we had
lambda as the solution of differential equations depending on n and what was the conditional
expectation the next step is to change a little bit this is that instead of
assuming that and is exactly the conditional expectation i introduced some eighty in the random
x y and z
so n will be some solution of
another investor then which would be any implicit versus problems will have to take into
these people inverse problems
to derive some results from associated solutions for
so now i term to
the following relations and is far less
the result of in the best
i have again
differential equation also interested in the the solution of the differential equation nine first parameter
function lambda
but now the difference is that
i have the second
more than steady
is equal to n of ix y six and i don't have the identification condition
that the expectation of and even it's y is equal to zero
so i have to
introduce some
instrumental variable devoted to solve
this first problem
and then we place as the solution to the first problem to solve
nice and i differential equation so i have to
two c stands to inverse problems to solve
one is you one is linear
one is
involve some into was using some different show
OK great
one will be well posed and use would be
in schools
the idea
what i'm going to present you is how to solve
nonparametric this problem and then we use
and we call the results obtained by a threshold which i'm just going to include
all the articles on parameter estimates immigration
and then apply their estimator
in two
these first expansion a hand
for the estimated solution of the differential equation minus the so what happens now if
i may
by something more complicated
then the conditional expectation and the estimation of conditional expectation
and that's going to focus
the linear integral equations to solve
and we call the result
the hopefully know
compared to the initial problem i presented
this is
also an inverse and inverse problems i introduce some
instrumental variable the value such that
in expectation of excellent given w
is equal to zero
so the question i want to solve the following one
expectation of the minus end of x y given the equal to zero so i
can rewrite it more generally by
of these sequence are
he is an integral operator
and it has been shown that this inverse problem is ill posed it means that
you have to transform it to obtain a unique stable solution to your problem
and the transformation that was used
the article by the whole for us
the station used
this method
to regularize problem
and so
instead of solving
directly the problem and is quite two are i sort of know regularized made in
regularized down
introducing some
i isation of smoothing parameter i
so i have i five plus scottish
played in and i five equal to start and really been too far
the star is i dreamt of your favourite t it's also a conditional expectation
when i introduced some nonparametric
can estimators i have associated estimated
relation to solve
when we places
when placing your right TNT style by estimate cells and the conditional expectation
it's not
so this is
the worst case
it just
you can try
it is
and this is
so that was the
one can
so the
because you want
one is
so what
or he
not so i've got a bit more
i don't like
so this is
after the about what is your
i see is that the
you know
this is shown here
it well
and the classification
since it is
based on this problem but
so some of
so we
so to say
english television and he is
in one of people
quite well
with all this
what i want to go to the first i was i would like to get
by the way
the question
how we understand what's in the image
i think
so what
well known
which they
o thing
what about
so much
the just but
and it's not like you
i'm not to understand what that means
the more which
now other
just before be true
i've known
all example
his like
but they
on ln
how old
raise your right
by the way
in one thousand
but now all
because y
because you
of course
right because it was and there
all but
the which was the course first that
the result in in
to do
except if you like
the problem which
in the born
the point
i want to go
of the
the town hall
i hope
and the right
this one
i'd like to was
all just
he played
o thing here
you know
and it was all
the school and the from
but the
able don't to understand what do you want to change
you see
it true
we're not going to the left
they somehow
which way are they gonna fall
so good
pretty good
so people it turns out are pretty good at at a bunch of these tasks are here we can say
suppose these some gray blocks are ten times heavier like these are stones some kind
of lightweight plastic and then we can show subjects the very same sets blocks but
coloring them differently you're gonna get a very different prediction if the gray ones are
heavy this one now hopefully you can see is pretty unstable whereas this one is
much more stable or here if you say which way is a gonna fall
if the gray ones are much heavier than the green ones then you can say
well it's in this case is gonna fall out way whereas in this case it's
more like that of all the way and it turns out again that people are
basically put quite accurate this
if we just add in these differences the model just adding the different the mass
differences again we get correlations are not perfect but you know around in the in
the mid mid-to-high point eight levels
and we can
we can just keep pushing the sort of thing like we can say right imagine you have this table
and we knocked the table so now we add an outside force
and we say is more likely to have read if i'm not stable hard enough
to knock some other block on the floor r is more likely to be red
or yellow blocks that fall so what do you think red yellow
red OK here
is an amazing how such that just a little subtle difference between these two
yes which is
most people switch from yellow here to read OK so how are you doing well
again idea are are thought is that you're running some kind of simulation you have
it's like this this is it's a snapshot from are simulator where you take the
tail and you bump and you see what happens there was a little bump here's
a bigger bomb
in this case basically the same result the yellow ones are the ones that get out of
and so we build a model which is just the very same physics model from before but now
it considers a range of different possible bump directions and magnitudes and again we don't
fit people's judgments perfectly but across arrive wide-ranging towers varying the number of positions different
kinds of blocks
pretty well captured most the variance with this model we can keep going i mean
i i don't want a boring with all this but the point is is just
like the turning test if you want to take the idea seriously that you have
this kind of abstract mental model like that you can run you want a show
that really there
you have to push it to some extent to show that it's really doing
enough work for you so it here i can show how well you can see
it we vary the size and shape of the object some of tall we put
these funny kind rails on different sides of the table
or we might q forces we might say in some cases i'm not gonna tell
you which way above the table you have to kind integrate out and other ones
i'd say was but from the side that's the that's and again the same thing
holds basically the this model for both the q and q forces for different size
and shape the blocks it's just this massive experiment here that's this all you can
get from that's is
you know across all these factors which we vary
it captures most of the variance it's interesting i think that it doesn't capture all
the very i mean sort of consistently imperfect right
i think that's telling us that's we are
we imperfectly capturing something real there's a real physics simulation engine engine in your head
that you can make these probabilistic inference about a we haven't got it exactly right
with the particular approximations that we're making
you can now if i'm sure at this point and probably about the time
just a just about on so i don't really have time to go into the
last bit the top which is gonna show you the same kind of thing about
how do
these probabilistic programs now for intuitive psychology but just just to give you a very
sort of quick
this basically these you know i think this is if anything can be more familiar to you
this audience because we're using
all the success in probabilistic planning a particular reusing pompey planning algorithms
and we're basically saying just like just like the there's this crazy idea that you're
into the physics might be based on a physics game engine in your head
here we suggesting that you have something like a ponte piece in your head and
you interpret other people's in another intentional agents whether the people a little blobs moving
as if they were
choosing actions by solving the pompey now i think can't appears is way too simple
but it but it's just that it's the kind of technology that you know i
think many people here familiar with
the basic idea is to say
ah i mean we are all just show you a couple of experiments just evocatively
so here we can we can see an age moving in a simple environment where
there are three possible goals and some constraints if you look down here you can
there you know various different
experiment different experimental conditions were remove the objects around already very whether there's a wall
and maybe there's a hole in the wall and the age and follows various paths
and at different points along the path we stop the movie and we say to
the subject what do you think this guy wants he was able see what is
he trying to get to
and as a function of all these different factors we can very people make judgments
that you can see here on the second row
the the red blue and green are color-coded to the three objects and you know
if you if you if you take take a look at this paper in and
studied a little bit more detail if you if you're interested but you'll see
fairly intuitive variations in some first two things that can really tell whether it's air
be on our definition agency heads there are i thought it was in this case
i thought it was being and it seems like you switch today
are you can get all these very complex things like are and i think it's
probably not be the can't every now and then is it can be where i
think it be here but no definite now it's
and this model captures all those details
with an even higher correlation into the physics modeling here the correlation is in the
high point nines what is it doing well again like the physics simulator is very
it is
the site is one
well just
they showed
you say well
we've made
one side
the main
well one
and you see
right so
one of the few
one of the most cited
or is
or this would be the or
one the
and for that
one or
it is
which is this one which is the hard part of the computation because it takes
all the other agents into account when actually moving there is very easy optimally because
you just choose to this very simple rule which is moving to a new way
to that particular target and so the actual trajectories of x
on given in this way
and of course computing such expectation value you can do it either some mistakes what
you can here we compare some me field to control and we compute these expectation
always mean field always belief propagation and basically comparing it to
to the exact value get very very similar values is the cost difference and just
to see that this this problem is actually not trivial
we have compared it was agreed to control where each agent is the same well
going to be used in the fire and
forget about everybody else you see that that indicates that there is hardly any north
there's not such much about policy but if this is the system becomes noisy that
greedy policy is actually very bad
it uses some computation times as a function of the number of agents comparing to
exact his align exactly on the on log scale
and you see these these my slides of the computation time for this field so
you can efficiently inference
so the OK so the conductivity in this case
is are distances and j is is the desired number of a of agent at
that five j
and so
and this these are numbers that are given
and and and j this is the basically the number of
agents that end up at phi j if you if you have this vector y
recommended go down and so this becomes quadratic
in y so this gives a sort of the pairwise interaction in the graphical model
and then the
and then the this term which is the is is also coming into the graphical
model right because it is that this term is here
this is all in the ground is the a graphical model systems also in this
case this term is of course only linear
in any position
so it doesn't affect the graphical model structure
and clearly this success such a BP or mean field approach depends very much on
the density of such committed to
no it's a good thing but sorry if its point wise so it only it's
there's no term y alpha y beta
so it's it's a single
single note
so as single
single variable
there's no it doesn't compute it doesn't there's no link is just a single variable
now these these these variables are here restricted to
to a discrete set of n points so in this case
each while fuckin have the values minus two to two
no no no no
none of these so the average
so we have here so we have here is a probability distribution over y
we're where y is the vector for each each other agents and y alfie has
minus two to two in this case the the one-dimensional locations of the of the
the fire and so we have
and in that graphical model
which consist of two ingredients one is the
point wise terms that don't come from the from the free dynamics of each of
these pages and the other term come from the interaction that they should minimize something
jointly at the end time
these two ingredients are in this graphical model and that to do graph model inference
and in this particular simple example for instance is just as an example
you have to then compute for optimal control the expected value of y alpha and
is expected value you see that they a so here expected value for for green
is here
and maybe it's computers computed in the context of war all the others do
and then
still images
so here's another example here seem little bit more complex example where we have a
number of agents in two dimensional space
and where the dynamics of each of the agencies the second order
this is a second order system and we see you whether some
so we have
the position
the change in the position is given by the velocity
and the change in the village velocity is given by the control variable
and the sunlight
so we have some initial position forties for these cars that can so you can
think of this cars was mass and can steer
no they have so the and you get back to the end of the bridge
so now
if you want to optimize with easter and you can iteratively optimize that time instead
by updating at each iteration so essentially
you spent one one time magazine the spectator
and then you might expected to do with it that fix and those two problems
are simply
it by it with with twitter is closed form
and with that the w since you have done the l one norm and two
it's supposed to be easier
but all those do not use the financial sparse and i think this is nice
but i do prefer method that uses sparsity as we know see how we can
we can do that
so for that i will always he the square loss because it allows it is
a lot simpler two to present
so first something that we something we which should should never do
is to write that as a quadratic problem
OK so that one can be written
you can you can separate the positive part of the negative part and you get
a nice quiet and to be OK quieting down
we now you are constrained to this is all nice but this is if you
use in june nineteen well this would be very slow never never do
but for the square loss this that you might use and the main one and
it is that if you know
in advance assigned but one of the solution so if you know
which by about the positive which ones to be get even which one should be
then you know the solution to transform why because if you know which one should
be zero
so JBB was once they can be widely objective of this is the last will
be just a strict to in j
and you replace one known but just linear function
which depends on the on site
location is assigned can do that and of course this is a quadratic function which
you can optimize in closed form
it exactly is this simple equation
so if you give me a sign in advances and victorian advance then you can
simply get solution
so of course you have a lot of things that also features p defines and
that also this is not used in guess in some sense and they don't it
was you understand that i need to check
with the optimal not so hard to achieve the optimal amount
so this is just your candidate viktor candidates saying that the nonzero but which is
sometimes called the support of your solution
and he was outside victoria you know in advance is going to be of the
so now you have to check the two optimality conditions that i've described in earlier
on the tutorial
the first one the side of the bridge is actually actually is subject gravity one
condition and also that the the gradient with respect to the the inductive bible scholars
this is the two conditions to you need to check
and now you have two cottages for that they construct the sages iteratively so you
start from the all and keep adding
variables and you you can have that satisfy
and the good thing is that it only requires a small number of you know
assistant to to get wj
OK you need to invert to solve
it is the least square problem reduced to
viable which is efficient market
but the techniques in the technique i really like is homotopy methods for the square
loss so this has been invented multiple times in fact the first one to do
it was markovitz nineteen fifty six
then was born and then the last in two thousand four and the idea is
very simple
if that is to that is that if
is to get first goal is the sum of four months ago also somewhat ambitious
you want to get not one solution one and that all solutions for all possible
and and for that you just not is that if you know this and that
this is the solution
for a few problems
it is to find lambda
great it is valid as long as those two conditions are satisfied
and the sign condition is also so it's not constrained
this in good conditions
directional derivative condition is also
something which is nine and so at the end you get in dublin of london
four points and that you get an in of london which may be empty for
which the solution is optimal for that number
that the only means that you are you have the set of possible find function
for problem for agent of of and so
solution wj the function of lambda is piecewise
find so we are sleep on the road the possibility of running on unix solutions
so you can do with that but i want i want him to know what
complex than just using the semantic annotations which we expect normal users to do
there's this kind of information will be done by
some kind of administrator gonna whatever i don't expect non-technical people to
but they will be able to do it a lot of money to be doing
already but not without some dedication and willingness to invest the time to do it
we would like to give you lot of the main
are going
it is a
it is a fact
one of the big advantages patricia has in this case that has this problem topology
telling me this is
this happens five this property is limited to five times this properties inversefunctionalproperty on this
kind of information we don't have to scan information semantic media wiki it can be
here and then has small of this information and on the other hand as well
even the british is automatic interface builder
pretty hard to
get him to do such a nice interface on the fly
so again you would have to the pieces just have a list of all possible
values but since you have wiki where people can add new properties on the fly
new categories and fly
this won't scale anymore
if you try to give me all the properties that the possible for this instance
after a while if you have an open wiki this would become very long and
very unusable
yeah it is the problem it would be really nice so that and then you're
going to be used
one thing you to limit
this is
so we
the project should not be
is and
one of
so one more thing about this is we have to keep in mind the database
it's working on the same problems for
decades and they probably have much better solutions that we have investigated and no actually
would be
i think it would be very worthwhile just to look at what they did because
there already
but they if they are able to create a database for forms of the fly
out of the database schema and stuff like this so this is something that can
probably just three users that which just didn't have the time to look into it
too hard
but we must not forget that there is a lot of work out there already
in this direction
and actually this doesn't look much different than the computer database to system
if you look at it in the first cloned
the big advantage here is
you can change the schema
with in the wiki system you don't have to go in the back you don't
have to go into the database and you don't have to go into your code
it's completely flexible it can completely change with the community
sure you could also look the state of the system in the back country we
have database working it's my sequence in the end but this is what is different
from that kind of work and that's why we always to think how much of
the rest of the halftime can we actually use for use
for the user interface in this case i definitively agreed that we did not do
enough so we have to take a look at what they read it and see
how much can be reduced i think the semantic web community this whole
has more often than not the problem that it's not looking hard enough
it out of work that so some of the problems
but it's a personal opinion so don't confer please
one of the big advantages semantic mediawiki
is said it's an open source project many people are working on it and so
with the right light
we should have a one of the the same year but in the four
but this slide
so when which
one of the two
there really blew here
but you will
so i
left to right
well it looks like cancer
and of course they tried to
just another day
to make it most right
this is just like being
expression and we're actually going to
a lot of the difference
of the two right to know
my commiserations
six months
equal to
some of the ways and means use that means
how to write so we have only one component which
red green blue or
the yellow k in the second and
equal model
that means the column to the point that we have a great power
the big difference between maximum and minimum
the most away
the left it is left to right
and this that just allow it to you
the number of
which we have between the right and on the
the class
after applied research
bright line here
but this
how many features they the
and the
what you can do it all on it
the first lectures called just the most
even if it cause image and really you should be able to
has problem the truth because
there were several comp
one of the reasons why true
o which
right to
and statistical measures the color in the picture
just among
it's called the image so you have
it's the
could which goes on to some article on this one
and the three
you already them and the police among the pixels of the image
which have this problem
and i can compare to his
using a lot like the one
should be done
o with
the histogram and
because one the
following colors
that are so you might be able to make which small
it was proposed to use color
actually all about this article
but he was real estate is called to measure the contribution
so i can relate and even
every college
so the police
four and we have a do
the hue saturation and we can begin
we believe that the temperature
and we can pull a certain
and it was shown anyone
but of course want to
this effect
for example you
so is a particular case which can be represented by the nine members
i don't know
talking about color histogram what which how
we one color so how
left out of our models
because the
OK so
so the way we can approach the problem of training these models whether they are
kind of a single stage or multiple stage of systems through sort of sort of
an energy based view
so i
so let's imagine that model this kind of box that you feel it and inputs
and produces a single scalar outputs that we could call an energy called f OK
what would like to the we're going to train this machine that is regardless of
what is internal structure is going to try to produce low numbers for training examples
and anything that looks like training samples
and higher numbers for everything else and if you think about this kind of general
view it pretty much is described as you know probabilistic approaches to two learning like
you know maximum likelihood density estimation the likelihood like many people learning so many foreign
inconsistent sort of you know essentially identifying the manifold but energy to manifold and high
energy to everything else but it doesn't insist on the fact that the energy have
to take certain values which is what the probabilistic approach would would would say this
energy was apportioned says you i low energy for the training examples and for everything
else or for the region near the training samples everything else
let's imagine sort of a single one-dimensional situation where you have a single viable you
initially the energy is flat and the training examples are shown the bottom here and
what you want this kind of law energy for
whatever values for four around hyde the two regions and the density regions and what
you want to avoid this is flat energy
so you can do this by essentially feeding the energy function to a loss function
loss function is going to take
it's more like a functional is take the function
the energy function as an arguement is going try to shape it in the right
and we can just use the energy itself is lost
the average energy of training samples is the lost because we might result in catastrophic
scenarios where the energy surface become low and flat everywhere so the loss function
what we get in the way we're going to build the loss function in most
of the models that people use in deep learning way supervised learning for that matter
of that type you take a loss function that is a decreasing function
of of the energy on the training samples an increasing function of the energy of
all the samples it somehow dream up
and the idea is that you're going to
take a training sample
and pushed down on the energy by changing the parameters of the surface you pushed
down the on the energy of those samples
OK so most by those those are the
and then you can to generate some of the tree of the sample
known training example something else
i push OK
so because you push down on the training sample you put up on everything else
you know the surface going take the right shape and that's the basic idea behind
which it was machine and other other models of this type
so you can always turn there the energy models into probabilistic models by basically taking
into the minds of the of the energy and normalising
so if you really insist on computing probabilities you can take the energy function you
could even include additional slides and do e to the minus some positive constant normalizing
you probability but there are situations where you might not be able to do this
because is too complicated and you can compute the denominator so in fact lot of
the techniques have to do with how to not compute dominator
but if you have model like this you could do a lot of things you
could do an image denoising you basically model the data by training model like this
so the probabilistic view
you basically want to make the numerator big on the training samples and the denominator
which is going to average measure everything small
and the problem is you can compute this piece
because it's it's it's the sum over all possible configurations of the y variable and
why might be high dimensional bible you can compute this integral this is a very
simple form and most cases it doesn't
so what so if you want to compute the derivative of this suspected the parameters
minister w symbolizes the parameters
the ricci looks something like this has got the energy of the training sample
minus the is actually the average of the energy over the of
the average of the gradient the energy where the average is taken over the distribution
of the model gives to each other samples
OK and you can compute the city so replace it by something which is why
RBN's two
or use other tricks are going to talk about the tricks
so so here is here's another trick
the trick is going to build this model
with the special structure and almost all of the deep learning models use that structure
and internally
the structure is that we're going to build the model so that it has hidden
valuables e which we call the code that we use this as the feature
that's all model extracts
OK so the model is going to have to use this invaluable that's going of
an argument to the to the energy if you will
and that's going to be your code
and the way most models are built
it is true reconstruction so all you the autoencoder RBN's are actually the same nature
so taken inputs you run into some sort of encoder you get code the neuron
through decoder and then you compare the decoded code or the result of passing for
the chain with the original inputs
compare that that's your energy
right so the model has to use the code to reconstruct and so we use
the reconstruction error as the as the energy what you want to do if you
think about it you would give low energy to the training examples high energy to
everything else what that means is that you want your model to properly reconstruct the
training examples you wanted to explicitly not reconstruct anything else OK
so what you train two not reconstruct
anything else but the training samples of things around them
it's kind of weird thing that you want to try to
there's something wrong
and if you think about it if you try to reconstruct everything you get trivial
because this would become the identity function it will be constructed absolutely everything perfectly and
your energy surface is completely flat because you has your reconstruction are everywhere that's not
a good model
because of some and you get
the same thing
many of
something else it doesn't matter actually if it's a valid input on usually people twenty
three cost to produce
valid input when you give it a non the or corrupted input gets the idea
of using the algorithm based on the models of this type
OK so this is the basic and critical to model that a lot of us
have been using
which you can stack and then you get rid of the decoder and you can
use them is going to feed forward
feature extractor
but here is going to be more slightly more general view of this encoder decoder
model where easy as a latent variable really now sells is not just value to
compute with younger but it's the kind of latent variable you have to do inference
over OK so general model you take actually run into an encoder
for machine and the service level certainly they are different than concepts are quite different
too difficult to visualize then we deal with high dimensionality which means that all statistical
techniques might problems and so on
and also we deal with very high number of
hundreds of thousands so it's not so unusual
so all these properties make the whole problem quite difficult on the other side
text has one feature which is very
pleasant are friendly for analytic methods and this is the fact that the data is
highly redundant and basically all practically all methods count on this single property which makes
the easy for everybody too
with very simple idea also text and most likely everybody will get some kind of
results and so basically very simple recipe for
kind of ad-hoc text mining methods would be just take out some phrases out of
the text find some kind of related words and create some kind of summary out
of it is most likely will work
and a lot of text mining papers with what was followed this recipe
now let's put the text mining can the context so who
in this scientific area actually works
in the text analysis arena
so on one side
it's a machine learning context mining so this would be this community of this KDD
conference and maybe ICML ECML conferences for machine learning apart when you decide to have
this natural language processing so that this would be linguists these conferences like a COI
and so on so they're more interested in linguistic aspects of text
then in the last decade very popular fields information through so
this area is more less concerned with search and related problems and recently so semantic
web and even more recently that two point o which actually also deal with text
quite a lot
although they also other problems as well
so this is roughly the
the landscape of the area or communities which deal with text
and what's interesting some of these communities have almost no overlap to be honest especially
the semantic web and machine learning overlap is almost zero well with this other fields
there's a little bit more
so this would be the typical tasks each of these committees and so that analysis
conditioning greece takes reason knowledge representation and reasoning and search and databases for information through
so if you take text analytics
and try to
the main
areas of work are the most relevant concepts with which we are dealing with when
dealing with text so we can say that first we need to be
a pair of what kind of representations we use for representing text
so this would
this would range from character level representation is very simple once a month and then
on the other side to first order theories on the next slides we'll go through
all these levels
next techniques
how how we deal with
with text so one side we have many work still a lot of men are
actually being done in the text of the learning be sort of the intermediate step
in the most difficult one will be reasoning quit text or with the content which
which we extract from that and the tasks so this would be the actual algorithms
are applications the and beach which we have so this would be search very popular
task then all kinds of learning unsupervised semi supervised unsupervised learning musicians summers the through
machine translation and so on
in the second part of text mining part will be the
so what's interesting is that these three
main group groups of concepts
i used for dealing with text somehow they all contribute or they all share ideas
intuitions methods even the data datasets and so on you know this
a kind of that with with these ideas although as i said so they often
they just don't communicate or some people are to be and
don't share ideas on the social level but technically they they are quite similar
in way
we can say that up here is politics and some of his scientific work
may be interesting to mention so this in the an initiative by
mainly by
w three c people
somehow to establish the so-called web science and this is the architecture of this website
so you can see the details here and this
site so
usually that's our community KDD community would appear somewhere here in a i
and computer science but everything else is around this from media law economics on one
side and the other mathematics psychology and
so all these contextual sciences which provide the context for websites
and this is relatively new so
that's why i cannot say much more on this
will discuss
do we represent text
we have
at least
three levels of representation
so i will discuss each of each of them a little bit more in detail
but let's just let's
make sure quick walkover
now when you look
through an optical telescope from the ground
and you look at the system
you will see the light from the donor
because there's very little light coming from the neutron star because there's an enormous miss
small surface most of the energy comes out in x-rays anyhow
so we only see the light from the donor
i have learned over the years this has nothing to do with doppler shift
but when you look at the spectrum of the star
they in general can tell
how massive stars
in other words
a star which is ten times more massive than our sun has a very different
spect and the spectrum from the sun
and so
they look at the spectrum and they say this is probably five times more massive
than the sun but this is probably twenty times more massive than the sun
so astronomers can tell by simply looking at the spectrum
of the donor what the mass of the donor
so let's call this star number one
so they look
starring optical light from the ground and they say
we know roughly in one
now they see the doppler shift of this one
so they see an absorption line in the spectrum
goes nicely back and forth
and they say i
we now know
the orbital period
and we know
the velocity v one
and we know the radius r one
we know all that
but of course astronomers no
i hope
they also know
whereas companies law
i didn't erase anything
but i did
they also know capital
now look at capital law
so you know i one
you know and one
you know t
but what you don't know is are two what you would like to know
that is the mass that's the radius of the orbit of the creator
you don't know this one
and you don't know that one
but you know
n one
times i one
it is and two times are two
so you have two equations with two unknowns
you can solve for n two
you can so far too
so now you will find the mass
of the
immensely powerful
so this has been the game which has been going on for many years whereby
actually astronomers
this is what
my specialty has been for the past
i can't even remember since nineteen sixty six for the past decades
so in x-ray astronomy we've made a living out of trying to determine the mass
of these creatures
and in many cases
do you find that the mass of the creator is very close to one point
for solar mass
we are sure that in that case
we're dealing with a neutron star
it's not an accident that we find one point four times the mass of the
john as the car
the quantum mechanical calculations
in nineteen thirty
and if you take a white dwarf
and you don't matter onto the white dwarf
and it reaches a mass of one point four solar masses at the white dwarf
can no longer support itself
the collapses
so that's the upper limit of the
white dwarf
that's called the child caliente mitigate got for that nobel prize in nineteen eighty three
wide by the way all the all by itself is the bizarre stories about the
radius of the earth
ten thousand kilometres
and it has about the mass
one of the
they already we it stars all by themselves
we demonstrated that the upper limit on the mass of of the white dwarf is
one point four solar masses so we were not surprised that many of these creatures
headmaster one point four solar masses not was they probably worldwide what in the past
and they were pushed over the chandrasekhar limit
later in time can general relativity
einstein's theory of general relativity
out of that theory it follows that if you keep dumping mass onto the neutron
the moment that you crossed the three solar masses line
the neutron star can no longer support itself
and collapses into a black hole
now comes the question
is a black hole
a black hole is an object
from which
light cannot escape
i have to something
and i think i'm going to raise the left part of the blackboard
it is an object from which
light cannot escape
i have to be more specific than that
black hole is an object from which the escape velocity is larger than the speed
of light
we know what the escape velocity is
because this remember and that's why i pay attention to it and mentioned is also
the escape velocity
so here is the black hole
there is a
radius around the black hole which has name wonderful name is called the event horizon
and all i have to do is make this e
and i can calculate what the rate is is
that means if you the inside that radius
then the escape velocity
will be larger than c
you can get up
so the radius of a black hole
is then the the radius of the event horizon i wouldn't want to call it
the radius of the black hole but the radius of the event horizon
it is that two mg
divided by c squared
if you are
closer to the black hole
in this case velocity would be larger than c which is not possible
to give you a little bit of feeling for what this means
if you take your
and you take the mass of the earth which you can look up in new
you substitute that in there
you will find that the radius of the earth to become a black hole is
only one centimetre
so you you the mass of the earth
and we want some sense of consistency
so that if a rule if the conclusion can be reasoned in several ways for
example that each way should be for the same answer
it doesn't matter which order you apply the operations in you still get the same answer
and the robot is not allowed to just arbitrarily ignor
relevant information
an equivalent states of knowledge have to be represented with equivalent plausibility statements
then it turns out
these belief functions must satisfy the rules of probability theory
and the sum rule the product rule and bayes rule that follows
so here's a kind interesting sideways approach to
arriving at
probability theory
it's a language for representing beliefs rational agents
it extends logic
strengths and beliefs
questions rather
so here's a different way of approaching
the problem that motivates probability theory
this is kinda gambling or economics approach
it comes in the form of the dutch book theorem
which i think is definitely the talk about
two so one of the founders bayesian statistics
so willing to accept bets
with odds proportional to the strength of your beliefs so now
the way we can assess the strength of your beliefs beliefs is that we're gonna make you gamble
thank you
you know
is it
but is it real madrid and barcelona playing tonight
thank you
right next week
so you could have beliefs about what you think is gonna win right
might be willing to bet
on the basis of those beliefs so you believe that
rallies gonna win
with strength billy point nine without means is that you'd be willing to accept
nine to one odds
are better
here is the interesting
in fact
if you have a set of different beliefs not one belief but set of different beliefs
unless these different beliefs are coherent with each other in that they satisfy the rules of probability theory
okay the most trivial one would be
my belief in x
and my belief and not acts
should sum to one
for example
but things along those lines
unless your beliefs satisfy the rules of probability theory
there exist some set of simultaneous bets called a dutch book
which you are willing to accept
for which you are guaranteed to lose money no matter what the outcome
this isn't about losing money on average
this is about
sure loss
and the only way to guard from that's fourier believed to
because here with the rules a probability theory
so this is kinda economics or r yet
by confidence values are ranges
in this setting
in the sense that
you know
if u
if u have a range
over something like between point seven and point eight
there's no clear way a betting on their
in this framework
so you need to basically the
need to commit
and actually in a betting scenario it's much more
intuitive is to exert to figure out what somebody's beliefs are okay
you know that if you ask them what do what are your beliefs they might
not know and then you say okay i'll give you
you know ten to one odds and also known you say ninety one eight a one whatever
and then at some point they're willing to accept bet
that's one way of figuring out what the person's you know beliefs are but of course
has a model of humans is quite
flawed because humans are not coherent
for example you know
little lotteries would never work if humans were totally coherent right
maybe i don't know
in general humans are not very coherence
so it's not necessarily it's a model of what humans should be
we want robots underwater robots we humans
well robots three rational
there should be more rational than humans
so this is just a model the economic rationality which is a bit idealise of course
just want
these are
well you could affect your belief in
that's true
poured into dictionary you got bytes of text
so how to solve this problem
if you using
another library
i'm not just once class library that using this approach
what they can do it can put not real elements in your crash
table you can do partially
this is you put simply point to the element and this element is least
and if you adding additional rewards for example
khatami has the same hash functions simply put them into a really
the disadvantage is that you are doing
using least it's again not local usually because you like it this element and and
again you have additional point
it's more
good structure
this is not a good here
another approach what you can do
and it's very good for modern hardware
he is to do to pass
what simply a linear expression
for example
we are going to index our documents and what we are doing
we are creating partial forward in one document
and what we've done with these document
results from this has to out the dictionary
and the intuition behind these
in that
dictionary from one document spread to small
and we can use cash for it which is very far in addition
and when we finished with a document and are this dictionary not a small dictionary
to the while using dry or another structure but because it was
repeating document many times
you don't need to all appearances of this for you
you need to put on the repeating documents
and for this small
only for these documents what we can do
we are trying to edit my and we see that this element is already occupied
by cat
we start trying all elements all next elements in disarray
and when we
if we come to the last element we can
you can jump to the first one
and this is catches refresh
and if you indexing it's my approach how are used implement it to increase in
distance speed i'm using is usually an indication station has two dictionaries
one small index in small is has for this particular document
and this is the first place to use linear
passion because it's perfect for
morning process standard fast
and then when i'm done with a document or usually a group of documents i
merge this this has to be a good dictionary
and for big addition i can use whatever everyone structure i'm not
i don't bother about
the speed of light into this structure because i don't do a lot of there
are added i remove all repetition of words from the action
fashion and this part of of structures that
what what what you want to
add to our system is
so as you go flat because i think that it's better to
start looking for from from this one
let because
today's lecture this this one is completely not
connected with information retrieval
and we need to introduce one more structure
so that's
and with some incubation
i want to give you a real problem
so we doing indexing of our collection and imagine that all this collection is coming
character recognition text
and the problem with
optical character recognition that is that we have
pretty big number of our
so i really
it has talked to our customer who
you this system
morning as
so i think get where we were last time
we talked last time about
experimental design
and not just elegant very careful to and having organisms that bred true in a
lot of work went into that
we talked about his
observations and his
really great
choice count
we talked about his ability to look at numbers that were approximate and somehow intuit
what was interesting about them and we had to take rough numbers and say
and i think this is a three-to-one ratio
although that was an abstraction
but it's a very good one and his partner and it's hard to know when
to make those leaps and when you're you're kidding yourself but mendel got a lot
of data i didn't mention
that he worked on not just around and recalled but he worked on seven
different traits
across people at all seventy
show these
very consistent properties of
going those are recessive and dominant phenotype in the first generation the dominant phenotype by
definition was evident in full force and in the second generation we saw three-to-one segregation
he felt pretty good about that he made other predictions based on this and he
was able to
put together very coherence story and as i also explained last time
some like a stone
it was an orderly abstract story the idea that there were these
articles inheritance factors of inheritance you can put your finger on and people hate stuff
you can put your finger on they say it's just the model
as i mentioned last time
the discovery of chromosomes in cell
was really laid the foundation for the beginning of
a rebirth of interest in men lysm in medals ideas and
the interesting part of that
characterisation of chromosomes was the choreography that we talked about last time that normally in
going undergoing mitosis normal mitotic division to make more and more cells when you stay
in the cells and look at them before they went into meiosis you of these
acts like structures however many there were they lined up along the midline of the
period then two
sometimes you can even see them kind of attached to
something pulling them back and they would pull back to make two cells
each of which had half of px
somebody as last time i drew drew four chromosomes was that the cells have four
chromosomes and the answer is no it's because i have room to draw four chromosomes
in that cells so this time i drew six chromosomes to indicate that you can
have different numbers of chromosomes they are usually
but i should note not always an even number of chromosomes in
a higher organisms but anyway so i do six this time and what's interesting was
this meiosis the generation of sperm and eggs for example in animals there the chromosomes
lined up with the different choreography they lined up in pairs and were you could
see differences in the shapes of chromosomes like maybe the little crossing point was lower
down they would appear or the chromosomes are shorter in length they would appear to
find their own partner
the one that had the same basic shape and they line up in pairs and
they would undergo a series of two divisions a myopic
one division meiosis one
and a second division meiosis two
and in meiosis one
you would get one copy of each
then it would undergo a second
machine in this sense the regime describes the character tone
of the society
what a society finds most
what it looks
up to
you can't understand regime
unless you understand so to speak what it stands for
what are people stand for what they what they look up to
as well as its again it's structure of
institutions and rights and privileges
this raises a further set of questions that we will consider over the term how
power regimes founded
the founding of regimes
what brings them into being and sustained them over time
the thinkers like tocqueville for example regimes
are embedded in the deep structures of human history that had determined over long centuries
the shape of our political institutions in the way we think about them
other voices within the tradition play-doh marke valley
so come to mind
i believe that regimes can be self-consciously founded through deliberate acts of great statesmen or
founding fathers
as we might call them
the statesman
lockyer valley for example refers to romulus moses cyrus
is the founders
it looks to we might think of
mean like washington jefferson adams and the like
and institutions
the very first of the federalist papers by alexander hamilton even begins by posing this
question in the starkest terms
it has been frequently remarked
hamilton writes
that seems to have been reserved to the people of this country by their conduct
and example to decide the important question
whether societies of men are really capable or not of establishing good government from reflection
and choice
or whether they are forever destined to depend for their political constitutions on accident and
there we see
hamilton asking the basic questions about the founding of political institutions are they created is
he is he puts it by reflection and choice that is to say by deliberate
act of statecraft and in conscious human intelligence
or are regimes always the product of accident circumstance custom
but the idea that regimes may be created or found founded by a set of
deliberate act raises
a further questions that we will study and is inseparable from the study of regimes
this park
cause statesman
what is the statement
again one of the oldest questions of political science very rarely asked by the political
science of today
it is very skeptical of the language of statesmanship
it's all the sense political science simply was a science of statecraft
it was addressed to statesman
what potential statesman charged with steering the ship of state
what are the qualities necessary
first sound statesmanship how to statecraft
differ from other kinds of activities
mister good statesman
played believe
for example b
the philosopher
first poetry mathematics
in metaphysics
or statesmanship as aristotle believed
a purely practical skill requiring judgement based on deliberation
and experience
his streak of cruelty
and the willingness to act immorally necessary for statecraft
this market valley
the number of test items are called projective models and models which don't are not
affected by permutations of the way items are labelled are called exchangeable models okay and the nice
thing with the CRP is that it is both projective and exchangeable okay and in
the case of partitioning what is meant by projectivity is the following so so
I guess first I have to define what is a projection of a partition so imagine we have a set S
and we have a partition of the set S and we have a subset S prime of
S okay then the projection of row onto S prime is simply you take our
partition of S and then remove everything that's not an S prime and that's gonna
lead us to a partition of S prime right so for example the projection
of this partition of one two nine onto the subset of one two six is
gonna be this partition of one to six okay and a projective random partition's basically
that if we sample from a partition from a distribution of the partitions given by
P M and we project it down to the set one to N then this
is a random partition and and the marginal distribution of this partition has to
be the same as as what we had to begin with
why this thing is doing this sorry okay I'll just show you the Chinese restaurant process is projective because
firstly we can derive it from the finite mixture model and we know that the finite
mixture model is projective another reason why it is projective is basically because we've
defined it sequentially so it has to be projective and a nice the reason why
we're interested in projective models is that it does is that whether there are additional
data items that we urned and we did not observe shouldn't affect our inference based
on the data items that we did observe and also this also means that we
can do prediction in a kind of a consistent manner and to kind of learning
sequentially in a self-consistent manner as well how about exchangeable random partitions we say that a distribution over
partitions is exchangeable if it is in variance to the way the elements of S are
label so the probability of this partition should be equal to the probability of this
partition whereas sigma is a permutation of one to N so if you permute it all in way
in which the data items are labelled then it shouldn't change the probability of our partition again the
CRP is also exchangeable because again the finite mixture model is exchangeable basically
because the IID given the mixing proportions and given the cluster parameters and another reason
is that if you look at the probability of a particular partition under the EPP F
of the CRP then it actually doesn't depend on the identities of the elements of
S alright so we can see this actually I'll come back here so this thing here
doesn't depend on the element of S it just depends on the number of on
the sizes of the clusters and the number of clusters in that partition so in
that sense it'll be projective it will be exchangeable so an an exchangeable model is
one that does not depend on the arbitrary way in which the data items are
indexed so there's kind of a fundamental theorem called De Finetti's theorem which relates to this idea of
projectivity and exchangeability and I guess I need to define it something else again so
imagine that we have a sequence of random variables X one X two X
three and so forth and it's an infinite sequence we say that this sequence is infinitely
exchangeable if the joint probability of any N of the variables is in variance
to permutations of the variables okay so this is related to the effect
that given our data set so imagine that X is our data set if
you observe X one to X N our model of X one to X N
shouldn't depend on the way that the data items are labelled so this is our
model and it is in variance to the way to to permutations of the way the data
items are indexed and this idea of infinitely exchangeable sequence is basically a generalization
of IID random variables right so if we have a sequence of IID random variables they
are all independent and all sampled from some distribution then of course they will be infinitely
exchangeable despite construction and in fact we can construct infinitely exchangeable sequences as mixtures of
this IID random variables so the idea is that we have some latent variable G
and it's gonna be unobserved and they have some prior given by P of G and
given G the N the first N data items are gonna be IID with
distribution that is described by G okay and if we integrate it out G so because
it's unobserved then we are then we'll end up with a joint probability of X
one to X N there's that would be exchangeable it turns out
that any such infinitely exchangeable sequence of random variables has to
have a form given by this so and that's De Finetti's theorem okay that
there's kind of a one-to-one correspondence between infinite exchangeable sequences and mixtures of IID random
variables and this is quite an important prior fundamental theorem in bayesian statistics because it's quite