in the process of
but not all
this is a a
they are problems on
i don't know
very good work on
that's what
one of
it's not true
one way
right so
do you want
o five
very small malls
well for all right
o or one
world war two
for example for example at small
what is
these are
i know
on the
now the role
all right
all of the cell
now we have
the fact that a lot of work on
one of
i will
my i
here we go
you know
if you
well written
you he said his goal
she is
the problem
by the
the above
right small
you get what to you mean the mean of all right
you have
your your family
right now
let's call our
well we have that we able get a one
you've got a
much much larger h models
so that they can actually generate output words that are not in your face
OK decoding
well you know this is the same thing in germany and how they will do
we translate you know each for time
but the problem is we have all these different choices and there actually no real
extract only the top four phrases four kinds of input phrase and you can see
the stuff in much of history
and the task of decoding as you figure out which are the phrase i'm going
to use the image automatically using it
and that's this search probably started beginning with the policies all these fine extensions and
themes explored pretty badly but somewhere there is the best path due to pruning
so what changes now when we do affect more according
so we do additional complexity but also previously we had a nice phrase mapping simple
phrase self-professed now we have
you know all these
mapping steps in there
so here in this case the like three that's where the map limit on the
amount of money that morphology morphology and generations that chris surface form
the interesting thing is that can do
all this beforehand before you do they actually coding you can
figure out for each input phrase
one of the possible
rendering so
the big mapping of input phrase supper phrase you don't have to do that during
that according to do that before he started according to you know of the source
and then you can figure out
one of the all the possible
so all these things can be precomputed
that means
when you actually go around the decoding we only have same decoding algorithm
but for each
of the
input words you know how much richer
annotation feature the output see also much
attention otherwise the whole thing is exactly the same
of course there are
many more translation options this way because you all these different steps in the combine
are much much more ways and you have seen the training data so you have
to cut down at some point
there's also an issue with
especially of current implementation
when you go through these mapping steps so
consider first generated word
the lemma we have made twenty choices that
then j then you
in two
part of speech tagging if i try to say something year five part of different
part of speech tags in twenty different
phrases twenty times five hundred different possibilities of this can actually look badly
we can have a solution that works
pretty rough if you don't do too many mapping steps the generation model
but is actually something to pull off but if you make it more complicated
need some work
but according to otherwise so that phrase expansion of this
the execution of all these mappings that doesn't get
too expensive the recording as the same as the first the second so much
OK so what can we do with
OK this was the first thing you always work
the motivation is if you have only produced the output
but also part of speech tags maybe you can have some kind of model the
checksum grammaticality output so you can build seven gram model nine model as any arch
large and model of part of speech tags
so the same as the tree structure but it does give you some kind of
you know grammatical here
so how does it work well you want to stations that maps input ports of
and then you generation step
using the graph structure now right i'm using the graph breaks the objective into nodes
and edges
OK so one last step now now we can think about this expectation
if i write this out long longhand what you could think is this is sort
of like taking an expectation over this is the marginal distribution of q
this induces a marginal
x of s
csco up a little bit
so this is like
a sum over that marginal
and this is like a sum over the joint marginal
it the joint mu st is the joint marginal over the pair of variables
i'm very dirty and what's happening
sorry about that affect legibility OK so now this is an interesting form because you
know in general this is an exponentially large vector this q
but what i've shown you now is it
in terms of how it interacts with the cost function because the cost function splits
it's graph structure cost function
it only depends on a vector
very low dimensional right that's a vector of length two in my binary case and
this thing here is the matrix a two by two matrix
right so somehow now all of a sudden have gone from exponentially large two
very small
right this thing is the worst if you had not binary valued and states you
now have at most m squared numbers per edge
and yet and roughly edges c of m squared times an edges if you're on
the tree
and here you have numbers per node
so this is very low complexity and this is the representation that belief propagation max
product is exploiting it six it's working in the space of these museums
OK so
i'm telling you works in the space of muse and i told you that the
messages and belief propagation or enforcing constraints
so we have to figure out what are the constraints that the messages are enforcing
right so what are the conditions that these muse have to satisfy
right so this is a vector
and this is the matrix
what are some conditions that those guys have to satisfy
right so he said the sum of all entries in this vector this marginal though
should be one
and of course it should have non negative entries probabilities are non negative between zero
and one so non negative plus sums to one that will do the trick
the same thing for this guy right this guy if double some him over everything
he should be one
right somebody said column sums in row sums
that's the interesting constraint if we collapse the sky over x of t
what should i get if i some over x fifty this guy
if i collapse the joint marginal then i should get back this marginal
and those should be the same thing because i told you that they came from
the same q
right so if we took fixed q and i computed mu s computed new st
they must be consistent they have to be locally consistent in that way
right so that that local consistency constraints that's exactly the constraint that the message is
trying to enforce
the message that's passed along edge s t there's two of them
and there's two constraints one depending whether you some this out one depending whether you
some that out those messages are exactly for those constraints
OK so now i can show you the the slide
OK so
what i've done years i've walked you through this derivation
i said that
instead of thinking about max product is in
you can think about is a different kind of optimisation problem actually what's called a
linear programme
linear program this means all the constraints are linear in the objective function is linear
linear programs are nice there's sort of the easiest class of convex programs probably even
with mentioned them i think maybe spoke about conic programs
more general but anyway linear programs are
generally very easy
and what we've seen a very good at this place things
where do you go the humans
what we see is that some of these marginal distributions should be relevant here
showing you how they look if you had three states not just two
we've just answer this question what are the constraints that the marginals have to satisfy
they have to satisfy the if you collapse the
across the columns you should get back this factor
and if you collapse the rows you should get back the other vector the mu
t factor
OK so if we think about what we're doing
a bit more generally so what's going on as we went to the space of
probability distributions
and then we said it's enough to sort of thing set of probability distributions were
what will work over marginal distributions over node marginals and over joint marginals are matrices
on edges
and so what we're actually optimizing is over the set is the set of all
marginals that you could obtain if if you let the choice of here i'm going
to p of mu here i was calling it q if you let that choice
of the global distribution very you're gonna get different choices of local marginals
and what you'd like to understand this
e eight is circular
what happens if you rotate a circle
yeah nice isn't it
what happens if you rotate
and overall
it develops into a full covariance calcium yeah
the fact that the problem exists
this trick being able to rotate the circle and it's still you come
tell you don't change the nature of the spherical noise if you rotate it that's
why you can do this nice simple i can value decomposition
on the uh
principal policies you can't do it for factor analysis
okay good
so this leads to this i can value decomposition actually while we're at it since i've got me
want to interpret this that's
well what's going on is you've got
you're covariance if you data
what you're trying to find is that
principal directions you're trying to find a china
is the direction that will allow you to axisaligned this dataset
so this is like you one
and this is likely due to
so that's what you're looking forward said
the covariance the sample covariance for your data is given by this circle here
and then you do and i can decomposition allow which gives you the principal axes
practice comes from principal component analysis of the covariance now the rotational invariance is very
interesting because the rotational invariance we had before remember was u
al are
transpose are el
u transpose regan
these things converter w actions so that's u because it's actually w one because it's
multiplied by igon value to give its land use the direction like that's
and the length is given by the eigen value
this rotation guy
what he does is things like this
all these are valid solutions for w
yeah so these two russian those different colours action so uh which either uh these two
would be one says solutions
and these two
would be another set solutions
the rotated versions
although orthogonal set so we tend to use your orthogonal also known to be orthogonal
because in that i can value decomposition that's incentive
what i think
as orthonormal vectors
and that's a set of scales yeah so these these guys must be right angles to each other
so that's giving somebody intuitions i have all i think of myself about
principal component analysis but just a finnish what's going on in the solution
u i can vectors of
the covariance
sigma squared plus elsewhere the igon values now in traditional
principal component analysis
you just beat el squared sigma squared is taken zero that's the noise
that's in hotelling's work the noise was considered a zero
but inference probabilistic principal component analysis you had this sigma squared onto the i can
values now what's that's saying is i means that is
you're constantly adding to your forearm
your data
so yes merging it so
if we were doing one dimensional principal component analysis like this
okay so we're looking for the first principal direction
and then when you add noise to it what you actually do is you at the second component to it
a little bit of noise in the direction and you add a little bit on the end as well
so the i can values you get principal component analysis probabilistic principal component analysis are
slightly different from the ones you're getting if you get peace you because you had
this little bit of noise in the end but you will so it means is
a proper probabilistic set because if you just take the vector
w w transpose the one-dimensional vector that's not a valid covariance it just defines
what is this
semi definite covariance it defines a line
so adding a little bit of noise
across the diagonal
that's a little bit a little bit there
so you end up having subtract out of
in your forearm solution for peace that comes out of the max but that's my
intuition the mass i think you can see in the papers i try to give
you information because that's what it took me longer to work out
so far the manipulation shows that we can constrain this then the solution is given
by the largest eigen values what you see here is that we
i can values you need to retain
if you're reducing the dimension a view of the largest ones but that's
you can show them as well
so the letter q largest eigen values
so some further work shows the principal eigen vectors and then it turns out you
can also work out this this requires quite a lot of manipulation
the maximum likelihood value for sigma squared is given by the average of the discarded igon values
okay so if you want to know what sigma squared is you have to take
the average of the discarded i can values and that's sigma squared so this is
some intuition people have always had about peace yea that somehow they look for these
people talk about all those finding dimensionality
these are amazing thing that don't actually exist in real data
the idea is if you do piece e eight you look at the igon values along this axis here
and you see some so
elbow like that's the i values go down and this is the album the mythical elbow
and the idea is that this is the noise level and then you retain only those components
case appreciate making this more explicit it's if few really took
i can decomposition about matrix form w w transpose
plus sigma squared i u really would see this this will be sigma squared
yeah there would be a constant igon value and this will be the dimensionality q
all these matrices here
yeah so
is encoded in this model is being fitted to the data
but in fact if youtube if you try and fit the number components it will
always say that everything is a component of the maximum likelihood is found by including
all components there's no magical thing where find this noise before you see we have
to one or two things one is the classic thing we all know and love
which is disliked the latent dimensionality q
and then fit sigma squared is the average of the discarded igon values but other cool thing you can do
which people often don't understand appreciate because they may not understand published piece e eight
is you can set sigma squared some known value
let's call it
and if you do not
then i will determine the dimensionality of the latent space four-year automatically but what it turns out is
but in mind this so this is you can the first q i can vectors
although the consump covariance
there is a q by q matrix
is given by
most of what we do these days are methods are theories or ideas are shaped
to some extent by p edges influence and so what i want to do is
big in this class is going to talk about content development by talking about his
his idea was the children are active thinkers
they're trying to figure out the world he often described him as little scientists
and incidentally to know nowhere is coming from on this
he had a very
an ambitious goal
he didn't start up because he was interested in children he started off because he
is interested in emergence of knowledge in general
it was the discipline he described as genetic epistemology
the origins of knowledge
but he study development of the individual child because he was convinced that this development
will tell about the development of knowledge more generally is very snooty phrase
that i don't have you heard before the great phrase
it's ontology ni ri capitulates for large
and the idea of this what that means is that the development of an individual
mimics are repeats development of the species
it's entirely not true
but it's a beautiful phrase and
he actually was committed to this he was very interesting look will figure out how
to keep develops and that will tell us about the development of knowledge more generally
view the child as signed as a scientist who developed his understanding these schemas these
little miniature theories of the world
and they did this through two sorts mechanisms
assimilation and accommodation
so assimilation
would be the act of expanding the range of things that you respond
p edges example would be a baby baby's used to sucking on her breasts
might come to suck on on
a bottle or on around
that's changing the scope of things
you respond to
it is changing how you do it baby will form the smell differently depending on
what is sucking
so these processes where you take in should have given us and very physical way
but in a more psychological set way of looking at the world you would expanded
to encompass new things assimilation
but you could also change
your system of knowledge itself
and phd argue that these two mechanisms of learning drove the child from different stages
and yet stage theory which was quite different from the freudian stage theory we've been
introduced to
so was methods were asked questions children to solve problems
and ask questions
and his discoveries that they did them in different ways at different ages lead to
the emergence of the stage theory
so for prj
the first stage
is the sensory motor
stage or sensorimotor period
for here the child
is purely physical creature
the child has no understanding in any real way of the external world
there's no understanding of the past no understanding of the future no stability
no differentiation
the child just touches
and sees
but doesn't get reason
and is through this stage the child gradually comes to acquire object permanence
object permanence is the understanding that things exist when you no longer see them
so those of you in front you're looking at me and i go
it could be a great magic trick by then appeared back
now on the that object permanence
if i win under here and then people said well hell i go
classes over that would show a lack of object permanence
so i don't have object permanence png is very interesting claim is
kids don't
before six-month-old
piaggio observed you take an object the kid likes the chorale
you hide it you put it behind something is like it's gone
and the claim which i really think
is gone
things don't continue to exist when i'm not looking at them anymore
and so he noticed they are surprised by peek-a-boo
and he and his claim was one reason why the surprise peekaboo if you go
you know you look at the kid is my god o thing because recovery face
because he's gone
people call
these gone
and you really you know that's the class
PNG also discovered older children
and it has this is known as the eighty not the task
and peter gray in a psychology textbook refers to it as the changing hiding places
which is probably a better name for
and idea
you take a nine-month-old entropy energy and i'm opposed just starting to make sense
of objects
and and or permanent you take an object and you put it
in in a couple
or you can see it was in the car
so to keep your ticket will reach for it
you do it again
three four
you do it again reached for that point then you take you move it over
we actually observe kids would still reach for this
it's like you're not smart enough to figure out is not there anymore even if
they see it will
and this was more evidence that they just don't understand objects in the this the
the thing takes a lot of time and learning to develop
the next stage the pre operational stage
the pre operational status shall starts stop grasping the world only in the physical way
the sensorimotor way
but when he gets to pre operational period the capacity to represent the world
that the world inside your head
comes into being
but it's limited
and this limited in the couple of striking ways
one way in which is limited is that children are egocentric
he goes centrism has a meaning in common english which means to be selfish he
actually meant more technical way
he claimed the trunk lid at this age literally
ten to understand others can see the world differently from them
so one of these demonstrations was the three mountains task
three mountains over there you put a child on one side of the mountains and
you ask him to draw
four five year-old can do it easily
but then you ask him to draw as it would appear from the other side
and sure find it's extraordinarily difficult
they find it very difficult to grasp the world as another person
you might see it
another significant findings actually had about
this phase of development
concerns was called conservation
and the notion of conservation is
that there's ways to transform things
such that
some aspects of the change but others remain the same
so for instance
if you take a glass of water
newport into another class this shallow
it would be
by the
this is from move from to
the set of all
those who is also because of the
you want to
o thing is
you have to do with this
the last of the interaction we is to the number of homes also
let's sure
has exactly the same as one of those
thank you for have know
it's a pleasure to be here is university
today i'm going to
discuss financial crisis and systemic risks
the motivation of
OK many but let start with two
one is
and has been discussion among the community around this risk initiative
is the emphasis on extremes that punctuate complex system in the
interesting system in natural sciences or social sciences any of this system are punctuated by
extreme events
and this extreme events are not as much appreciated in there
in fact in the consequences and so on
here the emphasis on the study of fashion crashes offers
first possibility to quantitatively
access one of these questions of
what are these extreme events what what what how are they characterize can we detect
them can we say something quantitative
another motivation of course is that we want to put this research agenda
on the quantitative level in the social sciences and of course financial economics offers a
remarkable example
of access to quality data so i'm using these
tion hopes to start
address this question
of the importance of extreme events in social sciences
the question i'm going to address one by one
in this discussion of the following
i will put the perspective broadly
from the perspective of my financially colleagues in academia
but also in crash real things that are worthwhile to study or even do they
you see that even this question which seems to stop stupid to start with actually
is not still the forefront of the research in academia
so the question i'm going to discuss is why many existing we pass over the
first hurdle life except exist
why are they so difficult to diagnose
can we even though know them first after that first
is about
could it be possible to actually that no them before they were so that we
can have some body
interesting policy making
and that will then pass on to
recent events with the real estate bubble on sediments worldwide
examining examining a few instances in the UK and the US especially
the subsequent about about but which is the mortgage
mortgage-backed security
above all can be considered as a specific level depending on
the financial but the real estate bubble
and the consequent dangers and possible systemic risks
that derived from these two interleague levels and then i try to show you that
there is some hope
by developing metrics ought to be quantitative
and i think that all the debate
would be raised in the first part of the talk
especially in all of that but i do think this can we can we say
something about them
can we do policy-making
should be articulated around developing new and better metrics
to inform us about this and show some progress the output of the blood
over the last decade or so
and some they would finish with some
prediction we
in which we stick all make out and
published in advance and what we the outcome
so let's start menu in for surfaces along the new
so what is how do we detect them how
can we predict i summarise you single slide
i would say the smallest the
o point of view
common wisdom in financial economics which is summarized by this review paper quite recent
and you can read that basically says what you can really developed
as that's when you look at the literature that for every paper that finds evidence
of financial bubble there is another one
that fits the data equally well without allowing for about
and we are still unable to the extra requested and able to distinguish bubbles from
time varying or regime
switching fundamentals mean that indeed there
in the kind of study that found can observe
these always from the framework way to justify these
supposedly numbers
price behavior pricing
in terms of different for series of the financial value
other firms
an interesting these but because they have
i should have said in the beginning there are
if they do exist if we can identify them and i think that in any
this debate scientific if we make
progress by looking at the moment is of course the monsters and the height
actually they don't have to reveal a lot of information between competing forces that are
seven interceptor way in normal times when these the extreme
we hope to see to learn more
so you see the understanding from the
economics fear in fact economics is pretty dismal now
let's shift two
professional a certain kind of professional
the federal reserve in the voice of
the previous federal reserve chairman greenspan
supposedly at the time the most powerful man in the world group
i give believe according to several
this is the statements in one of the papers he wrote
in the conference in
december two thousand two so
basically two years after the ICT internet communication technology bubble burst
led to approximately forty percent drop on the nasdaq and some of the major indices
in the US
also in major places
in europe and japan
and where was subsequently followed by continuous set of small shops and big towns
commutativity losing sixty seventy percent depending on the
financial centers
and you can see that what he said is pretty interesting we at the federal
reserve recognised that despite
our suspicions it was very difficult
definitely identifiable bubble until after the fact that is when its bursting confirmed its existence
and in addition even
so continued even if we had detectors such about
we wouldn't have done anything to prevent it
to prevent
what they were outcome could
from it
the risk of triggering
aftershocks of consequences that would have been content
that's very interesting from they said this was the most powerful man in in the
revealing complete lack of a
now lets me from this point of view now
try to build
the case
four indeed
pick a different randomisation unscramble the column
and hopefully by this destroy the complete structure which has been in your data
and then use this new grammar data to generate you reference
two to compute this
this uniform consisted taken scrambled data and apply to
i have some examples of this looks like
it's actually quite interesting to see what happens so here we have an original dataset
it's one we start off with
now the first they what i said you just generate a uniform distribution on the
same domain of this dataset so just check what is the smallest value and the
largest value it in this domain so that's the box here and you do the
for y axis you generate every uniform distribution in this box
the other thing the scrambling of the data
you see it on this figure already does something which
does not look like a uniform distribution so what happened here is
so you see that something which is sort of symmetric
we have
lots of so for example
none of the data points features in this
in this area here
and after spending we also have the features in this area here
so some of the scrambling
at least a bit
and the there
the area of the features
but it's not clear whether this is something good or bad
i think it can have both
and so what i have here is now plotted all those statistics
so no need to look
OK so the black line which is actually covered by the box here is the
original so we always with so for this dataset always concluded with since cluster similarity
that should be the measure which i want to evaluate my data
so if i look at the black curve it goes down like this so that
the curve and it's not very helpful
now if you look at the same curve for the uniform data
like this
it that's the other countries have which is like it's going down like this
but now if you look at the ratio between those
it's the started line here
it actually
that's this line here
in this case it's not really helpful so what it says something like it is
so i can say i don't know whether you can see it goes like this
so it has at its lowest point two
and then it goes up and small constant somehow and now take the minimum of
this curve you would say i take two clusters
and you can do it you can do is now for others like the dashed
line is
the line we used to describe the data here is the reference statistics it's more
or less constant so in this case it didn't really work very well actually
so if you take the minimum wage would end up with six h
but i mean that's more or less the way
it is assumed to
so in this example i only run once but of course it's better to run
it several times so what usually people do is you run you run your group
several times slightly different in sensational on the on your original data and you do
the same on the and in particular if you if is it to this randomisation
here i mean this is just a random instance so you should
draw maybe ten instances here and then average over it
actually i i can remember probably this is only for one example but i can't
remember how i
here we have the second example
well actually it doesn't show anything and so is what we see again is that
this kind data somehow
doesn't look the same as uniform data so someone just
it's also
right so
right so i think the effect in principle the effect is
it's got that
exactly that's what i want to the
sample from many parts of the space where i don't have data that could be
that it's a bit too restrictive so that means
it could be that i just by by chance only observed few features but in
fact there are some more features which are actually probably would observe more data but
i haven't so this so i think it's it was both the two extremes in
the in the the uniform case you just say i don't care at all is
simply random uniformly from the square
and the other cases say
i really only want to get results is or features it was exactly the same
values of as the ones i have my data so
something inbetween might be
so i mean of course but you could also try i mean by that i
mean again heuristics that you could try
simple sometimes for uniform sometimes from
from this grammar data and then take the average indian
i don't know whether that would be helpful
OK so that was about the gap statistic there's another way of
selecting the number of clusters which is the stability approach
and it's based
on a very high level some based on the fact that so we're doing science
working datasets and somehow one the results you obtained certain dataset is reproducible so if
i'm i don't have bioinformatics lab i do a certain gene microarray data experiment in
the cluster later on in all somebody else comes in a different levels the same
experiment clusters it with the same argument people would like that hopefully the results are
more less stable
OK on this high level i think most people would agree that we want the
results table of course something which is nice
now the idea for selecting the number of clusters is
we're just run over many times
four different numbers of clusters
we measure how stable the results in a certain way
and then we select the number of clusters the result is most stable
and i will show some figures how this works
in practice
two class case fifty fifth
it's a reasonable thing to do
and if the class is finite and small
it's often a good way to proceed to five small ten is more
in the case of
the continuous case like the ability to the class we had ten thousand interval zero
i mean this class is infinite but at least it's mathematically compact and you can
have a higher density
and especially uniform density here
the problem with the uniform density or
they generalizing the symmetry principle to the continuous class in this naive way is the
i assume that parameter in zero one
images p of ten to equal to
but then you know
but now somebody comes along and say OK let's think of different parameterizations
these square
which is also in the interval zero one
so what we then have we have
the detector
and you see the distribution size no longer uniform
so and i mean why is i mean this parameterisation
ten being by coin rather than taking
the square root of this
so that's the problem
which jeffreys and ran out of coal and so there is an analogue in
that is don't take it mathematically to literally sort of compact parametric
and you can employ jeffreys prior and if you would do that in the case
like glass case
it would be for instance ten times one minus that
two the power minus one
and what you would get is instead of la plata because k plus one divided
by n plus two
you will get half one
so that's sort of the default
prior in base so if you have a compact metric class
we have no prior background knowledge two labourers two
to get it then use jeffreys prior before fortress
no they have actually already
fifty fifty belief seems to have policies but then i see my data in the
past year then concentrates you know on the policies which is in this case is
more likely
i mean this case for instance that the MAP estimator then reduces to the maximum
i mean this is curves here so
i mean we saw in the continuous case
i mean you start with a uniform prior
tend to
and then you see some data concentrates
around the
true parameter
and the same is true in the discrete case
it so you get the maximum likelihood for you do but
if you see i mean if my parameter tend to live in
in zero infinity
i could apply maximum likelihood what i cannot use a uniform prior anymore
so this principle breaks down to do something else or if my class is the
class of polynomials of degree one two three four five
they assume even you compactify the range parameters
i mean what is a uniform parameter distribution over different dimensions
so that's sort of you you can argue maximum likelihood is good
if there exists a uniform bayesian prior
which is
often true this argument
the answer the question
OK so
but OK all the problem
this is the symmetry or principle jeffreys prior
is it doesn't work for large model classes
so even for countably infinite number what this
i mean there's no uniform prior over the natural numbers
you have to do something and the same there is no uniform prior over the
real or not impressed by all the real
so the solution is
the book come phrases which
favors simplicity
so what we need is and this is the next slide
quantitative and universal measure of complexity
let's assume that start simple let's assume you are binary
binary data
by spring
five or something
and i want to measure some of the complexity of the time
the file contains only zeros one million zero would say OK it's pretty simple
he recruited for the edges of pi
i mean there's more information and more complex
if there is no if you can't even figure out the structure so i mean
there's probably a lot of information in there
so the measure should i mean respect of course our intuitive notion of complexity
so what have you done for me you see the million one
i mean zero
the reason why you think this is simple because you have a simple description of
these are just one million zero
this description in english
so we need to formalize that so let's take a description of formal description
and the former language we can take
the programming language c
by small c program
four look for i one two one million brain zero
so you is
a universal turing machine or your favourite programming language
and x you binary string
and you look for programs which
plug into
universal turing machine the screen
your data x and there are many such programs
we look forward to take the length of the program and look for the shortest
and the length of this problem is called the kolmogorov complexity
and you see
that i mean
o zeros have short program
digits of pi
also quite a short programs of computer that high
but some random
the only way to store that
o to compute that some just print quotation mark in the data
if you have nonsense objects like a number of functions or whatever
you just call them in a binary way in
one way doesn't really matter
and then you look for the short program and computing by j
so in natural numbers
i mean there is a bijection between
and the to to the finer things we do that then you look for short
programs in the finance
and the icing
let's sing council
if we have this symmetry
in the probability distribution
of of r epsilon
you generate YT centered
that x t
and when you come to the ratio
of y or of x then you would have
q of x given y over q of y given x but you don't even
y is equal
q of ref
o y given x and therefore
the council
and all that directs
the use of
this random work in the ratio
of of the house
because just the speed
and the duration of stays at specific values are directed by f on
which is very nice thing because it makes are and if your interpretation of the
so for instance if you're rich
and next to
that has a very large compared with all the other if you close the mood
of f
it will take
for time to get out of the point
maybe if you propose values that are far away from that node
there will always fall in love regions
and you will stay
a long time
in that
xt on the other hand if c
is on the origin of
most of the value we propose
higher at
and therefore you removed
to this new that so on average
you will stay
to point
proportionally to at
therefore the frequency of visits of x
up to constant f of
never it makes sense that f is the stationary distribution of that she could f
of x
direct the duration of stay at
for the
so the disability
could could hold in in
theory and not in practice
well would say
example once more
OK i will processes that
we wrong proposal
and you will see that
there are two mode if you keep jumping
small scale
you can reach this but
the scale is too small to get to
to give an historical example here is the example of how things
in his original paper
it's the example of course you want to generate and normal
and instead of using the normal
use uniform
so the random walk
is just
xt and you move xt within the range of miners downtown
plus sixty
sixty plus delta
and of course the a property effective because around the world
is uniform
does anybody uniform is only the ratio
of the normals
you can get sample statistics that are not
of importance but the output
all of this algorithm depending on down here i began to take with you
one delta because you
o point five and that i call one
depending on the choice of tar
the move will be
on different scales of course so
down a small
i'll take millwall to go around and so this is the empirical mean you can
see that the empirical mean
it is very very correlated the integration of the sequence is very high
the phone content is provided by MIT opencourseware under a creative commons license
additional information about relations in MIT opencourseware in general is available OCW MIT the EU
so in this course because i am biological give you some examples between chemistry and
teaching the principles of chemistry and explained you
why that's relevant relevant how it applies to more life sciences biological areas is very
good sense of how i transition
being someone did not like chemistry i to someone who has now been a chemist
for the rest of my life
so this is another important point i like to make
which is never say
we need a subject
because as i said i really not like chemistry
and i became the doing chemistry for the rest of my life that happened to
very careful what you say
you may discover later that that's really what you want to be do it
all right
what are we going to do in the second half of the course
so we're going to start out by finishing chemical equilibrium professor there started this selection
from dynamic
the chemical equilibrium introduced you
the chemical equilibrium constant k
so we're going to take it from there review
what you cover on monday as well
then we move into acid base equilibrium this is four
and from there to oxidation reduction
reactions and just from this connection between chemistry
in biology
enzymes are proteins in your body that catalyze reactions which allows to
walk around breathe all those kind of things
most of these enzymatic reactions involve either
as these are catalyzed reaction
four oxidation reaction
so these are fundamental parts of living systems work
then we cover transition metals
and i'm going to explain during that part about medals in biology a lot of
enzymes required transition metals for their activity
so we'll talk a little bit about that
and then we end with that's in terms of the connection with biology
genetics rates of reaction
what enzymes do is they work it's how help you know those reaction
so all all these topics are fundamental chemistry topics they also applied to biology
so it's quite the second course is quite differently
in the first half of course go on the basic principles atomic theory orbitals bonding
lewis structures one really fundamental things which thermodynamics which you need to know to be
able to do the second half second happens is really more
these basic principles
and when you put this together
get the fundamentals of chemistry that you need to go on and study
chemistry organic chemistry inorganic biology life sciences the fundamental principles of chemistry which you get
through this has list of course
so it's one of the different transition i just like to
what you know
time it's going to be like the different cause you have a different structure
and really different material will be what you were before is really more applications so
it's to have a little bit different feel to it so don't be surprised by
are there any questions also the technical aspect of course is the same
lecture notes the with structure and everything
like that that's going to be the same person
calculators all
the rules of course do not change
but it's a little bit different materials
are there
any specific questions
feel free to raise your hand try
it is can help me i don't
so we see that someone has a question
in one extension usually know
what's fast
right so
we're we're doing a fairly smooth transition from material
on monday tuesday
we're still in the chapter nine o'clock on chemical equilibrium
and i just want to point out some things about the handouts received at the
time and i have a chapter and page numbers available
so if you want to
where this material is in your book so always going to be listed at the
top of the hand
i also on each hand out of the top topics that are covered in canada
or in lecture is just useful when you're going back and reviewing for the final
the yes on this day we cover these topics so that's going to be listed
at the top of each
and as as professor sara told you in a
is this lecture
help you
you don't have to scroll right all the time conference back in with more and
write things
like professor sara or something like sometimes when if you want to ask questions
so there are something like that you know and so
are available because there are many places are going to be wanting to write
we provide the summaries to make it easier
you don't have to scribble constantly is actually going on so that you can listen
what's going on
so that's pretty much the same what you experience course don't like lecture series and
no put way
he notes that you
even if it is simple size very close to and there's no point introducing this
was something operation because just introduce local violence OK and additional limestone so you don't
want to do that so whenever it is sample size that you can monitor is
essentially quite i just respond out of date and parties on your own you resample
when essentially you find the effective sample size is can become quite small below and
of the two
OK i'm not gonna i'm going to speak to you that but important thing is
despite the fact that you're using this with sampling the approximation of the state the
importance of the target distribution of interest but you also have an approximation of the
marginal likelihood of in terest OK
the only anything with this approximation is that despite these very complex was sampling operation
you're doing this estimate is unbiased so you can still do this week from c
or something or is it doesn't matter to estimate of the marginal likelihood is unbiased
so it may be seems to be like a complete detailed plans of that you
try to develop sophisticated algorithm later on the fact that this guy is is is
actually a very important part so
because my voice is weighted by
i'm just going to go through an example nothing else to
so let's go back to the you know remember the example discussed before two despite
the fact that sequential importance sampling doesn't work so
remember the example we had we had an email to aggressive policies for xk this
acceleration equation
and what i should in this case is that was are you will using the
prior distribution
essentially a clever approximation of the optimal distribution in both cases categories and was collapsing
in the sense that as n was increasing the effective sample size was going from
capital and to one
so now what we're going to do
which is going to do
this one fails on this one of the first
so what we're going to do
which is going to first
check the case
so this is the
the same algorithm as before except that now
whenever this is the is using is an important distribution something quite them because it
is the point of what is going to do now is that each time we
monitor effects on both sides on each time becoming bad
i'm using resampling step that is i'm getting rid of particles basically we've low weight
on them into playing particles with high weights so if you check know what's going
the algorithm to this is the empirical measure of the sample particles we see that
these songs to is very
simple resampling i'd like to reason is still a bold to keep track basically of
the true sequence of mister distribution that is actually already is just straightforward modification still
so we can obstruct basically of the sequence of the distribution but if you look
a bit what's happening to the effective sample size you can see that basically
sometimes egoism actually some sunk kind of collapse because you see for example at stage
eight all
in part of the solution was extremely bad and effective sample size at this stage
basically collapsed one which means that essentially guide or is completely cosh actually but never
mind found the resampling stage we were able to kind of course on we managed
to basically come back to keep track of the tall postal distribution
it may be delayed by one or something like that because it's a bit suspicious
it's true actually the remark
that must be delayed by one degree
so now let's have a look at
sequential importance sampling resampling algorithm where in this case instead of trying to using the
sampling distribution instead of using just prior distribution is involved in something distributions i'm using
these approximations
of the optimal importance distribution
we see that the algorithm still managed to keep track also of the second episode
and in particular if you look at the effective sample size which is the really
much better is that we see the effective sample size doesn't go
really really low
basically so it seems that it means in the sense that in agrees and they
leave a better approximation of the posterior distribution for given number of samples on that
is that you have to be careful because
it could be that actually
sampling from the basically
approximation of the human body distribution is very time consuming so maybe for and computational
complexity is better to increase the number of particles onto sampling from the point but
these things completely time this problem dependent so i don't have forty any i cannot
give you any general recommendations thing is like
so now i just wanted you to finish today by an important remark actually
from the very beginning
this morning we discuss
SMC methods in the context of in the framework of hmm OK
basically remember that we
so far
all the bayesian networks and markov random fields we end up with
we end up with the factorisation
and now the question is
should probably wait a bit until everyone is
it's here
i mean
there are some parrots outside people are excited about those things
i told them to bring inside
i think they have been bassett to bring the parents inside
whatever you call those animals
OK so certainly municipal graphical models are not as interesting as a
we can do much about
so well at least they have some green and red star
basically what we really saw so far in terms of practical terms was followed
a lot of all theory and laudable definitions and concepts
about graphical models
from the point of view of practice
what we saw
it was basically
of the fact that we have a factorisation of the joint probabilities for the question
is how do we actually compute things with this
representations of the joint probability distribution that's the question
if you want approach
so again i talking about distributive law fields and we think about it once again
i mean
what is being
what we are going to do here in in order to exploit
the structure
of the probability space that arises
the conditional independence statements
it will be the distributive law
and this is basically
the tool for performing
exact probabilistic
in a given probabilistic model
so in their essences here i mentioned already basically if you
use a common factor
in both terms of some
you're busy losing
basically you have three operations here the left hand side into operation the right hand
side actually
give you the same result
so you don't want to do the left hand side with the right hand side
so you want to put all the common factors in all the firms outside
performed the song
and this is actually the basic idea of exact inference in graphical models will just
instantiate general principle
in particular type article models and see how it works
so basically
for example consider and compute the marginal probability
p of x one
for a given microphone feel
remember that in the market field we have a normalisation constant
xe here
and have a product
over arbitrary functions of the maximal clique
in this particular case is probably takes this four i'm assuming given
graph in my mind
psi x
i an exit one
from i corps one two n minus one
so who would be able to tell me
which graph is this
so again
now each such suchanek yes such a so basically you have changed here OK
what you're utility from having the
if you have ten links may be getting one more than seventy five hundred forty
five two hundred and get them more
that we like overflow even what as your
so the fuel offload now right so the question is how much utility
get from from links and i think if we could get some handle on that
then it would be
they couldn't actually answer questions you asking missing
then you could define see what is the utility people are getting and then that
would be very nice to connect to
two adoption
so the way people creating links and so on
i think i think it's it's so it's a good point and i think the
only sort of
the the
the basically the work of
fabrikant papadimitriou is i think that the only one with the some kind of optimisation
going right when they say you know you want to create things but you don't
want them to be too long
and then power was much much
and i think there is a lot of connections to like
did here and so on
how to design
but i think it's a good point
the reason of
i think that's
it's it's called
actually we reject both so it's true what you're saying that if you start collecting
the citation network you will have this problem of you know taking up paper not
having sort of the he's right so have to start collecting one then actually checking
for that
and our conclusions they don't change and we also have networks for example
the networks social dislike linking and so on there computer networks that we know all
the edges that happened next densify
it seems densification is that for two uncertain about paper specifically we also just measure
was the average number of citations of paper has that also increases
so yeah i would reference lists getting
sure sure
on her
are like so many papers
it's been three years so i don't have a good for medium
we definitely checked like the everything that was going on and you should check medium
so this ability tell us is it like
you know is it on the average in some sense or is it like you
the data i steinwart papers
and then
four robustness
so what you know about the is that you know if you're going to remove
animals from the network then you really need to remove a lot to change things
but if you're going to remove high degree ones
you really change things alone
it seems to be like a universal property of networks and
now of course the question is how many emotions people like then that would be
doing that to destroy
i don't know if i have a
the answer
i mean in general we you know that going mess up with high degree people
that that for whatever reason there
that would mess of the network along
and that's probably the reason because we have a skewed distributions and then this and
this sort of extreme people are much more extreme than they've ever been
if we look can
if we can find gulshan distribution
here a
i mean this as i'm already excited now because sort of we are able to
two sort of modern humans as galaxies right or we see that even humans are
no different from galaxies in some sense which is sort of fun right
on the other hand
i don't think you that but hopefully he will be some questions also what statistics
does one they can use sort of because also
for example one problem today is like i showed you
i showed you case
two months my talk of the same thing so depending on what
but what granularity you want to model which is a different model so
we still don't have you no one working with one would
do everything correctly i sort of individual edge level and as fight on one long
enough and i think this global statistic everything with way so one thing that we
are doing this
getting this to sort of views together and trying to do everything by saying one
i don't know
i don't know if i can say more
so one
this this
harmon when i compare statistics
no no i mean i haven't done because i'm not true
so so what i know like i can prove that distributions we have this particular
parametric forms right what what this proves don't value is how these distributions are correlated
in some sense i can say for some value of parameters i can get
at the end of a distinguished career
in russia
whereas i was a teenager i was in high school when i had the idea
and i wrote my
first paper on this one i fifteen
when i was in high school and i wrote my first one paper on this
subject when i was eighteen
and half of it was published when i was nineteen in the journal of the
ACM and the other half was published a few years later in the gymnasium the
paper was only split into two halves
OK so the question the kolmogorov and i were most interested in was how to
define lack of structure or random you know some kind of local latin absolute lack
of any pattern structure in a string of bits
in fact in both cases
solomonoff was interested in induction in predicting the future
and that was not the main concentration the comoros and i had
how what i compare
this work will come over the maybe one or two small papers proposing this definition
and basically he was the end of his career and i was just beginning
so how would i compare
our work in this area
kolmogorov can be you know considering that the eighty had i would say it's remarkable
that he came up with the idea that all
you know as you get older you tend to get more conservative
so so
but the original version of program size complexity that he and i proposed and also
so of
proposed to send the same idea the size of the smallest program
i was wrong
it was actually wrong and i'm going to discuss that in a and part b
the question is self-limiting programs
so so on the one hand the original definition is wrong
and ten years later i changed the definitions the whole theory the theory was good
first ten
this is common and i came up with essentially the same definition
about that but we were both wrong so i'll tell you what the mistake was
and it only took ten years
in my case to get it right and come off i think was the
almost at that point so he did not didn't realize the definition was the wrong
second of all there is the question of what to apply this to
and as you know
i'm not interested in practical applications
but i'm interested in
in theoretical applications
and the application
the reason i came up with this idea
it is because my basic interest was incompleteness the basic question that fascinated me
i was getting competence
and what interested me was the question of
you know when you can see any structure in the world of pure math is
it's your fault or there is no structure
you see
because the good old talks about cases where there is no way to prove something
is true
so the question is if we can prove something
the way i do it i i i'm not a physicist but i studied a
lot of physics i love physics
i'm a mathematician mathematician but
but i read a lot of physics
and you know in physics you talk about the notion of randomness was discussed a
great deal in the nineteen twenties when quantum mechanics was developed
and when i was a schoolboy in this with the nineteen fifties
of the nineteen sixties
you know people
creators of quantum mechanics people like max born and schrodinger and einstein and bore was
still alive
and they were still discussing
they were still arguing over whether god plays dice in the physical universe you see
because the schrodinger equation is a probabilistic equation
quantum mechanics statistical physics you see in this other einstein for example is not deterministic
view of the world
so there now we've forgotten maybe about all of this controversy but but when i
when i was
as a student
the the people who worried about this was still alive
and also the echoes of that controversy which basically was from the nineteen twenties and
you you you know this this was still in people's minds
my idea you see the question we get all the fundamental problem
with kernel get show that there are mathematical assertions in arithmetic having to do with
zero one two three four five addition and multiplication he showed that their mathematical assertions
which are unprovable
that are true but unprovable
now unprovable depends on the formal axiomatic theory you're using in in fact he was
have theories have different composition of red and white
ships and then proportions which one is more likely what's the relative probability that the
standard data and it turns out people are the kinds of things
you give them just a few statistics that they could plug in today's rule in a very elementary way
and the average person that often doesn't know what to do with it
and this
crept into the popular r
press and all sorts of ways and you know maybe the young
the most famous was one stephen jay gould's most famous essays again this is what
people are reading when i feel saying our minds are not built for whatever reason
to work by the rules of probability but people who who came with age when
i did you know they saw that not just the workaday prose doing all the
probabilistic revolution in machine learning and i i just thought you know that's that's crazy clearly this
this this is the strong candidates for understanding something about intelligence so that the beginning
of this research programme was for list was work that i did together with tom
griffiths where we took a number of basic cognitive capacities and just try to see
how could we understand these as basic forms into the statistics typically bayesian statistics where
there's some kind of
key role being played by some prior knowledge that we can formalize and simple kind
of textbook-style statistical distributions of show you just one example of this
because it's it's one that anybody who study bayesian statistics
you might recognise and it sort of sets up the logic you might want to
obtain foreign and raises the challenge for how do we get more structured kinds abstract
so here a bunch of problems that all have a similar form
you read about a movie that has made sixty million dollars to date how much
money will it make in total
you see that something has been baking in the oven for thirty four minutes how
long until it's ready you meet someone who is seventy eight years old how long
where they lived
your friend quotes to you from line seventeen of his favourite poem how long is the poem
are you need the ust congressman who served for eleven years how long will he serve in total
so each of these is what we call an everyday prediction
four there's some
quantity event duration
will represent their with tea
that's u i would like to make inference about but you don't deserve
this you just observe some sample the state it was sorry and here's my notation
teetotal is represents the unknown total extent and duration and one of these phenomena and
you observe one data point tea
all you know is that it's a random sample between zero and teetotal and you
have to make a guess teetotal now what's nice about these problems is that these
different classes everyday events we can go out with publicly available data come up with
the right prior
the those are shown along the top you know what really goes through the specifics
but free to these different domains movie grosses poems and so on lifespans you can
compute the empirical
distribution on on how long these things last
and then you can now do bayesian inference you can condition this prior on one observation
and then make a guess the particular estimated that reusing is what's called the posterior
median so updating this this prior with one sample that we know is all we
know is that between zero end
and the team that's the prior on two to total
and then we take our posterior distribution we look at the median so that's our
best guess how long this thing is going to last
and what you can see on the bottom are plots of the posterior median predictor
four fourteen for the empirical priors there
and they plotted against people's judgments four five five different data points that be
the x axis is represents the value that people were given the why axis is the median people's guesses on
you know i need to these problems given one of those inputs so
for just to be very concrete that's means like some subjects were told about the
movie that made sixty million dollars but others were told about when amazing thirty million
dollars or a hundred billion dollars and there are five different values across subjects for
each of these different questions
and all i want you to take out from this is that's people are extremely
close to the bayesian predictions there's a sense here which people are sort of w
optimal the optimal in the sense that what's the mapping from the top to the
bottom of the prior to posterior predictive is the optimal bayesian prediction
and people seem to match that's but notice how these the qualitative form of the
optimal bayesian prediction varies across each of these domains because the priors have different forms
that shows up in the past year prediction people seem to get it's as if
they're doing the right mapping from prior to posterior with the right prior to enter
the structure of the domain
so this another kind very basic quantitative successes convinced us and others take the idea
of observed the probabilistic inference framework for
cognition seriously
but how do you get this disk these hard problems i'm saying we really want
to solve like the problem of learning
a label for objects from a few examples are intuitive reasoning about physical scenes are
intentional agents interactions you it's not even clear what is the right prior hypothesis space
how you can measure it process scientist let alone for human learners who are trying
to build up this knowledge so this leads us to to turn toward some kind
of more expressive knowledge representation language something that isn't just you know
exponential family distribution you can get for bayesian stats
and you know like many people in
any i was it heavily influenced by the work of a not just probe and
many others in the traditional policy graphical models
bayes nets directed graphical models seem particularly appealing because so much of human cognition so
much of what i'm talking about here
is essentially causal
but it more generally the toolkit graphical models
has been very influential not only in any i but according to model as for
similar reasons it gives you two main things that gives you eight
eight general-purpose knowledge representation language right away to represent the cut this the structure of some complex domain
and it gives a general tools for doing inference saying you know all you have
to do with the model as described the causal structure here using bayes net
and just these sort of direct causal dependencies that's the errors in the graph and
then the the tools and bayes nets give you in principle and working tools that
people are built
and ability to do arbitrary conditional inferences to observe some variables and make inferences about
others right so in the famous q mark network air you might observe symptoms and
make inferences about diseases you might then make predictions about other symptoms the results medical
tests you might see
and so on this is again very familiar
and something basic you i think some there's something basically right about some kind of
probabilistic also representation language is the way to think about common sense but what's missing
from this
and this is what leads to these these kinds of representations we call probabilistic programs
basically it's the it's the idea that a graph
is too impoverished representation too simple
describe because the kind of rich knowledge that humans have about the causal structure of
the world we need some kind of more powerful probabilistic language some more prop powerful
way of describing the probabilistic causal structure in the world so think about this kind
this workshop seen that i've shown a few times right how can you take an
image and make an inference inference about not just what's wear
what what supporting what would happen you know if you if you move the table
you know that those things would fall
you can see there's a maybe you can see over there on the lower right
there's a tyre leaning up against the table you can probably make the inference that
tyres a little more precarious than say one of those
cups right there very solidly on the top of the table so a slight bump
might make table might make the tyre fall that won't affect the cups on
how can you do this
well here's a way of thinking about it which in some sense looks like a
bayes net a way to capture this
intuitive knowledge here but but also i think draws attention to what's missing so we
have this have this picture here which describes the well i think it is roughly
the causal processes that are that are giving rise this data
there some kind of image that you observe and here i'm showing just a static
image but in general we could be looking at dynamic scenes like those movies showed
and that's image is
in some kind of output of graphics processor right graphics is that it let's say
dealing with this process of taking disease that story potentially vast array
acoustic parameters and using those as input to our feature detector
extracting a set of features for example these might be
for the multivalued set that attributed to king here we might have i guess eight
different features and each of these features can take on
the values that are listed here in the table
and so
i in that case i would have one any cause eight features and these could
take on these distinct values i may then perhaps as output at this stage i
would i might have perhaps the posterior probabilities associated with these features that would get
passed along two
this search phase where i might have a lexicon that is defined in terms of
feature distinctive feature bundles as we talked about earlier in the sort landmark based model
and we might have various other knowledge sources that we can represent in terms of
those qualities as well
something is one way of doing so
there again there's problems
and the biggest one here is
how do we see you know we're doing supervised training if we're going to train
the detector will we have to give examples that have labels if i'm going to
train detector for say
let's say
for the manner of articulation
i'm going to have to label my speech frames
with the proper
many manner for that that segment and assume that will serve as the truth
as i as i as a trainee systems
the fact that we really don't know these quantities and that in fact there are
hidden in all we can see is the acoustics is a big problem so
one thing we can do is we could we could say that we have the
feature transcriptions right we can say that we've got phonemes right we have let's say
we have had labelled phonemes will assume that we can expand each phonemes in each
phoneme into a list of features editor of all it's a it's you know like
i could go back to each of these this of all i i could tell
the what the manner of articulation is i could tell you whether it's low mid
or high vowel
we could say is voice phonation so basically i can look for each of my
phonemes i can look up in this table
and say OK here the the distinctive features is the correct values for this distinctive
features and i can then use those supervision and training
problem with that
it is the actual feature values are going to change in these canonical values and
really what we acquired if all we're going to do is mapped from the phonemes
to the features and and train these these detectors that we just in that case
coming up with just a different representation phonemes in fact that's not true but but
that's something to worry about the
the other possibility is let's uses direct physical measurements let's go to the the databases
where we've collected aligned acoustics and and and articulatory measurements let's just take those measurements
and use those as the truth
well first that it's a bit hard to come by will have people spitting out
you know the the coils in their their articulagraph
choking and before we get enough data and the other thing is that it can
be difficult to actually convert these sort of geometric physical measurements to to feature values
well i'm new writing the possibilities here and they all got their downsides the we
can actually go through and manually labeled distinctive features take an expert in go
decide whether or not there's voicing at this point separate from the question of whether
or not the place of articulation is where it's supposed to be
that's that's fine too but there's the issue of defining labeling scheme this repeatable that's
and and where we get agreement among labelers and that takes time actually carried of
i looked into that i guess with simon king as well at the works the
art workshop in two thousand six
and i think the labelled the whopping like eighty utterances
and they figured it to become a thousand times real time
and again i guess was practice you get back but it it's a thousand yeah
OK so there's again the issue of
of the that being difficult to come by one interesting solution that people have been
looking at recently is is doing embedded training we start off by using these kinds
of features is the basically start with the phonetic phonemic transcription map those to the
distinctive features and then we do it training procedure that allows these things the boundaries
between the individual features slide around
OK and i will describe
essentially the
this is to be quite active in a lot
in dealing with places so not just face recognition but
do expression recognition
trying to actually this track faces synthesizing new faces and things like that and
if you have a really good registration like this registration you can do very very
good job all these other things become a lot easier
my trying to recognise the face from recognise expression because you actually getting the proper
measurements from five
whereas up until kind of
quite recently opened the last five years or so people tend to do this stuff
does using a box kernel is putting to big-box in into supplying extract machine learning
but what i'm going to try and argue to you guys today
it is actually
we should be relying on computer vision for a lot more than just providing box
you should be trying to get very very dense registration to better the registration that
you have the body going into in the machine learning task trying to do
at least in the vision role
also i think registration is sorely seeping into
well the techniques from vision that we're developing seeping into other domains as well but
particularly talking about vision
some other kind of cool things process my
it's kind of cool this is something that we're doing for car company essentially and
you have the light detector frontal face
and we use something called interest point detectors and you don't have to have a
model of what the person's face looks like from this angle of this single what
it does is simply track individual interest points over time
and you have the interplay that until some so obviously a human space doesn't look
like it so that they can actually do a pretty good job of tracking the
face and actually getting ideas of the pose and things like that
some of the things we had to do with prices we deal with body tracking
and again it's sort of like the non rigid movement and there are things like
you can do
background subtraction and the types of things that actually get meaningful features where the body
bodies but there is the additional problem of everything and doing that the registration and
really what i'm going to try to do this kind of going to
there are the
the nuts-and-bolts what's going on
this is something that comes
close to my heart this is what i actually did my phd thesis in visual
speech recognition couple of a number of years ago now
and so
and again it's another visual task that essentially is very very important for
doing the computer vision
now if you were to ask this
kennedy had is now viewed as a my
head boss CMU to canada
what the three
the biggest problems in computer vision that he basically just rattles off registration
registration and registration that's and basically we're at CMU kind and not about registration that's
what we can do a lot of work on been doing work over that for
a long time and i think we're going to continue working on it because there's
a lot of
problems that still open in the slot and new avenues where we believe we can
apply a lot of this stuff
another application is in harm's palm recognition so we can come to see that this
measure is very small this machine more exact set using the exact same technique but
what is
this is kind of odd
visual example showing that
we can apply the technique to both things and also in contract
so this is something that's interesting here two and again this is what kind of
back to the box depicted here
even with the box effect these sort of things are difficult because when you tracking
an object over time especially all of the time and in traditional tracking what these
do is essentially use the last box was tracked incoming use that as the model
for the next frame
but what tends to happen at the time to get this thing on the drift
so if you look at this track are long enough time
this box will come to get caught noise solid drift dot
so a lot of computer vision researchers also that can recognise problems with drift so
that you can
adaptor things at the time but you don't lose the object itself
this is some motivations obviously there's a whole
what more
applications of things is sort of things that i worked on various government projects and
papers and other things sort of and so forth for your visual pleasure so
so that's the kind of motivation for why that we're looking looking at this problem
now if you guys who now
can i get a kind of a
sample from class who's done anything in computer vision you all kind of like that
that is not really does it so
hopefully some of this you also get something out of this for a larger audience
out there i just want to collect make a kind of
these are my thoughts
as a machine learning person or someone who is applying machine learning division what should
actually be thinking about and essentially
machine learning has to revolutionize a lot of money i disciplines say computer vision to
example speech
some of the text mining and so on and so forth i mean and machine
learning providers with you a set of ubiquitous tools that can kind of plug-and-play into
these different domains but i think hopefully what you guys together into this last
two weeks with two weeks are wrapping up
is that all of time with this machine learning tools there's a little bit of
carol you really have to think about the domain specific information
that goes into applying the tools so something that my work extremely well
speech may not work well at all in vision and actually that's that's very true
looking speech literature
things known as generative models like hidden markov models gas mixture models will be sort
of these these things that are very very prolific in speech gives much mention in
vision spew we over time out of this but the main assumptions and domain specifics
about the problem and so what translators if you can think of vision problems is
being cast
and you're gonna make you kind of got the the standard that screwdrivers got the
ball in you get everything else
if you're not
take into account
the domain specific information redundancy for the distribution so if you try and kind of
you to take advantage of that we don't to have knowledge about
this is the sort of thing that goes there goes on
it's also what kind of goes on when i
that's my concern markup but
so what kind of one
essentially was you guys is that
really and this is not just the vision this for anything where you are applying
machine learning and that's what
in my research so far that's really what i've done been really inspired a lot
machine learning but i'm really motivated by finding applications
and a big thing that i kind of motivates me is going to disappoint all
the people just avoided for active
but there's nothing to prevent you from having to additional develop
so what you then would have basically
a decision function
well you wouldn't
white star
of x
being the argmax
overall y fronts
part of x and y fronts of it
but it will just use that
the trouble with this is that as you get
lots of y for instance if looking at every station
you get in factory many why you would actually need to for the efficient way
it's not really so much trouble finding good representation for it
if you're talking about the five hundred plus from the recovery
you're talking about graph matching
sequence that i
web page ranking
don't bother
just to complicate the story
it will just really seriously messed up the optimisation of
i mean as in the implementation of make it so much harder to do but
for the
any other questions
i have also seen this
approach to multiclass problems where people have four in classes they they have in separate
is millions and then they somehow combine they are going to think about this system
obsolete now OK so
there are various ways on
solving multiclass SVM optimisation problem
so one of the ways of solving them is by
well i mean yes you could do exactly what you suggest namely have in one
was the risk classifiers
and then you just fold in one of the rest of the misation problem
and the idea would be
at the correct class will always win
but you can actually get lots of ambiguous solutions out of it
this is one of the reasons why am i might not want to choose
there's another one way you could simply have like the tournament
for let's say like like this or
in the final round around the world cup it just how well you character classes
as the colony with further down and down
you can do this
you will also get some people
not happy the uniqueness problem anymore
i mean how do you know which way you should combine the class
he might actually be making a problem much harder
there are
very nice productions like all by pope john langford
but but but really what is the point at which
the net
a lot of other stuff companies like
he has come up with a
nontrivial version of this
tournament scheme
and he works local reduction so what is massive is married to find some
essentially combination of finding that problem
which also performed fairly well multiple
it doesn't work so well for structured estimation but multiclass has also been
i'm not saying that
this is why i think and why tried mapping is the only way you the
thing is also well is not only one simple way of mapping x and y
to be just right
you can probably cover some of the other things but just in the right
it's by the politics and what i
and in days
a set of
this information
written and experimented and corroborated by people from the might
which argues that actually those one versus the rest
but it was incorrect somewhat better
OK beta distribution
so now we are going to into more and more exotic exotic territory of distributions
that you might encounter
well actually not quite
you and before
we had logo
where x in one minus six is our sufficient statistics
for the
binomial distribution
here we have the loss of those
then i just taking product with some parameters theta one and theta two and i
again restricted domain of the axis
now to be the interval between zero and one
before that we had just events zero in one
well that's a beta functions
that's why it's called the beta distribution
well you can essentially model a lot of
and peaked distribution on the unit interval with this
they don't have to be symmetric but i've just drawn three symmetric ones
for instance the uniform distribution over the unit interval is member of it one that's
peaked at the tail
one this peaked in the middle or you could also have some which are skewed
you can actually model a lot of distributions over the unit interval
by the distribution
likewise you could take a gamma distribution
well now rather than taking the unit interval
takes into all between zero and infinity
and we get slightly different sufficient statistics you get the slightly different integrals here
enough you go gain
the one thing to notice is that he had this to say to
it's actually
in a rather funny space
theta one so the first quite efficient here can take any value between zero and
let's equal infinity whereas the second parameter
it is within this opening to all of them both scenes
so the overall domain is convex but there is no guarantee
the interval that the domains are actually close
make sense so for instance when you
i have a normal distribution
well you can have
i mean there in an inverse variance
which goes as close to zero as you want to know what the variance can
be as large as you want but it never will be infinity
so this means that the inverse variance will never be zero
and so therefore we always have an open interval in the parameters
there is no guarantee
that the intervals on which are operating on closed
and actually have sometimes get really funny effect happening at the boundaries and if you
want to know more about that you should talk to have issues with an entire
papers on that
some galleys submissions
OK and basically you can get things which are really peak that's zero
or something which is
little bit what else but essentially reasonably heavy tailed
mister can make them this way
is an entire solar g some in eq
go on and talk about more so you can have this latest revision of heart
and what have covered all those
and the way they are all
just different in terms of their choice to fall picks
and the domain
in the measure
as soon as you pick any combination of some topics
the line which you define it
and the measure with respect to which you want to measure this domain
you have everything that you need for exponential families distribution
in quite a few cases you can be solved in the integral analytically
and it's great
and those are the cases that most likely would have already been studied before in
some stats
well then you just put things together and you can build larger inference model so
for instance if you use this as a conjugate prior in certain cases you can
produce an entire
stream of papers based on exchangeability and so on so make sure been
using this
distribution here quite extensively
and for instance if you have
what happened on the a
so you see that you should be done in time for the next two seasons
times k
this just
he was
it's not that the way
this is kind of
common in real
the structure
and i think i was attacked by three wrong
compute trees have or common
so what happens between two
three years
this is a very
the concentration of
these are usually
so three
you should be extension
we we can actually do the right thing to do
i mean use
it's not
what we can it
well actually
they really
but i have to be
well don't know
OK so the
probabilistic models
approaches one
so we also have the right all of
we're trying to use
like it
reading of the world
the model
to the
he well
she was
and you can i
don't know
we can put a
we can actually
and the
a ten
OK case
so this is quite interesting
this model is
the probability of generating
three of the to be
we found
with a lot
in some way
and this is a
small providing one feature which is the probability of the
how about of those two
examples in all
as i said from the rest of the pie
the set of all time
thank you the for
to some
an efficient way to do this
what i do
you need to know
i think it would be down
we need to work
i mean this is to do so
design the
so i
not sure
OK so
i think it's
this ridge regression is called
that's because you find additional probabilistic information
it's fun
we've seen
what you need
some really
so this whole
the problem
and there's also something called a query for which she
and just
i two
this is that it's important just
new solution regression just
which is much more actually
this is really
and that is the reason why we're trying to
for example
so i mean people that to
this mission
one that this is
coming off
why is this idea
so far
rather than the
the question which is what
he saw
i'm long on my top talk i have zero
can lost art i know what