but it's uncertain examples often cases even for the human it wasn't it was very
difficult to distinguish the right feeling of of that sentence
and so there are few include table that
it's about time i'll skip over it
but this uncertainty sampling and relevance and for more negative
they were quite
so successful
and then i go to the first to the last five minutes
we have a project together with many computer vision people
there we
try to
how the computer vision this is the first objective
to help computer could recognition in computer vision
based on text analyses but also we want to build a second goal
is to build a joint models
models of content recognition
they jointly exploit text images and this is the european projects the class project you
can put in
some some reference to its tool in the text
it's a joint project with the university of oxford and systems which is very good
group with india and france where it
the machine learning group of two billion of that not show
schalke of
so we and also with university of helsinki so we have
quite interested in this topic
now i'm going to show a very small part of this project of which one
of the phd students work
he is interested in
semantic role recognition sentence so my my you shut up walks towards the field
so we have all these terms
we have to recognise this one to be named entity recognition
so we have these terms which
described by a feature vector we want to find clusters y
maria is active the move we want to recognise the movement actions
two locations
also this is also common sense two
and i have
we rely on
video debates from buffy the vampire slayer
i don't know if know
fifty three different
i i don't have the sound
but i can say
that's it
no it doesn't
they should be
thank you
i wanted to play video but some sentiment
we have these these videos
of buffy the vampire slayer and these soaps for teenagers and there are also lots
of teenagers who
all right
this writing scripts for its videos on the web you can find so
actually they follow the images
and they very accurately right
what is being done so buffy opening the refrigerator it or somewhere i wanted to
stop the video
so buffy opening the refrigerator and taking out a carton of milk
you see opening the refrigerator this kind of action that is being performed by the
actor the
she's also taking out a carton of milk so these are
semantic role that we want to to recognise
there is a lot of these in this area include it also some references
the earliest
references from several should they are in two thousand and two in computational linguistics
but we have currently who
the issue of computational linguistics
assigned to these semantic rules section
now our task is to do weakly supervised learning here so we a limited amount
of training examples and also to combine evidence from the images
the first task we have now called accomplished the second one is its
so we use hidden markov models conditional random fields
and we have to fight
learning of
we will also submit to speed
we learn mixture multiple mixture models
we learn that interference in based on expectation maximisation but also
approximate experiencing gibbs sampling with a markov chain monte carlo
two too weakly supervised
but then this is quite difficult it's quite difficult to
improve the results based on
so we have lots of petulance
we have this sentence forest features which are not
usually very accurate
and i defer is also
on the
there are some work some years ago
by like university of pittsburgh
funny building housing kevin actually
and the child to recognise factors and factors are
abstract concepts in the law
like medical malpractice might be a factor
or maybe it's it's maybe already more an issue but factors are a certain constellation
of facts
and issues of certain constellation of factors so they are more abstract concepts that they
want to recognise in these descriptions so that because they usually search
you can have some facts pictures in long
when you are really looking at similar case
based on the exact facts of the case
so like also intelligence services of police services you have some effect and you want
to find similar cases
but in low there is also another type of search when you're looking for
abstract concepts and you want to find that all these cases where certain concept applied
whether the facts the facts can play can be
can be there from different domains to have similar concepts and then they want to
reason with it is concept even if it's
you know there's a lot of cases in other domains for instance of india
this was
they use also machine learning techniques
main base and decision tree learners use in this case
so induction of decision trees
and that it was difficult days
they did not succeed very well in finding automatically
these factors
this set where difficulties in the language or the language combined with the typical legal
syntax semantics
lou is characterized by long phrases sometimes answers
lots of close
so far my and difficulties
there were some of us have this
this is something we are doing our group
is recognition of argumentation
so we want to find out
what is the conclusion of work primarily legal cases you also the european court court
of human rights
we want to find out what is the final conclusion of the church
and how did he came to that conclusion what are the arguments that
the premise somehow
that's way
that are the basis for that conclusion
but it's not so easy
you have very little discourse cues and if they are they are quite ambiguous
and also argumentation business that so we have
one of the conclusions
the final verdict and then you have this is to that conclusion that each of
these parameters can be a conclusion itself and can have supremicist there so it's a
very nice
it's almost tree so
most of the cases the tree like structure
so that makes it a little bit more easier
but it's still
quite difficult
but also here we think
there is some rules also
when monitoring meetings or discussions political discussions speeches political speech
also maybe
medical decisions
what are the arguments
for a certain treatment for instance of patients so we could we could find these
then we have this processing of informal texts
well as
you know spam
email spam for instance
in lots of diversity need lots of
information that is being and
because the u
spammers want to mislead the filters
so they tried to
to use all kinds of tricks actually
in these emails to this doesn't make the processing
of this information easier
it's quite a challenge
when you try to hide compared to in the males
we have be some publication on this
the second yeah good as gold mining station i use relations that always explain
now i get that sort of the only things
you've probably seen by state machines
it's some point in your
courses on this is a probabilistic finite state automata OK i mean if you move
between states with some probability not deterministically
so here we have two states as well as to
you have two actions change or stay
when you next in action
the probability p called whenever on air healthy with probability
you take that transition
so if i phi phi device could actually stay in stage one
it was point nine probability of transition back state one
with point with probability
i transition
stay one to the right to stage two
this that the transition probabilities of next given the current state this on the one
now if i change deterministically i always transition state one state two and was a
institute and this stuff
but actually the probability one will transition back to state two
OK can read this
problems the question of how many
given given to
take an action s
you stated symbols
i can find the present tense problems however one so so try to reach much
natural language into high label these things the idea and this this is the same
as the previous problem that i showed you were essentially you can change the state
one state two
but but if you try to change the state to just get stuck
stuck in situ two
i recorded in absorbing state in in this instance is instead of illinois
yeah exactly
so so stochastic you take an action you want that certain what the world will
choose for you
with some probability how were stacked
the sequence of again
fully their this notice assumption
OK states
so to set of one two actions stare change
OK stay because one article stay i get to it given the red
i get
if the states one
OK this is a i i think
inconsistent here
if they are
technically would condition reward and next as well
in order to get this diagram to show it to be our current state current
action next state
then you get rewards that shelter in the red
so yes
let me
rewards can be conditioned on the current state
the current action in the next day
the two
you would be doing ten
in in this diagram
many you know it if if you want to model them
then know
and that's what i want
o point point this is a bug in my slide i'm trying to cover up
as i'm in it this way
but you can only think of the next state and reward function it is legal
and finally there some complexity term penalizes for the number because otherwise you would always
prefer to explain everything with more layers for this is what chris and john promises
in the christmas gifts the number one christmas gift the arkansas is you need some
kind of complexity term here as well
these are
after four hours of use that's important but i do want to emphasise that this
is not a quadratic energy function so you have binary then multiplying the quadratic term
and you have sort of parts model kind of interaction and so the minimisation is
much more complicated you can solve this simply by inverting the linear system of equations
but the use of sort of algorithms to minimize this we did find that these
kinds of low energy minimisation models
pretty much wider range of perception human vision that is not
but the previous algorithms that but they can also explain for example here in this
display that we've been looking at
they take these four dots group them with the sorry this down here
so this is the assignment variable to number two
and this is the calculated motion field the rotation
whereas these fifty that are perceived to be moving up and down
and then just showing but we found that for a large range of stimuli
this kind of low energy minimisation model correctly
predict the motions to correctly here in quotes because again there is no such thing
as the correct answer these are inherently opposed to
but you can find a solution that is
consistent with what humans see
he served
that was my thesis defense at least part of the natural question is what if
you can do so these ellipses can you translate models on the real
sequences like this one that is can we take an input image sequence of images
that look like this
that was photographed in the real world and somehow automatically figure out how many layers
there are the motion of each layer
any assignment of pixels to layers
and one thing that became apparent that when you start thinking about this is that
all these small constants that appear in these energy functions you might be able to
get away and tweaking if you need to explain i don't know ten different stimuli
between different stimuli but if you really want to know that become complex a large
number of complex sequences and that those energy functions will tend to have many many
parameters and this is just because of course it is hopeless to try to tweak
these families by hand we method that would allow us to learn this energy function
the challenges the real sequences poses the optimisation of the inference challenge
again binary variables so this these are nonquadratic energy functions with continuous and discrete models
so maybe you can get some heuristics for some very simple stimuli but actually optimizing
these energy functions
for arbitrary complex sequences of very challenging problem
so here's the the journey and the gene has two parts large part and
different parts of of the dream is that we should
just lose energy functions automatically from data that is
just showing two randomly chosen image sequences here but imagine downloading tens of thousands of
genes of image sequences from youtube
feeling those
image sequences into learning algorithm
and that will come magical energy function that would have no free parameters everything will
be completely dictated by the learning algorithm
so that's the first part of the dream
and the second part is an inference stream that supposed to be figured out this
energy function
we were taking your image
in sequence
and just get into an optimisation and inference algorithm
i mean automatically find the global optimum of the energy that would come to layers
the number of layers and the motions of each layer
so as you can see by the fact that colour doing you can realise that
i'm not going to give you
the solution to those two parts but in my defense i have tell do you
something my brother
who a mathematician told me which is how to to get a ph d in
so is the algorithm advisor proposes an open problem
the student fails to solve the problem from lemmas along the way
in the ph d thesis describes the lemmas so the rest of this talk will
follow similar
so we really solve this problem
but i tell you about two so-called like that we've managed to prove along the
and not really was of course the more sort of results are as follows the
first one
is an optimisation or an inference result which is that for many real world low
level vision problems we can efficiently find the global optimum of the energy function and
the second one is learning
result which says that for many real world low level vision problems we can efficiently
learn energy functions
and actually be discussing
examples of these results from that i listed here just
a small number of additional results by many other researchers and this is just the
a sample and they think these two kinds of results
have been demonstrated not only now but in a number of other papers over the
last ten years until about the first one first the inspired
this is the issue of global optimisation in stereo vision
so stereo vision is that
what i was doing the day-to-day basis when we look at the world through two
of his fingers stereo
it's actually is given a sequence of images showing here is a man meeting a
sequence of images but the sequence of images were not actually taken by camera over
but taken simultaneously by
many different cameras so if this were in the case of human vision you could
imagine and animating the two views taken by two hours at a given time and
the point is if you do that if you have things this way
this way the motion the relative motion
between the two
this corresponds to death so that's called the disparity of every pixel and basically things
are very far from us
you appear to be the same in the two hours was things that closer to
us will have very different location two hours and this is a very strong view
that we use to estimate the
so this is an example lot of this task because our job is to go
to put
at every pixel
the disparity at every pixel
and i was surprised of population of the energy minimisation this goes back at least
to martin junior these is by energy minimisation
writing down an energy function has two terms a local data
which essentially just looks at a single pixel and says given the current in the
sign that i
how likely is it that this pixel moved three
up to the left of the pixels to the right so that the data terms
and there's also the smoothness term
which penalizes pages that penalizes discontinuities in the disparity field
typical instead this one energy would also take into consideration the colour
so you larger penalty
for discontinuity
if two neighboring pixels have the same colour and much smaller penalty
all of them so on
on one side we have the simplest answer this would be character level then
from characters we compose words we can deal with words and phrases and part of
speech tags and taxonomies like
wordnet and so on so this sort of this would be kind of lexical
type of representation next next to vector space model language models
what are seeing and cross modality so i've pulled this
representations under the so called syntactic syntactic level and at the most
used actually in text mining so especially vector space model would be most often useless
in information three will text learning and so on
and the semantic web presentations would be that's a collaborative tagging social web two point
zero would be hidden somewhere here templates frames so popular presentation and so one of
the most complex ones ontologies and first order
slightly roughly semantic so or collaborative tagging is hard to say whether this is really
semantics not but somehow it's closer to semantics and it's just syntactic level
OK now let's go first this character level
so character level means simply just taking the documents taking the text and split on
the characters and maybe use just sequences of two or three characters and that's it
another this sequences of characters we constructed constructed vectors of frequencies and this then used
by learning and because
he said that text has this nice provided that
uh it has a lot of redundant data it's a lot of redundancy in information
so it's
quite likely that we will be able to solve some of the problems
so this representation has
a couple of very important strengths first is very robust because it avoids language morphology
and especially resentation is used but for language identification that a lot of applications including
i think that's a good will and so on some are using language and ification
and this can be done very efficiently just by
checking the frequencies of
the character sequences
you can also capture the simple patterns on character level and this is then used
for spam detection copy detection so these problems are fit very nicely to this presentation
we can do also learning clustering search with this representation but somehow these this can
get them quite limited is also quite popular inspection this kernel methods support vector machine
so-called string kernels which are trying to capture this more complex sequences of characters but
some of this can get quite complicated and a little bit less efficient but this
experiment i guess this was
quite well accepted from the community for some deeper semantic desk tasks like understanding the
this text this presentation with me wouldn't be a properties simply too weak
we don't have even worse become just a couple of
character sequences
so for this next level we can go to the level of words
obviously this is very obvious representation of text documents so that we just
do they could tokenisation and split the document into the more items you can find
numerous of the positions of the packages on the maps it is quite easy what's
also important to note that worked for some languages at least it's not so well
defined as in china some important somehow worked
words are not so nicely list split investor languages so this is just
what are the most relevant words properties
the main ones would with the following so
homonomy so
we have the same surface form but different meaning plenty river bank or financial institution
so the the bank means what
and we need to be able to
decompose these two meanings
december great this
two meanings in the proper than polysemy
very have the same forum and related meaning like
the bank will be the blood bank or financial institution again two
meanings but similar ones
synonymy this is usually the most problematic one different performance a meaning like singer or
locally so they mean the same but they have different
surface form and hyponymy one word denotes a subclass of
the other one like breakfast meal
it would be such a relationship
so we need to be able to deal with this property is when we are
doing some kind of analysis of texts
what also very important to say so word frequencies in texts have the so-called power
distribution which we will see later on when we will discuss graphs and ling link
structures there are basically
it was down to the following two properties we have small number of very frequent
words like the and the and so on and big number of very low frequency
and this the the structure generates redundancy in
in fact so this is very important underlying property which
usually we are not even aware of it but some of the generates lot has
a lot of consequences on algorithms which we use for text
so a few more things about this word level representation so we often use so-called
mismatch between the doctors and the people who actually looking for the information OK so
you have the technical vocabulary on one hand and then you have the
you know
layman's terms of describing certain symptoms and diseases and so on and so forth and
but very often you have documents that were both things corker
and so you know using statistical methods you could actually figure this out
so here is actually
right and then you can we can also do things like
actually disambiguating queries this just an example of which
i used to show you that once you have learnt a richer model in the
so you can you can you know there's certain usability features that you can derive
from that so here is a case where we have a query like in this
case bleeding
which is in a sense highly ambiguous because
you know
there are things like concept one concept his bleeding disorders
gastrin and intestinal bleeding administration and so on and so forth so
if someone as the query like bleeding
right what would be the right answer well you know we believe there is no
right answer because the queries underspecified right someone you might think of you know one
of these right but might not be aware of the fact that it's you know
it's highly ambiguous so what you can do that in these cases you can you
can make the ambiguity explicit by saying well look in know their different results if
you mean
you know bleeding disorders then these are good results but if you're interested in administration
problems and so on and so forth and know this might be good for
so anyway you know you can
some people call you know a few things like this for result clustering writing search
and if you remember so he really result clustering but we're using
a concept structure that we identify
prior to the to the query it's not that you know we first computer resulted
in an cluster it but you know we we compute this prior to the query
there's been a
nice improvement on this model
which i just want to mention briefly here which
has been called the latent dirichlet allocation model by david blyth lyon rating and michael
this is fairly recent work
we're actually
this parameter
pi in the
in the probabilistic latent semantic analysis model which is the probability
of given the document of the particular concepts
right there was true there was a parameter in this model is treated here as
random variables in this latent dirichlet allocation model
and they put a dirichlet density
prior on top of this by variable so what is this good for well for
one thing is you know you have a nice bayesian
another layer of bayesian modeling so you can smooth things out a little bit you
know you get someone
a better estimate
so you know it's kind of the bias variance trade of course but usually it
pays off to
introduce some bias and reduce the variance of the estimate here and the other thing
is that if you do that way you actually get truly generative model where you
could also generate new documents because then you have the distribution of these things
right well before we just had those
number for every document but for a new document we wouldn't know
right but here we can actually sample new document by sampling the spy and then
something worth recording
you know the is basically the mixing proportions here
so the way you would generate documents is you generate a mix of topics
according to the dirichlet distribution
and then you would generate a certain number of words you know what
according to that the same appeal as a like a mixture model right we would
pick a topic according to distribution and then pick award according to the
to these probabilities here that we've seen before
and we can we can actually integrate out these
pi variables OK switch here and then
you know we
we get we can compute the marginal distribution over of particular particular
OK so and there are some issues here too you know i well first of
all is also geometric interpretation is also true for the kids and the way it
is you know you can think of these topics are concepts
it's kind of spending subspace
you know what you're doing is every document
is a convex combination of these topics right in this mixture and different documents are
different convex combinations but you only have a very small number of topics are concepts
compared to the number of dimensions in your space which is the number of terms
a right so what you then do is you you know you're topic
you can think of these as vectors that spanned some subspace
o actually a set of points and then the convex hull of these points is
everything you can represent right document will always be in the convex hull of those
so what you're asking for the in the way is you know in this very
high dimensional space you're looking for low dimensional
the simplex or you or convex region of this of this type of dimension humans
or or less so that you know you can you can find a good approximation
for each document within that within that context switching
so the geometry and in in terms of if you do this just allocation model
as opposed to the
simple kid is a model
it get a little more sophisticated you you have to
one way you could do it is you can
two variation OEM and other people have suggested other methods case it gets a little
more involved in this trade off between approximation and efficiency
but i want to talk about this you can look this up here and
in the paper
OK so
can someone tell me how much time is left
in this
ten minutes
all right then i am
just to you know the i wanted to talk about
but i could also skip
who's who is familiar with this hits argument by jon kleinberg
relatively few
OK well then i should
to do something different
they say you know what
since it's a hundred times more
you click through is a hundred times higher
i can actually take on the rest a child you're only somebody clicks because you
know one
i'm pretty sure some instantly and make more money by charging on click-through purchases charges
just show you
which is other than this
and being naive newcomer to the space i started asking some very simple questions
from a strategic perspective again from from the side
which is what's unique about search
but search for instance
of interactive applications
well thank you know to point
he words in the box you get six hundred thousand results look at the top
that's very very simple interactive applications such you can get a box and when he
imagine applications online
like for example
a travel integrators like yahoo travel expedia any of right
you're actually configuring online right so this thing knows all of your schedule when traveling
to fly preferences are what you tell preferences go for the cheaper to go the
expenses business pleasure
family in other travellers such
so if it's all about relevance
then think about that i just want a bunch of interactions with
in fact i can infer more knowledge about the context and your hand
i for more
then he said that a hundred keywords one after the other
that's the question of our you know this is what i said how much to
charge for me to the right of the travel confirmation page but when i know
everything about the
and the answer was well that's a premium so which are something like thirty to
forty dollars
see here meaning thirty four dollars four thousand views
if i did not participate that they could search just a
semantically more powerful search because i actually no intent way more
i should be charged
ten thousand dollars
four thousand years
three orders of magnitude bigger two or three or to begin on the money side
right the market has figured that out and part of what i want to show
you here is that you know we're getting there slowly
for example related to search
somebody search and this is an example of moving objects
what if i just did somebody search ignoring everything else politics and everything else and
what if i
for the next
our actually turned out to be forty eight hours what found by that search
by the way
brown had this is graphical
so there statistically more likely
to be out of the category of financial services in this case
what do i get
about two hundred percent the law twenty five percent two hundred percent lived
english words
which is not
surprise but remember this is not just a graphical applications one
i can search and i said OK if i see this person again which they
come back again and again with no within forty eight hours short
we get that look like
that created whole new products on the market actually direct marketers who would only spend
money on direct marketing suddenly started by
practical oriented
that's a big deal today we actually has
behavioral targeting and other things to it but so is just one of the words
in this case i'm just showing what happens if you search so an example of
how you can use the data
that are much more relevant to the consumer and of course the business
we after a lot of things have to anonymize the data after this category don't
actually keep he doesn't exactly where private citizens and so forth
looking very good example to convince you that it's very important
and is actually in all the examples but it's very positive
which is you know you know everything somebody does example of yahoo autos
and you know
somebody with four cars
for the last that's and looking for
if somebody looks at a car manufacturer website
if somebody goes on in order to him interested in kind
it turns out that this is together
we can actually find something like three hundred thousand consumers
well we know seventy percent confidence by ninety days
so you have some of month in the US is about
about thirty percent of the US car
i guess what we actually have ninety days
the chosen one
because you see them all the ninety days before the fight
right i
just a quick can show you some of the other members that show with sort
of public numbers
we need to test campaign
of saying that these people
four at outside the orders which is the only place where you will automobile manufacturers
like to spend money on you
so if you want to email what about this
and what we found was the target guy
based on what you know about which is an inference that the market for cars
that the conversion
as measured in this case by some actions they took on the advertiser side is
up by two three orders
that's a list nine hundred percent that's huge
that's not that's not trivial stuff
that shows you how much is an example of the power of behavioral targeting
because nothing predicts behavior like human
actually even how many different definitions of what is see subgaussian but basically the idea
is that in a certain way you have
you have to
every every probability distribution function you might see on the space of distributions into two
and it's just enough to have the have
PSI that belongs to the right half of the space
so maximum likelihood estimation is more is easier than you might think you don't really
need to have a good estimate the nation of this density
on this
the communist
OK this species
so what happened actually here because i mean the display here doesn't change at all
whatever i do what what actually happened here
it is shown pages
OK because of this screen i see on the same page so i thought disposal
OK let's just
if you just to run actor but again it doesn't matter if this doesn't show
OK well let's let's get it on the screen name
the reason for
this overview says very much but i just previously said
this most of these approaches can be as they can be also interpreted as maximizing
the number of independent component so well that's my viewpoint of somebody might say that
all of these approaches can be interpreted as maximisation likely
so what actually but there is one thing that we have to to choose which
is this not a nonquadratic function that we had in each of these methods so
looking kurtosis we had the fourth power
then in differential entropy we had always the logarithm of the
of the probability density function which we have so we were in the likelihood we
get on with the probability density function of the independent components and likelihood we get
a logarithmic of that
and that is always and there is always someone with nonquadratic function because the only
distribution that has a quadratic pdf for local pdf is the gaussian distribution
yes so
what we can use so we get it the fourth power of the law of
the density of then like in these approximations all entropy what i proposed is that
you could use something like that small approximation of the absolute value which is kind
of a seems to be working with universal approximation
and then another choice that we
i have to make is whether we want to estimate these components one by one
as i proposed in the in the first in the first place as as as
a simple at least at least you know intuitively simple method of estimating these things
always we estimate all the components at the same time well you actually expected to
estimate all the components at the same time although you know it's it's it's perhaps
easier to understand this method estimate to make them one by one and also it's
easier to pull things like consistency in the case where you have access to them
one by one
and then one thing that i didn't really talk about is whether we
do make this constraints where
the data is first whitened and then we use or not transformation which is the
same thing as as concerning the estimates to be white
it is and this is quite necessary especially in when you don't like maximum likelihood
estimation you can skip the constraints so in that case you have a slightly larger
space of
of all the parasite large parameter space where you search for parameters and probably in
most cases you all the optimal parameter values will not exactly like in this constraints
constraints because i mean only theoretically in theory for infinite sample sizes and assuming all
the making of the assumptions of the model we we know that constraint is exactly
true but in reality in practice it is only approximately two
but that doesn't mean that this this and usually make a big difference the estimation
next question is
how we actually maximize this objective functions
of course the first thing that you could try to do is to use some
kind of
some kind of a gradient methods
and that's what people usually do it is it is not very difficult to derive
in closed form the the the gradient of the likelihood of these measures some gaussian
for example this is
what if all the various reasons people often use this these adaptive or stochastic gradient
methods which means that
did not already talk about this
yes i will never die
i wanted to make sure
OK so
so this is is what the stochastic gradient of maximum of like the likelihood looks
like and it's relatively simple
but the problem is that we have here
the universe of w
which is basically the same thing as a but we also believe but in this
case we have to invert the running estimates of w at every step which is
of course competition not very nice now is a very funny tricks that you can
actually do to avoid this thing what you do is that
you just multiply
the log partition function is just to the data
and once again we don't have the natural parameters
because the ones in the natural parameters are not the ones
one of the ones we are familiar with
the natural parameter space occupies the entire real line
and the ones we are interested in i actually need to the natural parameter
so in this case the natural parameters longer here
let's do one more example
this one's a little trickier
because the we need more than one feature
this is the number gaussians with mean o and variance sigma squares
so this is the form of the gaussians
and now we want to write this is an exponential family
as an exponential family distribution
if you expand out the square
you end up with two both in x and x squared
so you need to pick you need to pick two features x has to be
a feature and x squared also has to be a feature
and if applicable to the things that you can write the exponent is a linear
so in this case of these set just are
of these measures
you know for convenience i to one of the two pi i could just make
it uniform constant still matter
and i need to pick two features not this is not sufficient to just one
features i pick x and x squared
and not just from this i can read of what the natural parameter is going
to be
and once again we can compute the log partition function
and in this case the natural parameter space
these are times
so so fine so there are a lot of these distributions that are clearly important
standard distributions and we found these can be coerced into the exponential family form
right but what is it by us to actually deal with this formalism
you know is it the case that
when we first look to the exponential family thing it looked like it was really
specific it's you know what kind of distributions could possibly have that form
now it seems like it might be too general
you know we effortlessly express the bernoulli only the warsaw the gaussians exponential family this
models right
it is so general that it's not useful for us in the world wide highway
what's so good about this exponential family what's special about exponential family distributions
and it turns out that a lot of the special properties of this distribution
lie where one initially were not expected to live namely in the log partition function
OK so the weight is log partition function came about is that it was just
the normalizer
it was just the thing you can attack on in front to make it all
add up to one
however it turns out
the this normalized actually contains a wealth of information about the distribution
OK and we're going to use its properties quite heavily
when we when we get back to maximum entropy
is the first in first of all it turns out that this thing is strictly
so for instance
the force on
in the fossil case it was e to the data
the exponent which is
it was like this is a strictly convex function
among other things it means that is derivative is one to one if you have
a strictly convex function and its derivative with the derivative is increasing its one to
to one to one
the derivative actually has all the properties
the derivative turns out to simply be the mean of the distribution
so if you take the derivative of the log partition function
the log partition function just compute first derivative and and that turns out to be
the mean of the distribution
the expected value on the random draws from the distribution of of the feature vector
OK so so why is this the case well let's in general the feature vector
has many components it it to one o to two and so on
let's take the derivative with respect to the i th component
you take the derivative of this with respect to data with respect to it i
well the derivative log x is just one over XTX so it's so one over
this thing
that the derivative of the top which is this
and i can see that this is just the probability
so it's just me
of that particular feature
again this and if you do the similar things for the very all for the
second derivative
you get the variance of the distribution
OK so just by taking the first derivative second derivative of the log partition function
so we end up getting the moments of the distribution
so there's a wealth of information
contained in this log partition function
so so what else wall
in one of the ways the exponential family me
what is
what is special about why we singled out these distributions
as being important once you know well what else is unique about them
so the real the real benefit comes when you start looking at maximum likelihood estimation
suppose dealing with some exponential family OK and as we've seen to specify an exponential
family just specify the base measure and the features are going to look at the
support for dealing with some exponential family and now we see a bunch of data
and we want to find the best member of the family because of privacy budget
points and we wanted go out into the
so let's find the maximum likelihood choice of the parameter
OK so you just plug into this we want to maximize the log likelihood
so take the logo of this it's it density x i minus two events
last longer side
you're invited because you can pull the it out
can get some of these two guys
and these this is just a constant
and they get the sum of the log book size
and to maximize this is the derivative and you take the derivative is that it
is zero
and many of them
so there a move away from things
context today's
this was part of literature on and structural pattern recognition probably maybe problems you have
not thought of before
that really needs
addressing one cor
on the core problem is correspondence
correspondences above
in in learning and inference
and what's happened in the last decade also is that been free approaches free new
approaches to solving the problem of correspondence that they are interesting
and at some way optimal
this is what is optimal
and i'm going to talk about the three men
the spectral methods
the least squares methods in the bayesian network methods
so you got the there's some
some sense of smell hearing is in this formulation
china japan and i've been working on a on bayesian networks methods internet
it was kelly is a work on spectral methods so
i'll get my aim today is to give some flavour of these of these methods
i don't have to get to the bayesian stuff all the
but will see how we can
so spectral methods right
the core problem again just now
of all my
this talk is how do i correspond end points two points
well points
our vertices of the graph
so it's classical
subgraph matching
in spectral methods
and the least squares method
the most common
why need to encode a relational structure
is in terms
although matrix
for a graph with n vertices
their attributes for a vertex and
attributes for a change
well matrix
well this example
well got
all way i through
and i was injective
you might be covered
in my opinion the human values i hold to the
the next one might be the
the next year
because community values properties of vertex
i might be the saturation value will not be the
and so on
submatrices down to build the binary values like the distances between the vertices in the
angles of something like this
so in thing
this may be true
in the
but in
the matrix
and this
while encouraging
and attributed
as the matrix
with guy and one correspondence the from a submatrices submatrix corresponding to diagnose playing some
matrix for each
attribute of the vertex
and they are diagonal matrices being able to the attributes for each to the edges
now to
what's being done in the literature
this has been
this really not being considered
and i talked about today about about the degenerate case the matrix is simply
the adjacency matrix which is a very general form
do not on the density matrix would be this is the most simple form would
so this is not a property of tablet PC and all of this or powerpoint
is a function of my laptop which is
become very unstable
in the last twenty four hours
i'm not saying it's not follow the software just saying that it doesn't usually do
try one more time
he said you get lots of practice of this
i wasn't quite what i had in mind
so imagine that we
he has given x
supposing we want distribution to have the property
the the
the distribution is that given x and y
let's say doesn't depend on y
as an example of the conditional independence property and will be looking at those in
detail later what effectively we're going to do that is to cross at that link
we write down the distribution of z given its parents it will only have the
parent x and so why
i will
not appear in that conditioning statements
so that's essentially the idea
so think
this is
the point i think it seems to me is the pen
well i have to resort to have project john shawe taylor probably
happy buying something
the joint distribution that is the product of all these conditionals
i'm going to do this and to do this
is john here
can a hundred and twenty people be sworn to secrecy
as everybody got a copy of the and that the body
so in right and the joint distribution
x one x seven
so this particular examples would you go through this example sort of laboriously you get
the point
so this is a joint distribution for the project was a joint distribution over seven
variables so there's one node for each of the variables and
there is there are a bunch of links but you'll see there are lots of
missing links in this graph not every pair of nodes has the link between them
and those missing links in code for certain properties of the joint distribution
so in this but for that particular graph i simply write down the i go
through each variable in turn halifax
it doesn't matter what i take them in
which is the distribution of the
variable conditional on its parents well it's one doesn't have any parents are just one
and x two
it doesn't have any parents x three doesn't have any parents
x four
as parents x one x two x three
x five getting point by now you smart people
x one and x three
six is conditioned on all
and then take seven
so when we look into their look like thing x four x five
OK so that's a particular example
so i think this point then you should be clear about the definition of the
joint distribution for for directed graphs so directed graph
this expression
for the factorisation of the joint probability distribution
and so the factorisation in terms of factors which are conditional
conditional probabilities and there are lots and lots of models that you
maybe we should have heard of
which can be expressed as directed graphs i just put a list up here to
show you that there actually quite widespread
and we'll see some examples of these in detail as we go through the through
the tutorial
so that's directed graphs going to show you know the other
very popular class of graphical model the undirected graph but i should say that
these two
classes of graph and not the only possibility the other
families of graph search chain graphs in factor graphs and you could invent others the
point is that
the family of graphs of has to represent a consistent mathematical framework and it's very
really telling me
was that the world is flat
and i wrote that down in my notebook
the world is
i go back to my hotel i ran to my room i called my wife
and the first i said honey
i'm going to write a book called the world is flat
she now says she thought that was a brilliant idea
that's not how i remember the conversation but the men are from mars women are
from venus but i that i don't come home and basically call my owners of
the new york times and say please i need to go on sabbatical immediately
i need to go on sabbatical because my software the intellectual framework to which i
look at the world
is out of date
i'm i'm a basic engineer and it's the job world
and if i don't go going leave immediately and update my software
i'm going to write something really stupid
in the new york times
to great way to get leave i have to say
so i started this book in march of two thousand four i turned in in
december do not try this trick on kids i blew my forearms along the way
but in the field of energy and passion produced kind of the core thesis of
this book
and the course is to sort of the meta argument of this book is very
simple the meta arguments that there have been three what call three great era of
globalisation the first cycle globalization one point o began fourteen ninety two and lasted until
the early eighteen hundreds with the beginning of global arbitrage that globalization shrunk the world
from size larger size medium
and then you globalization was really spearheaded by countries globalizing there is you went global
through your country nation-states were the dynamic agent of globalization so was spain exploring america's
britain colonizing india portugal east asia you went global
through your country
globalization two point o began in the early eighteen hundreds last till the year two
thousand three just and
it's around the world from size medium to size small in that year globalization was
really spearheaded by companies companies going global for markets and for labour
UN global through your company
while you were sleeping or this while i was sleeping
we actually entered globalization three point from the year two thousand to the present the
trick in the world from size small size
i mean
and flattening the global economic playing field at the same time on there was really
new really different really exciting
and really terrified
is it this year globalization
it's certainly not spearheaded by countries and it's not exclusively headed by companies anymore
it's really new really different really exciting
is it this area of globalization
is spearheaded by
we've gone from globalization built around countries to one built around companies
to one built around
how did we get here
how did we move
down this progression
two point where individuals
can compete connect and collaborate
as individuals
we had to create a platform really for that to happen and i talk about
the whole platform article the ten flatters me talk about four forty one is basically
the relevant both open course ware anything to where we are today
basically the first of these forty flatters was
i'm to do this really quickly the PC what the personal computer allowed in this
is really the beginning of the whole individual nature of globalization the PC allowed was
for individuals
individuals to offer their own content in digital form
it's great to be able to talk about this at MIT right not explain what
those things mean
what PC allowed was for the first time in the history of the world
four individuals to offer their own content in digital form now
individuals have offered their own content ever since k women caveman etched on cave walls
with the PC
individuals can offer their own content words photo data spreadsheets video music
in the form of bits and bytes in digital form and once you're content
it was created in digital form it could be manipulated in so many more ways
by individuals
and dispatch so many more places
it was the first basic basically second flatten or some of these technologies others are
dates second flight nurse today eight nine ninety five august nine nineteen ninety five which
i consider to be
for the whole game to work we need encoding system to add
this is an informal thing i'm saying here
to the transmission
that redundancy which the decoder will know about it will know the system that's being
used to add redundancy that redundancy has been to help the decoder to infer
but the source signal
it is critical
that's the plan
it's going to exploit the non redundancy adding system to do that inference and i
say inferred in the sense of well we may want to use bayes theorem when
the time comes to the some decoding
so let's have an example
to discuss this small
how encoders and decoders work give ourselves an example channel
you need more light on this board
so the models and we're going to discuss
for the rest of today
so this is just the model one information theory covers lots of lots channels this
is the favourite model
simple channel is called the binary symmetric channel
and it looks like this is going input and it's own output
and every time cycle every quadratic you get put one in
and immediately and output comes out of it and the input you can put in
is a binary variable is either zero or one
and the output comes out will be zero or one and you hoping to zero
zero one to one but sometimes you're unlucky and you get what we call the
the bit split
the input of course say
the output y
and probability one minus from these two arose and probably on this arrow property
on the side of this little diagram here
shorthand for a set of false statements of the form the probability that y equals
one given that it's zero is
that's the meaning of this arrow with anathema this isn't the graphical
this would be a graph model
this is a diagram showing you the probabilities
all right
OK so this for such statements and the one i've written down is one for
this error
you can think of this as the model for this drive let's imagine
that with your certificate of
engineering competence in your pocket you decide let's go and make a start up company
selling this rising got a wonderful new nano
super-low temperature way of making this rise and we went prototype and it is
and the problem is it flips ten percent of bits that you store on the
here's a question for you
imagine that this model is an accurate model
new describe you've you've made you've got this described unfortunately flextime to bits and imagine
that you sell it anyway you know yes yes snake-oil salespeople to help you with
the pitch to the VC's and so forth stop producing these
and you say i want to you first customer and the first customer tries to
ten thousand bit file
on this day strife and then read it off again how many bits will be
flipped is the the first question
so if you store
ten thousand bits
i read off again roughly how many bits are going to be for i want
to rob and so complete with a robust police habitat your neighbor
OK roughly how many bits
philip chan yuan
a thousand plus and minus
one thousand plus minus thirty any other uncertain apart from one thousand plus minus thirty
plus and minus sixty
why saying sixty
two standard deviations why saying thirty
but this just conventions right ground
excellent so you all know the binomial distribution and one of the really wonderful things
about information theory is you only need to know the binomial distribution to do pretty
much the whole topic
question one a with your user be happy with that number of bits being flipped
never i imagine not OK
well how
many bits might they be happy with in a typical file
zero OK so
now let's imagine that by making either a new physical channel all by adding encoding
and decoding systems we managed to create a new channel that is a binary symmetric
channel with a much lower for probability how small the need to be if we're
going to get what he wants which is zero errors so his question to to
make successful business selling one about describes how small
if you actually want to flip probability
to be about punishment channel habitat your neighbour
you're not chatting to each other you done
you have an answer what that
what's that
we like there i want to another and so not zero talk to each other
to each other
OK let's get some answers
if you want to go
not long
part of
you can
you know
the old people
one two three
during the
you might
and is well
and you
you might
in my
you know
OK so
what i want to do now
is show you
the reverse to summarise what was sounds summarises whenever you have a derivation
then phi gamma had i do and i said well if if you tell me
the derivation will look at its shape if
a one step derivations so its size in gamma
then we know its ideological and if it's an instance of an axiom one step
the relation with this is an instance of an axiom then again a consequence of
gamma because the axiom schemes are such that they all all instances of them are
valid points of the empty set
and then the only tricky bit will modus ponens necessitation induction hypothesis so
it is shoulder-to-shoulder derivation shown
change the turnstile to the other turnstile
and now we have to do is this is the property of logical consequence
but we have to prove and if you look through your notes you'll see that
somewhere if this
and if this
in this
they should be able to check this in your
what about consciousness
i want to show complete winamp
five is a logical consequence of gamma
then there's the deduction
OK says that calculus is complete all of the things that should be deduced
so we do the standard lindenbaum construction using maximal consistent sets it up that i've
got might differ from the one that john's lane used in these lectures but
the flavour is
what's the lemma
you give me enough consistent set gamma
the main consistent means i can't deduce phi and not five from
i am not five from for any five that's consistency me every consistent set gamma
is icts instances
greater than
joe kidd
and how
so i'm going to do it not directly
so the direct way would be to say if i is a logical consequence of
and now show that there is a reduction of five and if i tell you
that five a logical consequence of gamma what do i tell you
i give you anything to work with all i tell you is that whenever you
have any model like which makes demetri everywhere
but if i say OK choose the model model
where do i start a moral might have fifteen states the two states
OK so i have nothing concrete to work with whereas in the other direction in
the derivation had structure a tree structure i could do induction on the tree structure
it is we use classical meta reasoning and we do the contrapositive so what we
say is if you want to show whenever this holds in this whole
to improve the contrapositive
that with
this doesn't hold that's what i'm saying up on the slide
so if there is no did
then they then phi cannot be a logical consequence of gamma that's it i'm going
to show you how you do it and assume it's an if statement that you
something then something and could canonical model construction
OK i'm going to assume that gamma
and now i'm going to construct a model
called the canonical correlates
is the set of worlds
reachability relation are added value you
is not forced by that model was
i'm going to assume that there is no need to show that is the model
such that
it is not pause
which means there is some world in that model which makes five vols
he's going to make all of the things in gamma true it's the other condition
i mean that it is that
there is some model which makes all the things in diameter subway
that's what this lecture
eight to do is only just switch to a local consequence relation is the important
that define
the turnstile within l
right not distance different ones
which is defined in terms of the bigger one just says
all right let's locally deducible from x
if there is a finite subset size
such that
the conjunction implies phi is the
so this deduction
what we've got over
but i'm just going to use this is shorthand flight right
so everywhere you see this means is a finite subset of silence junction of the
size implies fast
now as think that if this whole in other words if their home
doctor using the traditional media
and you'll actually be able to do that by the
given here
city is maximal if what
try OK
infinite set of formulae
and this city is maximal if you like and either that formula will be in
their or or its negation or so x is already in
what's the idea of max melody words that you can't squeeze anything in a linear
formula phi
and identifies in there or not five
you can't you can't add anything more
without making an inconsistent
and what
consistency means that sign not so i are likely to do so
the system means you have both
in other words i can't deduce sign outside from
then i kx systems nick starr
which is a superset of gamma
how do i do it action of formulae phi one of the fine
just number them anyway you like so
and do that can
so you start off with gamma not
and you see whether
as X transpose move the parentheses
right it X transpose A transpose Y and move the parentheses
so that I'm looking at a transposed was then a transpose what what that have
to kind of what yesterday
the key steps so simple or matrices corresponds the integration by parts
continuum problems that we've met for a while OK and now why is this so
that's OK right actually was at an even equal now that was right there OK
0 that was even an equal sign
was that was even equals 0 because they X was exactly the OK now emerging
from the step that this is less or equal this now why is that
because A transpose Y
if you don't mind what order this inner product comes in those images to vectors
of I'm happy to write X transpose see if you if you would like to
let me right up there is x transforms which is the same as C transpose
X just
just the dot product doesn't matter OK here is the key step then obviously and
why is that true
well 1st of all a transpose why that we have to it's beautiful all the
requirements community A transpose Y is less or equal to see
so does that make this true
right away if A transpose Y is less Rakosi not right away I need to
know that I multiplying these this inequality transforms wireless frequency by positive numbers
but if you might take inequality multiplied by negative number it reverses
but that's exactly where this comes
and in a way
get more than in a way here we can see
that is an
so that so that any feasible 1 match was less frequently than any feasible while
I gave us the transfers why that was smaller than or equal to C transpose
X now a point is that
so that's the easy steps and the right that is at and there was a
corresponding to the easy step when we were doing
minimizing potential energy there was something called the complementary energy that involves the
the flows
the of the year
for the
stresses whatever with dual variable was and we could have found a weak duality and
then ultimately
so so I'm from like at you'll see that often tell to prove is that
in 1 direction it's it's easy that's the direction we talk and but now
together equality is not so
but actually when with equality holds so now this is actually not only gives us
of the easy argument but also gives us a conditions for optimality when
when the simple
went well ways since we have all equal sign I only have to ask right
there when does well it's 1 they're equal 1 very polite
as X transpose
so but when will equality holds X transpose
not just gonna put them on the same side of the equation times C minus
A transpose nu what has to be worked well right it always greater or equal
0 from feasibility but to get equality so this is to get to him to
to get equality equal sign
to be optimal so that was an important word in there
optimality that meant
what's the condition like
derivative equals 0
this in this world will well it's it's this it's just that this has to
be equal to 0 right
I just coming out of just looking at the only place there was any questions
and saying everyone equality
then we gotta have equality at that step so there's less or equal followed immediately
for any x and y
equality is only going to happen at the best ones so maybe I should put
the stars X . transpose C minus A transpose nu y star that's how we
the winner
and and you see what's going on here this is the dot product of 2
and what's the deal with those vectors what we know about those vectors
well there orthogonal but then each of those vectors
it is
non-negative the X is non-negative and C minus A transpose Y is non-negative so all
well and good to
non-negative vectors
the biorthogonal
helium too stable and looking at bonding versus antibody titre let's ask if we take
Avogadro's number
of wave functions and blend them in something like copper can we make sense of
what's going on so this is what their contribution was it was linear combination of
atomic orbitals inter molecular orbitals for for large
ensembles of larger and
and so here's what his that goes let's take a look at
occurred to you recall last day we looked at something like the 1 to ask
whether any blends with another way to make a 2 we can start at at
some level I just look at the valence shell OK so look at the valence
orbitals this is atomic orbitals and when to come close together we used to have
become close enough that the operating as 1 system in order not to violate the
Pauli exclusion principle these energies have to just a little bit otherwise we run the
risk of having more than 1 electron with the same set of quantum numbers so
these will rearrange themselves into what we call anti bonding and bonding orbitals were anti
bonding or slightly higher energy than the parents
atomic orbital and blinding are and slightly lower in energy than the parents were so
this is a tuna suppose to I do this 1 more time suppose I take
a + 82 and I wanna make a 3 what would happen if I took
a + 82 will again not to violate the Pauli exclusion principle this initial whatever
this orbital is let's call it an acid only 3 as whatever it's I have
to allow for
that number of states
I think you can see by analogy this is what the hyper and that they
kept going until they got a
n where N is large how large all about the size of
you thumb
on the order of the cubic centimeters in other words a block of matter
a block of metal so there is a large what happens this thing keeps going
there's a little bit of a broadening flat
this is what happens we have many many levels here starting at the highest anti
bonding down to the lowest bonding but now
the space so the energy difference between successive levels is getting vanishingly small
and in fact you can think about it would what's how many how many of
atoms would there be a cubic centimeter of copper
what's think about the forget cubic centimeters I can look on the periodic table if
you look the periodic table the molar volume they call atomic volume the volume molar
volume of copper is 7 . 1 1 cubic centimeters so there's Avogadro's number in
the right who's buried in grants to grant how many atoms in a molar volume
of 1 mole so this contains this contains and have gabbro Adams
so divided so that ever get around can divide through a pretty soon you figure
out how many states there are variety if of either 1 cubic centimetre it's roughly
10 to the 23
patterns of
centimeter cube
so that means I'm going to have 10 to the 23 states here
and what's this energy difference is on the order of some tens of electron volts
so suppose I put in here I'll even give you a thousand electron volts cause
I got I got a lot of protons in the nucleus suppose this is on
the order of 10 to the 3rd but it's divided by 10 to the 23rd
contributors so what's the delta in here it's about 10 to the minus 20 electron
volts which is about 10 to the minus 40
this is less energy in the universe movement of the eyeball mosquito there's nothing here
there's nothing
so from a distance you I get really close this is still out of principle
the electrons come to you just as Noah's are from the bottom up to the
top these are all distinct quantum states but from a distance there so close together
that this appears to be a plan continued almost continuum of
so that the band is a set of very closely spaced orbitals
now you see how to populate and for something like copper we know coppers got
its coffers are 3 D 10 4 1 sole coppers 2 by 2 coming in
and fill up to the halfway point of the bank
because I can put 2 per orbital but only have 1 for copper so if
I blow this up what do I have about this bandits half-filled and it's half
filled and then the next level is a vanishingly small energy difference and so forth
then I apply potential extending side of the crystal negative sentiment the side of the
crystal positive it takes a tiny bit of energy to pull in electron out of
the topmost orbital put up here and now it's free to move about
so this accounts for the high degree of metallic nature
of materials because the energy levels were so close together in the past we suffered
a classical gas-phase atoms it took a substantial amount of energy to move something out
of its ground state in this case the move ground state takes a trivial amount
of energy and the gets curtains and indicate this goes back to drew with his
cannot be some books will actually call the
atomic or scatter but there'd there'd be a sloppy with the terminology because it's the
it's the ionic or consisting of
protons in the nucleus plus the inner shell electrons but in electrical engineering to refer
to this as can the city of valence electrons so here's a cartoon showing what's
happening as you progressively and larger and larger numbers and not to violate the poly
now all this
looks like usual but actually it was known
in a sense
by people that we're just trying to write down supersymmetric gravity feeds people had realize
that or at about the same time in parallel that there are two speciality supersymmetric
gravity theories which are maximally in the sense that they we have as much approximately
as you can have
in two dimensions which are known as type two and type to be supergravity
and all these is simply one one-horse supersymmetric company of graviton that's also in a
sense it looks complicated but it simply gave it to super symmetrized in ten dimensions
there is no freedom here everything is very rigid because supersymmetry fixes everything and it
also completely fixes the effective
and interaction so this theories is very unique and it takes
a lot of work which has been found
to show that the notion of private string theories are consistent theory surely does give
exactly in the effective low energy limit this two supergravity theories called type three or
type to b
now here comes the last take control i want to discuss which are usually brains
and which in a sense has full revolutionized this subject in the mid nineties
well i talked before about
closed training giving super gravitons described by supergravity theories which are still far from what
we want in nature but of course remember the big thing about them is that
they are finite consistent can try to use them as quantum theories and then try
to see how to recover the standard model later on
as the tomorrow but
how about the open strings
now i remember from this far the open strings have two types of boundary conditions
at the end months or the slayer
no correspond to free
moving open strings deviously correspond to stock strings we can have some of the some
moments and initially why not after all and what do they describe what they describe
open strings push toward poets of stock or fixed
surfaces in space time so here is it
brain that's how they are called the dirichlet brain think of it as some surface
in space time
the trajectory may be of some extended objects and effect of time which is very
indirectly described not by an equations yet by simply but by simply saying that open
strings can have their endpoints talk of course this thing is free event to go
inside the bottle be theory by the end points out there are therefore open strings
are intimately tied with these dish usually brains now
is the spatial extent of this object it could be a particle in which case
one talks about the desire of brain particles this would then have been simply straight
line going up in time
time goes up here
so open strings with this fact to live in the same space boring and then
moving time of course
but then it would be one of these would be a so-called this string
he could be too
three and so on it can be anything up to nine
we'll just have nine space dimensions you
so the picture is that you have this open string stock there have closed things
that can move everywhere
and of course you cannot be copied the they can interact because one of these
close things can go at an open string and make it longer for instance
no polchinski realized in ninety five that the correct way to think about this the
brain so that was the big surprise is simply as new kinds of excitation surely
tonic like excitations of string theory
i would have a mass density tension of their own more than one charged a
couple of these bizarre moment fields as elementary charges
and they really are very much analogous to magnetic monopole some grand unified theories
now let's think a little bit about the simplest non solid this is the so-called
team actually
because then you'll see every everything goes through
now the kink is simply domain wall in some theory that has to degenerate vacua
shoots this separation between viking one and viking two that can happen in real space
now let's take a very simple example just to be precise here is a scalar
theory it has to scalar fields fire high it has the potential which is the
and you can see that actually the same
just taking the first half of information gain in the formula
it's just taking the
one occurrence
into account not something we then were not occurring
which is crucial for the performance here
it's also intuitive in the way fitting in
there are many words that are not in your testing document and if you base
your model on saying this word is not in the document and this is not
and this is not of course there are not many other or not
and if your mother mainly concentrates on saying which words should not be the document
it's not going to perform very well
at least not if you have a problem where
most of the
documents negative
the mutual information for text
also seen you're just
if you look with a bit more into what's happening in here the difference is
but here
in addition to class probability
which is here there is joint class probability class and words
which is multiplied here in front of the fact
and it performs
similar to cross entropy a little bit worse but
i can't really tell you that no consistent
alterations to measure i mentioned that makes difference between the class values
so if you forget about this
the last factor which kind of just to help the calculation
what it does it selects features or words
they according positive
and not in negative documents in
abstracting away
so features that are characteristic for positive documents
and hopefully not from negative
and that performs
very well
and the frequency just taking frequency of the word
and taking no
the most frequent words but don't forget what people usually do first remove stopwords
so you don't really take
you know the most really most frequent words like that at and so on you
remove them and then take the most frequent words
and there is this being normal separation
which also has
this idea of taking was characteristic for positive but and measuring how the differences between
characteristic for positive and four negative documents
this one was shown to
the performance of the night
so all these different feature scoring measures influence the performance in some way
but also depends on the machine learning algorithm that is used i already mentioned that
for SVM
they don't really help much most of them
and it's possible because SVM has already embedded this weighting of features
so in some way
has some feature selection embedded in the system so
it does not perfect so much of some pre processing of the data
while naive bayes actually
really can use feature subset selection to improve the performance
but at the end of the day
the overall performance of naive bayes and document categorisation at least the experiments show you
is towards the SVM
you would rather use a linear SVM and be happy
so i some slides to show you
of running different feature scoring measures on data
the first couple of slides naive bayes classifier
on yahoo data
hierarchy of the pages
and then
the other experiments of ideas two thousand news dataset
using a linear SVM
also in a space and perceptron
is there any questions so far
we went through all the number two is just and just going to show some
experiment results
i can't
this work
so he found that works but i can't really in this paper he doesn't compare
with the other one so i can't tell you if he really tried and this
will work better or not
but that's interesting
however during the time
so just to give you
the idea of the data not going to be the just
if you know what the next slide going to talk about
so these are five datasets
extracted subsets from the yahoo hierarchy tree
the whole problem behind this karaoke and cold but we won't talk about that here
so this is the number of documents in each of the datasets so you can
see we go from two thousand up to eighty thousand documents
this is the number of features going from thousand
two about thirty thousand
and the number of classes or categories going from about one hundred to eight hundred
so you can see we have a range
of difficulty of data
and maybe just mention as features
in addition to using single words
some pairs and three posts up to
of words i used sequences of words that are occurring frequently nothing to data
so in this way in statistical they get phrases like
i don't know text mining or
dimensionality reduction also
so what is the performance
so we go from about one hundred
to about eight thousand different categories
some decide what they want us to show is how the
a growing number of features
selected in the feature subset
in places the performance
and the idea of this light is only to give you
show experimentally
the different scoring measures
we so there formulas
really behave differently
depending on the number of features you use of course at the end
when you use all the features they all have the same performance
but at the start
and the
o point be interested in
out to map with the same and i am quality differently strength
it just
they excel why
and the right
the product of the individual probabilities by the product of the joint probability
if it is about one they are independent
if it is high
they are very correlated if it is
low they are negatively correlated
but during the orientation because it is the definition of this is the same is
usually takes with the y
the result is the same so we don't have the orientation
i am not going to enter into the many alternative so we only mention one
later on
so how is the process
this the decision making process as follows
you the set with a number of sections show each of which is a set
of items
and surprise for for support for features
and you know it
back all the rules that hold in this dataset and dust levels are high
and usually what you eat
is that the show what is your guess you're investing your i about one hundred
fifty thousand three hundred ninety seven to one in the image show them order to
you don't want the system to show you
one hundred fifty thousand rich
how do we identify the london who have although we take off and was
there are many not just for the next year and this is my favourite because
they are
about four or five different ways of expressing than she
each of them says he will but not exactly
like the other and they are now to be equivalent
which is not
so i am not convinced that by the end of this is that with one
that means that the confidence will be high in every
now a as i mentioned it in passing before
the notion of course itemsets is behind the scenes and you have to take it
into account but let me not get into the taste of what it means to
share the same single space with
action and this conditional selling groceries
and this invariant is particularly with because it
create separately implications with the minimum size bases they can basis and the but implications
with or one minimum size
how does it work
movie is not that much into the basement essentially you take place where the confidence
is high enough but if you are doing
it with the consequent or smaller to see it it doesn't work and confidence falls
below the a
and then there are choices so where he invented the social question but in other
cases it's not necessary because there are necessary to finance this into the they share
they do that they call the confidence that all the rules that hold with confidence
can be inferred from them
and that any alternative set of rules having the same two properties is at least
as large or or or
and here is that after the growing
the size of the basis
for one specific data set of all sets which really
this means
that you that lower confidence
this is the number of rules
in each of the two bases iterations the representative assembly have these
and now somebody may say i don't understand
you know that
at ninety five percent more
and that ninety nine percent of course
but then how come
due to the lower
in your love for me
and with less many
lower confidence means that we let pass more things
how can it happened
you get less
and the reason is
that we are taking out redundant users
well there wasn't that much more than that here
as we got official a bit lower will happen it will it pass a very
powerful ruler
that wasn't there may be have computers
ninety or eighty five
at ninety five
percent confidence it was not
eighty five it gets seen
and this very simple very strong misalignment many many many many others
he takes them off
there it is
and this is why sometimes use these two sites
you're confused
number further growth but sometimes you just computers number of course tricks
because one of four hours
have been
and if this has to be this notion
now were proposing a few years so i
confidence we
so essentially
the government there are many others that that individual here not here or
rule of confidence a ninety five percent was out of the basis and the basis
this point
and will at some point here maybe asking kind of by a stronger
this we think of the entire that's interesting
if you if have a rule that has a very sharp with
of confidence is where there is no basis means that well it has a high
confidence that some other
but not much
whereas if it stays in the race for a long time
it means that it has it is much much more confidence
then there all those who was alternative rules that would have the same effect
so this is a region of novelty
first we discover the missing that is going on
this covers entailed by the basis kids and they
the result of left not intended by others that means that it has a higher
confidence that what do others suggest
the question is
how much
higher confidence
so we take the a bayesian based confidence of which there and compare it with
some confidence
and this may be one or much more than one or a lot more than
so if
this in turn this is low this internally short this means that at some level
is very close by
and so on
whereas if this
watching these high missing that only flourish
or use that make the kind of london
i have confidence much much slower it's confidence much higher than would be expected from
the other
this is somehow price combined with the other
it's not exactly the
quantity that works well
he said about the website
what what
you've all from there and more sophisticated and more sophisticated than the bush but in
practice but has war's former properties
i'm not particularly happy with either one of them is the one i i would