local supervised learning in other words learn
each level
for initializing each level using an unsupervised learning algorithm that takes as input and transforms
it into a new
o space
tries to factor
because of of of the rhine
you can think of what each level is doing his job isation of PCA ICA
but with PCR ICA
when we try to stack these things at multiple levels we don't gain anything here
you can use something like an RBM
restricted boltzmann machine which are going to explain which is going to extract a bunch
of numbers
from my input
in these numbers turn out to be useful at explaining the variations in the input
so once you've trained model of the input distribution
what you get is a side product is a new representation for your input just
like you would get PCA
and what you can do is take this new representation
input data for training the second level
so now you transform the
this new representation h one into reservation h two
you can do that for many levels
it turns out that stacking all these one w of the other actually makes sense
from a mathematical point of view
and the next thing you need to be doing typically is taking all these levels
of representation and
using them as initialisation for a supervised task you care about
you could ask well why would we just trying that
model supervised learning from scratch
well it turns out that doing this treaty
layer wise unsupervised pre training
makes a big difference somehow but the parameters place
before you do gradient based optimisation of the criterion you care
there's a difficult optimisation problem somehow
and by doing this supervised initialisation level by level
somehow our able
to get better results
so the job goes like this we train the kind of unsupervised feature extraction like
the RBM auto encoders i'll talk about
that maps inputs to some representation
that hopefully captures try to capture the activation in the input
you get a new representation
then you trying second level exactly
as before
using this representation as input and you do that
so the number of times
let's say you want to do
you want to predict some y given x y you can take the
the last level observations input to some classifier
and train the classifier
what you could do
that seems to help in most cases actually is once you've
put this classifier on top which might be an SVM logistic regression or something
you can fine-tune all the parameters not just of the logistic regression but also all
these representations
with respect to the supervised objective
and that
give the best results that see in the experiments
so not all of them now
was i didn't say what the feature extractor should be
and i'm going to explain that the but
interestingly you can replace
are the abuse with many other things and get good results
maybe not always as good as IBM's but still
there's something more general going on
what is an RBM
IBM research was machine is a probabilistic
which is essentially a markov random field
some of the
random variables related in some are observed
so the joint distribution of the observed x in late h
it is just a normalized exponential
where in the exponential we have the quadratic polynomial with a particular structure
such that there are no terms for the interactions between
and no term for the interactions between observed variables but only terms for the interactions
between the hidden and and verbal and observe
it turns out that this particular structure
makes four
inference and training
although as i said a lot of variations have been proposed
that's that's that's the european model we can train and by like you we can
compute the exact gradient but we can approximate it
the approximation is is based on gibbs sampling
in in those models so
i won't have time to go through the details of this but the gradient of
the log like likelihood gradient
it involves
a term that
simple and says we want to be
polynomial here to be
large for the observed
x and we wanted to be small for all possible or other possible axes
and in proportion to how the model gives in probability and to get
the gradient respect all possible axes is kind of difficult because we would like to
some of all possible configurations of input
so we use sampling techniques to get these negative examples
and because of the particular structure of the model
gibbs sampling
is very convenient in these models very easy to do you can sample the hidden
variables given the inputs
and then you can sample the inputs given the hidden variables
and those each of those steps is easy because those conditional distributions
meaning that given city input each of the hidden variables are
so number of algorithms have been proposed to train these are RBN's
the first one and still the most commonly used is called contrastive divergence
and the idea is that we're going to start
a chain
to obtain these negative examples
he's one negative example
but instead of running the chain to convergence which would give you
and by artists
estimating of the gradient we just a few steps in fact once that looks very
fast training is very fast with these things
now even though it's unbiased estimate of the gradient
in practice it has been found to work very well
and one reason why it works well that we found is that
the gradient estimate we get
divergence even though it is not the right
but but use like
it's actually sexually mature
and so the cues we find beautiful are cues to that large eyes
full lips
smooth tight skin
signal something else
the reason marker for health
and so what we find beautiful
things like the absence of deformities clear ice
unblemished skin intact e
very big
and an average face
that last part might seem a little bit strange
what would be so good about an average face
and there's different answers to that one answer is
on average based on
it should be considered attractive
because any sort of deformities are variations from the average
and if you average every face together
you get face that were nothing bad has happened to it
there's no distortions there's no deviations as one gets older face gets less symmetrical
and so on
aborigines seems to factor out all the bad things that can happen
good theory how do we know it's true
there's a photo raster
that comment that i have access to for this class so i can look at
each of your pictures
i will make you bet about who has the most beautiful face
in this course
that is it would be
all of you
well to be funded by showed somebody may
if i did and you know a
i don't have the energy to do this and b
it would probably violate four hundred different privacy laws or whatever but if i took
all those places and more them together
i would get a very pretty face
and how do we know this is what people done this event were sold interfaces
here to here
and if you're like most people
you see as you're going to the right
looking better and better and better
but it's actually not so subtle
that babies don't notice
the same researchers are constructed this these spaces average caucasian faces
male and female
i have shown in faces the babies and find babies prefer to look at average
suggest that our preference for averaging is not the product of culture rather is to
some extent hardwired
these people don't exist
the computer composites
a heavily average
male face
and the heavily average female figures both from application data sample
they don't right
the faces they don't seem to care for instance is is identical so don't you
can use here
but pretty attractive
but the story of attractiveness does not end there
how do you get a better than average face what can you do spaces and
traces and make them work
even better
well the vote
was pretty
who says the one on the right
this is the one on the left
left is average face
and there may be variation in this cluster definitely variations what you will be able
to this is a feminized version
of the average face where certain prototype features were made more feminine than average
as more sexual
this is more complicated
the interface
o thing space a is more attracted
the main phase b is more attractive
most people
face b
the exception is
and this has been statistically replicate i think now in three laps
phase a is preferred by women who are violating
and then the story about why
is it is
complicated and will take is beyond the scope of this class but the idea that
that is really handsome guy he's young he's healthy he looks strong good provider
this guy's really high
he may not be a good provider and everything but i'm sure is wonderful genes
so the idea is that once you have sex with him
and then have him raise the kids
we've talked so far about things about about sex and sexual attractiveness largely from a
biological perspective
looking at universal's and in fact there are some universals in what men and women
have in common and what distinguished men and women
and some of the sex differences particularly related to aggression
and preference
seem to be universal they seem to show up to some extent across every culture
they have to explain
many more data
in this calculation
same time penalizes simple models
because by the introduction of the noise
the error model
they have to also explain alot more data
everyone happy with that so far
that's just setting the scene so what i want to do the rest of the
maybe will creep balance the next
looking very simple problem in
data modeling just modelling
univariate real valued data
hopefully the and will arrive back at this point where we can look at
potential models
sequence of models
see this effect to work again
so here's a
simple modelling problem
so we have a set of supposedly mystery data we don't really know what's come
imagine as we go along really don't know anything about it but the truth is
the purposes of this lecture
and many of them for years that generated the data right again
there are actually fifteen samples generated from
so i wavefunctions
with semantic as you know is standard deviation of twenty
and just in terms of notation
are you call the input x
of functional call y
and our observations of the target variables are called t
got fifteen of these fifty inputs fifteen corresponding target
kind of models gonna look at
because you want to
have some
transparent analysis of what we're doing we're going to give her
almost the simplest form of model
those models that are linear in the parameters
so all prediction is simply going to be weighted sum
of some
fixed basis functions
the basis functions
could be linear but
typically we use nonlinear functions in this example using gas
data center basis functions
so predictable be non-linear but of course the key thing is called a linear model
linear in the parameters model because the parameters
only appear linear
and so
and optical problem we've got fifteen these gaussians centered on
on the x axis
on each data point
so are prediction model is a linearly weighted sum of those fifteen get
so somehow we want to
find a good model to find good values space and
built in weight
the range approaches but perhaps the most simple simply to say
let's try to fit the data
by defining an error measure
sure you're all familiar with this idea of least squares
so we define the relation least squares error
is simply the sum squared deviation
the data from all predictions
and this is the population for different reasons but one obvious one is
because the weights appear
we can minimize it analytically
and if we defined
the design matrix phi
as the
matrix of the output of every basis functions
for every data point
we can have this analytic
they expect to expression that gives us the solution
the set of weights that minimizes
now of course we know in this case i think you probably expecting we've got
fifteen basis functions
fifteen data points
we should be able to fit the data
and that's what we see
so that's the least squares fit using RBF model with some gasoline basis functions
noisy data
in principle
this is the idea of it
we know
the underlying generator was assigned from
so this is the sideline
an obvious question is
which of these models is actually better
so we get to a sort of philosophical point
it's important to realize
without any further assumptions without knowing where the data came from
we can't judge
between these two models
we don't know
whether the data really came from this more complex function with no noise
or whether it came from a simple function
with noise
we just can't tell
without any further information we can't make any further progress modelling this data
we must accept
we're going to have to introduce some prior knowledge or belief or understanding to this
so we don't give up
because we're fairly happy to make any assumptions
in the real world and the kind of data modelling problems that we tackle
the underlying functions that we expect to find
probably smooth and probably
people can get and get to know each other a bit better while the quality
is not very good and
maybe can install this here
OK i'll not use the microphone because
and i have to focus this
actually trying to break
i tried break but the light was still on
so just before
me i'll switch the lights because maybe it will make things easier
i don't like this
OK now you see quite a few face detections lighting up
some of them are faces some of them are not faces
but of course it's it's a pretty poor quality camera and a fairly cluttered scenes
which again
so what you're seeing here is
of course support vector machines that some of you
some of you may know
some of you may know and others maybe not it's kind of classifier let's train
on data in this case the data are positive and negative examples
so the examples of faces in examples of nonfaces so background clutter
and the classifiers trained on a few thousand such examples and after which can automatically
recognise faces from non faces
and this this is the problem of binary pattern recognition of binary classification with two
different classes of objects and we would like to find
general rule which will assign new inputs to one of these two classes based on
one face
so let me start with some
it informal thoughts on machine learning
so in my lecture will be fairly
none theoretical because there are other lecturers lectures for in statistical learning theory that will
afterwards provide you with the
statistical basis for what i'm talking about so i will not talk much about statistics
talk about some informal ideas in machine learning a little bit about functional analysis and
statistics because of lecturers will supply you with that later on
so for my purposes
motivation learning is quite simple so we have some data taken from input and output
domain x and y so for instance they could be a class of all images
of a certain size
it contains faces among faces
and why
could be a plus or minus one plus one
meaning face minus one million on so it's just as
set containing two elements
when i trained classifier on given training set consists of males x and y
some of them places some of the nonfaces and
in machine learning people often talk about something called generalisation given
a number of examples you would like to make a prediction on the new example
so you would like to find the general rule that will generalize to new examples
that you haven't seen before so in particular given a previously unseen x
given a new face on one face patch
i would like to assign it right as we would find to predict that you
would like to predict the right output y for it
and one way to think about this would be to say well in some sense
my prediction why would be reasonable if the new pair
x and y so i'm given x and i want to find the corresponding y
is somewhat similar to the ones in the training set
this is the training set here
and then of course the question comes up how do we measure similarity
for outputs people usually
use something which is called the loss function to measure similarity so for instance if
we have labels plus or minus one we could just say almost zero whenever the
labels correct so whenever we say face it's really if a is almost zero whenever
we say non face and it's really an en face or losses zero likewise
but for the inputs it's a little bit less trivial hard to measure similarity
between different inputs and that's where concept comes up which is called kernel
which is
basic four
a number of different learning algorithms nowadays i would like to spend some time on
so what i will consider this possible kernels are symmetric functions
so defined on x times x so i have two inputs x prime could be
two faces so they could be computer on nonfaces of one phase one and phase
and i would like to assign a kernel value k of x can prime
two these
one example of such kernels this this function k
it's called the kernel
this function of capture some all notion of similarity
for the moment
in one example that we could use it for input domain is a vector space
at the end we could just consider what's called the canonical dot product between the
two vectors x and x prime
so this is the sum over the i th coordinate of x
times the qualitative
now if
x is not a dot product space
and it's not obvious why it should be the product space me even in the
case of images
you first have to represent them as vectors
before you can take the product but if it's not the products based on we
will assume
that's at least k has a represen tation as a dot product space has a
dot product in some of of space which is the products
so we're assuming that if x and x prime are not living in the product
space then at least they can be mapped to some dot product space using a
mapping phi
but we can think of is all representation sometimes is also called the feature map
so we assume we have nothing to them of space which is the product space
and then we have the the products k corresponds to the product in some other
space at least
so in that case we can think of all the inputs or sometimes they called
patterns the axis of the inputs we can think of them as actually five x
five x y
and then in that of a space is not the product space we can do
whatever we can do based on dot products we can carry out geometric algorithms
the first question we want to discuss has to do with the possibility of my
surviving my death is there life after death is the possibility that i might still
exist to survive after my death
at first glance in fact i think it's that england is going to turn out
to be true
you might think that the answer to this question would depend on two basic issues
you do i survived my death do we survive death
you think first we have to get clear on is
well what i am i what kind of
o thing and i or generalizing the kind of thing is the person what are
we made of what are our parts it seems plausible to think that
before we can answer the question
do i survived we need to know how i'm built
and so
the first thing we're going to spend a fair bit of time on is trying
to get clear on what that person what are the fundamental to the fundamental building
blocks of a person second question that you might think we want to get clear
on is what's the idea of what the concept of surviving
so we need to get it to ask how do i survive we need to
get clear on what and why
and what is it to survive what is it for something that exists in the
future to be me
now this question can be discussed philosophically quite general terms what the nature of persistence
of identity over time but since we are especially interested in beings like us
this topic this sort of some specialized version of the question of identity gets discussed
under the rubric of the topic
personal identity what's the key or the nature of the basis of personal identity as
we might put it what is it for somebody who's here
next week to be the same person
as me
what's the nature personal identity so as i say at first glance you might think
but to get clear on the answer to do y
well my dir could i survive my death we need to know
what am i what the person what's the metaphysical composition of people on the one
hand and we need to get clear on the nature of identity or persistence or
more specifically personal identity now as i say i believe that when push comes to
we do need to get clear about both those questions and so that's going to
take that for several weeks of the class were going to spend a couple of
weeks talking about what that person
and going spend several weeks at least weaker so talking about the nature of personal
but before we can even get started there are a question really an objection to
the whole
enterprise so about to spend a lot of time asking the philosophical question is there
life after death could be life after death might have survived my death
but there is no philosophical objection to the entire question and the objection is fairly
simple it says the whole question is misconceived it's based on a confusion
once we see the confusion
we can see what the answer to our questions could i survive my death the
answers back to be this is what the objections says has got to be obviously
not hard to hear his objection
i should mention that the very first reading that you're going to be doing a
couple of pages from j rosenberg a contemporary philosopher and he gives us a version
of this objection
so i'll give you one version you have another version in your readings
the objection basically says what is it
i mean to say that somebody's died you know asking is there life after death
what does it mean to say that somebody has died one natural definition of death
might be something like the end of life
all right so then if that's the right thing to ask is there life after
death is just asking is there life after the end of a lot
and the answer to that would be pretty obvious well
obviously the answer to that is no
after all if we say once you've run out of life
is there any more life
so that's that's that's like asking when i've eaten up all the food on my
plate is there any food left on my plate
what happens in the movie after the movie ends
these are
stupid questions because what you understand what they're asking the answer just building it follows
trivially so although it has seemed to people over the age is that the question
is there life after death is one of the great mysteries one of the great
philosophical things to ponder
the objection says that's the kind of illusions in fact what you think about it
and not all that long you can see the answer is going to be no
they couldn't possibly be life after death couldn't possibly be like after the end of
or suppose we ask the question a slightly different way
my i survived my death
well what's the word survive me
well survivors something like we say that somebody is a survivor if something's happening they
haven't having died is still alive
you know when a car accident you ask you know so-and-so died so and so
survived you know this person survives to say they survived is just saying that there
still alive
my i survived my dad is like asking
might i still be alive after
well what's death death is the end of life so
might i still be alive after i
stop living
might i be one of the people who didn't die when i died
that's the answer that is again
i don't know
you could possibly survive you're death given the very dif with this in mind as
and this reminds me of this joke you probably told seemed hysterical when you're were
seven right
plane crashes are exactly on the border of canada and the united states exactly on
the border with and the dead people everywhere where they bury the survivors
the answer is you don't vary the survivors so we use everything i don't know
any better than it can be very america right it has no bearing the survivors
because survivors are people they haven't yet
can i survive my death is like asking could i not have yet died after
the answer is
of course you have to have died a few died and you have survived if
you died
right so the question cannot even get off the ground that this is how the
objection goes
now i don't mean to be utterly dismissive of the objection that's why i spend
a couple of minutes trying to spell it out
but i think there's a way to
respond to it
we just have to get clear about what precisely the question is that we're trying
to ask and this is something that rosenberg try to get clear out as well
so here's my attempt to
make the question both a bit more precise and question that's an open question a
question we can legitimately raise
in the online setting so in the the set up for that is we have
we have
we want to at every iteration
we have some mahalanobis matrix
at step step t say and we receive a pair of points
and we predict the distance between those
those two points and and and then we receive the true distance and incur some
loss for how how far off we were from the from the true distance
then we update our
mahalanobis metric for the next iteration
and what we want to do is we want to minimize the total loss the
sum of the losses that
at all iterations and what's typically done in online learning is you you want to
prove some sort of regret bound that is you want to show that your you
don't do much worse than the best possible
offline algorithms
so we were able to prove the bound so al amal is the loss of
online metric learning algorithm and l a stars the loss of the best offline metric
and so
note that alistar is not the the loss of of like are off offline
information theoretic metric learning algorithm is like the best possible offline algorithm that could exist
in theory
so in in a few minutes i have left out just present some
empirical results of of this approach
what we did is we set up we did your typical k nearest neighbour classifier
so we have a training data set we we generate constraints from the training dataset
we learn the metric and then we do k nearest neighbour over the
the test data
and some of the details are written up on the slide
we compare against the number of different
existing approaches including some baseline metrics like the squared euclidean distance and using the inverse
four year mahalanobis distance
so first we look at some of the standard UCI datasets that everybody looks at
the leftmost side of the leftmost bar is ITML maxent which is information theoretic metric
learning with a not equal to the identity matrix
what we see is that in general that
that algorithm is performing quite comparably to
two other methods and and
it is often is
is within the confidence intervals is always for performing the best
we looked at application of metric learning to
nearest neighbor software support
so there's this system developed at UT called clarify the way it works is every
execution of a program is
it's like one data point and it and monitors things like function calls and so
forth and so if if you run your program and it crashes you might want
to say oh you know what other
programme executions are similar to this letter from say some training sets so i can
figure out now
why my program crashed so we looked at so so we looked at metric learning
in this context and looked at
a few different programs like attack and an MP three player database manager
and this linux kernel applications
and then again we found that that we do quite quite well as compared to
the other methods especially on on the lot tech data set where we seem to
be doing very well
in terms of timing i don't have the results here but we're also
very very
fast so in general i think where the fastest of of the methods that we
looked at
so to to wrap up we
so the
the formulation for this problem is that of minimising the differential relative entropy of two
gaussians corresponding to
mahalanobis distance DNA in my home in the mahalanobis distance d and not
and that's that straightforward of set up
has a lot of nice advantages we can
we have a very simple
and scalable algorithm based on logdet projections
and it includes able to incorporate many different constraints we can catalyze that we can
prove regret bounds and empirically it seems to be quite competitive with with existing techniques
OK thanks
have to complete
it's like
you have a a lot of
at the end of the
the above
ah i don't know if you can have banned said and so how would you
so that know this is the data the gun
the god of love from the log will go the likelihood of the data to
get this
it would be all here this this and this means that there will be
and an edge from
six four to six
this is an events
events description of the temporal
it's also it also can be an event
of course what you can get this also
from the
from the internet just click here and you'll get
this is the the same data set that i
so this is just
just to show how
things can be done then
nicer and the visualisation can be really nice when using it when using piped and
we're going to look at this temporal network from september eleventh well the network was
what network the data were
together by steve corman with collaborators
and they were you they used the writers news
in sixty six days and about september eleventh
they were they get big idea articles and then
the collected works
different words that appear in those articles and
the line between two
but this is too
what would that mean that there is that they appeared in the same text in
the same article
what would this mean that the thickness of these edges would then mean that they
appeared so many times in so many different articles
by i also kenneth export
there are
drawings to SVG that's a scalable vector format and i'm going to show you are
here how this looks like
this is the whole network
and this is just the first day
so in the first day there's
a lot
about a lot written about twenty our world trade centre new york pentagon then also
attacked to the united states
then the sea territories
on the right
well this is a low-resolution that's why i have two
go from left to right we have also the
the weight of the lines
and if we for example want to just see
to see what the lines that appeared at least thirty
thirty one
times so
the the words that were thirty five one times in the same appeared in the
same articles we would click
and what we get is
just the
the vertices and lines with the highest weight
but if we so then we can go forward
four weekdays
the next day
a bit more diverse for example here we have like that
conference used
o and then rescue rescue workers
and of course we can again look at that and try to
i'll get some useful information about that
and the
sorry i
but then
what's interesting here
that if for example could the thirty nine
we get a lot less
written about that but the
the weights change two different subjects so here as opposed to worker the anthrax
skin and so on so
these are two
the main topics that were to be the the the article's talk about
on the
thirty nine thirty nine days
and about afghanistan and so on
so it's
they were
there can be a lot of things said about it so
you can of course get to go to the article about the september eleven
it's also in attendance
is that a slide show
the data from cat some from then county kansas event data set data service that
it is
presented like like this how they are recoded to
five format
and how they well this is like
the first
number here is the date so this would be in the
the year nineteen eighty nine in the fourth month and in the second day then
these two countries
had this
activity or this
relations so the it's right
here and that's how it's
code so we will look at the
the first country in the second country here vertices then we can have all the
are we have all the arts and all the relations here so that's how they
are just sort it will just listed down all the different relations and then at
the end
we have the number of the relation and the numbers of two countries that one
of two two states that shared this relation
what we tend to be and the idea and there's
the time event over time to time
timestamp when this happens so this happen in time step for what we have to
be careful here is that we have also
this third number and this is the weight of the
i think even if
the weight is always one
that's how did
five will now
so this is the end of the first part of the talk that was about
networks what kind of network what kind of data sets were are used in pike
and will start with doing some more analysis some more statistics so the first thing
which will be what kind of input data we have and what kind of statistic
we can use statistics we can do
we have no merits numeric
data that would vectors
and in the values of lines
then we have or not this could be one k one k one
possibility of station and then nominal data of course to the
clustering or the partition and the
good afternoon everybody
my name is
new shoes for microsoft research asia
and i worked in the hardware computing group
and this is a joint work with you i want to see
the department for electronics engineering
and the high tories
pg based mapreduce framework for machine learning so this is something different for the case
should based
for the machine learning approach i will illustrate more about
why we select this approach for
efficient computing machine learning
so quick so it who has no
the PG
over the head
it was pretty much sex
here the offline d
first i will introduce the motivation
and the proposed solution
and then i will introduce the case study we have implemented we implement
it was named rankboost
and i will
present the results and in the summary
this is a very popular figure
and the
general purpose CPU has the
the power the power limit be column it
and people have to go into the parallel
as we know them and who has utilized many many motions in these data centre
this the have the parallel computing power for their web applications but is still
requires a power
and you can see that the
the is they have and the annual
for the the cost for the power consumption and the queen will cover the hardware
for each year
so we can see that you large problems you when we go into the lead
processing with many commodity motions
so here's the challenge for general purpose CPU architecture
the memory wall
because if you that past member benefits to slow
and we also has a very large area in the cheap
for the cash
and only part of the areas for the computation logic
and also many areas for the normal arithmetic operation like
old for order for the prediction speculative
address the
to again try to guess
what's the next state is what the structure is so
that is not efficient
OK this is the architecture is here and also
for the
parallel programming we also
i need to manage the concurrency explicitly that means we have created to create the
threats and created the
synchronisation manually and two
get it work we have a long block two
make it work and when we
how bad hardware we want to increase the scalability of this has to go through
many many motions we may want to retool in the parameters
so we have at architecture and the program intended is
so what's the
the solution to that
this is our proposed solution is called cost of the mosfet computing for motion and
there are some
interesting fact before the fact
here is the primary goal of this project
we want to automatically
but this expression for z
is monotonically increasing in epsilon t
and the range that we care about between zero and a half
so we're minimizing epsilon t is the same as minimizing this expression and so is
the same as minimizing zt
so what we see coming out of that proof
is that both
adaboost which is choosing alpha t
and the weak learner which is choosing ht are working together so as to minimize
this normalisation factor on every round of boosting
so that's equivalent to saying that they're working to greedily minimizes the product of the
so they minimize if ct separately so they are trying to minimise the product of
the it is but they're doing it in a greedy fashion greedy in the sense
that you're just doing doing it on round t
you just minimizing zt without looking at what effect it will have on the later
so apparently
adaboost is
would seem to be a greedy procedure for minimizing this product of busy tees
so what is the product of the is
well again if you go to the back to the training year proof
we show that the product of the ETS is equal to one over times the
of this exponential function
we're half again is this
weighted sum
of the weak classifiers
so this is a loss function this has come to be called the exponential
loss functions
so what we've argued is that adaboost is apparently trying to greedily
minimize the exponential loss function so that would seem to be the loss function associated
with adaboost
so why exponential loss
well intuitively
exponential loss strongly favours f of x
having the same sign
graph of x i having the same signers why because if they have opposite signs
then this exponent will be positive and we take the exponential of that you get
a very large number
so trying to make this loss function small
has the effect of
they bring their
predictions f of x y
having the same sign as one
which is just what we want in adaboost
another reason which is kind of what we used in the training year proof is
that this exponential loss function
is an upper bound on the usual training here
so the story goes well we really like to minimize the training air
but the training area is this nasty function it's not
smooth it's not convex it's not even continuous
so instead of minimizing will minimize this upper bound on the training year which is
smooth and convex and continuous
but it is a very loose upper bound on the training year
so those are two motivations for why this exponent exponential loss function might make sense
so how does adaboost go about minimizing exponential loss so if we try to abstract
away from adaboost and viewed as a numerical method for minimizing the loss function what's
well again let's let g one through g and be the space of all of
our weak classifiers
so we can take half
which is this linear combination of weak classifiers
and rewrite it in terms of the entire space of weak classifiers
so in that case nearly all of these lambda is these parameters will be zero
so be very sparse
combination of this large space of weak classifiers
and then loss function can be rewritten in this way we replaced f of x
with this linear combination over the entire space weak classifiers
and now we just have this function
of these parameters lambda one two lambda and that we're trying to minimize so adaboost
is just trying to minimize find these parameter values to minimize this function here
so how does it do it well adaboost is actually doing it kind of coordinate
descent on this optimisation problem
so if you think about it in these abstract terms what it's doing is that
initially setting all the parameter values to zero
and then on every round it's choosing one corner lambda j just one of them
to update
in its updating it by incrementing by some amount alpha t
choosing coordinate lambda j
corresponds to choosing one of these weak classifiers
which is exactly what is happening on every round we're choosing an HTN every round
which has to be one of these weak classifiers gj
we're just using a single coordinate work updating that one coordinate we're doing it in
such a way so as to cause the biggest decrease in the loss function
so this is called coordinate descent it's an approach that
goes back a long time before adaboost
and so it seems to be very slow slow compared say to gradient descent which
might be a more natural way of minimising
some function
but it does have the advantage that that it's very convenient when you're working over
a huge space of weak classifiers are huge space of functions
because you just updating one of these on each round c and up with something
which is sparse and you often can use some kind of work the boosting case
the weak learning algorithm to look for the one to date
OK here's another
the of boosting which is as
for doing something called functional gradient descent
so instead of viewing the loss as a function of those parameters we can view
the loss as a function of the function f
so here again is our loss function which is now a function of the function
so it's a function of functions sort of functional
so the loss is now functional
and we're looking for the function as which minimizes this
so if we had current estimate for half
one natural thing you might want to do is to use gradient descent which means
to take a stab
in the direction of steepest descent
two basically is now from a logical point of view i suppose you might have
a third possible view know we've got them monasteries has only and those bodies but
there's no souls you could imagine somebody who says there are stalls but there are
no bodies
this would roughly be view according to which their minds but there are really physical
objects physical objects are kind of illusion perhaps we fall into
or thinking about the materialistic terms might be greatly confused or mistaken
this view is sometimes known in philosophy as idealism
all that exists some mines in their ideas
physical objects is just the way of talking about the ideas the mind has or
something like that
idealism is the position that's got a very long history and philosophy and you know
for many classes would be worth taking you know a fair bit of time to
consider more carefully but for our purposes i think it's not a contender so i'm
just going to put aside
the positions that i'm going to enter other possibilities as well
you know there there are views where the mind and body are just two different
ways of looking at the same underlying reality
with the underlying reality is neither physical nor mental
is also worth taking seriously in metaphysics class but for our purposes
i mentioned it put aside the two views we're going to focus on are on
the one hand the dualistic view
people have
souls as well as bodies
and the physical is view
all we have all we are are bodies
well let me say something more than about that are dualistic position
according to journalist
that the mind is is immaterial substance and we could we could call it by
different names we could no harm would be done if we call it to mind
though the reason i will typically talk about us all is to try to flag
the crucial point do all this view the mind is based in or even just
is something non-physical something on material
we could call mind called so called psyche is a are typically try to call
it the soul the soul can direct and give orders to
the body
on the one hand
on the other hand the body
sort of
input that eventually gets
since or felt by the
you get you take up in and you stick it through my flesh of my
i feel pain
in my
in my mind
two way interaction and is always in with philosophy there's there's more complicated versions of
we are maybe the interaction of we're both ways but let's just
limit ourselves to good old fashion
two way interaction this dualism
so my
my mind control of my body
my body can affect my mind in various ways but for that there are separate
still there is this very tight connection
we sometimes put it the cells in the body though of course talking about spatial
location here maybe maybe some metaphorically
intended is that as we think that if start opening up the body finally find
the particular spot OK here's the place where the souls located
well it does seem from this dual is perspective is all souls are located i'm
sort of viewing the world from here
just like each of you is viewing in the world in particular locations so maybe
your soul is located more or less in the vicinity of your body
the crucial point of course the the attraction of the dualistic view
so far point of view is that
autoregressive models they was how random elements to them so the prediction is itself a
random variable so we simply sampling fairly from the distribution of the random variable to
st anne's and finally the like weights by TNA
are simply
as before likelihoods evaluated at the positions of the new particles and for the new
here's a picture of the same thing
articles depicted along a horizontal line which is the one-dimensional depiction of the state space
and the positions of the particles along the line of values as in the size
of the particle depicts its weight
and so you sample from each particle
with probability that is proportional to the
the weight on the particles so you see some large particles will get chosen more
than once in some small particles may not get chosen at all and if we
split up the prediction into its deterministic path and you know as in the autoregressive
process and is random part you see what happens is that initially when i choose
this big particles several times all of the new
drawn from that
i have exactly the same value because so far have used only the deterministic part
of the process now i we'll in the random part of the process and these
duplicate particles freedom sitting on top of of one another here split according to
draw independent draws of the random variables and i've got a nice have non degenerate
distribution of particles along the line and this this particle set equally weighted forms the
prediction distribution finally particle gets passed under their likelihood curve this is the curve says
to what degree
a particular value in state space agrees with the observations
and so if the particle happens to sit on the peak of the likelihood function
then it will get given the largest weight
a light weight and values and sit on the floor often like a function will
get given small weight and so on
i've got an animation this maybe it's going too far
well the animation
bit of animation
they are particles
drawn and this is the first time step of the particle filter
so some samples are drawn according to their weights
at the previous timestep and they get
reweighted according to this thread likelihood curve and a got particles of different sizes some
of them almost disappeared because they had such low likelihoods
that's just the first time step and the particle filter and now we take
that that particles that is being the prior for the next time step and so
on the
possible selection process is repeated
i guess this slide is just to emphasise
how much we need this
mechanism actually
when particle filtering was invented in nineteen three
people used it for
linear filtering problems but you know what i would call not particularly interesting nonlinearities where
for example bearings only tracking is one example where you have particles in the plane
but you're only able to measure the angle so the the arctan of y one
x is you're nonlinearity in the observation function which sort of mild on long nonlinearity
what my
colley is art and i realized was that they were much more
pressing nonlinearities that arise in problems of tracking in cluster and so he that picture
again that we had before the normal
with the responses on
the normal
and features found along each normal
and you expect multiple features and so for each normal
you're going to get the likelihood function may be something like this where there is
a peak in the function corresponding to each response of your low level feature detector
but the and
i won't go through this argument here but using the probability of association which is
the standard way of modelling these things between features and events we can build up
a mixture distribution the likelihood is naturally expressed as a mixture distribution with a again
let's gasoline component sitting on each of these observations but the point is that this
very this multimodal and therefore the nongaussian distribution is what you get sitting on one
normal curve now if you refer those observation distributions into the state space using our
beloved h matrix remember the tube of the the two on the on the trumpet
we refer all of those observation distributions state space now
you've got the combination of the modes from each of those individual lines or if
state space ECM massive the multimodality problem is once you aggregate all of these are
the observations associated with one curve and c in state space so this is a
much more extreme form of
nonlinearity that arises i say with class and to me
it seems that the real
who of particle filters has been in there
the ability to do filtering class i think this is whether really important
and a depiction of the remember the picture of the kalman filter we had an
electoral two back
the idea is that you take guassian distribution
and in the prediction step it drifts and gets diffused and then the observations that
peaks in the distribution are emphasized again correspond to observations and what this particles that
is modelling in this admittedly somewhat degenerate way
rather the mixture of delta functions is just the same kind of process but now
we nongaussian distribution
of course it may be that the complexity
you can have the nonlinearity either the likelihood model or in the predictive model boats
OK so
i started the talk a few announcements to make
so remember there will be talks and after knowing he is studying the store clerk
there there's some very nice stocks so
that would be a good place to go to
there is also sold
i don't remember there it's under
you can go to the website
so i
way should come and find out
so maybe it would be a good idea to print out the schedule for the
afternoon talks
so that's one so that talks in the afternoon then they will be
three fifteen
and i'm this is log
and password
if t i
c underscore zero methods
and what
what i'm going to talk in the second part of introduction i will talk about
so i will talk about kernel based algorithms
and so the kernel based algorithms it's it's a large family of algorithms and it
has been quite popular in the last perhaps fifteen years or so and that's probably
was could is considered to be one of the biggest developments in machine learning in
particular associated with support vector machine
but there are
other algorithms like regularized this question which actually built up quite a bit and the
kernel principal component analysis and there are many other algorithms
and basically the problems this algorithms address
the usual problems were interested in machine learning
which is classification regression
density estimation and there is another thing
outlier detection for example and
other things also
OK so
this algorithms in this talk i will
more mausoleum talk about regularized least squares and support
vector machines
OK so
so what is the problem that remind you what the problem is
of course you
the standard in pakistan but
i think it's good to say that again
so regression and classification
and here is the problem of regression the fundamental problem of regression is to estimate
a function from some space let's just say are and for simplicity into our
so you have a bunch of
they for example switch which x y
axes and around one thousand and you want to estimate
a function from this example so
is to make the function that given in your example you will be able to
tell what the well and there are many
cases in which this is very
for example you know there is
maybe you have a house and you want to estimate the price of house depending
on various parameters of the house on the market and so on so that one
example maybe you have a patient and you want to find
the probability that they will die depending on various parameters of their health
and so if the insurance company very interested in this question
estimate lunch and you know if you are
trying to if a few have rocket and you're
going into space maybe you would like to know what your rocket is going one
to five and in what is going to do and say
two months from now and it's going to end up
so that's estimating
some sort of four actually position of course is not one real numbers three real
numbers but
OK so the classification is
very similar but you have minus one in one labels and typically you want to
say separate
images of one from images of
images of digits know five from
digit nine or perhaps you want to separate
grammatical sentences from ungrammatical
so this a classification
and basically this
in something quite similar and what's interesting is that actually
but really does classification people what people the people typically estimator real valued function
and then the threshold of real valued functions
like this
so if basically say if it's greater than zero then its class one
so this is the two class classification just to classes in reality you might want
to have more than you have to stay in character recognition you want to
we can put a name to
so let's think about it all is happening on facebook is once you go past
a hundred and fifty will you actually doing
is adding these outer layers and which is just a part of normal everyday life anyway there's nothing special
what is it surprises in these data
is that
networks spent roughly fifty fifty within a hundred and fifty into family and friends we
had assumed the kingship family with something only happened in traditional small-scale societies and
what these
what we're all our data come from either britain and belgium are two big data
both pretty much identical
we still find that about half the people including your network actually family
and only about half a friends
places are on the left it just gives you a sense see
interaction rate
he intensity as social investment in the different layers you can see huge proportion your
social time is devoted to the unit circle a five andafter the at a time
two people in the different layers is is just
and dropping away very very fast anyway
friendship and kinship
turned out to be completely have completely different dynamics
so these data from an eighteen month study we did the following through
the changes in people's networks
after they moved away
from the original
places that were
and what you can see is and with kind of interested in the pressures that physical distance with put on
these equality as a relationship
what you can see is fact
the average emotional closeness which is the wire axis
is very stable over eighteen months with respect to q and if anything goes up a bit
almost as the absence really doesn't make the heart
and that this is not just you know your brothers and sisters and your mum
and dad says you your entire extended kinship this is the average for the entire
extended kinship groups but look at the contrast the friends
so this is this is the emotional recorded emotional closeness that's these three different points
in time for the original set of friends that they started out with at the
beginning of the study about sarah it just plummets and particularly permits away
in the first nine months
one of the things we are interested in this figure studies how digital technology allows
you to slow down the rate of decay of friendship
so this is what happens
and what turned out there was a surprising
sex difference in how
stop relationships and this area is just friendship so
on the left-hand side we need each
the two graphs
on the left hand side
we have the change in emotional closeness to a friend as a result of reduced
interaction with them in some way
over i think this is over
nine months the first nine months in the middle here interacting with them we enter
the nine months about the same is true
beginning and on the right-hand side view interacting with the more
and on of these two graphs the one on the right here
is essentially
frequency and talking to them either by phone or in person
in some way or even perhaps by email
on the left hand side is doing stuff together a catalog things you might do
hand how often have you done been shopping parties holiday to help them move house engage
by stuff would have been
basically the story is
if you don't do stuff
with somebody with a friend
the relationship deteriorates over time very quickly
the way to stop relationship deteriorating particular when the physical space
it built and put into in between
the menu
to keep doing more as well but there's a massive sex difference
what stops
the goals
friendships deteriorating is essentially
talking together
what stops the boys friendships deteriorating is banging their heads together
doing stuff
and in fact doing stuff has a negative effect on girls they
the next thing about rape laws
is that the overall
order of the reaction is simply the sum
of the exponent so the sum of all the individual orders
so if you're rate law
it was you rate constant
and it's a two to the two
so that's what water in a
second order
and what order and b
first order
and your overall order is going to be
so the overall to word order
second order in a first order and b
and overall
so it always breaks my heart on the test when people get this part right
and they say what the overall order the reaction
and they had one in the two to get great so
remember that part that that's like give me point on an exam
to be able to add these very small numbers and come up with the song
so remember how to do that
so overall it's just some of the individual orders
OK so here's the bad news
and that is
of the unit for the rate constant k
so the units are going to have to do
you know what units you have concentration and rates and what terms are in there
so there's no one unit that you can memorize and we know that that's what
it's going to be
so you have to actually think about what the unit for the rate constant or
so that's a little bit trickier this one much easier just that so but the
units are little more complicated here
all right so that you need to know about great loss so it's it's not
not too much
all right so here are some of the problem
with these kinds of experiments
some of the data they might get the you're trying to analyse may not be
too perfect usually if it's in the textbook it's pretty perfect data but in general
these things can be tricky to do
and they can be tricky to get the good data to figure out what the
order of the reactions are
because you're often measuring
really small changes in concentration of material over brief intervals of time so that can
be technically challenging to do
and so the approach that uses that is to use these integrated rate laws
and so here you can express concentrations directly as a function of time
and this makes it easier to get at the information that you want
so let's look at a first order reactions you know what first order means now
so we just have one thing going to another thing in this particular example here
first order for a
i rate of the reaction could be written the rate expression can be written in
terms of the disappearance
of a over time
and you know its first order told us first order
so you can also right
the rate law
so the rate law for first order reaction in a would just be the rate
constant times the concentration of that so and this one here
so now
we can derive the first order integrated rate law
from this simple expression right here
so what we're going to do
is we're going to take
the concentration terms
and put them on one side
of the expression
and we're going to take time terms and put them on the other side
so we're going to bring
the concentration of a here over to the side of the expressions there it is
one of the concentration of a we have dt
as well
and as we move that
and we have k
and the negative sign over here and we've moved the change in time
over to the other side so we have all the concentration terms on one side
we have a rate terms in time turns on the other side
and now we can integrate
and we want to consider
change from the initial concentration of a to o for all original or to the
zero so the original amount that you have of a to the concentration of a
you have at time t
so we have our our concentration expression in terms of time we're looking from zero
time to time t
and now we can take this
and solve this expression
so this is the same one and it's moving up to the top of the
so now we can
we can express this in terms of natural log
so the natural log
of the concentration of a at time t
minus the natural log of the original concentration of a equals minus k
and we can reorder that put a box around it which means is going to
be important later on
so we can rearrange this in terms of the natural log of the concentration at
time t
minus katie plus the natural log of the initial
concentration of a and so we come back to this in a few minutes we
can also keep going and rearrange this in other ways
so we can rewrite this term instead of by subtracting them rewrite as this division
so natural log of the concentration of a at time t over the original concentration
equals minus katie
and then we can take the inverse natural log
and so then on the other side we have e race to the minus eighty
and we can write this in this expression again box is the way that you
often see
the first order integrated rate law
where solving for the concentration of a at time t
is equal to the original concentration of a times e to the minus katie
so how the concentration of a changes depends on
the the rate constant and the time that has elapsed
so this is often the way that the integrated first-order rate laws written sometimes you
may see a little bit different expressions but usually this is the final expression that
you see
and then
is an equation for straight line
and that's why it was box because it how did is going to be plotted
so if you're going to use that now plot data
you can plot data
the whole act
so the concentration of a is changing sphere measuring how the concentration of a is
changing versus time
then rather than focusing on getting concentrated on the
the centre of this triangle
the probability mass starts going towards the edges and that the more you decrease the
o from one
the more concentrated around the edges that become so this is an interesting property
this the distribution
ants this is basically
these are basically what it looks looks like when you have
different values far
he landed on test match increases but
the special doesn't really want you to look at very long
you can you can play around with the
this their distributions by using the
there are density that's
you don't need to that now but this is basically
going to show you what happens when you do
input different parameter values and so on
so that usually distribution again
an interesting property right
if you combine entries of additional distributed probability vector
you will still end up with there's a distributed vectors
but with less number of dimensions this time
so if we have key dimensional
vector pi
that is usually distributed with parameters alpha one two alpha complicate ants if we simply
sum up the first two entries of this
similarity sum up the first two parameters of this distribution
this is what we get
the vector with one less dimensions is still
this distributed with this the shape this time
all the parameters the same except first planets are being some of the
first parameters there
and this is not specific to of course the first national first dimensions only you can do it or mentions
and the colors of this is also true
so you can have
of kate dimension
if i
being distributed with alpha one t alpha cape ann if your sample
these two one to two values from a two-dimensional dish which is also called the
but a function the distribution
and then you multiply
the corresponding entries with the corresponding
well you
like this by one times
the tau one and pi one time start to similar to offer one times but
one and alpha one one times
but the two
i think there's a typo there
making sure that this one plus with better to is equal to one then u get additional distribution
you can run
deep you generate
to see that we can
actually draw from additional process by
using this property
we start with
uh uniform distribution
all zero ten
and therefore did this is it's a o point one
and for keep refining by drawing
from this better distribution we keep refining
ah that this space
like this for example so i mean first row from the
but the distribution it
devices into two
two parts
and the height of that is proportional to the
values that we draw
and then we will keep rehearsing on
each of these helps like this like this and if you do it long enough
we're going to have something like this so
you actually you're going to have different personal
infinitesimal intervals
some of which will have
huge spikes and some of the more most of which will have a tiny spikes so
this is a very easy and fun way of
draw from the dish that this deletion process actually
it shows to that you can get it as the infinite limit of the addition distribution
there are different ways where you can define the distance
you can construct samples from the show there's a process or you can sample
from the process and one way to do it is by using the stick breaking construction
so if you go to the court the speed generate that's
code is going to
fixed four-year
so these are going to be
sticks that are
that i've presented a of the
none of these
rates forward additionally
parameter values so the sticks
i'm going to look like this because they are defined using this recursive formula
you is drawn from the better one of distribution
in expectation they are going to be
exponentially decreasing so the this red parts artistic lens of the
this process
these are going to be exponentially
decreasing in expectation
there fore
here was in one
black and white male female
interested not interested in this course
so that got me
and i'm going to go through the whole procedure of
standard CS
from a to c
well even beyond
before a and b and c
it is easy to side
they're going to develop the second technique
which is called an because he stands for
ninety value because you
it is simply an extension of course
meaning to still
i have clear categories in the data
but more than two
let's say
if you're working with social classes and you have
three qualitatively
subgroups that the working class middle class and upper class and you cannot three dichotomized
well then you can use any see
you have three values instead of two
there are
pros and cons i mean strength and weaknesses in each of these approaches techniques
one difficulty with images here is that
when used a lot of MV multi value
terrible conditions
you will
this page expand
because property space there will be a lot of diversity in the data and therefore
you will lose parsimony
you see as one of the core issues going to develop in the course
there's always a very important tension between
complexity in parsimony
every time they make a choice from complexity
well you you are bound to lose parsimony india
and the whole thing is weighing the pros and cons of
keeping the complexity
all going for parsimony i would like to be i will advocate quite strongly in
the first week
the the usefulness of a crisp set to see the basic one
zeros and ones that got them is
the shocking to some of you
because you seem to be losing so much information
if you
restrict if you summarize information that could in fact academic say if you have
information about the richness
affluence right in euros dollars
and you
you have very fine grained data and summarized as a dichotomy
you seem to a lot of information but then gives you a lot of leverage
on the data
because you know you will achieve a lot of applications in the casinos
it's a trade
so the chance cast and schneider in the second week
we actually made some counter-arguments and argue why it is interesting to use
fuzzy sets which is much more fine grained
and you will be able to choose
what to make arbitration of
your own way
we also in the first week do some refinements
and makes me more advanced things but it was the first big movie
kind of more basic
the second we will be more advanced
and then cast list neither will present
what is called viscous you
stands for fuzzy sets because you
it is not an extension of course it is see this kind of another approach
it starts from fuzzy sets
which is of
whole of the set of literature
fuzzy sets
are another way to envisage
let me say
a few words about this in a minute
in a few words
the functionalities begins by
defining pure set
pure set is like it to public property
some given kind for instance say a
you could define
theoretically or actually
pure set of what a rich country with b
purely rich country with a country where everyone is a millionaire in euros or dollars
and then you are the empirical world
and you will be able to two
determine to what extent each case observation
he belongs to that pure set
it's called fuzzy set membership scores
forget about it
it is here
for instance maybe
the the sultanate of of oman
before the crisis
it would have been
nineteen ninety nine percent inside this because most people over there are millionaires in dollars
hi t
we probably zero point zero one
compensate for perturbations
says look at learning the target territory first
difficult specified by hand because helicopter dynamics is complicated we tried we tried very hard
and we didn't succeed and prosper about a year year and a half
resulting in the video you saw the helicopter going through the trees
we read a lot of books
tried a lot of things
that was said this by the water readings
this is too hard for us maybe we can just have a machine learning
our solution was to collect demonstrations of desired maneuvers
and somehow
extract the queen trajectory from
the challenge here is that the pilot even if he's an expert pilot will not
do the same thing over and over and we ask him to do demonstrations
so getting rid of the de-noising problem you get a budget demonstrations
some i wanna get a clean version out
and that's going to be a target trajectory
show u
the title demonstrations were getting from our pilot
are you see here is
six demonstrations
all the same air show
it's a sequence
aggressive aerobatic maneuvers
we have very sort of sensors on the helicopter on the ground track position and orientation reasonably accurately
and then we see here is a graphical replay
of was actually flown up to some reasonable accuracy
look at this these demonstrations are very similar
this outcomes are going through the same sequence of maneuvers
they're not doing it at the same time not the same place now what exactly the same orientation
so we want to clean this up and get out one
that's the best abilities
and better than the best evolves
you work in machine learning and natural thing to do is to think of these as well
looks like in its human rights in the sequence of states they you try to
recover the end you get observations over time
so that's all we started out with
the sequence of states we don't know what they are but we're going to recover them
the dynamics model
but a helicopter can be plugged into the transition model
the demonstrations are observations so we get to see
so the helicopter states
because the timing isn't exactly the same in all these
we don't know how to come up
it is in a state
but if we knew how to come up with average
how to align these
before an iterative procedure so the first thing is to say well let's just randomly initializes initial trajectory
let's say with one demonstrations are some
often makes them
we come up with by hand usually we take the one has the average duration of all demonstrations about five
they going with the
middle the median
duration but in the hidden trajectory
was about in there
we can do pairwise alignment
so alignment is expensive from multiple sequences
but you just have to it's fairly
efficient do
so we live demo one
an introductory that we now have an estimate we line them up to
now in a state
state sequence
now we're going to recover
and a set of observations
two and each time
we run
it's meant forward backward here
is a continuous state space be extended kalman filter we run forward backward it's the same idea
standard probabilistic inference
right backward gets city-state estimate sound and this is our first with the hidden trajectory could be
was the first one we iterate so now we have a better assessment
we disconnect these observations
we get dynamic time warping which is standard already from the speech literature
and the same are enemies is known as minimum wage
in the biological sequence alignment literature
so run down
the real line
then rerun the forward backward
in new trajectory out
keep repeating this until this converges
using this takes about five iterations
x y
we have actually
i'm family
so that it decomposes show
some these
which far from
unknown to him
the british
of time and
in a way that it is the last station
it also allows to capture on the frequencies
but also by the way she
it's all these basis functions that depend on one another
have one
what to this
the basic
and it is the basis functions
and based on these models we can all these are just performing she scaling of
the model
so we have article actually is called scale
and applying this scaling by my mother
we cannot
all the basis and that they can be infinite
because we can apply this scaling
in thing that's mars but usually is
several hours
on the be
and after that can try to come
i don't
into as the new system of
what can we do not
and i understand why know here functions when
you can imagine that in which it is to the actual function
so i
we have the value function just intended to land
the point
x y
so it's the
ordinary dimensions described one
and we can apply
this could transform this function
and the two of them
in new way
look and is now in which one to
but you can see that these
works actually like he does
because when we project
our portal because it's a white card
the car according to be
we know how many
in our and how we know the great white fleet
it's the same with these functions so we know
the first was it
basis functions
and we actually project our
six function of the bones of function
and the because there's lot the because there will be one of the coordinate x
that means that the best of
this one is this really is the basis functions
and now we can make
another way
so that the function is usually like two thousand images this
only ever basis functions kind of it and therefore
one of the which was always the first
so actually performed
the formation
the formation of our
you need to function
which is that the
then mention what we wait
this debate function
one of them
and you
the late energy so we don't really exist some way
of this form
the because the
the method the function
which is one of the soul
it is more like this
it's the basic idea of all these wavelet based
the station
there are a lot of weight so women can be complex
we can be
like the three women the same way of life
generally the transform applied to the one way
is that they are
this kind of formation become just so well we're usually called life
so this
basis functions
which of scale
just an assumption right you may not believe it or maybe you believe it to
some degree are not that the degree of anything i definitely want the function which
is global is most to some degree i don't want to for suppose my unlabelled
data it's crazy i don't want to function which you know will fit very well
and whatever the crazy stuff and unlabelled data but doesn't somehow respect global
niceness of the function
for example the line the manifold assumption might be completely false
right you it may be that actually the correct but first
then why would i want to you know keep that up
i don't know in real life it seems to help so it seems that helps
usually set this up
to be a little bit
because it somehow allows you to control this extreme sick niceness of the function which
you get
and in some sense it's it's sort of denoising if you wish
OK so
but in this case i don't think it makes a difference
OK so here are some experiments
basically blue is using unlabelled data and RAD is not using unlabelled data those guys
error rates
and there are some digits dataset
so you can see that using unlabelled data helps
that's the main point and there are some comparisons which i think i
but effectively
so OK so here you have rigorously square and here you have to pour support
vector machine so support vector machines with laplacian penalty versus support vector machines and he
regularly nicely
versus regularized least squares a lot less in
so if you are first it's interesting to note to the basically support vector machines
and regularized least squares actually work about the same
which is the case in many real applications
now while when you add unlabelled data i think this is roughly ten times more
ten to twenty maybe twenty times more unlabelled data unlabelled data
you get pretty dramatic drops in there
so actually does
this is the same for sphere SVM
and and this is something that comparisons to something
to actually vapnik for support
and again
there are some more comparisons
i would like to ignore the various other things which we can compare but i
think the most important point here to make
events for this support vector machines
using just to label points
and this is
support vector machine
using all points so you you know you in principle you know the labelled of
unlabeled points because the cell standard datasets
so this is using all points
this is using just
and labeled points and this is using labelled plus unlabeled combination
so you can see the three percent this is a this is five so that's
in between here
you actually get a zero if you point however if you don't know them you
get pretty awful right twenty four percent when you add unlabelled data you drop from
twenty four to three percent
you have
the true error rate three
this is readily outside was only inside
that's what the rainbows
so i i you know that if you look at the right there
like for the directions
all of the
all right
here is my shape parameter
i can that all the light through now in the middle
and i'm going to rotate it
now i kill that life
that is convincing proof that light
highly polarized
almost hundred percent
i can do the same here
i let the light through this parameter
this is apparently for the sheet
a direction
order was asian
i rotated very slowly gets darker and darker now
britain dark almost nothing goes through in
you see this
highly polarized also the white light inside there
just below the
white light
we also see that in nature
that light is also
nearly hundred percent polarized because the white light also goes away
from now on
you will always
carry on you
linear form
you simply
cannot go out on the street
without a linear
i always have my wallet
please one million
and whenever you see a rainbow
you take the linear polarizer and you make sure
as per
maybe they will come
that is not polarized in which case
you should call me
right away
i always carry on you
a linear flow
now i come to the third
the way last part that we can
well i like
not by means of reflection but remember i mentioned
fine dust particles
light strikes fine dust particles
it doesn't reflect nice way
but it's getting all directions
it goes off in this direction something this interaction we give them different would recall
that scan
and when
fine dust
can also become
one percent
paul this
do we just the right way
however the light coming from below
later that's where it will come up
beam of light will trade
and dust particles in here
and those the article
next before
which we will use cigarettes much as i hate to smoke
after the war
well the article
and some of the slides
which comes up
changes the direction not as nice as it will do of glass
reflects some of it will go in this direction some in this direction some in
this election some industry and some other countries
some of the world
if this slide
in this way
is scattered over an angle of ninety degrees
that that's not what i just want to show
this four
how can we be sure that you see is getting over ninety degrees well
all of you will almost perfect conditions
because the light comes up like this
and so it goes in this direction
no matter what goes there were there were there were there
the change in direction is almost always no matter where you sit in the
ninety degrees
we follow that goes from this
this that's ninety degrees
this this is like three this is
to all of you are almost in an ideal position
you see that light that was kind of my small part
and it will be polarized
but also circles
that's all
alright like this right in front
all rights like this
a little bit there will be more like this we would this