and if we
o thing i want to make a procedure in which global
they like
that's like right
i don't believe thresholding when the original
so just to our
which she and the police
threshold when
for every
and actually think man
independent from
that's all think
and that is because
depends on the
on the web of because that's the only way and
eleven of this particular age
i'm my just
o thing but not as the global image but also for particular radio
this segmentation
it also
as the act like
but the
and on my on
so much so the that way know
probability distribution of background
these people are
the distribution over
i think and this is the probability distribution of
thank you
is that probabilities
the big the long approach
the pixel belongs
four of the two
peter big two
the probability of the event
because of the way
so the distribution can be described this way in the first democratic just equal to
because of its role in the world i there are a of
dry what
you have some threshold will see
again the
which the
and can this error this area
so output the pixel which actually
has been the level of
then he
but we chat belongs to the
so which at these
these pixels of
time by the
and the thing
you well because of best
because the threshold
but there there's something about that they belong to the
four the architecture so they can be a
i think the bank
and when they belong to
so here is the
background pixels just signed by you take part in the brain
and then
part of
nine there are some things we do
assume that all been level much bigger than you make
and think about
the same
on this
well the parameters if have further
what are you
the royal authority they here it should be from people who live in thank
so human rights this area
i think you might have be
so we have this
dogs are
and our goal is to minimize the error
so i
to minimize
that involves the smallest number flip
that's the correct universal answer to the problem and has an awful complexity scales is
due to the k
two before
sixteen so we have to look at all sixteen hypothesis but there's actually a sneaky
way of getting there
more efficiently
we can find the most probable answer by taking a single diagram
and writing
received one received two
c three c four
c five c six hundred fifty seven
into this diagram and then seeing which circles are happy and which are sad
here we go
right in one one zero zero
just to remind you there's a little secret that's the one we actually clicked but
we don't know that any more
and now we create a green and red and we say which circle the happy
remember the rule is the number of ones in circle has to be even and
circle number one
so there is no no i'm unhappy
which is red
so the number two says i'm unhappy
and second of three thousand one or two i'm happy
what we're doing here is computing a thing called the syndrome is
like talking to the doctor about the things you're feeling at the moment which onto
description of the actual thing that's wrong with you that the signs of the underlying
problem which is maybe some of these bits conflict with certain at least one of
them got because all the circles should have been happy if no flip so definitely
something that happened who was the the troublesome guy well the decoding rule
the decoder says find a single bit lies inside all unhappy circles and outside all
happy circles
and that is this one because it's inside all the red and it's outside all
the green
and then use a conflict that one
and fled the one bit
it has that property
so we do that
and we get one zero
so on this
we solve the problem
in this case we got the right answer
and wonderful homework problem for you to enjoy is to confirm that if you
single bit
where there is one of the source bits in the middle all one of the
parity bits
this code can detect and correct
this decoder
detect clearer
i think that's exciting
what's the probability of error for this seven four
hamming code well it's going to be in trouble in fact as you can confirm
if more than one bit flip because then the decoder is going to detect and
correct single error and you end up with three
failure still occur you end up with s
some believe as not equalling what was it was meant to be this happens
there exists
all or more
so you end up with some errors occurring and another homework problem for use to
work out exactly what the the probability is
of a particular bit
not including
what it ought to be equal
and what you find
as before with the repetition code is since it messes up when there's two or
more errors this is gonna end up scaling as x squared and the constant references
something like nine
that's the probability
and this is very exciting why it exciting as exciting because
it scaling is that square
which is the same scaling there are three had
but we've got a much bigger rate so generate for seven
and their probabilities in the ballpark of s where happens to be nine x squared
a little bit
a little bit bigger three times bigger
his switch to any open markets such as europe or asia
and watch the little thing go up and down and just try to predict try
to predict your brain when it's going to switch
and this is a interesting exercise very interesting i've done this a lot in fact
it's almost obsessive
because it's really what it's really to me with the fluctuations all about that by
stating the daily returns but i call them microtrends little migratory not then something like
and you cannot predict anything you think you know it's true then it doesn't and
why because it does turn up a little bit then that the same way so
what we do
is only one more picture come but have to build up to it
we have to look for signs that look like critical for you see my dream
is to see that there is some
insights and economics based on what we all learn from spending phase transitions
so we want to look for that and to do that we need data and
the data
that tobias price broad
in addition to its brain which is the main thing
was the database of fourteen billion trades
in just one item that one item is the dark future contract
and it's traded so much that in nine months there fourteen million trade was people
literally sit there
and trained this object it's hard to believe that they do do it
betting on horses i can understand betting on this this thing i don't know what
to do it but i was doing it because they think they can make money
so what did they do p now means price which is also the name of
the student price and of this tax futures
you know
this is just an american one second through the data and it goes down it
goes up
and the question is how we can analyse this and since the fluctuations on all
the only thing you have to do first is set some scale i'd like this
you have to say within this window the local maximum this red
and this went the local maximum is redundant so forth and then you could change
the scale later but right now just fix the scale and the growth of maximum
that's which show you now in the real data is not schematic
the time window seventy five takes
and and you see that the maximum to allowed meaning
is maximum rate is minimum and of course in between the local maxima and minima
over there are fewer than seventy five six
so everyone knows this the fluctuations the market can be is just words can be
described as microtrends microtrends trend and down migratory
so nothing new that nothing at all no
now what's new
because you have everything
everything is you everything everything everything so you know if you're on your laptop and
find something more please tell me this is all there is one simple one-dimensional variable
not one of these is gone so i can make fun of him thomas looks
want everything to be motivated
this is what you univariate
and again left because viruses simple-minded but you can if you can get something out
of univariate why do monte verde
and the univariate thing is the time interval between trades
and between trade them between maximum and minimum between individual traits
and there are forty million traces one three thousand so this so this has five
thousand trades so there are five thousand trades in every territory as the time intervals
so there are four thousand nine hundred ninety nine
little points here
and what can we see with our mother's gift mothers give teaches us
that's the time interval between trains
has a dip near these extreme so if you find one of these extreme maybe
it's a good one here is a dip each extreme another little dip and dip
in the time that their trade just like in the cartoon of thomas looks
and and and similarly the vi v
is doing the inverse of that near the near the
the was going you because obviously people are
are buying treats every microsecond or something
and then there is the volume in a given time interval is better
so these are the data the question is what to do so they key observation
is a very naive one
actually i made it is so rare event that i do anything i have to
so what you do is you take all three forces
and take a bayesian average over it and you can do that efficiently in linear
so i mean this from the perspective the best compressor for finite resources and it's
very efficient
OK rods factor five ten flow on computers so
if you it doesn't matter because of the constant but in practice that matters
and that's another reason for the beautiful compressor
so now we have everything
we have a metric is is normalized and
we can compute this approximation let's do something with it
so now instead of having to up bunch of objects
we compute the distance between the PS
so this gives you a similarity metrics
and now we cluster similar objects
there are many ways of doing that
one way is
to construct when the minimum spanning tree
so what
cilibrasi and we tried it it construct the minimum spanning tree but they constructed something
similar which can has into an every internal node
and they use the so-called quartet method
until finding this because it's an NP complete
o point p hard problem
OK so that's the theory
he one application
it took i think it was twenty four members of cell
the to the middle DNA
it is
o thing over the alphabet a c t g
so it's
o thing or
can easily convert to binary string
and then just compressed samples if the bill passes compressed put into formless and compute
these numbers here
what you see on the diagonal
the norm of the brown bear is very similar to the genome of brown bear
the number is very small
it makes sense
well you also see the genome of the gorilla is very similar to the genome
of human
but not as similar as human to human
much similar they're so chimpanzees even more similar to humans
all right
luckily we are not so similar to cow
so you can look at these numbers and they all make sense but it's a
little bit hard you know to get the main picture and also to put the
whole table here because it is
five countries
so if you look at the minimum spanning tree
and then plot the
in way
often done
so if you these memos
and this is the minimum spanning tree
and as you maybe have recognised car is not exactly a memory but they just
put the car into seen what happens and indeed
it falls completely out of this class
and you see you look the whales are together
the BS
i mean best to get this user to their act together and here we have
all the
all the monkeys of the primus
and so you have the australian animals wallaroo huebner plotted course
and that's the together housemouse
it perfectly reconstructed
the phylogenetic tree
we biologists you know
built up
in many many years
without any biological knowledge just using levels of compression
and it with i mean this was sort of postage dictionaries was there for them
to start stimulus came out the classifier the different kinds of biases
i have followed up the work over the turned out to be
correct or not
if biologists have classified them now
OK here's some viruses
and so on
then there and some test examples so they took some
genes of foxes some media music of hendrix some musical work
some classes some ask text summary notes executables
i just want to know that relying on the hard disk
and you get this classification trees so
fox and red together the best together again here than the music
is classified correctly
and the other five types OK i mean of the easy case but still mean
language tree reconstruction
but it is the two sixty languages
some text
they could have taken the bible because that is written in all languages but they
took the
declaration of human rights
it's also written in both languages
the same thing i mean concatenative languages compressed with little four b set
this tree
it's not perfect but pretty good
i mean he appoints afrikaans dutch luxembourgish and german together
finnish and estonian this together
the roman roman languages are mostly together
i think there one or two errors
i mean have
greek letters in greek is missing because
greeks have defined the alphabet
there were some problems
russian i think is that this is russian
should be also
and garin is the wrong place
a job is not here anymore but
i mean hungarian is also special like like finisher they
on i mean except for one or two exceptions
it seems correct
and this is pretty impressive i mean there's no bias towards you know the sort
of application just use some standard compressed
i mean it works if you have a reasonably clear data if you noisy data
levels if not good
you need to compress images incrementally improving so which takes advantage of if it is
compressed the first part then compressible the second part of its movies and you just
use and pick compressing it emits separately
you cannot detect the similarities between movie movie parts so you would need some real
salt intake or so it really is an incremental pictures and nothing has been done
in the
four for comparing images
so that would be interesting to do
but you need incrementally
you can do an ordination of the thirty five i five similarity matrix present into
some two-dimensional space using multidimensional scaling
and now you see someone who of these different well known from which are available
so the fact of millions
and you know the cluster
the four different different variants million which for cluster together
so this shows a distinction between a clustering method and the clustering algorithms that the
approach to doing things the data analysis from is one instance which utilizes the particular
two to implement that and so it's quite interesting gave spectral
make sure all of you for the link and they all seem to be clustered
together in space
perhaps we should look at some empty space try to
and that
empty space
it turns out that you can also do an analysis it is beginning to happen
the the the various clustering methods which have been published there have some underlying links
and it turns out that there are several methods
which can be tied together
in terms of the i can analysis of the data of the similarity matrix so
even though they appear to be
very different but if you're going to be put into how the
what approaches it turns out that they are quite similar
for some events in the cells
in terms of that
but what i like most
it is how do we
evaluate compared algorithms without
without looking at any particular data
but looking at the head and characteristics
and again i must point out the classical papers by fisher this is that most
of the
most of the people working in machine learning are not aware of appeared environments
in nineteen seventy one
and they proposed admissible
thank you
of clustering so this well let's first define some properties in a set of properties
clustering reasonable clustering algorithm must satisfy
right and then find out whether the clustering algorithm is admissible with respect to those
properties not the notion of the admissible if algorithm satisfies the property
fisher in one this proposal about eight to ten different properties
four i thought would be easy to
two to explain here
one is the point proportional
class proportion last mission and one of the
one of these properties so basically
these are the properties that the sensitivity of a clustering algorithm with respect to changes
that not all
essential structure of the
so one simply leave you with monotonic transformation
of the distances between the points
last mission is what happens if we delete one of the clusters
from the data
pakistan essentially remain unchanged
after deleting cluster
the proportion what happens if we
change the number of points increase the number of points in one cluster
relative to the other cluster
o point proportional means
that just increase the number of points in the cluster
and it turns out that
all the clustering algorithm known at that time
did not satisfy
many of these properties
and then you probably are about lindbergh possibility to which
perhaps it works along similar lines
life and he proposed three different
the idea of constraints scale invariance richness
and consistency property
and scale very similar to what we should one is proposed
maybe one of on the to simply say all possible partitions should should be possible
what happens if you improve the
increase the
distances between the clusters and decrease the distances within the cluster
and is impossible to basically said
there is no clustering and it satisfies all of these three
constraints what does it mean it basically says that it's very difficult to come up
with a point
concept clustering and we always make some trade-offs
when we design a clustering but we we don't really understand what and i think
the point is that
we should try to understand what the requirements of the clustering algorithm model what property
this slide for a given domain and then try to choose an algorithm we're design
one based on that
so this is
the summary is that even though we have
very many clustering algorithm hundreds of thousands of the best
clustering algorithm each algorithm implicitly them
explicitly imposes the structure of the
if the match is between the
in having structures you have the most important thing
and the structure of the data from successful otherwise it's not going to be successful
so here are two different
dataset mixture of three gaussians and two half rings
and if i apply it out mixture model with equal to three predefined
actually the three cluster doesn't work very well on this
if i try spectral
how to it doesn't work very well on the mixture of about but it works
very well on this
two half the data
so in spite of these sort of
limitations of clustering algorithms
it is being used have a lot of success in a variety of different applications
and one of the
applications of data compression in this particular case the showing
this is with one hidden layer
and this is with fourteen this
that shows you that adding extra layers help separate helps separate
one to use four letters
and i don't pre training and i do gradient descent actually do worse than when
i use one
one is one
if i use
pre training when he fall as i do better than phase one
that's a very satisfying result if you want to claim the network to better prize
you appreciate
so this is the test error
as a function of how many layers used without pre training
two less is slightly better than one so the results to john john platt tried
this kind of network i tried this kind of network and those were the ones
where you get down to about one point six and they see it
which is a relief
as you add more layers it doesn't really work any better in fact by follows
is worse
whereas with pre training
if you ignore the last data point and things just get better
and if you don't want ignore the last stage point at least you can have
this explains why the brain
three or four
three it is all search
i'm things two problems
the ones that you can't find a good optimum
and the other is that
you could be
the pre training put in good region the search space
which you don't get if you just use the labeled with
it is also used
the reason i guess there are
we were commissioned
it using a kind of gradient descent to model the
structure in the input data right
which normal back provisions in trying to model
so is the fact that using an unconditional density model
that means that you get it
you get much less problem with overfitting
and it also means with very few labels you can do quite well
so you see
on the training set if you try backprop
it's still improving on the validation set when zero tester
so i guess that means the answer is no
this is using a dimensionality reduction technique
model different nets too
so you can take the
function from inputs to outputs that is you can have a whole bunch of test
input vectors
and you look at the output against feature these test input vectors and then concatenate
all those outputs
over the span to test in practice to integrate big vector
and nine great big vector you can say is how this network behaves
this particular network behaves and then you can try training lots of times and see
if you can networks to behave the same way
so you're ignoring
the internal structure saying how to behave as an input device on this set of
which is kind of except
they used a dimensionality reduction technique called need to take a whole bunch of
let's train pure backprop
we start off here
this is after all
one iteration two iterations and so on and you say they'll go off to
slightly different solutions
but this set of solutions has nothing in common with this set is solutions these
are the ones that were trained with
pre training followed by
fine tuning
so really it's finding different part of the space there's no overlap here
so this is probably the most important transparency the slide
shows you how old i am
the whole tutorial i think is why this deep stuff makes sense
and use the technical concept called stuff
the axioms for stuff like it's happens
and the stuff that we don't know that we don't know and all OK so
there's this stuff goes on and stuff creates images
now if you believe the way the world works is the stuff we create images
and images and create labels
so that the label is conditionally independent of the stuff once you see the image
the magic it's like they from better
again it's completely unchanged to all of this is exactly the same as what i
had before
except for this step with
you move you get a new x from the latest y by taking a step
in the negative gradient direction that has to change because we want the wise to
stay inside the set my omega
and in fact this is how it changes you choose the next next to be
the as close as you can get to that point that you would have gone
to any unconstrained case while staying in america
that's really the only change made to the math
on the convergence theory pretty much those side
now what about when you've got not an explicit constraints that make it but you're
trying to minimize f plus ten time some regularisation term
and this was the topic of bellman tutorial this morning it there are lot of
applications like compressed sensing and less so and so on
we've got some smooth objective here
and you got something nonsmooth here but simple like an l one norm
so how do these methods generalize to this case
all the methods of to almost assume smoothness but
so the generalizable to nonsmooth so what do you do in that case well again
a lot of
generalized if you can
explicitly handle the size of the regularisation term if you can deal with that explicitly
they often generalize very easily
so for example
the one where we would move where we just take a short step in the
negative gradient direction
if i can replace that
minimizing this thing
which is you know as close as you can get to that short step
the regularizer exactly as it appears here if this problem is easy to solve
which it is in many cases such as when this is the l one norm
then most of those methods like astros methods
gradient methods and so on generalize immediately the theory can go right through
so the first method for instance
which is one of the ones i had up earlier on
it immediately general in factor analysis and first
just works with this regularize case and if all you care about the unconstrained thinking
just said this to zero in
and it will still work exactly the same
so the bottom line here is that for a lot of unconstrained gradient simple gradient
first order methods
it's often not that big a deal if you want to toss in the regularisation
term or an explicit constraints
so this is the end of the first
and these are a few references we can go for further information i would be
happy to give you more if you
the more is two thousand four book by
nesterov this paper by back into bull actually is the two thousand seven or eight
they've written a review paper which you can get from to bills website which is
a little more self-contained and up date
this an album by polyak which is where the heavy ball
come from it's very beautiful book actually is got conjugate gradient
and and steepest ascent things like that and
this is the barzilai borwein paper that i mentioned and this is
very recent paper by nesterov
OK second part of the talk this is the part where we can't even get
the first derivative
OK so i'm going to talk about stochastic incremental gradient so the setting here is
that i'm going to allow
after being nonsmooth i'm going to assume that
you know i can't
economically get a function that is so i can
gov and test to point to see how good it is
at least i can reliably do that
and i'm going to assume that at any point i've got access to some sort
of estimate of the gradient or subgradient in the case of the non smooth functions
so here's a couple of common problems that fall into this setting
there's one way or objective is actually the
well you've got a function f which depends on your variables x but also on
some random variable and what you're interested in minimizing is the expectation is that of
the random variable
OK so that's your objective facts
related settings where you're fx is actually made up of the sum of objective some
finite size
OK so these were each of these is convex and nonsmooth
now these would ring a bell with a lot of you because SVM
standard SVM setting has this for primal SVM
typically has some sort of regularizer here one norm and two norm squared and then
has this loss function which is made up of the sum of losses over each
piece of data
in the training in the training set
so for instance in linear SVM this loss function l might have this form
the variable might be w
a new loss function is a function of w transpose the feature vectors
and the classifier and the label while k
another very closely related cases logistic regression where the loss functions of some of these
log functions and the regularizer might be one of
so this is something that obviously
the setting obviously fits well in machine learning
OK just mention here of terminology and notation since i'm now dealing more explicitly with
nonsmooth functions i have to talk about subgradients i've got a picture subgradients here this
is mine on the graph of my nonsmooth f
you can see that it's mostly smooth except at this point he was the king
so at that can i can define a bunch of supporting hyperplanes in because this
is the one the function hyperplanes just winds and they just plain kind of libel
of the graph of the function
the slopes of each of these lines would be an element of the subgradient OK
so this upgrade in this case would be an interval on the real line
so in general subgradient is some sort of a convex set
we we can still talk about strong convexity when i was dealing with smooth functions
mu is the lower bound on the i can values of passion
i can still even though the hashing doesn't exist because they don't even have a
great the nonsmooth case i can still talk about
modulus of convexity mu and i can still have a relationship that looks like a
lower down on the second order taylor series
OK so classical stochastic approximation for stochastic gradient descent method
what a shame here is that i've got access at any point x got access
to this thing big effects inside
which is some estimate of the gradient of this gradient or subgradient
x OK so you can get there by sampling site from that distribution with that
points and all this is happening in the feature space so we have a new
point we map that new point also in the feature space and now we
want to classify it somehowso let's say the new points are bold-faced points on
vectors in in my feature space in the reproducing kernel hilbert space I want
to classify this new points somehow and the simplest way of doing this might be just
to say I'll assign it to the class whose class mean is closest so I'll compute the mean
of the positive class so let's say this is a number of positive points compute the mean
of the negative class actually this shouldprobablysay C plus and C minus here not c
two and c one and i'll just check which of the two is closer and
there's different ways of checking that for instance I could say I'll compute this vector
Wand I'll compute this vector X minus C where C is the midpoint between the
two classes between the two class means and then I'll check whether the angling close by
by these two is is larger than ninety degrees or smaller than ninety degrees
which I can check at by looking at the cosine of the angle whether cosine
is positive or negative and the cosine in turn I just compute by taking the dot product
so that's nice because I like to do everything in terms with dot products because we
want to work using kernels we don't want to explicitly map into that space so
that's one way of doing it the other way of doing it would
be just to compute the distance square distance between X and this center and the square distance
is between X and this center that's an exercise that maybe we shouldn't do now
in the interest of time but you could you should try it sometime you compute
these two squared distances take the difference between the two and then check whether
that difference is positive or negative so that will be our decision function if one of
them is larger than the other one we will assign the point to the other
class and vice versa so if we do that it's just a few lines of
algebra then we end up of course everything will nicely combine into dot products so
all this dot products will then be replaced by kernel functions and it turns out we then
get a decision function which consists of an expansion in terms of all
the positive points so the points with positive labels divided by the number of positive points
until all the negative points divided by the number again and here we have some
constant that doesn't depend on the test point X so let's not think about this
constant for a second but uh what I want to say is that uh you can
think of this as a density estimation based classified because in the case where
for instance we use a gaussian kernel here let's say we use a gaussian kernel
that's normalized to have ones so this is the density model and
then we're just putting such a gaussian on each positive training point we divide by
the number of these points that's what's called a parzen windows density estimate in statistics
of the positive class here we have corresponding parzen windows extensive estimate of the negative class
here's a constant so roughly speaking I mean i don't go into details on the content and so on
roughly speaking we have these density estimates and we check whether the probability of the point
X is is higher under this density model or higher under this density model
so we're looking roughly speaking whether it's more likely that the point comes from the
one class or the other class and we arrive at this with this purely geometric
point of view so it's just simply looking whether we're closer to the one mean or to the
other mean so these means are kind of interesting and we will return to the
means in a minute before that I just want to briefly show you we will
come back to support vector machines a little later but just to give you the
first idea so a support vector machine is almost the same as what I just showed you alright it's
almost the same so it also computes hyperplane in some other space remember this decision rule
that I told you about in the last slide so you have a mean of
one class and a mean of the other class and you're checking whether you're closer to here or to here
these induces a decision boundary that's a hyperplane support vector machine also a
which with hyperplanes only that these hyperplanes are a bit different for the hyperplane that's
orthogonal to the vector connecting the class means here now we
now will use a hyperplane that maximizes this margin of separation between the classes we'll
get back to that in a minute but it's also between the feature space and
then this would correspond to a non-linear decision rule in the input space and also
if you look how how the decision rule looks it will also be a kernel
expansion like before so it will be this sign of a kernel expansion and some constant
and the difference now is in the previous case the kernel expansion was almost trivial
because all the weights were uniformed so all positive points had the same weight and
negative points had also the same weight with the negative class as we didn't
have to do any training ce could directly write down the solution in the
case of support vector machines it turnes out we have to do some training to find
these lambda Is but the advantage will be that typically many of these lambda Is
will become zero okay and if you now choose different kernel functions here this means
that you choosing different kinds of mapping into the upper space and therefore how
what do you do want to say
what exactly was in your mind
and he was the one giving cos those tools
to analyse and criticize
getting the arguments back
and in english it's much better than slovenian because argument
it's not only you know the proof
but it's also a conflict
and that's what happened when you expect people to defend themselves
later said writer on
i realize that is three four
it's three quarters of all know
three out of four conversations that so what does was running
given no constructive results
that's how it is in our meetings as well isn't it
because we also read the very
so much
let's have another idea that was to follow
you know with this idea that
the truth
is he
and we have to find it
in that case trolls
is only one
if only
one truth exists
who owns it
was the order of it
if god exists
it's my
i am right
which means you
are not
that's how we think
i'm right and you're wrong
whenever my mother says
this is how you should make it you can
that means that she wrote later to much
now that's what i think i think i'm the the only one who has possession
to have
and then there is there is totally
you know making everything into categories
this is the table this is not the table this is the chair this is
not the chair everything should be know like this and if i see the
aristotle is in problems
because it's not in the categories in this black and this is what
and this is life
it's something in between
and but you know
from politics
left and the right
no blacks and the rats
this is our team this is the others we are right there on and we
will prove them
how constructive is it
going nowhere
maybe slovenia going backwards
not helpful at all
we can't have it like this
sheet of the ocean OK OK
to leave behind the time
what happens is that you know
with church
after the greeks after romance
the black the black h the dark ages k so that are
the euro was actually illiterate
charles the great united europe for awhile was an illiterate man
where was all the knowledge where was all the reading
you know that in one thousand years of dark ages there was only three percent
of course
of national product
in one thousand years
let's hope of activities
it was all happening in charge actually all the reading was happening in church
and they actually do this tools of greek thinking
which is easy for them because they have the dopamine
it's fixed position
you know like six position
this is
half litre
we all agreed upon it we can't fight about this is half litre
but we can already fight
whether this water is called
or war
but is my perception
i think it's war
you think it's called
and then we fight
most of our thinking mistakes of perceptual thinking
with the and
i think something is like this you think it's like that and then we find
out about it
but what we should do is to accept it
we are so used because of size because of charge because of greek
probability theory that are called extension theorems of projective limit theorems which guarantee that this is actually the case
the idea is
you have a one-to-one correspondence between
singer infinite dimensional distribution
an infinite family of
finite-dimensional distributions
all right you need some
you have to be careful with these kind of
results because we need some you have to do some extra work
to make sure that what you sample from that
is actually a continuous function can you know this defines
using this differ gives a distribution on functions
but you would like to have more than that you would like to have continuous
the continuity property and that's a bit harder
but i cannot tell u
how to do that without starting to talk about things like topology and i think
you will be all glad i don't do so
have avoided
this is a warning
but basically be deum
the idea is you can define a stochastic process so
the probability distribution on
infinite objective are infinite dimensional objects
means of family by all its finite-dimensional marginals
that is the basic the basic idea
well the gas in process is the distribution the definition that we always use or
the construction think of this as a construction
that we always use
and i said
before that we have this problem that we don't have density representations for these models
now this year is a representation
it's not a density is not as nicely
we are not able to write it down as nicely as the density but this
is a representation of an infinite dimensional distribution
and this is in fact this kind of these kind of results are the most
generally applicable substitutes we have
so far density representations
on stochastic processes
okay now can we do something similar other directly process
yes we can actually
so we can
yesterday i showed you this this nice
simple a constructive definition of the iterative process which
which tells us simply how to sample
this discrete random error piece by piece
but we can use a similar construction as was the other girls process
in the gaussianprocess case we have constructed a random function theta
and now
theta is a random measure so
i called you again right because it plays the same role but it's it's this
random measure and random discrete measure remember the some
over the weighted sum over classifications
all right so now
the the corresponding results
to this construction of the girls and processes this we have to find in the gaussianprocess case
in the gaussianprocess case what we did we looked at marginals and how did we
get the marginals we chose points down here and then restricted ourselves to these points
four probability measures it's not really very helpful
because they are not
you know that that they are functions on sets right so
this this year this random function is a function on points but probability measure is a function sets
or put differently
for most probable like say continuous probability measures you put it in a single point
the probability is always zero right for gasses
so that's not very helpful
so what we do instead is to get the marginals we don't use points we use sets
and once again we want from the marginals to be finite-dimensional so we choose a finite number of sets
and we choose sets which partition our space imagine that this square here are the rectangular either
it's space on which we would like to put process or some other random
now what do we do we partition it into a finite number of sets which
i have called it one two three and so on you
so we can write these sets into a vector
together they from the whole space and now we take our random
a random probability measure
and we evaluated on each of these sets
so just as before we took a random function reflecting the point
now we take a random probability
and we say how much probability doesn't put on set one on saturday to and
so on and that gives us a vector
which properties well vector have well it's finite
all these entries you probability so there are all between zero and one
and they will sum up to one because these sets together form the entire space
so that's now are analog of
what we did before so
the intuition that john mentioned this morning is
think of
take a vector and think of estimates vector larger and larger it becomes something like
function right the infinite limit becomes the vector becomes a function
this seriously analog of that we have a finite
probability distribution now we make these this partition into sets we make that finer and
finer makes a set smaller and smaller
you get a larger and larger vector and that you can roughly think of that
is converging to a probability measure
all right
once again if we know
model so the
the expansion coefficients of the
of whatever the basis happens to be
so we want the joint probability
more or less everything is associated with the model so that the probability of
target values
the model parameters given unknowns and
as mikhail sure this graphical models we can read we can we can decompose this
and a number of ways
using those expressions
we can invent those probabilities to obtain
the probability of our
the model parameters given the data and everything else that we know as a function
the likelihood
this probability here which we'll talk about shortly and then this here which is the
marginal probabilities in other words we've taken the likelihood and this prior probability and integrated
over this piece of
values of the support that
as given for
those coefficients
so the only thing then it's really new
is this
distribution here
the prior distribution that's just talk about this a but then
so in the bayesian traditions
the prior probability is the
i the distribution of probability mass
that you
i sign
two your parameters
before you have observed in the data
and so it basically
encapsulates the core defies any prior assumptions of prior says that you half approach model
and this is something that we can
we can say in any way that we choose we can either demonstrate a complete
all of the sort of complexity of our model of the distribution of the parameters
of our model or we may actually have some some idea of what the
the overall distribution is going to be an again you can we can quantify the
and this prior distribution
we met the likelihood before
so that's all fine
no the posterior
of course is obtained
after observing of data
in in this case here
we have
just said that the prior distribution on the weights the coefficients of our
basis functions is independent
clearly of x but is also independent of sigma no
a more realistic modeling situation we would actually probably put a prior distribution jointly on
w and then sigma
but at the moment we are as i said we just assuming that this is
determined and we know what that is
this term here the marginal likelihood as i said is just obtained by integrating over
the support
of the
the the weights and it's it's weighted by the prior probability
and this is
in many interesting models this this is just a measure of great importance but one
which is far from
straightforward to obtain
OK so
i guess this is again some schoolboy
let's just remember that the posterior
is basically the likelihood weighted by the ratio of the priors
and the
overall likelihood of the data of the marginal likelihood
and that
that little formula
apparently it's just about the was in machine learning more or less
so if you remember that you don't remember anything else is
you've learned something right
let's get onto this prior
now as i said we are perfectly free
so we get
OK so
so state of this for a few seconds
a very common form
the unknown voltage
is equal to the stuff on on the right-hand side
the stuff on the right-hand side
i multiplying the source voltage v
and some of the multiplying the
current i
OK and
if i to put distance of the symbolic forms
my unknown or voltage is something
constantine of e one
some constantine
is of the form constantine's
the source current constantine the
source voltage and so on
the other units is these different because here
in this case
and it has no units because these voltage so is e
in this case is b has units of resistance
OK so that the times i give me a voltage
standard this equation for a few seconds
and this should help us build up some insight that will allow us to write
the answer almost by inspection
OK i'm going show you method now
in a few minutes which would allow you to write down the and so you
just by staring at that so could not have to go through node equations one
and the more and more about that issue the more you will be able to
do a lot of this completely by yourself
in this particular example simple circuits but these methods would be particularly useful when you
have more complicated situations
before i go on the media
spend a few minutes pontificating on
so that's a linear circuit and this equation
is made on one or more pitch e
as a linear sum of source voltages and source currents
implies two properties
the property
and also give rise to the properties of the position
let's two hundred eighty first
so what it says
if the circuit
some circuit
i feel some sort of inputs
let's say the output is as
if you're feeling hungry think of these as
apples and the circuit converts them into applesauce
so what i we he says
is that
what i can do
is if i take to my apples
and in the feeding into apple
or if i give it three quarters of an apple
so multiply
all my input by some constant alpha
three quarters
what that says is that the outputs of getting one full model of applesauce and
we get
three quarters of the model that was source
OK so if i proportionally reduced all the inputs and this is a linear circuit
then social my output it using the same
and what
next let's let's look at super position
the values of position said the following
synchronous circuit
few apples
and they get
apple sauce
i think the same circuit
and this terminology for feed the circuit in a different set of inputs
this is very
and let's say
my output of it this way
so output i get blueberry sauce such exist
sample that doesn't really give very sparse
what i want to get if i mixed up the two
so let's take my circuit the same circuit
that's the say that the effective charge is growing as a function of distance just
so we have this charge it's building up and building up
and of course that's a runaway process because the things that make the charger interns
quarks and gluons virtual quarks and gluons they generate their own fields and so we
have the charts building up and building up and making a sort of away
so we have charges of course then we have fields associated with that and fields
have energy
so we're building up the configuration from our little tiny seed that carries more and
more energy we go to larger and larger distances
and in fact it's runaway process is nothing to stop it so the energy just
becomes infinite
that would provoke
a severe energy crisis
the feed single quark
and if it really happen that way
it would be very dangerous to turn on the machine like lap
but mother nature has a way of solving that problem
that's more parsimonious
that is
instead of building up this enormous clout this enormous thunderclouds just as if you in
the weather if you try to build up an enormous thunderclouds starts to discharge because
it's cheaper
to to discharge the iron spring positive and negative charges together
no the nature's response to trying to put a cork in empty space by itself
is to produce
quark antiquark pair sparks if you like
i have one of those and i quarks with the opposite charge sit right on
the charge
if it if it's right on top of the original work that you put in
that we can cancel of the field entirely
so that's the way you could get rid of all the energy of this
however there is a price to be paid
in quantum mechanics
it costs energy to localize particles
so to localize charged particles have wave character and if you try to localize the
position very precisely
the waves don't want to do that and that caused a lot of energy to
if you try to put it that i quark
right on top of the court to cancel its charge
that would be persist very infinitely precise localisation that will also cause an infinite amount
of energy
one way to think about this is in terms of heisenberg's uncertainty principle
if you try to localize something within a given positional uncertainty its momentum gets correspondingly
and of course momentum transfer large momentum transfers into
corresponds to large energy so it costs energy to localize particles according to heisenberg's uncertainty
so there's competition
this is on the one hand
to discharge this thunder cloud of growing effective charge and fields
you want to
cancel off
charge of the quark
go on
on the other hand if you try to cancel off exactly this the price to
be paid
so there has to be some sort of compromise
and in fact there are many many scores stable part compromises
this may be reminiscent to you
if you thought about the hydrogen atom and how it gets stable in quantum mechanics
the way the hydrogen atom gets stable in quantum mechanics is
you have
the coulomb field of the proton which has a lot of field energy
and you have an electron electron electron around it would like to sit right on
top of the proton ideally to get rid of all that energy quantum mechanics was
invented in fact in some ways
keep it from doing that and it is precisely this way
in this way that you get stable hydrogen atoms and in fact there are number
of stable compromises and those are the different energy levels of hydrogen
similarly here
we can have different sorts of compromises
those are different stable compromises of ways of putting quarks and antique works together or
it turns out you can also neutralize the charge by having three quarks
and these different stable patterns of equilibrium these differences
compromises are what makes protons neutrons and the other strongly interacting particles
when einstein learned about wars theory of hydrogen he equal the highest form of musicality
in the sphere of thought
let me remind you that bores original theory was
sort of the solar system and i presume he was
harking back to have kept his idea of music of the spheres
he never accepted it but real quantum mechanics is much more musical
real quantum mechanics uses the mathematics of musical instruments vibrating waves in stationary wave patterns
the mathematics of QCD
the mathematics of chords because we have three different colors or oscillating at the same
anyway these different stable patterns which if we could visualize them with look extraordinarily intricate
and beautiful
are nothing but the different particles
these different to
compromises between localisation energy
course from quantum mechanics and
field builds up
color field
college color charge
now because each of these compromises is not perfect
doesn't cancel field energy exactly
four and doesn't have zero quantum mechanical energy each one has some characteristic energy
einstein second law tells us then
through m equals the divided by c squared that have the corresponding mass even if
the underlying stuff the quarks and gluons had no mess to begin with
that's the origin of mass
as martha stewart might say it's a good thing
to get rid of mass
because removing it enhances the symmetry of our equation
already discussed feel
the gluons absolutely have to have zero mass to ensure the underlying symmetry gauge their
symmetry of QCD
removing the and quite masses also gives
as in QCD light enhances the symmetry of that theory
it gives us the so-called chiral theory
and more generally and i theories of physics and the standard model we understand things
much much better if necessary here
mass is somewhat of an embarrassment so the fact that we can and should do
bed times this term t minus to so if you're role that's
then you effectively get a big sum of terms
where the the weight is decreasing exponentially fast
so that's why i on yes
so the question is i guess why summing the gradients is that of
average sorry why averaging great is then summing
and his relationship between using mini-batches and the optimal
learning rate so so average motivation is to think of it as you're
trying to get an estimate of the expected gradient on the training
distribution so it's just a monte-carlo estimate essentially
and indeed if you have more examples mini-batch can think that
your gradient is more accurate there's as variance in your estimate
so you might be able to move faster so be
maybe able to make faster or bigger steps
and there's probably you can probably construct cases where
you can sort of make a recommendation as to what is the
relationship between a multiplier on the learning rate in
the number of examples i i i actually not sure what it is but
ok i'm going move on yeah for the interest of time
because i know enclosed finishing so
there are other more sophisticated optimizes out there
that you might read up in papers and that can also help you
if you have you know neural net that seems to be harder to optimize
one is adagrad so thickly all these you is using a form of adaptive
learning rate that is for each parameter
effectively have their own learning rate that is changing during
training so one so adagrad the way it's scales different learning
rate so here instead of showing that scaling the learning rate i'm
just going to scale the gradient ok but that's the same thing
and in this case adagrad would you do you compute
the cumulative sum of the square of the gradient
on your parameters so this is this squares done element wise over
this gradient vector and so what i just do is i keep this gamma
variable where in which i accumulate the square of the gradient
on my parameters and then what i do that my a
descent direction i will divided element-wise by the square
root element-wise over this gamma term
thus maps just to make sure that this term
for numerical stability in case this term is too small
so in this case because you keep summing positive terms because
these are squared the learning rate is always decreasing
that graham for a convex optimization problem that's
fine yeah if it's non-convex can construct cases where if you
learning rate decreases to much eventually might read something like
a slight plateau and in that case you might want to actually increase
the learning rate so it might make more sense to use something
like this prop which is instead of using derivative some it's
exponential moving average fuzzy this is more like a moving
average because you always have like an average between this term
and that term but anyways there's exponentially decreasing
contribution of the squared gradient terms
in this case here so it could be that in this this term here is
not selly i'm always decreasing with steps as
with the number of steps and then finally one that's quite popular
right now as adam you can look it up if you want a full description
in short it's rmsprop with some momentum term
and it seems to work pretty well like some people just only use
this instead of some you know manual schedule over the learning
rate and momentum and i wouldn't re-size making
absolute claims about which one is better
if you're a situation feel like you're not the model doesn't seem
to be training well changing the optimizers def something to consider
so and funny just about debugging so imagine you've implemented
neural net it's a new type of neural nets unit
you know you've implemented some of the backprop yourself some
of the gradients for thing you should do
the only at test whether you're computations of the gradients are
correct one way to do that is with find a difference
approximation comparing that with your computer gradients
geographical are so landscape and no
topics which are more
relevant or events are have been more documents inside it would be represented mountains higher
well the less relevant topics would be smaller smaller mountains here c
is the biggest mountain is
this one
which is described with
typical keywords so this would be israel israeli-palestinian so three three keywords which would
corresponds roughly to this topic well it's a here would be
actions you gonna or chania
this is still
what's most this was the war in bosnia at the time and so on and
you can
various topics
there are going see live demo of
somewhat improved version of so this is one typical example where you see
each document here
which you can see exactly but each document is one dots one
but in this map
and it's a document is basically presented in two two dimensions although the document itself
in original form is presented in much higher dimensional space maybe ten or hundred dollars
again very classical example
from the literature would be
this picture which was most probably was made manually are most mostly manually so this
is analysis of
fidel castro speeches from december nineteen sixty two
june sixteen one
and it's
betty castor was known to
or that he was not able to heights much
five of political guys from the time i think they all improvising mostly and of
course if he was met then this obviously his speech was also
he expressed his madness in one of the other way
and if you analyse this speeches then you will they so what he thought this
so this is the time period of this
crisis this rocket crisis in cuba
and you can see
how different words
we are different topics were present in particular
moments of time and by the smallest u
one from the american and
able to to reconstruct basically what's going on in the head of costs
later on again would see this time time analysis of texts in a little bit
different form
next musician which i can show i think life is going to com this physician
results this is again the same pattern
nobody's going to
it's not OK
it's a
this image is
search query
and so what
the system does it it's kind of metasearch engine
it issues this query two
one or several other search engines collect the results
it's a
class that performs clustering kind of published results in an visualizes
these different concepts
so this would be the main keywords words which appear as part of
and this would be
well the main concepts like
book hotel travel
time well it might not be
relevant or maybe a generic
what would be
so the
well they deserve
all this generic stuff
try that's fine
that's our collaborators OK what this
keyword that networks and collaborative
training consists of
you can you
when and and now if the click
european then OK
twenty two
and then you get slightly different so this is all automatically generated
sort of two-dimensional graph
of the terms which were found in
you know results which we
bishop that the
search engine produced sometimes
it can be quite informative sometimes not too much
you can recognise some some terms but
but we are showing this is an example of visualisation of search results
searchpoint so this is
one of them which we our guys produced
and it's again similar type for
musician accepted the idea is slightly different
so this looks like
the search but it's not just the muscor google search so now if we
five no
it is a key or some such query past
four search and then we get classical google results as
and this is guaranteed to converge number in a finite number
that is called a column generation one cutting plane
i think alex smola about it
this is but
i would like to use this to have to ship short one is shogun toolbox
machine learning toolbox implements most of the string kernels and also
includes like
implementations of thirty different kernels
which are based on a mission to the on the efficient string data structures which
are described can handle different data types can i think there seven different implementations in
that can just used from mid level take what i think are written in c
and t plus but you can use it for any of these programming languages for
interface functions to it
and it's available under GPL license
other advertisements so if you're self interested in writing open source of than this
special topic in JMLR might be interesting to you so it has started just a
few weeks ago
c'mon now supports open source
the open source movement and they are are going to have an open source
special topics so we can submit papers which are just all pages which are description
of software package
this could be like implementations of machine learning algorithms for machine learning toolboxes the sherwood
or languages
so and you find this information here
OK so
it's not
main topics
so you don't you know i'm going many going to talk about the applications
so this one is going to to be an alignment where we use structured output
learning for
coming up with a better alignment
on the
OK so this is a joint venture with two the students of mind changes when
i posted
OK so the most abundant kind of data which we have computational biology are seeking
so and that the genomic sequences but we also have a sequence parts of them
on so
called used t expressed sequence tags so this is usually just a small part of
an so you know from within a the transcription and then employ explain
used is are small facet of the model
now given these MRI can now
tried to make peace on its back to within
to try to find out where the exons the
we try to reconstruct these get here
so we can do this
in order to discover new genes so because we have sequences of on a story
by mapping back we can find new genes
we can use
we can find the exonintron boundaries you can find alternative splicing in several variants of
and sometimes you also used for finding affordable
the problems are that sometimes the genomic sequence is not unique so there might be
several places where people on a committee
then of course you decide where we would like to align so then they are
far looks easily duplicated genes or
pseudo genes which aren't active anymore and you have you know
and of course that sequencing errors polymorphism select changes in the genome and there are
some rare cases of canonical life science and another problem in x i really really
short just like five nokia something that it's really hard to unambiguously match behind these
and i'm going to talk about this a bit later
so the problem is given
there has been
get more than ten years of research on how to do this kind of alignments
and i just want to mention a few of the approaches here some of them
are just really likes him for blocked use kind
c algorithms so they start off looking for all substrings what certain substring of a
certain length and up in the morning try to find it in the DNA
and once we find a match which is long and they tried to extend the
and come up with some aligned
this is like you like
but there are few other
so the problem with these tools is that we usually only look at the the
alignment i mean
how good the sequence is actually found in between
and what we would like to do is we would like to integrate additional information
information about splicing into these line
OK because you know
not only the secret
but also that my side and at the boundary between exonintron so those should also
be showing us here
so there some additional information and use it for line
so users by science we also used some
link model for the entrance entrance should have the
and we impose this using structured output learning somewhat principle combination of these different sources
of information
OK so i talked about this two class sort mission use the machines but this
and so how can we use this kind of information that we first describe typical
i mean the typical alignment
so you usually have to stick it
so in our case is the DNA sequence and use to the east i think
this part of mind
so we have some kind of substitution matrix
there the score for every pair of looking up to him
in alignment is essentially
sequence alignment sequence of here
of let
o which comes from fifteen and from the east
OK so you can just
we have two sequences a eighty
a and
a g a then maybe he
he so you see this
this built up here
this another here
this is here but it's not matching
so we use the
metrics and
the score of can
and you see this actually matters
so actually there to get in between
and with these gaps we also scoring
thank you very much and thank all of you coming on as he sat on
my Culver with Amazon Web Services and act before argued started
1st full apologies that I cannot speak English but up before it started how many
people in the room had heard of Amazon Web Services before they heard about this
updates coming you tried
but now that's that's about what they so what I'm going to do it this
sounds agreeable to everybody is amended kind of divide this talk into 3 parts
I'm going to start by talking a little bit about what it means to be
successful as a start-up because there's a lot told me that there's a number of
books and this
community that are thinking about start up the kinds of things but even if you're
not thinking about being a software start-up but it's still a really good way to
look at it at a project Oregon 0 what is some of the scaling issues
that I'm going to talk about it talk about being successful I think applied always
I'm going to spend a little bit of time just kind of talking about some
but not all of our Web services and then finally I'd like to end with
water to gambles that I guess the big when I want shows how to set
Our virtual server environment but it also showed a more rounded database of somebody wants
to see that this under
but so before actually start on any of this
I always start
explaining who were not the result of 3 parts that Amazon is you can see
a clear of and I think most people know what our 0 . com partly
on online retail business is you can see I know we've been there for a
while and I don't need to say much about that because I think most of
us know about that
we also have a merchant business and the merchant businesses sort of divided into 2
parts on 1 hand we run high scale websites for other companies that would like
to adjust outsourced the the problem in the issues around Gardena Heiskell website so for
example in the UK Marks & Spencer 1st website we run
the other half of them
line of business are vendors who sell through the Amazon platform sold for example
if you were to go to Amazon . com and orders for example and although
park or you know something like that chances are high that it would your order
would be filled by 1 of these other merchant partners
and then would have a technology business and that's the part that I am here
to talk about
this is the essentially making available to software developers a set of salt Web services
that with the Web services come operational best practices because of Amazon's operating with services
in the same operational best practices in the same principles although not directly always the
same software that runs on Amazon . com
so we believe that there is a high
among demand out there in the market for it
1 of the the things that makes me say that as you can see we
got over 3 130 thousand software developers who who've already registered to use Amazon Web
Services so I believe that the young people are paying attention in Salfordville Persia using
our act also want say before move off of the slide that everything I'm talking
about this afternoon
it is designed for it a platform EPI Web service API
designed for software developers or somebody who's technical at any rate like in case of
a server that we stepped in Doha run server it's not designed for an end
and it's not designed for a non-technical business persons were really looking to all of
you to build solutions on top of the platform it if it's going to be
ready for someone it that's an inducer
or software array of business use
so far
just before I came across a came over to this session I shot some screen
shots and when we explain what we have here so
the 1st shot here is a years
sliding window of elite PG used for BBC that Kodak that came in the reason
I'm using this is what I'm trying to do
In establish a baseline for really high-volume website
it on
so on the x-axis here we have a three-year sliding window
and so on
yesterday according to this it's essential 3rd
and at the Y axis is really please use per million delivered a top of
the Texas
is 3 thousand page views per million Internet users now these steps were measured by
a but that time which is a subsidiary of Amazon's but I'm not using it
did not using these steps because Amazon owns them using them because they have about
300 terabytes of Web Kroll information that I was able to plot graph against now
my assertion that if I must start or if I can get some idea of
reusable this line whether it's over here or whether it's over there as long as
I'm making money along the way I probably have a successful business
so let's look at what this means to what this looks like some other sites
In his 1st when his flicker
so you know this is you can see the fairly successful they started off back
here in 2004 2005 as just an idea and along the way you know they're
all BBC's page you numbers and think that they're doing quite well I think this
is probably young but I'm not certain
and I
saying that I know anything about our special about flickers operations I because I don't
but I do think
that I would not want to to be the guy in operations and feature that
liquor because this is the dark side of success you there's always something to you
when you have an inflection point like that
you know that there's something that went wrong you don't know what it will be
an advance unfortunately you don't know when that day will come but that it that
it was only after about them is that had a week's worth but
it's important to know how things really happened so then what happens is
the bacteria
are separated from these particles and it turns out these particles are the viral particles
are much lighter much less dense than the bacteria so how do we separate the
centrifuge them we centrifuge them bacterial particles are there up in the super may turn
out to be are age caps eds
and now what we do
we take this stuff we measure the radioactivity
in the super latent
that is the material that
stays above and we measure the radioactivity
in the palate
and what we end up seeing
whereas most of the
p thirty two what shows up in the palace
mostly p thirty two
it shows up in the palace
is there no s thirty five in the palace
you know in the textbooks story of course there's no s thirty five was they
want to be nice and clean but in reality there's going to be some
s thirty five
it was you know
less than one percent
o VS thirty five
ends up in the hell
most of the s thirty five
stays up here in the supernova
there's all the phosphorus going
and of course some of the viruses that even attach and everything is and so
the story that the phosphorus up in super names but the striking thing is that
the palace primarily has gotten the radioactive phosphorus not reactive sulfur sulfur and therefore we
can conclude that what
well more DNA went in
and protein
we therefore entitled to include the DNA is the hereditary material
i mean i suppose that one percent sulphur
is tracking one minor protein that is the secret
you can it's very hard to rule out there is no contaminants travelling along with
the DNA and if you really truly disbelieve DNA you could be churlish and say
well i just don't believe that that you've sold purified it you can completely rule
out that some minor protein component is really conferring credit
in fact we really look closely
every mccarty mccloud biochemistry i believe
i was pure
then the purity of this experiment
by this point thinking it began to shift toward
DNA being reasonable hereditary molecule in addition it was the second line of the proof
different from this from the number carcass
using a different system both pointing to the same answer and the intellectual tied shifted
to recognising that this probably was right and the reason these experiments were pointing to
DNA was DNA had to be the right answer
but of course how is the right answer
what was it about DNA that could confer these properties
this was still unclear in nineteen fifty three but not that long
it became clarified
relatively soon thereafter
and of course it became clarified
the understanding
of DNA structure
the double helix
nobody here has not heard of the double helix probably is nobody
you know grown-up up it doesn't have the double helix and all that but nonetheless
i want to stop and take a little bit about also al-samoud personal this is
this is the first year of talked this class after
the first time after this class when
crick and watson not both the lines of you may know the francis crick died
just this this past summer
which is very sad is an incredible person
but actually you know as i've said mendel was one of my heroes francis crick
was also one of my this is just an extraordinary person but jim watson is
still alive and kicking and still quite active and so in any case you're not
far removed so i tell you a little bit about this stuff is history but
this this history i'm telling you about these people are for the most part francis's
passing notwithstanding alive and kicking jim watson is still quite actually mccarty is still it's
really anyway so nineteen
fifty three
just a year later jim watson
and francis crick
are working in england
watson is a is a
student from indiana former waterfall just had his interest in ornithology originally and then studied
more biology came to england as he wanted to study the gene francis crick physicists
density plus three-times the pressure is negative so this factor is negative canceling that sign
to given an overall an acceleration and this requires a fluid but the an equation of
statepover rho smaller than one-third and one possibility for that is an equation
of state of vacuum energy which is p equals minus rho or
W equal to minusoneso the idea behind the inflation is that there is some field that
we will introduce call the inflaton field which dominates the energy density during inflation then we`ll be quantum
fluctuations during inflation which produce perturbations in the inflaton field which in turn
produce perturbations and the temperatureandenergy density then the field travels outside the landscale
travels outside the Hubble radius eventually to come back in the hubble radius where we observe density perturbations
and temperatureperturbationsthat are related to theperturbationsin the inflaton field
produced by quantum effects
soh barthe action of quanta will play a role in generating the large-scale
perturbationsin the universe now the idea of the quantum world having something to do with
these perturbations is related to the creation of particles in the expanding universe this is
not a particularly new idea that the expansion of the universe leads to particle creation
but in fact it was discovered bythe earliest particle cosmologistSchrdingerin the min
Schrdingerdid some something of importance in the nineteen twenties but in the nineteen thirties
his interest turn to cosmology he was influenced by Eddington and Lemaitre
and there was a very interesting paper written by Schrdinger over the period of nineteen thirty-eight to nineteen thirty-nine
this was alsoa verytumultuous time in the life ofSchrdinger in nineteen thirty-eight he was
a professor in Austria at the University of Graz and then when there was the
annexation of Austriahehad to leaveAustriabecause of his political writings and his political
statements andhe snuckout of Austria and went to Rome there`s some interesting correspondence
in the University of Chicagoarchives betweenfermi andSchrdinger when Schrdingergot off of a train
in Rome he was met by Fermi Schrdingerof course could not take any money with him
so Fermi lent him a couple of thousand lira and then in the early nineteen fifties as a long series
of calculations that Fermi andSchrdingerwere doing trying to convert a thousand pre-war lira
into dollars in nineteen fifties Fermi never did get repaid so he went to the vatican to find asylum
in the vatican and those of you who know something about the
personality ofSchrdinger realise that the cloistered life of the vatican was not an ideal place forSchrdingerto live
so he decided in nineteen thirty-nine it would be a very safe bet to move to belgium
and then of coursea life before the outbreak of the second World War he
realized that this wasn't so safe so he found his way to dublin
soduringthis periodSchrdinger wrote a paper called proper vibrations of the expanding universe this
is a paper that`sremarkable to me and not very well appreciated today
In the introduction to this paperSchrdinger wrote that proper vibrations by which he meant the positive
and negative terms to field theory e to the plus or minus I
omega t cannot be rigorously separated in the expanding universe
then he wrote in the introduction that this is a phenomenon of outstanding importance by which he
didn't actually say this but it's implied that he was talking about density perturbations from
inflation and tomorrow we'll talk about wimpzillasso he didn't actually use the word
wimpzillas but he could haveSchrdinger wrote with particles it would mean production or annihilation
of matter merely by expansion alarmed by these prospects I`d examined the matter in more detail soSchrdinger went
through a lot of calculationsand came to the conclusion that there will be a mutual adulteration
of positive and negative frequencytermsin the course of time giving rise to the alarming phenomenon
of particle creation thereare two words thatSchrdingerused again and again in this paper one
word is alarming and the other word that he was very fond of was adulteration now
I don't know whySchrdingerwas alarmed by this but which
Schrdinger was alarmed at was the possibility that sometime in the next ten billion years
in a volume of ten to the fifty-seven cubic centimeters there could be created a particle with an energy of
ten to the minus thirty-three electron volts does that alarm anyone here
I think it alarmedSchrdingerSchrdinger was alarmed by this when he was actually running for his life
which questions in which thinkers should one pick up for oneself
perhaps the oldest and most fundamental questions that i wish to
examined in the course of the semester
it is the question what is a regime
what are regimes
what are
regime politics
the term
regime is the familiar one
we often hear today about shaping regimes or about changing regimes
but what is the regime
how many kinds are there
how are they defined
what holds them together and what causes them to fall apart is there a single
best regime
those are the questions i want us to consider
the concept of the regime is perhaps the oldest and most fundamental
of political ideas it goes back to play-doh
and even before
in fact the title of the book that you will be reading
part of this semester platelets republic
it is actually a translation of the title of it
of the greek word pull the tail
that means constitution
or regime
the republic is a book about the regime
and all later political philosophy
this a series of footnotes to play-doh
and that means that it must provide a series of variations so to speak
and players conception
one of the best regime
but what is the regime broadly speaking
regime indicates a form of government
whether it is ruled by the one
i feel
it is more common some mixture combination
these three ruling powers
a regime is defined in the first instance by how people are governed
and how
public offices
by birth
by lot by outstanding personal while personal qualities and achievements
and what constitutes
the people's rights
and responsibilities
the ricci regime again refers above all to form of government
the political world is not present itself as simply an infinite variety
of different shapes it is structured and ordered
in into a few
basic regime types
in this i take it to be
one of the most important propositions
and insights of political science
so far
but there is
corollary to this insight
the regime is always something particular
it stands in relation
of opposition
two other regime types
and as a consequence
the possibility of conflict
and war
it is built in to the very structure
of politics
regimes are necessarily partisan that is to say the
install certain loyalties in passions
in the same way that one may
i feel partisanship
to the new york yankees
the boston red sox
but yale
overall rival
colleges and institutions right
fierce loyalty
inseparable from
the character of regime politics is passionate attachments
not merely something that take place
you might say
between different regimes but even with in
there's different parties and groups
with loyalties and attachments contend for power
for honor
and for interest
henry adams once cynically reflected the politics is simply the organisation of hatreds
and there is more than a grain of truth to to this
although he did not say that is also
the temple an attempt to channel
those hatreds and animosities
twenty something like common good this
raise the question is it possible to transform politics
to replace
in factional conflict with friendship
with harmony
today is it is the hope of many people both here
and abroad we might even overcome
and even transcend the basic structure of regime politics altogether
and organize our world
around global
norms of justice
in international law
is such a thing possible
it cannot be ruled out
but such a world i would note that is to say world administered by international
courts of law
by judges
in judicial tribunals
would no longer be a political world
it only takes place
within the context of the particular
it is only possible
within the structure of the regime itself
but the regime is more than simply set
a formal
principal formal
structures and institutions OK
it consists of the entire way of life
the moral and religious practices habits customs and sentiment
that make people what they are
the regime constitutes an ethos
that is to say distinctive character
nurtures distinctive human types
every regime shapes a common character
a common character types with distinctive traits and qualities
so the study of regime politics is in part a study of the distinctive national
character types that constitutes
a citizen body
to take an example of what i mean
when tokyo study the american regime with a democratic regime properly speaking in democracy in
he started first with our formal political institutions is enumerated in the constitution such things
as the separation of powers division between state and what federal government and so on
but then went on to look at such informal practices is american manners and morals
a tendency to form small civic associations are peculiar moralism and religious life
o defensiveness
about democracy and so on all of these intellectual
and moral customs and habits
help to constitute the democratic regime in this