this is what we want to bound again the offline algorithm
if you just want to minimize this it puts you things at that the average
but in a more fancy one if if you want to compute an offline output
and now
what you would want to do always
you would also
maybe at some kind of prior or some kind of finish divergence to some initial
weight vector
and if you minimize this
this is not the bregman divergences ricci is this is the
cumulant function associated with the gaussians which is quadratic the simplest case
then you can define
can minimize
this term
and what you get
see i didn't it didn't do the form it OK
except in third
OK so this is how you would motivate the
the batch algorithm
the online algorithm you'd motivated
taking a divergence
also the initial parameter but only the loss
so far into it so far
and these different
this weightings of the initial distribution this one
the first is this one
might be different
an alternate version of motivation of the online algorithms you take the divergence to the
and then just the loss
the current loss occurred at the end
and while your parameters set this way
and if you do this kind of updates and compute this minimum you get the
following the offline algorithm
puts a certain weight on the initial
and then
some of the instances and divides by
this trade off parameter plus the number of trials a number of trials number of
the online algorithm has a very similar form except these weights might be different
you can also
derive this
OK express this in terms of the previous so this is the previous one minus
eight top t plus one comes this with this is sort of the gradient of
the loss
and this has
one of the t type of behavior
you can also see
this update here
can be written in terms of link function
you remember when we derive think that bregman divergences is always
you talk about idea you went to another domain
this is not going to be the expectation expectation domain
you add in the gradient and you go back
so this update
you can write this way
and it's from it's similar to what we used before
the online algorithm has
the freedom to choose
this additional
trade parameter
which could be different from the initial trade for the trade off parameter of the
batch algorithm
if the two are the same the online algorithm is kind of an incremental offline
sometimes it's good
make the align parameter the online parameter a little bit bigger
OK so this corresponds to
the following situation
if you
plug in everything and you do it for gaussians and so forth this other reasonable
the plane line
algorithm would be
you want to set this parameter to zero and you just sort of two maximum
if t examples you divide by t
the online algorithm on trial t
has seen t minus one example
it turns out by setting the these these eight parameters
a little bit differently a better way to set it is
to add here plus one
so the number of examples plus one it's it's like regularizing it by adding initially
example point zero
we call this the forward algorithm because it estimates it doesn't just
compute the maximum likelihood estimates it but by putting another point zero
before it before it
compute its current parameter
it guess is that the parameter is
actually had zero and that includes that into the estimate and that gets you plus
imagine here plus zero which doesn't show up
can do the same thing
for the newly
maximum likelihood again is the average but
fancy online algorithm would be
something like custom of trust him off i don't know it's two russians
which put a half count here
put an additional example at the half
and then divide by the number of examples plus one
and that sort of a regularized version
love plus estimate is another case where have one here
and repeating this because
you don't use the joint decision trees use again my mind for a zero
seventy five
the wrong one so a zero
this one
five of the six negative and here we have five of this form and we
need that
well my i think and simply multiply these
the marginal
likelihood ratios to obtain an estimate of the joint
like ratio one prior to the posterior
it's by no
and to visualize the right to get
and you can transform these probability these ratios the probability is as before can
right and as you see
nine days may one while the mistakes because the models in this case are misleading
but the model a
one more of the next year and again all of the next years multiply those
you get something like twice as many of the next year but in fact
there are more than simple so that they form a ranking which we all know
what to do that you can visualize wrong space
why is this
again we have this only sixteen points to work with some of the ROC curve
and i think it has to go through these points
and blue actually indicate the marginals because the market decision stumps and again they must
be somewhere
among those sixty points so actually
i think this is me
well zero
this is a
a one
this a
here and b
OK so basically
nine baseball all my face has four blue vectors and price
you will end up in ROC space and cyberspace makes mistakes
so we have the game
marginal probabilities you can do anything about that but i want have is we have
access to truth joint probability which you know
so we have this ranking
but that's something think this ranking
why simple
she that become the left and right children of the truth
so it's too long for free
if i just small values of a around in both cases i get three four
now this is what i call the lexicographic ranking
a simple left to right or of the tree which
if we could be before a and we always will be
zero for the one and
a one
before a people there so why do i call lexicographic ranking well
think about that the brain is what do you do find people for
for instance
you want to know whether by people flocked to understand what the stuff from the
before know right
if you want to know
a lot of people that we see that one of the many applications of my
suffering in england
then you use standard two
names until you find the first position where they differ
and then you say if a because before
and we know what comes after that right so lexicographic ranking is basically finding the
first point where two things differently and use that point is the criterion which store
the addresses and that's exactly what we're doing here
if we want to compare two examples
if they
for p
i just need to know which one of the people zero i know that one
if they are equal for the goalkeeper in the tree
of course in practice you wouldn't do the mandatory
exponential space that this is this is the different
in practice
we use the odds ratio
two towards the attributes because they basically gives us the the fact lexicographic ranking has
strictly stronger lines the naive bayes
so this is very quick
the o racial can be understood as yet another splitting
they have quite nice nice properties
so basically i
ratio is
people by and which is the film that divided by
the ratio of gold rush and one of the reasons why is so much like
something like information gain for instance the odds ratio
at the closed form if you want to draw knights
red lines
japanese man rocks
so one way to understand the
if you look at this
ratio p
and what is and is something like
the area
this guy here
and the other one is the area that there
o point
this point of ratio five
because of this i five because that want
and if i go along this
one of key problem as an argument
he met some
in what i'm about to show you
we actually use the odds ratio also is this is true
but it did
now comes the moment of truth for enough to decide to give them all
to my students and then at the bar had spent long
and also
the first were to produce is it's still in beta which means and it can
be something else
i just want to visualize some of these ideas here
the problem is the problem if you're old enough
to understand how many
you even though there
that's not to say too much about the
so house
it's a
actually incorporates
some of the best classifiers of web
so let me just show you what it does i can open
data files diabetes
if you know this is
if even if this increases decreases slower than the really what you know pieces of
luggage for practical purposes basically constant so the idea is that even if i i
even if they can lead to large networks my cluster size remains unchanged and my
cluster sizes
you know the medium medium class size sixty in there and if i take the
average i think i get hundred nine
so the point is
even if i take you know huge networks of best of millions of nodes
the best clustering
are of the same size meaning around hundred
so that's the first so
just don't get because
and if i go look and you know what they want
what are the last what what he described as likely would look like this is
how like that so this edge
between red and green
is the edge cutting and you can see that these things are
launched this as they are richer than trees
so they are
as i've shown the next slide actually there are bigger
and then what we you expect or
what you could ask if you know this
this is the painting of the just the result of course this is a big
but the idea is real networks as sparse right every degrees of super-low so we
naturally expect something like this to just by chance because frankly because it's
and if i plot the distribution of you know this because sizes
this is the real network and this is the network with the same degree distribution
so basically a random graph with the same degree sequence right so i keep the
density and keep the degree sequence i'm just randomizing the edges so
and you can see i get much smaller and much fewer of disease which means
that this is actually real
OK so that's that's the next iteration
this small pieces on the edge of the network that do what you would expect
chance from the
OK so this is one
so then you could say oh you know
if this these things on the edge of the network are really causing trouble what
if you just going to remove
right so what i'm showing you here is that this is now i think opinions
on i would like to read these plots were shown before and the green now
these plots were shown that i removed is green set up the network and i
only considered
the yellow let's say take this yellow clouds sort of these networks where in the
and what's your situation
observation is that nothing happens right i
at least one years to get pretty much the same the same shape of of
the network community profile the only difference is that you know now the green is
a shifted a bit upwards and a be a bit to the right
and what does this tell me this tells me two things first is that
when i remove this risk is connected by a single edge now
what is causing me the travel what is being managed by is the discussion or
this more components are connected to the network the two edges
right so
the two edge
connected whiskers
i'm responsible for this but this is this is what remains or explanation for this
but remains as it was
so what this tells me about the structure of the networks it basically says the
networks this mess the core periphery structure that have this this is on the edge
the i can very easily cut away and then i have this
on you like dance and then supported the you know if i give away the
outer layer i get to se in millions of
so if i move the periphery the core itself will always be decomposable to the
so that's why
and here's the picture just schematic right
if i got away is small pieces
right i'm getting this part of the of the network community profile plots and once
they want to get wants to go beyond that size scale of hundred and i
want to be immediately says i got into these denser and denser part of the
network and might not getting worse and worse
and just to be clear what the result is that the network core contains around
sixty percent of the nodes and eighty percent of the right so there is significant
forty percent of the nodes this
well let's call the lemma one for you
so there is still a lot of nodes
that's the point
now i want to get a bit more technical about how we got the network
so far i really i just told you what kind of algorithm i'm using to
find is to find now i want to get a bit more
into detail what kind of set different clustering algorithms give
so the first thing we can say is what if we allow cuts like that
right for example you come to me and say gimme gimme cluster on a node
i say you know his clustering night no write these nodes i cut wages and
you know i get whatever inside that's my
so this is the first question is you know what if i love
cuts in some the
at least you know from the last point if you don't make much sense right
if i if i want to now go and you know
call is a single community that that's not what i want to do
and then the second heuristic i using it's very so i call this a bag
of whiskers heuristic and all i see is
i identify scores
i mean i put them in the back and then when you come to me
and say you know community on seven other whatever i just take the appropriate to
discus throw them in the back and say here's here's the cluster right here is
that you ask for a particular number of nodes here is the class that number
now the question is how these things work
so this is a bit busy but
i don't know so again you can see that because we had before
this is the number of nodes in the cluster which is the quality of the
cluster of better
we start up here
if we just minimum around hundred and goes out
and then each graph here is a different person
so that is the one we saw before
right and you can see that there are clustering methods that even better clusters than
the red the then the red
so what
and therefore
if an object sinks
and the density of the object is larger
and the density of the fluid
and the amazing thing is that this is completely independent of the dimensions of the
the only thing that matters
the density
if you take a pebble is thrown in the water it sinks because the density
of the petal is higher than water with a piece of wood
it has a density lower than water you throw the water flow independent of the
but i don't think so it floats
the buoyant force is always identical to the weight
of the displaced fluid
and this brings up one of my
questions that i have for you would i want you to think about
and if you have a full understanding of archimedes principle
you will be able to answer
so concentrate on them going to present you with
i am in the swimming pool
and i'm in the boat
swimming pool
here is the boat
and i'm sitting in the boat
and i have a rocket in my boat
i'm sitting in a swimming pool
nice rock in my book
i'm like
the one line
of the swimming pool
very carefully
i take the rock
and i throw it overboard
well the waterline go up
well the waterline go down
well maybe
what will stay the same
use your intuition don't mind being wrong
home you have some time to think about it i'm sure you'll come up with
the right answer
o things at the one line will go up
swimming pool with things that the one that will go down
the things that make no difference at the waterline stays the same
is OK
four line will change
but you figure it out
OK you apply archimedes principle and you'll get the answer
i want to talk about stability
particularly its ability of ships which is a very important thing they float
suppose i have an object here it is floating in water
the water line
and that he be the centre of mass of that object
i could be way off centre could be nice work be bowlers could be rocks
in there
right doesn't have to be uniform density centre of mass could be off the scent
of the geometric center
so it is object
has a certain mass
and this is the gravitational force
but now look at the
centre of mass
that's clearly
four years
somewhere here
the displaced fluid
that is
where the wind forces
so now what you have
we have the talk on this object relative to any point that you choose doesn't
matter where you pick a point
the talk
and so was going to happen this object is clearly going to rotate
in this direction
and the talk will only be zero
when the buoyant force
and the gravitational force i one line
and two become zero
and then
it is completely happy
now there are two ways that you can get them on one line
we discussed earlier
in different context
i have the
centre of mass of the object below
the centre of mass of the
this place fluid or above in both cases would be on one line
however in one case there would be stable equilibrium in the other
that would not be stable equilibrium
i have here an object
which has its centre of mass
very low
you can tell that
no way of knowing
all you know is that the
the weight of the displaced fluid that you see here
it's the same
as the
weight of the object that's all you know
if i took this object
and and i tell the little
with the centre of mass very low
so here's an
and here's some underwater line
the centre of mass of the displaced fluid is somewhere here
fp is here
we force
you can see what's going to happen
it's going to rotate to the right it's a restoring torque
and so
it's completely stable
i can wobble back and forth
and in stable
if i would turn it over
that is not stable
because now
i would have the centre of mass
somewhere here high up
now i have g
and the centre of the buoyant force
OK let's get started it's so
now i introduced you the basics of kernel methods
actually you can
you could leave now
because i think you know everything if
well you know now is is sufficient if you want to to to do kernel
methods you know i support vector machines you know things about kernels and if you
just want to do the applications or if you want to localize your own algorithm
i i think you you already have
everything to do that
one thing i want to show you now is actually i want to show you
two things and probably won't have time to show you the last thing of the
of the of my talk about
you have everything on the on the printouts and then if you have questions you
we can discuss any points
if you want so the first thing that i want to talk to you about
is the i want to show you examples of kernels for structured data because
one of the the very nice things about kernels
as i said to you before is that you can use them to do classification
for that data that are structured that have information on on their structure that you
cannot have when you just work with vectors so this was very in advertising thing
about kernel methods
saying that now you have all the algorithms
on one side and all you have to care about is having a good kernel
for the application that you want to to to address
i'll show you a specific kernels for sequences
and graphs of course there exists many many many different kernels you can build your
own kernel
but i still have to do is the specific kernels that i'm going to show
you because in some sense they contain everything that you may need to to know
if you want to build your own code
why talking about kernels for structured data because if you want to tackle the real
life applications
you may have to work with
so structured data it's very it's very rare when you have a attribute vector data
it's an usually if you have that then means that somehow you've left you've lost
some information on on the data you're going to work with
the the
again a very nice thing about currency that you may want to tackle problems with
structured data and try to
preserve as much information as possible on the on the thing the objects that you
work on
and for instance here you have you have DNA DNA strain
we then the different i remember how it's called english but ATC in g
and here you have molecules
so i'm going to talk about a bit about molecules because those are
a typical example of of
of graph that you may encounter and and they
molecules to pose questions about how we can do virtual screening meaning that you want
to have
ultimate process to directly identify what
molecules can help you sure these kind of disease are these are the kind of
these is so it's very
i mean it's i mean it's very easy to synthesize and to build molecules in
instance what they called in silico studies to model molecules in in the computer is
just generating graphs
it's just using a computer so
among all the billions of
molecule that you have sometimes you may want to identify some of those molecules that
that may have
desired properties
and it's very very very important for pharmaceutical companies
this is a very rough draft scale on on the state of the art
on classification problems if you have structured data and unstructured data
basically in machine learning etc
usually very easy
where i put quotes here because it depends on the problem and the application that
you have plenty of methods that you can use way if you want to to
do classification with
victoria vectors
this is something that you know you know you've you've known from high school
and there are many many many things that you can use
and then you have sequences sequences are a bit too richer than x because the
position of of of of elements that describe the sequences with respect to each other
are very important
and but in end there are methods to deal with sequences but they are not
as plentiful as they are for for vector data
and then
you have graph data
that are very hard to handle
because you
easily end up with
np hard problems because comparing graphs trying to to identify award because identify common substructures
and things like that is very computationally demanding if you have no hypothesis and assumptions
and the kind of graphs you're working on
and this is the reason why there's is very few things on the classification and
graph classifications and at his there is no state of the art methods that or
or propose a method that says OK if you want to do graph classification i'm
going to use this method because i know that is what i have to do
there is no such thing for for graph data
and so here again we see that there are very few methods to to to
tackle problems involving graphs
the phone content provided by MIT opencourseware under creative commons license
additional information about our relations and MIT opencourseware in general is available OCW MIT you
all right so we have a few more
powerpoint things before i'm going to attempt using the board
again we're in the transition metal unit and today we're going to introduce something called
crystal field theory
and this is in chapter sixteen in your book
so let me just tell you about two different theories and again chemistry is an
experimental science we collect data
and then we try to come up with theories that explain the data so the
theories are sort of a hundred percent summer more simple and some are more complicated
to try to explain what we observe
and some of these theories of other pretty simple approximations of what's really going on
the pretty good job of explaining the things that we are observing
all right so there are two
there are two different kinds of theories that you hear about with transition metals you
hear about crystal field theory and ligand field theory
and so these were again developed to explain certain types of properties of coordination complexes
of transition metals so there are observed data and then people try to think about
how you could rationalize what was observed
so the basic idea behind the theory
is that if you have your metal ion with its given oxidation number
and it's in the centre of the core nations
the energy levels of the d orbitals for that particular metal
we're going to be alternate when ligands are bound compared to sort of free
so the binding of ligands around the metal where there are those d orbitals associated
with that metal is going to have an effect and creates special properties
so crystal field theory which is what we're going to be talking about is based
on an ionic description
basically you're going to be considering ligands as negative point charges and negative charge and
you're going to ask the question is that negative charge pointed toward the orbital it
so that'll be repulsive and that's going to happen that
ligand field theory includes covalent as well as ionic description
so it is a more powerful it theory and it it can describe things that
little bit better but it that we don't have enough time to cover it here
and if you're interested in transition metals you probably don't want to take another chemistry
course called five o three which is in organic chemistry so at this point we're
just going to be doing the more simple theory which just considers the ionic description
but it does pretty well you can explain some things with it but you should
be aware
but this is not the sort of the the mos that you can do a
little bit better with another theory so you should just be aware that this is
really the most simplistic kind of of representation or theory to explain some of the
coordination complexes
so all of these series
they require you to think in three dimensions about the orbitals because they're all about
the interactions with ligands either covalently or
ionic interactions but they are all about the interactions of ligands with those d orbitals
so we i mentioned last time you need to know the shapes of the d
orbitals and you need to be able to draw them to some limited liability
so we went through the names of the d orbitals last time let's just review
it now because we're going to be talking about this more today
so what is this guy here
he z squared
and here's our reference frame so these up here why along here x is coming
out towards you
so what about this one
d x squared minus y squared
down here with that one
dx y so we're from the amplitudes are forty five degrees off the axis in
the x y plane
over here we have the why these an our along the
and the last one is
x the over here
right so those are five d orbitals that will be talking about a lot in
the next two lectures
all right let me just show you this is all it's really three-dimensional so let's
take a look at the three-dimensional image of these are of these d orbitals
so this is a
square this is in your hand out of the movie
but you can forget that little better sense of the three dimensions here
right so moving
first rotate the axes russia why does that
and then it's going to rotate the idea orbitals so you can see the donut
in the middle with the whole
and the maximum amplitude are long
the axis here this is is square
and it's right along the orbitals right along
this the axis which is important
so now let's take a look at the
x squared minus twice square
and the important point here
is that the orbitals are directly on axis and the axes are
can generalize that slightly i can say that if i have a bunch of nonnegative
parameters lambda i which sum to one
like probabilities if you like
and the someone i
lambda i times
this convex function which this case is z
i'm sure that i
is less than or equal to the log
of the someone i lambda i said i
so that's just saying that the
the linear combination of the logs which is the point here
it lies on or below
the log of the linear combination which is this point here just by saying that
convex function
and then if you allow me the liberty of replacing the sum by an integration
weighted now by
the probability density nonnegative
function which integrates to one
so we have the following property that the integral of q
log of p over q
minus that in z
so this is a convex combination of the log
the function
i can apply this inequality the minus signs of the inequality is reversed there's no
greater than or equal to minus
of the integral
of q times the function which is here the q
now the two cues will cancelled
entropy is one
so on the right-hand side have minus the log one
which is zero
so the
the KL divergence is greater than or equal to zero
the result
that was one property the KL divergence
so another property the KL divergence another property the KL divergence is the
his the definition
recall that if if he i said he was set equal to
he said
this is a q which is one of the longer one is zero the average
zero is zero so
here equals p implies the KL
vanishes vanishes when
q is equal to p
that's the only situation in which vanishes
so we can
we can show that as follows
and i apologize if the mathematicians in the audience to find the proof less than
rigorous but at least it's not intuitive
derivation so that's the that's the KL divergence let's look at a stationary point
so will will
stationary points with respect to q z
maybe this is a good excuse to explain why all this is called variational because
recall that q of z
is actually a function
so this thing this KL divergence
is the function now
the function or rather the probability distribution qz
o functionality something we you take function input output the number
seven function takes the numbers input and output number
in calculus
we differentiate functions
and in the calculus of variations we differentiate function functionalities
so a typical problem in the calculus of variations
would be the following i got a point a and point b
i want to find the shortest path between a and b
the path is defined by some curve
the distance to affect curve is s of x
and the distance the length along the path
is the functionality function as of
this effects
in other words
for a given function of x this is just the number
and in countless variations we differentiating respect to functions not just to a finite set
of numbers
looking for stationary point usually point
is easily shown to be a straight line
i want to point
to do the same thing over here
differentiate this with respect to the function QZ so what we're doing
it is we are
exploring all possible functions qz
finding stationary points with respect to all possible choices for q of said
one thing we must do of course is to
it's all functions qz such that
subject to the normalization condition
so we need to add electrons multiplier
which is q
the interval of q dz
is equal to one
and now we can differentiate with respect to q
and so we end up with
the following with the functional derivative to zero
so there's is a q here
so we can differentiate if we differentiate back you will get longer
he z minus log
there's another hu here longer q
to the derivative of the log is one of the few that will cancel this
user will be left with a minus one
the final q here
his first music
and if i exponentially as it says that qz
is some constant times p of z
but q and p have to integrate to one so the constant must be one
and so he said
equals p of z
so so we left that out but that's a good point that we've where we
have a very simplified model only trying to relate sort of the what we might
consider sort of the instantaneous positions articulators to the acoustic output
so it is simplified in that respect so what i'm trying to do is just
make the relationship between two the shape of the vocal tract and the acoustics that
come out
and this is about the time that all the computer scientists get up and run
the course right where i didn't sign up for circuit theory but the point is
that we can very easily use this electrical model where all these electrical components are
defined in terms of of these sort of acoustic quantities to derive the wave equation
and actually we can do that by just writing circuit equations here and letting these
distances go to infinitesimal quantities and we get these differential equations and then a we
can plug in boundary conditions i can have a simple
vocal tract up there at the time where we have the
volume velocity into the glottis
coming out of the let's i want to know the transfer function that from the
input to the output i can assume a certain form of the solution to the
wave equation plugin boundary conditions i could get i can groups how can i could
get this
self for the transfer function and i hope i get something i i get a
a expression for the
transfer function of the vocal tract which is in terms of a propagation constant and
what's important here is the length of this too
this led to the two something that depends generally on the individual i might have
a longer or shorter vocal tract than you do
it's something it speakers speaker specific
and again rushing and i could go through here for a typical value of
link seventeen and a half centimetre
acoustic tube
corresponds to a typical male saying i will get performance structure here that is roughly
a sitting here in five hundred since equally spaced at one thousand hertz centers i'm
making certain assumptions that i can make the band big smaller
the the message here is that for a this simple model
i can have formant frequencies that have that they have certain forms frequencies and the
second bullet here is that these formant frequencies are inversely proportional to the two blank
with the tube length is dependent on the speaker
so in this implies that the effects of
speaker dependent variability
can be reduced simply
normalizing along the frequency axis so in other words i had this physiologically plausible transformation
i can perform
normalizing a normalizing frequency axis that has this direct correlates in the in the articulatory
and so
this has led to an people have been doing this for years has has led
the use of of frequency warping
as as a speaker normalisation approach in in ASR
and the
one the way this is performed as well but it was will basically what's the
frequency axis over a relatively small range were compressed by around ten to twenty percent
will generate the
actual acoustic
the actual acoustic features associated with these worked utterances
and and then we to choose the best warping
as being that those
is corresponding to those worked features
that somehow maximize the likelihood of our utterance with respect to the model that we
use in speech recognition
this is the end result is is you could also use some training to give
you more sort of compact models but the end result here is
we were able to
get a really significant increase increase in performance
with a very small amount of data
the amount of data that would require a to get this similar increase in performance
by more traditional adaptation algorithms that don't really have any sort of physical correlates with
the amount of data for that which is maybe almost an order of magnitude more
this is the sort of the message here is is it for
even in in the sort of traditional algorithms that were implementing in our traditional ASR
systems when we have a sort of of physical justification to them
this week there can be
lies outside the boundary which is also
five hundred years
the one we don't need to practice
i changed the problem because this between our web site will be pushed
so called from the the twenty one
what we
because of that when
the people
the selection
first of all the time
to try to
so that that's where
so the bot
the small
because it
i don't
the about distribution of what state
we can
it will provide
the way the way so i have point in ways
which are distributed equally
there are no
some query
don't have something like this is the
the case
it's clear that this was a great
the small amount of white the along the boundary
the smallest distance to practice before three
so first of all all
it also like such
partition of
but perhaps the smaller
and we can mention that actually should select one
one of the space
because it was the first step toward
about it will have like this one
it was selected by for
on the
also managed
it will be like this it's possible to follow the links to
already smaller than this one
but this was one of the first one which is like
and the kind of place you will have smaller power
and our approach
so to try
partition by what to
i do we have one
in other quality and
we want to
the ranges of british actually
so it really well multiply that is
and our
you might end
tools like that for
i mean
one romantic what we need
from one twenty two hours i space so
select the best rating
many had not just by the way
they how that first when the point
by buyer
for example
these points be managed
and we
the standard deviation of
OK well this
for every
this image so this is the one that want to say
and was that
that would put them up there
what does it mean
the division is
we want to select one change the according space so which are
why from all at once and the bigger than that
big distribution
we should actually from all these points that one
we have a
when you have something like here and division the like
from the disease
and if take
this one so will be
problems with the standard deviation is much smaller because all
close disease one of them is one
o point which
class one
like one range
the device
done owing to lack of data
beginning of the first
and this is the right
three three areas
and here we are
well also
no no what
also they were ones i was that good quality
i mean these
it was selected this weighted start with
well first of all that these
and this the first issue like that
the partition
it should that next the point which is the game
the has longest
so like this but
this is the
and and we
and the the partition according to this point you right
and this
when the point
the problem
OK so very
so the elementary example of bayesian learning
the talk was called introduction to beijing learning but it does illustrate a lot of
a lot of the key ideas i think any questions about that
so if you can
the reason we just images go back and take a look at that so
so a model
is that
for any value of x the value of t is drawn from gas distribution which
is centered on some function y x and w
and we've chosen function which is linear in w so this
for t
it is
against his mean is
a linear function of w so
so it's
so p c
it is of the form
so with respect to all of these parameters w
it has this functional form is the same as that of the gaussians is e
to the minus the quadratic function of w
so the density distribution because of the distribution and the w but it has that
form the conjugate prior
is guassian so there's
i have chosen the conjugate priors
because i've chosen the conjugate prior constant country prior is that priors gaston because its
conjugate on observe some data remains guassian
i support data is still guassian
and that's
and has simple sufficient statistics i just need to compute
means and covariances of those phi
and that
vector in this case is just the two-dimensional
that china two by two matrix and about how many observations i compute you just
have to update the finite dimensional set of sufficient statistics
so those are the two sort of
key things was only
oh sorry sequential i just yes the order doesn't matter so
it for these independent observations i can absorb them in any order just the products
so it doesn't matter whether i take the product of the likelihood functions for the
observations and get that big like function multiplied by the prior p the posterior whether
i start with the prior lives on one data point i absorb another
get same answer
sort of
is because we have the same
i don't think
it's because your computing the product of n likelihood functions with the prior if you
multiply you know and plus-one things together as much if you first of all multiply
subset them together and the later multiply and the other thing is the sort of
commutative multiplication
what's going on here
the school moved
on the
so really
these are sensor data points so we're
for example if if the temperature is above thirty centigrade you don't observe that value
so that's example data points not being missing at random
so you
so the missing data course are very important
aspect of many practical applications is often assumed is convenient to do so the data
is missing at random so somebody just randomly removes subset of data has to be
very easy to deal with because you just marginalize that is unobserved variables if the
missing this depends for example on the value of the data points and you have
no missing at random and you could i don't have experience with this but you
can in principle model this within the context of the graphical models you can model
the missing this process
and it will be missing this random it is something that you can but you
can model and then do inference on that more complex models
three other classical methods
requirements the the relationships in the priors in this century
what can you try to make a connection since entering the choice of prior use
i'm not sure it's necessary the prior i think it's the process by which the
observations get censored but you want to model
not necessarily the
but you write down the generative process of how these data points came to be
and how they got censored
if you can write down that model
and then you in good shape
should we this is quite detailed as a fascinating topic should just take it offline
getting quite short on time and this one final topic very keen to please mention
briefly so us
if that's the case of the other points of clarification
but have said
it is but
you sometimes have to keep
sometimes you have to keep track of things that may be the number of data
you've observed so for instance
you know the gas you just keep the mean and covariance of the data use
so far been absorbed one more data point it matters whether you you know kept
and this is
as the name the school auxiliary
what what they called
you know the the statisticians have a name for these so this is not is
not formally called policticians to stick to just link you know something that the number
of data points
so you don't have to keep track about as well that's also justifies just the
so doesn't the key point is the that amount stuff you have to store is
not growing as the dataset grows is finite
but for the likelihood functions can those ages don't matter because you're you're interested its
functional dependence
on eta
minimize the problem of all want to maximize
let's see some
introduce a bit more the notation for the classification
we have find
there are in the dimensional space
two each data point to label is associated
but this time the label can be done on two
can on
plus one minus one
we are looking for additional functions
i put to
by the way the following
with a slight abuse of notation just use that as follows
including by
do it but i'm going to fix
this is the formulation for fisher discriminant analysis or in discriminant analysis
and you can see that
it is simply changing the set of the label and we are solving the same
problem and and sort being different task so from regression to classification
we have we can solve exactly
in fact what the fisher discriminant analysis is doing
is maximized the function that represents the difference between the mean
two classes normalized by a measure the
represent the spread of the two
of the data
this is the typical correlation that is minimized by maximizing fisher's discriminant analysis so maximize
the distance between the mean of the two classes normalized by the sum of standard
we can rewrite to be more of that
w by considering what happened
well known
between between the metrics and within class scatter matrix
the this is the formulation of the problem of fisher discriminant analysis
we can only for these also will arrive before
and this solution is the same of course but what we see before
later we see an interpretation of fisher discriminant analysis
i would talk now about some again by this problem
well known
principal component analysis can be cast by problem
or the problem that i want to find the relationship between the data sets
OK so again by the problems for example by combining analysis on the data the
each summer
easy to think about problem fashion square the the problem of canonical correlation i can
the above problem
for all of them economic
and we can stand or to this technique tool finding relationship between more than two
data sources and we will see the way canonical correlation analysis
it is the general form of an eigenvalue problem
this is not because we have a nice properties on a problem like that
first of all that for many methodists begin value in a vector v
then also that you have to
and the
good news is also if we are able to ask what problem and then again
by the problem you have to compute because of a lot of studies of technique
can solve the fact that using these problems
so let's talk about the most famous line that is
think by combining that
in first component analysis we want to find
of large variance in the data
and we are maximizing
this a function that represent the divide of the projection of the data set on
and again
and this is the type the function
and we can impose their capacity control
just recall the framework introduced by now look imposing the normal that is equal to
how do we solve problems again we can compute the ground
and so on
following a by so
as you can see that the problem
of this form
another way to formulate principal component analysis is used by the shell
and the math except for all that he can't covariance matrix that is positive semidefinite
symmetric matrix
the solution of this problem is given by the las vegas the again vector corresponding
to the largest i
the value of the ratio
they correspond to the largest value
if we started to play the data then we get the other
five combining and this is usually used for dimensionality reduction would need to approximate how
about making a low dimensional subspace
so from k two d with a much much smaller than d
why do we need dimensionality reduction
for many things for some high for visualisation but was is imagine that we want
to be able to do that in two d two dimensional three dimension
we can use dimensionality reduction from the impression when we need to store
the amount of that like images
we can use dimensionality reduction for example
forty nine because
we remove small noise action somehow
dimensionality reduction
very often imply information loss but we have no guarantee that PCA
what information as possible i say not always because
let's assume that i for example one feature that is constant for all the data
points that
if we project our back to the
dimension d minus one
we don't use the information but this is in general the case we missing information
so is how do we
project to our about dimensional space how we get these compact representation of our by
considering the begin that correspond to the
the largest eigen values
send it usually relies on many of going back to the
he managed to components that we keep
was studied by the spectrum so we study divide and explained by
all the components
and this is an example of taking value spectrum we we can for example use
this rule to choose k
well actually it into some of the first k
we can deal with this partial occlusion because we still recognise parts perhaps on this
side of the car even inside the because including OK
this is sort of some of the reasons these parts methods have become popular
in this tutorial these things to concentrate on going to go through a set of
models applications papers that people have developed over the last two three years and was
going to be in common is going to be some parts
is going to be a structure term
and maybe some learning and some recognition OK what would differ
is how these parts are defined how they learnt the same with the structure of
the different models
sometimes it will be very loose model of the structure just saying something one part
is to the left of another part of it could be very tight models like
everything is modeled by a calcium
learning methods differ the order in which the parts of structural and whatever
and to course what's important in terms of relevance as well as the complexity how
how long does this actually takes to run
and to learn
right so these are not going to cover the start of with
papers methods that first of all of the parts and then at the structure
gloss on top of that the case parts are important
now comes to contrast that with
methods which
start really the structure of the structure is the primary thing
i'll take a fair bit although i'm going to go on
class of models where the parts and structures are fairly equal and in fact they
learned simultaneously it's not you know one and the other
now we work that we've been doing on what's called the constellation model
and finally i end up with some
summary is state-of-the-art
they on two
pascal challenge
OK so this is starting off with models were the first step is to learn
this is the basic idea is somewhere in the image
and you want to home in on the bits of the image interesting
and the way to do that
tradition is to run an interest point detector
over the image that throws away the bits of the image like this which have
nothing of interest in them
then it finds that the text the image
so the best interest operators people use common ones are the ones by harris offers
finds interest operator and around each of these
interest points you grab a region the size of the region is the parameter can
vary so here showing ten by ten regions six hundred dimensional
each of these
interest points find the region
and this is done over the whole training set maybe face images
that's the data was gathered
and then
the status cluster to some similarity measure between
the image regions
the together i'm sure you've heard lot about clustering yesterday so
you've got the idea has cluster
this type of data
and perhaps will come out is the cluster for the i here
and across for the mouth here
and because these parts of these regions occur across all the training data the foreground
regions that these big clusters the hope will be the bigger clusters
are the ones that you want
so each of these large clusters defined apart
and then we go back to the
here's an example by the way the sum of the parts that are found
now we go back to the image
find interest points
and then each of the regions
these interest points we we can see if we want to
decide if there's apart there are not that we know about so say want to
find if this file this mouth in this image
we compare
image region to each of the regions around this in it interest points and we
find that they fit quite well in these two positions
OK and
it can be that we find the best fit all we find a set of
parts of it will be without within defined
the parts
for this
in particular image
that's the schematic for all of the methods in the first part of the talk
this clustering step of this gathering from text from various training images
and that defines
and the parts
not going to particular method run through that's the general introduction to the particular talk
about is one given by lee
and she'll
over the last couple of years
and this is exactly takes this
approach is because we have a set of training data for cars
find interest points find parts
so in detail what they use is model cars actually
clustering produces
so people across just the interest points produce these candidate regions are going to be
let me just say
from my point of view
these images
training from our good the segmented images even though
they haven't explicitly segmented because these images and you can see the background is so
simple effectively they know what the foreground object is
and so it's making a little bit easier
these are clustered
and what you're seeing here
the various clusters that they found find so here
the the will of the car
most represented
and then maybe this is
part of the car sector you get salient parts the car coming out by the
clustering is carried out using this measure of similarity
which is the normalized cross correlation
and then term for the size of the part
because that's a measure of similarity
for clustering and also for determining
the similarity between this part
and the image
so now as before i can ask you questions
so why is it you think they use
normalized cross correlation
why do use that rather than some other measure difference
yes in fact actually in these methods they do allow the two pixel adjustments
but that's that's that's translational shift is another type of shift they want to be
invariant something else please
thank you very much like yes so that's the answer by using normalized cross correlation
if there's a fine transformation
of the intensities of in that region they are invariant to it
OK so it's the reason you'll see all the way through you'll see that
in this first section people use the researchers used this normalized cross correlation very good
so here we are with we've got all parts
it would take an image and you want to see if that's got current or
not that's the question
find interest points
fifty candidate parts and now
this is where we bring in the idea of structure so far we had no
the notion of structure
the way they
in this case the largest lower bound is the maximum absolute value of the entries
of p
and if you minimize trying to over x y something equivalent to this
so that's a few examples for linear programming
so the next
extension and this quadratic programming and that's
something else
back to the fifties so here we keep the same types of constraints linear inequalities
and we take in convex quadratic cost function of x
so p is a symmetric matrix and this was the surface with the of this
quadratic function
so the consensus is still polyhedral as in the case
but the level curves of if have changed their now
if is a quadratic function so these are ellipses
and then depending on where the midpoint in the centre of these ellipses or the
unconstrained minimum of the
objective function is the
find an optimum that can be on the boundary
i can go on the corner points or it can be in the interior of
the fort hood and that's the constraints
so that's the difference with linear programming
so very
example that actually
motivated the development of quadratic programming in the fifties is a linear programme it's today
what people call linear programming with uncertainty robust linear programs
so this this comes up in investments
science so this is the basic markovits support for your problem
so because we have an LP
we assume that data and the constraints are exactly known so g and h are
exactly given but we assume that c is uncertain objective is
so animal it as a random variable
then obviously that makes it i suppose x objective function and random variable
and then we have to define what we mean by minimizing random variable x
random variable
that depends on x
well if c has mean sea by covariance sigma
then you have the trail between the expected value of the test was x just
see part i suppose x
and the variance
accessible semantics
so an investment that would be the expected
the minimizer we would minimize expected loss
so the
the mean will be the expected loss
and the variance would be the risk on the portfolio
and there is a trail between these two by just minimising
the expected value of the transpose x we might have a solution to the high
that's very sensitive to changes in sea
so i to model this is to look at the linear or convex combination of
it it's a combination of the two objectives
so suppose we minimize the
a combination of a weighted sum of the expected
after value expected objective function and a variance
accessible semantics
it's amazing parameter that expresses our risk aversion to commas zero
then we're don't care about the risk of the variance in the solution
if we are very are higher
risk averse to which is the larger value of come on put higher penalty on
high variance
but for positive any positive value of x this is a convex quadratic function of
so this is a quadratic programming problem
it's one of the first applications of quadratic programming
in the fifties
another famous one this just to continue this linear discrimination example from
linear programming
so here is the solution if you have two sets of points that are separable
by these two hyperplanes
then we can also try to find that in general there are multiple supporting separating
hyperplanes can try to find the one that maximizes the distance between these two sets
questions can
the first person to disperse the
this is rules something that it's also
from what i can see that you
why did factor graph you don't you can do everything by with the big page
mathematics right so the advantage of the graphs i think the ones i described earlier
well defined graph generalises in designing the model instruction model and helping us to set
out the calculation so yes i mean you
you know
you could just
manipulate the mathematics
but by
expressing is graph and expresses local message passing it just makes a heck of a
lot easier to understand the calculations to derive them to set might code in principle
you don't even need to draw the diagram
there's a wonderful story i think i can tell this because the very very smart
guy called steffen lauritzen who wrote a very famous book called graphical models it's quite
a theoretical book and some of the local jewish go also works in this field
was sent a draft of this this book from stephanie draft the this book on
graphical models and so he read through the draft back to stephan steffens by theoretical
sort of and he said you know stuff and this is a great book on
graphical model is fantastic is really going to be a classic there's one thing you
could do that would improve it make it easier for the reader wishes to add
a few pictures
so you don't need the grasp but for the for for me and i think
for many people enormously beneficial
in this country
yes you can still include directional lighting factor graphs you can discuss this
as you can so
underlying of course if if underlying this was the director graph that directionality is still
nothing here
specifies anything about any underlying directionality those so this is this is quite general so
so i guess i guess what you've lost actually is the following if you have
two nodes the points of the school head-to-head nodes these units pointing this node
then you have the conditional independence property these guys are independent when you observe this
to become dependent explaining away and you get get you lose that we just expresses
the fact that it's on the factor graph you can't see that the property of
the original cryptochrome across
the other
OK so you have the property here is this was all exact
we've actually done here if inference which is not only linear in the size of
the graph that result in efficient but a couple of other but is also exact
and also if you think about it for a moment may just to go back
to the original graph
to compute this
marginal we sent messages all the way in from the outside
compute the marginal
if not he said well i want this marginal you do the same thing you
send messages in from the outside to that node but actually all of those messages
will be
messages are already computed and in fact if you
let's say you pick a node and you send the message out
call that the route
so the message at all these comments and the measures and leads back to the
roots of each link is how to have
every possible message been sent once in each direction across each link
then you have all the messages you need to compute all marginals on every variable
and if you want the marginal factor you just take the product of the incoming
messages to
so its exact and by just using twice as much computation you can get all
the modules in the graph
wonderful stuff
it does depend on the graph being treated that that discussion breaks down the road
and what to do if the graph is not a tree well you can just
apply the message passing anyway the called
loopy belief propagation
and it's rather ad hoc
but it turns out that it works extremely well
and it also turns out that
it's equivalent some other techniques
david be talking about this in your
they will tell you a lot more about why this is actually turns out to
be really really good thing to do
think can go wrong with the marginalizations might not be tractable there we just had
little some asians but if you have continuous variables we need to do integrations we
may not be able to do those in closed form so what can we do
if the marginalizations an attractor
in general that we've got some complicated distribution and we want to compute marginals and
to make predictions using the distribution is not tractable we do about it
one thing about it is monte carlo draw samples from the distribution and we have
in very can give two
o talked about monte carlo techniques today and tomorrow i think
and what colour settings so wonderful for
couple reasons first of all the extremely generally compliant very very wide wide-ranging distributions also
in some sense that they're exactly they would be exact if you had an infinitely
powerful computer
the main limitation i think is that
they can be computationally costly so scaling up to large data sets can can prove
to be problematic
one scholar methods have a lot of advantages
i think i'm quite excited about is of complementary set of techniques which are based
analytical approximations and make use of local message passing on graphs of illustrate that schematically
here in monte-carlo we draw samples
which is distributed according to the true posterior distribution in these other techniques we approximate
the the true distribution in red with some family of simple distributions shown schematically in
green and then we explore that family of distributions to find the member which is
the best representation of the true distribution in some sense we have to define what
we mean by the best or the closest match
there's a whole bunch of these variational message passing loopy belief propagation already mentioned expectation
propagation and many others very active field of research
a disadvantage here is that we can only ever find an approximation so if we
for approximating this complicated distribution by cassie and we can only ever find against in
on the other hand it can be very efficient and can scale to large datasets
are show you in a minute and tom minka is going to give two
o lectures on that topic
so give you an illustration
of this framework in action so this is the problem of
and we can think of this
and in terms of concrete example think of chess imagine that we're all members of
the chess club and we were going to play games of chess against each other
we get together in pairs we play a game of chess and one person wins
or the other person wins or to draw
and from all those little pairwise results we want to drop the league table not
to but everybody in the room into the big league example from from
the best and the worst playing chess
so it's a partial ranking problem we have lots of partial rankings one person is
nationality couple
that says that my name is elizabeth coppock
so that will
mapping between the string concept
most of the politicians
indirectly related words to concepts
extreme so you have
dog theword
which can have multiple forms
dog dogs
the singular and the plural
now a mass nouns
i would have a mass number assertion
what are the words
the string water
and then those words
are related to
concepts so the denotation of dog theword is
first dark
this gives you a level of abstraction that allows you to
now both dog and dogs
to the concept doc
or you know
sing and sang
to the concept of singing
you one concept in the word
it's a one word
saying the word
that's an individual in the KB
and it's related to
and and well
because there's really only
one semantic relationship involved
a single word
that it sort of represents the root which is the meaningful elements in
in each of these strings
because that was
the mean
that would capture the fact that there's really only one
semantic relation is the relation between the roots and
the concept
and then the room is related to these
constraints immediately
it means it
you could infer
a direct relationship between of the strings and the concept
but if it's there's only one relation involved it should only be stated once
OK so
all talk about four different kinds of semantic predicates by semantic predicates i mean
things that really words too
words are linguistically things to semantic things OK so i talked about namestring notation
in mainstream really from concept denotation of the word to concept
and then you also have some transfer ticket
like verbsemtrans which really
two semantic templates
which is a kind of abstract descriptions of events
the word will be related to the semantic template
eating events
where the subject
argument is
plays the role of the eater
and the
object argument place thing
and you
keywords in there for the subject and the object
keep the roles that they play
and then
for generations gentemplate
and then we also have asserttemplate
which is
i won't talk about asserttemplate one much like gentemplate it relates to sentence template concepts
sort of an abstract description of the sentence
you can
interpret that as a relation
with gentemplate it is given relation
how do you
realise that
sentence you could use to
realize a given predicate
it seems strange
already covered
this example shows that
the same constant can have
two different names know mark twain
senior women's
you could use
have question structure
so indeed that's when we're done defects is the output for every vertex is going
to give us the shortest path from s to that vertex
along the way it's going to be some estimated distance from a vertex an improvement
over time this is an entity
so initially we know that the distance
we now
the distance from s to s is zero arrested that to be our estimates going
to be accurate everything else are discussed set to infinity as we know may not
be connected
the beginning we don't know much
as initially is going to be infinity immediately we're going to have less to big
and then the interesting careers q
which is going to consist of initially all the vertices in the graph
and it's going to not just be q with the letter suggests is going to
be a priority queue so it's going to maintain and in particular the vertex the
has the smallest distance estimate
so this is the priority queue
this is really an abuse of notation for a data structure
OK so this can be he whatever the vertices are key
on d
distance estimate
so in particular as well have the this is going to be i mean keep
as will be the guy who is the minimum everyone else has the same key
and we're going to repeatedly extract the minimum element from this cube and do other
OK so that's this is initialisation
i'm going to call the initialisation because well
it's pretty simple thing it takes linear time nothing fancy going on
the heart of the other
it is all in
six science
so we're so this is not really a step that the means the first step
here that we need to do
it is we take the vertex whose distance estimate is minimal so that
among all the vertices not yet as currently as is that dq has everyone in
general you will have everyone except as
so we'll take the vertex u there has the minimum key
in the priority queue
six extract the man
from q
and little u two s
claim that that is now
and that's exactly what we're saying here that s
but as the vertex has the minimum distance estimate and now we need to update
the distances we're looking at each adjacent vertex
are you should be
adjacency list for you
we look at
few distances
so that's the algorithm
or less
this is the key
should define a little bit of what's going on here
we talked mainly about undirected graphs last time were thinking about directed graphs and the
adjacency list for you here this is going to mean give me all the vertices
for which there
and it's an edge from u to v
so this is the outgoing adjacency was not the incoming adjacency list
wonder if you actually was everything directed graphs here we're only gonna care about those
ones so for every edge u v what this is saying
we're going to compare the current estimate for v
and this
canada estimate which is
which intuitively means you go from s to u
that's the view
because we now know that's the right answer this this in fact
he calls
we hope something arguments correct there should be the shortest path
way from st you because we just attitude as whenever we had something as it
should have the right values
so this is we could say well you take the shortest path from s to
you and then you follow the edge from u to v that has weight wv
that's one possible path from
s two v
and that's the shorter path than the one we currently have in our estimate this
is smaller than that then we should update the estimate to be that some because
that's the better so
i added to our database of past so to speak
a very intuitive
clearly shouldn't do anything
in this should be has the
it makes sense will prove that in the moment that's the first part of correctness
never screws up and the tricky part is to show that it finds all the
powers we care about
this is called the relaxation steps
relaxation always
difficult technique to teach to MIT students
and come very naturally but
OK so very simple operation it it comes from
optimisation terminology programming
terminology so to speak and
can anyone tell me that this this inequality look familiar at all
what kind of especially when you start writing it this way
you say well the shortest path from s to v
on the shortest path from
st u and some edge from u to v
that look like anything we've seen in fact it was on this board but i
just arrest
triangle inequality so this is trying to make the triangle inequality true certainly the shortest
path from s to be should be less than or equal to not this greater
than the shortest path from s to u plus some you know whatever path
from u to v
this is the shortest path should be most
so this is sort of a somewhat more general
triangle inequality
and we want certainly it should be true
so it's not really we fix it it to have greater than we make it
equal but i want to make it less than because that's not always true
OK but certainly should be less than or equal to so this is fixing the
triangle inequality it's trying to make that constrain true
and optimisation that's called relax relaxing the constraint
so we're sort of relaxing the triangle inequality here over and over and over and
by the end which level all the shows past that's the clay very simple algorithm
let's try it on the graph
and that should make it more intuitive way working and the rest electoral proving that
it works
so let's take it should mention one other thing here sorry
that whenever we change
this is changing the key of b in the priority queue
so implicitly what's happening here in this assignment
it's getting a bit
is it decrease key operation
OK which we talk briefly about
the last class in the context of the minimum spanning trees were also decreasing the
key point is we're changing the key we're changing the key of one element in
this relaxation step in the priority queue so that you know now becomes the minimum
we should extracted here
and we're only ever decreasing he's because we're always replacing larger eyes with small amounts
this is the state of the art general method that involves a lot of hand
tuning and taking parameter
this is the result of phd thesis
a lot of work to do that
by the fact that we that a lot less time
this is kind of of
upper bound baseline this she did this is actually
if you know the structure
and do the alignment
this is the best that you
there is still some room for improvement
but actually one
all right
more recently the second two
going for bioinformatics knowledge information people
but it stays the same thing you just have to specify these three things
you have to specify what the representation with the loss function
so here's the problem in information retrieval
so you we have to present results
people in this room probably going to be happy
but the rest of the world is not
all the people who are actually looking for
stock quote on servicemaster company which has
stocktickersymbol st
i'm not going to be happy used
everybody is looking for the french magazine as the is not
all students of that tremendous on my dad knows what i find that not going
people in the information retrieval have recognised is
the kind of putting
on x into one basket just looking at one interpretation of the is not strategy
in particular
kind of user happiness is a submodular function
users are not going to be happy all you don't give them any relevant results
they actually almost
they're actually quite happy if you just give them one
so better ranking to present in this case would actually be something like the right
people with looking for
machine learning methods are going to be happy people looking for the dog
because overlapping
boca fans happy
but to be able to do this we have to
he able to model dependencies between
in particular we have to recognise the model that once you presented one machine learning
we don't want you want to build another results for
in this way become structured prediction problem we have to model based
so how are we going to do that
so formally
only the problem of given act
which is the set of results may be
the top one hundred results that are current search engine
and y is
the subset that we want to predict in the top ten
so the mapping from the set to itself
actually want to to ranking
so how are we going to represent the problem well going to follow the idea
because microsoft called essential pages
we say OK topic diversity
is the same as were
if you think about this diagram here
these are all the words that are occurring in the one of the with current
these are the documents
let's say the one hundred documents
this result
the way that i want to pick the subset is
to maximize the
total number of work that have myself
i want to take a set of documents that kind of covers almost all of
the words
that occur in poor results
this is the max coverage problem is NP hard but they're good approximation for example
the simple greedy approximation it's this one
one wraps along one over e approximation because someone
dv over the last several
works probably is expected to start
it is the largest area covered most work
you take the document that
if you subtract the words that already covered covered most of the work that would
be too here
you know which of the next document covers the
kind of gives the most marginal benefits
before is actually bigger but
most of the work already covered e three
and then before and this way you cover all of almost all of the work
that would be
but as you sound like to put it in a corner of the world
is not all words are equally important
what we actually want to learn in this problem here is
what are the right way
get to each individual words so important words
the important covers get highway unimportant what should go away
and again with the model that has a linear function
and we can put in features like
you know
of mister woodcock occur in the results that
how often does occur at least in the title of the results that we can
come up with a whole set of features again because into the feature vectors
let me skip the details actually use songs targets ICML
two tuesday
i to that
so we've picked
now representation with
come up toward the argmax just we
is the loss function that they're going to use
we want
the kind of popular topic we have
i was also one two three four five subtopics and subtopic because the documents in
this one
and our loss function is following what we want to make sure we cover the
popular topics
the loss is just going to be
it's a forty one d ten
he won covers this subtopic t ten
however this subtopic
uncovered these we hear less
all are of you well
that's very low
if we
predicted d two and seven
these two here
then we will cover only these two documents you all of which i know
and again the separation oracle that we need to training and actually is
again the same structure to the next problem so we can use the same
so we just plug this into the general cutting plane learning algorithm
and here are the results
this is for
it's kind of hard to get there for this because
the learning problem that people have
look but there is data from the track interactive track
we're documents actually the in labeled subtopics
and so
you can think of the machine
and the
so you
you think
of course want
we have one or o
well of
so for me
you know who
i don't know
what we want
this is
she was
he was
so what
that is
four forty
well what i like about you when you
but i would like to
o or one that
all right
and the distinguished by
a formal semantics OK typically model theoretic of us a bit about what i mean
by that later
there fragments of first-order
and the closely related to propositional modal in dynamic logic
and one of the kind of key things about is that in general we have
the provision of inference services OK so we have some kind of sound and complete
decision procedures for key
inference problems and there are no a number of implemented systems of these things
so there's been
kind of a body of research
in this area has led to the
optimisation the reasoning procedures and implementations of system
essentially in DL
we have we apply this model theoretic semantics because we have the notion of interpretations
which are kind of mappings we have a domain of discourse the things that we're
going to be talking about
and then we map classes to sets of objects in this domain and we map
properties to sets set of pairs of objects individuals not to individuals
and then there are a bunch of rules that describe how we interpret constructs in
OK and they tell us when an interpretation is kind of respecting the statements that
we make with ontology
OK most will see a little bit more about that later
but the key thing to
remember really i think this is in some ways this is perhaps the the one
thing that i want to take home when you're thinking about about how is that
class description
OK so if i have some class description is essentially a characterisation of the individuals
that are members of that class was telling me about the things that are members
of that class
so you made you may see talk of various different species of owl
OK so there this notion of what we call layering and how
so there are three species in the in the al
recommendations and these are OWL full OWL OWL DL and OWL lite
OK we have what we call syntactic layering to say effectively they use the same
vocabulary OK so every OWL lite ontology is is lbl ontology is an alpha ontology
and there's also a notion of semantic layering which is the
but the semantic should agree
within the if i have a light ontology the inferences that i can draw upon
the OWL lite semantics should correspond with those that i'm using OWL DL semantics and
using l full semantics cases the the layering is kind of nicely behaved as it
so in know full
essentially what we have in full is
rdf with some additional vocabulary case we have RDF plus some extra vocabulary that likely
to talk about
my classes and properties and i've made cannot specify some kind of additional constraints markov
so there is no restriction on the way in which we use the vocabulary he
essentially kind of anything you can do in RDF you can do an awful
and in order to cope with this an RDF style model theory OK which which
allows you to kind of interpret southall ontologies are going to concentrate a bit more
there on the fragment we all the species known as DL
now within DL what we have here now is we have
some restrictions on the way in which the vocabulary can be used and this is
this is primarily to ensure that this then corresponds to the the language is that
these description logics such as first-order logic OK so for example we can do things
like restrictions on the way in which we can the kind of statement so we
can make it so we can alter the underlying ontology vocabulary itself
OK so i can't say things about the built-in vocabulary
so that's kind of so there is a notion that one needs to separate out
the the resources we talk about the language and resources which talk about the content
of my ontology can we can we can make statements about the language with LDL
there are restrictions on the kind of metamodelling that we can do
and the kind of characterisation of what constitutes ontology is defined by
by an abstract syntax which then allows that allows me to get back into RDF
graphs so i can characterize the the kinds of graphs that sit within this lbl
there's is a standard DL first-order model theory provided
and the and the claim benefit then is that this means that apply well defined
semantics we can understand the formal properties of the language and we can apply some
kind of known reasoning algorithms and use some implemented systems here
there's also a species called OWL lite which is kind of similar to DLP with
fewer constructs so some of the things we can talk about explicit negation or union
and the reverse space
and before
i did the shuffling into the card at
the probability of the front face being
white or black and reverse space being white or black
the probability of this hair
being white and white with one
the probability that being
brown brown was one third
the probability of
other two things the third because you don't like
the carbon black why can't just coming along
and this
fifty fifty
which was held
so the state there
and i think there
that's is the joint probability of everything
and now with this strong probability we can
data and anything else you want to throw in
and data is what given what given is more in this world
today the white came up
so we condition on the front being white
and we can then look at the probability
be reverse
white for example by on ising this probability distribution
and we get to this
this may not convince people who still really think fifty fifty fifty fifty how can
you say it's two-thirds that's rubbish
and so i've got one final argument
that i hope will help
and then once this argument has been accepted maybe will compel you to agree that
it's a good idea is right and probably everything
so here's the final argument and it's not that the reverse was indeed white
that's happened to be true but it didn't have to be
the argument goes like this
imagine we play this game lots of times and instead asking
what's the probability of the faces what i i always asking the question what's the
probability that the face is the same as the one you're seeing now
okay so
this one saying this one and the same this one and not the same so to that the time
the face will be the same on the back as it is on the front
so when you see a white
is to this chance that back is right
and when you see around the city firsthand the back is brown
so that's
not based on probability theory and i think it's a fairly compelling argument the correct answer is two-thirds
hopefully that's convinced you
that we should use probability theory because if you can't actually reliably solve this exercise involving just
one random variable which is which card another which is which way up when to run burial
problem if a smart audience if
graduates from cambridge
can't reliably solve this problem so i i know it's fine got the answer
that's really shows you
yeah inference is a little bit tricky
inference isn't totally straightforward humans are often very good inference but if you want to
be sure you get it right
use probability theory because probability theory will always the right answer
i okay
all right so let's now talk some more about noisy channels
and actually let me just
i remind myself a kind of let's talk through through this work where we're heading
is we're going talk about a bit more about inference
and we are also going to information measures for noisy channels
classic noisy channel is a binary symmetric channel at the top right
is obscured by any
while a cycle