it's definitely theorem something called came in theorem shows that
if you have an exchangeable random partition
then it comes
essentially then it comes from a random discrete measures
it's newspaper in discrete manner in this way
if and only if can
can agree not going to dwell on this today
i might come back to it tomorrow
vectors is induced random partitions so we have the dirichlet process
and induces
on random partitions and this
distribution on random partitions is called the chinese restaurant process
so you probably have heard both terms before
it certainly will if you go to machine learning conferences days
and the connection between the two is the directly process is a distribution on a
random discrete measures on the mixing action
the random partition that's induced this has a distribution which is called the chinese restaurant process
there's this
u u often
basically any paper that relates to the chinese restaurant process you see a picture like this
the idea is that these are tables
andy these are
what it very simply means customers are observations
and the numbers are the indices of the observation points come in
and the tables are clusters so they are the blocks of the partition
and then the customers sitting at a table simply another way of saying the data points in the cluster
are belongs to a certain block
i would quickly like to edit his trickery markets originally the chinese restaurant process
was not introduced has
has a distribution on partitions but on random permutations
i'm doing some pitman
use this
describe something like this where they
start points on these tables here
to generate random
random partition
a random permutation
and this random permutation is infinite
and that's pretty remarkable thing was not clear at the time you could do something
like this and the described this very simple idea with which you can generate this
and that's why by people in probability theory and more theoretical talk it's got excited about this
but basically what you do then is
in when you generate permutations the order in which people sit at these tables matters
if you want to generate a partition the order doesn't matter when he belongs who
is it only matters who is in which block
you get the distribution you get a distribution on partitions by throwing away the order
forget the order the solution and permutations you forget the order you get a distribution
on partitions
that's then also called the chinese restaurant process
in a way much simpler objects that's what we always use in
i would i would like to make a personal appeal you
if you write papers
on some bayesian nonparametric model
please don't call a chinese restaurant something
it's just not funny really it's
it has gone out of hand
it's an industry don't do it
don't participate
built these models but
call them something reasonable
when we look at these exchangeable random partitions these these are these are the objects
that you want to use a clustering now
want to clustering in a nonparametric bayesian way
unless something is is very odd
what we want to have is
an exchangeable random partition has a prior
and so there are exchangeable random partition the parameter
so basically what we have to ask is what distributions other an exchangeable random partitions
ten years ago
basically the only one that we knew we are the only one at least they
had already made to machine learning was dirichlet process
and today we have a much better picture
of what this is the landscape of these models looks like which models are possible
also to some degree which properties they have
even though there's quite a lot of work still to be done
and then and
quickly want to tell you a few words about the
here's a diagram of certain families of
of exchangeable random partitions
and we've seen a few of these so we've seen the dirichlet process
we've seen the pitman yor process and there's
an arrow here which indicates that
this is a special case of this
you can obtain the dirichlet process from the manual by certain parameters
okay we've also seen
the bayes mixture model where the distribution on
on the
the cluster sizes is simply directly distribution finite distribution
and so that's parametric
but it is exchangeable
so that is also an exchangeable random partition
and then we can generalize that and take a mixture of finite directly so in
the prior put in a mixture
and he remains exchangeable
okay so there is also a way of creating gender factor
so basically the ones i said in blue here are the ones we've seen before
and this one you are going to see on the next slide
and then there's a bunch of others you so there's is a large class of so-called crosslinking models
this is really not
i think this has really made it into statistics and machine learning this so far only studied in probability theory
then there's something called normalized completely random measures which is the very last class large
class of models and very useful
but it turns out that in a certain sense these
keep stivers might be
more useful
but most of this is very current research so on
this is all stuff you that was developed over the past five years
all right and you can see that these gives type measures you basically have errors
to to everything down here right
so that's a nice generalization
let me give you
heuristic description
description by circumstantial evidence what these gives type which not actually going to define them
because that would get a bit technical but i want to tell you what they
are and how we can think about
i will follow this classification here which has been suggested by
but you start with some
mathematics statistician
and this is this is very recent so you have an you know he he
has shown this
he using its talks but i think the paper is not even out it's just very current research
but i think this this classification you know
since all this stuff is ongoing work
i can't tell you whether this is the right classification might be that in ten
years we just understand things better
and we have a better one but this is i think currently
our best possible guess what things are going to look like
what would see is the following so he
he classifies
these models according to
the probability of creating a new cluster
and that is really a very neat idea because
because we're interested in the distribution on the cluster sizes
and that is controlled by how we create new clusters right so we can look at this probability
and use it to classify these models
he classifies them according to
what this probability depends on
so what could possibly depend on it could depend on
the number of clusters
you you need some time if you have corpus
you want to pass all these sentences
this stick sometimes particles flow
so maybe you can research
these expensive features
only four examples
well that may be
ambiguous way of current classification is not so
not so clear about it so that only a limited set of your
examples have to be passed but i show you an example of late so
make small clean
and finally we used techniques of active learning
to reduce the number of annotations
so active learning is a technique where
the system
two sons automatically examples from an unlabeled set
to be annotated by humans
so in the assumptions
by having them good examples labeled you can reduce the manual
annotation work
so this is why it's not it's not very clear sorry
maybe if few and large print out a slightly larger
it becomes clear
so we
just to the cascade approach
we had three levels in our cascade
in the first level
we were interested
in through its remember we have to classify
positive new positive negative and neutral
so in the first level usually there are many more neutral examples that
then positive and negative effects so in the first level we want to look for
neutral examples
can be of course nice sentences
with no feeling at all towards a certain product
but it can also be genk if you download from the webpage
you might also have lots of
but you cannot screen perfectly
o it's quite difficult to clean
maybe you know of of good clean of web pages
but at least the data that we receive from
from ten
they contain sometimes fragments of menus of also quite checks sentence
so maybe i forgot to tell first of all
we selected sentences
that contains search terms
that contain card names and moving
so we have a list of chord names that were search for list of movie
names that are search for in all these data in this dataset
and then we replaced the name of the current name of the move we just
in the sentence by the general called so we had more three examples
so we had to set
and then we did
ten fold cross validation or sometimes the averaged over five splits usually fall
cross validation
so we have data set of sentences
we knew that in the sentence
the entity is mentioned so we suppose that the and it is correctly recognised
so this is a task somehow escaped for real that task text
because you know named entity recognition might take only eighty percent of the curacy for
these brands or maybe eighty five
so this is the difficulty which we already skipped here in this exercise
first of all
in the first level
try to
we try to
it's too remove to throw out
o neutral
as many as possible future examples
so we had to have an aggregation of tree classifiers
which all had to be very certain about the classification
it's about the
if they were
so about the classification of the future example it is true and so this is
the idea
in the second level we
so here is an aggregation of tree classifiers so these examples of the all the
definitely classified in the second level we have a classification in three
in the two groups neutral positive and negative
but then for the examples where to this classifier was not certain about we
given we
input into it to love
and these were examples
maybe when you have
an opinion expressed
two towards different
different entities
or or or an opinion expressed
of the opinion expressed were different entities for instance so it could be a negative
feelings for BMW but the positive feeling for
proceedings of so
but of course we are interested in the feeling for see this in this case
this not the the case and be able to build a small crater from
it's hard
we tend to all the sort who is
are very control
to a lesser extent also
and all that generates those
the first thing
one of the more on you the
mike are for
it's very
we want to write
programme which primarily
o the
so her but really everything from scratch is a really bad idea and not only
and also
programs are going to communicate each other
a lot of people
because they have to look for
we need more might want to read what people write for readers
there's one
get some of the
the first people to
but this is about
reading and reading more than right because i actually read much more
many more intelligence than the average bits
because usually hoping people
with some of the getty supposed to build the
so that's why
one of them not all i've seen lots of success here
so people say
and the thing to me but i don't think about it though
the two opposing the term name or what
or four
email address
but you know that's like saying one thing wrong
i was doing
o point
all you can ask
six schools really also to two people
what is it
i understand that you can
create the service requires a lot
you know what things to read so that's a good thing
so the
it's not this
are we can change things change the more
all this is very important
it's a
it uses all and we told that stays
one more
four or less
three fixed exchange
if you can create an effective close
right so
that's one thing we're going to be learning how to do it
also mention
the idea
so much
the tower
seven hours were
the things he's trying to figure out
all right well there's no right
i thought it was like this
let me skip to this one for
we did this
should change which was to survey
how to solve
well there's always this
i had a good
all right
the company would been persuaded
maybe we would've killed enough people
that they would have been persuaded not to run this next trial
so it's it's a very dicey question i mean and make it is as simple as
i perhaps
but but
frank giles was persuaded i see no rationale to further delay moving to these designs
said doctor giles who is currently involved in eight bayesian based
leukemia studies they are more ethical
more patient-friendly
more conserving resources and more statistically desirable
my quest talked about simulations
um christian talked about simulations
we do this
simulations out the wazoo
you're gonna hate this
but one of the things that we do is we calculate type one error
so we can we have a very complicated design
but we generate
under the null hypothesis
to show what the type one error rate is
and sometimes if this is the registration trial-to-trial it's gonna go the fifty eight
we have to modify the design
get the type one error rate less than point of o two five
what that means is
that we've gone through this bayesian machinery we built this wonderful clever design
but then we made it frequentist
so other things as well
to recent
get rid of it
what is it
okay i
two recent clinical trials
with smaller sample size
one year they both use bayesian predictive probabilities actually
and they both use longitudinal modeling
but just to high profile
bayesian trials
this one again published in jama
journal american medical association
ah bee
abstract says a prospective multi-center randomized to one
unblinded bayesian design
study conducted in nineteen hospitals one hundred sixty seven patients
so this was
about a third less than the maximum
the company approached us
because the crew was slow
anne it was take forever that for them to finish the trial
could we converted into a bayesian
trial and we did and we did longitudinal modelling
together early information
and we did predictive probabilities such that if we predicted that he it's always going to be clear
with additional follow-up we stop study at that point
and we get
submitted it to
this is the journal
and the journal said
did a bayesian approach
you've heard the word bayesian in the abstract
we don't use the word bayesian are abstracts
now you can imagine
how i was
and i said maybe you don't understand
this trial was designed by a from a bayesian perspective
the protocol was bayesian
it was designed in coordination with the e fifty eight
it was approved for marketing
by the year after year in the basisof an expert panel
u have an obligation as a medical
to adhere to the bible medicine which is the protocol
therefore you must use
the bayesian approach in in the calculations
in abstract
because i thought i was whistling dixie that's
i thought it was you know what
i embarrassed enough so that there is
jamie used the word bayesian and also the primary analysis are all bases
well we did they did ask us to say what would be analog in the frequentist be
so we can communicate better to our audience
so we did have some analogs but you know going in the other direction taking
the data and doing a bayesian approach if the data were collected as a frequent
this is easy
going in the other direction is not so easy
because you don't know
what they
you know what the conference what he actual design the experiment was it was incorporated into the
frequentist approach so we did nominal things
don't i mentioned oncology perhaps the hardest
in oncology to study using an adaptive
early stage breast cancer and elderly women
because it tends to be
disease that innocuous in fact most if it is over diagnosed
patient would never
find out that she had the disease if you didn't do mammograms and sort harkened back
andy so these events are not very long in coming
i mean very long in coming
it took me a while to build this design because
these and see i said you've got to do
trial with two thousand patients
and i said we don't have two thousand patients will never finish the trial
if we have two to two thousand patients there was a long time and i finally had this inspiration
that i s okay his will do
we've got a six hundred patients
we'll do bayesian predictive calculations
if with additional follow-up
the probability of having a conclusion
yeah nay
in terms of these objective the trial
will stop the cruel
will follow the patients for the period time
and then published the results and
so they finally agreed that we could do that and so in clinical trials covered
said under sample size it said this is usually look it says it's a two
thousand patient trial
one other ones five hundred patient trial this one said
the sample size is six hundred ten eighteen hundred
surprise when we looked at six six hundred
the bayesian predictive calculation was such that we were going have an answer
we stopped the crows six hundred
final total was six hundred thirty six i think
we followed additional two years and published in
the new england journal positive results
are to have
to call on my favourite
well you
i think all right
around it
here we go
and this
no there are no
here we will
how right
it was very small you know
in fact
was the very
i have
show me
are you
of my life
because we want go
the term
from is
right so
the posterior you evaluated first and use that
as it were to mix over the predicted distributions given theta
and you get exactly the same answer
so the idea of bayesian statistics is
is that magnified is to use we're gonna use probability theory consistently to evaluate uncertainty in in all sorts of
situations we're we're interested in the given data
and we're now to do this because the bayesian view is everything is a random variable
every possible variable in your system observed or unbserved observable unobservable things that are you think
are parameters things that states of nature thing you know everything hidden visible missing
whatever it is they're all random variables
now that's not to say that
bayesians think they're all the same philosophically they don't they understand those are different
the future's different from the past bla bla bla
but they're just treated uniformly for mathematical purposes so we treat them as random variables
and it's just quickly is worth reminding ourselves that there's different sorts of randomness and indeed
the distinctions can be can can get quite blurred so
we sometimes distinguish between epistemological randomness and aleatory randomness
and the first of those is concerned with lack of knowledge things you don't know
and the second is to do with things that are inherently random
so I'm
indebted to my friend David Spiegelhalter how can I of this
and a problem is that you're euro coins don't have
don't have heads on them but
one of the several things wrong with euro OK I'll jump ahead to the
second step so
I I'm going to I'll hold up a coin imagine I haven't thrown it I'll hold it up
and I ask the audience what's the chance that this
will come up heads
OK what's the answer
we're not worried about silly things like coin being biased
and we're not worried about euros not having heads I then toss the coin flip it on the back
of my hand and I don't reveal it
I don't look at it or anything
I need to flip that I now say what's the probability that this is heads
OK so you're not quite nobody nobody's saying anything different from the half yet but you're a bit
a bit slower to say so
now I look at it OK and I know now what's the what's the chance
yeah OK I know it my chances are now zero or one what are
your chances
so something you know uncertainties are moved around
you are still getting fifty fifty I think
they take you longer to think to say so but
you know you don't you still don't have any evidence for one or the other
but something rather strange has happened because it's no longer random
what's happened is we've moved from it was tale by the way we've moved from something that was purely
aleatory it was determined by something in the future that was genuinely chance to
something that
is only epistemological it's just to do with something you don't know
and you and I think differently about it you know you thought at certain stage in
that experiment you had one view and I'd another so is in the
eyes of the beholder and so on
so the the the uncertainty can be of different kinds but we can
use the laws of probability to talk about both kinds
the different kinds can be perceived differently by different by different observers
so bayesians understand all that but they're still willing to use probability
for both purposes they use it uniformly and treat everything as a random variable
so the idea is to work throughout with the joint probability distribution you
you you put together in one huge model the joint distribution of everything you don't
know and everything you will know whatever their status where does that come from well it's not defined
it's not there's not a right answer it's something that's assessed you you
come to a scientific judgment about it you'll since
the result has to obey the laws of probability you will be guided by
the laws of probability in doing that
and then at some point we have some data you know we looked at the
coin or whatever it was and we model that process of of observation
by conditioning this joint distribution on the things we've observed
and we than use that condition distribution for everything else we want to know for our inference for our
predictions for our decisions and so on the probability distribution of the hidden variables given
given the visible ones so it's completely clean and
or let's say straightforward is philosophically straightforward but
you know it's not there's no particularly difficult philosophical ideas at that level
now I've got quite a long way
without mentioning likelihoods and priors don't think
and in a sense likelihoods and priors are a little bit
you know
they're not really the the front rank of the theory the the main thing we
need is this is this joint distribution
of observables and unobservables
but typically of course that Joint Distribution comes about by combining likelihood and prior
so the standard situation a sort of vanilla
is you got a parameter vectors theta you got some data Y you would have some numbers
and there are the two theta and Y they may be big vectors but they're just two objects we care about
and we gotta make inference about theta given Y
and as I've already said we gonna use we gonna use the conditional distribution of
theta given Y to make to make that inference and the key thing of course
is that
it's the joint distribution of theta and Y divided by the marginal distribution of Y
and that's as far as theta's concerned is proportional in theta
so the conditional distiribution we want to use for inference is just proportional to the joint distirbution
that you
decided on
and and
you know so we could just start with the joint distribution but but in fact we almost always
construct that joint distribution by combining the likelihood and the prior so so it
is it it is
considerable control or particle size means precipitation my conclusions in such rhetoric from the Pacific
nation of 5 sites where you find drop its effect is facing death and surfactants
so worst license
which are distributed in place so chemical reactions are limited to small specialty license and
the size of the property plotting yeah depends primarily on the size of the monsters
who just wanted to determine the particular water to affect the size of the uses
just changing my conclusion nation bearing
traditional reactions diesel
so by changing market
the composition and temperature of serious novel often plays a variety of different sizes and
that they don't want to go
With sizes approximately between on the parliamentary bloc party has the support Parliament met however
articles in general had no monetization so much lower to what we would produce a
take it to consideration only suggesting that the articles have different structures to what seemed
on high-resolution shown with crystalline Lionel particles of course thinking considerations that sell barometer of
spina Vichy surrounds you . 8 not only does it is difficult to walk talk
about recently the smallest number of articles for each the shell slice one-and-a-half not only
does justice to set parameters approximately 1000 km such articles on the use of high-resolution
mutual most of us
material follow own distinct areas
regular reviews so to individual
PDS really you know what the show
the presence of all Wilfried constituting silencing approximately the relationship probes the corresponds to starting
position so just a warning to the electorate prosecutors would not say why somewhere where
properties so had to go a step further by using X-ray absorption techniques like scenes
of Matisse's show variations manganese they achieve a suggesting that
the latest average dependency of manganese and ceramics found to be 2 points that
I'm not partly because the disease was estimated to be the last for the largest
state-mandated sized worldwide and on 5 and 3 bus water on a small amount of
articles suggesting combination of manganese free bus in many ways for lots cooperation of lenders
full blast into the speed spiniferus structures and Marion you would want to use bop
material so the structure
the structure of particles have been started using excess and its views
the new distribution of next at a restaurant in while we would hear the suspected
the it reminded me of the firearms in the summer of the was like that
its oxygen at the center of the next 2 weeks and the desert is favored
to those use of
function of the site where they cooperated with the marked a significant recuperation of selected
decides he wants to use the operation
but if we compare the of Bob
talking we could see a decrease in the on a peak was formed to stick
and how do you choose that
a large number but the larger is the worse it gets
let me first rate algorithm analysis should be obvious why it is the case
i draw sample
both sides a bit low
if we could just raise it for the time being
i draw samples from q effect
from the blue distribution is sample number from gauss in distribution so that is just
excise it got around then
one common one
and then you multiply that by hand
then what i drew that sample
i'm going to think i'm going to take an interval
the zero value
and the value of the function and time timescale effects
so this hide here
would be and
of x
so you have to evaluate we basically evaluating the cows in at that point
but you can evaluate
q effects
in some problems in econometrics that's not true you sometimes you can't evaluate the topic
in machine learning often that's true
you have that we draw a random number uniformly between here and here
the way you do that is you just wrote a number between zero and one
ex aequo
and then you must then you evaluate
and the scale factor
and then you multiply that times that number that you should number there
and the vertical axis
if the number is above the red line
if you is about the red line you throw it away
if it's below you accept it
so that when we throw away
we pick another one
o it's inside
so we accept it
o it's inside we accept it if you keep doing that
it's sort of should work
where this is high
be high probability of these guys being accepted
as long as i have a sensible q effects
and i'm going to give you
should a demo of that
so in matlab
you need to specify the number of iterations
god this was long time ago
the mean the number of bands the mean and the variance is if the proposal
distribution and so on but let me move to the algorithm
again the algorithm is just this
you generate a random number between zero and one that to you
you generate this proposal distribution from q
from the gods and distribution
q has mean q various sq
and this is just agustin number
the from gauss and distribution
you evaluate the target distribution we usually talk about the distribution of interest is the
target distribution
the target is just
by model gauss and distribution
here it's got some distribution
with the mean it's zero with white point three
and then there's another cousin distribution
with mean ten
and white zero point seven so it's sort of a bimodal distribution just like an
example is on
the proposal a single galaxy which has mean and q so these match
it has variance is q
standard deviation q
and then what we do is we evaluate
the effects of the and q effects like i had before
the acceptance
one e to the minus nineteen nineties because unfortunately computers are discrete device and continues
devices they have to deal with condition
and then if
if you is less than alpha
in other words if you is less than that height
you accept
if it's not
you throw it away
this ensures that it's between the blue line and the red line in the what
if you rejected do nothing
and then the rest is just a lot
and if you run this
you draw sample that's not a good one
i actually that's a good one that's below
on the first you pick on the x axis then you pick a uniform number
you rejected it
and then that when you accept
so now you've got the approximation of the posterior distribution
the target distribution the posterior distribution is bimodal thing
and you have access the right thing
and this is the approximation so with two samples we have agreed creamy lousy approximation
of it
and then you continue doing this thing that that that that that that that
just OK i'm doing this on purpose his rejection sampling is inefficient
and if comparing the actions that were
slightly faster and see it
we help before them it away
bit by bit
in the magic works
and you get an approximation
for one hundred samples starts looking a lot better
starts looking like a
good approximation of the posterior distribution
why is this bad
for cooking
what's the obvious problem with this approach
OK for maybe just enough product spaces may
did this last week OK
so if you have some vector space x
for instance of those areas
is it is an inner product space is that these two real values symmetry two
function exists his gets
that satisfies
scally x
always because it is only
and if you have
the enough project is treat if you have this property
this is the scalar product of x and it's equals zero if and only if
x against could
and the once you have an idea for that so symmetric bilinear
so which
check which satisfy parity to two
that's because it
dimension the two
then you can also decided on which is this is
square root of this kind of product of x and x OK this is the
classic definition of inner product space
but then fact is it is more than that
and despite its strict inner product space itself is was kind of a product of
x by x
which is zero then you have
you have the property of x equals zero
but more you the political properties
so to full of topological properties one is separated to is completeness
so completeness we suggest the following property
if you have some
caution sequence
so remember because she sequence is such
you have
if you take two
so test is to take you
the difference between two
the value of fuel course sequence
it takes norm you look at the
this set
so the maximum of this and if and then it goes to towards still when
n goes to
two at infinite speed that's the difference between two values
this is the
it is increasing
the completeness research to the following facts should get some
some courses sequence when it converges
it converges in
i suspect set h
OK so if you have this completeness properties
you have some cushy sequence it converges if it converges you it converges
the intercept
intersect match so here
is this space because we have decided
so you keep
the cause the convergence to the limit it was
so in that space
more value as properly it's so severity was supposedly if there is a countable set
of element h one h i if h is a space such search
that for all h
small h
in which there is i so there is some elements here
which is
so sorry i forgot
which is the
which can be closed
enough and good enough to pitch
so if you are
you can find
sign the conclave and that's fine but the accountable set of elements in h such
you can always fully function phi functions
among these elements which is
closed as much as possible so we have to
the that's part of h then you have to provide
OK so you must
you must be careful that respects is not only the scalar product it also
the political properties
so i'm going back to my
you that space
so the one
so we have this kind of for the and now
we have this function in space
in fact
he look at the property of the space you will get
an interesting properties
which is called in fact were produced
so what you are
if you have a function f in HK
at some point x
in fact it
it can be written as the scalar product of the function f
we the function
six to at some point as the same point x
and especially
for the can nuances or to work for this important
if you want to compute the image
also x x prime
using k
then you can use the scanner in
so it's not really the theory we want but let's take a look at it
for a moment
now there is
let's try to understand a bit more this correspondence so there's something that was noticed
by a general call for a long time ago
which is that if you have any theory
whose interactions are meant to matrix like as in young means
there is a very nice different way of reorganizing feynman diagrams by using what is
called the double line of topological expansion
so the idea
it is the following all your particles say the young man gauge bosons
can be thought of as
little dipole source strings with two
all the charges have the twins
technically that's because they belong to the so-called joint representation and all the interactions are
matrix multiplication like so here is a vertex four four gauge bosons here is a
cubicle vertex for for you was on some stories here and there
and now when you write your feynman diagrams instead of using
g young means
to organize the expansion into groups as we usually do
you can try to use instead in times g squared young males this is called
the top of the coupling parameter and the number of colors
and you see
that that is at each given order in and there is now of course series
in powers of that
but this
diagrams that but given up fixed them out
characterized by the fact that they can be thrown
on the surface of fixed topology here is the simplest case no powers of n
i can do all this diagram on this
i can easily drawn from and its first director miro has alarmed before because you
see that the article vertex that g square
another g and g that she seeks another forty one g eight hundred forty one
you know that is correct
no g six g seven g eight country have three quartic and two cubic so
that g eight
so i have indeed g a
a factor let's count the numbers of fan when the end comes from the number
of colors that can be done in this little loops now there are four
triangular loops here that's some into the four so that g eight and to the
four and that's exactly happened to the forum there is no one's
left of
but if i try to write almost the same diagram but with
these different running of the quark lines
what you see this quiet trying now crosses over to the other side instead of
try getting it game aged fifty eight
but now if you count the number of
loops here you will find that there is only one loop so there is only
one hour
and this gives you sorry if you are very short story one
two QB two particle that this is that g
therefore two cubic that's due to this six
there is one power of and so the whole thing is due to the six
and that's lambda cube over one
and all squared
and now this one about an inch where the
is actually telling me that they cannot draw the surface any more on this i
need the disk with handle because this thing has to go around handle otherwise it
would intersect days
so there is this
different expansion of government theory which was not like of this actually makes it look
a bit more like string theory
so because of these theorists have long suspected that the large n limit of game
is a weakly coupled string theory
the APS if the correspondence has made this hypothesis very sharp now
and here is a very precise but partial dictionary of how you would associate quantities
from the two sides
the power of copying lambda
the and i cant create good enough
function and binary think it's too long and it's the slow again
and if you are really smart guy's
what every programmer who are living in the
twenty one century should do in this twenty first century should do it
second there is this moment of time
you should
look for an open source
that means you are the station
there are a huge number of this project and that's good enough and that things
that don't have any any other questions to discuss
you can take the same as
the most popular ones
and you have four j
this is a last
i believe five
and it does everything for you
OK so at this moment in the game situation where
we decided
i can be a year
we give up
and you will take of this package
and all of them are implemented inverted file
all of them are implemented all this ranking algorithms and everything is like a series
of this
but if you are really interested in into in development of information retrieval systems
and if you go
one to look into the wreckage how they organize journal
or you feel
already using these packages and you want to understand
scalability limits of this for example can i take it scene
download the seen from watching or an index of the internet
good i don't know we need to
to look forward and to analyse policy to
we need to develop rather so OK
well all my people after this can stop listening to my lecture using this site
using this powerful and very good too
stupid and naive
i think that you are going for going to implement some
but before
the next step of implementation we want to map
this is very good
if you are a developer
you're going to implement some
before implementing so during all implementation you should do evaluation
in addition to that
i'm not talking about boring unit
that are also unavoidable
but then talking about testing the whole system
you don't know what is
gordon what where we don't know in what direction your morning you need to
how this time so you need some
characteristics of your of your search engine
and i don't know why but the main characteristics for the most people are church
maybe because
hard drives so cheap
and people are not thinking about the the search let's start from
is from speed if if it's so important for us
so we have
different size of collection
and he had shows whedon judged it's simply a number of
query that our system can process during the
some period of time
of course it's not so everything is not so simple because
different areas some queries about some queries go
to be or not to be the but we're because a a lot of a
lot of things to analyse it all common words
and the very very rare words it's very good
but we assume that we have
gordon makes a collection of various
queries from real users are going to use this collection or maybe maybe ought be
doing to record i mean i know you already
have all the square
for small collection naive kind this is the
because to one
because you don't need to analyse many structured only to search in an addiction
simply analysed document
then you will see that signature file is faster because the signature file again you
don't need to search in any dictionaries simply looking into this table
that's good
and for foreign inverted while
feel to be the slowest one because we need to search in big dictionary even
if you if you can see it in the dictionary file still searching the dictionary
and then on you get this fourth-placed and doing something is for this to get
so you see this very ground this recurrence
o sixty eight
thinking about what will be the next
you see that
for all all approach
steed is reducing pretty pretty fly
we can we can do more detailed analysis about the things that we simply don't
don't have time for
on what this speed depends on what we can do
the most smart idea is to change the
because without change or if you can change this
significant you can do with some small modifications without change varies but you see that
there is defined
four this car powered band
so we need
i can look into forest
another way the size of the habits of self
it depends on size of databases graphs all
going down some the
currently there still
because you don't see any numbers the
because it sets to graphs
actually it's not clear i i didn't do this experiment when i draw the graphs
you've graphical package so
it's it's from the top of my head
and i i believe that are very good computer you have much
because he and on
IBM XT
what sort of been talking about so far you can think of
i was assuming that you knew the model
right i was assuming that you know you're given a fixed graph structure you knew
those functions that were sitting on the edges are on the cliques those are somehow
given to you
and all you're trying to do is
maybe someone giving noisy observations you are trying to combine your data maybe future data
to make predictions are inferences
but in practice it's it's very rare that someone is going to come along and
hand you model it's not given two and a silver platter in practice you have
to actually estimating both the parameters of the model that is
what the form of those compatibility functions are potential should be and also there's this
sort of more general issues actually estimating the graph structure
so really
this is the typical setting applications that you really have to think that both the
structure of the model and the parameters are unknown and
to believe in trying to estimate them on the basis of available data
so for instance if i was doing image processing
say i wanted to compute disparity maps or i want to denoise or segment images
typically what you do of course is collect some large database of images and from
that database you're trying to learn something about the structure images you try and fit
your your model to the particular structure of that class of images
as much as you can do that you know derive power from your model
sam spoke about these problems but the problem of parameter estimation on one hand is
pretty easy to state
in certain cases it's quite easy to solve but actually in general will see it's
pretty difficult to solve as well
there's a bit of a chicken and egg problem here that all mention that
essentially in order to to solve this in general you actually need to perform inference
or marginalisation
for instance within the ECM algorithm you need to do that is an inner step
so it's
you really can just escape the complexity of performing these summations are marginalizations even when
you're doing parameter estimation in general
so just briefly maximum likelihood is to classical principles statistics
i would tell you that i suppose i give you a set of samples these
would be let's assume there would be
independent identically distributed
the imagine your model is parameterized by some class of those compatibility functions
this could be a text database be image database we you'd like to do somehow
choose those compatibility functions to maximize the likelihood of seeing that data
it's certainly to do the reasonable thing to do and under reasonable conditions it's it's
asymptotically consistent in the sense that if you were given infinite data
and you solve this problem you would get the right model in the end so
if you someone is kept giving you data more and more samples
in the end this procedure would give you back the right model that's that's what
consistency is
so as i mentioned in in fully observed up models this is actually very simple
let me just rewrite the compatibility functions in a certain way and this is gonna
come up later it's convenient to start writing things in terms of exponentials you sort
of have a weighted sum over configurations he has some indicator functions and these are
parameters the status sort of given one number for every configuration within the clique that
you can take what you're trying to do is is that these numbers essentially
so if you just had a for instance a binary image you can think about
in a two by two matrix i'm just writing this exponential of a set of
four numbers like this
those be my parameters
the reason i'm doing this in this special case it turns out that the log
likelihood takes a very nice form you end up just with a linear function of
your parameters times
basically it what known as empirical marginals are sort of you be taking counts of
the data figuring out how many
sometimes the data assumes a particular configuration and you get away to a certain weight
it's normalized for each one of those
so it's very simple the thing that it's also important is that this the here
this was that normalisation constant remember that thing that was just making the distribution sum
to one
remember i said before that pops up it appears all over and so here it's
appearing in this is the function that you'd like to optimize
c is fixed
you'd like to optimize over the parameters
and one thing that's coming up is that you need to optimize function involves log
see if this you need to be able to for instance compute this or derivatives
of that
so this is actually very simple as mentioned that it the optimality conditions for given
an optimisation problem
the first thing you would have learning calculus is that you would take derivatives to
try and find where the derivative is zero you've got signed words flat
so you take gradients you set them to zero this this simple problem i'm looking
at it is unconstrained
and if you do that it turns out that
the optimality conditions what they end up saying is that you should take the empirical
marginals accounts from the data
when you take the derivative of this function has a very nice property that what
it outputs is what marginal distributions the
makes it easier for us to assume that
probabilities are always positive in particular from microphone fields
but you see that a requirement
o so that later today approach from probably one
probably only to more
so this can be done always right
in this first line there is absolutely no assumptions
well let's go ahead
let's just keep on doing this procedure
because here we have a joint distribution in very much the same way as you
know we have drawn
well let's just do exactly the same process here
and people goal
at the end of the day will reach these
but people at all
will be able to represent his joint probability distribution exclusively
by conditional probabilities
so that's the trick
we represent is joined by conditional
and we still have a marginal probability
that year
i'll just for simplicity of representation here
let's just defined is smaller than i as the set of all is
j more than a
so it's more than five years one two three four
and then they can just write these
expression in this way is the product
from i two n
of p of x i given x smaller than
because all these files here that after the conditions by
they have
a smaller index then the wild the is on the left hand side
because i chose to do that in this way because i'm allowed to do
because of this
but notes that there's nothing really very special about this particular label
you agree with me that a campaign is labeled as a which
i mean
my choice of these living was completely out you know
i contribute them as i wish and will still be true
so you should know by
i hear permutation of this label
such that pi j
is smaller than pi i for all i and j
belonging to
so in this case we have phi is equal just one
this will be the permutation the
let's say that can only temptation whatever you call
you can certainly write the following
we can write
this as
p of x phi i x
smaller than
which not these ones
the belonging to less than nine i find it less denies this
i'm sorry this is not really less that this is just the motivation for this
but but that i
i wanted to write this explicitly here to avoid any possible
question so
this is just the patient will the the set of indices
where the elements are all the natural numbers
apart from his mother
so basically i mean the point is that they can write any probability distribution
in this way
where i have positive probability OK
just like this
if i can write in this way
so i'm making no
assumptions here
it will be useful c
can you see why this will be used
i mean we've seen conditional independence already right
and remember that when we were studying conditional independence basically what we had
is that
we had that condition in bar here in some reliable
and then suddenly we have a set of three variables we have two articles on
the other side
also condition
so we made
yes that seems to have a factor here
factorizations this represents any graphical models
this is how have factorizations be possibly the factorizations
which is given in in terms of conditional independence maybe if we have the right
conditional independence statements
we'll just feet
some of these factors and defectors will suddenly shrink
that's exactly what we are going to see
so any probability distribution can be written in this work
let's assume
the following
conditional independence statements all now we are going to make an assumption so far there
is no such
now we are going to make this
we're going to assume
that these conditional independence statements hold
remember that when we have a conditional independence statement
there are several ways right
conditional independence statements at a
well the other one which is known only to reach which
actually tries to understand the text a little bit more
which performs live some kind of form semantic analysis and then it represents meaning and
other that generates a smaller version of the same content some of this is a
little bit harder problem now let's
see what's techniques
first we have this selection based
there are usually has very three
phases and the all
three quite simple so first we take text analyse it
so this analyzing means just splitting down into the basic units which are sentences then
determining its important units
this would be synthesis or pieces parts of sentences by some kind of simple
four men usually and then we are in synthesizing the appropriate output and this is
this would be a kind of formula
which is often
used in determining its important points so
weight or importance of
sentence or parts of the part of the sentence is determined by a couple of
attributes i location in the text some
q phrases of this special words which are used in in the sentence that either
sentence starts with it's important to and of course then the system says well must
be important and that's included in summary a couple of statistic statistical information mobility the
this TFIDF weights and so on which mentioned before and maybe some
additional heuristics which
authors include and that's it and this formula
produce some kind of lumber and then all the sentences in the document i just
sorted by the weights and measures the top most sentences are
written output that's it so you feel
this is the screen from microsoft word so here have the threshold
and by moving this threshold physically you're
you get different sentences from the text and that
in the sentence appears at at the beginning of the paragraph then it's more important
to consider this one of these five factors from this formula giving some results
the other
technique or set of techniques i so-called knowledge reach some summarisation very said somehow here
we try to understand the text a little bit more and
so i will present here one example one which we
a with colleagues from microsoft research other basically the idea was the following that cities
are then step procedure what we did
again the beginning we have a document which is split into sentences then we perform
departing of this document and the next step is name entity disambiguation so
each different forms of
the name of the person company or place which appear in documentary tried to consolidate
in the same form so that george bush bush or president
fall in the same category here then we perform anaphora solution which means that all
the pronouns like he she would be replaced with the proper name
and then we extract subject predicate object triples
and the generated graph
and then by having such a graph then we learn
which parts of the graph more relevant and which are less
proceedings from the by simply by machine learning techniques so we have
the corpus of documents and summaries another this corpus we learn
how summaries
look like in graphs and by having such a model that we can extract also
important parts of this semantic graphs also unseen documents so here's an example so if
have the document
tom went to town in a bookstore he bought a large book so this bomb
would get replaced here
is he will get replaced and then we would extract all
three puts out of it and then the more likely to generate such a graph
can be learned such graph so this would be an example
so this is the full document and then
summarisation sexual extracting just the most relevant parts of this graph and this set a
set so this works quite well actually it it's not really or performing but still
it this is an interesting alternative representation of the content of cork on canonical because
of the content of the document
and this is another example so if this is the full
text this is a summary
so this would be the summary graph of such documents show now short them on
how we can
play the content of document
so this is a news documents from
l use or something
from nineteen two to this was the test corpus
chris the
so this is the full documents now if e
reduce association here we it all the learning and the model is behind for each
the following content is provided under creative commons license
your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or to view additional materials from hundreds of MIT courses
his MIT opencourseware OCW MIT that EDU
to get started
one announcement and that is that
reminder about the celebration of learning on wednesday
october second
test two
it will have coverage
spanning lecture seven three seventeen seven three seventy
so the
material that the new material that i'm going to introduce today will not be
covered but certainly this little review is worthwhile
and going back to seven with the beginning avionics
what i wanted to do today was used
this set the stage briefly review where we were last day when we looked at
the emission spectrum
the target an x-ray tubes are plotted
the intensity versus wavelength so long wavelength is low energy energy is increasing from
right to left
and what we see is the family of
nested curves
each taking a different plate voltage
low voltage gives us
low-intensity high-voltage gives high intensity so we see this whale shaped
background which we refer to as the continuous spectrum abrams' strong and then once we
reach a critical voltage
beyond which we start to see the second set
o lines here
which have indicated in
and this is the characteristic spectral and it's quantized it's not continuous we have discrete
values of
wavelength associated with energy transitions within the target nodes transitions are prompted by
the ejection of inner shell electrons and that doesn't occur until you get to a
certain critical applied voltage which translates into a certain critical ballistic and energy on the
part of the incident electrons
and there are few features here that we can point out
the various discrete
wavelengths of the characteristic spectrum are calculable
the KL for the l alpha
o lines are calculable by mostly slot which is given here
were the NF in and i are associated with the
spring a particular transition for k lines it's the transition from two to one
and screening factor is one
for the k alpha transition for the ll transition
it's from three to two and screening factor in that case is seven point four
so we can calculate these discrete values and the other point that we can calculate
on this curve is the leading edge of the continuous spectrum
the leading edge of continuous spectrum is the
designated here is the shortest wavelength which obviously is the highest energy and that derives
from total transfer of incident ballistic energy of the electron to
and capture the electron and that's the shortest wavelength given by the doing hunt law
which is twelve thousand four hundred over the plate voltage
giving you value
of wavelength and angstroms
so i think we're ready now
probe atomic arrangement with x-rays and in order to do so we're going to rely
on two
factors first of all we're going to model
we're going to model the crystal
as an array of mirrors
in other words we're going to look at
the atoms in the crystal and consider each other as acting as a mirror
this will
give us
that we can exploit in a very simple model
so let's model atoms
model atoms as mirrors
and that's going to allow us to use the laws of specular reflection
the laws of specular reflection
and the one
most critically rely on is that the angle of incidence
equals the angle
of reflection
the incidence equals the angle of refraction so that's the first thing that we've
and the second thing that we use is interference criteria
we're going to apply
interference criteria
so let's take a look at what i mean by that
we have two possibilities
we can have multiple beams
coming in phase or we have multiple beams coming out of phase and so here's
where we talk about i'm going to show will sketch were plotting amplitude
this is some
electromagnetic signal amplitude versus time
amplitude versus time so
let's look at two
we have some temperature and the child is basically the daily average temperature in the
form of a weather station and what we're trying to determine whether a full occurred
on this trace now
what we know is in this case has not been a full for the first
fifty days which is concerned the last
they fifty today seventy one interesting whether that forces that would build a good
profile of user behavior clearly this is not going to work because what the temperature
was two months ago is not going to be
very helpful predictive of what's going to happen on one particular day
two months later
but if you want to find the weather stations had to have the similar sort
of traces i don't have to be geographically locate similarly located could be examples
i have a jew on the cosine quite quite far away from each other just
as long as they recently had a similar behavior
it lies at the top
so we can say well this
look at the time fifty tonnes seventy in more detail
we can see at time
taken sixty eight
weather station has deviated quite greatly from its paper and indeed that constitute a fault
in the system
compare that to the the
four population of
of weather stations in the consequent density is in this but just basically overlaying on
on the whole population you can see this is the point here where
the folder
again is compatible with some genuine global outliers so
we could better to find these if we want to set a threshold
this sort distance was an outlier
then it will probably get an awful lot of false positives after this is
just those so simple examples is the basic that method again now page divided on
multivariate continuous data which is timeline basically
the crucial thing here is that what we'd like to know what other accounts doing
at the same time so this is what we need to solve the timeline the
concept so very and we do is
she have appeared when we know they are
we can just
basic at the moment the distance from p paper
of the target to the centre of the people who just take the mean of
the values and the current of vice versa matrix and discover distance
so what
what term
well the point is an outlier not we have extended set threshold was set distance
the mahalanobis distance is different too
including the generalisation euclidean distance and that the lack of points which are the same
distance from the distance from the the mean would be a circle in this case
let's distances the generalizes to an ellipse
so in this case the typical points which are
here the blue dots
what with a certain threshold which of two such as this ellipse here we can
see that the target value is now
basic some problems with using the this distance especially for building people
as with outliers occurring in the paper this can occur because we can we can
misfortune transactions and they can be then contaminating appeared
that's the types of issues that can occur outlier masking this is an example where
some outliers down here
has shifted the distance such that are
it lies now
basically on the on the special and in
that's what i'm asking this
the converse where
a data point which is strictly an in
then because of the defamation due to outlast comes in out south
so we need to consider
how to
robust cases of are some techniques for robustifying against
outliers from distance for the computation intensive
so we just use simple heuristic which was
an account that has deviated strongly from this paper of time t should not contribute
to any other people database one system twice once again said scores for all the
then for each
target can we look at its peak members and just select this percentage of those
we're trying to use the seventy percent of those just to help
another issue is that is not necessarily the case that you can deploy people last
on all accounts so is a simple matter of people qualities this quote this question
here is based at a certain time period
first one specific time points
which is measured the
the distance of
targeted to the centre of the
the mean of the period
a slight complications at different times of the
we need to know what i'd like to scale the data standardized so we'll standardised
and then some of
for example here
each time point
i would rather we basically is what in the data
and so here then it is in is commensurate
and it's it's standpoint in this sum is these quality values together
and so the smaller the quality the better the this is trapped this particular target
and so select the number of
but it tracked to target counts
after the building of peer groups so this is more of problem specific
it's possible already which what the people membership base an example would be
employed for detection so people with the same job description you could just put together
and see how they
if they based the north end of one of the d gates again that might
be considered unusual behaviour so with an example of this would be the
rbm forty management system
probably what's in healthcare reform in the united states
and what they do that you can just take they tend to some new york
and compare them all to see his claiming the most advanced on the health insurance
but what we'd like to do is to infer membership from the actually behave the
time series themselves what we need and this is different measure similarity between time series
and that again is essential problem specific thing and we'll discuss one example of what
a simple use
the dataset
in simple cases like
every single words and multiwordstring compoundstring but
when you have a relational nouns like mother temperature you have to
two classification
by hand so
mother denotes
mothers relational noun in the sense that
it relates to arguments someone and their mother temperature in
something and its temperature
and there are three
options you have for your relational nouns
there's the predicate denotes are going around which all go through
you can also search
the denotation
a certain make it the notation assertion in the relationparaphrasemt and then you can also
use nounsemtrans
so that will get us into the center some trans predicates they get to that
the nodes are going around
here's an example of it in
four other denotes the
relation mother
the relation of because mother
is a binary
relation holds between something and the mother
so the
term other
refers to the
the second argument
what that entails
is that
the denotation of mother theword
is the set of things
four which
they are the mother
for of things that are mothers basically
relation exists instance
that's what i call rule macro predicates that expands into
one thousand variables
what this means
such a thing
such that and is the mother of something
so the set of all mothers
that do not around most proper way too
let's apply
relational nouns
you can also just
flop over a relational nouns into the relation paraphrase MT where
directly connected to relations here the notation
and for some applications all you want is to know that there are some relationship
between the
the word and
the relation
you don't really care exactly which argument corresponds to another more proper way of
like find nouns
i don't know things with
more structure
it is using nounsemtrans so here i've given an example
and complicated example explain more about what's going on
the first arguement of the predicate nouns nounsemtrans
complex word
assassination was
the word assassinate
with the suffix
combined with this function wordwithsuffixfn
it takes a word and suffix and gives you another word
the second argument is a random number h is one hundred thirty two because that's
my favorite number because all
and the
third argument is
the frame the so that the syntactic frame
in which this
translation hold
it says
so generative frame
means either
is y
it works surprisingly well
at least that's what many people apart and i also tried to really seems to
i mean there well i mean i it works reason i mean nothing works always
in clustering but it's a reasonable way
but some it's also problematic because
i mean stability something like a necessary requirement but it's nothing which is
sufficient way so
you're not just say i is made all of group pretty is pretty stable but
not select the k which is most stable and this somehow
yeah OK can do it but it's not really clear whether this is really useful
OK so the way it usually works is
OK you get your dataset
and the clustering
and now
what you do is you take your dataset
you draw a subsample of the dataset say your dataset contains and sub thousand pointing
out of seven hundred points
from this data set a new clusterid
with a fixed number of k
you do this again and again so in this way for each fixed k
you generate
an ensemble of classes which
like they are always based on a slightly different samples
but the argument does the same
and then what you do is you compare all those
compare with the results you always get our model is stable
with a very a lot
to do this and we have we will go on how to do that
the first define some the distance between the clusterings who observed
and then we define based on this distance you get to define some of what
stability is and then choose the k they could do for different numbers of k
interested in and then you take the one which is
which gives the best stability
and if it and
people will
i pro stability they always show you figure like that to explain why so the
figures very simple assume
we have so so that the toy figure which would say something like this before
clusters in our dataset so each of the
lex service should represent one clustering or distribution some
now we sample from the distribution and we get those red dot
and so obviously in our case the true number of clusters should before because the
status it just contains those ninety four blocks
but now i tell thee
just these two clusters
what happens is
so now i do this like i sampled several times and was repeatedly
so maybe want to cluster them like this and the next time it just like
so all the result would be very unstable
the idea is now this will tell you that case the choice
the same happens if
which was too many data points to many clusters
then some more
it has two
split one of the clusters and can be very different which one can split
depending on your simple
and of course if you think i don't have here but if you take k
equal to four you will always get more or less the same as that state
the story somewhere
now if you want to do this in practice
we first have to define a distance between clusterings
because we went to want to measure how simple similarity similar the different clusterings are
and there again different ways of doing this
so we first start by saying i can assume we look at clusterings of the
same set of points
and then we can simply can't often
we look at each pair of points and contour of this is it in the
same cluster are in different clusters so here
this this number and zero zero one in one one
so something like
how many points pairs of points
are together in the
so for each two pairs of points you look whether there
ending up in the same cluster in different clusters according to clustering one or two
so and zero zero means i look at i can't how many points are in
the same cluster according to cluster one and in the same cluster according to cluster
and c and one says the pair in the same cluster according to cluster one
but the different classes according to cluster to some all you just compare with the
clusterings to the same or not the same on pairs of points and there are
lots of ways how you can generate the distance of the or similarity function that's
so the two most famous one another and make sure context which are
just some way so in the hamming distance is some of the opposite of the
random example but it's nothing
very fundamental you just count how often does the clustering to the same and different
pairs of points
now the
OK skip another problem is if you have
we know we had this subsampling scheme
i said OK we subsamples seven hundred five thousand data points in one cluster
and then we subsample another seven hundred points and of course
o seven hundred points will not be the same i mean there will be some
points which are in common but there will be other points which are not uncommon
in most cases clustering just give you reside on the point of set on the
set of points which gave it doesn't include
somehow there now there are two ways what you can do with it
so the first place we restrict
or the other way to extend so restriction in life
restriction means so you look at their first set of substance and and you're such
second set of subsamples
and then you just take the intersection between those and you just compare the clustering
based on the on the intersection of point so if you compare
so say the first clustering
well that can really draw this
so essentially you compare the clusterings on the points on which both of them are
so that's the restriction operator
the other way you can do this
it's an extension operator is just say OK
take the first clustering
and extent
the cluster label somewhere to the results of all the other data points
which are in the other subset
and then i have to find a clustering on the whole domain after extension and
then i can again compare it
and the way extend
so that there are different ways of working means for example it's very simple for
k means has the centre so you just get new data points just assign each
data point to the closest centre and and that it so it's very simple to
single linkage is also very simple
because it just nearest neighbour because it's more that's what single linkage does
for other algorithms it's much more complicated
something like that
good idea maybe there will also be ten or fourteen or
well ballpark numbers
there are some questions about this change
and others
so that's going
you can imagine likely twenty metres wide
i could perform as well you know what thing going
and moving the right or left
that the proposal moves when you come up with that will always in fact be
accepted and in the middle like that
because the probability ratio between any
and the q ratio what we want put that have come back
one when i the wall
if we propose
moving right
then i will be forbidden
and you'll get of the
in those cases
so the first twenty that's on the screen
james starting from the top of the
number replaced
the can i think about that
it went for the world
and that's twenty iteration so here
questions it
the first one
how long will it take until this chain generate a good sample from it
the change
sample from me
i haven't really defined good but i'd like the neighbour and
the question anyway in the real world people but
find things that
how long is it gonna have around what
andy struggling with the question is another question which is more precise
how long do you think is gonna be roughly
well one there
question in great how long until we
along you think be
with it but what
thank you questions during three are precisely nothing you are probability distribution and you can do it well
what directly
tell me what the probability distribution is how long
so one will out one or two and then you have think about whether
questions are relevant question one how long do
we need run the chain or
nothing wrong
say at the end
and so you think you getting a good
thank you neighbours
okay any thoughts on
any other questions
which questionnaire
together for example from is saying
it has to have a chance
getting quite a long way
and that's gonna be like wrapping manages to go a long way
they are suggestion was
once made about
ten unlikely things happen
maybe we'll up there
so what is our ten
problem is that after about one thousand that's
you know what you're saying then you might not be doing all right
people about ten like it
i mean interesting
training what may well be right any other way the
answering any questions
and one
i get
okay so you're saying we
have long enough hit a wall when it's probably long enough for example
all right how long is until we
what do you think this is the way international
about a hundred that's why about a hundred
distance together typical distance you don't
it's something like the square root
the number of times
more on what the let's
and even though
it only takes hands the inference operator will you be quite a lot and you
only that you want inference what you don't wait
you will
it will
so only that one but we're actually expected to take about a hundred
get a one wall and then you will get all the way and that's the al-nuaimi
maybe another four hundred five hundred they have a chance getting back
so let's look the reasoning so
let's define the distance that the random walk with goal
we delta
goes down
but if we use
now the combination
strategy so this is showing this plot showing
the game that we get full
four going from two classes to more
and it's at the same time it chose this is like thing how much we
can actually improve by using a combination of the combination strategy of using these independent
physiological features
so you see
basically that for most subjects
that have done more than two class experiments
first of all
you know three will improve
but typically only it only proves if we use the combination strategy on top
generally you see that that you know
we can
drastically improved performance
in terms of bit decisions so you know we can improve here by fifty percent
number it's the decision
i mean
absolute fifty percent
now if you if you digest on this plot a little bit longer than you
see that in most subjects it doesn't make sense to use more than three classes
because it's very hard for them to imagine more than three classes and it's very
hard to classify more than three classes in any case it's always good
and it depends on the subject whether or not
it makes sense to use a combination strategy between different physiological features all
or whether you know
you know where the game
almost nothing this not significant or whether you gain a lot
so this was done with
multiclass CSP
in there that i introduced with the simultaneous localization
and combining with with the readiness potential
and so on and so forth
what is beyond c CSP and this
recent work of steven lemm
that has appeared in i tripoli biomedical engineering so
one of the things that we ask ourselves in this in this work was well
CSP is somewhat
you know
because we are not
we just computing spatial filter that's it
and we doing that for certain frequency band
maybe it's better to actually
combine some spatial temporal filter
could actually gain some additional information this is actually a very simple idea
and the way this is done this is instead of using the xk and so
now you have all the mass on this slide in fact should have for the
order different things
this is just to confuse URI to keep you awake
access the data
OK and you know
you have some operator which is the shift operator so you have an axe
at this same time point but also
minutes tall
the shift operator for your bad today
data into into like in the non-linear dynamics sense
and because you hope that that there's something in the dynamics that you would like
to use for your filter
so it changes in the spatial filters slightly
because this
o tempo filter component two
so the idea is just to apply the CSP that that you've seen
these are multiclass two class whatever to the
the data that
and then this gives us
some projection w
into the state space because this is the state space expansion of the data
so in other words we can we can
basically decompose the projector into some
equal time project and some delay project
and so
if we now take just one
of this
applied to xk
then we can decompose this into
the spatial component and
temporal component
and we can see that
if we now spell it all out then this
some spatial filter here
and so just to get the scum i see is a combination between the w
and w told well this is some choice that we have to make
it's a reasonable choice for filtering
so this is normalized
and this is basically only containing the spectral filter
and so so if you if you look at this this is like if if
i have feel to wear at the zeroth position we have something and then we
have nothing for minus one steps and then we have something OK
so if you
rather like to think about
so now if if you
i will have this this quantity on my next slide is just the
basically the angle phase
these filters so
so these
this is just the way these filters look like
but maybe it's easier on nicer to look at them as spatial filter so if
we now to take some
projection of the class foot
this is the right hand
not sure whether you actually see this very well
so this is the usual
CSP protection which
you know gives you
something over the
overseas at some high activity
which is where the foot
it is located on the motor cortex
so this is
makes a lot of sense and we've seen that under a couple of slides before
but much more colourful
and this is so to say the second CSP projection because CSP gives you a
number of rejections
i kind of knowledge to
and and this is CSSP
so common
spatial spectral
and you see this is the spatial content which is very similar to the original
CSP but there's also spectral content which corresponds to the choice of a certain tau
and if you now look at
the classification rates began over many many experiments
then you see that
with the CSP projection