looking forward
at the same time the important to this twenty four hour CNN effect
the first gulf war was the first war which was covered real time by by
and this change the way everything works
the internet itself then then the internet the growth of news reporting on the internet
during the nine eleven terrorist attacks a lot of people were looking at the
the the
the the internet sites
because they couldn't get through
the internet sites actually crash because there was so everyone went there to find what
was what was actually happening
so we've got this
twenty four hour rapid information floating around the world
and there's no sort of growing group of
the companies researchers are working in this area which is called you open source of
open source intelligence
and we in europe we're not all these years and for
just after the end of last year
which brings together
government agencies plus
companies and researchers
and then the ISI conferences and
the tripoli conferences for intelligence in formatting
have been running since two thousand four
and there's even an editor handbook on an open source intelligence
which i
and they need to themselves run training courses
on open source for for
for this task
OK so what is it
open source information is the is the key thing is is is basically data publicly
it doesn't have to be the internet it doesn't have to be
it needs to be publicly available
so it could be
it could be a subscription service as well
but it's something that any member of the public to get hold of
open source intelligence then is proprietary intelligence recursively derived from open source information
intelligence means an interpretation of the data
collecting open source information which is what
the tools what the list let's say the data retrieval aspect of it
is to select the true the right information for the applications for the the need
the tagging cataloging visualising
i mean normally open source intelligence is the result of an expert who
analyzes the data prepared by collection by researchers you like
three areas of intelligence
information human intelligence signals signal intelligence means phone taps radio intercepts whatever
and so in principle it could also mean email intersect
and open source intelligence which is getting bigger and bigger
an important
so who uses it
as i said the security services
police law enforcement agencies more and more
getting involved
normal government organisations they
having need to be kept up-to-date date informed of what's going on that's why we
believe in and we both for the european commission because they they need to know
immediately when there's some critical report about some commissioner or when the
what if there is some
crisis brewing they want to know immediately
then the situation centre the a lot of organisations and for a
african union this is they have a situation centre and they're very interesting using our
software basically to keep them informed about developments news reports in africa
then the unit the united nations in
in new york got
twenty four unmanned
crisis room which is continuous in motoring news reports news wires coming in
the world health organization we can hear later about metastasis which is a let's a
medical intelligence system trying to pick up the first reports about disease outbreaks
NGO's and relief agencies they need to know
when there's an earthquake they want to be prepared for so this can growing need
for live information
targeted information to be brought to the right people
and large companies the big business
if you oil companies they
all of them have a team
o twenty up sometimes up to twenty people who are continuously monitoring
what's happening in
wherever they have oil rigs where they have
where they have their main offices but also
they want to look at what the competition is happening
they need to be kept continuously up today
and this is normally the report straight to the board so the writing daily reports
multinational companies the same thing
and then business intelligence things that can affect stock prices
so what is this thing intelligence it's is just the work but
in reality
intelligence is always
a report some sort
it could be classified but it's a report
now that is derived from the information is collected and the tools that help them
can make that life easier and it can handle more information
the point is is not just a text report it's just like i was just
as important as the math
or image imagery or data
and of course intelligence
it will be
from classified and open source information
the big advantage of open source
intelligence is that
you can share with other people
because it's not
and this is a big boon for inter-agency collaboration so if your
the police force in the UK
you can share this information with the french police force because it's not
classified or let's say the security services so one one other parts of the open
source intelligence is that you can actually share with other people
is this this closed down
i need to know doesn't really apply
although of course the report might end up being classified even if only depend on
on open source information that's not problem
a typical agency
or company
what do they do
so they have they have standard open source product
the first thing is
something happens and everyone in the company or everyone
who needs to know
should be informed by
email or SMS messages so we have for example system in in brussels which does
this so there's someone there
the checking the news wires as they come in it's not being updated like if
there's something
particularly in crime important for commission
all or
something that affects the commission in some way
then they send an SMS message immediately
newsflash so that's the sort of standard thing which have which companies and which
organisations have
it's always the case it and the daily briefing so there's a standard product which
is like a daily update on what's happening on what you're interested if you work
for the pharmaceutical industry this would be like saying daily updates on
the miracle of this method is happens to be
it turns out to be very good the average case
the worst case the algorithm the for the worst case also good the average case
why that's the case we don't know
we were just we just very lucky
so what
we did
you can find
what we did so far is sort of linear models
inputs linear weight vector
w dot x
and in our transfer function as a linear function in other words we didn't do
anything linear regression but now let's put in the transfer function thinking on networks
the sigmoid function
c h i transferred the dot product
into something else i turn the dot product which has range
are into of probability between plus and minus one
when i started teaching on networks
i saw that people were doing this and actually what they used as a loss
function very often the square loss
there should be references aren't you
which drove me crazy
it because it turns out that if you take a bunch of instances and you
look at the total square loss as a function of w
you can have exponentially many many many my space picture of this
wrote a paper on
with peter auer and
you can pick your examples
such that you have exponentially many minimizes log scale so it's very unusual example admitted
it but it happens
it means that somehow
when you have this kind of transfer function and taking this kind of loss
this is the thing to do
so what you should do
take the loss function
intuitively that matches
the transfer function
this is how actually i discovered bregman divergences
what happens is
if you draw the sigmoid
and then you take these kind of areas underneath the sigmoid
it turns out that they become relative entropy is
and i
notice this once and i
i had on the page and i
kept it around one ran into and eventually generosity bregman divergences and started all of
so let me show you in a moment
this integral here underneath
what you can write this way
has sort of these brakeman side form
if you integrate this out you get a capital h
corresponding to the integrand of the
the potential function of of little age
w that x minus again h of this minus this kind of linear term and
it looks
it's a bregman divergence well i
it's just a bunch of other things that happened as well because you're
two arguments one is the dot product and the other one is the h one
is one of the label but this
happens to be a bregman divergence
this is how i discovered that if you take this kind of loss
the bad thing to do is
you know what the transfer function is it takes some kind of other loss
but if you take the areas that underneath this your loss
which would you call which we call the matching loss
there's only one minimum
and it's not convex
so let me give you an example given is some some examples of these things
so we want to use
this loss
so loss of the instance because the match the matching is convex in your parameter
what is this well typical things if you transfer function is the straight line
then you can
this kind of
convex function and the square loss is the natural off
if you take the sigmoid function
then this is your convex function it looks like
the sigmoid function looks like this this is a convex function
and the corresponding loss is the logistic loss
if you take the sign
which is
this kind of transfer function is an increasing function
the corresponding h is this function itself
paint function
the corresponding loss is the hinge loss
OK so let me go a little bit more
on what happened with the update is
if you take the gradient of this
matching loss
remember in our data will always have the gradient of loss
that is very simple form now
has this form
so now
the update
kind of the
the frequent updates
it also
the gradient has this very simple form
kate has his age function and so this is the sort of and generalisation
this kind of the delta rule this can be
exploded now approves
again let's talk a little bit about
sigmoid transfer function if you have a slow parameter making steeper and steeper eventually becomes
the sign
and if you take the sign the new convex function becomes this and the matching
loss becomes this kind of hinge loss
it's zero here on the right side but increases on the wrong side
it's convex but not differentiable anymore in the limit
so why is this interesting well if you take gradient descent and use on the
loss side the hinge loss
then you end up the perceptron algorithm
which was one of the simplest algorithm first applied to learn
to learn in this tutorial i applied to learning
if you take
the exponentiated gradient algorithm with the hinge loss up with the winner out of the
i can motivate
all of these algorithms using these frameworks
in the case of normalized winnow i took of my parameter divergence my divergence that
motivates the updates the relative entropy and as the
as the loss function also one of those in tropical motivated what i took as
the loss function the one that corresponds to the
link function the function being the sine function then i end up with the hinge
loss and the combined thing gives me
embodied by this
code here is comparable to what you are expected to adhere to in your professional
they don't publish
results that you faked
you know publish results that you stole from others and represented as your own
so don't start here
and you know
it happens infrequently but i've got to tell you a few years back on the
final exam
a couple people
we're involved in passing information back and forth they got caught you know why they
got caught because for the first time you're being taught by people who are smart
as you are
so you're going to get caught my TA's are really smart
so i don't think it's like back in
place i could find somebody who it's not like we're back in
the whole country has that that's right
so don't try to
going to get cut these guys got caught i had to press the case the
committee on discipline
one of them did not return for his sophomore year
that's the crazy thing to do
huge price to pay
in the past no record first semester class
you know its most severe on the committee on this what it's made of faculty
administrators and students and guests with the most severe members of that committee are
it's the students your peers who are outraged that kind of behavior
springer behaves
i have to maintain for learning environment here we've got round numbers in excess of
four hundred people sitting here
so i expect certain things here
that's not going to go on
first of all
no conversations no talk
the conversation here conversation their heads
so i insist
no talking
please no food or drink
no food or drink works were ceded sheet to gel here somebody opening up the
clamshell with some hot food and it's not right
right places all kinds of trash left around nobody picks up stuff now this is
an exception this is
for medicinal purposes
it can make sure that my throat doesn't get dry
and i swear it really contains frescoes
and of course no disruptive behavior
no disruptive behavior are wireless communications devices must be silenced
OK so
from this moment for
there's some stuff will offer earlier but i let it slide because i haven't had
much chance to explain what my expectations but from this moment forward
cell phone goes off
leave the role
lord help the cell phone goes after an exam
because those things have text messaging capabilities
if your cell phone goes after exam
i come up there
grab paper by terence happen i give you zero
i am teach teaching professional behavior it's unprofessional
you can say that i
over the top on this
i got four hundred fifty people here
i want to maintain for learning environment you walk through that door it's an act
of free will
so that the free will
somebody's leaving
the school is getting get started right now please
it makes life insurance
you all these gals dinner i tell you
all right turn off
they have to make noises you term after my but that's it
when you walk through that door
it's an act of free will
and we enter into a contract
you walk in here you have certain expectations
you expect me
to conduct myself professionally
expect me to respect you expect me not to use foul language expect me not
to say
offensive things to you
expect well-prepared lecture
you know what i have expectations of you
i expect you to come to class prepared i expect you to sit there quietly
respect your neighbors
i expect you to contribute to the learning environment
that's the reason
course will tell you what this is
this is a listing for three online one
five zero seven
five zero seven five hours is contact
three hours here two hours recitation structures zero there's no lab seven one seven
that must be the time you spend
to proceed well applied let's look at the total
amortized costs
of an operation
that's just
the sum
i called one and c so i had
that's the total amortized cost
and that's equal to
by substitution
just to see i had for this formula
that's the i
was the
the i minus e
the i minus one
that's cool too
see i
and now what happens by some of these terms
what happens rise some of these are what's the mathematical
the term we use for
OK every term on the left
is an indian once one if xi
and subtracted it out when it's
i minus one
except for the first and last terms
the term for an
is only added
and the term for zero is always attracted out
cases because it telescopes
OK so this term is what
property we know this
gradient equal to zero
and this one
because there
so therefore
this is greater than equal to c i
and that's
we ties costs
are an upper bound on the true cross
is what we want some of the advertised cost is an upper bound on some
of the true cross
but here the way that we define the amortized costs
it was through by first defining the potential function
OK so the potential function is is sort of as i said the difference between
the accounting and the
potential method is to specify the bank account or you specify the cost
specify the potential energy at any point for you specify the cost in point
but in any case you get
this panel also this methods
i somewhere
like telescopes
the ties cos upper bound to
leicester table that way
so to analyse this we have to define our potential
anybody can get this off the top of their head
they're are better than i am
i struggled this with this for probably
easily a couple hours to get it right
OK because i'm not too smart
has the potential function to do this
two i minus two to to the
the ceiling of logie
that to the ceiling of log zero
this called the zero because that's what it is known
so i take
the limit
the log zero this becomes minus entities easier
so that's just a mathematical convenience
so that
what i get this from
i played around try look at look that sequence i raised my sort of chaos
what's the
reversing there are some problems forced to find a potential function is fairly easy
defining the amortized cost is hard
OK to define counter so for this one here the accounting method is
i would say no easier method use
however show you still can do with potential method if you come up with the
right potential
OK so intuitively
this is basically what's left in the bank account at the i th operation
because i've got put into why things into the bank
subtracted out this many essentially from table problems
OK up to that point
so first let's observe
what is the d zero
that's good
the idea i
it's critical to zero why is that
why is that
so what's the biggest
the ceiling wall guy
could be
so in of organise either logi
what i
twenty plus one
so the biggest it is this log i plus one it's log plus one
two to the
logie plus one
it's just too i
that's the biggest could be
one of my
plus one
it's just
it's just too
this is just
this other ways i tend to
OK i for that part two for that port
so that's the biggest it could be
o for its
just logo by
so this is going to be too on my side
or two i minus
two on
in either case
bigger than zero
selecting t but it doesn't have to be
and finally you can also use the idea of reproducing kernels to come up with
a much more general
formulation namely the class of admissible kernels that you can use are functions that are
symmetric in their arguments and the positive definite in the sense that for any collection
of n samples this gram matrix k i j is symmetric positive definite
so if you design a k in this fashion
it doesn't have to be either the minus something it's generally going to be valid
and in fact if you designed if you have two
admissible kernels then you can have an enormous number of new constructions by doing things
like a positive linear combination of these two kernels are the product of two kernels
are not any number of different things
so the reason i'm bringing all this up is just to put in perspective the
idea that things like the bilateral filter in the non-local means and so on these
are tiny tiny special cases
of some something very very broad that can be done
OK so before going any further let me sort of back off
the the equations a bit and show you some examples
we have applied these ideas to a lot of different applications
i'm gonna show you some examples just for denoising for focus stacking
we've also applied it to interpolation and super resolution in the blurring in these two
things in fact we've commercialized in a company that we started five years ago which
produces software for doing
video enhancement for lots of different applications
OK so for denoising let me give you an example so here's a photo of
of JFK
this is actually a real thirty five millimeter photo that's been scanned to a digital
was certainly the noise in this image is not gaussians is that even uncorrelated
it's in fact the combination of film grain noise and
scanning artifacts and so on
so here's the noisy image and here's the denoised version using our algorithm which uses
locally adaptive regression kernels let me just go back and forth as you can see
the fidelity is very very high you can hardly tell the difference you have to
look at this image for fair amount of time to see the difference and in
fact it's interesting if now you kind of scan the literature and look at the
algorithms that sort of state of the art
so here's the plot shows the mean squared error for that is i could show
you mean squared error causing the images just given to us i don't have the
ground truth but if you do a bunch of monte carlo simulations you can look
at the mean squared error versus the standard deviation of the noise added to the
image and you see is that sort of the top
few algorithms that are out there for
denoising are sort of clump together in a very tight band
and we've also done a paper called is denoising dead which came out in few
months ago we computed lower bounds kramer lower bounds and what we've noticed is that
all of these algorithms are very tightly bunched but there is still room for improvement
depending on the type of image that you have
and also later on was now let's talk in this session
well also give another perspective on these ideas as well
we actually transfer the image to why CBC are
do it there and then transfer back to our genes
well yes so so what you want to do is to be much more careful
about the the luminance channel the chromosome makes
much less difference so we can you can be more aggressive in denoising in the
chroma channels
OK so another quick application and this is something that is common problem that's been
around for a long time when you have limited depth of focus one of the
things you can do is take multiple images with different
for links and then combine these images together in these ideas this sort of regression
weighted least squares you talked about doesn't have to be done just for
it just in space if you have multiple images can also be done it multiple
times images same time can also be done in time or in any other dimension
in this case perhaps the focal so we've also use this these ideas to
combined these images together to get one fully focused image and this is the idea
that's been around in microscopy for for a long time with a very simple solution
to the works really well
it's just the extension of so the algorithm i showed you
with the proper weight selection
be energy is the energy of a spin system
some overload
cross has been
and then they will be
local field age and it could be
in and where x
and dimensional binary
that's an example
the problem we might want to solve the sort of thing
you might want know if you're not a magnet
what is it
average energy
what these fluctuations in the energy which you get if you know the mean squared energy
and the mean energy
what that mean magnetization which is
these or
maybe what i mean squared
about because the entropy
all which is which
is the average of all
love will be
a bunch of things you might want to
and magnet and you probably won't want to know although at the range in temperature open
from the beta
like this
local identity
and then got
and what people not depend on
in the temperature data
o inverse temperature
so there
example the things might and
am i emphasize last time when we do monte carlo methods we are not trying
to find the most probable date of that we're not trying to minimize
we would only be
doing at if we set the temperature
in the temperature very large value weight is very cold then it will be on land that's not
the goal of the month and we're not quite we're interested in sampling from the all
distribution seeing what a few samples from that what look like
and we're not trying to be all the people affected by the
easily be bigger
than the number
electrons in the universe
raise bring about our
okay so that's the rules of the game and an example of what we're doing
and last time we discussed the importance sampling rejection sampling
the sampling and the properties methods
the problem is that it is actually a very general
actual because many other methods are examples the problem and that when i say that the property that today
and quite often using it shorthand or
metropolis methods with a simple proposal distribution of the height i showed
little show
let's repeat the show now
just to remind you what we're doing
so we have a nasty probability distribution in red
have functions whose average values
during the then
look at simple
sampling from a uniform distribution
and then reweighting points
we look at
sampling from a different distribution
which you could draw samples from shown in
green easy distribution to the new reweight point that
all the importance sampling new reweight
the why values
to take account of having used the wrong distribution
and we didn't grow variety of distribution will here
then we look at
rejection sampling which is the way that
sampling from the red distribution by throwing away
some of
sample you grew from
the green distribution
and rejection sampling
doesn't work if you do wrong
and what they were doing i dimensions
but it
often the bible technique in small numbers government the first one dimension
and there are high dimensional
methods the sampling which a new project to bring the component to make them go
the reject something being used in one dimension
the time
so good heuristics for this is to
to be a prime
not too close
two of power
or ten because those are the two common bases that
see regularity in
in the world
prime sometimes inconvenient
but but generally is fairly easy to to find primes and there's a lot of
nice theorems about primes
generally what you do if you're just going up something and you know it is
in the prime out of
no textbook around of
you know looking up on the web or read program whatever
the prime not going to close to paris to attend probably works pretty well
i worked pretty well
so this is a very popular method the division method
but the next method we're going to see is actually usually superior
the reason people do this is because
they can write it
right in line in the code
OK but is not usually the best method and the reason is because the vision
one of the reasons is that division
tends to take a lot of cycles to compute on most computers compared with
multiplication or division
in fact it's usually
and several applications
so the next method
actually generally better but
none of the hash function that we're talking about today are
or in some sense probably good hash functions
so for the multiplication method the nice thing about it is just essentially requires multiplication
to do
for this
we can assume that
number of slots is power of two which is also often very can
and for this we assume that the computer
i w
the convenient on a computer with
with thirty two bits
or sixty four bits for example
this is very confusing
so the
this function is the following each OK
is equal to
eight times
two to w
right shifted
i my so
the key part of this is a which is chosen to be in
in the range between two to w minus one
and two to the w
so it's an odd integer the full with the computer work
what you do is you multiply it by whatever by this
for any integer
and then take it to the w
and then you take the result in right shifted by the fixed amount of human
so this is a bit wise
so let's look at what this does but first let me just give you a
couple of
tips on how you pick what you don't take for
for a topic
two close
two power of two
and it's generally if pretty fast map
two w
i think the right shift is that
especially because this is known shift
you could you know before you computing the hash function
w and are known to the compiler can often do tricks there
to make it going fast
a short latencies and accuracy
so and this tutorial on
the can
learn more
i look like
so it knows
this section and so this
of my
my course of the last source
i hope i
convinced that machine learning
good reasons can be very useful in single trial EEG analysis but
there's also
problematic parts and this is the validation of the methods and unfortunately
i can see in many
manuscripts that i submitted to journals and even in
published articles that many many groups are not there are not many who some research
let's not available
problem set
one is to take care of the validation rules that
it's trying to
give some some advice to make the problem
validation so the
the principle of validating this method is quite
quite obvious so
what is machine learning methods to typically require one training data set
to tune you all your parameters
and the test dataset which
then in the real applications the feedback data is
you of course don't know in advance what looks like
so it
validation can only be proper if you don't use this test set in any way
determine some some of the parameters
and also in the
tests are independent from the same person
training set
this more concrete
problems that male
that is the problem then if preprocessing methods use statistics of
o datasets
example so
validation typically take one dataset want to validate the message on that
and if you first use of the whole dataset to compute some statistics
and pre processing then to the
validation afterwards
so that
that's wrong and that that's the problem so for example if you apply
i see a to the whole dataset in the beginning and only do the cross
for for the classifier in the end
so then you can use some statistics the test set
four preprocessing and what you
should i feel
normalize the future based on
samples from the from the test and this is particularly severe problem
if the pre processing methods used label information for example the csps i'm showing you
if you calculate CSP first on the whole dataset and then to cross validation only
for the classifier part
he was severely underestimated the arrow
so in particular we have
on several datasets if you do that you would get like zero percent error because
it's better if it does some overfitting
and if you do a proper validation
you get a chance
so in
so that means either you do
this preprocessing within the cross validation which is very time consuming or your
don't to cross validation but just data once the training and test sets
so in which is
one is the same so if you do feature selection
on the whole dataset
and only validates the classification this also the
completely under-estimating the
perform over estimating perform
must be selected only based on the training
then if you
if you select some some hyperparameters slide
the come offering which if you don't have to automatically but if you select the
also a problem if you do
for each common proper cross validation
and then say oh i see
i got my first point two
it's the best best value and report this error is you
generalisation performance
so as an
the selection of the game are dependent on the test set for you
to select all these parameters also hyperparameters
based on the training set
another problems
artifacts are outliers are removed from the whole dataset then it will cross validation because
when you make
tests easier so to say so you're also excludes
artifacts from from the test
so of course you can have a method for on line detection of of artifacts
and reject them
but then you need to different performance measures
i hope that these points for
what is clear from
so audience and one point i want to focus on
in the remaining parts
and this is an unselfish and validation in
paradigm is blocked is
and this is what i mean by that so the task is to discriminate between
mental state in two different conditions and core
the design of block design
periods for which there is no
our generation between
two conditions is much longer than
the switching
should be in the
we performance in the online situation
so this can be maybe best explained the
so here we have different blocks
seven seven blocks in the first block
we only have tried according to condition one in the second globally
according to condition two
and so on
so this might be that the subject is continuously in one condition and
here you're just cut out
smallest thing try
i like this
separated single
so these
kind of design so
sometimes use the
condition is one that you can
it's it's more easy to
keep keep up for a long time so for example if you want to
driver BCI this
so a
doing mass or
mister thaksin mentally augmented mental arithmetic o composing a letter
the stick
and then if you changes i mean what is
is that because
whatever we play we you meet this
black circles
you can you can have a look
players zero
choose its rules so that whatever rules
player wants to play
we meet infinitely often
black circle
number black's position
maybe also squares that are black thing like you
i mean
on the other hand from here
if a one
besides two
so when he's here he phrases
here we present
whatever plan zero
and that
because he is the way to
two this parts where nothing is colored black
so you have an ocean of
winning play
positions were
i have a strategy to apply
i we
whatever the other one wonders
so what is very is that
so that's the
one player sigma law is the other player
so i called wlg of sigma the set was
well i have a winning strategy
to win
whatever the other one does
so again is that the mind if
like to be in the position
we know that
one of the two
o has a winning strategy so it means that
there's always
from one of them
two of the policy
in order to it
we turns for one player
and winning positions
for the other player for
in the summer of what i mean by winning what do i have a strategy
so that whatever the other one place
o winning strategy
and this is really about
you have this was
which tells you that
i think in the the mind it means that if i choose initial positions
i the wins
the show
hopefully what sure
provided he chooses good strategy and of course but that is can agents can't help
with the way to play a role show whatever the place
can be
to his
and something also very important
is that this is an example is given to you here that i wrote
i will honestly this
whatever his story
as long as i might play a
so cut passes the technical condition
might replace that by stochastic continuity it's not really very
very relevant for us it's sort of means that we can look at the random
function as well as the collection of random variables
so we want right continuous and pass pass with left limits
just to be to be definitive
i haven't said what the state space is well
this definition makes sense in very high generality
if you have something like a locally compact topological group then
this is a meaningful definition but of course we're going to focus on on real
valued processes and
one possible extensions to k dimensional euclidean space they can have two or three dimensional
processes you think of financial applications and you may just have lots of assets and
you want to study their joint evolution and we can set up levy
process models
in that space which has the dimensions
as the number of as
many examples
that you
well i have come across i i suppose is brownian motion
well we have normally distributed increments
and the pos on process where we have also distributed increments notice that
the properties of the stationarity and independence of increments are related to the fact that
we we have in the parameters to be
and linear
in t here
so i've got two simulations of brownian motion and opossum process
for you to look at here
what we can do is is calculated moment generating functions that characterize these distributions is
is something
because very very elementary here
nevertheless leads to a form that we are going to see in the more general
case of
of an arbitrary
lady process
later on
next main example to construct lady processes is going to be the company was sold
process component for some browsers is built from a platform process and as we've just
looked at
and a number of independent and identically distributed random variables so we sum up
have many of them by time t as the plus on process tells us
the evolution of this process is then to start from zero
and then make that jump a one
then do nothing until the possum processes
jumps to two in by which case we add the
random variable eight to twelve
process and we get this evolution
so to calculate this moment generating function
and we need to do a little bit more work and one way of doing
it is to
the condition on on the value of NT
if we do this then the random variable that we have
looking at is just the sum of n independent identically distributed random variables
and the moment generating function of of one of such a sum of random variables
is just the end power
of the moment generating function of the random variable
and what we're looking at here for our moment generating function of the interested in
an exponential serious
that we
can right
as exponential
and then we get this
this may be slightly strange time of
t lambda into expectation e to the gamma a one minus one
well that minus one
and we can actually move that bracket over here
because the expectation of one is one
and what we're looking at here
is an integral
of e to the gamma x minus one
integrated against the distribution
of the random variable
a one
and this is the key observation that will
get back to
lady processes are
o processors with with some strong properties and one of them is infinite divisibility
the definition is that
a random variable is infinitely divisible
if you can write it as the sum of n independent identically distributed random variables
for all n
greater than i equal to two
the meaning of this is that the distribution
of y j and will depend on n
but not on
so such a property you can sort of cut down your random variable and consider
it as the sum of smaller pieces
that's the property that all of processes have because if we look at xt
we've got that stationarity and independence of increments so we can actually take as y
j n
increments of lag
t over n
and if we take the consecutive increments here
then summing over these we get telescoping sums which means we are left with the
first term for j calls and and the second term for j equals one
and that means we fall back on two
well but we know that these random variables here
are identically distributed and independent so
this is showing
infinite divisibility of
the processes distributions
OK well this is
probably the most technical part of the talk infinite divisibility had been studied
the structural rules which can my afterwards
there's something different this rule
then the conjunction
tation rule
and that is
that the action goes on
inside of the track
something else looking at this matter and have
a complicated
or a special
variation of the cat world
and the rest of cultural much like the cut earlier
i realize that you can prove cut
in the system you know
there are induction
on the on line procedure need is four line inference derived cut
and here
also give us a little bit practice
doing the mission
so what we want
what we want is we want
x turnstile a and y
a day
how do we get this into the same form well we need three premises
and one of them has to have a distraction and
use the disjunction elimination rule
and here we go
and it looks horribly treat cheating trivial
is that
from here with a gives us a or
and then we were key to this
and now
we have the distraction over here can be written backwards sorry
over here we had one of the disjuncts and y here and the other distance
to be the same
OK so it's
disjunction introduction
she nomination
of all
that's kind of cute
cut into the system is a sort of it
is is a consequence
this is very much between
a natural deduction system in the sequence
but it is very nice
when you look
learning things called such logics because it has all of the e's it's easy
monkeys is
could calculus
it isolates the
the idea of structural rules or structural
OK let's go on to those
when structural rule is is the way of
being the premises
the way of manipulate
the hypothesis
the the the
things on the left-hand side
one of the
so you've seen if you have this kind of very long list
of interacting atoms
again i recommend the book
i recently to just photocopying the first chapter for forrester here is that we don't
to write these notes say usually just teaches book
the thing that's quite fun
anyway let's right
down three of the rule give us the logic
so far all before i do that
but we also need
in a way of
what if theorem it's OK now
you can help
and again since he encounters a lot of them when we move
now some of the theorem we just keep
things through and if at all but this is something like this we can push
something through intrigue and empty
for various reasons kind of uncomfortable
to handle and the left
of the
the systems that work in about
so instead we come up with a
we need a
what's called a zero place
structural connected
it's not
quite a formula
so it is replaced structural connective and it's called it we zero
and we have two rules for that
so be welcome news for we only need to here
OK anyway
current and then on the name should
the other way around
epsilon one before w one it's zero
and next to got epsilon to before w two it's zero bit epsilon lose way
smaller than epsilon one so w two it's zero first
and so
w two is mainly variable and i do the pivot fourteen here
and i think i show the next slide
forty here now i looked down and i have
the mind to and the minus one here
this act
x one
can go up
rate two has got abseil on one minus epsilon two
the plant is tiny compared epsilon one so
this is this basically epsilon one whereas this one
can go up to epsilon two plus epsilon three was tiny so basically epsilon two
o yeah and that's the right ones the right to that doesn't really matter
so the fact that there's this one can only got to and that's why small
someone tells the w three must be the leaving variable
and so i do the pivot
i've solve my problem i didn't do it had
well so whole put the important point here is
at every iteration now
even i'm doing degenerative it's
my symbolic object function is strictly increasing
because with epsilon inner i never did generative it
and furthermore you'll never
that's a wonderful
you'll never get a role with only excellence
having coefficients are zero
because all are pivot operations are reversible
and this is and then we started with an identity matrix here
if you think this all matrix here this is a full rank matrix
it's not possible to do a pivots and reduce the rank of this matrix
and so you always have some epsilon you'll get a rule zero coefficients in this little three by three matrix
you will always have some maps lines you always be doing non-degenerative
not the
the objective function in the right hand side is never zero
with the excellence
but they were just symbolic parameters and so once you are done once you've gotten
these are solve the problem once you've just got now the degenerate situation you can
throw away the epsilons and say i don't care about them myself my original problem
so the perturbation methods very
useful technique for
problem of cycling
there are other rules that one can talk about
there is the smallest index rule
which is uh
choose the
variable with the smallest index so entering very blessed be choose entering choose they
very well the positive coefficient that has the smallest index rather than the largest coefficient
so if you pick both entering and leaving variable using the smallest index rule that's known as blanz rule
and blanz rule has been proved not to
you can also select at random
and that's a good thing because
then the
probability that you may cycle
this is just like the things around but the next time just like things around
you know you make different selection and you want cycle
so so random selection is also a good rule for
avoiding cycling in practice on a computer
people are also considered
the greatest increase rule actually figure out which are the possible entering variables given me
the biggest increase in my objective function
but actually if you think about it is
doing a lot of
numerical linear algebra
purpose that and the
it is the expense prepare goes up quite a lot and there
and so the rule is actually not competitive
okay so brief a few words about the geometry of degeneracy
so i really qualitative scores are
are hyperplane are
perhaps spaces and we are certainly is half spaces
in an dimensional space and so are feasible set is
in two dimensions is a polygon in higher dimensions is a polytope
multi faceted
convex object
end the simplex methods going from
from vertex to vertex so
we started zero zero zero
and when we increase just one variable at a time so if i pick x
one is my first entering variable when i'd dictionary corresponds to a vertex basically and
offered the first order that's when entering our activity here
if i did the second pivot with say x to be monitoring variable
i would go to this vertex
if i take my next to that with
with x three is very well go this vertex
and so on
you'll notice each vertex here has a
it this vertex is the intersection of three planes
and there no in which the three planes
determines the vertex also determines which variables are the three basic variables for the problem
those are the
well no actually tell which ones which variables are zero so it tells me
it tells you which are the non basics
look at this
corner up here
when you look at this example in this example
the corner here actually has
four hour faces defining it as the three colored ones
but then there's the backplane the x two x three plain so there's fore faces
making this single vertex but the vertex is defined by just three
so there's multiple ways of expressing the same geometric point
i pick three if the
the faces of
i said apparently the termite basic
variables those available
anyway so
i have
multiple ways of representing this vertex here
i could say that
i could say x two
so this this point here has x to equals zero x one equals zero
it has
this inequality is zero slack so that's
the first and second one is the
as the second one w two is equal to zero at this one
and w one is equal to zero
at this one and so on
i've those four things i pick
three of them
to be non basic and one the basic
and so there's
four different ways of doing this is four different dictionaries that represent the single geometric vertex
so that's what that's what the degeneracy is
geometrically it's too many faces coming together
at a single vertex
another thing is
and probably the most important thing is efficiencyof
these algorithms
and the simplex methods are very efficient algorithm and that's
the density
the of the question is not something I have spent habitat have N and so
I can read sigma here you
this you a have a lot of things that you have already talked about it
already is that the quality of
maybe with that later but where we use the properties of the Gaussian kernel here
and there may be a little
want to mention that because of the way people just started to from the stadium
for Australia and all of the of the of the theorem is not specific enough
of it
but the reason why I'm taking the Gaussian kernel is that we use it in
practice in England and that's for sure each miniature work with the more general kernel
so it was the verification of the elements loss of all of them would have
issues with so many the other problem is that the
maybe there's nothing wrong with that of the of the of the of of the
went on with this site in and out and so the that earlier I prefer
and conceded those this result has no more and no more than the consistency results
in because there
I really don't know if this convergence rates is optimal
I have no lower bound for the moment and so on
I can say that we have stated the consistency of the algorithms
Conseil these are fast rates for 1 class a 2nd remark is that from this
as to convergence from similarity to the target and 0 it can be due right
that's the
but the real sense of signal had been greater than 1 might expect that converges
to the success
so with respect to for instance the criterion that I have described before
so far from the lens to convergence we can derive the following convergence between sets
I can't well this set is precisely so by definition of of 0 this is
administrative said that evolved to them that times 1 minus the
so from this result we can derive the consistency of 1 class SVM for density
level set estimation
1 of the 20
so we can move to the pool so the proof begins with the as usual
which produces some of the risk
in different terms that we we've separately bound
so I want to enter into details well I don't have time for but I
just like to mention that we need really
introduced so that excessive passing marriage because we know that we can say something on
because the world by definition of s sigma have we know that sigma hat minimizes
by recall version of our sigma so although we would have things to say to
control this term and well then that you have to
1 OK so the good thing is that uh there are 2 terms that are
negative so we can go there and finally there remains returned to bound for so
the first one is the 1 that we wanted to introduce its referred to as
the estimation error
uh and the 2nd 1 is the funny ones so this is the regularisation error
and to control the tool have to
you can enter their data about yourself your affiliations the paper written stuff like this
you can if you are in charge of an event you can make sure that
it has deadlines proper inside and stuff like this it's because one of the nice
features is that
if the state is or is available there list of upcoming events automatically created will
you can download them if i kill you can put in them in you cannot
directly and all this kind of of goodness
editing the wiki
is pretty simple said space the media wiki so it's mostly the same interface and
the same way you just you can just go to your own page for example
click on edit
and the idea is that double square bracket
mark link
and the type of feeling
it's giving the first
you have to stop the columns separating the property from the object and then comes
well you asked for the property
this is i've for another page
or it may be some way depending on the type of the property
so in both cases here
affiliation nationality
type of the
of the property is another wiki page
so there will be also wiki page about the
and there will be a wiki page about gracia because both entities by himself and
will probably happen on page in wiki
the other hand if you for example would like to say that you hate to
see you had for example in this case i would say OK then he has
to hate one meter seventy five
so in this case i wouldn't have the page but i would say OK itself
hey type parts of the length of time and then i can add things like
second to things like insurance or whatever i want to add it's able to translate
one to the other in the background for you
but you wouldn't have the page that's called one meter seventy five usually new wiki
so you don't want to have to link to a page but rather to where
you really and then this value is added to europe
and it in this case
so i was expecting actually did all if you would get some print out of
the slide
so these are are created to actually be a quick she'd she'd to look at
and how old
the wiki markup works to live in during hands on presentation so you can easily
enter then you have all the slides on the USB stick
so you can just take a look at them and their and then you come
back you can also open to modify like this kind of changes are actually done
much better she cheats on the web if you just search for them is that
whenever you have the media wiki cheatsheet it's basically the same thing because it is
based on wiki
so just go quickly so things like three apostrophes make it both actually to work
and to make it italic
that was a link
that then you can also given a chance to text links
so then it clings for example two cr but it's the text risk ratio and
because you have a case the world which is much more important in other languages
than english english doesn't have his that much but
slavic languages for example
very nice to have this kind of paternalistic
and the week is basically case sensitive
besides for the first letter
the strange that in the media wiki architecture you can switch it off but in
the usual setting
i it is fully case sensitive
but for the first letter which is always treated as a capital letter
and there are things in unicode so you can use are
all the funny that as we have in slavic countries all the funny as we
have in spain or in france and all the
the numbers of characters you can you you having an asian countries in arab countries
and so on to this there should be no problem using unicode they actually a
number of semantic mediawiki installations running on a red chinese so we know that
this work and forty arabic one we had no opensource developer sitting in israel who
made all the changes for right to left text for the thing it
really we are actually two edits right left text in the wiki
because it feels so very different but i think it's very useful use user them
but just when you try it out
the cursor jumps all over time value typing especially if you make something things that
partially left to right and partially right to left because then you have text then
you have number which goes the other direction then jump back to the beginning again
a lot
so what is semantic markup that is two
two weeks
you can say the the page belongs to a category is already able to store
possible in media wiki just put in category colon into to it and then this
page belongs to the category
we interpret this
as RDF time
which means that
the page
due to the topic of the page you are on
belong to the category
are pointing to in the sample of wilson was for example say the category city
which means that wilson is the city
so that we can now it's OK
this page is talking about the city
the second part is
the titling of a certain type of
from page one to page to go to the page p one
the subject of the triple
and you have this is
w two double at two college
and then the
link then do well you after
triple or the object of a triple
so for example was on left is located in
callan callan career so i'm saying the city was
it is located in korea
and the same thing values the city was
has a population of three million six hundred thousand
it's basically it with
annotating to wilkie
should go ahead
there may be some interest the first place this year i
you get in your eye for the city so you may always have an external
ontology that just you're reusing your eye display
so it is that we are providing a URI
the semantic wiki
so it's just like well OK be doing beginning in the fall URI so you
don't have to worry about this which is about the linked data things and documentation
and so on and so on
but you can also decided you actually don't want to use the you're right it's
automatically created by the wiki
but you already have a good you're eyes cities
have to look in hindsight and compare myself to the best single stack whatever and
the problem is
i guess the problem can be best described by
but i call my uncle made to me last
last year when he commented i lost two million dollars in the stock market is
really what happened said well if i had invested my money here
and then i move my money here
and then i move my money here and so on i would have made two
million dollars
and if that's how you're gonna
measure your performance you have a lot of regret so
so so that's kind of why we measure performance after the fact to the to
to the best single function and that compared to
the best of changing function although you can get these nice
changing function bounds
other cool things you can do it
article things you can do in this setting
i have the so-called multi armed bandit problem it is a nice paper about this
called how to gamble in a rigged casino
OK and this is a classic problem going back to statistics
from a long time ago and the idea is a multi armed bandits
o sorry the the multi armed bandit you have several
slot machines each one is one armed bandit
you have to decide which machine to pull
and each time he possum flemish and you get some money
you don't know how much you would have gotten from all the other slot machine
so it's kind of one of these classic problems in exploration exploitation trade-off how do
you decide which one machine the poor so they make as much money as possible
and what they give their actually algorithms for deciding which slot machines to pull
using randomness that will guarantee that are making almost as much money is if they
just sat and played the best single slot machine in hindsight
trying to take this back to the learning setting
the learning setting we have these
functions which were compared herself to
i want to point out that these functions can also be they can either be
you know linear separators but they can also be just some other weird class of
that also are learning algorithms themselves
that look at the sequence of data you can think of them like experts they
look at the sequence of data and make a prediction in the future so these
functions could be
decision tree learning and neural nets
you know an SVM and you want to get the best performing best of all
three worlds you want to get an algorithm that when you use it online will
make a few mistakes is the best
of the three
so in the in this setting
in the multi armed bandit setting not even trickier
you only have to essentially yesterday
commit to one algorithm before you even
i know what's going on you have to actually choose one of the functions before
you see any of the predictions you choose the function
you run your algorithm
whatever you find out its prediction you go with that you have no choice
you go with now we majority announced the band would you go with prediction we
find out i got
maybe then you move to another function
you go with its prediction
you see that
i had to go with conservatives minus you see that right
you so stay there
OK and you keep going and so on
this repeats OK so actually hear the nice thing the nice thing is that you
don't have to run all other algorithms each time
the only run
each each time you only one round one of your predictors to see what to
and still you get to guarantee
unfortunately the guaranteed that is now linear in the number of
functions you have
but still you can actually do better than that in this very difficult
any question here
so you
again we're comparing ourselves
so should be
i regret
i'm sorry but bunch of mistakes my slides i had a talk with many more
formulas and then i was kind informed that there were too many formulas in the
toxic so i kind of last night i went to try to take on many
anyway this should be the regret saying expected regret that compared to again compared to
some class of functions f
and here this capital after
represents the size of the
number of functions in the family
it's easier to compare yourself
in a large window
to the best
function because you don't have to adapt quickly
now i'm comparing myself to
five large windows
that's a hundred or you know ten thousand comparing myself to the best algorithm in
the last ten thousand
examples only after that myself
so once every ten thousand
steps to the best algorithm
to the best function sorry in the family lived him
if the window is one
such as one wants to
that's said idea
i took helps was trying to kernel
talk transformers as they say let's start to work on
the idea of
a computable
function k
functional computable by an algorithm
this is the approach to trying to formalize
you know in real life in finitistic y
what you what you mean by carrying out calculation or something like that
so you say
his this computing technique is the cell group
this mechanism which will produce the ants outside value of the function
as few different ways we can see to do that
informally and say here for a function of a whole bunch of variables
in place typeface function f
is compatible with this procedure algorithm which the which can compute its value value y
we've got an informal idea of what it means to calculate effectively to compute things
that algorithms
but some of those things of course might involve us taking a very very very
long time to do stuff
do we care about that
as mathematicians we die
there's also can be done eventually in a finite number of steps you don't mind
and there's a few other simplifications of that sort that you see on
i just stream coming up to second
there's lots of different things we might say can computable but we're abstracting away
specific things like we have time or you know electrons to park in the universe
and this kind of thing in our calculations
so in a sense since the computability is not human ones
but it's just effective it's fun
it's concept
what happened in the thirties the people kept for putting forward some different approaches computability
in an attempt to understand these issues around kernel theorem around the building program
but what turned out was that the various techniques for
saying what it is for have effective computability
alternatively assign
what we're not going to do today
set up three different approaches
three different approaches to computability
and start on the arguments but the
would lead us to sign the viral side
the different enough
that it's it's non-trivial
i will see what they are
keep that in mind got about three
techniques of computability
is this full concept we can calculate the value function by some of the algorithm
and let's try to formalize what that means
his these issues what about what would be the computability
they have taken be if it must be fine arts
the instructions themselves must be fine
OK the agent carries out the instructions meaningless here machine
just is steps
you can check what you've done
the agent carries out the instructions discrete stepwise manner
my fuzzy logic here
you can't say
we're not going to say that it's by the
or somehow
not clear whether nice carry step
each one does occur doesn't occur and so on
so here's a bunch of
of principles around what we're trying to achieve
the site will move to pretty quickly is
is an idea of calculi of having three different approaches
of these sorts is here
OK only number ten is contentious
OK well have to look at what that's about
because i don't have an intuitive feeling that
it's contentious
but some people do some putting in that
you want to look at
rogers rogers book on recursive functions
which is in
which is in the
bibliography references
so i want to make any comment and we're going to satisfy all happy just
receiving this place i go along
in order to even start one of the things you've got to colourlayout hold
core beginning ideas much less actually never developed the idea is that we're trying to
alright let's keep going
the three methods we can look at cold
recursive functions of partial recursive functions goes
sometimes when you apply the results from the up partial function didn't start one
part of techniques
and i'm going to call that this is my formal idea i'm going to call
this an axiomatic approach
so someone says what do you mean by the algorithm will follow an algorithm or
something it's constructive by procedure
one approach is
this is of things called recursive functions
and the way they defined
is by setting up some of the axioms so all these functions are recursive functions
if you apply these rules these other ones will be to
and therefore the cosine
continues on its merry way the only thing is it might be a little more
or it might be
four might be very
let's go back four
this will be the case in a question one well of course the most interesting
cases what happens there is exactly one
partridge is exactly just write phrases
two active goal
just right
when a is equal to one
so you start service cosine he gets to the design ever there
the function zero
i have a
visually for the only time this
it was it didn't work at all but on the other hand the data for
the last hour the people who worked there were not intrinsically baseball players
since will use the equation of the pendulum instead
that's a lot easier to match the the pendulum itself
it's on them because i declare today
and it swings back and forth
and here i am really sick when the the angle the variable is not x
or y but they the angle to the data is one let's say about race
and starts there and it swings back and forth
it's not them so it
never loses amplitude particularly place which
i would like
so i want someone with who knows how to better baseball that was the problem
last hour
two people
one two release all stand up and try to hold somebody releases
and then somebody who actually very skillful
i should apply the impulse unit balls of exactly one when it gets to the
equilibrium point
so can that
you can look like this one
OK somebody like that
right now
OK so we really to OK
somebody told handle
all i could be
OK so just call it what you take to be one gradient
when it gets
he really said what it gets the value of the get down way down
and they on this side
OK you left the right
OK better with that part
mean this work
it's also set prior to help
i'm not very stable
OK for you gotta be see where it's going
but you stand so guys can want to send you the right
so that's ghostwriter
i believe that the world
i have a false alarm or
the red sox have child
if did harder
you even harder it would have reversed direction going that way if he had not
quite as hard it would have continued on but more
with less still the cosine t but with less amplitude of but if you get
it exactly right it's fun to try to do
so really in our department is necessary this but in practice in the years you
so these content of course and instances of
methods that are used for us logical patterns in the domain dependent because they
allowed to use specific vocabulary
examples include
but to suppress part of general participation to an event in any event or how
to model plan or medical guidelines or essays order
all research topic or legal contract or inflammation situation timeinterval so meets of so suitable
solution that could be very general but also quite specific to domain and can be
organised into
this could be collected this the first kind of pattern and is being collected in
the ODP portal that i've already mentioned and that has
some function arising in between to submit to evaluate to contribute to organise this domain
based representation of this part is also an annotation schema that allows you to label
parts of aspects of the pattern and as you can do in software engineering for
example so i mean altering ten pros and cons and so on
one example is a gentle pattern
so you have here the representation the semantic wiki plus semantic forms plus semantic workflow
representation of this button on the on the fourth of
and so this is due to the metadata schema
and you have also the visualisation of some of the characterising elements of the pattern
the graph
by the way means that you can express i just the temporal
and you can have sensation of it for example i can
the role of the research but also farther north south player with it and can
use to use directly these and simply
so the simplest time interval in which you can use the property to express the
fact that the interval date has a beginning and the start date and end date
and then you
can use these for it is something that for example implements kind of an mission
logic part but applied to a content aspect which is pressing time intervals
another example is part of which you can display space for example transitivity of part
of in you that you made by the way we may want not to you
was in one context in which the seed is is also could be problematic
in this case of course this is always a plus extensive you don't spend time
of these
this more complicated if they want to suppress the top the fact that i'm participating
in these events in this talk today and not and when you go that symbols
and for example doing very similar one i have to use DNA logical pattern but
can also use these content oriented aspects so i can reuse the fact that they
can express
things related to the personnel two objects participating in events sometimes by using this is
like having a template OK in the sense but you can be used directly in
your ontology editor and then you can specialize it by renaming the elements of subclassing
them or instantiate them directly for suppressing the time war situation
was included centroid war and some time ago
another example is rule based on you can have rules
indexed by some examples
aspects so i can participate in i can have the role of to tall tutorial
this time but possibly not in one hour
and then you can be other domain oriented and so on
so i can specialize things for example when a about support to participation of an
object in an event but also taking part in a public enterprise activities are found
the semantic web project so on so you can have a partial order of
this content patterns or can compose them for example i can create apart like by
chemical treatment by using the
content patterns and create links between them
so let's use it how much time they have
the image
OK i tried to be to give you some examples and of course
it is important for testing ontologies and for use in the article unit test based
in this case i have the semantic web conference ontology the
users already some patterns that can be recognised that is not species that it uses
it so one point is that if you explicit the fact that you're using best
practices is that we make evaluation additional by anyone easier for any ontology so in
product class they typically use an entity relation patterns and in the topic but they
do use some
comm department so
this is topic models asking destructive and
represents the fact that they want to have
or uncooked spaghetti
electricity very well we call those insulating
porcelain is a very good insulator
three electrical wiring in your house
is made of copper
because it is such a good conductor
dry air
is very
you would air is a lousy insulator that's why
we have problems in september
and not
in february
it is not dangerous to touch at home your electric cords
the reason is
that the outside
is properly protected was an installation
but if you cut the wire you strip of the ends they use copper
that is really
twenty electric current occurs
but there is no danger because it's properly protected
this piece right now
it's potentially very dangerous
we're going to be ten minutes break you can be sure
i will remove this piece
and why do you think i will remove this piece
because some of you might just
plug it in
and then
what do you think someone touches that that is very nature
so we're going to remove that
but you have to be seen the idea
of an insulating on the outside
and conducting copper on the inside
you see here
the helium balloon
balloon filled with helium
suppose we have this belong here
and the building
is not positively charged
and the balloon is not negative
recall that neutral
there's no net charge money
but i approach it
glass rolled
and the glass rod has been raw silk positive charge
will come
two to run
even though
it is not for
why does it do that
electrons are being attracted by the positive charge and they can move very easily
and so electrons will move to this site some electrons move to the site of
the book
but you can create
try out of nothing so the other side automatically becomes a little bit positive
because the whole thing is still neutral for no net charge on the so now
you get
separation of charges in the balloon
the negative charge
is attracted by the positive charge
the positive charge is repelled by the positive charge but these are closer together than
these are and so on
the attractive force wins over the republic four
and that is called
and i will demonstrate that
before i demonstrate that i must be sure
that that balloon is completely neutral that there no chart on the board
in order to do that
i will have to touch it
i will have to considered
i will have all kinds of things to make sure
that whatever charges on it has been removed otherwise it's not fair experiment
from now on
what will
you just guess and it so i could anticipate
because it
that's what do you think this is finer space
we're looking at functions of finer scale and we're
this is it
multiresolution solar
power is to come and so
this space on the same thing
when he
finer scale scale
shifted by two
dilated by two
refined by two whatever
is that good for
key is that
refinement OK
many many papers about wavelets
will begin with
these assumptions
well i think it was the first to write down to put my stuff
often what i'm hoping to was like save you the trouble of going through the
assumption this is essentially what's going on we have a sequence of more and more
refined spaces
and we have a function with this translates
it spans the zero
and then scaled to
here the scale would be for the the scale would be eighty be feared eighteen
months and it's shifts
and everybody recognises five
OK so you have to do that
squeezes the function
by a factor of two
of course the model problem he always are
one or fifty
box function
and then we said what be zero
we describe these are last time
if if this is the box functional roles are one
i heard it described yesterday as the boxcar function so maybe that's also useful word
what's in the zero
take that function
they call it shifts integer shifts
the color combinations and what have you got
step function right
piecewise constant
so piecewise constant
on the unit interval
you know it
let me ask about the one
you withdraw we those pictures just
just constant every interval but jump between
OK what about the one
two what's the graph of f two g
it's of course
the same thing but only going to a half
what's in the space the one that
if i take all combinations of those guys
the shifts
that's what i mean
of all combinations of this and all its
it's half integer shifts
i can get piecewise constant
but the pieces of the half
after you know
so it is piecewise constant
on i say at intervals
you can imagine
the next extraordinary piecewise constant quarter rules and then
smooth function
whole function our whole space like whatever like that