we can construct a lots lots of algorithms that look like or that are dealing with
nonlinear function classes and but that correspond to linear things or lines geometric things
in high-dimensional space secondly  if we have  data that are  not vectorial
to begin with so we might not know how to we cannot compute
a dot  product between our input  data if we are able to construct a kernel
then we will get our dot product space representation for free because in this
case if we I mean  there's no condition here that our input points come from a
vector space so we might remember I told you before I will only assume that this X is
a non empty set so it could be anything but if we can define such
a positive definite kernel on this set then it turns out that we will be
able to construct a feature space such that the kernel computes the dot product in
that feature space so in that sense we will get a vector space representation of
the data yeah so maybe I should be more explicit so what I'm saying is the
class of kernels that are positive definite is exactly the class of kernels that have
this property that they can be let's see  which one do we use that that
have this property that they can be written as a dot product phi of X
phi of X prime in some other space that phi maps into so we will
prove this so we'll get back to this  okay so we can think of this
kernel as a kind of a nonlinear similarity measure and here there's  some examples of
kernels we've already seen the polynomial that we can also add this positive constant in here
in which case the polynomial kernel computes all monomials up to a degree D so
before I showed you only the case where C is equal zero where we compute all monomials
of exactly degree D we can also use a Gaussian kernel and
a lot of other kernels so that's so my experience is if I see a new definition
mathematical definition I have to work with it dit a bit  before I understand it so
I usually try to get everybody involved and and try that everybody plays a bit with this definition so I
hope you all have some paper with you and I have some some exercises that we'll do
or that maybe if you first do and then we do them together and
I would say we start with these and they all such that once you
see the solution you will say they're easy but if you don't if you
haven't seen the definition before nevertheless it's nontrivial to get into it and think
about these things okay so the first two properties  in the first two cases we
start with a feature map and then  want to prove that it leads to
a positive definite kernel so we start off with the so I told you before that the class
of kernels that are positives definite are exactly identical to the class of kernels that can
be represented this way this means whenever we have such a mapping phi and we compute
this thing we end up with a positive definite kernel and whenever we have a
positive different kernel we can construct or we can prove that there exists some phi
such that this positive definite kernel is can be represented this way so will prove
that this is true and one of the directions is the easy one this
is the easy one we start with phi  look at this thing and prove
that this kernel is positive definite afterwards we will prove the difficult ones so
please try to prove this what does it mean to prove this it means you
define a function K like this you don't know yet if it's a positive definite kernel
and then you try to verify that this such defined kernel satisfies this inequality
here no matter what X we use no matter what A we use so take take
the kernel on the other slide substitute it in here and see if you can prove that
and once you've done that you can try to prove the second thing so maybe I'll
say a word about the second thing as well and then you can get going so
the sec second thing is already it's also easy but it already involves
a little bit more  in the second thing we construct a kernel on
sets rather than input points so this is saying that if we have a kernel on
on the points of X then we can construct a simple kernel on sets of
points of X by just summing over  all kernel values that we get if
we compare elements of the one side to elements of the other side and  one
can prove that this is a positive definite kernel by constructing a feature map from
reasonable to assume infinite exchangeability if we if somebody tells you that my data
set the model my model should not depend on the way my data items are labelled
then you can directly say that you have to model your your data set using
a Bayesian model with an unknown latent variable G with some prior which you don't
know you have to construct it and then given G your data items are gonna be IID so it's kind of
directly goes from this very innocuous assumption of infinite exchangeability directly to a Bayesian
model which is given by this so how does this have to do with the
Dirichlet processes and the fact that CRPs are projective and exchangeable because the CRP
is projective and exchangeable  we can define such an infinitely exchangeable  sequence in the following way
so we first can sample a partition of all natural numbers according to a CRP
distribution parameterized by alpha I can't really say how you could do this but you can
imagine that you can do this in an iterative manner in the CRP basically every customer
that comes in you can assign into some table and if we imagine this process is running
infinitely long  than that gives you a partition of the natural numbers and that
would be a partition of the natural numbers then for every cluster in our partition
we can sample a Y a variable Y C IID from our base distribution H
and then we simply set  XI to be equal to Y C where C is the
cluster that I belongs to so we can visualize in the following way so
we have customers x one to x nine and we're simply gonna say that X one
X three X six all take on the same value given by Y one X
two and seven  are gonna take on the same value given by Y two and so forth
and because the CRP is projective and exchangeable you can show that this sequence
of X one X two  X three and so forth will be infinitely exchangeable so we can
apply De Finetti's theorem and say that there will be some underlying G that makes
all our data items IID and in the case of the CRP here the underlying
De Finetti measure the G will be a Dirichlet process okay so this kind of allows us a
different way of constructing a Dirichlet process from a Chinese restaurant process right I guess I've talked
about this before basically if you assume that your model shouldn't depend on the
number of test items and shouldn't depend on the way that your data items are labeled
then you should work with the infinitely exchangeable model and of course they are
scenarios where infinite  exchangeability is not suitable for example if you know that
your data your sequence of random variables is coming from some time series or
maybe  if so yeah that's the typical case in which you don't have
infinite  exchangeability another case in which you don't have infinite exchangeability is if
you know that there will be a fixed number of data items for your model
so for example if you're working with images and you know that the image's two fifty six
by two fifty six than you know that's the number of random variables that we have that's the
number of pixels that you observe okay in that case there's no you can't really think
about infinite exchangeability in that case because the model has to be only over a finite number
of pixels okay as I say exchangeability is quite important in bayesian statistics and there are generalizations of
infinite exchangeability to kind of other sort of settings so for example you can think you
can think about exchangeability in networks and in relational data so in in something
that collaborative filtering  we had these users going down the rows of a matrix
and movies going down the columns it's quite reasonable to a sum to assume
that users are exchangeable right so you can permute the users and that shouldn't change
your model you can permute the movies and that shouldn't change your model either so that's
what's called a relational exchangeability and there are like representations there are  generalizations
of De Finetti's theorem which applies to this more general notions of exchangeability
so there are hierarchical and hierarchical bayesian models and Markov exchangeability  as well okay
so coming back to the Chinese restaurant process now basically in the case of the Pitman
Yor process it also has a Chinese restaurant process representation but now this CRP representation
has two parameters it has the original alpha parameter and it has another parameter
called D okay which we call the discount parameter and the generative process
basically goes as follows the probability of a new customer sitting at  table C is gonna
be proportional to N C  the number of customers already sitting minus D where this D
parameter has to be between zero and one and D is zero we get the original
DP when D is greater than zero then we get a Pitman Yor process so we've subtracted
probability mass of D from each of this four tables we then need to
so at four times D to the probability of the new customer sitting at
a new table okay so the probability there is gonna be proportional to alpha plus
D times the number of tables that currently occupied so the idea is that
if we subtract what a D from each of this four tables then the probability
of a new table is gonna be lpha plus four D and if we have lots of
tables that are occupied then the probability of a new customer coming in and sitting at
a new table is also gonna grow as well sorry okay so the difference
as from before is that we have this editional discount parameter  and it's kind
of a nice parameter to have because it kind of  says that  if there are
we we should really do is average the predictions about these different classifiers
that's where the sum and product will give you but averaging even in parameter space
for this very well behaved problem
gives us different solutions to
what we get from max margin and really you can you can visualizes all very geometrically
u have data
and then
the data constrains in parameter space the feasible set of solutions
these maximum margin gives you a particular point in the feasible set
which has the largest enclosing ball
and the base point
would try the average
over the feasible set in a different way
this is useful to illustrate this also i do wanna make the point that a
lot of us and you'll hear a lot more about it work on bayesian discriminative
models things like calcium process classifiers and things like that
again just to reinforce this kind difference between parametric and nonparametric models
and i think i sort of
i make editorial commentary in that this slide okay so parametric models assume a finite set of parameters
in other words if you wanna make predictions given those parameters that
the rest of your training data is irrelevant
that's what this this is a conditional independence statements saying given the parameters the training data it can be dropped
in terms of making predictions about x
therefore you parameters capture everything there is to know about the data in a sense
your parameters are in a very strict and formal sense your parameters are information channel
from your past data
here future predictions
and all
the power of your past data goes through that's
other information
and the complexity of the channel is bounded by
the number of parameters that you have
this makes them not very flexible even if you have infinitely much data
you can only learn a finite amount of information from the data
non parametric models assume the data distribution cannot be defined in terms of such a
finite set of parameters but generally it means that it can be defined in terms
of some infinite dimensional parameter space
we can think of the
data as a function or an unknown distribution or something like that
the nice thing about this is that the amount of information
about past data that can be used for future prediction grows with the amount of past data that we have
and that makes them more flexible
another way to think about it is
parametric models are really model-based the really like
you know you write down any particular model you learn the parameters of the model
nonparametric methods tend to be memory based because to make predictions you need actually store
the past data in some form or store
a growing amount of statistics the past data in some form
in order to make predictions so this sort of the model-based memory
based distinction
and i think
on you
you know more important i talk about the bayesian versus more classical approaches
thing more important than the distinction is this extinction between parametric and nonparametric models
a lot of the most successful things that happen in machine learning so that the whole kernel revolution
and with support vector machines and all the other kinds of kernel methods
has really been based on
the success of non parametric
okay it's it's the
power and flexibility of nonparametric approaches
that has made us able to do a lot better than what we use to
be able to do with are small models
and even things like neural networks
like these large real networks are something like a deep belief network these models have
hundreds of thousands of parameters effectively
there are basically nonparametric models there's are so flexible
that's you know they can actually learn
whatever is in the data they let the data
it's code speaks for itself
and that's that's sort of an idea that that i think is quite powerful
okay any questions about their
so just as a preview
and i think john cunningham is gonna be talking about
nonlinear regression calcium processes
i could actually skip over this so that i can get to
the something making a very loud noise
the projectors overheating or something
alright interesting
we have a spare project about what we're gonna find a cave that's good
so i'm gonna skip over gaussianprocess processes just say
gassing processes define distributions over functions
her forget my polynomials example
as a practical thing you really wanna be fitting polynomials the data because you don't
really believe anything in the real world
comes from polynomial
if you want more flexible function approximators and gas processes are way of defining flexible
functions from data
you've heard about dirichlet process mixtures just now
maybe i'll just skip over this
because you've already heard about it
o point i wanna make is
the importance of distinguishing in this framework between
and an algorithm okay
so dirichlet process mixture r
is a model
of data
and now once to define the model
you can think of many different inference algorithms
so far
you know
predictive probabilities from your model
or r inferring hidden variables et cetera
and so
part of
all just in time series of their
so now we
most find of them
one might be
we want to all
not all
you know
both of
the wish
it was a lot of them
well you right
now he shouldn't
according to the
and then
there you go
it was you know
all o
if you can
it is
read thing
i have a
the problem
o one
it is called
and what you
let me
all right now
a one
i think that
we do not change
you need to
my office or vote on these forums
there are these
we do not
and the
it was
i to be the score that you give
two xl using the weight vector corresponding to the correct label so this will be
so this is our f of x i y i and then you will look
what score you give to all the other
one possibility is that are incorrect
right and
the margin will be determined to be the minimum of such difference
a y that is an incorrect y
and that means basically that if you know if we the minimum over all possible
y that means that we should we should choose this part in a way that
we use y had which is the argmax over all possible incorrect y
in that
passion he writes
basically what you would surely also you know diagram to explain this you take
the y hat that is the best which is different from why i write it
can either be the best if it if it is even better than y i
if y is the best it is it will be based in the second best
solution that you have and you will define the margin to be the difference in
score between the two
okay note that if this is positive then it means that you know your score
for why i will be higher than the score before we ever achieve the maximum
score with the rest sold also be higher than all the rest
right if you think the max
so here's here's a simple illustration
four that so
y value
here the hate is kind of the score the circles are the
labels if you like and in the field circle is that
correct one case we look at different labels and this score and there are three
cases that are outlined his case one would be one where the correct label gets
the highest score and there's a certain margin that you also
one to obtain let's say maybe it's this right margin of don't one something and
that's the case where
or let's say you want more one way you would be to achieve margin of
in fact a little bit more in the way you would measure the margin is
the difference in score between this and the next best example the second best which
would be this one right if this one word here then you would measure the
margin to the the to the circle right
then you can have a case where
the correct label still comes out on top
but it doesn't have sufficient margin to the next best one so this is here
the difference in score between this and this
and it's less than this a one here
and so then used to classify correctly but the margin into insufficient right and if
you look at the case here we're actually something else comes out on top and
the correct one is down here
you're margin actually turns out to be negative and that sort of thing so this
is so i don't know work with you you already seen this but this is
basically a way that you can introduce the margin
in the multiclass type of decision setting without necessarily thinking about things being on the
other side of the hyperplane can there's no sort of other side of side of
the hyperplane this is no more simply about the distance between the top the all
the correct one and the next best
OK so
and then you can
you can basically take part the two things together so what i talked about the
perceptron learning
four and
and then the
basically what i just said about the margin and come up with a large margin
formulation for multi class problems so this is all well known so basically you think
of your weight vector as being a concatenation
all of you know all of the weight vectors that you decline for the different
classes so this would be transposition OK so you take all your column vectors and
just stack them together
and then you do the usual things so if you do a soft margin SVM
you minimize quadratic objective in w namely it w just enters in a norm of
so note that the norm of w now basically is the sum of the norms
so you came here to be expected another soothing talk neil lawrence about faces and
now here first try
we're starting with statistical learning theory this morning
maybe fresh still and
rather informal
so the first twenty minutes may be required before and then
we have some
but actually falls out
maybe just some personal remarks about this discussion
i got the impression from the discussion and cognitive science
the weights right now is
it's about studying hall human animal cognition works
hello OK
so i got the impression about studying how
cooperation in animals works
i should say this is also what brought me into this field so i was
interested in theoretical neuroscience at some point but
i agree me have come to realize that for me is actually much more interesting
to think about the future of public goods cognition converge
more generally in
first of all animals systems in possible artificial systems maybe also what's the theory that
should be underlined such field of cognitive science so in that sense i think statistical
learning theory is one such
ten to construct a theory of some aspects of computer science
for me that's even more
fascinating and studying cognition in
and also humans even though i still think this is an amazing inspiration to look
at such problems for instance as discussed yesterday by chris
we have left cuts far from having a theory of cognition but
let's start with what we have and some statistical learning theory and i think even
though most of you probably won't work on statistical learning theory and actually i wasn't
working on currently myself i still think it's something that needs no one works in
this field so
i'm trying to today i'll try to give you an need how one can derive
statistical learning theory found so
just to make sure that if you see them in the future you're not intimidated
because the basic idea is actually not that difficult
but it starts very basic
so from the beginning from the empirical inference department of the max planck institute for
biological cybernetics by empirical inference i mean the process of drawing conclusions from empirical data
so the state could be observations and measurements and scientists were doing their friends all
the time with scientific inference so we might be measuring tools of x and y
which are related in this fashion and we might then be willing to infer
the there's linear law explaining these data points
but we might equally well
he willing to or actually we might
so it's it's already pointed out even if we scattered points of in
randomly on a piece of paper references but taking a quill pen we can still
find some mathematical expression that explains the states have what might be more complicated expressions
listed looks more complicated to us but it's also
a lot and
question is
why do we believe in the first law in this linear law
why do we not believe in the second law so what's the difference between these
so that's something that has been
it like this has thought about our mathematicians have also thought about it coming by
and try to be more recently
and it seems to be unclear what makes equations simple
what makes difficult the physicist robert full took a pragmatic view
he said that if this law it should be evident from the data
so he said if your experiment statistics you ought to know better experiment
so i tried to convince the interesting inference problems that are non-trivial
the problems were better experiments are not enough and i think there are lots of
sites from biology for instance in perception
let me show you some images of handwritten digits
so this looks like another easy problem of empirical inference with obvious to which is
which did you have no problem recognizing them
but it's the simple transformation of the images just apply a fixed permutation of pixels
so we just three all the pixels mathematically in computers we represent such images as
to tools
so this limitation is we are it just means we are really axis so for
computer and for many recognition algorithms these are actually the same kind of data so
for the computer this problem was not harder than this one you with a lot
it seems to be a paradox
and the point is of course the original only easy to us because we have
been trained on such images on our lives so actually the two problems in some
sense almost the the same difficulty that we've been trained all of life of brain
has been extracting statistical regularities of this kind of data
in the words of horace barlow was physiologist brings nothing but statistical decision or
so that's good because it means if we want to do
brain theory we have to statistical learning theory
and things like that
the most of them don't exist yet statistical learning theory is we know some things
so so far it looks like
there are some
trivial inference problems in science like finding a straight line to be obvious from the
data and there are some difficult inference problems in biology
but actually it's not the division also
many interesting difficult inference problems in science
and actually which is
study in the growth of knowledge
was applying machine learning methods in computational biology
so i'm going to be on this problem
they ask trying to see how people would label now the friends interface will create
sort of strength of the connection i can let the left side with the left
side of the bars means i barely know that i would never ask them to
lend money and so on and the right hand side means all very close to
me i would be very comfortable asking them for money i would be very helpful
finding had to find a job and so OK
so now
now this is that this is the first part of these are now the labels
they ask people to generate labels and now
the question is OK i don't want to connect the features for each for each
french so that then be tried use it for learning to try to predict what
the strength of the friendship is right and they have they have this four
four sets of features that were mentioned in the granovetter called the they can write
and they say how was density of the relationship like what is the number of
words in the world that were exchanged how many wall posts were between the front
between the pair of friends and so on then they have intimacy types of features
how many friends you have in common how how how much time has spent his
life last communication how how many miles between the hometowns and so on
sort of other classes of features that they consider about social distance meaning what is
the age difference what is the difference in education political views the reciprocal services which
is like how much information exchange was going on some structural features like number of
common friends groups that they have in common cosine similarity between vector of interests in
their profile and also some what they called emotional support we just count of positively
and negatively emotional words in the messages exchanged by between a pair of people right
now so we have this feature we have the ground truth because we ask people
what they think about each each each of their friendships and we try to try
to make predictions about what the price is right so here they train the linear
regression model and ask how strong is your relationship right now here i have different
sets of features and what you see that sort of intimacy which is like last
communication number of common friends number of intimate words was sort of the most important
the future in predicting device and that sort of followed by ten which is not
how many words did they exchange on the wall how many posts went in each
direction what was the depth of the thread of discussion
for example duration is another important thing then then on the fourth
this spot by important part is the social distance measures like on time difference in
political opinion difference and so on and then more emotional and structural features seemed to
be at the bottom
OK so now
now we sort of you examine what are the most predictive features of what people
consider as a strong relationship it is like negatively correlated with the they seems last
communication but positively correlated with the
how long have you know the person so the base since first communication and then
how many words they exchanged on the wall and so on and so forth right
so what is sort of the the nice about this piece of work is that
by obtaining a small label set of number of
of edges now contains kinds of fathers and possibly labelled the whole that the whole
facebook network we want to the strong ties and what does what sort of strong
more stronger relationships and what we relationships right so so this is sort of the
first part is going beyond just nodes and edges right so here it was let's
try to see if we can somehow automatically predict what the what the relationship what
is the strand two relationship of a relationship between a pair of people now i
sort of want to move on and not just say what is the same but
actually is this sort of strength positive or negative right so what i want to
what i want to talk about now is to think about links in networks as
positive and negative right so the way we think about this is that i have
some network that every edge has assigned
it has a positive sign or negative side right positive means something good something friendly
something that's what the negative sign is the opposite of the right and wanted to
look at is how how these signs in the network structure how do they relate
and they will also then you got
whether we can predict for example whether this of these two people that are connected
by an edge are the friends or enemies
OK so
the task will be not just a comment what the people i mean but actually
tell me what i think of the way you know would they be my friends
are within my own because in facebook you can imagine that in many cases where
you have lots of common friends with someone but you may not want to french
right so this is what it's like to distinguish OK so that's the idea so
the first question is whether we find networks that can that can be explicit signs
that actually are unlabelled pluses and minuses and here i talk i'll i'll focus on
three different networks for every edge
has explicit plus or minus late so in all these cases there is no way
to create an edge without labelling it with a plus or minus so the first
one is opinions productivity websites where i basically just means i trust your product reviews
that's the positive edge and negative edge means i don't trust your product right so
here this is us
it's directly
the data comes from wikipedia is election day so wikipedia is any ship promotion process
right after being on wikipedia for a few years you can you can be promoted
or you could be nominated to be promoted to become an administrator and if that
happens there is a public election where people come and say i support your nomination
i oppose your nomination right so now we have signed network plus means i voted
in support of your becoming an administrator minus means i oppose you becoming an administrator
right and the dataset we look at is slow datasets of this less of these
technological blog that has a social network attached to it which is called slashdot so
and then you can sort of label people as friends or enemies with friends means
i like your comments on slashdot and in your phone means i don't like slashdot
comments so what i should point out here is the following these datasets are in
some sense very much very different i mean opinions the interesting thing is that you
only your trust edges are exposed to the rest of the population while nobody is
one of the people who distrust on opinions there is no social cost of distrusting
everyone right nobody will see how people who distrust of how many people who don't
like and nobody who they are so you can be expressed would like know but
there is no sort of nobody will look at strange because nobody right but people
do not know who you trust so here only positive links are visible in wikipedia
it's different because here its election and its public collections of everyone gets to see
how people vote so it's sort of and it's a very serious process because after
you know two years of hard work on wikipedia you may be promoted and there
is the election so here it's very important what this outside and so on and
everybody signed the public archive and so so intensely in some sense it's it's the
most fun of the all because it's not really clear what does it mean to
be a friend or someone enough of of someone maybe you're just using someone if
you label them as well and so OK so very different but again every edges
either plus or minus datasets have around hundreds of thousands of nodes and between target
i will obtain the function that will fight together these two functions
i would think some function
of x a
x being
because i'm summing over see here
but this function will be factorized separately
in general
can not having guarantee that
the power
the only
between the available to get if you don't have any observations
and if
basically you have for example i spent three
just assume that it might mark mark of in the future
it is a spend three so there is no unconnected nodes
and you have not also
any know
so you cannot state that there is independence between any pair of not
i was there is a pattern that's not what
well as a matter of fact i didn't go into details into that because
that's actually
exactly matches intuition
we had to go through all the details for the vision advocates the separation and
all that but in case of markov random fields
we saw the initial condition depends but independent basically means
there's no path
if you don't need to condition well the party cases when the
set c is the empty set
even if that
you don't
if you condition on the empty set and there is no plan that
then it's independent
it means that
maybe i don't think so
so basically kris that's the reason OK
this is something that we should think about
also in the important concepts i mean they're theoretical concept but
i mean it seems since this is not the type of thing you will see
any graphical model for or in most graphical model for
i decided just to bring these up here
we can define what you call i maps
d maps and p maps
is that this is just informative but is important information
and and these are just labels that we give to a given graph
with respect to a given distribution
a graph will also be said to be an i map for the map or
p map with respect to a distribution
we see that the graph is that the map
of the distribution
if every conditional independence statement satisfied by the distribution
he is reflected
in the graph
in terms of
we have separation
a graph is said to be an i map
if the opposite holds if
if you take
at every conditional independence
the given distribution satisfies
is implied
by the graph is simple is satisfied
so what they say
the graph is said to be an i map of a distribution if every conditional
independences implied by the graph
he said fighting in the distribution so basically what you have here is
you have
and distribution
distributions may imply a set of conditional
independence statements
and graphs
i mean by another set of conditions
so let's write
set of conditional independence statements here in the set of conditional independence statements
if every conditional independence statement satisfied by the distribution
if every one of these guys
is present here
we have
but these graphs
the math
the map
or the
likewise he should have
if you have
possible conditional independence
that arises from graph separation these graphs
he is respected by the distribution
you say that these graphs is an i map for the
another class of really interesting graph which is this one
a graph is said to be a perfect map of a distribution if it is
both a d map and an i map for this
you basically have
he said in the set are exactly the same
so look at how interesting this is
you may
you may come up with a set of conditional independence statements
and that set of conditional independence statements
is the entire set
that is
implied by a given graph
and now we have to prove that the distribution that includes that set of conditional
independence statements has a bunch of for the
that may be OK for you but maybe
some of the others who are not interested in
i said we look at every and in fact we get a feel for what
kind of knowledge has been found to be most useful and then
those are all goes that so to
so the kinds of guidance that people were writing in this cave planning track and
this man jack in one two types of once one was deactivated knowledge for example
the collective knowledge about what are the solutions that have good water solutions that that's
not all plants are created equal
OK so for example my initial state was in phoenix my goal state was to
be in canberra and i can not in all probability was not particularly bright could
say you know what from phoenix to san diego and by from san diego to
los angeles and then you know take a flight from los angeles tools and yet
but yesterday i was talking to my my son and he came up to me
and you
which involves something like the extreme through increase my number of frequent flyer miles that
included at least going to a a couple of times and that would be a
it would be if you started from the initial state in
it's just that we may not like
OK so
people actually brought expert knowledge on top of the main physics saying what sorts of
humans implicitly
OK so these are the desirable plants that might last now they could write it
in terms of extra constraints such as you know these concerns might be satisfied by
this planners they could write what sort of state sequences remember when you're doing a
plan starting from the initial state as you do actions you're going through different states
of the world so you can think of the plan as a sequence of actions
i can think of it as a sequence of
and i might say
i have references on what's sequences of states i like and what from what sequence
OK so i can write knowledge in terms of my domain in terms of what
sorts of sequence of states good and what sorts of sequence of states that
and if my planet has that and being procedural and from being
progress and planning which is going forward then i can say OK i got the
steady state is state in this plan look this sequence is violating this rule about
bad sequences
so i want to go forward and this one
it turns out that one of the highly
effective knowledge based planners
game plan but the plan and i'll show you the kind of light and it's
pretty it looks quite complex and they were able to write that knowledge and they
were able to write an engine which incrementally
evaluate these formulas to decide if any particular brand is violating any of these
you know complex state sequence rules as soon as it violates the killing
getting back to the ground just by doing that they were able to get a
much faster solution
and then there is another way of doing it declarative grammar useful solution is actually
an interesting way of doing this which is suppose i don't value
what of the constraints of one of the sequences what i tell you that i
like a plan as long as it can be passed by this grammar that i
have that been
OK i think of the plans as primitives and then my grammar basically
it tells you these primitives together can be mapped these non non primitives and these
is going to map these non and then finally there's the root note
OK so if a plan is considered desirable if it has such a plus
it's not it's not desirable
this is sort of like saying a program is considered syntactically correct if the ground
grandmother actually passes the program
they don't tell you what it is that it was impractical to just give the
them and we have done this in in in the planning community that's called HTN
planning how to fast network planning where you can think of the knowledge that it
stands as a implicit grammar desirable solutions
OK and they will be inclined to now these are all essentially the quality of
in the sense that you don't change the inside of the customizable plans
it is extra knowledge this is given apart from the the main physics
OK and if the player wants to use it can use it if my account
is it and some some planet somewhat better uses certain types of knowledge some plants
what it used to but it's just given outside
the other possibility is procedural control knowledge which is sort of
either writing you know i hate level language programs for solving this problem
OK i
learning for control rules which are very specific plan so for example you might say
if you are looking at at the the following open condition and it has the
plan of the have the following unsafe feelings then don't try to establish this open
conditions using this choice
OK that's very specific it only makes sense that
and you can write those things to
obviously as you might expect humans are not very good at writing those and actually
much easier to learn automatically because you have to analyse the failures of learners you
can learn how to do that kind of search
so these are the kinds of guidance that have been tried in the knowledge base
planning and interesting of course the point of this briefly put is
depending on who you know
what i what i was writing the knowledge and then they are using you know
you have different kinds of planets between different kinds of planet so at least you
know as i some years back you know the it's the planners were able to
to be managed planners but the plan was able to be you know some of
the more interesting
reachability heuristic based plan is and then there is a sharp ridges and which actually
write sort of a procedural knowledge about domains
we haven't yet proved uh
there's the architectures something so far we are
now these results we just working with the properties are positive
the difference of the kernel
we're going to use them to construct they are so it's nice to
prove them
in by elementary means what we know we already and then we can
continue with the architects but every once we have the architects many things become
much easier to prove
okay so this one
maybe it's too easy and they don't want to answer any any
thoughts had approved that's
so you put in
practice so you have this
we have this condition
you know that this is positive
therefore we also know that this is positive if phi is nonnegative
now let's move on fine here
and then we have our original formula again
and then we have other five times
we know it's still
the positive
and what is this thing this is actually the same as
maybe now this is like
like a mathematician would write it
this is kind of our time scale value x
so now we know i've five times case a positive definite kernel
okay and basically
okay one plus came to works exactly the same point so this
sums is linear not only
products but also four sums so we can do the same thing to prove that this is positive definite
and this one
it's also relatively elementary
this one is the hardest one if you want to play around with it you can try tonight
this is
essentially a result of shawl
four put positive definite matrices social proof that
we have two positive definite matrices of the same size
and you take the element wise product
don't start matlab
you get a positive definite matrix so it's a pity if you don't know that it's a pretty surprising result
it's not trivial to prove
but it's also not impossible
i don't know the proof by heart but it's
maybe a page or something like that
so it can be done them
so if you want to try but we're not going to use it end
from that you can also
prove some results about tensor products and other things
and we wanted others
okay so
any questions about this so far
so even if you haven't solved all them more even if it happens after seeing
one of them if you have worked with the definition and that was the purpose
of the exercise
so u
might remember this definition are what it's about
and now we will
use some these facts to to construct the feature space
so the basic idea this is the overview of this construction
the momentary construction the basic ideas
we have to define the feature maps and now we want to prove
given a positive definite kernel there is a feature map such that the kernel is
the dot product after the feature map
we want to prove given kay
there is a map phi such that this equality is true
so let's define mephi hand and show that it doesn't what we want to do
so we have to define the find some space we have to
construct a dot product in that space so because we have both define phi in
the input space into which goes
and then we have to show that the product together with phi
satisfies this equality
four hour given concave
okay so we're going to
actually use a spacer functions like someone here in the back
i was mentioning before so one nice way of constructing its businesses today with spaces of functions
and the functions and we're going to use will be functions
defined on this domain x
functions in one variable which we get by taking the common substituting x
the second of the first symmetric doesn't matter but let's into the second arguement of
so now the first arguement still open which is why this is a function x
so the
the function and the argument of a function is plugged into you whether it is written
and visually forms as you can imagine if a user accounts and kernel
and are squared exponential kernel
exponential square whatever right
exponentiated quadratic so that the girls in process people have to have many words for concepts
we were talking about this the other day and
it's like the eskimos having lots of words for snow
pointed out like that the finnish having lots of different words for independent component analysis
so you take one of these kernels you map into that space
the end
the image of a point x in that space of functions will be
a gaussian kernel centered on the point x
the image over point ex-prime in that space would simply be causing kernel centered ex-prime so we have these different
these are functions
mapping x into are
because we subsequently
whenever we put some x into them they give us a real number
this is a compact notation for writing the space of all functions mapping x two are
so this is a mapping
we can do that it's not yet into a vector space
but we can turn it into the space required
we can then endow it with a dot product that satisfies this equality
this is the
nontrivial step this step where we're going to
exploit the fact that case positive definite
and the last step is actually
i'll skip that step that's sort of a mathematical details
so the first thing is
we have to into a vector space orally in space
and we simply do this by saying
well first of all i so i told you that this kind of bumps these
individual things there are elements of all space the images of
input points under all feature map phi
we will simply declare that if we take some sort of such bonds and actually in
if we multiply them with some real numbers before taking the sum so if we take general
linear combinations of such pumps people simply say
these are also elements not space so that's the definition of of all space that contains a
all functions of this form that we get by taking these
bonds end taking in combinations so typical functions our space so this form like this if are
so you just stop me whenever you want
so i'm a bit are real numbers
these are from all the main these are finite sums
now we have to define a dot product on such functions
well and we actually don't have much choice how we can define the dot product
because we want the dot product to be such that if we take two to
elementary pumps
just images of input points
and we want the dot product to be equal to the kernel
so remember
we want the
we want this to be true
now we have defined on mapping to it
to take x into a kernel centered on x
let's crew something easy here
sort of the aero version about respondents sometimes called assertion
so we have a hypothesis
and we give it the subscript
and what we're going to do is keep track
o lines in the proof or the hypothesis of the other hypotheses are used
OK we want to prove this
so we introduce that hypothesis to prove this so we want this and then use
implication introduction to get whole that's what we want is our goal here is a
narrow b
we introduce a or b is the antecedent of that we use it into implication
ah to get that if we get to prove b
OK so
the next thing we do
again you might be used to think systems where you don't have to do this
we just reiterate one
so we can use it to do
a modus ponens and implication elimination
so we reiterate one bring them
from two and three
get that now
what subscript e we put down on the what do you reckon
what we use to get b
which hypothesis
just to
and one
so i thought about this is why the segmentation
that's the set of premises used
now we can
now what
subscript you think we put on on air of b
we discharge the hypothesis somebody that we don't discharging hypotheses
we remove it
from the dependency list
so what's are
where we put on the subscript
it's just one
in order to discharge it had to be in there
this has to be in here to use implication introduction
that's the important thing it has to really be used
we couldn't just
we couldn't do
we could do this
where we just brought down and then discharged
because two wasn't in here
we have to find some way of getting it in
in order to discharge
so now one is in and so we can discharge
OK now what subscript if we put down here
the discharge once we remove it so what we got left
so you can leave it blank
often empty set
and that tells us that there
and it's not easy
some of the rules get a little fiddly
show you want the conjunction rules in particular
so that
shows you what the
the implication introduction and elimination rules are
the introduction rule
looks the same as classical works every got to keep track subscripts and the
hypothesis they are discharging has to really be an
the last subscript there
in the in the subproof
the answer is you can do it
gotta be really in there to remove
OK now that thing
is problem
we added to relevant logic it's going to give us classical logic we don't want
we really don't want and as i told you before it violates our intuitions are
relevant intuitions relevance intuitions about meaning of the word implication
so what do how do we get rid of it
if you look at this using just implication
as i said before
we can't
they were discharge that we can't do anything
now what happens if we add conjunction
and i think
the problem
has anybody studied lemon spokane
beginning logic
people don't tend not to any more because it's very out of date and has
very sexist examples but it's a nice system it's for classical logic but it's almost
for relevant logic but he has a derivation of this that is conjunction
so just with the implication rules we can derive in the fact
we have to have a conjunction rules to do this
and you might think the conjunction rules allow this
OK now looks like a good proof or we really used
so we brought in
and brought down a and just can join them together
on the basis of premise one two
we have
information and we have the information to be one of the conjunction
rather logic doesn't allow you to do that
they have to have in order to use conjunction introduction
and secondly
we don't know z
but it is
of interest
if someone tell us
be delighted to
no it costs
remember always that's what this is what we need to do model comparison so you
want to compare very small clusters
in data with one that says that just as you need to know the normalizing constant
those two
policies and then you can actually
the expression
we can evaluate the star we don't know z we like will
you won't complain if we don't know whether it
what column that is going to be talking about get is bonus
in general i'm gonna generalize and say that think that is the probability distribution over
this thing here
this is unknown parameters and assignments
i'm gonna give them they
and with apologies the canonical texts now
so this is the thing
the article that's why we talk about problem and x is the name if we're
actually talking about string x is the name for the unknown means and standard deviations
assignment of
data points
two clusters
what else to say about the rules of the game well what we actually want to know
we've got a probability distribution we are interested in
we can evaluate it any particular
argument so you can think and act and we can go there
well given the value of
and work out what this is all expression
come back to
and what we want to do
what we want to do is we solve these two problems
so just a recap notation gotta read distribution always right nasty distribution and red
can be written
also the artery at the minus e of x divided by z
it was just taking the log of star
so the assumption is that we can evaluate or equivalently evaluate
yeah that's child also has the energy that's very
so we can evaluate this what we want do we solve problems one
and two ideally
the problem is we would like to draw samples from this
what does that mean
i means i want to take this posterior distribution come up with some plausible representatives of it
i want to draw a few times on and say well i don't know what
the means sample assignments other his one credible hope is another and another
that means that could be there
you in this way the way you know
that's that's one
right now and sandro examples please don't get confused and think i'm growing points in this
i taking a risk
this is now the name or
unknown variables
the data is given it fits in our wandering around in hypothesis space and
coming up samples
posterior distribution over
all right
from two is
we would like to estimate the expectation of functions on the this distribution
what i mean let's give you an example
let's imagine that we are very interested in knowing
two particular characters
were written by the same scribe or not
is it can result
can you at the beginning something
so what would mean you want to know
well these are the same right
i mean you want to know
good to data points
and then use
all the seas equal to each other or not
when you answers
i don't know the name the data we can infer
probabilities and they are the same
so what want to do is take the posterior probability
all everything
it is this is given the data
and we want to know the average
averaging over theta
summing over
all possible theories about simon
we want to know
how probabilities
that's this proposition is true or one function that says
this is true is one one is that it is true
and we want to know the average and the posterior distribution this function which is
one when the two sees recall this zero otherwise
if we can compute this
expectation here
then we answer to the question what's the probability that those two letters written
six right
so what i said i'm saying that question problems that these to see the same
can be written as an expectation
another thing you might want to know if you're doing clustering
you might want to know
how probable is it that one of the means
it is somewhere in this book is is in this box
what's the role of the feature f
is there some feature
that the physical is cannot explain and so we need to appeal to something extra
physical to explain it
the physical this can only do a rotten job of explaining and if we were
to repeat like a demon theory did and we have more appeal to
something non-physical we do a better job of explaining
if we could find the right path
and make out the argument the physical is can't explain it or does a better
job of explaining it and the dual is does a better job of explaining we
have reason to believe in the soul
all arguments in philosophy it would be a tentative
argument is the ability we
we have some reason to believe the soul until we sort of see what next
argument comes down the road but at least give us some reason to believe in
the cell
so what i want to do is ask what might feature f b
is there any such feature f and
it's probably also worth underlining the fact that what i'm really doing is running through
a series of arguments inference to the best explanation is not a single
the argument for the soul
it's rather the name for this kind of argument
and depending on what have you fill in the blank with no one
pet feature that you're trying to explain by appeal to the so you get a
different argument so let's ask ourselves are the things that we need to appeal to
the pole
in order to to in order to
these things about as well as the first try
actually let me start by saying i'm going to distinguish two broad families of characteristics
we might appeal to the we might say
one set of approaches
focus on ordinary familiar every day
facts about us
that we love the fact that we think the fact that you know experience emotions
what have you
it is an ordinary features of us and then let's start with those and then
i'll turn eventually two
another set of possible things that might need explaining which you might think of as
extra ordinary
supernatural things you maybe there are certain supernatural things about communication from the from the
dead or
near-death experiences that need to be explained in terms of the soul so so we'll
get to those will start with
so the ordinary
every day
humdrum facts about even though the ordinary familiar x still could turn out that we
need to appeal to cells in order to explain the so to start
how about this
start with the familiar factors have already drawn your attention to a a couple of
times that you know you can have a body
that day had never corpse
and that's clearly not the person
living beings out person
it doesn't do anything it just live there
whereas your body my body
it is is animated right i move my hands around my mouth is going up
and down it walks from one part of the stage to the other parties stage
maybe we need
there are to appeal to the soul
in order to explain sort of one
and animates
the body
and thought would be
know when the soul and the body had been separated sets the dualistic planes the
soul has lost its ability to
give commands to the body
and so the body no longer animated so got a possible explanation of the difference
between an animated and and on animated or inanimate body
two it is the sole contact of the right sort with the body there is
a possible explanation
you might say look the physical is can't tell us that because all the physical
parts are still there when you've got the corpse
o if it's a fresh corpse
before the decay has set in
we need to appeal to the existence of the soul in order to explain the
animation of
bodies like the ones that you and i have
i said i'm going to run through a series of arguments
but that doesn't mean
doesn't mean that that lies just another and what does it mean that the
but rather it is that it doesn't mean that i think the arguments all work
now i know in the first class then i don't myself believe in the existence
of us all
and as such it shouldn't be any surprise you that what i'm going to do
and so it is zero
trouble with
they might even roots the in the first half of the twentieth century in that
it would very good
around the same time
there's hole in the middle here now
the invisible any
the issues
actually i think mean it
it's the one
this is an extremely who did
o four months
i mean that's a
so i think there was kind of
try to find a black and white
so there are a world of any not something that really BCE until you can
do tend to the other
during this is the
friendship relations among thirty four members of the university
right so
several times as slow
how to get into this
is very
social and technological networks as you
to information systems with intrinsic structure right to see that things like facebook and myspace
well i was not designed to use the media and the intrinsic of structure but
the point
this is the current context is there
well think the social networks as facebook or something that appears and creator of past
few years i see some water pre-tax things
for a long time and so what
these different fields learn from each of the convergence here is what can appears science
and social sciences
from each other
one of the learning sciences
the measurement social networks
mining social networks really
this is
so we get a
examples here but
two years later i was in
thirty one network
french citizens with his phd work
temple university in new york nineteen seventies and the idea was simply take a
so you enter politics take a very
constraints is very close to one membership and limited kinds of social ties
prior his
it's time for him and
to develop
one snapshot and whether he
planned in this way it is
that's the science division chance favors
here my
course these two years he was looking at a
five club actually split
nine hundred thirty four
she remembers here
why does
the founder of the students at the university went unnamed the story
number one here right or not there was constructed by the criteria very charismatic figure
he started throwing things to him away from the original core principles close and focus
was right
founder versus strong
ten five social ties between this we can and found
of taking up first with
they actually splits
tactile sensors thing really
well founded
the structure of the other way so tied the middle and in fact
politics he went into the
the literature on
algorithms and time was almost no reasonable all
so that you is going to be able to explain
minimum cut in social network mainly
we're told the fewest number social
this was
the way the patterns were
september nine years
which user apologize
three weeks away from for your first black belt in karate and could only to
the instructor was forced to return to
well i don't know what is really a
something that we were
we have to think
mining social network data from the nineteen seventies it took him three years after collect
this thirty four network and one
what do we bring to the table
if if if if all this is one of course is a matter of scale
right so it's not just a small things like club
many many others to i try to go and how it actually here think about
some of the social network to use computers
this is a very simple form
in the network
if you have mountain
what makes it harder to two thousand three
the last temperature on computers show that for now
network who
you know two
here's the first doing business
what the in two thousand six
and it's going to get into the realm of making the invisible visible right social
analysis of the history of exposing things that are all around us is
scale really minor imagined twenty years the able watch in time female to
in fact hundreds
four million people one would like want
this will be something like this
so much like my space in the past few months just to report by the
no no i was about to say and now for something completely different
let me start by saying that it's an honor to be here
in front of such august
company and such a lovely setting
thank you all for sticking it out so late in the day
so my talk is going to have two parts the first part is
generally historical
because a couple of years ago during the kernel centennial i was invited to
give a talk on girls which can be a little bit worried at the time
one thing i'm not a historian
so don't claim to have any great historical insight but even more worrying to me
was the fact that the time i didn't feel any great affinity to to good
so i was raised in the whole proof theoretic tradition
of of working in starting formal axiomatic systems and even though as well as i'll
explain kernel himself work from within that tradition i always felt tension in him that
made me
a little bit easy
and so what decided to do at the time was you know read and girls
work in writing and and
remarks he made to how long and and and and work through it and so
actually the first part is going to be a somewhat personal
a view of what was going on that tension
and also to explain you know what i take girls ambivalence the metamathematical tradition to
and then what i'd like to do is discuss some things are going on in
contemporary work and metamathematics proof theory that i find particularly interesting
like to discuss those topics in light of course concerns
OK so i would like to start though
before tell you about a girl my talking about health risks
so even though the mature formulation of public program didn't appear
until nineteen twenty two and nineteen twenty three he interested logic and foundations
began much earlier
so his eighteen ninety nine belong in the geometry given the axiomatic treatment of geometry
that was revolutionary
the nineteen hundred paper there gives the maximisation of the real numbers of his famous
list of twenty three problems presented at the international congress in mathematics in nineteen hundred
three of them had a distinctly foundational character having to do with countries continuum problem
the consistency of arithmetic and mathematical treatment of the axioms of physics
then in nineteen four he gave an early attempt to and flawed attempt to treat
the consistency problem in syntactic terms
and then after nineteen o four largely left the topic until nineteen twenty two
say for a lecture on axiomatic semantics is thinking in nineteen eighteen but his lecture
notes from the time show that he was actively engaged in in these issues in
much in the from much of the intervening period
for example lecturing them annually
so by nineteen twenty two the legal like constraints resulting from was intuitionistic challenge was
gathering steam and that's when hulbert
presented his program to secure the foundations of mathematics
the general features of his program are
now well known
the idea was that you were supposed to characterize the methods of modern mathematics so
including nonconstructive infinitary
reasoning is to characterize those methods and formal axiomatic systems and then prove the systems
consistent using secure safe finitary methods
now this program is often taken to presuppose the position whereby mathematics is taken to
be nothing more than a game of symbols with no meaning beyond that is that
beyond that given by the prescribed rules and so you can find such characterizations of
formalism for example in prowess inaugural address the university of amsterdam as early as nineteen
and it also ramses and mathematical logic of nineteen twenty six
and it's true that will help but is is emphasizing six the syntactic nature of
his program his language often does suggest such
but i think it's it's silly to take this
this to characterize the mathematics more generally any of course but we respect for mathematics
and he's the last person thing to to hold the view that mathematics is meaningless
symbol game
and when you
look past the rhetoric
and put his remarks developing context we are left with are just two simple
the first is that with syntactic characterization of infantry mathematical reasoning in hand the question
of consistency becomes a purely mathematical questions
this is the first observation
and second of all the consistency proof using restricted trusted body mass this would provide
solid re-assurance to anyone concerned that infantry methods might be unsound
and so i take the
the core methodological presuppositions of program to be embodied in the following simple outline so
first of all there is the claim the formal axiomatic systems provide faithful representations of
mathematical argumentation
and in the sense that once you have a mathematical proof if you can you
develop a formal representation of it
then with this representation and had at least some foundational not an epistemological questions can
be formulated in mathematical terms it's specifically was was
at least
most sales
concerned with the question of consistency
and then finally a finitary syntactic perspective makes it possible to address such questions without
presupposing substantial portions of the body mathematics under investigation by so if you're trying to
reason about the trying to understand methods reasoning about the infinite many observations here you
can you can study our methods of reasoning about the infinite without presupposing anything about
the infinite at all
so you see
from fifteen centimeters really goes to one million
here is our five hundred kv electrons
and notice that i
the the
calculation correctly
this is relativistic the corrected now you get two point six times ten thirty eight
meters per second
by applying the formalism that you see there
i will leave this
throughout this lecture
because i will return to this
several times
i want to sell you a
acute demonstration
i have an electron gun here
an electron gun
comes like so
this is the velocity of the electrons
i wouldn't mind signed to remind you
they are electrons are the electrons going this direction
currently in that direction
and so if now i have the magnetic field
let's assume the magnetic field is in the blackboards
this is b
i crosby's direction of the force
i think these are actually
using the blackboard
if i'm not mistaken
i think the forces in this direction
and so
you'll see
but it starts to bend this direction
if you change
the direction of the
magnetic field
if you just coming out of the blackboard
and the electron
this i can show you that you
it is not too different from the distortion experiment i did when i had the
television program there and and i had this strong magnet and we distorted the image
but this of course is a little bit
so i'm going to see the image there
and we
i want to make it quite dark in the room
two and on the
electron gun
using the electron gun it strikes a fluorescent screen
and that's how you can see it
and i have here bar magnet if i hold the bar magnet behind it
and i can create more or less
situations like this i can flip over the magnet
and then
the direction of bending should change so the outcome was the magnet
you see
curve that electrons
i turn the magnet over
and i come in again and the curve
very straightforward
very simple
there is a fantastic
the way in
that we can separate
one and the same element
if we for instance
and uranium
when you find it
two ninety nine
o point three percent
uranium two thirty eight
that means it has ninety two protons otherwise it wouldn't be iranian
and it has a hundred and forty six new pond
nine nine
o point three percent
o point seven percent
uranium two thirty five
again ninety two protons otherwise it wouldn't be
but only a hundred and forty three neutrons
and that you'll find in nature
o point seven percent you got chemist
and you get the cameras the uranium and you say would you please separate
these two isotopes for me
and he of course would laugh at you
and he would say go fly a kite because the chemical properties are exactly the
same for the two
because uranium as uranium neutral urania ninety two electrons and neutral during the nineteen two
electoral but there's no way that they could separate out
i'll show you know
how they can be separated which is what we call a mass spectrometer
during the uranium
sort of that ionizers let's assume is ionized one so it loses one electron so
it's positively
charge with one
unit charge one of those charges that you see here
we now accelerated over certain potential difference o
these uranium atoms to thirty five to thirty eight get certain
speed in the coming here
with the speed
so the positively charged
and let's assume that we have a magnetic field
that is uniform
and that is in this direction
comes out of the blackboard
so what will happen is that the
charged particles which are positively charged now
one unit charge
i going to go around the circle
and hit you
the radius
but if you look at these equations
so you will see that the rate is proportional was the square root of the
mass of the particles
and the mass of two thirty eight is one point two percent larger
then the mass of two thirty five
so with one point
two percent larger since we have the square there
he describe it
we accelerate them over the same potential difference and this one doesn't change
this is the only thing that changes
but it may be sufficient for the task of language identification
OK so
these are parameters
these are the values of the parameters that i was going to change the notation
one more time i just want to emphasise here these are just numbers here
right we don't have to call the probabilities at all of this point
we're defining
p of p of a string here forces as being the product of these numbers
i think i picked to stanford try grammar maybe for table
because you look these up in a hash table for example or re
so if you want to know
what the probability is either given or in as
associated with this program you look
and here's the number you get
and how do you get it will get it by
i mean we're that come from it came from counting things of the problems
so here's our prior
given a particular set of values of the parameters
we get the definition of p
and what can we do with our definition of a one thing is we can
roll dies
so we can say let's generate tags according to this flow
that's actually a good thing to do when you build them we'll do this happening
when he went to build a model of language you should see
what that looks like an end in well in this case we saw that with
trying to model it started to be pronounced all with the foreground model and started
have words with seventeen grandma what would i would probably just produced genesis
because for that particular set of sixteen characters
there's probably only appeared one time in genesis and there's only one character that follow
so just reproduce what happened in genesis that point that model has no no bias
at all it's exactly reproducing genesis but it has very high variance model of english
because it always gives you know completely dependent on this corpus the estimated from
if you really wanted to seventeen grand model then you need an astronomical texts
in order to be able to generate something that looked like english generally and not
just like the sampled you estimate
so once you've got he can generate
and more important for our purposes given that like a sentence you can find out
what the probability is
and in language i d
we say we've got the same model
it's got the same structure
we just have different parameters
we've got our english program numbers and our polish striker numbers
what comes out from
is two different
two different probability functions and then given some data access
since we can compute p of x in qx
and decide which one is
so far so good
i want to spend a few minutes now just talking about
just just talking about notation making it a little bit more precise because people sometimes
get confused about this so
this axis here is an element of some event space
for example the space of all races through the space of all sentences if the
that's the whole text
so we want to know the probability of the corpus
well that's the problem believe all the sentences together
and if we want that it's pretty reasonable
to take the general
in fact so if we want the probability the whole text we said let's take
let's pretend all the sentences are and multiply the probabilities of the individual sentences together
so is another example
well i've been repeatedly doing it
is this actually is this assumption actually
is it the case that sense to really is independent of sense
probably not
if i talk about brain sentence one maybe i'll talk about bread-and-butter instance two
these things are related sense two is unlikely to have here is you know unless
i mention the person of the appropriate gender instance one
or elsewhere in sentences
but you know this is
this is not a terrible such
it's common
all right so i've said that x is an element of some of the space
so often have a sequence of letters
well that's kind of funny because
this doesn't look like an element of an event is right this looks like the
of different sets of events
this is the the set of all sentences whose letters e
is we're taking intersection of sentences was first letters age with those who secularism with
those used the letters are
when we take this intersection we get all sentences whose first six letters spell horses
what is this notation really mean kind of content that before
so x two was supposed to be the second letter in the sequence going to
stick my story here they are space is something like the set of all sentences
every sentence is the that
x two is the second level here's another example
are there is a sequence of three point lines
but you might write something like the probability that the number of heads is to
remind previous in one of these ways
so what we mean by
over here the events of race but again we're writing credits
which pick out some subset of the set of races
so what's going on here
the answer is that
variable is really a function of the event as i hinted before
really the right way of writing this
it's like this
event is a sequence of letters
any event this so any is a sequence x two of that is the second
element of the sequence
we traditionally suppressed this part of the notation
what we have the probability that ages to what we need is the probability that
we have some of the whose age is two
in the images like a method call
which tells you back some property of in this case
the company has worked in that
races might be amazingly complicated events they might talk about you know if you know
the race you might be able to inspect the race and find out who the
jockey was and what phase the moon was whether the track was money and so
forth in this case we're just looking at one property of the race namely whether
the weather
so that's true some that's it's possible others what they think about the notation is
that here we have said that the events races but we could get more complicated
and say that the event was you know some even more complicated state of the
world and we can still pick fact
asked whether
what value of this function on the state of the world so we don't really
have to commit usually what the that space was we only have to that we
were working on our models one
things we have to be able to compute of events
OK so
just to do this for a couple of couple of examples we've looked at
when we ask of probability the number of edges two
what we need is
the total probability of all of this
that have two heads so that the total probability the set
now we can divide this set up into three pieces right
because these are disjoint subsets
so the probability of heads and tails heads tails heads and tails heads heads and
the total probability those things is
calculating expectation
is larger than one
probably you are very happy
if you are allowed to play a game
we do but as
because the expectation is larger than one then
you expand that each round
you may calculate
the expectation
all for the price of the asset finance which is the product of the previous
and you know
that the
the expectation of indeed all the product of independent random variables is
the product of the expectation
each fact or
he had expectation five or four but what together we have that feature
all the price goes exponentially it's fine
yeah but this is the
misunderstanding and danger
what i would like to
show you
you may ask
what are the typical values of the prize of the random prize
what is the
as input because of the growth rate
and and
for the asymptotics of the growth rate of
you calculate the average growth rate
this is the average of the
and here the average is also
an average of independent random variables
the average growth but the expectation
and if you can only be expectation one half time a lot though
last one half the log one half is zero
so if you just keep your money in these artificial park
then you have their growth rate
and it is it is shocking if the final guy can
i understand
from the people garden
he learned
that a random variable is around its expectation
and it is not the case here
because the the expectation
exponentially to infinity
and the random variable
it is typically around one
so it
it means
that if i applaud the density
of as an
then the the we large probability
the method used in this range
the expectation
is much much larger
then the typical values of these random variables
and the reason is that these random variables
it is the product
of some random variables
and the problem theory is on the average
on the top of random variables and not on the product of random variables if
you see a problem on the product of random variables then you have to transform
your problem in full
the number of random variables in order to
i have a right picture on the problem
the fear
i if you win the one dollar
the return means that investing one dollar what is the reader
even that one dollar that either you have to derive
it probably you one half or half dollar we probably you want
i don't understand
you you you've seen at this point that this is a misleading calculation
this is what you are seeing
that reaches the final four
in expectation and i gain
one over four dollars
in each round
investing one dollar
the return is filed before
the game is one or four
the point he is
that you have to take it at interest level
growth rate and in it the level
it is
random walk
is the
if it log base two
then it is last one
n minus one
but the in that level
if the random walk with me is there
the result in average growth there
but this is the the first of all in the second component
is the cash
that has there great
then i make a portfolio
forty two as i have to ask that both of them
zero growth rate
but they use the portfolio for the
thought of their growth rate
the portfolio mies
probability distribution so need
having first component b
the other component is one minus b
kernel methods methods just provide a principled way to address this kind of problems
with these kind of
of models
and this one is a very powerful on the kernel methods
so the idea is the kernel trick
i'm sure a lot of stuff
you guys know about the kernel trick but
it is
the crux
so the kernel trick
here it is
in a very it's simple way
you have a early separable dataset as
on one side and on the other side you know that you have a very
simple algorithm
let's say not simple but just linear algorithm you have something that is capable two
two to compute the hyperplane so your focus is hyperplane you know how to compute
a hyperplane
now what you want to do is to use your your favourite algorithm
to compute hyperplanes in the situation where hyperplanes are not sufficient to do classification
so the idea behind the kernel trick and the idea is a little bit reversed
the way i am going to present it is a little bit reversed with what
is actually meant by by kernel trick but it helps understand how
how how how it works so
the idea is that if you have a nonlinear nonlinear and a non-linear problem is
but you may want to try to map all your data into another space
usually high dimensional space where
this is the linear step separation can be
can be solved for
so these these mappings from the input space towards these special high dimensional space which
we're we're going to call the feature space
it is usually denoted as five
so these these guys here
and what you want is that these are the space age
you want to be equipped with a dot product because
if it's equipped with the dot product then you can work in this space try
to find a linear separator in this space and then only work with the images
of the training data
by bye
and on the the the training data by by themselves and
i think that this better summarize the idea is that you have these non linear
separable problems use
the mapping phi
that goes from x to some feature space h
and hearing have all the
images of the
right points
in this this space and the images of the blue point in this space and
in this space you can do linear separation
and again the the crux is that you assume that there is an inner product
in the space because if there is an inner product we just so that it's
possible to find a classifier
it's it's just easy if you have an dot product in the space you walk
in two two
to derive an two to compute the decision surface so this this is the idea
of the
the kernel trick but it's not precisely the idea i i'll come to it in
a bit
so if
i'm going back to the previous algorithm
the very simple linear algorithms
they means that
instead of having the dot product between between the exercise and x
then you will have the dot product between the phi fixi i
and the five x
so if you have your mapping phi and you can work with the mapping
then it's just very easy to compute a non-linear
by using exactly the same algorithm as before
provided that you have
and in the product in the space age
and here is actually the kernel trick
the bits
OK this is just the step before the actual work
the kernel trick
the kernel trick can be applied so this is trick again i'm going to to
take it and go into the
so the kernel trick is just a very simple thing which say that if you
have a linear ordering that works with dot product that you do something very silly
but very powerful every time you see a dot product review replace it by
a kernel function k
because if the kernel function k
then you know that it's using kernel function k
it is precisely like as if you were mapping or your data from an input
space to work well designed
feature space
so why is that the way that because what you're going to use is
mercer mercer or positive definite kernels
positive definite kernels or or functional
taking two arguments and outputting the value or
you know in the real sense
and so if it is positive definite if
compute computing
k of UV is equivalent to first mapping u
and v two some hidden space and then to compute the dot product between those
not those mapped instances
and the key points actually on on the the way i'm going to i'm trying
to to bring into the kernel kernel trick is that the end facets
is usually when you want to use the kernel trick and the idea of mapping
actually the the idea the emphasis on the very the important thing is not to
find the phi transform to the phi transformed the fine mapping but actually it's more
to find the
but then he meets
someone by the name of
what we have we have to follow
and he meets
this man wrote to partner
and this is where probability theory apparently comes in the two-parter now
tells now that he knows the science of gambling and he
well teach two
but it has to be done by whispering in his ear because it's deep and
extreme secret
and now is skeptical
how does the two two-pronged know how to to gamble
and so
the two parent tries to prove to him his abilities and he says
see that tree there
i can estimate how many leaves there are on that tree
by counting one believes on one branch over two partner looked at one branch
and then estimate the number of leaves in the tree
and now was
step to call
he stayed up all night and counted every leaf and the tree came very close
to what now are two parents
and so
he next morning believe now
they believe it to partner
now this is interesting hacking says because it shows that sampling theory was part of
knowledge theory
if you don't have to cover all the leaves in the tree you take a
and you can that and then you multiply
so anyway the story and now goes back and now armed with probability theory we
he goes back and gamble's again he has nothing left to wager except his wife
so he
he puts her and gambles her remembering now he knows what he's doing
and so he really wasn't gambling his wife he really very pure and arable land
so he won back the entire kingdom and that's the end so anyway that shows
that i think probability theory does have a long history
but it not being an intellectual disciplines it didn't really informed
a generation of
finance when you don't have a theory
then you don't have the way to be rigorous
it was in the sixteen hundred that probability theory started to get written down as
a theory
many things that happened in that century
which i think are precursors both to finance and insurance
one was in the sixteen hundreds
people started constructing life tables
what is the life table
it's a table showing the probability of dying at each age for each age and
that's what you need to know if you're going to do life insurance
so they started to do collecting of data
and mortality
and they developed something called actuarial science which is estimating the probability of people
and so
that then became the basis for
in france
now actually insurance goes back to ancient rome
in some forms
in ancient rome they had something called burial insurance
you could buy
that protected you against
your family not having the money to bury you if you died
and in ancient culture people were a great deal
about being properly buried
so that's an interesting concept they were selling that in ancient rome
but you might think
why just for burial why not going to make it into a full-blown life insurance
and you can wonder why they didn't
i think it may be because they didn't have the concepts that
in renaissance italy
they started writing insurance policies
but i read one of the insurance policies it's in the a journal of risk
and insurance they translated a red sox insurance policy
and very hard to understand what this policy was so i guess they didn't have
a language they didn't it was
there were intuitively halfway there but they could express i think the
industry didn't get really started
i think it's the invention of
probability theory that really starts and that's why i think theory is very important in
finance i
some people date
fire insurance with the fire of london in sixteen sixty six
the whole city burned down
practically in a terrible fire
and fire insurance started to proliferate right after that in london
but you kind of wonder if that's a good example for fire insurance because
if the whole city burns down insurance companies would go bankrupt anywhere here right london
insurance companies would because
the whole concept of insurance is pulling your problem of independent probabilities
and so
but nonetheless that was the beginning
we're also going to recognise however that insurance
got a slow start
because and i believe it's because people
could not
i understand
the concept of probability
he didn't have
they didn't have the concept firmly in mind there's a lot of aspects to it
you know
there's an ad it in order to understand probability have to take things as
coming from a random event
and people
don't clearly have that in their mind from an intuitive standpoint they have maybe a
that i can influence events by willing or wishing
and if i think that if i have kind of mystical side to me
then probabilities don't have a clear meaning
and it's been shown that even today
people seem to think that they don't really take at an intuitive level probabilities
very as objective
so for example if you ask people how much they would be willing to bet
on a coin toss
they were they will typically that more if they can toss the coin