all the weights the one
now at every time step
we observe our feature
and then
for every action will determine the probability
of choosing that action in this time timestamp so this is where
where forum our probability distribution over actions
that we will use so
each action
i will have some minimum probability
it was which it will get chosen so that distribute some
probability mass
but put it in every action and this is the remaining probability mass
after with itself
and this is how the remaining probability mass is distributed
over the actions you just some the weights
of the policies predicting that action and you normalized by the total sum of weights
so to determine the probability of choosing action a is just some of the weights
of all the policies predicting that action
on this axis
and you just normalize but it's it's it's pretty natural you choose action
proportionally to
the the weight the total weight
on policies choose in that action
but there is some probability mass that you put the site
and distribute randomly over all the actions
so that every action there is some minimum probability with which each action is chosen
and this technicalities needed for
the proof to go through so you need some minimum probability that
every action gets
and it turns out that the optimal value of this minimum probability skills was something
like one over root key
and there's
this log of the number of policies again
OK so what did you formed your distribution of actions and you draw an action
on that distribution
you observe the war it
and now you update the weights
so that they can be used
in the next round to be the probability of actions and you do that by
four men
an unbiased estimate of the war
if to update the weight
i have a given policy pi
if the policy
doesn't agree with the the action that was actually taken
then you do not have the the weight the weight remains the same
if you do that
if pi agrees with the action taken then you multiply
the the weight by
an exponential function of
this is the
estimate of the world trade to divide the reward by the probability of taking that
action where
the probability comes from here
right and we multiply by the this we can think about is the learning rate
and the importance of
multiplying by the exponential is that
you can say
when you multiply the exponentials you get some
in the exponent over the rounds when you
look at the some of you can look at the
some of these quantities so with around
when you multiply
so this algorithm gives there are no assumptions about
about how axis and are is a generated
so they can be adversarially chosen
and you can still compete in a very strong sense
so if you really good at will be will scale as
square root of t
where is your time horizon
and you don't need to know t here
so this is a very good of
it sounds
right so that's the theorem associated with that
and there's a matching lower bound
and so this is the bound
on the expected regret
and it can be modified
on their way to get the the algorithm can be modified to give a high
the vic's over px i just turned
the p and q upside down and again in the minus sign
so if you want to let me call this object
so it's a function of x
it's a new random variable y
so what i have is
expectation of the negative logarithm of y
the negative logarithm is something logarithm looks like this is the negative logarithm looks like
that so it's com
this guy is a convex function of y
this will be greater equal to
minus log
expectation of y
which is the same as minus log
some over x
p of x which was why again it was q over p
so we got
two pieces here we cancel it we get some over x q of x q
is also probability so it sums up to one so it's equal to minus log
some q of x x
this is equal to one one log of one is zero so we get a
zero is i've just shown greater or equal to zero so this is the only
thing that i need for the moment for the proof
so what i construct now is the following things
so i construct
the following object
so i just take any q of x
and i consider the p
the probability of the hidden variables given the observation y
so now i introduces the definition of p of x
p of x given y is
p of y common x
divided by
of y
right that's the definition of conditional
so if i put this into here and rearrange this
i get this inequality
so i just have to plug this in
right turn this the other way around
and again and minus
this gets here
and was just
insert this
into this inequality you get a new inequality
for fixed data the right is actually
the biggest value for q
it is actually this
because if q is equal to p i get zero here and there is no
longer an inequality anymore i to the best you can have is the one where
q is equal to this
let me see
so what we're not doing that so the first thing was in the e step
of the
go back to
to the EM algorithm here
first of all
what i need in the in algorithm is this quantity is the probability of the
heaven hidden variables given y and the previous parameters
how do i get that out of an optimisation procedure i get it out of
an optimisation procedure
when i form this quantity foreign this quantity look here
this quantity and ask what is
the key of x which makes this object maximum
and the object that makes this thing and maximum
precisely this
so i take this p of x which is the maximizer of that
in the second step
i'll take this
so q of x
so the best q of x is p t of x given y and the
previous parameter so this is qt called this qt
in the next step if
so if i rewrite this quantity
it's a bit
messy so i have a q log q that this part of it
and i have a q
log p and that is precisely
the definitions
after this
this thing
so what i have
it can be DEM algorithm can be viewed as doing the following things
well just
find q which maximizes this one
and then i find the parameters theta
maximize is this one
it seems like this is
this object is the one that is always maximized so i take an old data
maximizes with respect to q
and if i have
maximized with respect to q then i keep this t free this this data free
and replies it again by by one
that that maximizes the sick and say this is the object of relevance i optimise
for fixed that even i keep q fixed and then i optimize theta against life
cycle between the two things
right so
then i can show that actually in this way
decreasing the log likelihood
but i'm always going in the right direction
so let me see
do we have that
right so
we start from this
we identify
this debate
is that
and so we get a abound
so of this is what we actually
i would like to maximize so we can show
this for anything it is this period equal to that
we also know
if i said a to be equal to the old parameter i get an the
quality here
so that follows from
this line here
that if
if i put in qt year
then i would get
and quality
so what i have
it is these two things
one of the many many articles
here we
in the
we to do
running gag on
thank you
in here
this used
that kind of thing
and why
we i
if you
you are
that are
i are
the point is the pair xy
there is a joint distribution over x and you
which has the following conditionals
the position x the height is just uniform between zero and the height of the
case that this conditional distribution here
and then given the height
the conditional
distribution over is well we've got to be underneath the car
but otherwise the distribution is uniform these two conditional distributions very simple
so in principle
you could maybe imagine gibbs sampling from these distributions in
you take a position
and you
randomly drawn height
and then given height
you randomly drawn position
and then you randomly drawn height and in position and then any high
and like that you would wonder slowly around underneath the car
what is achieved
the question is exactly how we going to implement these updates
let's first see it on
you know metalcap so often we know that
probability distributions that we need to sample from the in the model that sounds like
like an easy problem but remember that we might just be updating one variable
as part of the system and conditional on everything else one variable often has been
you might all distribution
so this would just be one update of a markov chain
the update where we sample height is easy because we can evaluate the height of
the curve so we just or uniform number between there and the height
the update to the position is harder
because it's difficult to analytically workout
this lies underneath the curve is
what you can do for you mail system is sample
the line underneath the curve by rejection sampling
you sample from the bigger distribution
uniform distribution over bracket which you could find some sort of bisections that which is
guaranteed to think out outside the extent the curve
the sample from that and if you happen to stumble outside the region where you
just get sample
you are also able to shrink bracket which is the detail
and the sample again until you get a new point into the web projection something
to me from here to here on the curve
compare this to
based metropolis sampling gibson
trouble is something we had to take a step with so that we knew
how far we should propose moving it was nice but which here
we've automatically sort of considered the whole width of the distribution
it's something didn't have that we could also sample from this conditional distribution but we
had we would have to have analytically worked out that conditional distribution or constructed the
sample for
all we have to deal with evaluate the curve up to a constant
so this is again something where you can write to really generic routinely to
give me a function handle it evaluates you're
thank you for your probability up to constants and i'll just
question the question is how can we construct the rejection from will sample from this
bracket so it's important to understand
we i see them
that you have selected point thank you say
what you need to do is constructed bracket with the ends are above the curve
so you start off with some brackets around the point they it's not wide enough
certainly from here to here and you notice at the ends of your putative bracket
are underneath the cabin you could do that but just evaluating the cat at this
particular point
so then you just double the size
and then you evaluate the endpoints again and you keep doubling the size the bracket
it six outside that's one algorithm you can imagine many more sophisticated way the search
but is this thank you very much that just involves
evaluating the function at point
that doesn't work if the distributions multimodal of course a
here's an example of constructing the bracket where
we started with a brackets around that point which we slow down randomly just we
picked somewhere and we put them randomly around point and then this and the bracket
the left hand wasn't
above the curve and so we extended the length of the bracket
and it's not because it's the back again now it is so i stopped
so now i've constructed bracket which doesn't cover the whole region that we need something
that we want to sample from the gibbs sampling because we've ignored this region here
what's needed it turns out that
you can do this anyway
and it's a valid
this is the chain which isn't good to get some work is not able to
move over here
but it still is the stationary distribution environment and say
the introduction of a single height meant that we've just got a bunch of simple
rules that allow us to make decisions about moving around
without having to do any computation
there is that we're here
so width of the bracket but i had to pick before that i will just
do something exponentially grace and
that will be cheap so a
you could worry that i've now had to evaluate the function
at several places that could be costly
on the other hand in order to extend the length that were looking at this
is the linear cost so far bracket
it is sort of the typical length scale of functions was out and we have
a bracketed with the mass then in order to expand bracket out so that it
covers length l l over sigma when we compare that to the diffusion on top
and that was the square
thanks it if you get that size wrong in place are not going to matter
nearly as much as it does metropolis
this is a much more sort of robust algorithm for just routine news if you
don't want to
we too careful about setting up three parameters
when i noticed that when i run the practical on wednesday for if few if
you want to do it would probably encourage you to use the variant like something
because it was probably just be a lot easier to get working on anything else
is there
is one of the
we can go on so
here we see a very funny phenomenon this figure is again doesn't work but then
the next
on the next slides almost identical figures somehow starts to where can i checked that
all figures after this quite seems to be quite OK i don't understand what was
for this reason for the first sixteen slice of it's like wrong
sixteen is
the power of four that must have something to do with OK but so this
is just this is not a simple numerical illustration of fact
so we have
data distributed according to a uniform distribution so the independent components are uniformly distributed and
then we have here
mixed data
that has been widened so this is a scatter plot of the exterior and some
others and all this circles here denotes the unit sphere
and these the line here this is the idea of this line here is to
show that well now we have this w that we are trying to optimize and
w can take any value on the unit sphere
which in this case simply means that can you know
which means that we can the capabilities as far west as the function of these
of the angle of w
and we get this simple plot so ketosis
goes down and up and go up and down now point to note is that
since a uniform distribution has
negative kurtosis all these mixtures also have negative kurtosis and when maximizing the absolute value
of kurtosis we actually maximizing it here
on these two points
and how well it is not
not very obvious but well the point is that these two quantities to anglesey correspond
to the directions of the independent components that is when w is either pointing in
this direction
all in this direction
that is the directions of
given by this
square box
OK so
then this leads us to obey the basic ICA estimation procedure so first we have
the data x and we whiten the data well i did the whitened data by
by by z for some sort of summary
and now what we do is some kind of is in the best of the
basic case we can do kind of recursive estimation or iterative estimation of these i
mean i mean deflationary estimation and some people call it of the independent components so
let's be iteration come one then we take a random vector victor w
and then we use some kind of maximisation procedure for example in the simplest case
gradient procedure which is rather simple to derive we can we can rather easily compute
the gradient of kurtosis
so so we can maxmin maximize the case the
nongaussianity using some method under the constraint that the norm of w equals one
because for whitened data this constraints unit constant of unit norm equals the constraint of
unit makes
and so what we have competed one of those those components that we increment iteration
count by one and go back here we take another random vector and we do
just the same thing but now this time we constrain the new vector so that
is always
also going so those vectors that have been previously found because of these because the
mixing matrix a is orthogonal and and there is an optimum these W's will eventually
converge to the right to the columns of the mixing matrix
and so we do this in times square when we have an independent components and
dimensions so we
we assume here that number of the dimension of the data is equal to the
number of independent components
that's what we have been saying all the time for simplicity so we do this
and times and then gets the independent components it's basically
because there is there is there are many different variants of this basic method well
the first thing is that we don't need to like first compute one independent component
in another one and another one we can like it somehow maximize in parallel have
maximize nongaussianity is of of combinations given by many different w eyes and then keep
them you just thank you expect inspectors also
in some manner
OK so now you basically know how to to do i see a
you just need to compute the gradient
of kurtosis that's the main thing
and then you can do this
OK but that is certainly not the end of the story
this is really the basic way of estimating ICA also one one that is well
mathematical simple to analyse and therefore
it is easy to understand
it is
well this is it's not that this is something that is never used in practice
with the scale the methods that are really the same that similar to what i
just showed that i used and have been used with success but they are not
the optimal methods for many
for many situations well classical problem with kurtosis and any of these higher order cumulants
least be
OK so the column player can get the loss of at most p and the
row player can get lost spent most the
and the column player can always force lost about least p
so that's saying that p star is optimal for the row player
thank you star is optimal for the
max player for the column player
OK so
OK so so far i haven't said anything about boosting
but boosting like i said it turns out to be a game and what we're
going to see is that boosting its the very notion of boosting is very closely
connected to the minimax theorem so it's just intimately connected to game theory
so what we're going to do is we're going to set up a matrix game
and that matrix is the game that's being played
when an algorithm like adaboost is run
so the booster remember there are two players the boost the weak learners
so the booster will be identified with the row player of this game
the weak learner is identified with the column player
and now we can construct this matrix
so first of all
for most of this
part of the tutorial
i'm going to imagine that we can list all the possible weak classifiers
all of them so this is not just the weak classifiers which are actually returned
by the weak learning algorithm on a particular run of the algorithm this is the
space of all possible weak classifiers
so for using say c four point five
as our weak learning algorithm
this would be
the space of all possible decision trees all decision trees
this is a very very large set of
in general it will typically be in well not typically better will often be infinite
here i'm assuming that
it's finite
a finite but extremely large
OK so g one through g and is the space of all possible weak classifiers
and now we can describe the matrix which is the matrix game which is being
played by these two players
so the rose
will be identified with training examples
so there and training examples
in the i th row
is identified with the i th training example
the columns of this matrix are identified with these weak classifiers
so there an an weak classifiers in this entire space again and is gigantic number
gigantic but finite
so this matrix is huge
has one column for each week classifiers
the j th column corresponds to the j weak classifier
now we need to say
with the values of this matrix are
so these values are just something very simple and natural
so remember rose corresponds to an example
in column j corresponds to weak classifiers
so we'll just put a one for that entry of the matrix if example i
is correctly classified by the g weak classifiers
and we'll put is zero otherwise
so this is just a huge giant encoding
of which we classifiers in our space
are correct and which examples it's just specifying which exhibit which
weak classifiers are correct and which examples
when i claiming is that
the boosting process is actually playing this game
so before we get there
what happens if we take the minimax theorem
and we apply it to this particular game the minmax theorem applies to any matrix
any game so what happens if we applied to this game
well we get something which is very closely related to boosting
so let's go back to the weak learning assumption or the gamma weak learning assumption
which is the starting point for boosting
gamma weak learning assumption says that for every distribution over examples
there exists a weak classifiers
so that the accuracy that we classifiers at least have close gamma so in other
words if you choose an example of random according to p
the probability that you get an example that's correctly classified by gj is at least
the hapless gamma
that's what the weak learning assumption says it says the weak learning algorithm for any
distribution is able to find a weak classifier with that property
with accuracy at least hapless camera
so what does that mean in terms of this game
the fact that it's for all distribution gets replaced by millions were taking the men
over all distributions
over training examples are operated rows of this matrix
it's saying for any distribution there exists a g j
so if we take the max over all of the weak classifiers j
this probability
but in terms of this matrix that probability can just be written as pj with
this means expected value when i is chosen according to p
and which is the column j
OK so this is a max the loss that will be suffered by the role
players at least at least gamma
it turns out that taking the max over
rose is the same as taking the max over rho
distributions so this is equal to the the west
just because this thing is linear
and now we can apply the minimax theorem minmax theorem says minimax equals maximum
so saying that maximin is at least half plus gamma
but again this man over wrote distributions is the same as taking the men over
individual rows
so we get this the max over column distributions of the men over individual rows
of the loss
if you haven't seen it yet
so now want a
straightforward example
whereby we
a certain
dependent on x
i give you is given
is ten to fifteen
times x
so that
is a given
and this holds
between x equals zero
they tend to minus two meters
so it holds over the space of one centimetre
sort of potential changes linearly with this
what now is the electric fields
in that space
electric field to go back to my
description there
there is only one component xn direction
so the first derivative becomes minus
ten to the fifth
times x rules
and the other is zero
y zero
and these are
so you may say well book nice
mathematics but we don't see any physics
is more physical than you think
imagine that i have here played
which is charged
the positive charge
the play is at location x
eleven out here
say at location zero i call this place a
and i call this play be
this place is charged
going to do that
so i can put the electric field inside here
according to the
minus ten to the fifth
and it is in the direction of mining x rules so x roof
using this direction
electric field in the opposite direction
and it's the same everywhere
and that's very physical
we discuss that
when we discuss the electric field near
very large grains that the electric field inside was a constant remember
and the electric field inside
sigma divided by epsilon zero if sigma is the surface charge density on each of
these plates
and we argue that the electric field outside
the above zero
and that the electric field outside it was about to extremely physical there exactly what
you see here
electric field
minus ten first time six or the magnitude of the electric field here
the magnitude is ten
from either
well now is the potential difference well
v eight
minus b
nine b
this integral
going from a to b
one of the dot
so i go from here to here
i write down for DL i write down the acts of course
i call that the x direction
so i will write down the dot
and so this is
minus ten to fifteen
i'm integral in going from a to b
of x roof
look scary but it is trivial x rules is the unit vector in this direction
and vx is little vector x in this direction
so labels in the same direction
the cosine
the angle between the two is one
so i can forget about
vector i can forget about the dot
so this becomes
ten to fifteen
i was integral in going from a to b
of the x
that is trivial
that is minus ten to the fifth
times the location
i have to do the integral between a and b
so i get new x three
line is activated
and if this is ten to the minus two meters
we go from here
two years one centimetre i must multiply this by ten to the minus two
so i get this is minus one thousand volts
so a
thousand fold lower than b
that's what it means
that's something that's very physical
notice that if you go from left to right
that the potential grows linearly
this is lower than that
and if you in your head
like these parallel to the plane
each one of those planes will be people potential state
everywhere have the same potential
and gradually when you move it up
your potential
notice the electric field goes from plus to minus
the opposite direction
that's always the reason that's behind that
the minus sign
clearly i'm always breaking choice where i
two is my zero potential we discuss that last time you don't always have to
two is infinitely far zero
so i could choose
arbitrarily to be zero potential
this would then be full of thousands
so you then find that
the potential v
then simply tend to defeat
was something not very clear from lost from the last set of lectures have you
got any questions
everything clear
they still recall what's elements trick is and how cross validation works and all that
good who can tell me an example of a good kernel
garcia kernel
you can tell you that the one hand
OK can somebody telling example of something that is not the kernel
but it's symmetric
well a function it looks like the kind of but isn't
OK achieving new to let
what we're going to do today is to look at
essentially convex optimization for methods
for inference
that's basically what did yesterday's we started with a very simple estimators we just take
and they moved on to estimate which more or less smooth out the doctor
these are the parzen windows estimators
and then we saw very simple stochastic gradient descent optimisation procedure called the perceptron
which will give you a linear separators
and we analyse starting quite a bit of detail
it's very simple south me can find
what we're going to do today is
well look at support vector classification
and regression quantile regression of fiction the new trick so all sorts of
why is how you can do support vectors that's kind of standard fare
this stuff kind of spans the area from
nineteen ninety five
until about two thousand five the quantile regression will be about their novelty detection with
the abrupt
ninety nine or two thousand like what's new trick
the last lecture
we look at some
a slightly more cutting-edge stuff sequence annotation web page ranking path planning
and just in general optimisation
and how you go and implement some things
this one
the challenging
there should be reasonably easy going
that's it if you have questions at any time please let me know
i know this stuff i've written the slide
i want to teach you how it works so
if you don't interrupt me analysis and you know it
so i support vector
well what will do is will first look at just the standard SVM
and then the optimisation problem a few properties of that
and we compute what's called the dual optimisation problem
this thing is
it to my
this is
an example the query and yesterday we have two sets we want to separate them
what we
i want to do is we want to estimate the y given x thing in
well instead of just doing this we could try to find the function f of
x this task
so and already talked about that in the morning when he was talking about logistic
so anyway if you understood what nanda was talking about four
logistic regression
this will be a walk in the park is it's much easier
if it doesn't make sense to maybe after that people will also understand and
it's useful
anyway so
OK the neck and i can just fast-forward
let's say i got those states and i want to separate them
and any of those lines will do the trick
now the question is
who thinks the blue line is the base
who thinks the black line is the base
who thinks the red line is the best
given that a lot of people say
the the black line baseball why
why did you vote for the black then must have thought something
i mean i didn't write very well i mean actually to the
gone down here somewhere
and then they not going to ask you why you voted for the red one
so and
so that intuition to find a hyperplane that has the largest distance from both states
that's pretty much what we're going to pursue
and we'll see that this actually corresponds to the notion of scale
as in the simplest function the one of the largest separating function
the smoothest
linear function they all amount to the same thing and we'll see why this is
that's the one to rule them all
maximum separation from both sides
one you
what you could do it you could run a bunch of perceptrons
at the end of the day you just have perceptron solutions
and get fairly close to this
this might be actually computationally very efficient way of finding
people have actually explore that as much as they should
so how do we get this line
so that's
the picture is probably as old as support vectors are so
courtesy of an actual copy
when i was i think quite nostalgic value you see the point isn't so nice
anymore but anyway
so these are
a few points
and these are a bunch of squares and i want to separate the search from
well done OK
now how would i do this
well case i find some separating hyperplane
and if i want that both
six have equal distance from it well i can just make parallel transport of the
hyperplane to all the sites
and then just measure that this
everybody knows that i can describe a hyperplane
so it's normal equation in other words i denote the normal vector by w
written about ninety six by enough
and i think with some contributions from chris bishop's book about it really nice way
of playing with lots of certainly all the machine learning algorithms in to state the
i ninety six and i think it's got some updated stuff and i think this
new version coming out
so there is some great hours playing with these things you can look at how
these demos being done so
it can be very similar
two the demo i did with k means
we've got two clusters
and this is i data here so when someone what happens here
we can do
so what you're going to see is the red cross and the blue cluster
eight point instead of being allocated immediately to red or blue
he believes he belongs partially to write impartially blue so we're going to see that
visualizes the combination of red and blue in each of these guys and that's the
so you can see the collars changing the guys and then you can see the
senses of the gaussians and the covariance is moving so we see the collars changing
that e that when you see the sense the gaussians moving that's the m step
you can see that if i click on the right place
so his initial configuration of the mixture model is configured and can you see that
i can see really clear
the lights at the front somewhere
it's annoying because the blue circle where red circle that
and weights
i know
a real-time map
OK that's clear of so you got red component and the blue component here
then you know to responsibilities so initially because the blue rinse these guys o thing
i must belong to him and those guys think almost belong to him and actually
know really confident about it even
you know they're not close to any of senses the posterior says are extremely confident
about where they are but then we update the means and variances so that's the
first thing means and variances they move
this was a really bad initialisation just to show lots of steps and then the
the responsibility now the
confused they belong to and then using some iterations
so slowly they become clear about who belongs to what responsibility start going to the
correct things that we would have seen very quickly actually with the k means clustering
k means clustering via a lot faster this
this is fully probabilistic it's soft and extensions of this model
which have to reach process is sitting on top allow you to do infinite
components and decide on the number of components are using
with lots of other bayesian treatment of the problem so this is not bayesian because
we just using bayes rule to update something that we believe the stochastic model is
a sparse selection of ask
and then we assign some data sample given that
OK so i'm going to very quickly speed through my dimensionality reduction stuff
so you have to mention this quote
and then i'll mention the results meant so i love it so it's always a
must get to a certain age when you actually start bothering to read the papers
that you keep referencing four different methods
so tell nineteen thirty three is person first call these things principal components people credited
pierce but to my mind reading the two papers and this is the one i
preferred because it is much more in line with my image what principal components it
is also inspired by psychology because it comes i can't remember the name of the
guy who was responsible for factor analysis
you know just there's lord someone or another was is some really famous social scientists
yeah something first and the will of the people working on factor analysis around this
it was an important technique for you
people looking IQ and they developed these really interesting methods and hotelling was actually said
well mathematician and statistician who was talking to social scientists is what you want to
do that i think we should do it like this and he actually derives PCA
through factor analysis type idea that you've got a bunch of variables you observe and
he even has this is the function so this is a relation is a function
of some unobserved variables so this might be your IQ or whatever these factors are
then he says so this is called source of much confusion in future however to
the perspective case these ideas outside the in the computer uses of according to the
word factor in mathematics and we better call axis components of the complex depicted by
the test so he actually saying these are factors so is factor analysis in the
original derivation of what he's saying principal component analysis and actually really annoying me
the way the factors appear in the covariance function they do appear as factors in
some sense so you could have called fact aside almost think of these factors but
we start with the ten principal component analysis
because the he invented the message here so
he has a slightly different approach to how you fit in this model
and it's slightly different from what we would think in the modern context so these
prestigious honour
these are two important theorems
or anything that was something that
given a class of form
the ones on some
we can show that is and why
now completeness says that a class of four
that is unsatisfied
you want the understand the to show
don't need
i also like to mention briefly satisfied testing
so the satisfiability problem
quite interesting because it is the first
the saw NP complete
probably no
just says that
it has a polynomial time solution do it
i want to
the biggest questions computer science is
this equation
is the class
due to
people and
i think
this is this is is one
given that you and p
the existing
satisfiability so they should be like used
more than red round line
one of the
one the algorithm is a decision which
the decision to choose which you make
signed through two
propositional variables
and essentially is just the point
one set of the
so they can
so to learn from past mistakes
the next slide
but i just want to point you to this website
sat competition of this is a huge industry no
after you have
this competition successful
i have
huge collections benchmarked problems
and so on
most of the settlers
this group called p of
his partner
so i guess that
this dataset was not played
try to analyse the brain
the technique of this conflict analysis
here is one example of the technique
so if you can see source
quite surprising
they are often used as target
salford people the problems with
it is a set of
OK now i come to
representation of the form of
as i said can basically represents and we want
in the truth
this is all possible truth and come
it's expensive exponentially in terms of
so a
people are looking
for representation
and the reason why
we can represent because
in certain areas such more attractive
represents the transition as property
and they work
well first you want representation that is the smallest
it takes less time
the representation because graph
this is a form
the most useful
this is central point
everything here is linear and l is of fixed matrix i can bring it out
this is l
bring out on the
the expected value of
he transposed
l transferred to see that i just the usual parentheses
that's l e e transpose looks like a crossword puzzle
l prince
on saying as i can bring the only l transpose out of the expectation because
when i multiply these values by probabilities
l is fixed
now let's say
OK and what's this
that sigma
that sigma b
so this is
sigma b
it's are
you know if we can figure out what this is
we know what hell is now this is where i feel
like a bit of maths a typical bit of magic in these formulas is going
to happen now
i'm gonna
but in this awful expression for l
and see what i get
what i'm doing now is totally standard may be familiar to all of you but
i think about it take this last step
can i just say OK
i'm claiming that this is the right l to choose
well gauss
so it was sold
i was going to argue with again
OK so
there is no he he says that the right to take is saying is the
right see the take is is
sigma in
OK so can i
but that in here could you do that multiplication and you know what we're going
to get
make a little room
do it is a little long
OK here comes l
so i have
a transposing
inverse a
all inverse
times a transposing members that was that's the l finally
OK now comes the sigma
sigma others straight segments can be
time sigma
now comes any more room
four l transpose OK
this formula will finish before the borders
that was l
and what self transpose
sigma by the way of course is symmetric
sigma of course is symmetric
so when i transpose i don't have to worry about transposing sigma a of course
i do have to
and this combination is symmetric so i transposing that no no that's OK so now
i want to transpose this whole thing in the opposite order so i transpose that
just sigma inverse
suppose that a transpose that that symmetric so it doesn't change transposing inverse inverse and
what have i got
so this is following all the rules
and notice well there's the same inverse sigma identity in the middle there
and then there an a transposing the inverse a which i'll just put parentheses around
i call attention
and what do i have
i've got this inverse
times this thing
times inverse again so
so this is not all this and left me just with the
it's alright if i just
that's the answer what a beautiful answer
that the
the right choice of
the right choice of those are the right choice of the weighting matrix
a beautiful answer for the
variance in the
in the in the you have
and the beautiful answer is this
is the inverse is p
is our peak
that's the crucial matrix
in fact that's like the most important thing is output
so that the most important output is that
you had which we finally identified as
i think you had we finally identified as our matrix p
is that right
let's see
i didn't
yes sorry i didn't do this was wrong does
four to get four race
i met peter be
exactly this matrix that we're sorry crucial matrix for us he is
it is
transpose sigma b version
all inverse that's
that's the key
that's the beautiful matrix and the whole subject and
i can of saying
this is this is the inverse of our stiffness matrix those early lectures
we're about
this matrix right and its inverse
and now we're meeting
as the central output
that the inverse of the stiffness matrix
as the central output sigma you've that it's the variance of the
error in our estimated parameters
it's it's fantastic
well there is one more central
o point
you remember what was special about those matrices in
beginning of this
a course of lectures
they were tried diag
they were tried diagonal and that
and that came for the line of springs because
each frame is just connected to one brain below and one above
but springs here we're not connected to
springs ten
down or we wouldn't have had right diagonal matrices
all i want to say is that the most important word that's not on the
is try diag
it's that i have to qualify it
for the for those
first lectures it was
normal try diagonal matrices
we're going to have walked right
that's the central thing that makes the whole kalman filter process work
is that there is that the
he matrix in there
this matrix in the in the giant process
is blocked right diagonal that i cannot overemphasize that's the key
this is no i in no way to insurers
the community to come up first consistent vocabulary because well i can decide instead of
looking up if there is maybe location property of darius lives and property i can
just create a new property here that's OK that's
that's what happens in which is all the time if you look at the categorization
wikipedia we see that there were numerous categories created and still there that actually expressed
in the same thing
and the we the idea is that after a while
other users
so called gardeners come along and we try to re conciliator this kind of information
this works in an open environment that has enough users
it will not work if you try this out in a company are in a
small group of maybe ten people
if no dedicated gardener you cannot expect to begin to clean up itself without any
wikipedia can do that because they have potentially six billion users
and even if only a small
small small part of them dedicated themselves to cleaning up the wiki it still enough
to do it
if you're trying to use semantic wiki for your company are if new group are
smaller system
you need to assign someone to do this cleanup
they can have a lot of tools to help them to clean up so they
don't have to go manually for the weekend or this kind of stuff
but you can they can rise to in order to clean them up there a
lot of what's already written that can have this kind of towards the special pages
in the wiki that can help with cleaning up this kind of stuff so they
have a lot of help this still have to do it
look everyone becomes
shared by themselves but everybody who built ontology several stakeholders knows that you have at
one point two
conciliator because different opinions
so i think actually this is one of the hardest part in wrecking semantic wiki
but no way to technical means it so to social things happening
so we started to talk about that
and the collaborative ontology if in this case if it just hierarchy
for example this is the page about two trust
so what people people who attacked is being true to category to to there is
a description of human readable
about two just saying it uses the person that gives the cost of the tree
of similar events and they are in
this example two which inside the system
other things we can do is say OK tutors all belong to to category person
so this is the
in this case up subclass class of relation as we know it from rdfs
and this is the now knows that everyone was in the category twitter also indicated
the human readable interpretation is what's important to the community because that's where fit the
look up OK what do i mean if this term and how can i reuse
if they disagree with the can i going changes
when the can go on the discussion page every page on the wiki peter property
page and on instance page category page has discussion pages you can subscribe to get
informed if to get changed and other things so you can discuss
properties within the community and come up with a common vocabulary for this fact
category pages are also the page is spoken and that information like this
concert i'm talking here about actually refers is it's the same thing as the
term for tudor or whatever to keep that's where you can use external your eyes
as well
what i'd like to do later
i'm always kicking this things are what i tried to come up later the mu
is to come up with a vocabulary
where we can describe the group here we can describe the terms that we want
to use to describe the group which properties you want to use which categories want
to use and how to present them befriend the
we keep
well we can then do is just browse to begin to see the information is
see how it's connected this is basically are simplification of graph you and only you
can we get something much nicer than that area forget about show that later so
basically this means that incoming links so korean topics has body was found
whatever that means that was found polytechnic college is in the city was found and
was kind of information this is outgoing grand opening was on your dialect
wrong some dialects and so on
you see the examples actually recreate for isoleucine you see last year
which was in the percent
i'm sorry i didn't have time to update it
so when we have all this information to wikipedia
why should actually use of about entering the data i have just added into the
basic idea is that you can also query
the information you have inside
writing queries
looks very much like writing annotations basically if you want to know what the conferences
you just type in the same thing to do would have type four
taking a page is being conference
and then you can can actually that's OK
which pages conference
and then you can ask dedicated so in this case the answer can see a
little bit down here is saying OK to triple-a i two thousand seven was located
in vancouver to play at two thousand eight in chicago and so on to the
ottawa conference happened
it it consists of query atoms
once this category is basically asking for the time
hierarchies are
in this case take into account
you can put content conditions on the properties
which means for example located in tenerife
you can also
but these conditions with if it's if the red you actually be order you can
ask for anything bigger or smaller than a certain value so for all the people
that are bigger than one seventeen rec semantic web community for example are all papers
starting with the letter l
but like this
you can ask for
things that have value on certain property at all this
but in class
or you can print print statements saying that OK
as i said what change
in the war
this is
organizational forms part
so i think
the answer to this so one model that gives the densification is
is is is basically you seem like a community hierarchy
right so you assume that i know you have some
people here
but then joined into departments
OK here are two more
right and then these these people are again
all right i had this whole just
and that's going community hierarchy right and then if i assume
that the probability of the nodes linking
so let's call it f of h is like some constant
two minus h where h is the tree distance so this list of nodes that
distance one these distance to write it on many levels in the hierarchy to go
to meet
so basically so if you assume that people from the same
same communities tend to talk more than people from five communities that if you just
assume this this will give you network to densify
so the larger the community that the larger the discrete hierarchy the more people you
have the more the the the more edges just get so
to some power in this power depends on this constant
right so basically that's how hard it is to cross communities so if this is
this constant
on one spectrum of the core of of the
this constant we basically say that the there is no hierarchy everyone can talk to
everyone else and everyone but everyone else and you get a quadratic growth
on the other side
you can just get people just talk inside their own community and it's too hard
perform cross cross-community links
and so this type of process will give the sification where the where the exponent
will be a function of this but parameters
that's all
it interesting to see
but should should be in the web graph
we have
no i can tell you that you want
two which
the c
because of fast solution
so we should
now you two
exact solution it seems to
we use
one of the nation's
it was my identification and the changing their so
maybe i should have a slide
OK so i imagine this is your current social networking now you can't you can't
part so right that
that's your right you come to the party and you have someone who introduces you're
right now the idea is that
because small forest five so the idea is you start fire here this person the
men first met the bottom going into introduce you are right so with some probability
they will introduce you here and you will will become friends with this guy
and then this guy was going introduce you to other people right so
they introduced they
they did not introduce you to that person or you did not create a link
to that person but you created to this person
this is what happens right so basically you can say that
you add a new node based by
by starting
some kind of
why propagation of five propagation from one of the existing nodes and then you and
then you linked all the nodes that that so i think this goes into the
what was saying and if you do this
then the graphs you are getting
are so here is the number of nodes and the number of edges so we
get graphs that densify
and they also get the ship ever shrinking diameter
capture the
i don't know which
which is to say that
so in other words just put all formulas one she we have an optimal control
solutions which is of this form
where we can now we can write it as a path integral
we can take this to also to the pastoral where s is not the past
contribution plus and terms
and so
we can write this whole thing
as a free energy because j is minds local size so we just get exactly
free energy contribution where we you normally in free energy for some over exponent of
the energy
here we get this sum of the exponents of of an action and also divided
by new which is later of temperature
so if this is the partition so
the corresponding probability distribution
is this quantity
right so this is the
the normalizer
and the probability distribution is just the exponent which in the past that you can
think of conditional on the current position where you are
so you are here you can consider very many paths each of them has a
certain cost as
which takes into account the past contribution in the end cost and then you have
to then this is the probability of all these patterns
so far
to just put put together give a little it's while in
you know
and that
this is just
the probability will arise here once i
so this is an example using you'll see the right so
now we have such a
the last thing i want to talk about is how you can actually use this
to solve for efficiently some very intractable problem and this is the case of coordination
of of the number of agents so now we have not one of these processes
but we have an of them which are agents and they each have independent dynamics
which is given by f l five
and they have independent controls which are you alpha and have independent noise images kci
but their actions should be coordinated in the sense that they have to jointly solve
some task which is which is measured at a future time so for instance they
have to extinguish number of fires and they have to all run around two all
run to the model to the same fire extinguisher one of these fires would that
sort of cornish pasty that in time there is an equal distribution of agents over
over five years so we have an and cost which depends on the and position
of all the agents and we assume that these ages positions are restricted to these
and to any of these fire locations for each other agent
and position is in the case in an infinite cost for any of the other
and configuration
so then we get exactly the same formula
we get that
this partition sum is now some of the integral over all the
h positions the dynamics to go from x to y
factorizes as the forward diffusion of each of these agents to move from x alpha
two while find a completely independent and so you just get the product of these
of these independent agent dynamics and then the whole thing is penalized by an and
cost where all these and costs are coupled through his phi
and so
we can write this as a
since the end cost are restricted to these look discrete locations we can which are
fires we can restrict this we can try to some this integral is the sum
and we get here sort of energy expression where we put his role in the
in the exponent
and so we have we defined this PY
as this probability distributions and with before
then the optimal control
which is the gradient of j
which is the gradient of the log of site it becomes
this kind of an expectation that we have to compute so we have
to take the gradient of
we have to compute dynamics for each of the agents take the gradient with respect
to the initial position of that agency
and that gives us some formula
and that is OK we can do that but then we have to take the
expectation value with respect to this probability distribution which is really a probability distribution over
all the
and positions of all the agents and the entire
right so we now see
that is coordination task has become a graphical model inference task because if we think
if we think of this probability distribution
as a graphical model which is basically is
then taking to computing this expectation value is just depends on the single very also
like computing marginal
four y alpha
in in the high dimensional state state vector y going from one to two and
so which is the marginal
and for computation
the city of CO two to to to solve this is then you compute the
and the longer if for each agent to move to each target so each agent
is an agent alpha is the location x alpha where currently is compute for each
of the target location
what what the cost is in the absence
of the of the control
and of course is going to be but this factorized basically problem of all the
agents of you to do for each separately can still be difficult but you can
do a possible can be is made using monte carlo sampling or something maybe variational
and then once we have these terms
we have to do we have to do a graphical model inference in that couples
all these these other all these
to to basically put it in here
and then do this graph will inference in that case and you can do to
maybe exact the graphical model is small
you can use BP or mean field approximation
so in a simple
example or the state space is one-dimensional and we have an agent's
and we have no dynamics then this conditional distribution is just the gaussians
and in the end cost just as well i want all the part of the
fires to have the same number of agents
then we get this kind of a quadratic form
and then we can compute the optimal control and you can control is now given
by the expectation value of y
t t in this graphical model minus the current position
this thing is the is now the intractable quantity that we have to compute it
is the expected value
at the future for agent alpha in the context of what all the other people
are doing so to summary of all this uncertainty of all the list of all
the other i'd like to see it here is simulations
so here is the beginning of time
the end of time here is five fires
and here is a bunch of agents and they start to some locations use what
i've plotted here is the expected
target location of each of these agents as a function of time so these blue
agent reasons things initially he should go to to the target located zero
and then at some point something happens because the other agents are doing something and
he said well known that actually that i go to target minus two
and and then one she for so once you have york
s you expect expected target location
data jointly with the parameter theta
but what i'm interested in is now
i observe the actual sequence data
do i know about the parameters theta
what is my gaining knowledge what is my change in in ignorance what this might
change in
i don't know what is what what's my change in how much information do i
gained what's my how does my knowledge about say the change if i have seen
good so bayesians would use
this result
so by definition
if i
compute this i get the conditional
distribution of the data given the this is called the subject is called the posterior
the posterior density
of data given
the data
but the density
the answer of the bayesian is not i think this data is is is is
the most likely thing
the bayesian comes up with the density over theta
saying which they does are more likely to be responsible
and this incorporates two things the prior knowledge
which is this prior and this term is actually the likelihood because it's the probability
of the data given
the parameters of the bayesian takes the likelihood multiplies by the prior to this guy
is just the normalizer
it makes things normalized to one
so can turns out of this things comes out to be
just the normalizing integral right
because this
for the
tossing experiment this density
this parameter theta is between zero and one so if i integrated
from zero to one this whole thing should be one that means this normalizer
must then be the integral
right so this is the posterior
let's see
for the specific
coin tossing experiment
i just tried this out
did this for a couple of
for ten fifty and one hundred
so you see
this is the posterior
talk about yes so first of all this is the posterior so the bayesians if
they forced to do certain things they would say this is the answer right i
mean this is my knowledge about
about what i have after i've seen
three data points so this is my knowledge
before my knowledge was like that everything is equally probable i've seen three data points
so this is why i get
so to make right so still says you know it's more likely that the right
parameter came from here but it's fairly uncertain and i'm actually can say how uncertain
this is relative to my prior beliefs
now if you see more and more data points than
you see here becoming like this becoming like that and this was a hundred data
points is actually looks like the gaussians density
well you see it's
the true parameter was actually point seven so it seems like it's fairly
well centered about
o point seven
and fine so what you could try and do and say well if you really
forced give me an answer i want to know what your parameter is please tell
me what's what's the right OK so i can say is
you could even say
the map well this is the one that maximizes this posterior
so it's OK this but then what it doesn't sort of incorporate the shape right
because the maximum should not be the mean and so on
another popular thing is just the posterior mean and the posterior mean you take your
posterior and calculate the mean by doing an integral
so what you would get it's actually the funny thing is you don't get the
the probability that the bayes estimate
the probability of having one is not in one over n
but it's in one plus one over and plus to
and so it looks like bayesian estimate looks slightly different depends on the prior because
of prior knowledge that i had
and sort of this is always a useful thing for things to regularize i mean
in some cases if you say well look i mean i don't have many data
and in some cases some
maybe you don't have to call but you have something they can have multiple outputs
and some of the things have actually zeros do you really believe that that then
the estimate is zero if this thing doesn't even a short sequence of data you
thing doesn't really occur
so maybe you do you do you use this thing for making some other predictions
and is zero is really a very strong assumptions
no this doesn't occur the probability for this to happen is really zero
well if you have a prior belief at least
that's something non-zero and still there is the bayes method would give you
kind of something
even if it's a very small count that comes out and you have the yes
well it's going well there's this the question of what is and what is the
bayesian ignorance so you have to
even though is the theory about what's the proper way of saying i don't know
in bayesian terms it's not quite the flat prior which i can't explain at the
moment i mean
so there's is different ways of saying i don't know but
and you can also learn priors from the data that's a bit fishy sound a
bit fishy but priors speak have also parameters in which you can
so sort to adapt to the data which i will demonstrate in the moment the
least you should see that the bayesian answer may not be equal to the maximum
likelihood and but in one case it's the same
if you just stick to the
to the map the most
probable bayesian value
if PFA to is equal to a constant
like in this case i set it equal to one
so if this is the one then the posterior depends on theta only via the
so if i just look what is the most probable value for data
with the flat prior
it is the one that maximizes this it maximizes the likelihood
so the bayesian MAP estimation with the flat priors equal to maximum likelihood
so you see somehow this has got something those are sort of related but
right there are differences is if there are more
it basically can be proven
in the following way you basically convert the problem of cameron two approximation of the
sample into a classification problem
by adding one extra dimensions
and you can actually say you know if it's within gamma two
a positive example of it's not you know it's correctly classified as within government two
above and below
so we make two examples from each original example
the original weight vector actually solve that classification problem
with margin gamma two
so you apply the perceptron algorithm
and the perceptron algorithm
always adds in
the training examples into the weight vector
and we know by the
the perceptron convergence theorem that the number of updates makes is at most this number
and so the sum it will happen firstly
a discrete you know during presentations
in other words with integer values here
and furthermore the some of those will be correspond to the number of updates that
were made and that will be less than a task on gamma square
so that we know that by just running the perceptron algorithm for any weight vector
will find some
the weight vector in this class
that is a good approximation
of the of that original weight vector
so it's a very neat trick
and it actually gives you a bound for the size of the covered by
just counting the size of that set which you can do by sort of combinatorial
arguments basically putting
you know a certain number of letters in a certain number of pigeon holes in
this how many ways you can do that
so it's it's sort of standard combinatorial question and you can actually banned
this number
the log of this covering number by this quantity here k where k
is this value eight r-squared on gamma square
so it's i just sort of fell you know that's probably easier than just spouting
general talks about covering numbers
so i think it
the no because you can update more than once on the same example
but it will be the case that all the positive points always have plus something
and all the negative minus so you could reduce
but it will be
in some instructions
so it so there's a little bit more detail that you need to you know
why the normalized by that number here z and so on a little bit more
you basically that's the idea
OK so now we can put it all together with the statistical result once got
that idea of recovery in mind the same sort of outline of proof applies here
we are we've got the error zero
true error
and a large margin
and we move to the double sample trick same thing
we retain the large margin on the first half of those of the data
and we just now moved from having a true error that belong to a second-half
sample error one on two
and the factor two in here that's exactly the same as before
and now we
we're going to
do this by replacing this sort of
there exists over all of the functions by the functions in the in the cupboard
and as i suggested before
in the cover can be found which is within gamma on two of this function
may be messing us up here
and that will mean that it has a margin least gamma on two on this
half of the sample
and the misclassified points of margin less than gamma on two
and that's what that symbol means here
on their
the second half of the sample
and so this is again
you know
from the symmetrisation viewpoint a strange situation because you seem to have
lots of good margins everything with a good margin on this side and some things
with less margin on the side and again symmetrisation argument says that's shouldn't happen
and you get to the my sets on over two coming in
and setting that equal to delta
and converting into a bound on eps along
you arrive at this
expression here
we're now the logo of the covering numbers has replaced VC dimension expression that we
had in the previous
results OK
we would need to treat how to handle different gammas
but we can do that by applying their we can really apply structural risk minimisation
over the choice of gamma
and we can therefore make this bound to hold for
for any
the observed value of gamma
so now what does this tell us well we just need to work out what
this is but we've already done that
and so we can plug
that in
now in general
you need to you know for general function classes you need to have a method
of computing this i what i did was just for linear function classes or come
back to that in a minute which is what we need of course for support
vector machines
but in general
you would have to have the methods of computing this and there are n now
analogues of the VC dimension
but allow you to do this so well in the VC dimension we had sours
lemma bounding the growth function
and there is an equivalent of what's called the fat shattering dimension
and the result due to allow on how which bound the gamma growth function which
is what i want that log that covering numbers so that covering number is referred
so you have a more general framework that applies in
in you know two two general classes
that may not be linear function classes provided they have finite fat shattering dimension
which is
again a sort of
analogue of the VC dimension that takes into account the margin which the shattering takes
then all of this goes through
this result i should warn is is is pretty horrendous to the proof of this
is is
scary OK and the bound is very weak
OK so that's that that's the general case but in the case of SVM is
we can just plugin found that i i got from that explicit construction
and here is what we end up with
so fixing
during rotation
it takes o one time
so the total insert times
is lot
so once i figured out that this is the right information because we don't know
what we're using this information for you but
once i know that's the information showing you that it works in the insert delete
continue working order log time is easy
and i do believe actually a a little bit
this is similar
and then we go through and you find something
they have to go through the whole business of
swapping have
you know if it's an internal node you gets swamped with its successor predecessor
OK and so there's a bunch of other
things that have to be dealt with but it's all stuff where you can update
the information
using this thing is also essentially local changes when you're updating information
you can do essentially only on a path from the
from the root and most of the trees never
it dealt with
OK so i'll leave that to you folks to to work out also in the
book if you
OK that's good exercise
OK so for so any questions about the first three steps
four step is no operations
OK so
let's see if i could do that
so are also tries to find
the interval i
OK so i here's an internal
they get to court that's
in this rather writing recursively were write it as a sort of every recursive already
with the while loop
equally can write recursively the other one that we wrote we could have written as
well as well
and i had the recursive call
so here we are going to be to start x get through
the current later
that's the co
so let's just see how it works
let's search for the interval
the search for the interval
fourteen sixteen
fourteen sixteen in history
OK so let's see
so says exc starts at the root
and now while it's not nailed was not now because the route
and what is this doing
so we tell me what that code does
this is well so this doing give me
this is just saying something between i and into vex
was it seems x the interval stored index
OK what is this testing for
this is testing for
is question
or below so
and you just simple words simple words
test for overlaps
in particular test whether they
do were down
you don't have to tell don't do
test whether they so if i get to this point what i know about i
and two
and i
so in the backs
i don't
OK they don't overlap because
the high of one
is smaller than the lower the other
hi one is small and lonely other they don't overlap that way
they overlap the other way know because then because we're testing also whether
below the one is higher
it's bigger than the higher the other
so this thing is either like this or like this
right this is testing
not overlap
that makes it simpler so
what i'm searching for fourteen sixteen i checked here and i say do they overlap
and the answer is now can understand it without having to go through all that
arithmetic calculations now they don't overlap
if they did overlap i found what i want and what's going to happen
when drop out of the while loop and just return x
it's our turn something that overlaps that's my goal
so here says
they don't overlap
so then i say well if left of x is not now
they know got left child
and little by
it is less or equal to m of left backs
then we go
left so
what happens in this case if i'm searching for fourteen sixteen
is below by less frequent and left of x
and i'm searching
and is it
less than
m of
less than eighteen
so therefore what do i do
go left
make xpointer this guy
now i checked is it overlap
OK i take a look at the left guy
so is a
i compare it with
fourteen right
and is it
is it lower knows why go right
and now i discovered that i have an overlap here and its overlaps
returns then the fifteen eighteen
as an overlapping
OK if i were searching for
twelve fourteen
because the amount of energy that you can
then there is frightening four hundred and fifty
and my power supply here
that would deliver
three thousand balls that this is the
the voltage of the power supply is about thirty
eight hundred fold
and so now now the idea is that i'm going to charge the capacitor
always have to be very slow and careful that i don't make mistakes
because this is really
device that could be lethal if you
not careful
so i think we OK
the moment that i'm going to charge the capacitor the reading there will show you
the potential difference over these
and i will take a long time for that
to go up to three thousand people
so i think i'm ready to go
and i'm going to charge
so you see now that the potential difference over the plates
is very low is is zero
but if you wait just a few seconds you will see very slowly
that is charging up
and fifteen minutes from now
we will be very close to the
three thousand four mark
and then we will return to this so we leave it on
for now
it is charged
the idea of a photo
is that your charges the capacitor
and that to discharge
over the light source
so the idea being
that you have a capacitor
raise some of this
and then we charge the capacitor
for a certain amount of energy in there
and and then
we dump all the energy
in a bold so use the capacitor
we're going to charge it up
switch here
and here is the light bulb
and when we throw to switch
then all the energy will
going to light bulb is positive charge and negative charge
currently start to flow
and you will see
a flash of light
i have here
the capacitance of a thousand might prefer
so c
i'm going to put the potential difference over the past
one hundred
which then gives me
energy of one half the square
which is five due
in fact this is not just one capacity
these are twelve capacitors which i walked up in such a way
the twelve capacitors of eighty micro for each
combined capacity of one thousand
micro for
and so
i'm going to charge it up
and then
i'm going to
this charge the capacitor
for light
and then you will be able to see
some lights perhaps depending upon how much energy
we don't fool there
concentrate now on this slide built
a hundred
you should see here to use it
seven hundred volts now
and i'm not going to charge at the moment that i charge you will see
the voltage over the capacitor
and so it takes a while for it can charge up so goes down to
zero and then slowly come back two hundred may take five to ten seconds you
there we go
big only five or six
so now we have
on the vault so we have five drove stored in there
i'm going to discharge that now
over this light well
you already
one zero
a little bit of light
i can tell you disappointed
it's not very exciting
it's not really my style is
well what we can do
we can increase the voltage a little bit
we could go to two hundred and fifty four
in which case
since it goes with the square would have six times more energy than we have
many tools
let's see whether that's a little bit more exciting
so now i have to
back up the voltage to two hundred fifty falls now you see the power supply
four hundred fifty volts
getting there we don't have boy looking on but for two hundred fifty volts
and now i can charge up again will take a little longer
so you see the
voltage over the capacitor
four hundred seventy
two hundred
two fifty that we are
now we can see
where do we get a little bit more light so you go from five do
now to thirty two
one zero
now we're getting somewhere
now you really see how
a photo
now we all of course have
this drafted destructive instincts
and so you wonder
here's your thinking the same thing that i
so we try three hundred forty volts and see whether the
maybe explode
the idea for the supply condolences that let's go all the way
three hundred thirty seven vols OK
so that would mean that we have fifty joules roughly
is larger
so we have this model it's essentially the model we've seen before
plus noise analysis and novelty is that you know how to noise term which you
i assume
later on that is stochastic but for the moment we don't need
all right so in statistics typically the way people approaching are modelling the ways statistical
theory has gone for many many years is to assume that we have a fixed
number of variables that we have an enormous number of observations going to infinity
that's a classical set up the number of parameters number of variables p is a
fixed number of observations goes to infinity so we have this store matrix
and we developed a lot of asymptotics explaining what happens when the number of variables
goes to infinity
but right now you've seen already many examples were systems even in those setting on
to determine where n is about the same size as p of p
the number of columns of course is much greater than and that's where the field
is going at the moment
this is called high dimensionality in the field of statistics where the number of variables
greatly exceeds the number of
and this has a lot of applications compressed sensing can genomics we've seen
applications where we have few patients but thousands of genes
tens of thousands of genes that we need to
in chemometrics which have been involved with is in biomedical imaging and then after conversion
the number of times was this matrix is of this form and not super told
matrix is actually becoming the norm
in many applied fields
so we have
this problem we're now we have
to solve to try to recover x not only from fewer measurements but also no
easy and so we can assume at the moment that the noise may not be
stochastic but it's bound in l two that to speak like an engineer the noise
power is
OK so i'm going to have
my system that i wish to solve where
where y which is equal to EX sixteen houses underdetermined system but now we have
on top of that not only is this is this matrix is not invertible but
on top of these equations are not exactly reliable
so now
two kind of sort of this we can use the lasso which we discussed earlier
which we can relax the constraints and we're going to say well
right now i'm not going to enforce equality constraints what i'm going to do is
if i know the noise level
it is less than epsilon
one is
find that solution has minimum and one norman is consistent with the data and now
consistent with the data means that the reconstruction
needs to be within the noise
OK so that is in english among all objects consistent with the data
pick that was minimum and one or more consistency now means in this relaxed way
and that's essentially the procedure proposed by centers on signs in eighty three and by
in nineteen six
OK so
we would
reconstruction which is within the noise level to make sure that for example
that the true facts which i'm looking for is actually
in the physical sense
that is the basic constraints
all right so so what are the main results when we have possibly have an
adversarial noise we observe y equals ex-players e words easy is bounded as we've seen
and then we have this result that is
the to myself just among the turnstile
that said nothing goes wrong
OK so if we assume the same conditions is restricted isometry property that we need
even for less recovery
then when you solve this optimisation problem
then you guaranteed a good error and good air means here means what it means
that the distance between the reconstruction and the truth is the error that you would
get in the noiseless case
it's actually getting the largest component of x and so on plus term that now
so when you see we got i mean there's a numerical cost
plus it turned absolutely which is simply proportional to the past
to the nose
so this result is very reassuring it so that
well you have to feel question you asked me to invert matrix that is not
it looks completely down team because you know most of the singular values of a
zero but yet one excels in this relaxed and one problem
what is guaranteed is that you don't do that and the way you look how
well you do you get the accuracy you get if you had no no use
the term simply proportional to the notice that
and so
there's no blow up i mean things don't go to infinity or you know the
error bound is really well controlled
the recovery error is on the same order as the observation area and as the
noise level increases then the error
degrees nicely
and so simply proportional to the amount of noise that you
OK so that's
the reassuring because it said that is the knowledge level is small and the object
is sparse for example
and these terms disappear and you have an error which is just proportional to the
notion of
so why is this happening well i'm going to draw a picture
which is essentially the picture you've seen why is it that not only i can
invert non invertible matrices but i can do this in the presence of knows because
of kind of geometry again well let's look at
our exit sitting there are now i make measurements
but now i don't know that x is on this line because it's measurements have
been corrupted by
by notes
so what do i know about where x is
well if i had no knowledge that we need and we know that he would
leave on this line
but there is no is so what do i know
well i know that the one applies is a matrix
that a x minus the reconstruction
well by the triangular inequality
is less than a x minus one plus one minus VX
but because x is she's evil for the optimisation programme this is less than the
this is the talk about learning sum-product networks discriminatively
i'm rob gens this is joint work with pedro domingos university washington
sum-product networks are a new deep probabilistic architecture with tractable inference
you might not be familiar the SPN so give you a brief guarantor of a sample SPN
over some image pixels
so at the bottom we have heard
these distributions which model the pixels
and the products of this distributions would be considered image patch features
which which we have small and large
and then sums over those products would be considered mixture models over image patch features
and the products over those sums could be considered part decompositions
which you've one like this or one like this
and then finally are some node can be considered as pooling function
over party compositions
and this whole structure could be repeated the features that mixtures the
party compositions as many layers as you want
so as you can see SPNs are quite expressive despite the tractability
so in this talk i'm first going to motivate the use the sum-product networks
then i'm going to review how they work
then i'm gonna show you how to add feature functions to experience and training discriminatively
and finally I'll show some experiments where sum-product networks outperform support vector machines and deep models
and image classification benchmarks
but first i with some motivation
many is graphical models because they allow us to compactly represent the joint distribution over many variables
inference in graphical models is intractable
which often forces us to reduce the expressivity over model often with low treewidth
although many approximate inference schemes have been proposed role of difficulties
in contrast sum-product networks perform best exact inference
and high treewidth models
deep architectures use layers of hidden variables to increase the representational power
however when we add layers dependent variables graphical models this compound we already intractable inference problem
sum-product networks can be viewed as a model
the has full probabilistic semantics and tractable inference over many layers
up until now we've only seen generative training of sum-product networks however for many applications
we find that discriminative learning is performed better
this is our contribution
with conditional random fields we can use flexible feature functions
and yet the conditional partition function remains intractable
in this talk we're going to combine the advantages of SPN with those conditional models
namely flexible feature functions with exact inference over high treewidth
what is an SPN
let's define SPNs recursively
a univariate distributions is an SPN
you can pick your favorite discrete or continuous distribution
but for the sake of this example we'll defined Xs being a multinomial
one variables not that interesting so next definition
which is that
a product of SPNs over disjoint variables is also an SPN
so just part of another variable Y
which can be any distribution but
but in this example we also have a multinomial
now you might notice that the product two variables is just independent so last definition
which is that a weighted sum of the SPNs over the same variables is also an SPN
so now we just brought another distribution over these same two variables
and formed a weighted sum now now establishes dependencies
so these are some node sends out a hidden variable just like in a mixture model
so what we have now is sum-product networks are really directed acyclic graph
which univariate distributions at the leaves
and some some product nodes internal nodes
we can also use multivariate distributions at the least but you'd have to be able
to ensure that you can compute the partition functions and modes in closed form
and the beauty this definition is that it's recursive so we can build up layers and layers
more and more and more structured and yet are always remaining tractable
the key property spans
is that's all marginals are computable in linear time
it's easy to see why
because the partition function is the product node over disjoint sets of variables is just
the product of the partition functions the children
and the partition function some node over the same set of variables
this is the weighted sum of the partition functions its children
a marginal
it's just the partition function and nasty and
well you replace those degree distributions with seven over evidence variables
with delta functions
where the probability that's
so for example
if we are curious that the probability that x is zero in this model