calculator formula
for the plants transform of this guy if you already know the laplace transform of
now see this falls in that category because this is really needed the eighty times
one but i already know transform one so that if i can get a general
formula for this
i'll be able to get the formula for each of the eighty
as a consequence
so let's all look for the fourth postion that's really easy to see where my
doing calculations over here
so we got
so i want to calculate all plus from in the ATF six i'm going to
say that the integral from zero to infinity
of e the eighty
crimes f t
another is like out copy is high that's the function part of it because the
and then there's the
other parties part is called the kernel by the way but don't worry about that
however if you drop it in conversation
people also look at you in the
but also the idea
you will know the the kernel OK
i mean
well now what kind of formula could i be looking for
clearly i could only be looking for formula which expresses it in terms of
polar plus transform of f fifteen
but let's calculated see what we get
what would you do that they can make well obviously with thing to do is
combine the two exponentials
so that's going to be the integral from zero to infinity that t
now i'd like to put it
to combine the exponentials in such a way that has that still the same form
so i'm going to begin with a negative sign
and then see what the rest of it has to be
what is it going to be well
why is st
and plus eighty but i can make that minus a here and it will come
out right
so it's my necessity
plus eighty there are the two parts
those two factors
you take
so what's that
that's full force trans four
if this is the a weren't there this would be the old class transform of
what is it with the a there
it's full plos transform of f of t except
that instead of the variable as has been replaced by the variable x minus a
the second i just that
well you digest well on radio
because that's the answer
and the way this is most often used i had to qualify for the value
so if
if f of s
it's good for as positive of the way would be for example if i use
the function one here
finish that off
then after this might say
will be
this will be good when s is bigger than a
why is that well because
this is
this is true if
as my a positive
that's the condition
that's when this little plus transform is good but that simply says that should be
bigger than that
this is this does look pretty let me try to make a little prettier
so this is assuming
after this
is for greater than zero
now this is called something
this is called the well of
on the left side you multiply by an exponential
on the right
translate to shift the argument over by a so this is called
the exponential
what we called the formula
the thing before we talked about operators we call that the exponential shift rule
well the exponential shift law
but in fact
this is it in a way it disguised form of the same law
engineers who typically do
although work using plus transform and use operators of this is the form of the
exponential shift law that they would no
of what you can do with one you can do with the other you can
now use both
so what's the answer to each of the eighty
the answer is
i'm supposed to do
e the eighty times one
o plus transform one is one over s
and therefore what i do is
multiplied by each of the eighty
i change this to us
minus a
so that's the answer
but he will still we know well how about
size and cosine
well the way science and cosine is by making the observation that this formula
it also works with a is a complex number
so you can use
a complex number for e to the a one
BRI times t
o plus transform into the a plus b i times t is one over
mine is a plus b i
and again it will be for us because the
so let's calculate the past transform let's say
well i got to cover up something OK so
that's all plus transport
remember that
so let's calculate the laplace transform let's say sign
of eighty and cosine eighty what do you get for that
i just for a little variety we could do it by using that formula and
taking its real and imaginary parts of i'm going to
since some of you had so much difficulty
o with the
backwards oiler formula
is a good case where you could use it
but you want to calculate the plus transform cosine eighty
i'm going to write that using the back
i want to calculate using complex exponentials at the do it is by
they would be the most relevant search terms are the most relevant
bits of information for the radiologists also so this was our assumption so in the
the end we came up with these ranked lists of what we call are most
in terms of anatomy radiology and diseases for the limitations and we want to discuss
it with discussed with them to get their feedback
so we have these lists and we made all appointments around
all conditions are quite surprised actually
with our own achievement because we show our definitions our lists
so they got excited there were a lot of you i mean these terms are
generated you can mix them with these relations are related to each other things and
you can look here this resource and resource so suddenly they have lots of ideas
so the only they understood what we were suddenly we understood where they were so
we have the basis for our communication which we figured that was quite helpful
so for example one of the conditions that apparently the arteries are kind of light
spatial coordinates in our bodies so so they are able to keep track of our
of medical images based on the are trees like location where they are in the
image in the body so all this kind of information came out today so these
lists during the appointment which we really didn't have in the beginning
and this work is that has been already had with the results and these were
also presented in international conferences that was getting something about this query division technique
and work is still going on on this topic
next we came into the ontology identification
module or this up
such step let's take
well to to be a lot more complicated than we anybody in in the beginning
because of that information is always about three
perspective so we are kind of like you that the ontology
pre-defined for more or less fine for me because
four one for anatomy for idiology one for diseases but we still have to
actually says if these ontologies are appropriate for our purposes and if they are big
enough or if they are not so we had like certain criteria
the representation language to be OWL is it was pretty fine
it had to be comprehensive or we wanted them to be comprehensive because we didn't
want to make a mess important formation
and it is not domain experts we really could not also all there was no
way for us to know if these ontologies are really
good so we want we want by their popularity we look that they are well
known how many projects are using them
who is using them already well-documented so these are all the criteria that we also
even though the ontologies are determined we still look along this criteria two
to see
and i have the semantic formalism also to be the description logics so in the
end we ended up with these three ontologies
the list is not complete then might be others but currently we use the foundational
model of anatomy
four anatomical knowledge reflect the radiology lexicographer information about radiology and the NCI
cancer thesaurus for
the specific form use case
there's also be also drain these ontologies are available in two hundred nine
network portal which is quite good in the ontology portal for life science ontology if
you ever need it
to do any work there
and next i'm going to come to the ontology and alignment but really not going
to go too much into the details because this is very much
work in progress
but as i mentioned at some point now that we find these ontologies they need
to to
put together in a certain way
so that we can obtain the pieces of the puzzle
we can obtain the whole picture we are dealing with different types of
knowledge from different resources
so we need to integrate knowledge these different types of knowledge
in one picture and we need to the ontology aligned we into this problem is
ontology alignment under semantic integration task and we understand ontology alignment
the identification of it calling really cool and relationships between different types of ontology
that are relevant for image semantics
there are many approaches have about
people do that and most of them while some of them
two on me
on the schema level
they only managed ontologies some people not only the instances
some go with graph matching algorithms some go with NLP techniques most of them
use all of them together to combine their purchasing two rules seem to be the
most effective ones
and in theme and we also want to adopt a hybrid approach so we want
to make the best of all
of all the approach is possible available
maybe one additional thing that we want to
what we want to study further we want to add on top of it is
that we view ontology alignment also is an or the integration process also has contracted
process with the
user or with the radio radiologists for that matter like
the radiologist can
told to medical or if you like and confirm or negate and rejects
if b
proposed cooling speed or semantic relatedness
is good or not
so my life tells me that we're coming to me
final remark
let's we talked about so far
just that or we found that ontology engineering in the medical domain is
thanks for coming back but no one would come back
OK i didn't know what i had my first planned may not have shown but
i like what i was going to say
but i have no idea is for the second time
however fortunately during the coffee break
people might suggest and ask questions
and some issues raised so one thing i would like to say is
you know all of you when you work on pattern analysis in many different kinds
of work on pattern analysis is i've learned from this meeting
and all of you face the issue
in each case of weather pattern is is significant
or not whether experience or israel
this is a fundamental question which in every case you have to
you have to decide if you have to have an answer to that
and what i'm saying is this is a very fundamental question is so fundamental
the light discusses it
in his discourse on metaphysics discourse on metaphysics and sixteen eighty six
and it so fundamental that herman while in two books on philosophy while by the
way could you mention here with the dirac and in all these great physicist he
was besides being a wonderful mathematician he has two books on physics
two wonderful book from physics one called
round site not a on
on on on relativity theory
and another one on i think it was theory of groups and quantum mechanics
and so he is a pure mathematician who is respected by physicists the notion of
gauge invariance
is originally found in
in in work and while for example
and so he's he's a remarkable mathematicians so
so i'm not disagreeing with what you people are doing on the country and saying
this is a very fundamental questions
in fact it's so fundamental that the
lieberman violin from involves the fundamental question in way
in philosophy of science
so it's very basic issues
so you should feel good this problem that you face is is is is is
important problems
so i can not too
pre-season now i can not to bury about the price where
so that
the next question is
somebody came up to me and said
my last
but everything that you said isn't it come of complexity
i think i should answer that question so he asked me to talk about a
little bit about the history of this field
some of you may have heard of all of this under the name kolmogorov complexity
and you may notice that i was very careful not to use that name
i prefer to call this algorithmic information content or program size complexity
maybe i should give my version of the history of a little bit
but of course you know that everyone will have their own version
and in fact if you look at my book on metamap
one of the things i talk about is the controversy between newton and leibniz over
who invented the calculus
and this is a horrible thing
a war between philosophers title of
english folk and the object
i think it's better to avoid you know fighting over these things but since i
was asked someone was nice enough to ask me to talk a little bit about
the history of this
let me talk a little bit about the history of
this field i've back to alignment and fifty six but the modern version of these
really goes back to nineteen sixty
and the three main aims are raymond solomonoff who still alive
and there is an american interested in artificial intelligence and he wrote
a big paper or in two parts in
in a journal that i can recall the name
that this moment but anyway
his main interest was artificial intelligence
and he's still alive by the way
yes on period enormously long hair
and looks like a very interesting character
then there he was probably the first person to
talk about looking at the size of computer programs
and his main intention was induction he wanted machine learning he wanted artificial intelligence
and he was saying that are good way
a good approach would be you know this is the smallest program is the best
basically what he said so if you have to predict the future interested prediction
i'm interested in is there a theory for what we have observed up to now
cannot be comprehended
can be compressed
but but someone of was interested in predicting the future
so in his view a theory and mathematical theory of scientific theory would be a
computer program
which produces output first what you already saw and then it continues producing output and
that would be future observations
and he would say pick the
theory that is the simplest occam's razor
which would mean take the smallest computer
and in principle this would be a very good way
to do artificial intelligence except you can find the smallest computer program
you know but but but i think it's a very beautiful paper
of of solomonoff of now solomonoff didn't come up with the idea of a random
as being one that is unpredictable or incomprehensible
but the other two of us who
sort of a more independently i think i know in my case it was independent
came up with these ideas were basically interested in defining the notion of lot of
structure or lack of patterns
and the two of us were me and andrey kolmogorov who at that time was
i would suggest me what kind of magic which suggests me to break this network
into such hierarchical clustering in one intuition is that
these edges so what i want to to find something called
edge betweenness
when the idea that web when the betweenness of the edges the number of shortest
path that's
passing through the edge right so for example
if you and then once for every edge a calculate this importance or the amount
of flow
goes through it then i will be deleting these edges in the decreasing order of
their between school so to be more precise for example this edges between this forty
nine i because there are seven
nodes in this
this set the side of the network called have shortest path to seven nodes in
this next part of the network aldershot the spats have to go over the search
so forty nine short spats go over the search
and similarly this matches between the thirty three because the first three edges he three
notes here and eleven notes here and any shortest path from anyone here to anyone
in the rest of the network just across the search
so this is sort of the this one this one this one that one this
is sort of the edges that have the second highest betweenness and then this guy
here we can be left because from here
there is
either the from here to here there is a
this should be eleven nodes
the best through
eleven from here to any other node the shortest path first to pass here so
i have eleven
so he this is how this clustering would operate right first remove the largest the
largest edge and i'm getting the two clusters that i then i would go to
move the second highest betweenness and just now sort of getting this four clusters and
then this would be the right so the idea is that somehow
get an ordering over edges and then i'll keep removing them and the connected components
i get corresponds to customers
so just
here it is again the karate club that we see
today for the first time and this is the this is the clustering can get
it right or this is the dendrogram i'm getting great so when i when i
basically what i'm doing here and here
going bottom up and i'm heading i connect just whenever the than in order of
increasing between us
and then when i want to cluster i just decide on a particular court or
a particular speaking this and so if i got here then i get division of
these nodes versus those nodes and if i can't here then i for brigade division
of these nodes sort of the nodes versus this too
and here again this one
OK so that's one way
this is just a picture of the community the communities or clusters you find in
collaboration between physicists where every sort of every group here is
currently the different color and you can sort of see that it finds this then
groups then have you no one mentioned and is another dance group that has sort
of another edge and so on
OK so this is what the method finds
so what i want to create
show you now is how to compute the edge between the school
so the idea is you given we start with the network
we fix an old will ask how many short spats
from this node a flow
o every of these edges
the way we do this is to take a and sort of
order the nodes in sort of a breath first search breath first search fashion right
so these are all the all the nodes at distance one from a distance to
from a three from a fall from that and then when i'm doing his breath
first search i can just for every node i can count how many shorter spats
are that it is not right to where i can get it through this better
two final for two g there's just one shortest path to j there are three
like this one this one and that i think this is very easy all i
do is
i started you know he i started zero here
i have what counts one here and then we never go up i was i
just some of the number of shortest paths to my to my parents
and there are two things going on here three is two plus one nineteen sixties
three so i do is just sort of one breath first search
so this is the first step of the algorithm
and then once i had this
numbers these accounts associated nodes all i do now i'm sort of doing like another
now unlike preceding bottom up from the d
i read the idea is that
the amount of
sort of the county getting the node is one plus the sum over the parent
and then like splitting
discount based on the number of shortest paths that came to my parents so here
i have one last fifty fifty fifty
and then in this case i got so i got one short this sort of
i got one point five to be node in half because of the search so
now i have one half the they need to split
in the proportions of two n one so i give have here and i give
a one here
but now what disturbs me is that there is one short standard goes this way
what i mean this is basically
because there are
there are
cleveland show spence i sort of called inflection
so the idea is this gets one half because there's shortest go this way and
this gets one because the one shortest path and the other from the space here
but two shorter spans goal this guy and one gets over here so that's why
this is the ratio then i'm sort of i can just like world cup
the tree
and split discounts were always some sort of
taking the sum
taking one class whatever i have on my on my chin the edges what weight
i have on the edges of my children
and they stated that based on the
in the proportion
to my to my parents
and this way
i find the bitterness of the edges from a particular node now i produced for
every node
and i get between the scores of all the edges
and then i just go and remove the edges in the
difficult for biological molecules to be totally flat for an extended period and the helix
in fact something
that is frequently resorted to witness the alpha helix in the the in the protein
so these are turned around it turns out that each of these constitutes a base
and each of these base pairs is in fact
three point four angstroms
if a is three point four angstroms
so you have ten of the DNA helix advances three point four
thirty four angstroms every
every ten ten turns
and ten turns is roughly are i'm sorry ten base pairs is roughly one turn
of the alpha helix if you go up here count of ten we should start
again the same orientation another ten is another term another ten is another term
in fact i'm just recalling that when i was one city eighteen seven one
nineteen sixty five and there was a physics professor who became a biologist always talked
these double helix is a double helix is any always talked about
the measurements of different DNA molecules that you may know
the term angstrom is
named after
a danish person named angstroms
that's why got its name
so whatever this professor whom i never corrected god forbid ever talk about something that
was ten angstroms long
he called these ten
and struck
now as you know
when you go into latin from singular to plural it's
o to right
so he pretend this was the latin word
what's what's a good word
sorry what's good what's common latin where we use
millennium millennium millennia
so he went from amsterdam thanks
and went on for a whole year i never said anything
but i know better okay anyhow
here you see the genius of watson and crick
and by the way thanks to mister dane as i said another roman soldiers here
we see
OK so
here is the genius of their discovery
and the elegance of it is not how complicated it is the elegance of it
is how simple it is
because information we see is encoded into strands the information is redundant
because we can if we know the sequence of one strand
we can obviously predict
the sequence and the other strand because it's a complementary sequence if we always we
realized that a is opposite TNG is opposite c
we can now directly the sequence in one strand which may be a c t
in the other strand
moving in the other antiparallel direction
the the
the sequence is like this
i don't need to know the sequence of the other strand i can be predicted
by using these rules is called rules of complementary sequence structure and that in turn
obviously has important implications if if we look at the three-dimensional structure this is more
of what's called the space filling models
this is the way my the x-ray crystallography would actually depicted we talked about space
filling models models before
one of the things we appreciate
it is the fact
the phosphate
are on the outside
and these spaces are in the inside because these spaces have are able also to
start with one another
the hydrophobic interactions importantly the basis are protected the face where they interact is protected
from the outside world
what do i mean by that well let's go back to this figure right here
you see the interaction faces between a and t
four CNG then on the outside of the helix
there are hidden in the middle
and that's important because it means that these interactions between a and c and g
and you can see it up here as well
biochemical chemically protected from any accidents it might happen in the outside their sheltered from
that and that's important because the information content in DNA must be held very stable
very constant if it isn't then we have real trouble like cancer and therefore the
whenever cell divides in copies its DNA it's three billion base pairs of DNA whenever
that happens the number of mistakes that are made is only three or four five
three billion
a stunning something the low rate and this DNA consider on i told you about
neanderthal DNA consider around four thirty thousand years and it's bile is chemically relatively stable
in part testimonial to the fact that this base pair in the face where the
two bases interact across one another this is shielded from
the outside world because it's tucked into the middle
this these interaction faces here this is the inside of the helix here the phosphate
groups of sugar phosphate groups are on the outside
in fact when watson and crick were
we're struggling with the structure double helix they were in the horse racing with a
man named linus pauling
who was really the inventor the discover the hydrogen bond pretty much
who actually got two nobel prizes in his lifetime
who ended his life believing that if you took kind of vitamin c
grams with every day never get sick
i don't know what he died of the probably like doctor atkins he probably died
an illness he was trying to ward off
or it might have died of kidney failure for all the
vitamin c was putting in this way the analysis
i digress
but the fact is
the fact is that pauling was thought that the that in fact the con was
constituted of triple helix with three strands
and the bases were facing outward
well of course now we can see snicker now we can laugh but at the
time nobody in any idea
now we realize it's only a double helix on the basis of facing inward and
of course because i
appalling worked with their preconceptions he was never able to figure out what's actually going
on even though i watson crick thought that he had the answer and was about
to scoop
implicit in what i just said is the notion
that the structure of DNA which we'll talk about later
allows it to be copied by e now
referring in passing and we'll get this in greater detail later the whole process of
because if we have genetic material
and we've created a certain sequence we we must be able to make more copies
of it
keep in mind that each one of us as i mentioned use some lectures ago
we start out with the fertilized egg with one human genome
and through our lifetimes we produce how many cells in your remember
i did mention it right
is there one
nevertheless story of sodium moreover the lord says if there's one soul
OK maybe we should be playing the odds a little bit the algorithm should not
be saying i'm going to assume that i'm in the worst case and and learn
to make sure that worst case gets covered
you know it it should be able to
well i've seen lots of states before i'm just going to take a gamble and
say the state is probably like some of these other states looks like it smells
all right so
i think that's the main thing i wanted to bring up with the song and
also more about that means as i go
so this leads i think very naturally to a bayesian perspective for two reasons one
is because it seems to be the natural solution to this kind of problem and
the other one is if you look at the talks from today
right it was like one thing after another about these bayesian models for nonparametric bayes
so there's really no way i could give my talk today without having to be
the point just it just seem natural so
so yes so obviously this what you have to go to a nonparametric or more
generally to the bayesian perspective and so what does that mean in reinforcement learning settings
so what are we what are priors over what we going to do with that
so what we're going to do
start off with the prior over possible models so if we
from the this this is a model based reinforcement learning perspective the thing we're trying
to learn thing which i get out of our data is the description of the
dynamics what's going to happen if i choose this action in the state so of
the space of all possible transition functions we're not gonna lay down some kind of
prior that says which ones are likely which kind of transition functions you expect and
which one should we do not expect and which ones are impossible
so we start off with a prior then as we actually go wandering around in
the world we can update that and and and say well i thought i might
have been in the kind of world where i could fly
it turns out not to be so side pushed the probability that down and put
the probability other things up to compensate and basically just keep poster updated with respect
to the actual experience in the world
and now that we're doing that now we have the notion of posterior we can
talk about more less likely models instead of just this models possible this bottles impossible
we can say this is possible but new right i really have to put much
energy into because it's very unlikely so i will that's a good thing but how
do we actually use that idea to do exploration how we actually act in the
world given that we've got a posterior over models
so there's this this is very nice notion which has been very seductive to many
people in the field i got drawn into this for a long time of
bayes optimal exploration like i want to solve the exploration exploitation problem with a second
i can set this mathematically and solve optimally how do we know
it would be better than that
so so what is that what does that mean so let me step through an
example of how that actually works which would be perfect models we can plan in
the space of posteriors right so what does that mean we have we have the
current posterior in with the world that we the space world that we think we
might be in and we know what actions we can try and for each of
those worlds we can imagine what should happen
and we can know how likely that would be because we have a distribution over
the world
and we can see how that would change the posterior
so we had to post here if i was to go right how much how
my my post your change
so i can think about that even without doing that i could just do it
all in my head because of the bayesian
with infinite computational resources can choose actions that truly marked so so then what so
we can use actually project this out a large number steps and say OK well
eventually you know there is some probability all died some point but let me just
out search out to the horizon and say
of all the things i could do which one is going to lead me to
the highest expected reward where the expectation is taken over not only the probabilities in
the model right so what's the probability that if this is the world and actually
in this action will be successful but also the probability distribution of models and how
that will evolve over time
so the thing is so beautiful about this is there's no longer any artificial distinction
between exploring and exploiting
or learning and acting really is it's all just one lovely solution to one the
one problem trying to sell which is maximizing rewards so
that's very very nice the last bullet well we can ignore that
now i mean it's important it is it is hideously intractable to actually do this
acceptance is some special cases like bandit problems where you have a set of actions
and they don't change of state but they have their own payoffs and they are
all independent of each other that one turned out to be solved and it's very
pretty or really short horizons like i'm going to live three steps OK what's going
to build the big tree it's going to be very complicated but it's only three
steps so it's not so bad
and here's one with just two steps so so let me see if i can
set this up
if we had three nodes
bayesian networks
we can have the same types of rocks
and these two types of graphs
they beheaded one way
if you observe
then this should become independent
and this should become usual
if you conditions that
observation conditions
follow can if you conditions
on c
so basically
a b
this is a e
it's all here
independent of b
you can see
eight is independent of the sea
this geographical conditional independence statements hold
but in this graph
these conditions state the art
instead whole using this condition the
eight is in the field
because if you want to to see you need to have
that knowledge of all these will tell you something about
this is a good point in this
related to what
we are going to
to see in
the well
in fact there is no
one to one relationship between
conditional independence
a type of the graph
we'll see later that there are clusters
intersection in this class
what if you want see
in australia this true
it doesn't mean that two graphs
i proof
the factories the factorizations
in fact
there is no one to one correspondence between factorizations
and what was so there is a one-to-one correspondence between
factorizations here conditional independence
well actually we have factor
on a c
and there's the fact that you're on the
it the fact that on a CD in the fact that the
the reason why these things are things
but he will see the
we cannot separate into two fact
in gen
in general this the functionality via this p of
c given a b and c
you can not assume that
you'll see that they
and you see
let's say that in general
this is just a function the divided the function to work
on the other hand
one these two graphs here
you can see that this is in fact
some function one
of the sea
and some function two
of the
we're function one of sea
can be for example you're a fancy times you've see
the function to be can be p of the
and these here likewise you have some
u one of the sea
five j two or c b
where g one can be p of a
p of the given name
the future can be you know you can see
and of course this corresponds the initial offensive can check has
i will see these things become
more interesting when you combine
these in
in large graphs
during side b
and you for the clear difference
it should just get make out of course there are the other
which is the graphs
o denote
it's not very interesting
and there is the graph the nodes
the graph has no error is is that is all the
these are the five possible graph but these guys are not very interesting because this
all the conditional independence statements hold
in this case no conditions in the first
so have to study much
so we said in this case the
OK so that's why i mentioned my
in the beginning
because the p
how are you
so technically
b that will be
the network
that the graph so
but there really exists
there will exist to given or
such that
are if you take any two nodes
you need to know
and you fall
the pair
the old
o two the
where you start has a small and
you know hundreds of millions of data points like you know every time somebody clicks
on an add-on
you know microsoft being
you know it goes into probabilistic model somewhere
then does inference there not using bayesian nonparametric methods for that
they want something really fast that they can paralyze and running the online streaming manner
this is harder to do that with this information with all about this a minute
but i remind me if i don't
just as a reminder
there are two
families that have occupied a lot of interest in adding machine learning and statistics community
and i'm going to just basically review will little bit
and then i will talk a little bit about some
the interesting thing is that one can do
within nonparametric framework and then come back to
some of the
ups and downs of the framework is well towards the
OK so here are some basic building blocks for a lot of bayesian nonparametrics
one of them is the guassian process
and this defines a distribution over functions
so this is a sample from
guassian process it's a draw from a function
and guess process is really
but most importantly we can think of it as an infinite dimensional gaussians distribution so
just like the multivariate gaussians it has the mean and covariance but now it's a
mean function
and the covariance function that takes two arguments
a lot of models we have unknown functions
and we can plug in downstream processes in those places and then we can worry
about whether
that makes sense or not as
a distribution over functions
the other
processes and study law in bayesian nonparametrics is dirichlet process this defines a distribution on
distributions are measure measures
so think of of it as a function this nonnegative
and it integrates to one
and again just it just like the guassian process is infinite dimensional analog of finite
dimensional which is the dirichlet distribution
so we see g
it is a random probability measure
is drawn from a dirichlet process
with base measure or monumental mean
g zero
and then concentration parameter alpha
which controls the
so dispersion around the mean
and so
these are probability distributions over infinite dimensional quantities in this case functions in this case
so i
with permission
i borrowed a few slides from peter in are
and this is a nice like to motivate why people are interested in things like
galaxy and processes and actually processes
which is this notion of coverage of priors
so imagine
you have a space of
all possible objects that you want to put probability distributions over
so for example
this could be
the space of all measures
well now
you know it's drawn the triangle because you know you can think of it as
measures on you know three
probability distributions over
three possible events OK
but i think of it as more
and dimensional
tropical like
OK so
measures are measures or measures on on functions this is a really big space OK
this thing in great
usually when we define the class of models in the classical parametric world
we restrict ourselves
to some subspace of this
OK so for example this could be
the trial here could be all functions
this could be
polynomials up to order two
all right
and of course
polynomials of order two
don't have good coverage in the space of functions
right because
you know there good modelling polynomials of order two
for any function that i think in some suitable class of functions
suitably large cluster functions is not the case
that there is a polynomial of order two this arbitrarily close to it
i'm not spreading probability mass over this whole space in nicest way of course i
can do it turns out
for reasons that are
a little beyond my mathematical abilities that
you know i can put a distribution on the space of all functions as way
too bigger space
but you can put it
distributions on
very very large subspaces of those things
like you know near all
continuous functions let's
so what we want is we want our prior to have good coverage
in the sense that means that
we want our models to put to sprinkle probability mass
near everywhere on this triangle
they will cover the whole triangle but there will be
kind of probability dust all over the place
so when when the truth
is somewhere
there is some probability mass near that
in this case
if you're true generating process
right so it's not quite as
you know
you might
one of the parts on the bigger blogs socializing that optimises the bound holds
he because my cost gets higher
right i have to read more like since i considering the small one i can't
overfit too much in the future so here i am really like overfitting on the
future here i can't always the future
and here i'm saying i am OK
because you can select a small ones so you're cost increases far higher farther and
farther and farther so this is basically equiv is what is that is that you
can decide on the block street today and tomorrow used in the well
so there are or the other way to look at this is that there are
people who are constantly in
important so there is participating in an important story is not necessarily a matter of
it would be this would be the case
but this is solution
can basically get too close
two two two doing well on the unknown future
and then the last thing i have to show
it is this
scalability right so here we have the number of blocks we select and here is
the running time in seconds and
this is the if we would do the exhaustive search so here we would do
the basically we would need to and what we here we go and enumerate all
possible subsets of particle size and this way we would get the optimal solution but
you should software be and then this is the gradient greedy algorithm which basically scales
quadratically right for every additional sensory place you have to sort of go and check
all other sensors why this is this optimisation where we are doing this lazy evaluations
as explained before and this scales much better so in this case we were getting
like seven hundred times speed
by using this link
and i should
they can be bent cases
right i mean that can be better so you can come up with cases where
the speeding up doesn't really speed up anything
right so
there are many cases where this so degree should be the same as as blue
but in reality it seems it's not
so the other the other data that we were testing one is this water distribution
networks OK here i have a featured picture is a real metropolitan area where we
have like twenty one thousand homes and twenty five thousand pipes connecting these homes and
this is this is how these things look
and what we did is we use some realistic simulator that sort of similar to
how the water is drained through the day and it useful information about the diameter
of pipes and flow and everything else and we use a cluster of fifty machines
for a month to to to simulate three point six different epidemic scenarios right epidemic
scenario would be that this particular time of the day of this particular node some
poisonous introduced another estimating how these spreads over the network so that's why
the the number of possible epidemics scenarios is much larger than the number of nodes
because the time of the day also matters and so on and that is the
water consumption is different three different times of the day also the for the action
of the flow of the water in the pipes is different for different times of
the day it as it turns out so
we have this we got a hundred fifty two data bytes of data that then
by exploiting some sparsity and
instead of like really optimizing the function you are optimizing the reduction so instead of
optimizing the reward optimizing the reduction in penalty so a lot of better placements get
the reduction of of zero and these users sparsity so these another because i wasn't
talking about but basically it allows us from getting four hundred fifty megabytes the sixteen
megabytes of data and i can
did this in main memory and everything goes
right so again the same same same type of credit card as i was showing
so here is the number of sensors that we select replace and is again the
reduction in the population affected and again this is our solution this is what
he previously thought we could be the optimal now we know the optimum is somewhere
in between blue and green so again our solution
as it as it turns out is much better than what we saw before
you could consider different
heuristic placement so again we have a number of sensors and the
reduction in the population affected and
for example if you if we go and side we will place
the the sensors on only the big pipes right so we sort of the nodes
or by the way i think the some of the the the weight of incoming
pipes and this is in this way we decided to present his works very badly
again if we decide and putting it on these in a single where the the
the water flows through we put them there again that works really that interesting united
the red line is the population so for every node we know what the population
that particular note and now we say OK we'll put the sensors the most populated
note that also works better and we are you can notice that we are optimizing
the population affected so intuitively you would think that
putting it on most populated notes should do well but it doesn't really
and then degree of one of just how many bytes mean that that works quite
well in the end i also surprisingly works well in this case and this is
how well we can do
and we can do much better by the
the company spreads over the network
so this is first and i think one of the last slide is this about
different how different reward functions give different placements right so for example here the reward
function is the population affected so we want to minimize the number of people affected
animals bees bumblebees birds and other in of good bayesians
but people now
it's not the species
it's the representation
and most of the conditional probabilities but we get the face
the same problem does not only occur in
medicine but also in the court
in the law the typical legal scholar has
even less
into action with statistical thinking than the average doctor
out of the one hundred seventy five accredited law schools in the US only want
teachers occasionally cause methodology and statistics
and i actually have taught at the university virginia
probably the only
was the lobster
and you cannot imagine how this article sharp
men and women how little they know
when it comes to numbers
here is
here is the study that we did in berlin
we professionals that means judges and professors of law and students law students with the
same type of problems
so there is
typically there is say a murder
and this DNA evidence
it's the same structure as the mammography problem have the same thing
and just to make it sure
when the information is in conditional probabilities
few professors of law understand
when the information is not all frequencies than it
goes up and the same is the case for the students and more even more
there has to be a guilty verdict
the law
and you can see
the guilty verdicts
depends strongly from the representation though
the professors of law and the judges are confused without noticing
then the more often say
there is
i'm important message to the courts so i've been training
u s federal charges
teaching them about these differences so in one of these messages is the not allow
single event probabilities and other confusing things in
the court
and some have acted on that
it is actually the first orchard simpson trial research went into the trial
and just illustrated for you a simple question maybe
you will be accused to have a
where the first
he good for
it was not there's no evidence against you
except for one of his DNA matches mister traces from the victim so used to
try and the charge
i have no training in statistics thing
so i call an expert
and ask
what this is actually
the expert says
the probability that these
magic chains one hundred thousand
doesn't look good for you
you would agree
the probability that these matches were played chains one hundred thousand
so what we teach
judges is to recognise this is what another source of confusion in the courtroom
when nobody notices we asked them to send these
expert witnesses back and ask them make a frequency statement so now the expert witness
comes again says
what it means is to find out of every hundred thousand people
one with match
now we are in the same building
three point five million so we expect thirty five
that's the difference you can easily see
how people are being misled be no over number of court cases where exactly that
there's an unknown number
but still needs to be discovered
and here i show you
and as an illustration of the
what we call collective statistical illiteracy now back to help
these are
the german bundestag
the german parliament
has in two thousand two
put in all
that's according to which women aged fifty and older as a right for
mammography screening and health insurance will pay
and you will find in the deutsche that's the plot that's the
so if i if i were here i have a whole bunch of topics available
and i can generate some words i go down here i have a whole bunch
of other topics available connected to other words and so on down a branching tree
i'd like to find ways the branching factors what's the death
and what are the topics need to know
the document will be a path through tree
and the topics along that path the want to be able to generate a document
included sharing in many different ways in this in this thing in particularly
molecular literally shared node entry is higher up in the tree
so how do you do this well it's pretty straightforward to set up the chinese
restaurant metaphore elaborated that
you get this so
the metaphor is that tourists arrived city for clarification seaborne
and there are there for a certain number of nights
and they all go to the same room restaurant that this restaurant here
and the tables that you guys for people that
and at the table food you it but also the no which tells you which
respond to go to the next night
right now next you go to the restaurant and the number of tables picnic table
against people their tables
and then at that table is again although tells you which respond next night and
so on
we generate a random branching tree
and people who first details could take parameters
and both parameters in different clusters for associated with those people
so that's it that's sort of how you do it and you have to write
software to this and this really work
here's some artificial data generated data
this is the real trees that we generated randomly
so this is the true over here
and then we generated topics and words and so on so for this and this
is the posterior mode of the inference procedure after it's all done
this is the most probable tree
and in matter is this and if you go through all these examples is pretty
close to really does recover underlying tree
so we apply this to some data this is from psychology danger abstract from the
articles from psychology today over many years
we plug in data and there really are no free parameters this algorithm finds the
best tree find the best branching factor finds topics and does everything
and you can see it does pretty well
the words that are the most useful all documents in the percolate up the root
in particular function or part of the route you have to away function words
the especially when you go to the room very small documents
and then the next level down here words which are useful in some areas of
psychology and then as you go down things which are just more and more concrete
and we did this may be the more familiar from JACM
again function were partly at the top and then we got through the areas of
computer science at the next level
algorithms theory database and and so on and then you go down further you AND
get more and more concrete time to work
and this is my letter last slide
so there are hyperparameters this was the bayesian talk there are always some hyperparameters somewhere
that's always bayesian bet noir how you deal with some of these things
in this talk at the very top of all these these things there was famine
in the end of the day or help in order not to model
how do we set
OK well we did a paper recently which is our best proposal are probably the
best way to do this which is to not be the empirical bayesian
the religious bayesian answer to set hyperparameters is the always try to read over them
in the way you do that you introduce hyper hyperparameters distribution
after a reasonable thing to do but often hard
but in this case it really is very appealing because
jenni is infinite for object and i'm going make up for usually with that you
say that the galaxy with some unknown me
in nineteen something very parametric inside the whole nonparametric thing so an alternative which is
to be empirical bayesian is is kernel density estimation estimating not only sample that in
these pages which are flying around you put in
we can estimate the problem and get perfectly good
turn key higher empirical bayes method no more free parameters anywhere
OK so i have five
all right so that was kind of a quick run-through i know several of you
are working on this topic already this sort of bringing
coal to newcastle
but i hope that those you who are not aware that she found interesting to
appreciate what is to be nonparametric bayesian
my before the war that was going to be nonparametric bayesian nonparametric parameters
the considering the nearest neighbour that this and they didn't have to have other conjugate
priors gaussians are for
with increasing quite ten is asian this temperature strongly ship towards higher values
here you see the complete phase diagram
of the same suffix just changing the ph value of this is the non ionic
this is the ionic system
u which change in the existence region of the mexican
what's the idea behind this
when we have such system and and when for example when we said at this
of the non ionic system here in the so ution in the isotropic so ution
we simply change the ph value
and then we go into the
exactly the case in other words here we have the interesting
the situation that we can introduce the pace transformation by modifying the ph value of
our solution
what do we expect when we have such a network exec and nearly order polymer
as we have seen from the diagram
we start with the pure isotropic
one of the network
we can swear the parliament network
then we have the first transformation from the isotropic network into the exact second the
phase and that we should again have these interaction
between chain confirmation infrastructure here we have brought like aggregates in other words we should
observe and elongation one direction shrinkage into the other direction
ending up with such an organization
when we have our exec interface and when we additionally it water in other words
when we go in this direction
we should expect that the cylinder will only swell in one dimension
given by this slow
but the length of the cylinder
should stay constant
in other words
such a strong and isotropy in the swelling behavior
jump in the dimension and then this
two dimension as
here are one results
we observe this behavior we observe the anisotropy we observe such as low
here's some of the
which is simply due and can be explained by defects of the example of structure
in other words highly interesting system
well you can also
the mechanics by
variation of the water content of the creation of the
here one
nice experiments from the network if we look at the links
as function of time when we have some hydrochloric acid
huge changes in the dimension of huge large changes in the dimension parallel and perpendicular
to the director
which are determined by the diffusion of the system
what can we do with such high projects for example one idea was
an old idea originally from
given in austria
he said why not making bifocals
lands from liquid crystal elastomers
or a an optical about focus contact lens
the optical axis of the uniaxial crystal is parallel to the surface of such
then you have to
refractive powers
which is which can be used for example for positive people similar to these
classes having two
refractive powers
can be done with our elastomers you
such a high liquid crystal and has had which which is microscopically uniformly or with
the optical axis in this direction and which is
as these by focal optical properties i think it's the perfect solution
unfortunately or and i should say that also industry is highly interested was highly interested
in this topic unfortunately it's simply too expensive
but nevertheless let me summarize so far with the second part of my lecture i
think i could give you a very brief introduction that all these principles that are
valid for the thermotropic liquid crystalline elastomers the interplay between chain confirmation structure also holds
but the convergence would be very very slow and in particular you want get a
central limit theorem
so you get this tumor which is very poor so this is something that must
be remembered that when you pick a function g
once again you want a function g which which has
heavy tailed
if is the tower to defend then you can get into trouble for functions h
so i decided to say set of
examples just in included that one
right now is not in notes
we get a very nice example and found that
this is the most realistic problems
again we have a cushy
inferential problems we have ten observations from the cushy
this ten observations
the density while one person x minus either square and we don't see here
we put flat prior on theta the the posterior e the likelihood
this is the same thing
approximate the posterior distribution on c to
we want to compute the posterior expectations
so in general multiplied with the likelihood associated with the ten observations we something which
is very silly
which is the
new ones
so we simulate
sample of feeders from the normal
mu one
for instance we use
one thousand
generations from the normal
new one and this graph represents
the effect of the choice of
OK i started by simulated
they simulating my ten
cushing observation so i chose theoretical view
and i see made ten
co she is
and i have posted distribution
on the side the ten coaches and when i was new close to zero
this graph represents the range
my estimations
five hundred applications of my importance sampling approximations and you can see that the range
it is fairly
restricted to new
call one point five to two OK the you the pink
ranges does the ninety five percent range
but as new
get away
from the which is close the true value
you can see the
first generation degeneracy in the scope
or in the range of of the estimation as new increases it gets larger and
larger but worse after a while like when you is equal to
mister nations form i five hundred applications do not even get
to the true value
this is that because of the normal
one unit equal two
the musical two far i have lot trouble to reach something close to zero and
therefore his gets away
the y axis
is nice to their seat ahead
so this is the approximation
to the posterior expectation
OK so why try to approximate is
then to wealthy
product from i cycle one to ten of one of the one person x on
minus e square
divided by the same thing with those this year
and because
i feel that i cannot i cannot compute that numerically
what they use instead
the importance sampling estimator mary which is the song
from one to t
also see on
product of one class x
my last you i
and i divide by the normal distributions therefore multiply by the
new minus cedar i
and then the numerator is the same it's e
mu minus edi i square
divided by the the product of one class xk
minus i
and those you are are i i d
no more you want
and of course as you
increases and i see that
estimated from the normal
santa a new
so i knew it follows from the road
i get less and less point
in the region of interest and this is the recovery
very well if you can see he
so this is an example of finished there was an infinite violence because of this
e to the new iris it i call
just this creates an exploring factor and this tumor is is really poor and well
of course this is an example of that
since she
and this is
no none reputation
so my here
is that a minimum of five
i created five hundred replications of that
and the range i obtained is given
by these black
that kind of inference
is this work
i hope
it's like on its like
it's blinking
i don't think it's amplifying
well i should tell it not to sleep can
OK i'm going to talk about the state of
how i see artificial intelligence and
what i think we should do about it
i'll start by
i'm suggesting that it's actually an emergency
and that sometime in the next twenty or fifty years
we're going to need
really smart machines
because there will be
enough people to do
all the work
as you probably know
life expectancy
of people has been increasing about one year every four
for the last fifty odd years
this is probably going to keep happening and
maybe even speed up
so that a person born today
has a life expectancy of about one hundred
whereas in nineteen fifty it was
seventy five or eighty
with luck general health will also
improve so that
this doesn't just mean
more and more years of being
more or less disabled
but anyway at some point we're also going to
i have to reach some kind of equilibrium in population
so that when people start to live for two hundred years
and typically there will be
one fifteen year-old child for each one hundred fifty year-old adult
and that will be enough
to supply the infrastructure and
all the other things that we're accustomed to now now
course with the industrial revolution
the number of
people hours to make a product started to decrease
in some areas it hasn't increased very much
there's some strange kind of theory that the
you can solve some of the problems of supporting the old people
by savings
but as far as i can see that's meaningless
because having money is no use unless their workers to pay
to do things
with it
and so the idea of
beefing up the social security fund and so forth
so that people will have in comes in the future
it's just simply a big mistake
money is no use unless there are people who want it
now we have a certain amount of automation
so that lots of parts of cars are made automatically
and some devices are assembled automatically
a couple of years ago i was
visiting the roland company in hamamatsu japan
and where they make keyboards and plotters
music keyboards
which incidentally they don't sell in japan because
yamaha is in neighbour
they're very polite about not competing with their neighbour
so roland keyboards are
only sold
so they took me on the planet and there was no one there
it was all there was also part making
and there was nobody in the plotter factory either
but at the exit
there was a roland plotter and a
i think with hewlett packard plotters these are
big six foot things
each plotter came out of the assembly line and plotted something
and there was a person who would compare
its plot with hewlett-packard plot
and if it didn't look as good he would send it back
so that was there
quality control person
and as i remember he was the only one in the place
at the moment
there aren't any machines that can fix your car like
change the spark plugs or
make even minor repairs
and so
so we don't have any automation for maintenance of things
i suppose because maintenance means
something happened that wasn't expected
and so you need
anywhere from very small two
very large degree of resourcefulness and
adaptability and so for us to understand the situation
correct what's wrong
so we don't have any automation to speak of
of customized work
it's it is going to be a meeting
here in
three or four weeks
the subject of mass customization
and mass customization
it means how do you measure
clothing that will actually fit customers and that sort of thing
from the manufacturing point of view
i don't think that's a serious problem
if you can make it suited all
then by
fancy programming you ought to be able to make one that
is slightly different for each customer and so forth
on the other hand if you terriers suit
or shirt
i don't think there's any
machine that can so it up together yet
how can we solve that problem
by making machines that have
a large degree of common sense and
resourcefulness and great deal of knowledge about how to do things
and fairly dextrous hands are
the equivalent
but at the moment nothing like that is happening anywhere in the world
what's more
of course i would have to upperbound it but this is something which is the
property of the plant
so the
the final term like this chaining of the log and this is all an estimate
of the geometry but it could be a good one or bad one and you
don't know if you if you met but this is the best
you can get totally different balance of different people can get the results of the
same class because the knowledge out as
you know how
one thing that tells you that you're right is that you if you look
for example
the expected value of the supremum of
the difference between
the true and empirical
this is more or less what these bonds are trying to
there are two
estimate how far
these things are deviating
over the class
so that that
this quantity here
which depends
on the class
and depends on the distribution
we can prove that its upper and lower bounded by
you know one is the training ground
with some constants c one and c two here
so what this means is that
this tuning in capture the right
at least the right rate of convergence of these two zero as n goes to
so this is approved that
this is
now it's true that it depends on how well you
compute or upper bound is covering numbers because then
it is log and and but you still have to compute
and you may have
good or bad provides on the end
but again you can
in some cases you can prove that for example for VC classes
you can prove that
it's a good estimate or i mean
it's not exactly b but
say that covering number
at five eps that's register epsilon is something like epsilon minus one of the
and this
i mean it's not inequality is an upper bound but you can see that you
can prove that it's an upper and lower bounds which means you have within some
you have a good estimate of the current so
what i'm saying is that
all this one it is always hard to upper bound them precisely
you can improve the
at each step you get the right rate
don't get the right value with
asymptotically they are correct
given the data
a bayesian approach but also
converge to the correct
and in some sense because the priors easily overwhelmed
and in many cases
they can also talk about
five becomes one
and it seems like
this is a house
what you can prove in the vision contd
the question if the question is
in the bayesian case you can prove that
after why the prior is washed away have enough data then you can
you know you converge to the true thing no matter what your priorities
and you can even get results about how fast this happens and how does this
relate to
yes yes yes
for the
i mean this convergence is consistency
focus on the prior
does with weight on all the functions that they that covered the entire
yes i mean
i mean depends what kind of analysis you doing the baiting is
but one thing is not i mean you can apply all these two
bayesian algorithm that finds
you have your prior you look at how fast the converges
and you can derive the same kind of results
you can have consistency but you cannot have rates of convergence to the true though
right because you have an opinion here and so that the number is also body
big picture
just a lot of how you want it and i think
you know you have to make the distinction between
bayesian algorithms or algorithm that are based on the you know using a probabilistic prior
using bayes rule to make two
to update the prior
so that's the bayesian algorithm but then there is
the bayesian analysis of algorithms
where instead of looking at the worst case scenario is you're looking at the average
case so where everything that every statement that you make in the bayesian analysis
it would be
on under the expectations over the prior over sampling the function according to the prior
but these are two different things vision algorithms can very well be analysed in that
svms can very well be analyzed under expectation over some over some prior
and the kind of result that you're being with bayesian analysis are
that same year but they something different because
you can't really
i mean to tell you something on average over something
prior sampling
doesn't really tell you something about the problem that you're looking at
it's just average over a set of problems and you want see get to see
just one problem
but it mean that you can derive something from the average
i don't know if it's a matter of choice but again it can give you
some guidance but doesn't
justify really something for your specific problem
just like
you know these mounds they are probabilistic in nature that there is something about the
distribution over all possible training said that would sample
but for this particular training set that you observe
maybe it's true maybe it's much true maybe you're exactly in the case where the
boundaries will finally right
but you can circumvent that
you know looking at this and setting that i mentioned before the only thing where
you don't even have this issue
probabilistic bounds to me about
in practice we cannot get rid of prior and we always used by your friends
dealing with practical problem and i always wonder how much i came from the prior
and how much they came from the data
and the if the valid question again
because hearing with very very
OK so
what you did this question is perfectly fine by to you
have your prior assumptions and
you have your data
and of course
so i'm going to talk a little bit about the fitting of the perceptron but
importantly it was based on a really simple model of the neuron from nineteen forty
three and a learning algorithm for how the neuron worked
now later machine learning research so has gone from that those sort of simple
perhaps neurally inspired models
theoretical foundations of such models such questions is their capacity to learn and i think
a real sort of example of that is you know that nick's work on statistical
learning theory is not part i follow but it's extremely theoretical very mathematical and it
doesn't really care
when learning algorithm has any basis in the brain it's just about learning algorithms
my personal view is the machine learning benefited really greatly by incorporating on some ideas
from psychology
but not being afraid to incorporate rigorous theory so
and i do credit
in particular when i think about the people around before i was around and look
at the community before i was around i don't think people like michael jordan geoff
hinton they were in this parallel distributed processing research group
sort of i guess in the early eighties and that was very
i guess psychologically based
the algorithms they came out with were inspired by thinking about how the brain works
but what i think is very impressive so it's easy to say disable we're going
to do something on computers and we're gonna be inspired by the brain and we're
going to do sort of learning or you could sort of look more recent things
like similar life for genetic algorithms all these different things inspired by evolution let's do
it let's do evolution does
i think machine learning in some sense is slightly different because
i think it's been far less afraid of very very strong theory and very very
strong mathematics and very open to receiving that i think a lot of the credit
of that goes to people like michael jordan definition through early on when physicists theoretical
physicists came in and said all
the model you've got of the brain is actually a spin glass and you can
do this analysis they didn't run away saying that's just theory we're interested results they
embrace that and those people are still in the community today and i think that
you really see that reflected in the machine learning community the diversity from people who
are very interested in just the theory
i have no
concerns about whether this what humans do may not even have any concerns about whether
their models
work in particular applications to people who are only interested applications have no concerns about
whether this is how humans learn to people who are interested in humans learning
and it basically has covered all those things i think it's very important that continues
to cover all those things because it benefits from that mix
of people in this is a lot about what i think this is the summer
school is about is partially about remaking that connection
one of the things happened is
machine learning people get accused of distorting lousy statistics
because one of the results of this research is is is the work we did
does work well on things are traditionally considered to be statistical applications
machine learning i think was viewed with some skepticism by statisticians because they saw it
as soon as sloppy statistics
now i'm glad to say
modern machine learning and statistics interact to both communities benefits so if i go
and visits so recently we had chris holmes visits group in
manchester he's leading bayesian statistician you know and chris simms when we're talking about their
applications were interested we have entirely overlapping ideas we think very much the same thing
we use very similar models very similar techniques some of those techniques are now coming
from the machine learning community in particular variational methods and i must admit that i
was falling into the trap one stage thinking what is machine learning just an extension
of statistics
are we just sort of modern statistics people with
perhaps sexier applications in video and stuff like that and i guess i started getting
persuaded by the argument
i'm going to offend people maybe when i say some of the things i'll say
that i'll continue anyway don't feel too offended if you're statisticians statistics this i didn't
really feel counter this because to me statistics was the most boring part of all
i remember the doing maths at the age of sixteen and statistics was
let's some of these numbers to compute the mean OK and i can remember that
the idea
OK so this is the last little step but i have to do i to
make sure that my function somehow has something to do with the interest
so how do we do learning in these things
OK so so so now we have to do some some inference so we already
looked at the slide this the how to do inference in in in a parametric
and we also looked at the the bayesian inference here so again what what normally
happens in
in parametric models of our model is now in the nonparametric model normally happens here
is that you put a prior on the weights that you construct the
the posterior over the weights
and then you
use posterior
two to compute the things that you are interested in it and you interested in
making predictions
so that's an integral over the posterior distribution or you might be introduced interested in
the marginal likelihood
much like being the the
the product of the prior and the likelihood is the unnormalized posterior so again it's
it's an integral over the posterior distribution
we can also do
we can also compute the probability of the model if we have different different sets
of models and indeed this is what we what we going do now the problem
here is that for most interesting models these schools are intractable so we can't actually
compute what's going on
but interestingly gas process are tractable an interesting class of models we can exactly do
those intervals
so how does that work now firstly
this a little bit of a problem here right because where the weights
i just saying well we're just using
prior over functions and then we have some data but it also tells you something
about what the function is and then we're supposed to combine those those two
but how do we apply this methodology when and
what like where where the parameters like where the model here
so it turns out that
the the right answer to that question is that the parameters in our model is
the function itself
OK that sounds
that sounds a little bit weird right but what we're doing inference over is just
and so if we plug into our usual framework if you just plug in every
time saw the parameters before we just taking the function and let's see what happens
after all we want to do inference about the function and the likelihood tells you
something about what the function is doing in the prior to tell you something about
what the function is doing
OK so we have so so we have the same ingredients as before we just
turn the crank on what we're supposed to be doing so so what about the
likelihood function so we have again gauss the likelihood function
the like function tells you what's the probability of the observed data given
the parameters so now that would be
and we're not modelling the input here is that the probability of the royal society
to change notation so this is shorthand for p of the thing that says is
the conditional probability and right the PC more everything i write down the probabilities
if not a piece missing
so so the likelihood function is the probability of the data given the parameters
so let's write that down
so the probability of the data
in the end we only interested in modeling output it's probably the outputs given the
data the data is now the function
OK so now i condition on the function put in f f of x and
what is that thing well the likelihood tells us something about if the true function
is something then what's the probability of observing the thing that you actually observed
and that's if the if the noise that depends on the noise assumption about the
noise assumption is calcium that says well then that the likelihood that probability is going
to be proportional to e to the minus the distance between the actual function and
the observed value
so that this is going to be
so so the question was
the vision
the the
so so what may be maybe this is the wrong the likelihood function is the
probability of the data given the parameters
OK and now we we've we've now substituting the function for the parameters in the
probability of the data is it's only the upper part that we really modelling so
sorry if i if i said that wrong
OK so something interesting happens here right because we actually only the likelihood function is
only interested in what the function does at the locations where we have data
right it's and it doesn't say it doesn't actually depend on what the function does
out here where there was no data
right so i know
although when we write it down it looks as though the likelihood function cares about
what the function does everywhere that happens not to be the case but it actually
only depends on what the function is doing at the places where we are where
we made observations
OK so the so the likelihood function actually only depends on the values of x
at the input locations are use boldface x f
as a vector of those of those f
and this is just to show the shorthand notation for for gas distribution so that
the gas in here is centered on the left and it has whatever the observation
the likelihood function yes
so what we see now do we
the in the
are three
here just mean i just mean what the function is actually the function is unknown
just like the parameters are unknown when we're doing inference so this is just you
can just think of this as being sort of an an abstract notation for the
stuff that we don't know
we don't know what it is right
but we do know
that if the places where we have observations f should be close to those observations
OK so now we have to put a prior on our on our parameters right
now propositional function
but luckily we know how to put distributions over functions right so let's put against
process prior on the functions so
all prime here is the probability of the parameters given the
OK so
so we'd like to do is is trying to analyse poker
using this notion of minimax optimality and we like to see
you know there's a lot of different
issues that come up in poker things like blood thing grandstands where you act like
you have a stronger hand and you really do
or underpinning where you actually you weaker and and you really do you might ask
are these issues solely kind of
human psychology issues or are they
so the mathematical issues
and i think the answer is there both
but there weak we can analyse years at least show
that they are mathematical issues as well as whatever social
you know were sort of
psychology issues
so we can take a simple game and said the are minimax optimal strategies will
see they will in fact two bluffing and two underfitting
OK so here's a
let me just described in this game which is kind of the simplest version of
poker that has the kind of
ninety with poker is that there's some
lack of knowledge and you have what the other player and if you don't know
exactly what the other players hand was it would be very interesting game
so is the simplest version that's just repeat the setting this three cards
two players
and the players ante and the dollar
OK so
how many dollars here but i have cookies
all right so
god i five
right song with fifty cent game for each player antes and the dollar so the
part starts with results
and then
HK one car to car
and then if you're the player goes first
can the decide
where you want that dollar pasta
if you decide to that dollars of course the person that even if all the
faithful you get the part or
they can put in
human dollar and then so they can either they fold you get the part doesn't
matter where cards are if they play dollar to the house for large
so you if you that the other player call a dollar to fall or you
might choose not to that you might say well
i'd rather not that and the second player gets to go the second player if
you pass the second player can then decide well they can either pass is just
the the anti and you just review your card
before they can that
if they that bends back to you
the first player so you can either call for years our fold and they get
the party
whatever it is you can't
this of your
the mayor poker you kind make sense the very simple version
does anybody know keep going back and forth which is just one
you start eating cookies insectivorous OK so
so there's the game
and the high card wins if there's no fault there was falling whoever fold
max part two dollars that's not quite right that was caught on the next winningest
and so those are positive and one of them which are the most you can
win parameters to my
you could when dollar twenty dollars
you could lose the dollar two dollars
so there's again it so we could even play
you know
for bit but
we can write this matrix
so the question how would you write is the matrix k so ution it i
think about this because the rows are your strategy the colonies what the strategy in
this game
so the strategy is
what you're going to do
a complete specification program
a strategy arose like a program you are write computer programs to say what you
would do in every eventuality
so here's an example
OK so let me to forgiven car let's say your player and the player a
is the first one i want to go for that so you
you can decide
for any given card what you're going to do so that i mean what you
do is you pass
by your phone
if he chooses to bet
that the possible strategies you might decide the forgiven card like two
i might pass but
the that snowfall
or i could decide use them in the past
but if the best thing
we can write such
are right so well
another strategy you could have forgiven card
is you might pass
but then called the that to be so so when you're going to advance think
about what you're doing every eventuality you to write this down you give us two
right this a computer program to play for you
so you could say for any given car you want italics
OK for this like the one and the case of the three possibility given card
you could pass the ball with the bat the very weak strategy call past fold
you could pass the color the that that's kind of intermediate strand you called call
or you could that call
and then there's nothing else to do the other player has to make a decision
to the colony
so reason three
cards you can do one of these and so
there are
about imagine movement
and how to control
BCI i
and how to transfer information
i showed you
why i discussed
that there are some
directions that are helping disabled
so clinical applications i showed you want the arm is i discussed others from
the bombers that
and this the general issue of
human computer interaction
the games were some part of of the
the story
so so the idea is to have some signal that is not you know i
movement that is not
you know motor movement but something beyond that and you see what we can actually
do with it so it's an unexplored channel in the human machine interaction
and this we would like to explore
just to give you
overview of what we want what we did so this is some something really is
real and it is done with the with the car maker
i don't say who and and the goal here was the following so given that
you're measure e g in the car
can we actually
find out what the workload
to a certain driver is
because if we would know that
we could
try to try to change the
the driver
core into action
just to make an example so if we would know that the workload is very
four in the acoustic domain
we can easily get this with microphones but c
with your brain signals some i mean even if you have loved music it might
not be high workload for you for you
in this in the sense of cognitive workload so
if we would have that and you navigation system starts talking to you there's no
way you can you can really grasp what it says
on and if you have already high workload and then you
might even have an accident
so so one way is
to use this information of of or detector and saying this too high workload here
let's shifted to another
it's a visual input you
projected onto the screen so this is
one of the very simple application
going to show it to you
and they have to
in this from
OK maybe
so there's an EEG trace running up there
and you see this several
task the same time is the primary task driving this secondary task responding to write
direct links which between right and left and you have to push left and right
and then there is some some further tasks which are mental calculation
and listening to one two and mix of an audio book and news
makers of these different different
two ways of actually simulating high or low workload situation
and so in this point in fact the
the drivers doing some mental mental calculation task so so you can try to do
it yourself so i give you number
seven hundred and fifty eight
and you subtract seventeen
when you do that
for a while
and you say
you know you always say the numbers you're not allowed to to mumble
and it's actually what you're driving and while you're doing all these sorts of things
it's quite
tedious and so you could also
i have another mental calculation task which is subtracting three for example
and so you could distinguish between high and low
calculation workload
and so if you
you would do some kind of
the training set up which means that you drive the car go through some blocks
of high and low workload of acoustic and and calculation
and you try to to calibrate your classifiers to the individual to this particular task
of detecting high and low workload
and and then you you just two and a real experiment and and see how
good you are
and then
mitigate the
OK so that six hundred fifty six so that was after a long period of
calculation so
so you see that now the mental workload because
down for calculation because she has to do something
and you see the secondary task with the links always
and i actually have to move to some
o point where
you can actually see
we just get the do
slide number video
so this is just
the acoustic the story of news search certain news thing and also an audio book
read and the subject is instructed to listen to either one to tell later on
to what it is about so he has to fill out the form to tell
you can so you can say what what
we can find out
well i mean that it's makes it to make
about one of them
i'm not sure
what the definition of a positive definite kernel in implies for this special case where
you have only one point and only one crayfish
and the problem is he already
in the handouts
compute the determinant of the gram matrix
and maybe are meant to him by saying
since this is a positive definite matrix
the determinant to be nonnegative
OK so the determinant of positive definite matrices nonnegative
maybe many of you know this from linear algebra
so the determinant
is nonnegative and for the last problem
i'm just saying it's in it's implied by the problem
once you've proven three it should be relatively easy to prove for
OK so
OK so there's a few herself solved also we get to the solutions now
so again if you want you can some brownie points for the
best student prize of this summer school is someone who would like to
present the solution of the second problem
all right
the model
i mean
it's you
and then you
as well
one of the school
as long as go
and this
is that what we
take your name means going through OK
so that's one point
i think about was going to solve present problem number two
so there was number three actually now we go back to number two positivity on
the diagonal someone who so this one
you can use new one
so just to let me know slight modification let's say
this is true for all possible values of a
i'm going to have a to one
and then i can directly see
this great but
OK this is also i think you know what you think
OK so this again
she's using only a sum over one term so she has eight times a year
and then k of x and x and then with just saying since it has
to be nonnegative no matter what a we choose
by definition of a positive definite kernel that's just choose some a which is nonzero
and then we can divide by a so points let's choose a one and then
directly we can see that k is positive or negative on the diagonal
OK any questions about this one
if not let's go to the last one
if you want to what this picture is that comes up in between it's picture
of the northern lights
and considering in the constellation of orion
OK so the last one vanishing diagonals so i can manage is on the diagonal
it vanishes everywhere
anyone want to
should this one
that's more
but OK so all right to use these things
OK i x x prime squared
it's smaller than
zero time zero
so the square of the next prime minister
smaller than smaller equal to zero because we also know that is larger or equal
to zero because of the square
so it actually has to be able to zero
good morning