so PAC MDP is very similar kind of property right well would optimal all but
a polynomial number of time steps this is where bayes optimal but a polynomial number
of time steps there are different in each other and the way in which are
different i think it's really interesting
and that this is sort of an open question in some ways so bayes optimal
PAC MDP are not the same thing there's examples and culture and had have one
in their paper in my students lihong li input but is the system is realized
the basically show that here's the task where the bayes optimal action and the
the near optimal action diverge
in particular what happens is these be the bayes optimal algorithm sometimes decides that it's
just not worth learning anything new right so it may take a couple steps before
it actually gets this new information and pick between discounting and what not an opportunity
cost and you know that maybe
the optimal thing to do what you get out there but i don't really ever
want to be there next sort of goes off this other way and by virtue
of the fact that it goes off to so the way it never actually learned
about what really happens in another state if it knew that the state was good
it would have gone there but wasn't sure
the support of
could be solved by weaker prior of
i don't know the examples that being the actually relatively weak priors
so in fact when li hong his thesis to view i read through his profound
like this is broken because you have two stronger prior needs to be true that
strong prior and he just ended back to just read it because i just issue
because they like it can be true ads can be true so i just told
him it wasn't true but that was that was incorrect it was actually true
i can i can point to example
but what what what i think is really interesting about this is a very there's
a fundamental difference in perspective between these two models that actually it's not clear to
me anymore which one is exactly right so what near bayesian or or the bayes
strategy says is my current self needs to get near optimal reward
and it really doesn't care very much about the future self
except have to do in this concert features of making a decision now
and then
now there's a new me essentially right i'd like oh i hate that old guy
who put me in this horrible situation
but there but here i am and i have to do the best i can
and a lot of this sequential decision making is about trades of trade-offs between these
various cells right so i would like some water now all but this is going
help me now it's going to help me when i actually go and get the
water so the me now has to say yes sure whatever it takes additional energy
now but you all have your undying appreciation
thank you
like so so
so this is this is the standard thing in fact the red
a book about human decision making in end
lot of psychologist talk about these things this way as well this the future self
and and
and current so so so so near bayesian is all about you know what's the
what's what's good for me the current self now
what's what's going to maximize my future discounted reward PAC MDP if you think about
the way we talked about this yesterday it really is all about the future self
it's like i'm going to do some things now that might be fairly stupid
they're going to bound the number of stupid things i do but we're gonna but
we still can do stupid things out all to what we want is that we're
going to be in some future time in some state and we want to get
near optimal reward at that time
i don't care what it is now as much i care what is going to
be that
and so
they really are very much focused on two different
that is the world's press
that's right
the result is that she deserves
in the sense that it is
this was that that was not
right and if we really believe it then we can just say we're acting for
our current self and that is just the correct thing to do but it's but
then on the other hand you know i mean this state and i maximizing or
my reward for right now but if only my past self had done this exploration
action i would be getting higher reward right now
so i've been blown off
by my past self
if i'm if my past self was being near bayesian but on average that self
is low probability or something like that is the right so so this right so
the new bayesian does take into consideration future selves but averages them all out that
so maybe maybe one way to look at it is this sort of expected case
in this sort of worst-case right this is actually caring about the states i could
get two with very low probability is a song by the
function is
the the best
or there using sort of two different discount function to choosing one that's that's using
first decision
and yet and so in fact if you look at it if you look at
human behaviour al behavior people people do this they seem to do something sort of
in between future and current self carrying they don't do what appears to be the
bayes optimal and they don't seem to be strictly PAC MDP as they've been described
as are we've been described as having hyperbolic discounting geometric discounting
that you will do
i see what you're saying far more
is requisite OK OK so
i want to say you're bayesian but i mean that in a kind way OK
but in the following sense is this i feel like this is what you just
did to me use said and he said it's just about the test specification but
these are two different has specifications
right this is actually written down like formally defined and there's no hyperbolic discounting in
it but what you said is but because it's got to be in its flexible
and we could put in other things to make it the right path specification which
we could do with this
it's not clear that we could do with this
but but the my point is that these two as they currently are out there
are not quite right and so what the modification you suggest is one possibility and
i am open to it another one i was thinking well or we could just
stick with PAC MDP but either way
we have to explain why it was the right thing to do and i think
i think that's a really good point
so i put this slide not because there's some published paper that covers this topic
but because i thought it was sort of interesting and i was looking for feedback
like that again
OK alright so
but that's not what we did in our so so we decided we're going to
use some bayesian stuff and we decided to do a little bit differently so we
actually putting bayesian priors together with PAC MDP
this make probably no unhappy right because it's not bayes optimal we don't care about
these optimal more trying to PAC MDP
in the next round we randomly chosen x one given y one
and this keeps going we then generate the next the next day y two which
gives us the next output x two and this keeps going until we get to
a final state so it took two n plus one stochastic steps or rules of
some dye to generate the whole sequence x y
everything was produced exactly once
and the features were really restricted to this local decisions as local random steps
OK so
not going to say too much about generative models i imagine most people have seen
these before and recognise an HMM it is is it is an example
the nice thing about the courses that are very easy to train if i have
if i have data as described all i have to do is come up all
the events and normalize maybe do a a little bit of smoothing
the problem of course is that this does not include any notion of loss
apart from this sort of log loss approximation to the full sequence
get a hamming distance of the full sequence on x times y
and you can use any features you want you really have to respect these markovian
independence assumptions if you want to keep the parameter space small
from a machine learning perspective i think these are some of the least satisfying thing
to do in NLP
but we use them all the time because they're just so darn easy all you
have to build this year decoder and a little perl scripts to count the events
from from a from a treebank or some other this
but of course i'm probably preaching to the choir if our goal is to do
a particular type of prediction
from x to y then there's no reason to ever learn the distribution over x
of course
if we really want to model that can do any kind of can kind of
prediction or different types of prediction may be a model that can turn wine tax
in x into y
maybe you want translator can go in both directions that are just take an example
then you may actually want the generative model so there are times when i think
that's appropriate but if we have a particular decoding function we want to implement the
discriminative method is probably the right way to go
there's a there's a typo in the slide
so the first the first thing i thought about discriminative models as they were starting
to to arise in machine learning came about in in the mid nineties and the
idea was that if you break your outputs just drop it into parts
they can be built incrementally
you can think about some kind of probabilistic automaton that that slowly consumes step by
step the the
sorry that slowly step by step reduces the output while looking at the input or
maybe even consuming the input
and we use the different across different classifications step for each part
we can train that discriminative classifiers
for each part on its own and gets it's probably just a classification problem so
it could be multinomial distributions are just aggression SVM whatever you want to the classic
example of this was magnum and sparse and this was the first statistical parser user
decision tree and the idea was that it moved along the sequence step by step
and make the decision about whether to attach the word or start a new constituent
was essentially what should produce sparser you've come in
i'll get there
i organised this way
partly for historical reasons
and partly because i think it's a good get to this kinds of models
our work will definitely get there
OK so
so the the general idea when you have these local decisions is that they tend
to shy very well with with decoding methods that are based on search
so the idea is that if you imagine that your data were generated by some
kind of step-by-step automaton then really doing prediction is just running out of time and
in in the other direction the prediction so the idea is in the greediest version
you start out by making up but by using a predictor for x for peace
structure one and then taking taking the output of that you make the next prediction
about the next piece of structural call h two and you keep going into you
have the whole structure and usually people don't do this greatly although occasionally they do
this this sort of thinking works pretty well if you like to think about state
space search and so this really caught on for a lot of different problems and
and continues to be
so what is see another great example of this is the maximum entropy markov model
where you start out in your start state and then you look at the first
x one and generate y one which is the label for the first the first
input and then you generate the next one given the previous one and the next
observation and you can keep going until you get to the
and this takes and n plus one steps
one one there are some flaws with this is it feels wrong and there's been
a lot of being spilled over why it feels wrong what might be wrong with
the one one thing that people have said is that these kinds of automaton based
models lead to something called label bias
which says
hasyear as you sort of generating the the output structure y
if you made a bad choice at some point
and there's there's nothing you can do this can easily happen in hmm
it might be the case that as you randomly generating from from an HMM
you do so you move into estate it's incredibly unlikely to have generated the next
one started the next the next input symbol x the next observation simple acts
and if that happened then you know this whole sequence was bad and this just
wouldn't have happened so when you're when you think about the generative process
there's there's there's an understanding that there are things that could have gone horribly wrong
that you would never have been able to recover from this can happen in any
and then if you get into a bad state you're still forced to do something
you have to kind of keep going and so what what what i guess the
reason it's called label bias that you can keep paying attention to the previous labels
and ignoring the observations
OK if there's been a lot of question over whether this really matters whether this
is a real problem there are a couple of other things to say about these
kinds of models one is the inside the training doesn't match the testing
when you train the model
you train a bunch of classifiers make a bunch of decisions in the cascade
but you only but you always when your training assume that all the previous decisions
are made correctly
your model is unprepared for the case where at some point something went wrong
another another interesting fact is that some first for certain classes of models and restricting
partition the unit square into rectangles
eighteen years before mean are too i hope that of them but you
first of all the problems of the squid is all this which
this is the core of
this wonderful book problems in discrete geometry by class
william also in you
and all the discrete geometry is which is extending more than one hundred fifty years
it's about to open problems in high school
so can understand which this is what i call that
some of these problems are notoriously difficult and are intimately related to the questions
in other fields of mathematics
many probability of be of clever undergraduate or high-school students
we have ingenious idea
and the kinds of skills used in the mathematical knowledge
so here is
in december of two problems
the first one is part
well first of in nineteen forty six
now we lament and point to the plane
how many times the distance one in the core of these important
the second one is a nineteen fifty followed by now
and this is what is the come number of the unit distance graph an exact
definition in the second
in diameter last week in jerusalem in
a long debate started which one of these two problems is more things
and the information is what is the same as is
i don't know
so maybe you can think about how many people are aware of the first one
and having of second one
and use it as assembled to decide which one of these two
his more famous
but one day when we see her become famous is repeated many many conferences until
one day
progress is made
OK so here is the citation for
geometry junkyard
well the website with all kinds of problems and there was finishing
well already start the
argument about
what is the proper name of the national park
in this particular website called the hot or that some of them
and let q be very well with all points of the plane
as far
this is not locally finite of course
and vx y is is an edge if and only if the points x and
at distance one
what is the chromatic number of g
so these are two things
one of starting configuration in the middle
it's called the moser spindle
is it full that these four colors easy straightforward
this article or hexagonal tiling
of the play was the first part of your body was already in nineteen fifty
one by is bad
that doesn't prove that you can kind the play in
seven colors
i will come back with more
details about the distances guarantees the distance one
it does not
the main simple tree
and in this form is what are called
it can transfer or more precisely this we can't transfer
five small subgraphs such that in any kind of its users
two specific verses must in the same of
in this case is
these two triangles
if you can do it in three colors these two vertices must have the same
kind of thing
so this is one
you need to use force
so what makes this problem for us
it is fifty seven years
he was born in nineteen fifty
very simple to understand
at least five occasions credited with
and so on
who we are we almost
and martin car
so the problem is also famous because right now it is part of the story
because so if there so very nice studies focused on
it trace the true ownership of this problem
he was start to nelson was acquired from the university of chicago
when he came up with this problem
he actually labeled b
of course
the requirements were established in nineteen fifty
and since then no progress has been made
if you want the papers
that are dedicated to this problem
it some places rules that boring
moscow moscow state university
and those who works on
the problem and related to
like what he was
a disaster
the closest
i call it an opportunity
OK so what made famous problem is the answer
all of is still in every
we conferencedisplay with problems and you would be the man who was
and as a result of the more impressed on problem all over the
any other type of mathematics
OK so was a sample of a few variations
this particular problem genoa for example
in order to fooled
you need at least five although needed is a finite graph
they can be embedded in the plane so there
the edges are at distance one in which was five
so for instance since the start with four toes
the simplest example
we saw
as very few words in this triangle harbor trying to flee class
how about graphs larger
all this has been sold
another variation
you can kind of the plane in six colors and quite a few
ways to do it
with different types of tiling such that five of the callers will miss the distance
the the sixth of may is another distance not the distance one
i would mention so in
dimensions we
no the concurrent space fifteen colours
in recent one of queen one great-grandchildren
it's the end of the november alone
now pushed and pulled the need
sixty six dollars
and that is different
that of course
it's all i know
how to use it for
when we look at is the posterior all in each image please
which is based which is simply the ratio of positive to negative three years four
here two to three
one to five years one
positive negative so it you is rather than you would say
this is the first
the second is the belief that fall
instance based looks like this
and ranking it looks like this
OK so quickly
this is the
this the there
this is because we times
in the ranking nationally goal is to going to say only five times in the
right kind of thing
and so
and this is quite nice ranking because you know you go from most of those
on the left side of one that you have the right
the next
so that's fine
what we do we use decision tree probability estimator we use the posterior of themselves
we will lose their all and you converts them into probabilistic one although i actually
think that very often much easier to calculate
this all that is if you want to probability what do you say forty five
platforms one
o point
two five factors
plus three
o point for so long
i that the probability is that in this way so these these hormones are the
same as director but they are distributed along the real axis from one zero
right so this is all new and and you may wonder why i tell you
this now let's look at this a little bit
from analysis so
i use rather than as lot for visualizing not necessarily related to visualize by the
right it is i don't get the question mentions stands for receiver operating characteristic it's
totally obsolete
this is this comes from a signal detection theory has its roots in the second
world war one
very many things do
but that's just treat this as an issue without real
so what you can do do is basically
if you want to visualize performance
the main idea is to be
constitution in in each leaf is that
so for instance this the vector for
four of them on the right is the vision of the two
this is the right
and if you see that was
the ranking order
that could like this
and this is a bit like or you know that was
the about
the wealth distribution so service a twenty percent of people
eighty percent of the
and that's the similarity is so when you could you say something like
you can say things like the numbers on the right you can say things like
forty percent of the negatives
together with six
and of course you want that
b so that basically
when the ROC curve comes from
so in this what you see
it's on the vertical axis you've both examples on the
for example you know some of the
essentially the
all of these offices classifier
you may be more used to actually not having as numbers on the axes
relative numbers namely
you're you're probably used
one of the very few which is the absolute number of
possibly not yet
right so instead
the previous era we would say
in the next the same four out of ten positive examples so we have point
four and true positive rate use except for
this has confused me for a long time here is how i got to grips
with this
i now switch very freely between these two perspectives and the reason is that
if you do
the ROC analysis thank you essentially
distribution of the population and yourselves in your space likelihood ratios
so it's the thing that you multiply with the prior
to get posterior
so this is if you want to racial because you
the prior of the distribution of the equation
this wrong
your thing
if you instead want posterior odds
then you want to
in then this space is this the right place to work and now know can
using it with equal suspicion so it doesn't matter
but you can imagine that if you have a little distribution this space will be
coming back to the rest of the world
just i just choose whatever seems most appropriate the patient and most of the the
stuff that actually use the absolute numbers of interest there are
this is sometimes called coverage space and before possible PN space that
i used the whole
these rocks space is important to distinguish between the two
as you know we have again
presidential elections this year in slovenia
and as you know we have seven candidates for
president but
some time ago
we had about eighty eight presidents
that was in
ninety seven
and these are the names
and then t slovenia decided to
organised debates
eight evenings
and the are three candidates
to appear to each evening
they have
yeah that was
it was running in
two weeks
friday is already can so nothing there
and then the next week again monday
tuesday wednesday thirteen so there were two weeks
three candidates each week
and what happened is one evening in TV studio
there are three candidates
two serious ones and then
one which is not listed this
and there are seven days later
the same two serious candidates appeared and then the
there's a guy
who was not important so
a colleague of mine dragon the shelter
letter to the editor
saying that they should ask mathematicians
why can't they
this evening's debate so that each candidate
it would appear at most
each pair of candidates with appear at most once
so if you ask mathematicians
we could have solved the problem for you so the question is can we group
the eight candidates into eight triples in such a way that no no two of
them will meet more than once
if you want to
so this
the problem you have to find
to make sure
so what we are asking is that there exist it's three
configuration combinatorial configuration
and it turns out there is exactly one of its three combinatorial configuration is called
images configurations so here you may view
o point
eight points of the candidates it lies are TV debates
for instance
if you have such a debate
that would be the first
evening with these three guys
what is meant but then you could schedule differences so that they would meet these
two guys were not meet twice just once
but who knows
history cannot be
we know
who wants
and let me just give you a surprising connection
if you look at this
no presidential
media coverage of presidential election
what we're going to learn is there is a very deep connection
to this
three-dimensional sculpture that is now
technical museum in this
and here is just part of it because it represents the drawing of the graph
on the other tourists
and that the graph is related
to that
maybe this kind of configuration actually
it's not just the graph
is the group itself
so here
the vertices
to the automorphisms
of that
so there is a very deep connection between geometry
what we mean by the air
and which for this particular example you wind up with an estimate of the standard
of the estimate of tau
o point one five one
that's what the distribution of tau values looks like
that's already kind of interesting because what is this curve remind you of
this is sort of gaussians
shaped curve
the data
i have nothing to do with the gas in distribution the data are exponentially distributed
but notice that the estimator itself
is proportional
two of some
of the data values
and there's fifty terms in the summer and recall with the central limit theorem says
it says that if you take a sum of random variables in the limit that
there's a large number of terms in that some of the resulting
value will follow calcium distribution and so that's what we're seeing here and in fact
it's a very general property of maximum likelihood estimators is that for sufficiently large number
of events first sufficiently large data sample
the distribution of the maximum likelihood estimator
asymptotically approaches a calcium distribution very important property
all right so so that's one way of
doing your error analysis to actually write a monte carlo programme to simulate the experiment
there are other ways
and there's another way
it is to use what's called the information inequality sometimes also called the
kramer fresh air inequality are CF inequality
this is an inequality which sets a lower bound on any estimator not only estimators
from the maximum likelihood method but this is the lower bound on the variance of
any estimator
and in in the case where i have just a single parameter the formula is
the following
the variance of any estimator theta had must be greater than or equal to
one plus
the derivative with of the bias with respect to the parameter square
divided by the expectation value
of the negative of the second derivative of the log likelihood function
kind of long formula but was not too bad the kind of thing we can
work out very
easily in many cases
in many problems the biases these are small
negligibly small or in some cases even identically zero so the numerator is very often
just one
furthermore in many problems of practical interest
even though i said that this is an inequality
very often a quality
approximately holds
that is to say that the some approximation i can replace this greater than equal
to sign by
an equal sign or approximately equal size
and in that case
so if i can neglect the bias and if i can regard that as an
approximate equality that means that i can estimate the variance of my
estimator by minus one over the expectation value of the second derivative
of log l
find so actually
that expectation value is a function of the true and unknown parameters i need some
way of
estimating the variance
of the estimator of the parameter so the way you can estimate this is simply
by evaluating the second derivative
of the log likelihood function
maximum likelihood estimator
so that's the formula that you can use in practice two to get the error
bar to get the square root of that we give you the standard deviation of
data had and that's the that's the number the report
as the statistical error
four for your parameter estimates you do i have another example
i should mention here that many of you have probably used route or mean we
argmin we within route to to do some sort of parameter fitting
and you'll notice that when you do the parameter fitting at the end of the
exercise it will spit out some number to the screen that calls the statistical error
and you might ask yourself where is it coming up with that number
and the answer is what it's doing is it's making a couple of assumptions it's
assuming that the bias is zero it's assuming that you can you can put equal
sign there and what route is doing is simply evaluating the second derivatives of the
likelihood function numerically
and using that to basically give you the standard deviation of your parameter estimates so
that somehow is the mathematics behind what route is doing what it gives you the
errors in if it
now we can use this formula as the basis of another
method which are called the graphical methods
and the idea is the following
is it if you
i wish i had a black would actually make a drawing but just use my
hands but you can imagine that the
the log likelihood function is some curves that comes up and goes down
is very often have sort of parabolic shape
and there will be some value of the parameter for which it is the maximum
the value of data for which the log likelihood function is the maximum that's that's
the ML estimator that had so what i want to do now is to expand
the log likelihood function
in a taylor series about its maximum
so say the log likelihood function is logo of data had
plus there's the first derivative terms
with data miners that had
and there is the second derivative term with
miles that's where and so forth
let me stop there let me just take the second order and stuff
right now
the first term was the first term log l of data had by construction that's
that's the maximum of logo because of define had to be the value of data
for which l
is maximal
so therefore the second term is zero
right because the derivatives of log l has to be zero at the maximum
and the third term
this is the second derivative of log l
with respect to the parameter value at the ML estimator
but for that
i can flick back and use the formula that i had on the previous over
here i can relate that to the to the variance of my estimator
OK so if i take that formula and use i use that
to replace
the probability of one because if t one is equal to hand
we can add that you this situation
or this situation
what's the probability of this
i work for
what's the probability of
one four
that's what it
this is exactly the marginalization
that t one
is equal to heads
is equal to the sum
over the values of t
of p of p one
because two had
p two
if the two
is equal
we have p
you are because had
because to head
if the two
two one
because had
because that
that's exactly what marginalization
is it what you know
of course in this case
very very simple why because these two rivals i made them
so in fact when asked what the probability of q when he calls it you
could think immediately is one happen because it doesn't
what happens the other in some cases these viruses will be
in fact some cases you have to three
before and after tn
when you have an network of dependency things by
how do you compute
will see all the
it's fine it's quite
so we say that
we say that
XA and XB
they are independent
if this holds
for all x a
we see that
a b
in the thing
he said to run bibles is independent
for every realisation of these two run
these holes
that's the correct way to write what i've written
it's more formal way to write to be the slide
this is
the definition
now the definition of conditional independence i mean this is critical to the critical the
of this causing it to understand
the good thing that is very simple
conditional independence is just independent
however we require that we have
and observe conditions these on some of
if you look at this expression
p of a
and c
is equal to p of
x a
next that
you fix
equation here is exactly the same as these equations just that
we put a bottleneck c
in every time
never effect
these are our sense
census number one of ring theword
they're not very consistently used it's
not a very good system i think around sense
in addition
a short
there you have very little relies on the sense number
if it were up to me and
removes that argument to change
great company which
i mean it
the senses hearing some
then their meaning
so i think
the fact that
one appears in these two positions
symbolizes something
this is the same
a sense of the word
but if they denote not different concepts for exactly what it means to be the
the sense of the word ending but you could also say something like sense number
ring theword
is the preferred sense
i think it may be that was what they had in mind not
no i mean i guess it's good to have a structure that the
the average but not much is made of
returns numbers
so here's an another example
the singular
but the number has
both that can be both the count noun and mass noun
this is a very now
we do have review on count nouns versus mats nouns
but on the really account people are also ring is accounted one ring two rings
sand is a
the last known
two stands
coke can be either and that's
now so
and seventy can have
only mass nouns take determiner somewhere
plural marking on the noun
you can say can i have some ring
unless you're trying to be funny
he is the
so called universal grinder which
of count nouns into mass nouns
red sands mass nouns you can say can i have some sand although i don't
know i would ask sand and
since coke is ambiguous
it allows books
so coke
as as numbers is a station on it
signifying that the mass noun form of coke theword
it's this thing
but to be
the singular form as well
and singular
goes along with
count now
then then called is also proper noun
so it has
proper now massnumber
as well as proper noun singular
in its proper
how announced
it means one serving of so
i bought a coke
is the sentence in which the
sense appears
there are c
this is an example
thought that take singular agreement when you is it is susceptible to every other laboratories
developing a new
the united states
a big
but there are there are proper nouns that take
laurel agreement i can
example the moment
it it's that's
sort of an issue
she when linguistics
dealing with for all proper nouns this
the motivation for
overhauling house the predicament it's done
generation system
so should be able to come up with an example
i'm not able to
and so
the animals are playing
well that's british
right so in and british
you use
plural for
cope with difficult
in the sea
words that denote groups collective entities
the parliament has decided
it's OK alright let's get back
i have some coke
the capital c
that sentence
right coke
and back in those days i got and i that the people that were doing
that program actually
to some people at stanford i was actually going on at the stanford research institute
down the road from stanford and they needed statistical help they asked me if i
would be a consultant i got involved in
since i was the only statistician working on this i kind of became the statistician
for the various laboratories around the world that we're doing research
in this area so it actually continued to consult in this area
throughout the years
and as i watched the evidence mounts i also noticed something very interesting psychological sociological
phenomenon which is that
most people ignore the data
most people have prior beliefs
if i asked people have shown the data and said
which would be more convincing to you
another set of statistical studies or one
overwhelming personal experience most people said the personal experience
would be more convincing so here's a case where we had
this mounting statistical evidence that was pretty much been ignored
so this makes it a natural topics in bayesian statistics and i think it's like
i said i was an excellent example for hypothesis testing
so why the bayesian
OK first of all i think there a philosophical reasoning and practical reasons
the philosophical reason is that
the bayesian interpretation of probability actually makes more sense in some situations
the relative frequency interpretation doesn't always apply as you know
so this is just a quick example suppose i in the united states it turns
out that about fifty one point two percent birds are boys
so relative frequency interpretation would be that for
conception the probability that
the then birth will be a boy point five one two
but now suppose woman's pregnant
she doesn't know the sex of her baby but she said it has done so
her doctor does not the sex of baby
now what's the probability that's going to be a boy
it's zero one
is it still point five point two
well it to the woman it's probably still points i want to because she doesn't
but the doctor now so it's either zero or one
so there's a case where bayesian interpretation makes perfect sense it's your degree of belief
the outcome
and then what about non repeatable situations the probability of an earthquake in california something
that we pay attention to the probability of an earthquake here is something want to
pay attention to those are personal or subjective at lists
probabilities because it's not here are completely repeatability that we can't face the probability and
relative frequency
so that's part of the philosophical reason continuing
we all know the p values are not we want them to be our students
things are different than what they are in most cases we would all love to
be able to say that what's the probability that the null hypothesis is true
that's not true value as you know
but you can do that sort of thing bayesian methods
and also people who are highly dependent on sample size we also know
and most people don't understand that
bayesian methods make more sense here as well because there you keep adding data and
keep updating your beliefs or your information
so amazing results actually assess things that we would like to know about it
practical reasons
it's actually rare that we don't have any prior information so just two example suppose
we walk we go into new community where public health worker
we want to estimate the
prevalence of HIV infection in that community
well if we're frequentist we start out assuming it could be anything from zero to
one but that's not really true we know that's not true
and know what the community is probably have a pretty good idea
these range that might fall into
whispers right estimate the mean change in blood pressure after programme in meditation
do we really think it could be anything from minus infinity to infinity
probably not
so it makes sense sometimes leads to incorporate prior expert opinion into our analysis
these days most statistical analyses are done as a collaboration between statisticians
knowledge experts so why not take advantage of that expert knowledge and incorporated into the
now course having said all that i mean not bayesian myself
i do that with one
OK so on this topic i do think because bayesian methods are being used more
and more these days in other fields i do think it's time that we start
talking about them in our courses i'm not sure about the really basic level introductory
course i think is already too much they're getting another talking eleven o'clock session where
i'm going to talk about things i think we should include their we don't but
about one or two
percentage points
as a soft margin increases then my performance degrades are typically go from minimum OK
that was cl one
error norm and this is the other one the web and on a post small
positive quantity
to the
contract law
and course when zero that lambda equal zero
i have my normal what i call hard margin
svm the soft bond became a course that to have seven
percent error on test data
i introduce the alpha OK
goes to a minimum
around about five point three
and then starts climbing because of obvious if used to holiday
soft margin then the i degrade performance OK so we do see the introduce yourself
margin lessens the effect of noise and actually improves performance test error is reduced typically
with noisy data
now there's justification for those two
largely comes from learning theory says well very
to date the picture i can give you is of a sort of relaxation of
the hard margin constraint they introduced earlier on
indeed what we're gonna do just have a look at the l one error norm
and you may remember
from the first lecture
but i had the following conditions
here this thing here constraint came from my canonical hyperplane idea
so that was missing OK
so in my picture
which i have
for the sphere
i had the following
my two types of data
plus plus plus plus
minus minus minus minus minus etcetera
and i had to a separating hyperplane
and indeed this sort of zone here
i call the marching band so this was the margin
and so the zone here was it would be called the marching band
one do now is actually allow
for some data points to actually be within the margin band on the k
on the far side had this anomalous data point given in blue
he could be appointed which can be within the margin band sound like a band
like this OK so here he is going to allow him i can indeed actually
allow him to be on the wrong side altogether OK just a few data points
which could be these outliers
can be in the marching band or even can be
wrongly classified OK
now i choose an idea
by introducing this site here
so here was called slack variable
and if that is about point five
then rather like here
is within the margin band
and if that was greater than one
he would actually be on the wrong side altogether so it actually get married during
my training process but it could be a good idea because it like kinases sample
could be just totally wrongly labelled data point OK
so that's how i relax the hard margin condition when choosing the slack variables
in other words my optimisation task
it will be the following previously without that slack variable i didn't have this term
i wanted to minimize
W's www that was my condition to maximize the margin
but now i've got this extra term OK
because what we really want to do
it is i want to maximize the margin
like so
one of the same time i don't be over-generous with the number of points which
within the margin band or to erroneous
so try penalize that's all trying to minimize the sum of such errors
i call these errors OK
minimizes to
while also doing my expected maximizing the margin my c
with the trade-off
between these two
i could really
they take c infinity
i get rid of these all together
as being
spinning out five
into some of its consequences
however these are all logical consequences
if we can always decide
formulas like this valid
one of the things we have to do is turn their back on this tour
machine gun
with the other side
by effectively checking in nine number steps
whether or not
particular consequences like such and such a machine halts
is in this theory
but then putting it back here
we would have managed once again to find a way of determining the nature an
arbitrary turing machine hold
just so it's not possible
so just the same way
it's not possible
they have decidability in first order logic
that's the general intention of the argumentation
created gigantic mapping
between turing machines and formulas of first-order logic
which allows us to
this is something like a universal machine
and something like moves in the game
as in the game of carrying out state industry machine
logical consequence here in first order logic
we're going to carry out
in particular
inference particular derivations to prove this works
there is such a mapping when OK otherwise two
because we know it's pointless
because if we were to do it by
when using this thing here
the figure out whether germany she health that we would have once again get out
of holding machine holding problems so it's not
the theorem would be
the decision problem for property there is solvable with his mechanical test
the and eventually classifies every object correctly one way or another
OK classifiers correctly
as having the property or not
the theorem is that that's not so that there is not a solution to that
and the proof idea
is that
is a very grand reductio
assuming that there is such a test
then we would be able to find out that an arbitrary turing machine
could have halted we would be out
we would have a solution in general to the halting problem for our future machine
which can be done
i'm just going to go through now
take this sort of general idea of this mapping
could just gets
messy enough that you know that you would only want to follow it to prove
if you had
book in front of you and your training step twenty one so finally
and not one but you certainly
like a big formulas and what sort of stuff it's not the
the actual
steps and that had been given in the text we're talking about
well sorry some course
so let's say i'm just reading out seeing if i can
go with the flow here keep your eyes on the head or whatever understand
so i not a few places i
this is not in new know and not
you know
these pages
i particularly didn't number so that everything else is still numbering ca
this is one of the things that i added later tried to
today still here
what's the story
OK let's not start out with such a grand
the notion as a universal turing machine or paying particular mind about whether to universal
now let's just imagine we got description of turing machine
when the flag graph
that's a little bottle things
k flowgraph machine type whatever it's got states it's got symbols
and it's got an important
it's a it's trying to compute function
and it's the machine and
it's got
input end
and we want to turn that into first order logic
what we do is we construct a whole bunch of sentences
which takes textbook away following called delta
so we construct
to describe
the operation of
we construct
a second school here i
which describes the lies in which is machine could stop
particular dissolve and sensors
these are just sentences in first-order logic with
particular vocabulary corresponding to the traditional
construct a ge informally corresponding to
in which
actually always
which includes stop
that's not so hard to do i just continue to say that
you know let's do that
it's the second one is and so had to
remember i said in the discussion of turing machine
if you think it is a big matrix
with all the states here
and the symbols it's reading here
the ways in which the machine could stop would just be
places where
there was a whole
nothing to do next
no work to be done
if it ever gets to state q five
and it happens to be reading s eleven
sorry this is solution
and that's blank the description machine title
well in the machine stops
so i je
would just be the disjunction of the whole of the blanks in this type
this title is found
OK maybe all states and all symbols but it's quite it's fun title there's an
infinite number of ways in which machine
don't get this confused with fear and with the machine actually reaches one of those
we can sign advance what is like to hold
well we don't know is if a particular machine in operation whatever get the
you might never find itself in q five might be part of the description
that doesn't mean have achieved that
particular combination of circumstances
i je there is a big disjunction essentially all cells
so it's a description of
description cell
you know a blank cell one
i mean
description of blank cell two
how many thanks cells are
we take a machine
we can construct to the circumstance in which i je
since h circumstance in which a sentence
i'm told you that delta going do that in a second
so just go on
and if someone is only interested in the classification at level six let's say whether
or not i misclassified something that belongs in one
in class two then it doesn't matter because they don't
number six wakes for that person that mistake doesn't even make a difference right so
that's kind of the idea behind it and then the way we model this as
a structured output in kind of this SVM struct problems basically that we took
feature vector for so this is the tensor product idea we take a feature vector
for the class is basically the way we describe the classes is by
indicator functions of the successor nodes so and then also the themselves are also so
it's kind of service reflexive relations offences there's no number two it's it's kinda related
to itself to number six and number nine so you get entries there at position
two six and nine
in this spectral representation k and
right so you have two six nine right and this number three
so you have an entry at three seven nine and ten so so in some
sense what these things now do is actually they
described to think of it as attribute of the classes right the fact that the
particular class it's below node number ten is a particular property of that class can
you make it explicit in this in this vector here and then you have whatever
you have for your x representation of documents right you just stuck it in there
so basically
if you do the tensor product but if you do the tensor product sort of
what happens is that it could just transported transport you copy over that vector into
the positions that are to have a one here
and you can see this here and then you know in order to evaluate this
in approach we talked about this before
you know get the inner product between the documents but also between the classes
and what you basically what you basically do is now you can learn across classes
so you could even have classes that have no training example right just so that
you conception understand what's going on but you know you have properties of these classes
and you can try to generalize to new classes that have similar properties in classes
that you know and you could still try to come up with a meaningful score
for the new class
so so anyway and then you can also combine it with with the tree loss
as i said before you loss function is actually
taking the tree into account
and then we did some analysis on
actually this might qualify dataset pattern databases publicly available and then we compare the two
and we found like some improvement using the structured approach was on the order of
what we get the are five to ten percent so it was not a huge
but it was particularly significant if if you if you're in a sparse data setting
where the number of training examples per leaf node is very small OK and that
right so this is this is also an example of
where you can use the SVM struct you can basically just plug in directly
now this the next problem that i want to show here
binary classification with unbalanced classes OK so
it's it's a problem
in many applications but definitely in
in text categorisation information retrieval that often you have classes but there's only a relatively
small number of positive examples or the fraction of like your prior probability of getting
a positive example is small
compared to getting a negative one right so
there is also true for something like you know the IPC with a large category
taxonomy right just
if you have sixty thousand classes and achieved if each document gets assigned to one
or maybe two classes
primary and secondary that it just means that
you know for each
you only have a small number of positive examples and lots of negative right so
it's not uncommon that the positive examples have a probability that's less than one percent
and so the problem now is that if you use the classification error to train
these things right and you get the degenerate
the classification function that classifies everything is negative then already you get ninety nine plus
percent accuracy
right and on less than one percent error unfortunately
this is not very helpful because you know your classifier does is basically saying no
to everything so you never get enough so it looks good according to classification error
but it's really useless classifier so what people have done that of course is they
look at other scores right so you can use the one score for instance when
you look at precision and recall OK and basically the you know two times precision
recall divided by the sum so its harmonic mean and you can try to optimize
that and other things like precision recall breakeven point so
that has always been well known right but what people have often done is
basically they just trained their classifier using classification loss and then in the end they
just reported
you know the good news of the classifier on these other metrics right but if
you care about these these
you know the f one score the question is why don't you optimize only the
f one score right away
well the problem is that if you look at the f one score right it
depends on
basically you know you will write something like the ordering of pluses and minuses is
one one neuron and the index j indicates another neuron so here and representing only
one neuron right so so i don't have indexes for
four white
for simplicity
here's the update rule of having just says that you know if you have correlation
activities then increase the weight
so the reason i'm presenting this very simple rule that is not used
so much in practice since
except that you need for present twelve united by approach is that you can very
easily understand with this simple rule
how the kernel trick works
the country is the basis for a lot of algorithms of chrome method algorithms
and it shows that there is a correspondence between the perceptual representation and the kernel
based representation so the two you know
learning machines have been presenting you the percent
and the kernel methods they can actually
be representing the same decision function how is this going happening
well considering happens rule that i was just mentioning to you but applied to the
perception so the weight vector is going to be a weighted sum
of the y i phi of x i so how is this if you go
back one slide you see that if you use this update rule if you reinforce
always the weight according to the product of y and you know whatever it's plugging
into x i j
then if you will the training examples
in the end you will be having something which is proportional to the of the
y and the y i x i j
i'm running the sum running over all the i
so for all the training some by every time you show the new training example
you're going to reinforce all the connections according to products of the outcome
and the inputs
and in the end you just something a weighted sum so for the case of
the simple had one is just a few short link every example only once you're
going to be just having the sum of all the examples of the y i
phi of x i so replacing the inputs by the phi functions
and so this special way of calculating the weight vector
makesthings very simple
because now
since f of x is you know the dot product between w andphythen
you can plug in
this form of w into here and expand and you obtain
this new
form of the decision function in very interestingly you can exhibit the fact that now
your weighted sum is running over dot products of your phi i
which are the phi
computed for all the training samples and your phi of x
and so if you define now in new
OK of x i and x as you know this dot product then you can
transform your phi f of x into the sum now not over the phi functions
but over the k functions
right so
you have shown here that by the mere fact that using this perhaps will yield
a weight vector
which is the weighted sum
of the original
templates original patterns so each example it's training sample enters with the positive weight if
you why i are you know plus and minus one right if your outputs are
are binary then this simply means that all the examples of the positive class are
added all the examples of the negative class are subtracted and this is the way
you compute your w vectors in awaits very twenty right if you want to compute
for each feature
the weight with which are going to be
calculating your decision function
what you don't like you know is that you say well the weight is going
to be
the difference between the frequency of of how often i see my feature positive and
how often i see my feature negative right so all the features positive added together
and all the negative ones are added and subtracted and this is how you calculate
the weight
of course there are you know much fancier ways of calculating the weight this absolutely
does not take into account possible redundancies right if you have many examples that are
similar you don't necessarily want to all add them up you might want you to
consider that once you've seen one type of example you don't want to again add
so information Dimitria we're not
explained you because you mean you presentation to of information geometry Jews grabs stunning squeezes
the walk of the high that
the bride and therefore receives an average height next euro on walks along last addition
to read only a school that certain factored in Baghdad and that could be good
news could be defined by factional output slows it could be that different users to
of these exploration
on you could also will introduce the classical music in Baghdad announced by the a
fact that you convert community approach
on using distilling from not to change the of sophisticated Baghdad
which is bereft important that this issue to which makes it inquisitive tension don't also
mission that Iraq where you could see that it will have suggested the characteristic functional
not generating function effectively could've said that it could buy Getty the demise of the
generating function on India's uniting function could be be obtained by this operation just 2
of the situation where are you out of the to seasonings with theory in the
Commission humidity will you you you use a suspension below also mission
when we try to apply that's good information geometry uh which is even basic places
would use of differential which we even by the future all official may take all
it discussed it to provide basic become almost supervisors metric system Italy's as what which
is in the office of the metrics on when you apply these definitions from action
did we should know because it will mean you have these equations has the task
of a test of air at the area where are you could upset of using
the island by injections so the distance between that this is not a word to
the distance to the end of the match on you as extension falls amid United
which procedures this expression and you couldn't sales that 1 is a classic demanded the
distance because when you consider and you will have to press to men and the
so if you want to integrate the midfield in fact we have basic questions said
starts we Salo also square also look at it was extended begin value between the
2 life is also a value of these countries could use in that state commutes
between the maturation of investors might wanna come by that the we're seeing my once
he went to met to what virtuosic worked well on all the systems is equipped
people so it is also rates he too was dry left in geometry which has
been presented by Mr. unmarried so you in case of
like pollution godlike oddity stand on potential functions identifying to cut its stake so you
can coordinate you can give to a different system for the meeting I did push
you extract the subset f one with the
we these smaller than n
so that
all functions are similar to atleast one of these functions
right so it
picture is simple
you have again you can consider
a set of function some object or some subset of a metric space
among these functions so
actually here we're considering finally many but
it doesn't matter so among all these finite many functions
you isolate
a subset of them
the idea of them such that
every other function is at least
sorry at most distance
here i denoted alpha
of one of these functions
which means that if you were to draw circles
the geometry may may not be
euclidean geometry there but if you were to draw balls if you want around
if i i d then you would
cover the whole space so all functions would be in one of these rules
so that's the notion of color
and once you've done that
you can apply
the result
that we seen just before and say well if i want to control the deviation
for any function in the set
i first
find out what is the closest function
among these cover
if one of the
and i see the deviation will be those of
this function
this little alpha
and when i do that
i get so what i call covering number bayes bounds
i can replace
so the log cardinality of the set by
alpha times the locality plus
i have to count how many functions i have in my cover and this usually
denoted by the end of the which is the number of functions i need to
cover my space of two x two accuracy alpha
so this concerts can be done
even if you're a set of functions the function you set stimuli but you can
extract a subset
four which all functions are similar to at least one point in that subset
and then what we control the rate of convergence of your empirical process will be
the behaviour of beams and these covering numbers and
rule of some
is that
more less
covering number at scale alpha
four spades for like if you imagine a cube
in dimension d
and of alpha is
one of the fact that right so if you want to cover the cube of
dimension d with balls
you need something like
one of
to the d when outside the radius of these balls and see the cube the
unit cube
so this is an and what interest in the bound is the logarithm of that
so that's why
and that's something you obtain the logarithm of this is something like
the times log
one of
and if you plug it in the bounds of something like
square root of the log at one of our power so
the message here is that
if your space of functions where
so your subset
of the unit cube in some space of dimension d
so for example if you have a linear functions with the parameters
then you would have some some of the older square root of the over
despite this trick you know
you can actually go even further and further than that and repeat this construction so
here i was using only one scale i think
it i covered my class with balls operators and
but if you want to
it was
if you want to
capture a little bit more of the structure of q plus you can
iterate this construction
compute covers at all possible
registry actually you start by
covering your space was big balls
and then
you cover with smaller bills
and you do that
so four let's say four alpha of the form two to the miners k where
is from one two
infinity so it's in figure
or you stop at some level maybe
and what you do is now
you look at the centers of all these rules
of the small balls and all of the big ones and when you when you
have a function to for which you want to control the deviations you first look
at the closest function in the
the smallest
and then you approximate this function again by larger one
i mean from by a point in the larger cover and so on so you
construct what is called the chain and that's what is the
the value of things called chamber it's you construct the chain that goes from
the function space
centres of covers
of larger and larger edges and eventually we end up in the centre of the
whole space
again this is the picture that does not really correspond to the true reality because
you're not in the euclidean space the space of functions can be very
we are in no way
but this is give you the right information
and if you do that if you do this chain you can actually show that
the relevance notion of complexity that enters the barn is of this form this integral
of the square root of long enough
so it will again depend on the rate
of convergence and the rate of growth sorry
of the covering numbers
it's one of the symmetric space
thank for would whole
but not enough to specify that it means the inner product is finite dimensional
which is not the case for and it will be
but if you have a very large and
this is a view of the whole
so for you
the function space
what do
one of
all o
o eight
and here
first of all
how say
that said
it is
so you know it
they don't
if i hear
it turns out
now we can
all right
redand green pointstrying toinfer the restwe've done some integrating out so weno
longer have themuse visiblewe don't care about those we simply care about
whether or not a X is matched toone of the Ys so that's the
existence of these matching links noticethere arered pointsthat arenot observedand there are green
points that are not observed and we still care about that matching and the transformation
though I've actually assume now of course thatit's a straightline so lookquite hard I think
and thensorry alright I'm gonna assume no more noise from now
on you can do you know the other settings as well bu that this is a
Sphaeroccocusian noise and essentially this is this this termis what it is doingis reallycapturing
you would'vemeassure erroractually fundingthisoccasion and in the data but also the idea if
we think about is thesehidden point models being somehow the origin of whatthese proteins areof
their shapethen we're saying that over time of evolutionary proteins there's been some disturbances to
the to the originalpattern somaking allthose assumptions that simplifying assumption weget we
now have the basic thing we need for bayesian analysis a joint distribution of the
unknowns and the data so theunknowns are the matching matrix the linearpart
and the translation part of thetransformationthe variants of this noble
disturbances and later itself andit has that that structure and you could possiblyget to
this model from from other placesbut but I think this hidden hidden
process generation of this model is quite an attractive way to think about it
noticethe form it has this is basically all to do with prior stuff the
thethere's a Jacobian there to do with the transformation of theY space
and then the main thinginhereis you have a product over the matched pairs
so that's something you know we don't knowit's not a fixed number of terms there and what you
see here is basically a product oftwo thingsso youcan think of it as
a ratioof two things reallyit's to do with expressing the completing competing explanations so
we don't quite know how to match so wh wh giventhink of it
thisway givenA andwe'vefind X J and this transformed version of Y KA are
in close proximity andthere's two possibilitiesthere either they are matched and that's
captured by thislike thisdensity function all this happened to be close
coincidentally so remember that lambda was the background rated hidden points so if there's a
loss of hidden pointsthe coincidentalexplanation is more likely and that's gonna lower
this joint probability so I thinkit makes some senseokay so how can
you make inference with his model wellthere's a number of different approachesyou
can useofEM type of algorithms of variousyou know trading descentorcoordinate wise version to gradient
descent and indeed you could use those with or without a prior information
and you'd get a solution but actually they are not trivial they're still quite
a big algorithmicload andeasier than what I'm about to suggestbut
notthey're not trivialsowe'll what we do isgo straight into this
to do thatM C M C sampling and that raises a couple of interesting issues
so we have thisI'm not going to suppose that theA matrix is
a rotation so it's a rigid body transformationnow it's not a general transformationthere's no
scale changethere's no skewingit's just a rotation and a translation that's a rigid body
rot rotationthe effect of that is thatdeterminant of A is one so that simplifies
things but the main point is this it turns out that theyunder the
Gaussianassumptionthe the conditional distributionfor Athe unknown rotation given the matchingthen the other
parameters has thisformit involvesA in aquite a simple way we have whatever
mention that i later in that session
so spectral clustering and racially processes
i think one thing modern sort of interesting things spectral clustering
i think it's really interesting but i don't know what the i don't understand what
the theoretical foundation is enough to see how that's being pushed forward i mean i
think we seem to have a bit of the doldrums at the moment good technique
but i don't know where it's going to reshape prices lots of people are working
on these various different things it's sort of bayesian nonparametric approach to clustering
so finally so my
the topic dimensionality reduction
one could also equally as a latent variable models and i just one
a little bit why dimensionality reduction is important so far everything i've shown is really
a trivial toy examples are well and this will be fairly trivial to hopefully the
one of the the things that's missing is something i think is really important and
that's the
very often
you're working with very high dimensional data so
a lot of these things
i'm drawing on the boards of very deceptive
you can understand three-dimensional dataspaces very well
and two dimensional space very well but in high dimensional data a lot of intuitions
collapse and i've done tutorials and that which themselves take a a couple of hours
so i'm not going to be too much that today
but i want to give an illustrative example of something like sometimes used try and
justify why dimensionality reduction is important and what can happen high dimensional data space so
this is the six digit our favorite machine learning data datasets we like to use
them all the time to demonstrate our algorithms
it from the USPS
and it's got three thousand six hundred forty eight dimensions so x in this case
is all the pixels in this image and i sixty four rows and fifty seven
columns so it's a very high dimensional
eight point but having said that that is not extraordinarily high dimensional if you look
at the say text datasets with using words the features you've got some minimum six
thousand there was for some applications and you may have many more so a microarrays
twenty five thousand genes so an extraordinary
for the sort of things we might try
OK so the problem with these spaces is they contain just more than one digit
right so
in this is one way of modelling the digit would be to have the probability
for each pixel being all independently so i'm going to model this it by saying
well i'm going to count how many pixels are on and how the probability for
each pixel being on which is the proportion of black pixels over white pixels and
then i'm going to sample
right so sampling from my model and here is a sample from my mother
within that space within that modelling space is obviously a lot more than this one
digit and in fact even if we sample every nanosecond from now until the end
of the universe you won't ever see the original six
the chances of becoming the space is so vast in terms of the dimensionality that
we're exploring how to model the so-called you will never see that six i mean
there's more possible samples in that image than there are particles in the observable universe
many many many times more
those spaces are kind of extraordinary
so the things you and these things provide problems because we're trying to explore the
space is sometimes with probabilistic models we got to some of the spaces that size
thing i want to say there is another sample and look it wasn't the original
six so that proves my point
so here is another way of thinking about how you should be modelling in those
spaces and it's one that i used to motivate dimensionality reduction so you can rotate
a prototype so his approach type six what we do is say walking model by
considering rotations
well six
now the interesting thing about that is we can project
what we can do is we can look in that space that is formed by
all those sections being rotated around and it's kind of interesting because this is the
linear two-dimensional projection
so that space is again three thousand six hundred forty eight dimensional but i found
the two-dimensional projection which is just the circle and i'm trying to show what these
images are so is this article because we just rotated
and this looks very one-dimensional so actually what's going on is three thousand six hundred
we just covered several different methods
actually just for value functions
before from from other comments made the claim that you have to the q function
is not value function OK sessions surprising there's also a method for controlling temporal difference
approaches control meaning you want to optimize policy
they used to control the process
that is exactly
the same as the value of the we saw earlier isabella to use
two values in place of
q values also known actions in place of your
you're just state advisory so previously
so it's a again look like in the coming war
in the gamma
for the
gamma time the q value for the next stage
with the a priori actually would take the next and the current policy
but he does it to athens tournaments method with
two is
OK so just see this as TV for q functions now
so one might wonder why this
the album's called source
i have to admit that i spent maybe in our two in vain searching for
this man named source
only to later realize and i read the book that sources stands for state action
reward state action
so yes so we have a current state and action get a reward given xt
next action source
but it is the it's just TD
temporal difference
approach for
two values such you can actually what that q values recall you can take to
maximize the action reinstate determine the best policy
now more theoretical importance if you know of reinforcement learning you may know about q
learning this is probably the most exciting temporal difference methods this is probably the most
well-known algorithms
i has a beautiful properties in theory no one use in practice
but let me me are all all introduce it just because of properties
instead of the sample back up so i sample state as prime and then i
look at the
action a prime under my current policy
four q learning
instead of choosing the action of macro policy actually just take the max over
often actions i can do this because i've got the q values
so if you do this update is because the previous update
this also converges to the optimal policy
to the other of the apple two values but more interestingly it doesn't require a
policy to be fixed
right there is no policy
or you don't have to fix policy
you can take any action many states
and this will still give you the optimal q values
and that's why it's so popular in a and so well known is the one
or lower than that doesn't require policy to find the FAQ values
no one uses it because
so in
the reason is
this one step updates
property values very so so so that the problem i'm going to give you also
applies to the to do this is the TD methods
that i discovered except that in primitive methods in a moment but you can particularly
OK so so let me let me let me give you some insight
imagine that i have a very long
change the world
and here is my goal
start there
and i think it all literally stated very simple actually i just go left to
now to make it all the way you write your water one
and if i may be one here
and then
thank you
one should also fail
so we need more
that's why
so just she was quite a bit
not all of
that is
that's the way to the people who
it may be
and then
that is my
it does and i here
the court
probably you know
the every
the main line
which is exactly the same way
this can also not
is there and i think
they are
the same way
so here we have some interesting because of
you know what
o twenty five
there are great
i think it's likely respect what you do it because want
it is
so before
first it was only two pictures
everybody agrees that features on the band
but even then it was sort of my
some pictures
by one person
quite number one hundred sixty four
especially in the
i don't know where
in my
so here is six
the reason why they are marked by
it's that passion
six thousand nine
the park is by one person
the collection
well it just that's why it's not so much
so we have two hundred images which are not lie about this and
every which was marked by someone who is great
every day
this image was where
it's possible
so far more than eighty percent of the vote
all the band
the only
the day pictures like
this one
i have exactly the same people
so there seems little
one of the people
i think that they are
things that
there no pictures
you also
similarly most of
there first some all my them is irrelevant
there's a lot of
but there are a lot of
i have also
so what
there is
pictures of the life span of just where i one person might one of the
and that
of participants
come the
there you
are some consider them not only have
i think the most probable the
and the
i give you my
there was
if you want