this is part of the
approach which is the discriminative which is that we don't care about the joint distribution
of modelling
i think we just want some function f of y given x
we the inputs and and give me some estimate whether it's spam and then we
went directly
so the generative approaches related to conditional density estimation probabilistic approach in order to
sometimes rest in in sense
so lets us zoom in on the
first case since this is a probabilistic talk and how to write down the generative
that's why the prior probability and the conditional
class priors and these are called
class conditional distributions condition
and the prior we usually use
promoting so say that the probability of life
if k is one
this just
constant and this one
and of course the posterior probability which were interested in is the
the posterior probability of y given x and our this is going to be the
most likely value of y given x
so this is the
in terms of the likelihood the data given the model
and the prior probability that two different one
this really don't want to use
the maximum likelihood classification which is a particular class which scientists
you can convince yourself
you know this is hard to make sure
you know i think situations in which extremely unlikely
you know that's a classic example of this the earthquake
you know in the third world
j for over the night
probability in artificial intelligence and when he wrote the book you think california is still
there is still a and so on
you know california
thanks chris so he said well let's say you have a nice house and the
house has an alarm alarm i activities earthquake shakes the hands are somewhat greater endurance
and you come home and you see that the alarm is ringing and you want
to know
you know it wasn't what i was working
and here you might have different likelihood of the people are going give was very
quickly and you know it was
so we also
even california
it is still much lower than prior to breaking has in the prior probabilities using
the series
so this is all in bed we're is by maximum likelihood
maximum likelihood in this case it's very easy to sort of the data into batches
by the class to take all the spam e-mail one box
all the songs you
fox and you know
prior probability by counting the size of the factors
in my training set i saw seven hundred spam messages and two thousand nine spam
messages so i think that the prior probability
you know spam is you know seven divided by
and then estimate the conditional probability of x given y separately within each patch
the spam emails
and we estimate our model x given spam
and we take all the non spam email we treat it as a completely separate
from the main effects given on
and the
estimate using maximum points and for each of these steps
prior and the conditional distributions we need to use some kind of regularisation parameters so
example with the points you don't want to the maximum likelihood estimate because i can
be very useful for a lot more to
so that's the general scheme here and
now i want to
tell about this idea of a relation which will help you avoid overfitting
so to avoid overfitting what you can do is essentially
priors on the the parameters of the class and the class conditional distributions
so the simplest thing to do is say oh i think some parameters are unlikely
in the parameters are likely to penalize parameters that were more likely
but the important thing you can do which is like putting a prior on but
it's a little bit more complicated in it's time some parameters together
the same of for example i think this parameter estimates
some probability some feature model is the same in five zero cost one
so what does that gives you more data for estimating the parameters you only have
one value announced separate value of course one so all the data for anything lots
of parameters and lots of classes in this parameter computer
and the third generalizations regularisation excuse me is that you can make factorizations independence assumption
it is so this is the regularisation we focus on
beginning saying well don't want to allow arbitrary
distribution of these distributions here q x y and the factorized so that says is
that this approach can
it's time to choose the distribution qx given y instead of putting in general
i think it is
it would was be talking about
this is the only way
OK hello everybody so
basically my my fundamental goal is to talk about independent component analysis but to begin
with i will first use some slides stolen from my co-author you are whole going
to talk about some that some kind of background things like principal components analysis which
is often confused with ICA and other kinds of stuff
this is the contents of this introductory part which takes something like one or two
hours actually have no idea perhaps depending also on your questions you may to interrupt
me at any time and ask because well i suppose i have an already well
what back what what's your back level of background knowledge on this i these subjects
i suppose it is also quite variable
so first i will show something some basic ICA examples of what is i see
all about
and then i will go into this kind of stuff like motivated optimisation especially multivariate
statistics in estimation theory that are necessary theoretical background
so it's a very nice illustration and probably i think also very impressive illustration of
what ICA does
so what we have we have settled
we originally had six images that you was see while but here we see some
mixtures of those images so i mean this make this grayscale images have simply been
linearly mixed by adding the grayscale values together with some certain random coefficients that we
don't know that the point is that it is possible to find the original images
without knowing the coefficients of all that mixing
so is we did that we have is this thing here
so six makes images and nothing else at all so can we find the original
well you may has you have made this with can this when compute do i
see you compute the independent components
so i see a means independent component analysis what you get is these six original
images which was some of them may look a bit weird that's because they have
been inverted the polarity has been invented and white have been
but still if you know that if you convert them back
and then well you will see that actually yes you you get
all of those original six original image
so in terms of statistical estimation what we have here is is a latent variable
model and these independent components are latent variables meaning here we will have something about
that a bit later on
and so this mixing was completely linear
now see a ICSI we got to consider here is completely linear methods in the
sense of
having completely new mixing
and here is another example of a bit more practical example
because you may not encounter that kind of linear mixing some images every day
but this is really about practical example where we have recorded brain activity electrical or
electromagnetic brain activity using a sensor
there has been a large number of sensors basically something like one or two hundred
sensors that are located on just outside of the head
so basically
these three last ones are just for reference i mean they are not really recorded
they are not really of interest but the point is that of these signals here
given some of the outputs of the sensors and what you can see is that
there's some kind of some kind some kind of mixing of certain kinds of phenomena
you see that's like this kind of stuff here
OK in many different senses
well into video you would think that this kind of me these signals make sure
lots the different kinds of interesting original signals
laser pointer
this OK
this is also very not
and a phallic symbols
this is actually a decision rather that practical application of ICA
people have done this kind of stuff for a couple of years and as an
example of what you might get here are some nine independent components that have been
estimated from that and if you analyse the for you will see that there are
actually some some of the independent components correspond to something like really independent sources of
well not necessarily in the brain some of these correspond to for example heart beat
and so on but then again
i see you will find some kind of underlying underlying sources of activity in
in this brain signals we will have more about this in that towards and so
and of this lecture
i see it has found application in many different application areas recently
here's a rather arbitrary list of those well for most probably the
and conscientious verses
not conscientious and careful is careless reliable versus undependable
a good way to think about these things is in terms of the of the
word oceans
o CEA and
the first letter captures openness conscientiousness extraversion
agreeableness and neuroticism
and the claim is those are four to five fundamental ways in which people
differ from one another
well why should we believe this why should we take this
very seriously
well there is actually some evidence for it
it seems
that some reliability
in that it's stable
over time
if you test people
over years by test your personality now under five traits and test you five years
from now
it will not change much
and once you pass the age of thirty
it's very stable indeed
if you think about your parents
and then give mum and dad a mental test on where they stand in each
of the five traits ten years from that moment that will still be there
it also
seems to get agreement across multiple observers
if i ask three to five traits
if i ask your roommate
what he or she thinks of you
they ask your professor what he or she thinks of you and your mum what
here with what she thinks of you
how would back to gender how would
the matchups
and the overlap alot
you walk around new leaving your personality to trail in the minds of people around
and this trail is characterized in terms of these five dimensions
it seems to be
predict real-world behavior it is the number of the real world you wouldn't be very
happy calling it valid you would take it seriously is that but it does so
it's so conscientiousness how he's going to conscientiousness scale
it relates to help pay for you or your spouse
on how
openness open you are are and psychological personality test relates to how likely you are
to change job
extroverts were people and i'm more and have more sexual partners
because they are experts
so these are real scales the batman hulk wonder woman doesn't correspond to anything in
the real world but where you stand in each of these five dimensions the seem
to capture it
as an example
the agreement by the way
somebody this study
several of the characters on the television show
this instance
because they want to find characters which everybody knew
and at thirteen subjects judge
these in turn characters on each of the five dimensions
his openness neuroticism conscientiousness and extraversion
they found
considerable agreement
and this is actually what i covered up is the agreeableness
for pelosi you've never seen a television show this is all going to be
but those people have
can you guess which characters would be particularly agreeable
anybody guess
you right
the most agreeable people are flanders in march
who would be not so
krusty is actually present the complicated cases
but but mister burns but also
where is a
there's no
nelson was nelson
there's nothing
you get strong consensus that ned ned flanders
and march simpson are highly agreeable people
six point two seven and five point four six one mister burns and nelson are
very low nelson schoolkid one trouble happens eagles high and that's
that's the psychological signed for military ability OK
that's what i want to say this point about personality and how we measure it
and again we're going to get back to it later when we talk about differences
in personality now i want to deal
with the second big difference
the second big differences intelligence
how do you define intelligence as no easy definition like personality is kind of difficult
to get your fingers on what we're talking about here
in one survey they have thousand experts to define intelligence
and some answers showed up over and over again
so just about everybody said intelligence involves abstract reasoning problem solving and the capacity to
acquire knowledge
that's the core being smart
other people mentioned things like memory
mental speed language mass
members meet again knowledge and creativity
also as hallmarks for intelligence
and again
it might be difficult to define it but you have a good feeling about what
it is so
you homework
is actually in this is part of the show is actually of limited intelligence
my colleagues
is very high intelligence
wonderful followed
but is probably not as smart as that guy
was like really really smart
this guy
ralph wiggum is particularly stupid
so you have range and and and it's important to figure that characterized as well
researched as but the feeling
that there are some people who are smart
and other people who are very smart and some people would come and others who
are very that we want to do it do from a scientific standpoint
it is characterized this in a more robust and interesting fashion
the textbook has a nice review
the history of attempts to define and measure intelligence
but there's a couple of ideas i want to focus on
one is an idea developed by by experiment
which is there's two types of intelligence
and there's s
and this is your ability on specific tests
so if there's ten tests they are given
as part of an IQ
an IQ test tensile tests
you get a different score in each of the sub to be a math test
in reading test and the spatial test in the different scores
refers to general intelligence
the general intelligence is something you bring to each of the tests in common
so this is diagram here
the six test for each of them there's an as
and then above that there a g
now g is very important notion the term g is used by psychologists lot even
i now integrate everything from minus to save so i don't endlessly we copy all
integrate by putting it up in a yellow chalk and you are left here on
this is definitely a color and type of course
so you want to integrate from my point quite good just integrate everything
everything on the right-hand side also from minus five to five
plus these other guys
just indicate i have
there are two
analysis what happens
what's this
every term is zero
because of the orthogonality relations the all of the form a constant times cosine in
time something different from cosine and he signed katie
that constant terms
all the other terms is zero and the only one which survives is this one
and what its value
the integral from my despite apply of cosine square and i put that up somewhere
it's right here
it is part
so this term turns into a and y
a and
that belong but this is where the integrals where the cosine to find
so the end result is
that we get a formula for
they and what is a n
a and is
well a n times pi
all these terms is zero
and nothing is left but this left hand side and therefore and times pi i
is the integral from
negative for
phi of f of t e
times cosine t
but that's a n times part
therefore if i want to stay and i have to divide divided by pi
and that's the formula for the coefficients a
arguments exactly the same if you want to be an but all right it down
for the sake of
completeness as they say
and to give you a chance to digest what i've done
thirty seconds just
that's because the arguments the same and the integral of science square density is also
so there is no difference there
now there's only one little caution
i have to be a little careful
this is an one two and so on and this is also in one two
unfortunately the constant term is slight exception
we've got to look at that specifically
because if you forget it you can make it into gross gross gross errors
well how about the constant term
suppose i repeat the argument for that in miniature
a constant term
plus other stuff
a typical of this stuff
a and cosine was
how my gay to get that constant term well if you think of this is
sort of like
constant times the reason is the constant is because being multiplied by cosine zero t
because i zero one so that suggests i should
i should multiply by i should multiply by
in other words what i should do is simply integrate this from negative
support i
fifty dt what's the answer well this integrated from my despite apply is how much
is c zero times two pi
and the other terms all give me
every other term is zero
because if you integrate cosine nt you're sign overcomplete period you always get zero
as much area above the axis of below where you can look at two special
cases you know
you always get zero the same thing with the site
so the answer is
that c zero
is equal to is a little special
it's not you don't just put an equal zero here
because then you would lose the factor so
see zero should be one over two pi
finds this integral
now there are two kinds of people in the world
once learn to separate formulas and the ones who just want to separate stations
so what
most people do
is they say look i want a i want this to be always the formula
for a zero
well for forty five minutes
so here is the key staff assume that you have six
we have lines
in three space
in each one of them you randomly select unit that
either one of the two possible directions
the new form
the gram schmidt matrix
i think only know products of these factors so clearly you get one along the
two unit vectors
it would be even with the small angle between them
or its complement
in other words what you will get in the off diagonal either plus out of
myself while the cosine
between the what
this matrix being question matrix is
positive semi definite
it's right is three
which means it's smallest i can value zero
and it's multiplicities
let's take a look as an example
of this class which consists of the pentagon plus an isolated words
so i call favourite graph
and you see in the second
OK if you don't mind OK let's we this little sequence of matrices in people
thing from right to left
let's look first this matrix
this matrix is defined as follows you start with this craft
and if two vertices are connected by an an edge
put minus one in the matrix
and if they are not connected by an edge
put i one
so for instance the forest for the first
correspond to the isolated vertex
this is covered by the way
there's no reason in the world to define the adjacency matrix of the graph to
its use in once
one minus one one
there's a lot of interesting information
in this particular presentation
this was introduced by
dutch mathematician side and we call them decide to make this is of the
so if you look at this matrix you can know
can't really exciting things
lo and behold it's smallest igon value is minus five
and it's multiplicities
if you just
one of the most
you'll get this matrix
you can multiply by
take o five get this matrix
so this matrix is positive semi definite OK
it's smallest like value zero it is multiplicity free
and then use standard linear algebra to produce this expect that will actually give you
the six lines on which you can produce the i'm sorry
if you start with this
six that was or any number of draws on the
born in england
you can
produced of this system this side of matrix of the graph
in other words with every
system of a single lines we can associate the
and vice versa with every graph with
sick and i showed you
i can correspond to a set of equivalence
now this correspondence is not unique and it's very easy to see why
if instead of choosing that
in this direction
i choose on the line of battle in the opposite direction
it will we first
all the inner products of the other factors
in other words this is equivalent
two taking a role in the car and divided by minus one
if you
what does it mean in the graph that is you take vertex
and you do this
you actually switch its relation to all the other approaches
towards the people's connected by an edge
it will not be connected by an edge
and vice versa
we call this operation switching was introduced by side
it is defined as follows
either way
i mean if you switch repeatedly with this
with respect to a sequence of axes
it is the same as switching with respect to the whole set the same time
this is defined as follows a subset of
switching g with respect to you means that if you knew x
is nothing new then remove the edge u x if it was an age and
if it wasn't
switching is an equivalence relation
the number of of the number of women lines
is equal to the number
of switching equivalence classes
well it's sort science
so far forces
there are only three switching losses
OK for
and and for the set to be open you have to be able to choose
an epsilon small enough that the whole the whole ball of radius absolute around points
to the set
so one intuition about open sets is is is what you get if you take
a close said like a closed ball and you remove the surface
that's an open set
but what's really important here for for for this why we want to what i
want to use this image in
integration is has nothing to do with the surface
the idea is basically that
that integration corresponds to something like assigning of all u
right and if you think of something like say a hyperplane
or a flat disk in three-dimensional space a that doesn't have what you write because
it's flat in one direction
and this definition of an open set which says that every point has a neighborhood
still in this
it means that this is the the set cannot be flat completely degenerate in any
and even even in some small region of it cannot
even locally if you if you focus in on one point
there's always
the set around it always extends in all directions
so that's the set that has a meaningful notion of all u
associated with it
in in abstract mathematics this the system of all open sets of of a given
space is called the topology of this
so you've all heard the term topology i'm sure and
in in more like
calculus or another this kind of mathematics it's not like in the graph right has
basically the neighborhood structure of the graph
but what it tells you is which sets your space is like a lookup table
politics like a lookup table you can look up OK the episode
and so the general method for constructing these sigma algebras this these domains for integration
is to start with all the open sets on your space
and then you take the smaller sigma which contains all these open sets and that's
denoted in this way so this is the system of sets
then taking this closure the smallest sigma which contains all these sets
is denoted sigma of
that's called this kind of sigma algebras are called borel sigma algebra
so you know to be of forming as the borel sigma algebra a sigma algebra
generated by the open sets of this space omega
basically the reason why why why everybody uses sigma arises once you have defined what
you open set
there are different ways how you can define sigmod but it might be meaningful
so you can make different requirements like all the open sets should be in there
i haven't said what a measurable function is but all the continuous functions should be
measurable different kind of different kind of things that you could could require that all
also meaningful one context another
and it turns out that
the sigma algebras defined by these requirements all end up being the same
the the real question is what are your concern and once it settled
one says that always get the same sigma algebra
number matter how you go about it
and just just two
to clarify the so the signature will contain all the open sets
but it will also contain all closed sets because closed sets complements of open sets
and it contains a lot of sets that are neither open or close to take
for example to think of taking an open interval
so in an interview with the two boundary points removed and closed interval and then
you take the union of the two
there will also be in the sigma algebra but neither open nor closed
this is
month long
six months small OK so
that that's a good question it's not not maybe
so it is not very intuitive and actually even if you want to prove that
it can be huge problems what actually is the smallest sigma contain something
they they if you have any system of sets
down in your in your space is always smaller sigma algebra so small as system
of sets that satisfies these these
conditions and contains all these sets so that's unique
actually finding that sigma algebra
can practice if you actually want to to do them as it can be huge
proving that something is the smallest technology for given systems that can also be huge
OK so the question is why do you want to work with the smallest sigmod
about why don't you take a minor injuries kevin some surplus that's in there so
remember that the original problem was that that
if the sigma algebra gets too large
then we have trouble defining and measuring
that's that's not
only scratches the surface of the answer so generally
generally if you
you want your signature us to be as small as possible
in the sense that
you can think of that have it as
as the resolution
if you have the the larger sigma algebras defined as the resolution is
what kind of sets you can integrate or or tree
and and as a general rule of thumb
for whatever problem you request you wanted to choose the causes resolution
gives you all the information you need
it is smallest
yeah exactly so one one thing is is such properties for example in statistical estimation
but i
i i would love to talk about it
but i was simply one of the time the second problem is that
if you just make it too large then we get back to this problem of
the power set which is so complicated that we can't even define the problem measure
the reason for
here's something four
some example of constructing is ignored algebra
if you want to define say integration
on the real line
in this way
you want to set up something like
a measure that defines volume on the real line or maybe in euclidean space
but measures cornerback come to the limit
so that gives you get taken to take a subset of euclidean space
and you want to have a function that takes its subsidies an argument and science
that's what
in order to do that so
we want to set up to measure and we need to define the set of
so what happens to my fancy you absolutely think the the node with the largest
mass not with the highest peak of the largest man
and then the variational bayes is doing something more like
and then as you move through two alpha positive infinity
you get an an upper envelope
c trying to do this for an unnormalised q distribution and you get up in
the late on your approximation
and that's going to try and include all of the mass in the distribution
similarly you can look at the behaviour different evidences with respect to
zero is in the in the p distribution and you move from the exclusive zero
forcing behavior with zero impedance must be there in q
so that you have regions where
which will mean we tend to underestimate the variance of
moving food to the other behaviour
he will try and cover
all of the mass of p
even if there are serious in p
finally if you look at the
unnormalized q distribution that minimizes the divergence you'll see
that the posterior mass
moves from being estimate alpha equals minus infinity
through actually the correct alpha equals one
over two b
over estimate
a alpha equals positive infinity
as i think as you the reasons for moving between different alpha the not really
going to address that
in this talk but some sort of reasons might be
one is going to be tractability when these computations are going to be a valid
for different graphs there is what sort of approximation you're looking to get
which parts of the posterior actually interested in
but that exact minimisation is not
OK so that was just brief activities thing and then only going to look at
the two settings africa's there in africa's one for variational bayes and expectation propagation
so the nice thing is that we can
point is
the minimum divergence minimisation by message passing graph so many the factor graph notation
we're able in the we have a factor and we're just going to look at
the message
eight from the message from f to be
just to remind everyone here you might not be familiar this is the
update equation for expectation propagation
and so what you have you ever some product like to just something
from then the incoming message from a
over the fact that modelling marginalizing a something of a
and then what EP is going to do take the backwards message from b to
multiply that in
and projection which is going to project the resulting distribution back into the family again
allow for messages
and then again divide again by
that backwards reverse methods
and so
one way of thinking about this is that
well first you should know that if projection is exact if it turns out that
the results of the qualification is in the family of distributions which are going to
be able to approximate then what you get
it's just BP
you have a belief propagation because
these two to simply can't fly
so what about the case where you're going to have to make that approximation you
can have to take this possibly unpleasantly formed
distribution and projected back into say the gas family whatever using then how is this
reverse method influencing that projection
one nice way of thinking about it the hint two
algorithm is to where it should make that
the approximation accurate
so the that is going to say
and i suggest that you try and make the projection accurate in this sort of
region of space
it's quite a nice way of thinking is as we move towards richer family messages
then that message will get increasingly ignored let me try and simplify
message family then it's going to have to use more information to try and find
out where best to to approximate this awkward
message distribution
variational message passing doesn't use that this method always uses the same form of the
message computations
which is as we already being covered
log form of the
belief propagation
OK so
and it's going to take those message passing computation
and apply them to a number of cases so we can see
the behaviour
of these two algorithms
the first is is a very simple example
all like graphs are going to have exactly one but almost all have one but
very few variables keeping very
so here it just going to have the factor in the
with looking in the sense the output messages here so
is going to be one of zero
b is the probability of being
into the pieces of pre-defined length
annealing again but not simulated one so
the point is that we are cooling this still here in the device called the
malt primary cooling is performed by water here we have water sprays and in the
support roles there's also water to perform schooling
the problem is OK this is just practical interest illustrations from the plant this is
it comes
into for the production
the main problem here is
different defects
we want to a wider
mythologies are unhappy with it cracks
we'd internal
inhomogeneities and so on
this is something they want to a white
now how
what is the way of
preventing these unwanted effects this process
it is actually controlled
by a number of
so called process parameters including the speed of the moving this to these devices and
certain flows so you so that's praising the second recording zone
and the engineer of the plant has two
two during these parameters in way
you can imagine that this is not a trivial problem
because the number of parameters and possible settings is rather high
in this case and how a particular
that's a subspace definition and help for each parameter set minimum and maximum value and
certain step size it makes no sense to search for the right to value continuously
because these parameters can be set in a discrete way so this is a discretisation
for each parameter which hosts a number of possible values if you multiply these
you would again get the number of possible settings and in this case is the
order of
too much to check them all
not possible to experiment in practice because in if we are very unlucky could even
result in some accident and so on so
in this case is the only way is to use a simulator of the process
in america simulator
the work
lucky enough that in this case it exists for this process
the numerical simulations that are reliable enough
exist so the idea is
to perform or to integrate an optimisation algorithm work which was the genetic code written
in this case we don't cost to simulate
and to evaluate each procedure each
parameter setting according to some quality function
the idea is
rather straightforward this is the loop of the
our iterative optimisation procedure
this is the algorithm that
o operations on the parameter settings and this is the way of evaluating them how
this is done this simulator
for each
but parramatta vector performed the simulation
calculate the temperature field in certain calling criteria that needs to be satisfied they are
they do they are defined mathematically you're not going to these detectors and the result
is a certain numerical value
which tells us
good the process
is performed what is the quality of the estimated quality
this may
look to you but it's actually
decades of development before behind the simulation procedure and these functions so this was done
by people in different
universities and steel plants it's the combination of theoretical development and empirical practice
and this is what we did in our case so
the genetic algorithm was coupled with the numerical simulator that performed evaluations again the here
we how certain
what we call performance traces here
this is one of the initial studies performed for this problem
the discrete variable
indicating to which cluster data point belongs and it's not known in the training data
and test data but we don't want to be in a specific right now about
the first thing in bayes modelling is to think about the joint probability distribution of
all these quantities involved and decompose it into a smart way
typically you start with the parameters you assume there is just the application of this
product decomposition to this problem the set of probability distribution of the parameters
then you say OK in the next one is so the data and the hidden
there was in the data given the parameters so this is still completely general
and then you say OK i want to put the of x h given and
then i should series of the whole
pennsylvania that data HD
but the assumption is that the observed data independent from one another given the parameters
are known so that's why we can drop of these terms out of this expression
and you end up with this more compact representation
so p of ten is the
prior distribution of parameters
p of d HD given theta is the complete data likelihood
but of course actually is not known so we have to
integrate out the next step the complete that means
assuming you could have made everything what is the likely
the like is always the probability of the observed ovations given the parameters
so typically have you might be interested in predicting x given the data so we
are really interested in all these other quantities here we want to calculate this quantity
so the first thing is as i said we don't know we don't know HD
so the first thing is to marginalize out to make this expression
without the d so this was one of the operations we've discussed before shifting to
grant great out HD and get this
the likelihood of the likelihood of the observed data depending on the amount of data
this is the first operation to do
next operation is then we can calculate the probability distribution of the parameters given the
data by simply using bayes formula this was specified in the model this is that
we have just
a calculated that is the normalisation here
the next thing is that we end up with the product of p of x
is given that p of ten
given the
but we are not interested in that at also we have to integrate out and
obtain the simple expression p of x on h given the data and finally we
also not interested in age but in p of x given the
so we also have to integrate out hidden variable in the data point so these
should go through this may be
when you review the lecture something really not be difficult operations derive from the basic
principle of the technicalities involved
all these integrals and and and the sums over here everything as sort of
this i had this
minus point eighty one
which makes minus point eight i hope
check it out your calculators with them out
press the button
now multiply that by age
and which means it's going to minus point o eight
perhaps with the zero after i didn't tell you how many decimal places was carried
out to two decimal places i think that will be good enough
finally the last step two here and one another one ten so the value of
x is now two tens
and finally what's the value of y what i didn't tell you where to stop
let's stop that y of point let's stop y point two because there's no more
room on the blackboard
seems like an excellent
about approximately how big is that in other words
then this is going to be
the old y
plus this number which seems to be
pointing to to be
so the answer is
new values five eighty two
OK well we got to number we did what we were supposed to do we
we got to number next question well
i was asked a few questions of one of the first most basic thing is
you know
how right is this
how can i answer such a question if i can
now if i have no explicit formula for the solution
that's the basic
problem with numerical calculation
in other words i have to wonder around in the dark to some extent yet
have some idea when i've arrived at the place that i want to go
well the first question i would like to answer
the question is is this too high or too low is is oiler
i'm sorry he will forgive me in heaven i will use him
by this i mean is the result
when you say something first and then i'll criticize it is allowed to high
four two
in other words it is the result of using oil is that i e is
this number too high or too low is higher than the right answer what it
should be
or is it a lower than the right answer or god forbid is exactly right
it's almost never exactly right that's not an option
how do you answer that question well the sensory geometrically
basically if
the solution world lying
four straight line
then the oil and method would be exactly right all the time
but it's not aligned that it's a it's a curve
well the critical question is is the curve
is the solution so here's the solution let's call y one of x let's say
here was the starting point
here the solution is convex
and here the solution is
i concave up concave down if you learn those words i think those are by
now free michael pretty well disappear from the curriculum
call it if you have an upper now what mathematicians call it
convex is that the other one is concave
well how to the oilers solutions look well just sketch i think from this you
can see already
when you start out on the oil solution is going to go like that now
you're too low
well let's suppose after that
the line element here is approximately the same as what it is there
you know roughly parallel after all there are not too far apart and the direction
field is continuous at the directions don't change drastically from one point to another
well there also of
but now you see is still too long it even more
as it pathetically tries to follow
it's losing territory and that's basically because the curve is convex
exactly the opposite would happen if the curve or concave the solution curve concave now
it's too high
and it's not going to be able to correct that
check over the microsoft instant messenger so it's like more than a billion conversations with
a two hundred forty million people from the whole world talking at the same time
exchanging information and so on
so scale is going
but scale gives you more or less
what when i when i what i mean by more is that we observe some
global phenomena that are genuine and it would be
invisible at smaller scales for example heavy tailed degree distribution thank you won't see them
if you have if your network is small or if you have a network of
few hundred people
it is very hard for you to measure any statistical significance as we bigger networks
that counts for sort of what you get less of is that we don't really
know the the role of the nodes or we don't know the
let's say
if i say no that is maybe strong but we don't know
we don't know the semantics right we have the observed things that such a large
scale we can't you don't know the rules of particular nodes and i know the
backgrounds and so on
and the goal which is to find to find problems that lies somewhere between where
we can sort of exploit both things
and sort of moving towards what i'm going to talk about right so what do
we know about networks i think we know a lot about the structure
of the
of the networks and here i have like list of of buzz words or terms
when structure properties that were discovered in
in large networks in the last ten years and you probably recognise a lot of
the right to be talking about power law and scale free networks small world and
so on but what i think is that we know much less about processes and
dynamics that take place in networks and this is the topic of my talk today
just to sort of
what if i told you so here i have two
the features of networks are one of them is
is a network of
traces of how disease was spreading and the other one is how people who recommended
the DVD challenge and i want to tell you which one is which but this
is what study this
so what i'll talk about that diffusion and cascading behavior in networks and i was
that the the top you have park
first i will talk about basic mathematical models like virus propagation and diffusion or cascading
behavior sort of two traditional topics and then we'll see some great consequences in finding
the most influential nodes in the network then i'll show you some empirical studies on
large networks
radio radio cannot going to measure the cost the cascades and the behaviour of how
things spread over the network and sharing the publications come from by the marketing and
blogs and the like in the last part i show more and more algorithms and
consequences come out from the real and then you can
so what i mean by diffusion in social networks this would be at the behaviour
of the cascades spread from node to node like an epidemic in in the network
and there are now numerous examples of this for example you can have news propagation
gravity some events in the people get aware of this event by hearing about it
from the friends i'd like opinions rumors and things like that we also have like
this one of the most effective way to here that something is good from from
someone else like the rise of new websites free web based services and so on
of course also like diseases like flu propagates via right i get the flow through
contact with some other person that's the same that we have i know some kind
changes in social principles like smoking maybe you really somebody may stop or start smoking
given the pressure from their friends or whether they smoke or not and so on
then similar for financial markets and so
then there is a long history of the study diffusion and here i want to
measure mentioned the two
the most famous one was for the for the first one i want to quickly
talk about is the spread of new agricultural practices in between two hundred sixty i'll
farmers right so random crossing forty three they went ends and study how this new
type of course see the hybrid corn that would increase the
the game of i know how much you harvest every year by by significant amount
of how this how this adoption of this new seat was adopted by function basically
what they found was that as far as got aware of this new
the miraculous it very quickly but what happened is that even later when they are
sold this
actually works they would go
and by using this is so what what that sort of child was the diffusion
is like this is a social process right it's a social network interpersonal communication that
made these people involved or by businesses and
the second classical study is spread of new
medical practices when they beat all this studied the adoption of a new drug between
doctors in illinois so there must some new and abiotic that
that was very good at that point in time and what happened is that it
was not like people became aware of the of the neuron and biotic or the
new drugs like
because studies or in sense trying to sell the new drugs but they wouldn't prescribe
until their peers i from the same hospital and someone with this drug actually works
so again it was like the social power of the year that made people start
describe this new
so again it's like it's just diffusion is like a social process and also there
are many other studies of diffusion that can go in many interesting ways so here
are two the more interesting one one is that there was like that
obesity which is basically like
if somebody is always the that this sort of
while or
diffuses through the network and they found some evidence that if we can friends then
your probability of
yourself go away like significant cases
another thing that is sort can also one can think of us up pressure of
on on the person is is this experiment from this from the sixties with a
group of five to ten people they were put into the room and the like
every person had to say which line is the closest way
and what happened was the first line of them they were like they paid daughter
they were set up in the last one was the genuine experiment and what actually
the bayesian methodology and within that you you have
algorithms which help you too
decide how many clusters
should one
his plan yes
oh i see so that's come to two dimensions right so each data point could
be high dimensional
and then you can have lots of data points
in terms of the high dimensionality of the data points yes you could do dimensionality
in fact
one of the examples which are given in the end
is on hand handwritten digits and what i did was i used PCA to reduce
it to a low dimensional space and then hierarchical clustering in the multinationals
that's the difference
dimension to the
the to the different hierarchical clustering approaches of that
o which is
along the lines of
more or less bayesian algorithms so let's start with the traditional ones which i call
linkage algorithms
so this you might have heard of them like single linkage average linkage complete linkage
and this up algorithms which in a sense this prescription prescriptive so
if you simply given the algorithm
which produces value a free hierarchy
and it's not clear
in from a probabilistic
perspective is not clear what this tree actually means
but you know it's very easy to implement as very simple to that to use
this is very popular
coming being more bayesian on so
the next set of
hierarchical clustering algorithms is based on probabilistic models because
the probabilistic models gives you a way in which
to judge how good your hierarchy is
based on how good it is
a generative process
of the data
and they could be more bayesian and you could do things like
so this a probabilistic approaches which we tend to use a single tree
and if you are interested in recovering a tree from your data
a hierarchy from the data
if you don't have enough data
you have to be uncertain about what the tree is
and in order to capture the uncertainty you what you like to do is to
take a more bayesian approach in which
you have the whole distribution over trees and then
some ways higher probability than others
but you want to actually report the distribution of the trees
the tell was basically going to go through
this series of different
hierarchical clustering algorithms
so let's start with the link showrooms is very easy to just tell you the
algorithm and then we'll go from there
so the input
is you're given a set of data points x one two x
you also
you also need to tell the was some distance measure to use so this distance
this is the function is simply a function which returns to the distance between the
points x and y
so this could be things like l one distance euclidean distance
it could be either so distance measures as well
and then given this distance measures
you also want some way of combining
distances so the distance between two clusters so c and d here are subsets of
data points
the distance between two subsets two clusters here
is some function of the distance between
data points within each subset
then the algorithm is very simple to use but you initialise each data point in
its own separate clusters of initialise x i in cluster c i which contains only
and then we iterate forty and minus one iterations
in each iteration we simply find a pair of clusters c and d
that minimizes the distance between them so the idea is that if two clusters are
similar to each other that you want to much
and the more similar they are
the more you want to prioritize merging them
so you pick a pair of clusters with the minimum distance
and that simply much this two clusters together by basically
removing cnt
from your list of clusters
and then adding the union
two classes together
into your list of clusters and you just repeat this
in each iteration so you start off with and clusters
in each iteration we remove two clusters at one so we subtract the number of
clusters by one
and after
and like
after n minus one iterations all of the you only have one class the left
and this is this cluster contains all the data
so this is of
class of
hierarchical clustering algorithms
so that's the different linkage algorithms you have to use a single company and average
and they simply correspond to different
distance measures on clusters
so a different function to define
distances between classes given distances between data points
so in single linkage
the distance between two clusters is simply the minimum distance between
have data points one from each cluster
of the distance
complete linkage the distance between two clusters is the maximum distance between data points
in the cluster
and then in average linkage is simply the average
that's of course in many different ways of of
defining distance between
two clusters given distances between data points so
this i some of the of examples mean centroid ward weighted versions of this so
but the most popular history in fact the most of the probably everything
just to give you the intuition about what this too
history algorithms this
so in single linkage saying that the distance between two classes say where one class
the here and another the cost that
then the distance between these two clusters simply
the minimum distance of data points
one from each
of pairs of data points one from each cluster
notice that
according to this
distance measure this two clusters are very close to a very close together
if they have two data points which are close together
two you can write it has a some
over data points
of terms
what region
okay so we keep this one because it grows linearly with then
dear to logpi therefore it doesn't grow then
there is a growing anything
the grows with pi pi doesn't grow
okay grows with the number parameters right
okay but that we're keeping the number parameters fixed here
and now
this one half log of the determinant of any
that's grows the end
and i it's with the it's a couple lies derive it but essentially the hessian matrix
is the matrix of second derivatives of the log likelihood
you get
one term
for each data point again
so i can actually write
so sorry i can write the matrix any roughly has
end times
some matrix called they not
okay which doesn't grow them so the matrix eighty elements that they grow linearly with ann
if you have a debugging matrix with elements grow linearly with end
the determinant will grow
with enter the dean
and so when you take the logo that's
would you get is
sorry log enter the deity is dlog again
and the other term is a constant that doesn't grow them
so basically when we examine this term with a couple of lines map what we
get is a term dealer to log in
this is an amazingly simple equation is and it's an approximation to a marginal likelihood
which says computer
the maximum of the log likelihood
and penalized by
the number of parameters
over to
times log of the number of data points
this is a simple number that use the penalized maximum likelihood
super cheap
quick and easy to compute doesn't even depend on the prior
some of them went away
and we can use the maximum because it doesn't depend on the prior we can
use the maximum likelihood estimate is that the map estimate for example
it's equivalent to the minimum description length criterion
by people like
your memories and the
wallace and so on
although there is a lot more to the minimum description length literature than just this one one criterion
in the limit as n goes to infinity assumes that all parameters are well determined and the model is identifiable
otherwise the number parameters these should be the number of well determined parameters
and just as a word of caution
basically this encourages parameter counting
it says
the complexity of the model is going to be determined by the number of parameters
and that's a very very dangerous thing to do
there are simple models with only
one parameter
and there r
sorry there are complicated models the only one parameter
and there are simple models with infinitely many parameters so parameter accounting
is very dangerous but in this asymptotic regime for identifiable will determine models
this is a valid way of approximating the marginal
this was
yeah we removed e um
we remove the fisher information matrix
but we kept the way in which the fisher information matrix grows
right so
disingenious myself my name is there is always it is and i've been with accenture
just about a bit more than two years
and my previous experiences information retrieval we are actually i'll talk about because we actually
tech labs so accenture is the big consulting company and tech labs are small organisation
doing applied research and therefore four locations who are in north america in chicago in
silicon valley and one instance of young people is france where i come from and
we have one in india so the type of things we do is applied research
that motivated with real business problems and some focus areas machine learning in that to
mining that's my group so engineering collaboration knowledge management and a number of other topics
what i'm trying to do today is give you another view of
are not the case study what use cases how did we get the requirements and
one to do it shows the use cases that we did
as well as i try to present some technologies that we develop in scope of
active and how they're being used and if i have sometimes aluminum example of an
application that's not necessarily part of active but it deals with context switching and it
is actually deployed application which is inspired by real business problems
so it is you can probably make a stew heard probably by now activities in
the end aiming to increase the productivity of knowledge workers and is trying to do
this in a contextual in process backs task aware way and it's using a number
of technologies for this but what we are trying to the next being active accenture
we are trying to develop prototypes that integrate active technologies and some other technologies that
we develop the necessary with the end goal too
do exactly these invisibility we give knowledge workers so we are aiming at our own
workforce as well as in some long around we're aiming at their clients and the
goal is to assure that the technologies developed in active are in line we need
real world business problems
OK so i'll talk about the use cases
so um
big companies like accenture there are number of business processes and tasks to perform every
day but by by the employees and their range in types like proposal right so
all big companies consulting companies specifically to do proposal writing then marketing selling products for
instance requirement analysis software companies need to have a process of how requirements analysed in
order to develop the products the this the same goes for some protesting then companies
need to know how
they approach training their own workers their own employees so all this about to these
different business processes that because it's in company
there is different and specialised interfaces in company for each one of these
processes that for application that support this process is what is common to most of
them is that in why one way or another either directly or indirectly there's need
to access the central repository why central repository because this is the main it's into
the document centric knowledge management system that most company have implemented and
for instance for proposal writing the process will ask whoever is writing the document to
go to the repository to find similar documents it will ask to find people
it will ask to find similar vendors with which we have worked in the past
so in why when one way or another our employees are actually faced with having
to the central repository numerous times for different tasks so we decided to make
it's one of the processes this of interest for us and not that specific knowledge
enquiry what does this mean this this is basically
supporting all of these acts of the accenture employees that go to why central repository
numerous times for different reasons and for example that could be is no executive that
is writing proposals and he might you know all about his particular small domain which
is an expert but you might not know what's happening what is accenture doing within
the whole area in the industry so he would go to the repository find information
he will look at what similar products have been done for the same client maybe
he would look at what's what's new what's new products going happening and
usually people refer to
the internet repository and when they cannot find any information to go to the person
that person that always people for help
another very important process
actually go through the processes probably happening the most often in the consultants consulting companies
proposal writing and
this is an and this is a very important part of accenture's work because
most of our work is project based which means that
a client has the problem he writes a request for information request proposals and accenture
responds with a document and this document should contain it's the proposal is it's why
are we the best people to be chosen to do this work
what kind of credentials we haven't kind similar work we had that we have done
in this area in the past how well that would how however solve the problem
so i guess
because that is yes with respect to the original formulation the problem where we have
multiple levels in the graph
corresponding to
different labels
yes of course they in now the l labels and then graphs the the new
graph has an l
plus two nodes the the source and sink so yes it certainly be graph so
that the more work to do
and i guess what you'd expect in alpha expansion
no because
at every step of for expansion
you just have a binary labeling problem on the original graph to do so each
as the same complexity as one segmentation if you like in the previous one but
of course we now have to many steps and in order to get the results
you have to
cycle through the labels in some order
several times
where several turns out to be a few right you know
less than ten if not hundreds of thousands in some iterative methods and the reason
for that is i guess intuitively because OK this is the beauty of alpha expansion
compared with other iterative methods like belief propagation is that each iteration is doing something
the belief propagation and iteration can only extend you know the influence of the modification
of the solution if you like
like away from
you know it moves like away from one one set of the time to move
along the way have an influence over the entire image you have many many iterations
with rock that's not the case although it's not you know where alpha expansion is
the method itself is not finding a global optimum
each step
it's finding a global optimum and that global optimum involves long-range interactions so you know
intuitively that's why alpha expansion might be really good in cases where belief propagation is
is another thing which i think probably skip as well but just to say
well there's is an energy bound you can get
four alpha expansion so you know even though i'm saying the strong guarantees about global
optimality only apply to individuals that's not the problem as a whole there is a
guarantee that applies the problem as a whole which says that the energy that you
achieve is within a factor of two
of the optimal energy
or actually a factor two and that
depends on the details of the problem but
it turns out
you know when you look at the examples that's not useful that
so you know the difference in energy and energy in real problems are you know
relatively tiny far less than a factor of two
but yet those small energy differences matter in other words we look what happened to
the solution
two putative solution is energy is some some small facts much less than to greater
than the optimality the solution is all wrong all over the place
we care about energy difference is much much less than a factor of two so
you technically there's no guarantee but not going to get you anywhere sorry
again you know that's like you probably had experienced many times in other domains
let's get back to stereo because one of the things we really want to do
i'm not going to be able to deal with
the stereo problem in the generality it deserves but promised me no i promise you
say i promise you you can use graph cuts to solve stereo in quite some
detail that respects all of the detailed geometric constraints the there are that argue that
labour that but i can't quite tell you the entire thing very simplest formulation of
stereo which is not really satisfactory but it's a natural extension of what we discussed
in dynamic programming remember we said
dynamic programming
but should be
dynamic programming patient problem here as well
it looks just like this but the gene function they dealt only with neighbouring pixels
along an epipolar line
what we said looking at the solutions to that
the program problem is and this is a pity because neighbouring epipolar lines don't get
along quite frequently see artifacts arising where an entire epipolar line gets misaligned if only
so forth who gives you adapt graph right
so as i think there be at least one talk on friday which which actually
gets into one of the popular methods
so if you stick around
one of my favourite methods using
so that we can actually recover structures of these graphical model the dependencies
i'm unable to find new then variables and ask you which things depend on which other things
we have made progress as a community on on those as well
so i'm going to sort of our
give an example
of an undirected graphical model
we illustrate how much these algorithms scale and what they can do for you
right so so we look at the problem of drug detection
we are going to look at so so detecting about you know a couple of
my climate colleagues are very interested in specially significant doubts which last for like five
years or more
or period of time and spatial
because that's unusual that shouldn't have happened they want to understand the climate conditions under which the sort of
happening our is probably the most widely studied dropping it
it started in the late sixties and went on for a very very long time
this is the region in between the sahara and the south are
that that's what is another popular example in in the in north america and so on and so on
what we did was
we talk about this he argued it has this is the precipitation data it's difficult
to get precipitation data is what i'm understanding but this is one of the good
ones that people use
and we have data from nineteen one to two thousand six is the said we
used to have a resolution of twenty five degrees latitude longitude right so
this actually gives u precipitation value at orlando locations and we use the dataset
what we're going to try to do using this dataset
is we want to try to detect
these significant droughts
using a markov enough random field framework
right so
so at any given point of time
you can assume that you have this lattice latitude longitude
this is each location
and each location can be in one of two states
right so
its location can be in one of two states
are dropped
right it's it's it's it's a billion
be able
i'm saying i'm contacting them because this is normal and actually have some dependency depending
on what the condition this thing so that you so i don't want to make
independent predictions on each one of them
right and
i'm not going to show you the results we have tested at u just get
a very nice results if you're doing
so we are trying to maintain some dependencies at any point of time this is
sort of a snapshot of the great but each variable is the latent variable which
i don't know about his as you go along with it's it's
it's it's normal are it's drought conditions
then they replicate this thing or one hundred and six years
so far this toy example i'm i'm cooking up a markov random fields which have the statistical dependencies
i have no arrows and and columns and three and so that's basically each such
the time scale by a twelve five timesteps
that's a total of sixty
william variables
which can be in one of hundred sixty states right so of sixty billion variables
and which can be in one of two to sixty state
given observations on these points one set of observations
i'm trying to figure out which one of these two to the sixty states it
is in what what was likely explains what you've just rub salt
that's a hard problem
to make matters worse we actually using this year
he said well they developed number don't be seven million states which means that all of other seven million
seven million william labels which means that the total of total seven million states and
i'm trying to solve the maximization problem on this
i'm give you a sense of the scale
of what we can handle
using distributive law methods right so so this is not
your car use i acid run one hundred data points we can handle set up
an integer programme with seven million william variables
and the way we do this
is a bit complicated but it uses the distributive law
we essentially to a linear programming relaxation in a sense we are actually solving a linear programme
with seven million variables and while solving the linear program we use the message passing algo
right and that's why the fastest way of doing it if you use a commercial
package for doing this it probably not far we got to and then died because
it's it's not designed to handle this class somebody this scale of problems
something new with graphical model inference is something we can do this is the scale
we can do i'm actually going to show you know
sort of the f one of the outputs we got
so we can you know we can do this for droughts we can do it for other things as well
some other people are interested in sort of heat waves are precipitation extremes of things
so that's are and we can sort of handle bad
now we have reached a point that we've got all of these results and this
is sort of what we call the decoding the map inference that has happened
think of it as has
like a big big version of viterbi decoding but run on on bad many millions of variables
and if you want to sort of look at individual things whether it makes sense or not
this is what the water fountains there
it starting in the nineteen seventies and this is the reason you can go back and look up
we know that this the span nutritional so here this is exactly what it far right
you can add more variables like
five much content and other things that you think are relevant to improving the prediction of this problem
one thing you have to what is that we are not getting those red dots here and there
which is what will get if you just short based on the precipitation
right one month you want a little bit of low precipitation a purely thresholding based
approach will give you a dead
dots all over the place
and what this model actually doesn't that you don't have to worry about it if
you know if you don't have to worry about it
okay so so we have plenty of results and i'm not going to bore you you know sort of what
going to all of these but we found almost all of the major ones that
are known some ones which are pretty interesting which we're looking at in closer detail
and but this is what you can do so must be wondering seven million variables
half long it takes it takes about hour and i think we should be able
to bring it down to about a couple of minutes
within a month or so we are working on another variant of it
high confidence
it is compatible with negative correlation
we will see this later on
this is because you have to normalize obviously you've going to taken as it used
to normalize these two normalise new lows the orientation of the implications
and then what and then
about fifty two
one hundred substitute measures have been proposed it and no one is a clear winner
sticking to confidence but because for
do we mean by data mining this is famous for that you can read from
the distance of the query them the patterns that appear in there i was showing
i mean this is one first difference of machine learning with data mining to an
audience of
data mining and you have to show it this way
know this of machine learning you have to show in the way
and the content is the same
a few names and this to but they want these images they want something that
speaks to the
right brain hemisphere
and this is constant in many
i steps this is also my fiance proportions
selection of the process
preprocessing of the transformation modelling
obtaining models are part
validation and professional degree of the mode something and here with me
modelling point
which is where the machine learning algorithms are going to play and therefore this is
the area where i would be mostly meeting
some people call data mining these whole things
some people call this whole thing knowledge discovery and for these data mining
there is not for general agreement so i only used the data mining
as the places
for instance in the title of today's talk
but not in the real things i prefer to use just modelling for this and
knowledge discovery process for the whole thing
this is not the only diagram there is this whole thing i'm going to create
a is similar
and only that it
it makes it into a senior books the data preparation the process of selection and
preprocessing and transformation
or maybe we don't rush at copying these you we have this and the
late we're going pdf
but they and a number of things first the business understanding and the understanding for
they should
and then
we need
which is what one wishes not to do very often
that's very good
as i say that i will be concentrating in
this works
but let me just spend one slide in the processing transformation that everybody
four the actual data mining projects
part of the time is devoted to the preparation data transformation data selection
and evaluation and the tiny portuguese devoted to modelling
but in any lecture on data mining like mine
or in any book in data mining as you might find around
ninety percent of it is devoted to modelling and just
tiny comments are given on the other face
and this is not a contradiction
why do you have to spend so much on the faces because there is that
there is no from the experience of others
and when she
the reason for which it is difficult to make the first it's difficult to communicate
with ideas and second it's difficult to go
the weight in practice
just one more of these and i really
i have a lot of
stories that they were can we talk a lot of stuff but
but what do we learn not that much
so there is collection at the moment
axillary or
the processing of information
the most we can do and this is what i am attempting at in this
slide is to warn you that
it doesn't it is not sufficient to say they will analyse
the interview with indian entrepreneurs who wanted to do my taxes from bangalore r
and the one wonder right my new
software from bangalore r and the one who wanted to read my x-rays from bangalore
r and the one wanted trace my lost luggage on delta airlines from bangalore
that's while i had
been sleeping
something really big had happened
and i couldn't explain
in fact i wish i could show you out-takes and interviews so be sitting across the table from jerry rho
on a company called emphasised that
it's part of a group based on four hundred thousand american tax returns from india last year
and i say that injury
what happened
i missed something
how can you be doing this
what happened
well the last interview we did was with a friend mine on the nilekani who heads emphasises sio which is
one of the premier indian high-tech companies and now and then i was sitting on
the couch outside his office before the filming began doing kind pre-interview with them
and one point is that any time i gotta tell you
the global economic playing field is being leveled
and you're americans
are not ready
all i wrote that down my little notebook
the global economic playing field is being leveled
well after the interview i got my jeep o
and then went back to my hotel and the whole time back in the right
i kept rolling over in my head what inundated said that global
economic playing field
is being level
and finally occurred me when i'm done with saying was that the global economic playing field was being flattened
and then
and i thought of this book
i said to myself my god
he's telling me the world is flat
he's telling me the world is flat and he's citing this
as a great achievement in human development
that we've made the world
in fact
well i went back to my hotel i called my wife is exactly how it
happens that honey i'm gonna read a book called the world is flat
she thought i was stark raving mad
but i came home i called the publisher the new york times in my boss columns perpetrators i only
i gotta go on leave immediately
because my software
these updating the framework through which i am analyzing foreign affairs
these updated i'm seeing things out there i cannot understand and explain
if i don't go on leave immediately
i'm gonna write something really stupid and the new york times
it's a great way to get only if i have
very hard to say no so
so we worked out basically and down
i've eventually got three months' leave and don
during that time basically
between march fifteen on december fifteenth in a complete frenzy ov on
obsession really i wrote this book
and dumb let me just go through the first three chapters very quickly on
alpha chapters called
i think probably not while you were sleeping
end a big in the book by noting that christopher columbus set sail in fourteen ninety two looking fourie
shorter route to india
that's what columbus was going in fourteen ninety two
the muslim power so that they had blocked the overland routes
end i don't want to go around the horn of africa so columbus sailed west
he had then you know that enter the santa maria
he never defined indeed
but he calls the people he ran into indians
and we call them back to this day
and he came home and told his wife honey have accidentally discovered the world is round
i set of free india five hundred twelve years later
i knew just which direction i was going
i sailed east
i had moved tons business class
any cheap satellite that popped up in my seat told me exactly where it was
and i came home and told my wife
honey i've accidentally discovered the world is flat
and the first chapter really goes to all these encounters i had in india
let me to this conclusion
but unlike columbus
i kept going
i next went to delhi in china
the capital
for japan
town major town in northeastern china where thousands
upon thousands
japanese speaking chinese
are now running the backrooms writing the software
and doing the beat the business processes and from nature japanese multinationals
and major american multinationals formerly based in tokyo
let me repeat that in case you've missed heard me okay in light of the recent headlines from china
tens of thousands of japanese speaking chinese
we are today
running the backrooms of major japanese multinationals from delhi and wear it is now a
maybe would sign a one to the blue and is zero to the green and
finally squares fit
and then that would be a plane the third
the third dimension here would be the one of the euro and you have a
plane in failing threshold of sources point five that would provide a cut off point
decision boundary if the two classes have different misclassification cost the boundary might move
but it would still be the plane would provide the fit
if is a false alarm false dismissals problem where false alarm seven times more expensive
forces was also expensive false alarm that you might move the decision boundary to minimise
cost but it will come from that single fit playing in the model would be
your left hand is
the a function of x the constant weighted linear terms
and here i guess you have to label one minus one they have decision boundary
zero that's mentioned in the
now this is a straight line has its has its value people can do wonderful
things with aggression if you use the right input
but more flexibility would be very nice and decision trees provide
almost the completely opposite way of looking at things where
the first make split
and say on first solve the whole problem with one single question and typically a
single variable single threshold and try to see what split amongst all the variables
with best separates two classes so here t i o five
we're fit greater than five we call it
and it's less than five you would the
so read this
the yes goes to the left to read this
and then you continue iteratively looking at those two sides sort of independently so the
data is fresh look at the first look at all the variables and all spots
are possible on the two sides of the tree
and continued to carve the space of classifiers
with different
you get at the end something that's equivalent to an expert system rule
that if tn is in the range two five and PE is one of the
sets in one and two and three it's bad otherwise it's good would be a
summary of the decision tree
normally be given training data cap in the number of cases
here the output variable y for all x
former vector
the measured values of attributes winding response out x being predictors
your data
this is where
none statisticians suspicions disagree how to look at things statisticians think of there being the
true underlying distribution there and that you've somehow draw a random sample from the distribution
and i think it's a useful way looking at things
the computer scientist
as a rule don't have as much
until the work that they don't have as much respect for noise or uncertainty in
the number number of machine learning techniques remember early on would push their products there
the models until they could exactly answer all the training data
but it is you know that leads to overfit because you fitting the noise as
well as the
so there seems to be a much more common understanding of not wanting to model
to be too complex at some point in eating regularisation so
the two so the two methods
that will try to minimise the risk
there is a loss function averaged over the
the output variables and the fitted model
ordinary least
ordinal regression is the least squared error loss function
the minimum can be found
instantly with over all are with regression so that's one reason so popular is the
math good this kind of thing
drunk looking for skis outside the street lamps they ask him why
you probably lost in
in the bard inches the the lights better here so sometimes that's what happens with
using regression the methods so beautiful
that's used in places one it's not appropriate the trees are
and neural nets and clustering and support use heuristic algorithms to iterative nature
so there are much slower compared to
so let's look at his
here's an example
the third stage
take an x four
we use all this lot here to train with
we try to test rx four
we don't need for
type should we test using x four
how we produce
y four
from this trained estimator using that block of the data
so we now have finished the fourth stage
we carry on
the same thing for the fifth stage
we have a complete
set of
based on every
member of the sample
we can compare in some way
which is convenient to ask why
and z
OK that will give us some estimate of our generally called generalisation error
but it can be any measure performance you like
so that's what happens with
cross validation
it should be
that are not
it doesn't
i mean there is good practice you
come across bits of this in the lab this afternoon for instance
it's very important that there is no
irrelevant ordering
in your training samples
if you put everything in
if let's say it was a classification problem and you put all the class eighty
ones in the first half of the sample and order to be one the the
second of the sample
the whole thing will break down
typically one assumes
these are independent samples that here
and you would
randomly ordered them to stop in order to
artificial ordering
within the sample
we talk about in the lab this afternoon because you'll see this in action
OK so
all that fits very nicely into the linear in the parameters
type problem
mainly because we have a very nice property there was ten is already mentioned that's
this this idea of a unique minimum
so there's only one right answer for any given structure
any given choice of basis functions
you get
one answer
it's the best answer
but the question of how do we choose these basis functions which has already been
and there's been
answered by the fact that it's hard we don't know what the right answer is
OK so
one way we can do is to
try to adapt them
linear models essentially based on an idea of taking out data axes
pre processing them in some way
through the phys
that's a fixed function we treat it as fixed
o operation
and then
we estimate the parameters
typically the cost function is in some way benign that is
it has this nice property of the unique
that's why we like to
because it is easy optimisation problem and no surprises
as the dimension goes up
these problems can become
OK particularly if we look at the polynomial problem
then you have this
massive explosion in the number of terms as the dimension goes up so if you
example often give you a sixteen by sixteen bit map
OK and you want to
true true that in some picture processing problem with a cubic polynomial function
three million terms of nearly three million
OK most of which will be
totally redundant
you want it with a very very big
starting with a relatively modest picture processing problems
there is a downside to doing these linear things typically wind up with lots and
lots and lots of things that maybe you don't need
and we've got the arbitrary choices
things like
things like the which is that such degrees and we have to
i work with that maybe in cross validation strategy two to
to to make these choices
the question what is the best preprocessor
we think about it that way to choose
this is what we got as a kind of control really so this is what
i tend to think things
signal flow flow through block diagram
what we have is the input data going into some block which does
something five there
that goes into an effective layer which generates an output which is compared to the
generates an error
the air is fed back into the adaptive layer there
to find those w this way
one way forward
be instead of trying to pick
fixed pre processing layer
using some
this go
straight for the jugular
and try to adapt it
directly in the same way as you're adapting
the output layer
optimizing the output layer
what about adapting or optimizing
this preprocessing
and that's what we talk about the rest of this
OK the multilayer perceptron is the archetypal
version of this approach is not the only one but it's the most