the rental
values how their fluctuating from
from a to a to respect for example or you want to see
the traffic in some places some drastic change
compared to
previous months or weeks
so and when that happens people want to know what is the main reason is
because of the
population growth for or some breakdown or
there are you know rules
you know somebody the
being or something and so forth
and you'll be surprised that you know sometimes you know
in a large
you know huge countries you have various
administrative departments they don't necessarily communicate each other so for example let's say
somebody digging the road
probably influenced the local municipality
but not necessarily traffic control devices for example
so they want to change the signal and then you come there and then you
realize are going to morning you try to see which way i can
get out of this place and go somewhere
there was a classic movie thing was done by israeli forces
most beautiful program and bureaucracy
for this person who comes from
escaped from the mental asylum
man is defined
you know what they call these digging devices you know that compression one
goes into the main traffic
and if the
the police things this is a legitimate one they put barriers to protect it
and then the the the water management people think all we have to stop the
what this topic nobody knows and this guy seriously misleading the thing
so finally it goes on for a week in the whole film you can't stop
laughing and you know you can't sit on your journey anymore to what
so it's actually
marking the government and how they work and lack of communication and finally they recognise
that the lost the patient from the mental asylum
so so it's it's really
the contest mining might help
you know what this is you know we been missing person year
road is being that there may be you make some connection
OK so
classification association rules
so in this case
i'm not going to
go talk about this association rules this is another very big area
guideline in brackish aggarwal
i think it did this paper
kind number n so
not more than maybe ten or fifteen years ago
this paper is quite simple
you know
you don't need more than a high school education
to understand that
and that is probably cited no more than ten thousand times more
and the guy's not elected to the academy
USA canada national academy which is
very tough to elected
that it was such an infinite
influential one
he created tool
two and i was almost
kennedy international conferences of these qualities
and solar cell journals
from that one page
and that's association rules
and basically what the association rules do is that
let's see you you have a relational
that is given to you
and and then you have features so what you're doing is you're trying to find
the patterns
let's say
beta one taking to this value peter to take into this value and so forth
and if you see that
then you say that
you know this is the secret we have the feature that in his context but
here we used
all classifiers as especially tribute but they don't have to be so basically in his
a set of values here a set of rounds here what you're saying is if
i see the set of values
there's is a good chance i will see these values so in some sense what
he's doing is is doing
between group of values to group of
that that's what association rules and then you give two parameters and one parameter is
the probability to see
the pattern
of all these values
and the other one tells you that
what is the confidence that means if i have seen the x values
what is the chance that i'm going to see this one you give you a
that means there are cases that x part is true
but this is not his fault
so that gives you
less than one hundred percent accuracy so so basically support means that how many instances
i have
has this pattern
both ex
and c to be true
that's the probability that is that is
and then sees that tracy part of x how many times seized that is the
so one of these two parameters is given
when you meant to find all the combinations of these problems
and and that's what association rules
and in our case
we are not interested in very general
patterns but we are only interested in RDF group of values
all features that tells you
and then also boosting with soft margins i'm going to talk about later so we
have a slightly modified loss function and
and these weights it's actually quite similar to logistic regression
let's try to understand what's
what this level reaching on what is actually doing
i mean this is essentially an optimisation technique so into the optimisation technique which is
already known which has been analysed before was in
optimisation in the field of optimisation was the one of coordinate descent and i'm showing
you that according to send essentially what what leveraging doing
OK let me introduce what call consensus
so this might be negative so you might not you should not use the like
the way the classification error but these extract so they use this some of the
DNA label of x and so many use this then these rates can also be
then it's the distribution anymore so this distribution property only comes from the use of
the relative entropy will from the exponential function
so it's a kind of a special case
OK so
gordon descent
let's say we would like to minimize a function that is a function of several
variables let's say b j j variables OK
and particularly simple strategy to minimize this function is that we iteratively selecting one very
minimize with respect to that variable and then select another
OK and continue iterating this until you have reached the minimum
there's actually converges when
one historian i mean
under certain conditions the conditions include conditions on the function and also on the order
of selecting these very points when you select always the same variable you probably want
to minimize function if the function is not smooth you might doesn't converge
to the minimum
so how
OK so how do you choose these directions so that different strategy you could for
instance choose these variables just at random
that already works under certain conditions but made might not be the most efficient way
this something which is called round robin essentially you go you start with the first
variable then the second third and so on you just go over the all the
there is also not very efficient when you have a very large number of variables
that's another method which is called gauss southwell scheme
so that's selecting the variable which has the largest gradient component so you look at
all the variables sorry
you look at all the variables you compute the gradient in in in that direction
and then choose the variable which has the largest gradient component so the largest absolute
value of the great in that direction
OK that is called gauss southwell the message and
the show you will see is actually doing
and then you could of course also choose the direction which leads to the maximum
improvement of the objective so but this is much harder to find k
so in this converges under certain conditions i'm going to outline these conditions no
OK so maybe
to make it very explicit how this related to boosting OK so i to leverage
its abeid leveraging the only for hypotheses in the hypothesis set
OK now i'm doing three iterations of leveraging
so initially all the rights of the of these poor possesion persisted as year
now in the first iteration we just choose one hypothesis which has the largest gradient
component points
that might be this
the second hypothesis
so if two different sets of first one set of others on the hypothesis set
on i mean that we have policies and the hypothesis that has not
and then we have this on which is chosen in the right so this is
the first iteration so i for one is this value
this is associated with the second hypothesis so this up to to
little is equal to this OK in the first iteration i mean this mapping between
these two
OK so the second iteration you might use of this could have
this is the reward is
the escape from water escape
that's a rule
the mutant do they eventually acquired memory
right they they do if you know what this is what we call or what
if you
forced them to do it many taken on much longer than one week
eventually they find their way
two to find the proper what they know
if you do that if you look at animals
in some of the activity in the brain
actually campus independent some other parts of the brain is compensating
there is the second backup mechanism we
but we don't usually use
one among the interviews
so we have yes if you look at the
memory which is another
paradigms task
which is known to be
OK with independent you know if you are surgically removing the campus around and then
they can do some kind of task memory task
you know they can do it
and for those kind of task of course this animal
is not
i will try to emphasise different kind of memories i'm only right now talking about
focusing on
this because i will memory we take all the credit memory can depend on the
current web
and the spatial memory is one of those
OK i skip this
that's right
taking longer than i thought i want to introduce you to
just following this question
put a different kind of memory
called working memory that probably some of you have heard of this political phrase
working memory is very crucial
for the data
for me
typical typical approach
although became working memory probably is due to ageing
if the old often grace the my grasses i can find way i put the
grasses minutes ago because my mind was something else and i have more of the
we find
to find it so in other words
if you're working memory the working well
can you hold information
of specific information for some period of time while you're doing something else
and then you can accomplish what you have to do
and it is known that the working memory is very
each dependent
so o
it is different compared to their spatial memory where you acquired by
many training center and p BP the training and gradually acquired the memory this is
the sort of one short thing and in the short-term memory which is we you
know where i put them in the rest of the here today this morning
it's not going to be used for tomorrow
that information is not useful because i'm putting somewhere else
but this one is different this this one is the testing working memory with the
it's called eight on radio maybe see appendix express
the central area from which the eight arms
the project
the residual so this is the difference between the correct output and the actual output generated
by the current weight vector the current function so this is a vector of residuals and now we're trying
to actually minimize a squared error so these square
those residuals the norm squared of that vector is the sum
of the squares of those residuals so this is our error term
and what we do in a ridge regression is actually introduce a
regularization term which is controlling the norm of
the weight vector that we use so we trade off we minimize W over a term that
involves the norm squared of W scaled by a parameter lambda which is referred to as the
regularization parameter plus this error term which is
dependent on W through that function G that
or through this X W here so xi depends on W as
well so this is our error terms so the choice of W will attempt
to make the error term small but not if that involves
making a very very large norm weight vector so it's
trading complexity of the weight vector with the error on
the on the training data so this is the optimisation
that is adopted for ridge regression so let's just run through it see what
happens well we can explicitly write our xi squared as Y
minus X W Y minus X W in a product with itself if we multiply out this in a product we get the following and then if we set the derivative of this quantity equal
to zero we get the following equation X X
primed X W that comes from this term here which with a
factor two but I've cancelled the two and we take the X primed Y on to the other side and this lambda W comes from the derivative of
this term so this is the derivative of this set equal to zero
and treated as an equation okay so this is what
we're trying to solve and clearly we can solve it by just inverting
this matrix and that in the indeed gives us what's known as the primal
weight vector solution so we use the term primal to mean the explicit
representation in the of the weight vector in the feature
space now in this case it's in the input space but if we were doing
in a more complex feature space it would again be in that
in that feature space so this is the primal solution
vector all I've done is just invert this matrix and apply it to this side here and it's got by just setting the derivative of this equal to zero so notice
because it's a linear function we are optimizing there's
unique solution well and a quadratic loss so it's a convex
loss as a unique solution and we can actually
explicitly write it out and we can find it by solving a set
of linear equations is very straight forward and if we want a regress on a new data point we can just
take the weight vector and take the inner product with that
new data point and here we have the explicit representation so this is just you know regularized least squares regression
so far it's referred to as ridge regression so
now what I want to show you is that that can now be
actually performed in a kernel defined feature space so this
is where we showing the power of the kernel method and how it can be used or this algorithm can be
used in combination with the kernel defined feature space
so okay the key idea is that you need a a so-called jewel
representation of that weight vector so instead of that explicit vector we are going to express the weight vector W as a linear combination of the
training data so we're gonna express the weight vector in terms of the
training data here is the expression that we're looking
at W is just a sum with weighting coefficients alpha rhi
of the training data now that's a you might say well how how do I know that's gonna be the case well in this
case we can actually write that down that equation that we
had for W and we can actually express W by taking this on
to the other side and dividing through by lambda we
express W in terms of these other terms in the equation and if we bring the factor X primed out front we see in fact W is
expressible as X primed time some vector which I'm denoting here alpha so alpha is just one
over lambda Y minus X W so we have okay it involves W but we've
shown that the solution does in facts lie in the span
of the training data by that manipulation well in a
sense that's almost a no brainer I mean in in because what we are doing is computing in a products with
hypothesis they say that well maybe on comparable to by let's try that and they
do chemistry experiment in the revised the hypothesis and so on but this also seems
like something which you could use active learning and that's what that's what these people
so in this setting each unlabelled point corresponds to potential compound and it turns out
that the chemist came up with a very high dim dimensional descriptions space for these
compounds was literally something like one hundred forty thousand dimensional some incredibly high dimensional where
it captures a lot of the chemically interesting features
each point is going to label either active it binds to the target or inactive
and and now the querying process actually corresponds to a chemistry experiment and so they
were able to
they were able to some sort of traction on this fairly difficult in problem
using their active learning method
here's another example this was from a pedestrian detection experiment that was conducted on the
streets of paris i believe in this is by yotam abramson in your freind and
q the setting was the
inside inside a car a camera was placed
taking you know images of the of the world in front and the idea was
was to find the pedestrians the hope was that you know this would eventually become
part of some cars software and make cars more safe for pedestrians
that kind of thing k so each data point in this case is not an
entire image but simply a rectangle within an image and these rectangles can be of
different sizes and the label is is that of pedestrian or not and using this
using active learning the world they were able to
avoid having to label too much of the data OK so you can collect masses
of data just by having the camera sitting there in your car but but it's
it's really laborious to have to label it so what they did is they developed
a system in which some human beings sat and looked at a whole bunch of
these images and drew boxes around the human beings and they came up with the
classifier that basically you know was able to correctly classify those examples anything that humans
had encircled was basically negative example so they were able to come up with the
classifier that with those examples and then
and then they went through some sort of refinement process
you know the classifier was then applied to whole bunch of other images and if
it if there was something was really unsure about human being was asked to label
that OK so for instance if there was something on the sidewalk that was like
a phone booth
maybe that's something the classifier will be unsure about or a fire hydrant
anyway so these are just two examples of
of active learning and it turns out that there's actually
a large number of
with active learning algorithms out there
which which have already enjoyed a certain amount of success
and in some sense you know
since it's in mencap occasions it's really needed to you
you know you have to use something and so on
so the whole sort of a collection of of active learning strategies has emerged
and so
i'll start by talking about a certain class of these strategies and and then and
then talk about
what happens when we when we try and get some sort of basic statistical guarantees
for these kinds of algorithms what what what turns out to be the hurt
OK so so there's a lot of strategies to look like this have a bunch
of very natural sort of thing have a bunch of unlabeled points in you start
by just choosing a bunch of them at random to get labels for just to
sort of get the lay of the land and once you have that
then you do have some sort of candidate or you have some idea of where
the decision boundary is going to be because you have some sort of candidate boundary
and want to look at that boundary you can then
you know decide well you know the point i should queries is the one i'm
most uncertain about there's no point wearing this one since i know exactly what is
going to be so why not choose something near the boundary
OK so there are strategies that for instance
look for the point closest to the boundary
which in this case would be say this one
this variant that might look for the most uncertain point where for instance the distance
from the boundary might trends the transformed into some sort of posterior probabilities and in
that case this might also be the most uncertain point
there are some variations in in which the consideration is that well
and although this might be closest to the boundary it's kind of far away from
the other data and so maybe a better point to pick is one of these
because if you have the label it would most influence
it would it would lead to the largest update it would most influence your your
classifications of the other examples OK so rather than simply being the most uncertain point
it's the most likely to change too or to shrink the overall amount of uncertainty
and there are various ways to formalize this
OK so there's a large class of
heuristics in this form
and actually it seems to me this seems like a very sort of sensible strategy
but there's one sort of basic difficulty that emerges and so let me let me
just outline what that is
basically in you know in this sort of setting we want to come up with
the classifier that does well on the natural distribution out there
you know the underlying distribution from which we have a few samples
so in the first step of this process we have chosen a few random points
we've got the labels and the labelled points we have because they are chosen randomly
truly represent the underlying distribution
a random sample from the underlying distribution
once you start the active learning process however as time goes on the training sample
the i minus one and two
the i
view the
operation the structure is a mapping
mapping one structure to another data structure one from before the one after
they form already it's nicely mathematics
and of course the cost
of operation i
it means it CI
and now i really do
is defined
the potential functions
which means the set of data structures
into the rails
associated with every day structure now
is a
they are real valued
often in potential
such that
the d zero
it is equal to zero
so the initial potential is zero
and the CIA
it's great to equal to zero for all i potential can never be nonnegative just
like the bank account because the potential is essentially representing the bank account if you
in the
accounting method
so we always want the potential to be
nonnegative now actually
there are time series potential functions we violate both of these properties
OK there's some really interesting potential arguments which don't violate this but for the kind
the simple ones were going to be doing
in this class will just assume that these tend to be true
but you may find the we will actually see sometimes where the zero isn't zero
but it doesn't matter
OK but generally this is where we're going
in the potential type of potential function argument there were doing
OK so i just want let you know that there are bigger and bigger space
of potential function arguments and the one give
showing here
OK so then under these circumstances
we define the advertised
i have
with respect to
as this is one of these formulas that you
stay within your budget
so there was code one hand we have some other ideas
it was code number
was the selection that we made
where was it
code to
which doesn't go over budget but it didn't quite is that the whole budget and so noticed we could
make a change in soviet buying that there's a one
could right top
we could look of final one by
the there's are next door instead and then made expected length shorter which is good
and then we look this guy
it was my silly idea
sorry about the wonders on the one zero okay
and i went over budget
and it was a great labour find a proof that when that didn't work
we have to think about strings but now the kraft inequality we could demonstrate way up
no point even trying this thing it's violated kraft inequality so it can't be uniquely decodable
in blue there
we have to be optimal code
ant is
see seven which i want of
which is why we reverse the services is also uniquely decodable
and you can see the difference between the prefix code in blue
which is sort of sense walk through the supermarket from one side to the other
buying codewords that you were confused with each other
whereas the silly
back-to-front one
see six
bought one one zero one zero zero which are prefixes of each other and are on the same
why coordinate in this in this picture
all right
so that's the kraft inequality
gets right up to the budget that uses the full budget
we will call it complete
a complete code is one has some particular myself i
equal to
if you have chosen yourself a complete code he advises you can probably go back
to the supermarket makes switches and get yourself a shorter
code so is a bit silly not to use the complete code
all right
and as we observed easy to decode codes are prefix codes
let's address the practical
question or not the theoretical version very first practice
two five minutes on each
the theoretical question is how well can we do
symbol codes
so if i give you any ensemble
x and if you come up with the best symbol code by whatever methods
how small can expected length
the definition of the expected length is summarized he i
now i
i am
we're not going to show that whatever you do
with a simple code you can't be the entropy and will also identify what you
need to do in order to get
close to the entropy of all the way to the end
and it's all about
figure out what these expected length should be
let me give us
a clue
i'm going to define
the ideal
for codeword to be
ways to
one over the probability
thank goodness
so i'm gonna
introduces the definition
namely the shannon information content
so i say
for this thing which are very here namely the square or minus m squared is
given by some
over all the amplitudes of transverse oscillations of this thing absolute value squared summed over
all the frequencies and remember was the frequency of this way going around the string
and this is true for the left and for that i overstepped
one can go on to do similar calculations for the angular momentum one finds for
instance and they want do it here about that this being the angular momentum
is less than or equal to alpha prime m squared it can go up to
to alpha prime m squared for relativistic string
this is to be compared to an angular momentum which grows like square root of
the energy for a rigid bar
and actually this is the beginning of what you see these edge trajectories
now we don't want to spend too much time here on these
a classical a relativistic strings even though they may
play a role in nature as cosmic strings if cosmic strings exist out in the
and then they would have very similar properties to this classic relativistic strings but here
we are interested in quantum theory right now
he is you see that if i go back
the mass
like all all other properties of this classical strings are continuous but that's of course
natural because the amplitudes are arbitrated continuous parameters here but of course elementary particles have
a discrete spectrum of masses in spin and everything else and
this will be automatic upon quantization so quantization first of all it is important
because we don't want continues must parameters for our elementary particles they have to be
discrete and that's of course and automatic and quantum theory you know
now in practice the way this works is that this amplitude of oscillation squared with
appropriate normalisation becomes simply numbers of excitation in the same way that the amplitude of
the electromagnetic wave
becomes in the quantum theory number of photons
well in the same way this amplitudes of oscillation are traded by integer numbers of
excitations running around this training this will automatically k take care of the discretisation of
these various quantum numbers
what looks harder at first
is how to obtain massless particles after all we want this theory to describe photons
and gravitons and everything else and if you look at the expression of the previous
page it was a positive definite mass squared as you would expect for a relativistic
strings so how on earth what's interesting describe massless particles
well this is what get quantum mechanics comes to the rescue nice beautiful way
it quantum strain has got out of the ground state energy which could be negative
and you can actually compute these very easily what is the this is given by
so remember to gain for those of you that a
no this expressions from QED we have here in my squared which would have been
which is given by the sum
of later amplitude square the
the classical theory and the quantum theories has become operators they have nontrivial commutation relations
and that is the ground state energy it has energy which comes from the ordering
of additional predators and which is simply given by the sum over all frequencies of
the field the one half its bottleneck right that the ground state energy of quantum
oscillator when you summit over all frequencies that the ground state energy for quantum field
so we just do the same here you know it's one half of the frequencies
and have to sum over all land and there are d minus two transverse oscillators
these the dimension of the string
and when you calculate the sum you find minus the over minus two over twenty
four basically this infinite sum is minus one of twenty four now you may well
be about these
being nonsense how and if it's some minus one of twenty four obviously there's visiting
normalisation here namely this quantum fluctuations of the string create an infinite block of energy
density that we have to stop doctor away very much like in the corresponding calculation
of the cosmic force
however this subtraction is thought only an ambiguous and the reason is purely dimensionality
if we introduce a small part of epsilon
to cut off the short distance fluctuations of this training this up fraction of the
energy density can only be proportional to one over actual square there's not the scale
around and is uniquely defined for you this number which is minus one of twenty
now that's a bit upsetting because it means that the mass squared off the ground
state the first thing is negative actually if these more than two
and this is called the vacuum
so this is this thing in its ground state it has negative mass squared if
we think about the first excited states well they correspond to exciting the lowest possible
frequency of waves the lowest frequencies one
so you are applying one of these raising operators one for the very first for
frequency minus one and and these have been mass which is one minus minus two
over twenty four but you see these are not articles vector particles they have the
sure because they have this index j which points around in transverse
direction directions now the only massless particles that we know which have only transverse polarization
physical states are the massless particles and therefore if this theory is to be at
all consistent with this first excited states better be massless and if you check what
this tells you this tells you that dimension can only be twenty six
so this is the place where you see the first characteristic features of string theory
critical dimension to the dimension cannot be anything it has to be twenty six and
it actually on excitation plus muscle estates which are quite an unintuitive from the point
of view of classical
theory but which are of varying the quantum mechanics
other than the states if you think about the the remaining states they all have
positive mass
that gives me
i can help it
seven percent error
so i have a seven percent uncertainty
multiply by point o seven
i cannot trust this any better
and thirty seven centimetres
so now i'm going to put the markers out
five metres and thirty one centimeters
this is the five metre mark
thirty one centimeters
and i love for thirty seven centimetres on either side
it's here
and thirty seven centimetres on this site
that is you
going to set the angle of thirty degrees
i have a
we need a woman power
state here
stay out of the fire line
and when the ball hits
jump on it jump on it
everything under control
five make sure market right five meters three one that looks about OK
and now i have to
change the angle to thirty degrees
as close as i can do it
you are
the things are called
what you can argue now
and successfully
you could say perhaps you have been a little bit too conservative
on the other i admit that
but believe me when i did this morning despite six times at the error in
the zero
it was quite substantially high differences were sometimes fifteen centimeters
and so i had no choice
but it look like we were a bit
on the conservative side
suppose now i repeated this experiment
at sixty degrees
what will change
OS change
no because the size of hundred twenty degrees is the same as the sign
sixty degrees
you have to offer you
the final sixty is the same as the science
one hundred twenty
if you allow for uncertainty
one degree on decide
you'll find exactly the same numbers
because of the symmetry of the sine curve
so again you're of by two percent
no difference
so this prediction is unchanged
however i want to ask you one question to see whether you are
half alert or half-asleep
at thirty degrees
so this
at sixty degrees giving it the same initial speed
you will see this
it will have to it
here within the uncertainty of our measurements at the same location
it will of course
of course go much higher
you can calculate that
because you have to use this forty equation for the height
that goes with the sign of all
sign of of four for sixty degrees is way higher than thirty degrees
now comes the question
real this trajectory
take longer
then this one
or will they take the same amount of time
was for the same amount of time
it was for long
which for short
i'm happy with
one set of fingers and unhappy with another set of fingers
what is the horizontal velocity
of the golf balls
when it takes off
if the velocity is the same
in both cases
that this horizontal component is way larger than this horizontal component
and if they travel the same distance
then this trip must take longer
because it's the horizontal component in the x erection that determines how long it will
take to go from here
suppose i shall it's straight out how long do you think it will take to
hits here
it has no horizontal component
all right
think about this this trajectory will take longer
but it ends up at the same point
all right
number three
you come here
so i don't have to change these markers
they are perfect
provided that nature is willing to reproduce itself
sixty degrees
so we'll go away high
but if all goes well
it two hit
within the same marks
you're right
thank you very much wonderful look
many by uncertainties were not so
that we were lucky was the jackpot
comfortably was in the area
close to this one so i'm quite happy
that i took the certain because the way i did
can we recover the ball that someone see it
think of you
all right
now we will
enter different parts
of this lecture
which is actually
very sad parts
you know the people in africa
should monkeys
there's a monkey unitary
very happy
and here is the hunter
will never took a to one
he has a
a gun which is a golf ball gone
any aims that go
right at the
he shoots it with a certain velocity
the golf balls
this b
the horizontal component
going to see that again and again
the zero cosine of
and the vertical component
equals the zero
sign of
this b
by increasing value of y
this be my increasing value
this global this this goal of god
the set of all theorems of the logic
one possible definition
let's look at
this definition for this model logic
so model logic model came
we find
as set of theorems generated in the following way
all instances of propositional tautologies k
and all instances of this true more axioms theorems
we just had made it
this is just syntactic
so no meanings attached to a particular form
we just say that we have a bunch of false positive way to generate and
more fun
anything that can be generated this way which is called an hearing
and the principle of minus one in
after at implies she is she is here
and the the substitution principle
in g
his appearance and it is obtained from g by
uniformly families
for the last
and this principle of generalisation
she is here and then box g
so this is the syntactic where you define
now again come back to this notion of syntax and semantics
the questions we ask is whether
all the appearance generated this way out of the different
is every valid formula here in k they every form found from can be generated
following syntactic procedures
and the second year
for this model logic k a systematic procedure show the form
we were not discussed here
again this is this
we introduce the syntax and semantics
and then once we define k we can define
the whole family of models you just extending k with some more action
so this is usually called no more
most if not all logics using AI
it was a normal modal logic
including his term
logics using agency staff
so would not not a normal modal logic is defined k with a set of
seven years
this extension
it is defined as
except that you had
o point you at all
axioms that you're standing
some standard access
i just this
so there's actually team box like or people
which we already
which character well
and there is actually a
x four
diamond dogs by the
what why
i just called the logic that extends came
OK and putting action
for example
OK to form a larger
is obtained by adding to k
p four
this axiom is actually
corresponds the shape of right
for example
is found
the knowledge
days of the war
we have is related to itself
and now what's interesting is that
his car goes both ways
it flexes his muscles
so the the model action actually characterised precise class frames
for which their
friends reflects
after all this data itself
the next thing
he was related to the
the reason
our in our
practically is just
every feature points in the ground this
is related to a
in the first
so are to
that's right
yes and no
i mean because
we end up here
metric is also
in our going from
there's always a successor
now the correspondences
correspond to let's train
from the semantic frames
or vice versa
by we need
again we
for the correspond
three classes of frames
for example
another incompressible when you decrease the volume
of the gas
by fifty percent that's no problem
it's impossible to do that
four liquid
in liquids the atoms and molecules
effectively touch each other whereas in gases they are very far apart that's why you
compress the gas
if you take everyone one atmosphere
the density
thousand times less
then the density of water
it tells you is that the
much further apart
there's an experimental facts
that there is a simple relation
mean the pressure that you see there
the volume of the gas
the temperature of the gas in degrees kelvin
and the number of molecules that you have
now when you see the word molecules i may often mean atoms i realize that
kryptonite and i on
i atomic gases
and that
o two and h two n c o two
well actually gases so i'll use that word molecules even when i mean atoms and
maybe vice-versa
just four
relation that exists
between these quantities
he calls and rt
four volume
is the number
of moles
i'll get back to that
are is the universal gas constant
which is a point three
o degree kelvin
and t must be
in degrees kelvin
so what is more
the more
has always about six point zero two
times ten to the
twenty three
adams in the case that you have
you call it molecules
and this number
it's called advogato is not
that's the definition
a more
if you take a model of helium or more of oxygen or sio two n
two doesn't matter
always has
this number
small molecules approximately
now each of these substances
very different masses
if i take for instance
then one mole of carbon would be very close to twelve grams
if i take
one mole of helium
very close to fourgrams
and if i took
oxygen two o two
then one mole
would be very close to fifty grams thirty two gram so
masses are very different in the mall
but not the number of molecules or the number of atoms
when i take a neutral atoms
then we have the nucleus
in the nucleus
contains protons and
it has z protons
and it has and neutron
protons are positively charged
and has the electrons
it is a neutral
there's almost no weight in the electrons you can almost ignore everything is into protons
and in the neutrons
and plus z
it's called
eight and that's called the atomic mass number
let's look at
carbon in a little bit more detail
we have carbon
and i call it carbon twelve finale doshi shortly y
carbon has always six protons in the nucleus otherwise it is card
what it has six neutrons
then eight twelve that's why we call the carbon twelve
so the atomic
mass number of carbon is twelve
but if you had for instance
carbon fourteen which happens to be radioactive
again six six protons otherwise it wouldn't be carbon would have eight
neutrons now
and now you would have atomic mass number
would be fourteen
the mall
is this numbering grounds
so you see carbon
is the
atomic mass number ingram you twelve
if you go to helium
two protons and two neutrons
so is for this very senior fourgrams
if you take oxygen
eight protons
eight neutrons
so is sixteen but you have o two gas for
so now you atomic mass number has to be doubled thirty two
so in a more of
o two is there for thirty two grams
i got always number is defined
through carbon twelve
if you take twelve grams
of carbon twelve
if you count the number of atoms that you have
then you find exactly avocados number that's the definition of the number and that's very
so what we have there
six point zero two times ten to the twenty third
the mass of the proton and the mass of the neutron
nearly all
i wrote down and tool for the mass of the neutron of course that should
have been more than
so the mass of the molecule
or whatever the case may be
it would be
this number eight
because that the some of the protons and neutrons times the mass of the neutrons
and protons
and so this is a time approximately i should put we here one point six
six times ten to the minus
twenty seven kilogram
there's no individual mass of either an atom or molecule and all the information you
have there and that's
of course on the web
so let's do a
trivial example
i take
gas is any kind of gas you choose whatever you want
and i take one atmosphere
so that means that the pressure
one zero three
times ten to the fifth moscow
i do it at room temperature
so t
two hundred ninety three degrees
and i take in all cases
only one model
so and this one
and i'm asking you know
what will be the volume of the gas
well you take the gas law
it tells you that
equals nrt
divided by p
you know and this one
you know i
there are
so scaling up and down weights doesn't change the place where
the activation is zero
which is where the red line
so i was playing with a single
now what we're gonna do next is going to about learning with a neural network consisting of just one neuron
learning means that you get yourself in data
and the data
takes the form of a set of input
so the target specifies
roughly what you want the neuron say all the neural network to say
in response to
the input
and i have label
and runs through
and the idea of moving is that we just
learning is just a silly name four
the parameters
that's that's
the output of your neural network why
when you show the accent
after and
floral at
when someone says
something like that happened
what you'd say the the middle ground just tell me that the objective function plays
an now minimize all the by get function
which measures how good the weights are
hand start off with energy is gonna have and turns into which measures how close
to you is to why in my measure of closeness is gonna be
why then is my shorthand four
why don't children
and a weight vector w
okay so the w dependence lurks in why here
and in this way
this objective function is a sum of terms
each which is the looks like this
or it looks like
this depending whether the target
the target
is one
if one matches the target
the objective function given easier
and if why doesn't match the target you penalty that increasingly big
if there are few are
you could think of gene has being
thee information content of the data
from the point-of-view of the neuron who
views his output why as being the correct probability distribution for the data
so it's the information content
all the data are completely it is
the description length
of the data
the view why
as being
the correct
now when i said the data and being a bit imprecise what i mean is
the set of students
so if you if you've already been told where the data inputs what x is our
and in some sense now i'm going to tell you that he's this is what
the description length would be if used a perfect
many coder
or other compression methods to encode them using this neuron
okay so
show an example of this
so is a single neuron and his and data
the sort of data we could be talking about might be we're trying to run vegetable floating factory
the pigeons are gone on strike because they realized how good they are compared to
the computer and they will be paid the same wages supercomputers so now we're trying
get a simple neuron to replace the pigeon
job the pigeon is to sort the potatoes and carrots or the reasons from the petals or whatever doing
got some labelled data so we measured x one and x two for ten objects
five and them were raisins and five foot pedals
okay so the classes are
coloured there
so we know what class
each other ten things in
because x one connects to
and what i showed you in this input space x one x two is how
neuron can produce a function that
is u around
soft sigmoid ramp
so what is learning learning is minimizing an objective function like this with respect to w
what does that's involved well if you're a sensible minimizing things you'll say
it is easy to compute the gradient
and the answer is yes it's easy to compute the gradient
so you get the gradient
look like gene
which is the energy
by w
and then you do some sensible downhill
thing based on the gradient
be very simplest thing you could do with gradient is called gradient descent
that's not a sensible thing to do because it doesn't
the sort of co-variance that you'd like appropriate treatment
vector spaces and their duals
this mixes up vector spaces their dual which is a crime
but lots of people do it
so you just look at the gradient
many say let's make a step in the direction of the gradient
so that's gradient descent
hand this
parameter here
is by neural network people called the learning rate
and that's an ad hoc parameter that you have to set somehow
it's fairly easy to
and this is left as a homework exercise
that's the gradient can be written as the sum over all of these
the examples
of t-minus why
well there are cases where it's not the PRD software actually gets to make this
the task is quite clearly world
estimates y given x
just some loss is minimized obviously
you could have something like a squared loss and then you just take the difference
between the two values square
let's say we're talking about money
and i care about the actual difference between the value that i was going to
try and
and the value that
having estimated so it may not necessarily be a square loss it may be a
loss of some kind
while this might be really nice and easy to implement
don't automatically assume that this is the right thing
just a cautionary tales at the end of the day
ask whoever as to solve this problem
this regression problem what they really think is called
that might look at the very surprised
you might want to go into and string
for instance i might want to find out
what to
chances are that the g
four and a year
it's just some sequence
you might want to annotate all you
so this is what happened with the
telstra speech recogniser a couple of years ago
have you got any australian here like native-born australians
can you read
this one and case that one if possible in
mister howard's accent
because this is basically what happened they part of this feature is right speech recognition
on how mister howard was saying it
and this high pass
you can see why the speech recogniser had quite of trouble
novelty detection
so you
could have things like network use it happened
and with digital
well i think that's a factory status
we want to find out
whether something so is going wrong in the factory where the jet engines blowing up
with a
let's say you're putting in some control system for
a chemical plant well obviously you cannot just go and blow it up in all
possible ways in order to figure out how to
what normal parameters of operation are
what you want to have a system that automatically takes when things are going strange
like was project in the mean
it will be quite costly
so the idea would be well you might want to find unusual events
you might want to clean database let's say for instance somebody just insert garbage into
the database
you might actually also want to find some very typical observations
so it's a bit similar to clustering but not quite so clustering as well find
me prototype
here it's will find me typical observations they could be that there's only one really
typical use
as you can see it's this is not very straightforward problem it's a good start
then i could for instance claimed that those points out here are a bit more
or especially if i have these points here
could say well you know those are really unusual
and maybe those are the boundary two
or maybe only the ones at the boundary everything in the centuries to difficult come
something like that
it depends very much on how you specify your problem
so i
finding a new observation is not an easy thing i mean even so you can
easily derive bounds in those bonds would work for any of those cases
asking the question is actually the heartbeat here
once you've as well
solving is just happily optimizing away
i'll be quick on this because i think it's going to be controversial
so i think machine learning and logic differently two different things
it would be very nice if we could actually merge those two things inefficiently what
efficient way but
i think we're not quite there yet
i'm also not trying to the artificial intelligence
this is
i mean what and what i'm going to talk about is one of the building
blocks that you might want to use it but it's definitely not a i
and it's also not the response in biology
this is one of the traps that people fell into in the eighties
sometimes even now they say it once in a while you hear the story OK
we know how we can
well the system that simulates the brain
we now know how to build intelligent system
this is something that is usually
the reasoning made by people who got the big research grant on building a huge
machine that can simulate the brain
and you see a press release on that
version is
well i have found the really cool machine learning algorithm behaves in an intelligent way
therefore the brain must work like this
problematic things
the ZBDD is zero suppressed binary decision diagrams
i think it's
i forgot the office them bright
right or something you know you can look at
on the
on the internet
this is they think this is probably the most important contribution in the whole of
computer science
some people would say
why why that is
because it seems to be useful
you know doing any complex computationally complex problems this data structure is a very useful
how many of you know could
does anyone know
that is anyone who doesn't know
if a computer scientist should know
but the is a professor from stanford he is it probably the best books
on algorithms and computation as a result
so you know his goal was to write
for computer science
and then after reading three books then he realized that
this is much much harder problem because science doesn't stop
because you want to write about
and then he but there are fantastic plastic machine we're all
one of those today
you know i would be surprised the wealth of information that is there
but anyway he's the guy who wrote
you know what you take because you want to write the next any thought this
is rubbish not four types because they want all the good master do
so he's impact is just phenomenal you know text is written by the guy
and then he saw tatego he writes all nodes all the kinds of bugs
he made and you know the program and how he fix
but the point i was trying to say is now he's writing a book on
and you want to call them
and you want to
drop the word binary i think you want to call it z
zero suppressed binary decision diagram he thinks is one of the best one so he
about four hundred forty pages of discussion
you know when document could attract hundred forty probably you you and i will be
writing pages
so he's very concise no sentence
would be
you know read everything you if you lose one sentence that means you lost
the plot
so he's a very good writer and he has written in one hundred forty pages
so usually
you know then exercise he would give you know you put one time is difficult
to start needs to be able to pieces
three stars means probably turing award
if you saw
so he's writing a book on the so so maybe
a lot of pretty soon
OK what is you know you know this big cat thing i want to say
too much for so you have to go warn read
so typically this is how
binary decision diagrams are written
suppose that you given a boolean expression c and
or DNA
so basically what you're doing is that you're encoding this
drawing a picture like that so
so this is basically a truth table driven is the tree
you know what it truth able right
you build the true
i give all possible combinations and then if the expression is true
the truth value one otherwise
OK so
so here
it's equal to one so let's go through these and see if sequel to one
and equal to one
then we don't care what this is that that is the true
or if c is false that means this expression doesn't play any role
then we have to rely on this road
so you come here if d is true
and if it is true then is one all of the branches must before
so basically we encode the truth table by tree and then you can compress that
in this form so you can you can have its implementation
simply saying that the unfortunate that we can see here can you see solid line
so anyway when you see the slides so
so typically you know that now
come on
OK it's not responding to my thing
OK so
the c to d
is a daughter
OK and c two a is the solid lines
so so basically we compress this into into this form and you can see that
a lot of showing is taking place the first thing is that is the canonical
directed acyclic graph
representing bullion from let's node sharing means identical nodes are shared if there's any sub
branches shared the new share it says that compressed stream some sense
so the idea here is that you can use caching that means past computations
i'll get back to you although you may not need
so we now have the
two opening all the way on the left
they are so close together this is the screen close so close together
can be separated what this is the point with the
one of the things i
and we are going to look
on the screen which is far away
there's is a screen which is going to be that screen
and we want to see
all the constructive interference it means light shows up on the screen and how desperate
to the darkness shows up on that street
so here it is two openings light comes in from the left
and that this this is BLP
and so
i want to know if i look on angle data
seen from
i want to know
kind of that and i will see
let's call this actually equals zero
and we call this x positive action that's negative
you can also say that the sign of data if you want that
it is approximately x divided by albert that's only true
four small angle theta
and with this kind of interference we sometimes have angles of data
which are not small
i want to warn you that this is not something you can use universally they'll
we can use it
so i started now
red light land
six hundred nanometer
that's the light i will use so i use monochromatic light
and we will have the distance
to the
three which is about five hours
the set is here this is about five metres
and we have right light from the red laser
which is a little larger than six hundred nanometers but i just one
right now numbers
and the separation here the
between the two slits
is one quarter of a million
now you may think that is rather small well you see that that's what you
you need a very small values
one of the
two even see this phenomenon
what and this
let's evaluate that is
let's evaluate what the sign is
of theta alpha
and then we will
evaluate of x of and is
and we'll do that for
constructive interference
numbers that you're going to see here
this will construct
and of course if you want to you can do the same exercise for desperate
i need constructive interference
so i have to turn
that's and i make them and times
and i start with an equal zero
well that's easy and is zero
delta zero sign theta and is zero and axl
that's where you will see maximum light
constructive interference obviously
that's the plane
that goes right through the middle of those two opening and the distance
each one of those sources everywhere in the plane
it is of course the same so you expect here
it seems like next
now i don't plus minus one
and i calculate now delta is then i got plus and minus two pi
so to sign
now two point four times ten to the minus three
you can check that
because you know what the
the sign theta is times lab
and i told you will have those
this time is no
and we get n equals one you know lambda is you know what these we
can calculate
the angle
sin theta
and that translates into an exit value of about plus and minus
plus and minus one point two percent
buried here statistically
if you you will see it with four days
the most but not that the if you want to try
what you do is is you put your
finger in front like this and that you think
and when you look at your finger what will probably is it you should see
what's on the
and now i'm moving you finger in and out
i have come where you want to get certain
moving you finger in and out
you know the amount of the homeless
of the of the thing on the screen will vary
and you probably you think quite a long way from actually
and yes me about something close to a slide
and all of a sudden you find your
your vision fusing
and not the way it was before
it's like a weird feeling together with feeling hold onto it don't go
and you have to
and you have to just sort of
you have to hold it for a while because it actually might take ten seconds
for this impression of that the here is anybody getting it
is anybody feel that
if you feel that your c
a three-dimensional shape very
i guess for me if i look and i think that's too much
allow gays to go very slowly if you think about the whiteboard but not too
keep keep the dublin my stop halfway between your finger the whiteboard
in this sort of
usually long position
and really getting this
and what you see
because you see the flowers
it's valentine's card
it's called a heart buried
saint valentine's day the patron saint of love
you guys may be struggling with this but the computer it's easy
the computer we do the cross-eyed admitted did across a bit for me it's just
that the computer says he would write either
you know you're supposed to do with your right i was left died the bit
that you're supposed to have died and then we asked the computer to fuse the
two images
and that's what it sees
that was what you saw it
four of
that's it sees this is a map showing that brightness that is the most distant
i think all one
well the whole
i the computer can you know
can sort of solvent such detailed paper this hidden
so this would be nice to know it
we're going to about stereo problem
and why it's hard to be the
the problem is that the computer has to take
in the left image
for every pixel in the image of a partner in the writing it will match
it so you know you have you know that those here match
notice here but can you doesn't have the benefit of the sticky semantic something like
all of you one time used to argue a lot about you know whether you
would have sort of recognise the things in the image
doing being able to do the matching and i guess now they
received wisdom is that you don't and actually low level
the top level analysis the level of image processing rather than semantics is enough in
principle i mean to enable you
to enable these to a computer program to the math
so it's not necessary to assume that
human vision recognizing reported very
so where does it match
the computer want that
i could be anywhere
and you know we're in trouble if we really have to consider all of those
implicit subsumption relationships
is there any specific question with respect to
t boxes
yes please
you mean that at ministry staff disjoint from faculty
and research assistance are disjoint from faculty are disjoint from administrators stuff
so it might make sense to explicitly say that
people are disjoint from departments and so on
the system doesn't take this for granted one has to
somehow implicitly states that this is the case otherwise the system has not enough restrictions
imposed this meaning that the point in the other thing that is
the usual
technique is to say that it will be
there there's three kinds of employees right
administrators staff faculty and research assistant and nothing else
that's that's all
so we have a so-called cover
we specify that employee
it is under
the disjunction of this one this one and this one and you see
if you specify this you are far away from you know standard modeling languages however
as you
ontology languages and the description logics behind them
modeling facilities that are available in
entity relationship modeling as well as
large parts of the u mailing which
i mean the advantage here is that you have a formal semantics no guessing what
this spend might mean
if we have a look at the definition of chair
i have a look at the axioms here
i can take the i will show you one one text based
just for the
for the impression
and then we see that
we have a chair
find here
as class
and there is
the chair is a person
and there is a restriction on the property had off of fillers of head of
must be
if you see this is for machine processing but it's good that there is a
language that machines can process according to the semantics of the
plus of ontology languages and you use see
this is far more
then just representing triples in RDF triple store and use some triple query language that
just gets you what's listed in all those
triples cell
p PM
semantics that comes into play here because you see it is not explicitly mentioned
the chair is the professor as you have seen on the previous display
this is
exactly represented here
in the definitions for the
head off so it
as you see my my example is life example
here you see the domain restriction and it is obvious that
here we have a specific syntax but no matter what syntax to use
the resulting in the effect is that a chair is professor which is something that
is not explicitly specified in the
xml call that you see that dealing with ontology reasoning systems is more than just
define explicitly model i lost my pen
but that is
this is an an issue of the editing environment to automatically generate the things that
you want to have
now we wouldn't change your reasoning as we said you would add axioms implicitly
right good point yes
yeah good point is now
i think we understand quite
much about the ontology is about the particular about the tee box level i would
like to turn to the instance level to the box level
oh yes please
most query tools to retrieve what's explicit if you have a reason for RDF which
has an
semantics that is not at all easy to understand then you would get the same
love your
so most of the conversation at dinner actually revolved around people falling asleep during talks
after dinner so
so is making a very nervous but you know i noticed some of you have
appearance of have coffee so i can just keep keep an eye on whether there
is any correlation between
this way
anyway i was in a funny mood whenever the abstract to this and this is
got me in this position here i just thought well what i want to talk
about at all as small workshop
among friends right and i don't really want to talk about my own research because
you know
i know about it
it bores me to talk about research but it's fun to talk about you know
kind of the big picture of itself
here's what i mean do i'm gonna
i'm gonna run through sort of
the canonical story we could give to motivate people for why they would want to
be bayesian OK and then i'm going to try to critique that have been not
going to say well do we really believe this
and then i'm just going to jump around and talk about a few of the
questions that i think should really be on our minds and certainly are on my
mind so you know a lot of machine learning involves classification regression clustering and things
like that and we all know that basically we can take any canonical machine learning
problem and write it down in terms of the two components we have some data
we have some model with some parameters and then we have some gold that that's
bayesians we can write out as an inference problem and most people don't really think
about things exactly that way but really you know take canonical problem like linear classification
you have some datasets these crosses and shows you have some models some linear boundary
and rather than thinking of it as some sort of optimisation problem we can think
about it is the problem of inferring some unknown quantity that these parameters from the
data source to predict future labels
this is part of like a canonical tutorial you would give
and you know that the
i and i'm sure all of you
also give for doing this is that we can apply the basic rules of probability
going this sort of learning
we all know what these rules are
we apply it in the context of machine learning and we think of computing posteriors
over unknown quantities given the data by multiplying some likelihood by some prior and renormalizing
and we can do model comparison we can do prediction
this is part of this and blasting through the canonical stories so that we can
critique so that's it that's a really you know in some ways i kind of
feel like that's all we need to know about machine learning the rest is just
sort of mechanics algorithmics and so on
but that's not how most people in the field of machine learning think about this
which surprises me still
let's ask some of these questions well
should all machine learning be bayesian and you know if we think the answer is
yes then why isn't it that will come to that later like you know if
we really think that this basic framework is really elegant y
if i go to
typical conference like ICML why are bayesian papers maybe like ten percent of papers that
so again what i'll do is out of blast through some of the arguments that
these i have given tutorials these are clearly not things i've come up with these
things i picked up from other places i giving tutorials for why i you know
how i try to convince people that bayesianism is the right way to go
OK and then we can go and critique those because we're in in in small
company here and nobody on videolectures is really going to watch this race
right so why should we be bayesian
so one of the arguments is that if we want a system to behave intelligently
should represent beliefs about propositions in the world
and we want to represent the strength of those beliefs numerically in the brain of
artificial agent like a robot for example
and we want some set of rules are calculus for manipulating those transit beliefs
one of the standard arguments you get from the
artificial intelligence point of view is the sort of arguments based on the cox axioms
that are described in james's book and there's a really nice paper by kevin van
horn actually
that is sort of more modern
treatment of this and discusses some of the critiques of those arguments into this spells
those critics so the arguments are basically that if we want to represent the strength
of belief and propositions about the world
assume that we want it's the strength of belief to be somewhere between zero and
one where zero is
that x is definitely not true whereas one is that x is definitely true and
we write down conditional release
what is your strength of belief in x given y
that if we accept certain axioms
and you can read about the if you haven't already
the consequences of these axioms is that belief functions this be of x
b of x given y et cetera
they must satisfy the rules of probability theory
including bayes rule so this is one way
we can justify
that if we want artificial systems of beliefs about the world than
we should use
the language of probability like we do in normal discourse right like you know we
say i think it's probable that you know the sun will rise tomorrow that statement
of one's beliefs about something that's going to happen in the future
certainly not repeatable experiment
that's one classifier for bayesian thinking another classic argument is the dutch book theorem where
now we're assuming that we have strength of beliefs and were also gambling people so
we're willing to bet
and if our strength belief is point nine then we're willing to accept bets where
if x is true we win anything greater than or equal to one dollar if
x is false we lose nine dollars or something like that and the dutch book
argument says that
beliefs are strands of beliefs satisfy the rules of probability theory including bayes rule then
there exist a set of simultaneous bets called a dutch book which you would be
willing to accept but which for which you are guaranteed to lose money no matter
what the outcome is
of kernel adatron
that retains the threshold allows the threshold
and the corresponding constraints on the way it does it i mean the problem with
the kernel adatron is that if you into individually update the
alpha rise you know make this update than that
that constraint will fail
because you just change one value so what SMO does is just use two values
of the
you know so that constraint still satisfied
so it's just a little bit more complicated but hopefully now one thing is very
nice to observe from the kernel adatron algorithm is the act convergence you know i
convergence three things can happen
just show again the
here's the update
nowak convergence alpha rai doesn't change for any of these updates right because they just
assume that this is fixed so what could have happened well
one thing
could be that this can be zero
right which means that
this update to offer i will be zero
OK another thing could be that this could be taking alpha i
downwards but alpha rise already zero so that fry was zero
this was negative
alpha right they will be negative but then it will be put back to zero
because we push it back into this interval
so that's another possibility
and the third possibility is that this alpha rise already the top of the interval
and this is positive and so it's take it outside the interval then we're updating
back onto c
so those three possibilities that there could be occurring at the
so it's very easy to see that if
this is
this possibility of right was zero and this less than or equal to zero corresponds
to implies that if the margin is bigger than one
in other words if the points are not actually
inside the mountain region and the corresponding alpha rai zero
OK because that is the only constraints
it satisfies
you know if this is because one
and in that case alpha i must be zero
so what this tells us is that the
the points that lie outside the margin region have zero alpha so in fact many
of the office nonzero
and is that there is one of the key properties
that makes this
working work efficiently
i both the kernel adatron algorithm and the whole
you know support vector thing because that someone more evaluating new example
some alpha i y is not a sum over all of the training data is
only a sum over those that having non-zero offers
and those are referred to as the support vectors in the sense that they support
the hyperplane and that's why it's called the support she
because these alpha rise effectively defining the weight vector
just to quickly go back to that
so this
some here although i've written it i was one to n
in fact in the support vector case many of these out rise will be zero
and only those that are
in this sort of margin region will be non-zero
so that some will be a much smaller sum on the whole the training set
that that's
so now i'm going to the sort of just
they have to give you a feel of the general
applicability of these approaches so in order to apply support vector machines you need to
choose a kernel
you could either use the standard inner product
you could use the polynomial kernel
calcium kernel
or specific kernel for different datatypes
polynomial kernel was the one i described the gas one i gave on the slides
you need to set parameter c and you can do that by using cross validation
but frequently the data is normalized than the standard value when i mean normalized mean
feature space normalized you can you can again do that quite easily
usually a value of one is fine
so more generally kernel methods are
extended beyond support vector machines they're built on this idea of using kernel defined feature
spaces for a variety of learning tasks
and the issues are
you know choosy kernel
for the different data
what other learning tasks and out corresponding algorithms you know what is
we love to support vectors other other ones
and subspace techniques such as
principal component analysis for finding the kernels
in the feature space so those are the three sort of if you like i
think additional things you need to think about
and this is if you like sort of plug-and-play
display of what's going on so you start with your data over here
choose the kernel
this one was suggested in fact
by office
should be less than
this number
because he subject some some rather be c
surprisingly this is not the case
little proved in nineteen fourteen
that for infinitely many x
biophys is greater than in
but it was purely
but a little gave
no kidding
a particular example of such an act
not even about where to find it
and this was done much later by news
who proved that instead there is such an expert find this inequality
is in such a balance
you're lot today about that time
this number produced a great competition
and for example
this is the largest number that have served any definite purpose in mathematics
and this number was called
q numbers
schools number
later it was
a small amount potentially also called cues numbers and sometimes
now the whole school's numbers at least at about four
such an next
how was involved in this activity
nineteen thirty one he became a student
in cambridge
and one of the professors was in government
who in nineteen
two published
classical book on number
and then is a book
he gave a simplified proof of a little theorem
and most important
skills the time was also in cambridge
moreover it is known that
student can skills
role in on the same boat very often
and disposable supposedly syringes this role and
student about his big number
and that is the intention of doing was just in substance more than
how to do it
of course one can look
the formula given by eighteen months
and it to explain what is this function briefly
it is defined as such a serious
it converges in
so plane
and defines analytical fast and can be extended to the whole
during the proved
that all
none really zero so that the function
lie inside so-called critical strip
this is the if the real part is below zero and one
know the critical step is
outside the region of convergence of the series
which makes it difficult
the famous americans
hypothesis states
that in fact all the real heroes
in the middle of the critical strip on called
critical line
and this is one of the millennium problems
over seven million problems
it is
very important
for example it implies that these different because
like this it's like of x plus
for some small additional factors like fixed
and text
the remarkable thing is
is important for computer
thanks also
was already mentioned the result of mean
in fact if the generalized remarkable this is not true
then there would no
there is no good reason for certain probability
in polynomial time much much earlier
so what is known as the time when student with interested
in the room and hypothesis
in nineteen all sitting ground
the first fifteen zeros lie on the critical line
later but proved the same for seventy eight
but because some four hundred thirty eight
and the final numbers