so now what is the definition of a gas process so here's the definition of
gas across a collection of random variables any finite number of which have guassian distributions
OK so this is the sort of mathematics mathematicians
definition here to mathematicians always very cautious when we talk about infinite things here so
they don't actually say it's an infinite collection of random variables that have joint council
distribution maybe that doesn't exist whatever that might mean right they just any finite number
of them should have gotten distributions and then there's OK so there there there
there was a bit fidity when when it comes to to infinity right yes
i don't think it matters i think we we don't need to be i'm not
going to look into the to the mathematical details i'm trying to get give you
a high-level intuition here right i think it's uncountably infinite
is is it probably right the right answer
OK so gas industry gas and process
this is somewhat mysterious object right just think of it as being very large gaussians
OK now analogy would be good enough
OK so let's see what happens
so whereas the gas in distribution
is fully specified by a mean vector
and the covariance matrix so it's it's like this so you have the gas in
a joint council distribution over over d dimensional object are like this
we have the mean vector and covariance matrix in the mean vector will have the
same length as the number of of dimensions of and the covariance matrix will be
a matrix which has size d by d
in that d dimensional space
so what happens if we tried to lift this up to infinite dimensional thing
now what is the vector what is the mean vector turn into if you want
to try to follow this analogy
it turns into function right you need an infinitely long
i mean vector and we think of infinitely long vectors is being functions right so
the mean of the gas and process is a mean function
and how the covariance matrix
that's right it's the function is a function of two variables right
so just like you normally think of this group of covariance matrix is being indexed
by the dimension now this is just doing exactly the same thing but the index
set here is the other values of x which happens to be the inputs to
regression thing we that we're trying to do
OK so
so so so maybe
i want to try to prove this that the this thing actually really exist but
if it exists it should definitely have this kind of four right should be you
know very long mean on here in this this two-dimensional
the function of two arguments
OK so
let's worry a little bit about this thing about it being infinitely big so we
can write it down
so we might this might be totally impractical but it turns out that it's not
totally impractical and the reason for that is because of the marginalisation property so remember
that if you have a joint gaussians
then you find the marginal distribution for some of the variables by just integrating out
the ones that you're not interested in
in particular if i had joined get joint distribution between x's and y is here
and the and had
and the mean for four x would be a and the covariance of of x
would be capital and the cross covariance between x and y is here so i
think of this is being let's think of this as being being used in the
case where the
i mean vector is infinitely long line
if i now happen to be interested in only a finite number of these entries
that could just rearrange this thing to say well let's put the a finite number
of indexes up here and call them x and then
infinitely many other indexes that i'm not interested in i put them down to be
say well what's the distribution over x well distribution axis is just this
good fashioned gas in distribution
it only depends on things that are
that that i find in particular if you had the entries here then this would
be one by d
that in nineteen
covariance matrix
OK so this is essentially why it's possible
two to work with these things without using infinitely many
in fact the infinite amounts of memory
OK so let's look at an example of one of these things what these things
actually look like so here's
is it is it is the one-dimensional gaussianprocess so x is the one-dimensional they're all
here so i choose the gas process the distribution over these functions so i have
a probability distribution over functions now
which is gaussianprocess here and have a mean function
and i'm just going to use the function zero
good news that throughout but there's no reason why you should always do that but
that's the simplest thing you can choose and here's is the covariance function
and the covariance function i'm going to use the this function here
so you sample entries uniformly at random from the and MSP the matrix and then
we can show that with very high probability
your matrix which satisfy which satisfy that published OK
this would be true if n is bigger than the constant time scale p
OK so here is kind of funny that if you give me an x i
cannot say whether it's going to work on that
very few simple x then it's going to work because the interesting
and of course what you would like is to relax conditions into a convex optimisation
essentially if you can compute is also possible values maybe you can relax and in
the way
that would be computable so there is also a small industry of of relaxing the
types of problem into a convex optimisation also semidefinite programming and essentially is a sparse
they can use
and here if you look at all those references you can see this work but
still again
OK so you can take the condition
four which again is is of the order of canada p
but if you relax the condition becomes very fact that you can verify it
but the right so we can
so right now there is no way
of getting an assumption that you can verify
four which we get the rights of the in
so to be some of the other problem but is it is possible
so people will be able to design
so it's of sufficient conditions which allow
to be verified which was scaling all is impossible
so this is kind of interesting problems
common extensions which i won't go into much into that often people complain about the
less so because it will we have some bias
seems to need long big to remove viable
to set to zero sum available to the end your estimate
on the active variables are shrunk towards zero
one way to remove that is two
keep the active set and they do not give rise estimation
and this you can get better theoretical bounds but i think it's
not separable because if you describe his your active set then you will go back
you may have to many levels and you will need
to regularize and if you don't get overfitting
another thing is to use the elastic net
which is replacing the one known by the one norm plus a bit
of the square there two known so that's two effects he says is the effect
of making the problem strongly convex so with a unique solution to the nice and
also in hollows better behavior with heavily correlated variables
so this is a very important point is that went to have also very close
to the last so we choose one of them
but depending on the depending on the case my my my change this idea we
this idea reason for your problem OK you add a bit of nice he might
select another via OK if you have two which are very close it will always
be david in the two indices so might not deserve
and this is the elastic net in this sense of that a bit and i
refer you to the people of minister hasty manner
so now what about the relevance of the theoretical results so first of all the
results are for the square loss this is by no way limitation
all the results of four and one can arise are this is by no means
limitation as well and i will present some results later in the tutorial for not
beyond everyone on
so black is the things that we can we can do it
in red this is
the interesting stuff so first in the condition and coalitions is is very very restrictive
very far from could get
with the basic ninety presented so there is a huge gap between what we would
like to know what we can do that then it may be
true that there is a such that there is no way of closing the gap
you know
first of all the work is considering non sparse generating vector is very sparse uniting
the task is is only to work
which will study all business when you want alternating the is far from being sparse
and often and of course is always the same problem how do you get london
that's what you usually do
in different you know what it's exact or approximate inference typically is officially convert the
bayes nets to markov networks and then you do inference over them so in some
sense a lot of the because the more
fundamental notion then then the innovation network
so how to do inference in markov networks
our goal is to compute marginal and conditional probabilities over any variables in the network
given in the other variables
so is the expression
unfortunately doing exact inference of these is the shark to complete problems so not only
able to do it exactly
one thing that is easy to do is to condition on the markov blanket variables
so computing the probability of variable given its neighbors is actually very simple
it's just this you know the normalisation constant cancels between the numerator denominator
and it's just the exponentiated some
of the weights of the features that are true
when the variable has a the state one
versus the sum of that for the states to industry one
the variable has more rose just more turns here but the main point is that
this is very quick and very simple to do so we can do is exploit
and you know style exploits this is called gibbs sampling and it's and it's very
simple over the
here's what it does
we just start with the random assignment of values to the variables
i'm going to assume that there a billion so
the truth assignments and then what i do the following
for some number of steps until some convergence criterion is met
i i repeatedly sample each variable according to its neighbors so i getting new state
and then all i do is i count
what fraction of the time
whatever variable i'm interested in was true and that's going to be an estimate of
the probability
and you can show that you know under certain benign conditions this actually converges to
the true probabilities if you take enough samples so simple algorithm but very general so
very very widely used
there's many others
in particular there's lots and lots of variations of markov chain monte carlo gibbs sampling
is just the simplest version of the there's also a family of algorithms that go
by the name of belief propagation in particular this is what's called a sum product
from the publication because what it's really doing is computing is sum of products
there's also variational approximation and and various exact methods
which are historically the earliest but they tend not to scale to the kinds of
the things that we're going to be interested in your so we want to focus
on that much
so the other
type of inference that we often want to do is what's called any
four MPE inference
which is the following problem given some evidence x these differences arose i know
compute the most likely state of the world meaning the other variables y which we
can call the clear variables
so if you're familiar with hidden markov models this is for example of the viterbi
algorithm does
and this is like the journal version of that problem
notice that the most likely joined state of the variables is not necessarily the most
likely state of each of them individually
because the most likely state for a and b is not necessarily the most likely
state of a and the most likely to be so these are different problems at
the level of and this is the question that we want to answer for example
to the collective classification you know classifier whole bunch of web pages taking their links
into account what we want to do
is is compute the most
the the maximum a posterior of or most probable explanation
of of the data that we've seen
and so what algorithms can be used for this purpose
well the oldest and simplest one is something called iterated conditional modes which has limited
the effect
gibbs sampling you just to the following
i repeatedly go each variable and i said it's to it's most likely value given
its neighbors i yesterday to its conditional and then iterates
the disadvantage of this of course is that it gets its it can get stuck
in local optima
so to avoid that we can produce simulated annealing which historically is you know the
standard methods for for doing inference in markov networks
it can be pretty slow another alternative more recent that that can be quite fast
is to use graph algorithms
what i do is i represent the problem is the graph and to try to
find you know the minimum set the least cost set of edges that i can
cut such that say one side is labeled positive and the other side is the
and we can also use belief propagation in this case a max
product version because we're trying to do is find the maximum of the product
OK so let's talk a little bit about learning now
so how do we how do we learn these models
well there's two parts
there's one in the parameters
i e the weights
and learning the structure i e the features
the parameters could be learnt generatively are discriminatively and we'll will look at both
in this tutorial i'm going to assume that we have complete data
if we don't have complete data we need to use versions of these arguments and
these are available in some of the software that i'll be talking about later but
in this tutorial for simplicity i'm just going to assume that the data is always
so how do we do generative weight learning
well you just the standard you can do for example maximum likelihood learning or
maximum posterior probability learning or full bayesian learning just as you could for simple models
the one thing that
not so fortunate about these models is that you cannot find the weights in closed
like seen in bayesian networks however
yeah it is a it's a convex problem so there a single global optimum and
you can find it
efficiently without of falling into local optima using something like gradient descent
in the simplest case or using a second order technique likewise i'm looking or conjugate
gradient methods all of which are pretty well understood
and here is the form
the derivative of the log likelihood with respect to weight the gradient is just the
vector of these it's actually very intuitive
and it's the following
the derivative of the log likelihood with respect to weight is
the number of times that the corresponding features is true in the data
the expected number of times according to the model
so what happens is that if the model predicts that this features is true less
often than it really is then its we needs to go up
however in the process i introduced ranking
he that's what so
this one this one i have decrease drag performance and in terms of means i
have improved probability that just to show that these things are not necessarily
here is a similar example
with respect to ranking
when you're all right leg he is on the
before the least likely to be if i throw themselves behind each
since time
actually this is a random random
distinguish between the positive and negative this
it was before
ranking errors
and you can use ranking errors that's exactly because the top because the positive and
it's not the whole ranking error because the negative not from positive with some kind
of this kind of one another way to understand this for the same way
in the united three of these are actually made no ranking errors in the brain
as a classifier
i have to say this ranking somewhere
and you will immediately see what i do that
for the classification errors when
so it's
the random
now this one
is one that make more errors
of course each of these and this is two positive
that this expression has been going on for ranking
six ranking
however the best class the best accuracy that can achieve here is the fact that
i correctly classified correctly classified minuses
and i only make two plus
so again we have similar phenomena we can
decrease ranking performance
one so the relationship between all these things is perhaps last
that's the thing
and they were allowed to go with his friend because
in one of the reasons for CSS
exactly this thing isn't good
probability estimates are necessarily a good ranker
and so the answer
the answer is
is might all this depends on how you measure the quality of the probability is
that we want to be addressed
this is also called tony
do you have sex with a woman depends on how you define set
OK so this is the problem of finite part the main part
i was talk about
building models
and will be treated based models models
well you
also analyse process of these models have been built and we can do with them
that look at the relationship between the national tracking and the by the relationship between
the ranking and probability estimation here is a brief executive summary for
now before i thought it might be a good idea for the health warning here
because i know
that some people in this audience will get very uneasy with something that's what i
these are mostly talk
as you were
training set
and from experience again ran before and this is another
you know this is like a red rag to all people
i think it is justified but not so much this talk about the great
model talking about so
you know if somebody
training decision tree
and they will use training data
are you would say that you can't do that sort of thing you need to
use the validation set that's what the training set for
so i'm believe here is that process and
let's see what happens when we train to model so this is not to say
that generalisation and overfitting issues just say i don't have to be a clever solutions
for in this also applies here as much as the rest of it is the
real issue is whether the stronger than can
generalise from training set test set but that's not something that concerns me very much
during this time
OK so
the first term is about building models i we consider that model
the first very well the decision trees and a long we have been used in
the paper this conference it's all let's try the lexicographic ranking which is
has strictly stronger by the naive bayes
that they do not want to go down the price increases
if you go down
since the degrees
what do these models have in common well actually you understand all the basic models
may not be entirely obvious if you think about naive bayes friends because that's not
how i used to think of ways but this will become clear from abroad
so let's look at the core the of city is kind of running example
the first
so i have to binary
and use a and b
value zero one
so for instance here
for a zero one and five of the six negative right one four
five is for so long
relatively easy maybe kind of it's certainly not linearly separable
it's something
decision tree and is like an axe or kind of concepts mostly plus their their
minds that that's so
i wouldn't be surprised if you try to decision tree and then you get something
which is a complete decision trees users
due to all the
so we first on b
and it's pretty good but it's not a we get here
the joint distribution danny hillis
so if you want to
classifier will do
we need a decision rule that only leaves the classes
all these possibilities using the majority class get in that case
you might want to apply the majority class you want your mind
during plus an instance based that's what it looks like so you know it's kind
of bimodal
x four
so that was d
i believe that's it
so that was definitely the end of that round
i too because we just looked at the edge
and she and jack indeed that's the last thing that happens we can check the
couple of outgoing edges
from d because that's the only one that just whose value just changed and there
are no more relaxation possible
so i was in two rounds
claims we got all the shortest path weights
the algorithm what actually loop four times
to guarantee correctness because we have five vertices here one must not so in fact
in the execution here there are two more blank rounds at the bottom nothing happens
what the hell
OK so that is the bellman ford i mean it's certainly not doing anything wrong
the question is why does it converge wiser guaranteed to converge in the minus one
steps unless there is a negative weight cycle question
don't think is that you don't
so that's optimization if if you discover whole round nothing happened so you could keep
track of the album then you can stop
in the worst case it will make a difference but in practice you probably want
to do that
good question
all right
so some simple observations i mean we're only doing relaxation so we can use a
lot of our analysis from before in particular the d values are only decreasing monotonically
as we cross values are always making smaller arches good another nifty thing about this
algorithm is you can run it
even in a distributed system if this is some actual network some some computer network
and these are machines and they're communicating by these links
i mean it's it's purely local thing relaxations the local thank you don't need any
global strategy and you're asking about can we
do different order
in each step or you could just keep relaxing edges and keep relaxing edges and
just keep going is for the entire lifetime of the network and eventually you will
find shortest path so this algorithm is guaranteed to finish the rounds in a distributed
system might be more asynchronous and so little harder to analyse but it will still
work eventually it's guaranteed to converge
as of bellman ford is is lot like the internet for finding shortest path
so let's finally proved that it works
so it should only take a couple aborts
so i suppose we have a graph some tweets that have no
negative weight cycles
claim is that we turn it with the correct answer
bellman ford
with all of these two new values
set to delta
for every vertex
proof is going to be pretty immediate
using elements that we had from before you remembered
we're just gonna look at every vertex separately
so called vertex the claim is that this holds by the end of the algorithm
so remember what we need to prove is that at some point dv equals delta
that's kind of because we know it decreases monotonically and we know that it never
gets any smaller than the correct guy cos relaxations always safe
so we just need to show some point this holds and that it will hold
at the end
so that's by
by monotonicity
of the devalues
and my correctness part one
which was
that's the these are always greater than or equal to delta
we only need to show
but at some point
we have a quality
research goal
so we're going to do is just look at the
and the shortest path to and see what happens to the algorithm relative to that
so i'm say i'm going to name the scarlet he starts to vertex easier just
one p two
and you can
and this is not just any shortest path but it's one that started as
these areas as
and it ends up be
so i'm going to give a couple of names destined bb so i can talk
about the past more uniformly
so this is a shortest path
s two
now i also want to be not just any shortest path from s to be
but among all shortest paths from s to v i want to have to be
one with the fewest possible and
OK so shortest here in terms of the total weight of the path subject to
being shortest and weight i want to also be shortest in the number of edges
and the reason i want that is to be able to conclude peace
how many if you wanted to call the random variables in a nice way so
that the outcome that are more probable
we have the shortest code and the outcome is that that are less probable to
have longer
could war
then the entropy is is that the
major you'd use to know exactly how many how many bits you should call each
of the codewords of of
each of the outputs of of your random bible
so all of these these these notions i have to do with how are you
going to be able to call it
your your random even seen nice way if you know something about the problem before
so we should be
closer to
statistical learning or problems of classification
so right now let's assume that we have a set of i i d samples
x i y i where x a year is an example and y is it
is its label
and what you want to do is to find a classifier our hypothesis f
so that f of x
the label of x
and so you will look for the hypothesis that minimizes y
that at least
the empirical risk
or you could look for i i processes that that actually minimising the whole risk
which is the expectation of the sort of
f of x y
since you don't have access to really two
through to the fall the full risk
you're you're only have access to
you bring up the empirical risk that can measure from from the data eg
x y y i
so i think
one think you need to do then is to control
how far is the empirical loss from that rule is that you're trying to
to minimize
so to do so
let's say a
what you want to do
then is to be able to
control tower
the empirical mean of the sum of i i d valuable
which is
it corresponds to the empirical loss there
is close to its true meaning which is the true
and we see
here we are going to see two or three ways to
get closer to controlling how the empirical loss is close to the true loss
so here i three different quick inequalities
time to take a break it and
all right
so i i think still
go to this slide and then the end of last in the next slide before
we actually think every
so the markov inequality the chebychev inequality and change changing the deep certain of adding
inequalities are going to help you
you know how much how far is the empirical mean for
i i d simple to whom
so there with be for a bit here exercises are i i d variables that
i equivalent to
two one another access
i consider as an which is the
the one over and some of the size and know that the
the median of as and in exactly the mean of x OK
what do
and then in expectation then
if exactly the same it's not exactly the same expedition as any of the exciting
which is x OK and i want to know how how close it is
the expectation of and to the expectation of
so i think
so we look for quantities and this one we want to know whether as an
is close to the to the true mean
or not and so
it's a
we want to know
if if sn is not close to the true mean then
this probability is going to be bigger then some excellent
so to achieve that you may use
things like
the reason
so much
this year
you see that
this picture was
let's see
you can see what
you know
so what
there no longer
he three
the same is true here
so three
to ensure
so so
then i
this is
one the
i want to that
i think it
look for me
we want them
what do you want to
and what should
you know
recognition model
that was
we the
sealed bid
the a
actually is
one the
one more
and your
if you can
so it is
and tom
the world
is very no
if you need
and so
what we do is just
positive current
the charge here on this right plate
i will call q
and therefore by that definition
is then dqtq
signed sensitive
i called the potential difference over this capacitor in going from the right side
to the left side
i call that
of c
that then is q
divided by c
all of that is signed sensitive
i go around the circle
and i want to calculate the closed loop in the goal of each LTL
and that close to the integral of e dot
it is not zero which many books
i tell you
many professors tell you
it is not zero
it is minus
the fighting
this is filed is law
our economy
because of the magnetic flux change
in closed loops
we can generate induced EMF
we run our economy
look at the lights
luckily this is not zero
this phi is the magnetic flux
go through the surface any surface you can that
that is close to
so i've done this before i can do with a little faster i go from
here to here
but that is i are
there is no electric field inside the ideal self inductance because superconducting wire
not be in the field
is zero going from here to there
when i go over the capacitor
i get my VC
and here
depending upon
if i zoom
this plot and this miners which you can reverse that
then i will get
when i walk into this direction
i would get minus the zero
but if you feel like reverting that i have no problem with that
that's just a matter of on the a degree phase
no different physics
and this now equals minus the phi
the only thing where you apply fire these laws you should always integrate in the
direction that you have your
current so
then is miners LTI
if you do the opposite direction
and this plus LTI
i have learned to certain discipline in my life
many years so you have a long way to go
and i always go
in the direction of y so i never have to think this is minus al
the idea
is now
covers the minus five so now what i do i bring the in
and i take one more time derivatives
so i get l
times i double got
players are
times i dot
BC but i take the time derivative sort cute becomes i
so i got i
divided by c
and that now becomes
the time derivative of this function
but it goes to the right side
which make the minus sign plus
but when i take the derivative of cosine omega t
get the miners omega
so i get your minus
times omega
of omega t
this is the differential equation
it has to be solved
and i will divide this
out by
l i will take
provide everything by l
i put to sea a little higher
so we are
over l
and we only zero grant
he was one of LC
it comes then
i i
double dot
as gamma
i doubt
because omega zero screen
times i
that now equals minus
the zero
divided by l
here you see
differential equation
that differential equation
looks amazingly similar
for this one
so you should be able to solve that
for in fact you wouldn't even want to solve it you can write down immediately
the answer
very together and i
which is and i zero it is
take place of that
eight areas of steady state solution go for steady-state solution
by the sign
of omega t
minus delta
no adjustable
constant steady state
the solution that i have
steady state
and i'll leave you
finally i zero
and you
and work out delta is that is part of your
problem set then you
with the knowledge that you have you could write it down
in a matter of seconds
minimizes the cale divergence between
star that's
and pee and the likelihood
copy of x given theta
okay so it will find the nearest
in kehl sense
two peace star
which in fact is the maximum likelihood model so my poster will converge
around the maximum likelihood parameter setting
subject to all these regularity conditions in the finite dimensional case
in the limit okay
so at least this is giving you some links between stuff that happens from the
bayesian posterior stuff that would happen in the classical
statistics setting
okay questions about them
so here's what happens
this is asymptotic consensus
this is what happens when you have multiple bayesians
so imagine you have two different
bayesians with different priors p e one theta and p e to data
but they observe the same data
here is the key
assume both bayesians agree on the set of possible and impossible values of theta
in other words
this set theta
that pe one assigns
positive probability to
is the same as the set date other people to science positive probability to
everybody happy with this so this is basically we wanted people to
have the same universal state is that they are considering but they just spread the mass out in different ways
over the universe
then in the limit
the posteriors pe oneof data given indiana peter data given the end will converge to eachother
this is what is called asymptotic consensus
given the same data
am assuming
there are priors are not mutually
incoherent with eachother all bayesians conversion the same
so this is comforting as well
don't worry so much about the pryr just worry about putting
probability mass
overall the reasonable parameter values then you can think of
you will converge into the same thing of course you can reanalyzed priors if you want
and in finite in
the finite data case
of course the answers we different but in the limit will converge under those same regularity conditions before yeah
abs absolutely there's a lot of more theory
there's asymptotic normality results
and convergence rates
there's a lot of work on rates which are not going to talk about but that's a more model specific
under live conditions you can get
you know optimal rates
you can also find conditions where you rates are not optimal
there is
this is this is something i'm gonna get to my last slides
a this talk
i will talk about the formal results but this is kind nice interface
between bayesian modeling
at frequentist are classical analysis
bayesian methods
so i see bayesian
methods as a way of of developing models
but i can use classical frequentist tools to analyse the properties and my bayesian procedure
for example to prove convergence and things like that
and rates yeah
by prior
to put zero mass somewhere here you say okay well
i think
it depends on how you parameterize your space
i'll be talking
and peter orbanz as well will be talking quite a lot about bayesian nonparametrics
where you have an infinite dimensional parameter space and then it's it's even hard to know
exactly where are your pudding
zero mass a non-zero mass on
in in simple cases
they knew you'd do wanna spread years apart out just in case
so here's a quiz question by the way
do you know
it's in the plane
applications so
let's start with the function f estimation account like links to the all articles in
processes that the colour
as has to about
let's start with the help of her parametric approach to function of estimation
so this is used in things like regression and classification and we assume that they
consist of two sets of points
the axis which crosses want to predict the are called a covariance basically things which
used to predict outputs y
from acting to predict what what is the value of y
and being parametric let's assume the model
it is as follows we say that y is a function of x
and parametrized by w
maybe some noise in this case we assume that goes nine
with zero mean and variance sigma work
and being bayesian prior over w
as you saw in college park
you can do
we can compute the posterior over
over w five basically taking the prior multiplied in the likelihood
and normalising
he basically the marginal likelihood of y given x integrating out w
and that of course the real with w
that if given new has a point x bar
our prediction
well why that would be basically
the distribution of y given x start as well as in a will be the
probability of y given x and w so this is just
that think of that
integrated over w
with respect to the posterior w
so that's how the usual
the bayesian approach to parametric estimation
now moving on to in the normal way of doing mission in the in the
bayesian approach
we use gauss processes and the idea of processes that
is there
i have a parametric family of functions
we simply say
that we place our prior directly over the class of all possible functions one of
which is about
basically really large clusters of
the class of functions
so now we say that
why are output is a function of
last night
and our prior over functions is to think of gaussians process which
come to begin later but you should be familiar with the culture and
will apply exactly the same missionary in which we
can't you both the real function as well as the prediction
integrating out
all possible functions within the posterior
so that's how they are four chan commission
that's the estimation is really quite similar so
we also
she is a little
like which i got from cult of which
these samples of the form of prior
and we observe
input output points given by the cross is here
and then we have a posterior which is count
described in terms of the grey area and as the samples from the function
so coming to that the commissioner so
it's basically exactly the same way out how how you a little bit about
the mission in the territory and what
and then the machine in nonparametric and what the
in the ordered the nature of data simply consists of all of the axis so
this is basically unsupervised learning in the previous it supervised learning in which you
you are given the label of the output which you want to predict
in the case of the information you have simply given a set of data points
you just want to model that has no output weight to predict
so again we model the axis
using a parametric family so again promise that by w
so what this thing is saying is that
the axes are distributed according to some function be solved
distribution parametrized by w so this distribution of
being distribution and the parameters w
so again we place prior over parameters
come do the first compute the posterior and they can do prediction again in exactly
the same way
of course the prediction is slightly different in that we are not given y we
simply want to figure out what the probability of
x are
a new test point x what what the probability given all the training data
and we are the in degree of w in the process
how do we move from which is apparently approach nonparametric approach
so the
basic idea is exactly the same way of assuming a parametric
so today
no no concepts no new ideas
relax a little bit
andIwant to discuss with you the connection between electric potential
electric field
imagine an electric field here in space
and that
I take a
charge q in my pocket
I start atposition a
and I walk around
and I return
at that point
since these
forces are conservative forces if the electric field is a static electric field there are no
moving charges but that becomes more difficult
the forces are conservative forces and so the work that i do
well i march around the coming back for a must be
it's clear when you look at the equation number three
that the potential difference
between point a and point eight is obviously zero i start point a and i
and that point
that is the
in going from a back to point a
of the of the
and that then has to be zero and we normally indicate
such an integral
with a circle
which means
you end up where you started this is online now this is not a closed
as we had in creation
one closed line
so whenever we deal
static electric fields
we can have no not equation if we like that
and that is if we have a clothesline
of you don't know
so we end up where we started
that then
s two
come here
later in the course we'll see that there special situations
we don't deal with static fields
when we don't have conservative if
but that's not the case anymore but for now
it is
so if we know electric fields everywhere
then we
you can see equation number two then we know the potential
so if we turn it away around if we knew the potential everywhere
you want to know what the electric field is that of course is possible if
you look at equation two and three
you see that the
potential integral
of the electric field
so it is
obvious that the field must be the derivative
of the potential
so when you have
field being derivative of potentials
you always have to worry about plus and minus signs
you have to pay MIT twenty seven thousand dollars tuition
b here
or MIT pays you twenty seven thousand dollars tuition for coming here
is only a difference of
a minus sign but it's a big difference of course
so let's work this out
in some detail
i have your chart plus q
and it
distance are
it should be
we know what the electric field is we found that the zillion times
this is the unit vector
in the direction from q to that point
and we know that the electric field
is pointing away from that charge
we've seen that already first lecture
divided by four by
actually non-zero
are square
in the direction
one of our world
and last lecture
we derived what the
electric potential is
at that location
the electric potential
divided by four i
actually non-zero
this is a vector
is the scalar
potential is the integral of the electric field along
the line and now i want to try whether
electric field
can be written as the derivative
of the potential
so let's take the VDR
let's see what we get
if i take this DVD are i got minus
divided by four pi
actually non-zero
or squared
of course
if i want to know what electric field is
i need the vector
so i will multiply both sides which is completely legal there's nothing illegal about that
with the unit vector in the direction are
but it turns into vectors
and now you see that i'm almost there
this is almost the same except for a minus sign
so the derivative
of the potential is minus the
not close
so i'll write that down here
equals minus
if you are
so they are
closely related
if you know
what the
so i want i want
this can be a vector
here are rules
effect on the left side you must have an effect on the right side
so if you know the potential everywhere in space then you can retrieve the electric
i mentioned last time that the electric field vector
electric field lines are always perpendicular
to the equipotential surfaces
and that's always what it has to be the case
imagine that you are in
in space
and that you move
with the charge in your pocket
electric field lines so you purposely move only perpendicular to electric field lines
so that means that the force on you
and the direction in which you move always at ninety degree angles so you will
only move perpendicular to the field lines the field lines move like this
he said if you plan to move like this
so you have to do any work
because the dot product between the l and
it is zero
and if you don't do any work
the potential remains the same that's the definition
so you can see there for people tential surfaces must always be perpendicular to
field lines and field lines must always be perpendicular to the
you create
i'll show you again the
view graph the overhead
projection of the nice
growing by maxwell
plus four charge charging minus one charge
same one we saw last time
only to point out again
ninety degree angle
i discussed this in great detail
last lecture so i will do that
good morning presenting
and presented the nonparametric bayesian dictionary learning for sparse image representations this is joint work
was held in turn john paisley lu
and the matter why laws carrying the policy at duke university
and the gamma superior
the problem is the university of minnesota
first ever give introduction
so i will talk about efficiently
model introduced as inference
it's our show very encouraging results
although model is applied to image denoising and inpainting and compressive sensing
finally i will give the conclusion
sparse vegetation has drawn considerable attention has risen in recent years due to the fact
that encourages simple model
just overtraining can be avoided furthermore
this dictionary elements and sparse coefficients
generally can be maybe then interpreted in terms of biological of physical minutes
and the whole reason may be applied to image denoising inpainting and compressive sensing with
low income without you which of the shelf dictionary or basis that DCT fifty all
commonly used by the recent research shows that if the chain of incomplete over complete
dictionary on
on the master to the signal of test we may get improved performance and better
so it's sparse coding trying to solve the objective function that given dictionary d an
observation acts were trying to find the optimal trying to solve the objective function that
could minimize the along the sparse coefficient subject to that set out to of the
observation and the representation is smaller than constant
it's well known that is that the solution to this problem is NP hard problems
so many approximate solution has been proposed which can be generally divided into two categories
what can we use the greedy
algorithms you which supplement in pursuit is represented representative one
so i currently is the correct solution approaches you uris lossless who appears come has
been widely used
it has been shows that sparse representations
and a property dictionary
can be used to carry cover the original data based on noisy or incomplete observations
of compressed measurements
so what kind of dictionary can be considered part of the dictionary
based on my past experience is DFT DCT and we
this off-the-shelf bases and dictionary can be for any used to to sparsity represent imaging
acoustic and audio signals and if he had a simple and faster computations
however recent research shows
if we use dictionaries adapted the signal under test we may get improved performance and
better interpretations
how do we do with addition and the general approach is trying to solve the
global objective function that find a proper dictionary and the sparse coefficient that would minimize
the reconstruction subject to two for each of the asian this possible smaller last seven
and the company has two stages the first stage is the sparse coding stage you
which we fixed the dictionary
and we're trying to minimize trying to solve this objective function in which we use
is true that we know the law is ryan's oyster we know this person no
then we can use the orthogonal matching pursuit either
to solve this problem
and the laws and was possible is used as stopping criteria
and the second stage is trying to update the dictionary you the wrong way is
that we fix the sparse codes and use the ordinariness this collusion to
two is to find the
to find dictionary which is known as the most to more direction modi and the
other way we can use the case with the which have proved to give better
interpret better performance and the convergence
which is that while fixing the sparse codes we are fixing the sparsity pattern
and using the rank one approximation to simultaneously updates the dictionary and the sparse representations
but is this dictionary training algorithms has some restrictions the first most obvious restriction is
that the need to assume the laws were run source possible always no then can
then it can be used as a stopping criterion and restrictions that the size of
the dictionary the to be set of prior
and this sort restrictions that only point estimates can be provided which means you cannot
tell us what's to come region of the estimation
so how to relax these restrictions
here we introduce a long how much based on dictionary learning approaches this can use
this is a fact that model and in fact noting can be considered dictionary here
and there
back to school
can be considered as the coefficient here
so instead of directly enforcing that this coefficient has a certain sparse alone will assume
we know the law as well as in the data
we we introducing a sparsity promoting priors on this fact in skin on the back
to school which is the coefficient coefficient here also we percent we presented dictionary size
to large unless the data itself team for will support was dictionary size for this
given data
so the line form representation is opposition x i
is equal to DCI plus noise ten you which the is the dictionary which has
OK dictionary elements and each dictionary element has the same dimension as the observation x
and we impose that all x i
can be expressed as a linear combination of a small subset of the dictionary adamant
plus lost it
we hope that representations e i would be sparse here we use the beta process
formulation to to impose these two
all here
in one of
all right
you have to
what here
which is all
they say well
you are right
five out of
they always
how do you
you know
i i
at model
but as
you have long
we have
of course
moreover the action or
it will be
that's why i came here
well defined
these are
one year
this work
thing are
she she
it is threatened to be
and you that
you are right
one not
well that's
so the
they have
this is
that means
at the end
four three
the we
most people
the problem
three months
in one
well as you
fifty years
i but it is not
four hundred and which
you know at the
i think
and these are wrong
OK for
as of
so so on
are you know
you know by
three times
in the end these are
we had make the
since bizer
and to be able to do this kind of
nausium almost
o thing questions let me
so what
so now we have established is that
the one
the longest common subsequence of
at the two strings we
draw the two prefixes when we drop the last character
first we have a COI minus one
that's why
is equal to one
let's see if i missed one j minus one
that's one thank you were born
which implies
that seems like
i just called to say the line
one j minus one
plus one
it is straightforward if you think about what's going on there
now straightforward in some problems is for longest common subsequence ideas
you know
the the
well will on some of the other cases are similar
in fact we get on one
two hallmarks
dynamic programming
by hallmarks i mean when you see this kind of structure in a problem
there's a good chance the dynamic programming is going to work
OK as strategy
i programming for following
number one
is this property of the
this is is an optimal
this really mean problem instance get changes
the same problem in schools
the problem is generally in
computer science you as a
having infinite number of instances typically
we're just because the sorting is problem
sorting instances in particular in
so really talk about problem instances distance a problem
so when you
something like my
the most valuable and unique of human attribute lay beyond the reach of the scientific
to begin with than in this case with the natural scientific metal
and the could be approached only by the rational refraction
and this is the approach
the branch of
investigations like could also be
labour leader psychology has taken
you the rational refraction and try to guess how the mind works
neuroscientists including life
because was wrong
and our position of it are
express very
by this and other
part of
which was taken from a book
called the to only
but because nobody
francis crick who was one of the
two people discover the structure of DNA
so he states here stories hypothesis one is astonishing hypothesis
this is the first paragraph of book popular book
in the u
you're going to use all all your memories and the ambitions sense of
of identity
and the free will in fact more than the behaviour of the vast assembly line
of cells their associated molecules
so this is what we call monism as opposed to the car
where the body
the mind separated
and in this case one is we believe that the you unified mechanism
four explaining
so called the body functions but idea what functions
my functions
and of course mind functions
it is also based on the part of the body
according to this view
that's that's this one here human brain is made of one
a hundred billion specialized cells called neurons
ten times more
supporting cells grid cells and the song
now these cell phone gigantic networks
and here is the country of
three neurons connected
by very special structures called synapses
the brain receives input signals from the environment
through the visual system auditory the sensory system
this is a combative in the brain
in each of these sensory organs into electric signal
these selectors electric signal around through
these processes of neuron
and then one can lead to this is a very specialized collection called the synapse
it really see the small compounds called neurotransmitters
it received on the other side the other side of the connection
on on the second the cell
by specific proteins called neurotransmitters receptors and that binding
lead to
creation of new
electric signal in the second cell
and the song
we are interested in among the many many mine
functions we have
we can guess from the name of and
we are interested in the particularly
learning memory and associated cognitive functions such as a piece of consciousness
things like that
so here is the cover of the famous
columbia later we're gonna governorship marcus one hundred years of solitude i put this up
actually it is amazing if you read this book
this was published in nineteen eighty three or something
and you seen the in
in my colleague
he had already predicted
that's three
i will help you
to consolidate memory
you have already published nineteen forty that would unite
now the define neuroscientists have no really seriously working on that
but in any case
in this book
he describes a small
chromium village
with the villagers were afflicted by plug
they don't describe what what actually is medically
in such a way that everybody in so many spread in the village
and one more
people get affected by the chemistry
it don't need this week
and then initially thought it's great to see any more the interesting things
but then it comes out that many of these people develop memory
memory deficit
and this spread so my thoughts on this matter
rico carty
i was very concerned about the story so
and you can read here
one day people might forget what what what cost
collinson and what to do with them
so here go around
and put it in the middle of the nickel they recall
but the
with this statement
so this is the columns must be every morning before that she worked with your
and then it must be born in order to be mixed with the coffee to
make coffee
i don't have to i think that you i don't have to
the importance of the memory
for our daily lives
if you
just sit back and think about it
almost everything we were doing every moment
it's very much depending on
your memory
of one form or another
and that come back to that later
OK so let's let gamma priors
with each
i replaced
the CI
we have to argue
the gamma prime
is consistent
in our private schools
and the argument is similar
if gamma prime we're not consistent there would have to be a derivation of a
contradiction from it
wherever you use these
constants in the derivation you could have used the free variables
instead and that would have been the country
the derivation of contradiction from guam
so the upshot of that is
we can get rid of the free variables
in favour of constants
foreign concept that
all right
they don't do anything
four x
that couldn't be done by names
gamma prime
it's still not
good enough
we need to extend it some more
and this is where we're going to need to use this stuff
what we want in order to build up a big delta that treats the quantifiers
in the expected way
is it in particular wherever we've got an existential formula
in delta
we should have a weakness for it
OK if delta contains something that says there is enough
then we should we should have an example of such a thing
in delta should be dealt you say f of some something
consider an enumeration
enumeration of what
i guess of all the
all the form all the the stanshall
the language
we're intrin sign language were interested in
that connect sites particular variable case
let's say it's just a
some arbitrary variable
an arbitrary formula
we consider all of these
we're going to
four now
a witness a formula that the forces eyewitness to exhibit
letting that
but that's just a formula can this this is an existential formula one of the
existential formula in the language
the the
this with
that the antecedent and the result of substituting a new constant
for the variable
foreign constant for the variable
zero zero one minus one
one minus one here this is the shooter
here's the going
if there's no deterministic
nash equilibrium here because
the shooter shoots
this way
the goalie e
she died this way
the goal is that in this way
the shooter would want to switch to shoot in this way
this addition this way only one of which died in this way
if the goal is diving this way the shooter was which in this way the
easiest way to go about doing this when there's no
deterministic equilibrium right so
this kind of behavior
leads to this kind of behavior should we want imagine a few minutes when the
going to want actually mean this should one
in this way the going
is no
deterministic equilibrium
but there is a
mixed right equilibrium namely you're go fifty fifty
going fifty there's no particular incentive to deviate
given the way the other players play
fifty fifty is illegal in fact
the existence of nash equilibria give the minimax theorem and we just proved core area
because you pick some nash if you think of a zero sum game
you pick some nash equilibria the VBE the value to the row player in that
nash equilibrium
the claim is
it's internationally calabria neither player
can do better even knowing the randomized strategy thereupon is planned to be taken actually
cleverer means that even you know even though the other guys doing you have no
answer to do anything else
so what that means is even in the con players doing there's nothing you could
do that we can do better than the physical ever even though when you're doing
something called layer could do
column player better than
the on the negative
even though when you do so
and actually calabria must be both players playing minimax optimal
there's there's no way neither one
even knowing what you guys doing to do better than this value
so actually the proof of nash equilibrium implies
but there is a difference which is that
OK so so so nash equilibrium in a zero sum game
both players happy playing minimax optimal strategy
if you want to play one of the players wasn't playing minimax optimal strategy then
you should be able to do better than that value
knowing what you guys do
unfortunately the existence of nash equilibrium is an unconstructive argument whereas for minimax we have
very constructively and our
but actually guaranteed to converge to released as well as minimax optimal we're better the
other player wasn't playing well so this the nice thing with this regret minimising algorithm
is the other guys playing optimally your approach minimax optimal value does not playing optimally
you develop that super
for nash equilibrium there is no known effective
no efficient algorithm for finding the nash equilibrium
the perfect is not constructive
so unlike the case is zero sum games we do not know any polynomial time
algorithm for finding nash equilibrium and by in general sum games
so for zero sum games we had these regret minimising algorithm or could use linear
programming solve
nash equilibria is known to be not NP hard but it's hard for some other
bizarre class called p pad
and so i believe
and i have polynomial time
well it's not i mean
in that sense i mean it would be a lot more money on the and
ninety point p versus the people
i would be
the difference is that these things exist it's not like the question of
from complete problems like existence
so far
kind of
one of
one so
i have not about
the last
o point five set of one
on the right side of
will tell you that i want
in thank you
one of the
on one of the
the world
what i want
the song
the people who
so the
if you really want
i want
in fact
the one source
so for the
o four four
in fact
the fact that i find it
there is a
now in the
the story
don't know
thank you for
four different very
that's what you
on the the other
one of course
think about
o five
actual care
all of the this
but also the
it's called
all of this
and then finally
things like
subgraph identification finding richer patterns and then metadata mapping so
a lot of the work and
ontology mapping ontology alignment can also be put into a framework that can make use
of some of the techniques and there's been some work in that area
so all of these are kind of higher level tasks hopefully
at least some of them seem compelling to you that you might have had an
information extraction system that would be useful to do a combination of doing
entity resolution may be predicate invention
and so on
the interesting thing is for all of these tasks
there's these kind of common things that come up
in terms of needing to collective classification needed to do
collective consolidation figuring out how to represent the relational structure the logical
dependence and statistical dependence in
a framework that can represent both of those being able to do the feature construction
selection aggregation
and figuring out
how to
can combine these things together ideally in a way that is flexible
and if possible decomposable
dealing with whether or not you act explicitly in your model refer to individuals
like a particular author that's very predictive or just at the class level
is labelled and unlabelled data
link prediction that kind of mention this but one of the things with link prediction
especially kid predicting the existence of the link is
prior probability of any link existing is just so
the kind of
confidence you can have in any of the
statistical inferences you get out can be very low and that's something you need to
be extremely careful about and then
making open world versus closed world assumptions
in your model
i think the interesting thing is
we met
no matter which these alphabet soup methods you end up using i think you end
up having to deal with
these challenges
not anything unique to a particular approach
i want to get into
some specific SRL approaches
categorization for approaches
that i'm giving it four approaches
it is based on
one set of them is based on underlying
semantics of directed probabilistic model
the underlying assumptions for the semantics of the probabilistic component is an undirected
the model
within these
the kind of logical
relational approaches
can be broken down into a rule based approaches versus more frame based approaches
and then actually there are
is a whole nother
category of methods
which much i chose the name programming languages approach that's probably not the greatest term
but there are approaches for example
based on stochastic context free grammars
probabilistic functional programming languages and so on and actually not going to go into
there's so much
but i think they have questions about them offline i'm happy to talk more about
so i'm going to focus
these four
like i said at the outset i think the thing is interesting
is that actually get very similar points at the end of starting with the rules
and adding directed models starting with systems are in directed models in but there's still
is something a little bit different amounts
can the mindset
during going in with these and so
the rule based
approaches tend to focus on
in fact what is true in the world and what depends on where
the frame based approaches
ten two
more focus on the modeling aspect
what are the objects in the world and how are they related to each other
and then
to contrast the directed approaches versus undirected approaches the director approaches
tend to focus more on kind of causal relationships
where as
undirected approaches focus on
things where there is a kind of symmetry
in the relationship
and this is the way that don't
so it can handle
non causal interactions
and then the programming alone
languages approaches tend to focus more on the process
is the world generated if this event happens then
how does that influence another that
so it's interesting because there certainly are
systems that allow you to make
directed and undirected but even then just the
propositional learning
there's then
certainly beautiful theory
developed for but
i haven't seen systems practically use
it is possible that people for some reason are doing it and
after a talk a little bit more about the two potential semantics we should
talk about
how we go
and i think then you might see the
even though it's not necessarily the most elegant way
you can kind of