OK which is
and is in the exponent
is exponential
and this the technical term we use something is exponential time
OK very
OK so slow
so this is really bad
take a long time to crank out
how long the longest common subsequence is because this so
now for the process of developing a form
fish now our this problem
russian go through several stages
the first one is to go through simplifications
already do
simply the link
one way or the consequence of x and y
and what do is expand
the longest common subsequence itself
these are all the allowing
to simplify the problem that he will just try to compute the length nice is
the length is
there's only one link is going to be the longest
well those
focus on the problem of computing the line
and what we do is we can back up from and figure out
however what actually is the subsequence realizes that way
and now we have big simplification
you have to attract a lot of possibilities every stage just have to keep track
the one number which is the way
this reduces it to an american problem
that the following
pretty standard notation but i just wonder
five per absolute values around spring denotes or
for a sequence of the note
so that's the first thing second thing we're going to do is actually working on
which takes a lot more insight when you come up with a problem like this
and in some sense ends up being the
the hardest part of design good dynamic programming
so for any
which is we're going to actually are
no rule
on some sequences x and y
we're just prefixes
just look at prefixes show
we can express
OK the length of the longest common subsequence
in terms of each other
in particular define
see if i j
to be the wang
longest common subsequence
the prefix of
x going from one to
going to one
around new is
we're going to calculate c i j for i j
and if we do that
the problem of longest common subsequence of x and y
we saw the longest common substring
i and j
then do we
compute the length of the longest common subsequence of x and y
SEM and that's all
the common man
just equal to the longest common subsequence of x y
this is
go from one to and
one day and on that
it turns out that what we to do is figure out how to
on express
five cm and general CIJ in terms of other CIJ
the idea
is just
it's as if the i character matches the change character and see
i think you're correct matches character y
and see i j is just see if i missed one j minus one plus
they don't match
then it's easier to be
no longer
by june one
right usually the weight
the addition of
integers is denoted is with the symbol
but here
in group real and i just said that usually we denote the group operation by
multiplication so
x plus y becomes x times why this is i'm going to refer to experts
why i hope it doesn't confuse it too much
under the same identification between addition and
the group operation
continuous spaces also for group in particular the rios and euclidean vector space so this
is just the addition of vectors that also group this is the first example of
continuous group in so fact it's the only group that i can tell you more
about those sources
other examples of such continuous groups
other rotation groups
i should have
maybe i could have put this in the context of the icosahedron again because
obviously there's a finite number of ways in which you can capture the symmetries of
the icosahedron but they come from a larger family of all possible rotations of three
dimensional space right so that forms a group if you think about
i rotation as corporation acting in three-dimensional space rotating and somehow then you can combined
these operations and get further operations so again the groups of axioms are satisfied these
this group is called SOM because it's identified but
a set of orthogonal matrices with determinant positive one
in the best way to get so this is these are the rotation euclidean rotation
rotation groups
a slightly larger groups
is the group of all rigid body motions so future then just take rotations about
rotations and translations
but again the symmetry
it again forms a group
and the fact that euclidean geometry is nothing but
the study of
of objects
euclidean space
and this invariant managed to this group
let felix klein to make this very general statement
geometry is in general can be regarded
has just the study of objects invariant with respect to a particular group
so an algebraic point of view geometry is not you might think that the geometry
is about the lines and circles and points and whatnot but in a more abstract
all that's happening is that you have
a set of objects have symmetry operation on them which is captured by a group
and you are studying the properties of the the objects which are invariant with respect
to that symmetry operations
now the special unitary groups should be familiar to anybody who studied physics
because they are fundamental to modern treatment of quantum mechanics
i also must mention the general linear group which is just the matrix of
just the group of all invertible matrices of
the size and by
so in some sense the rotation group is the subgroup of this group right because
those are just matrices which are orthogonal and have determinant one
if you consider all possible matrices which you can invert so which you can find
the inverse then you get the general linear group
and finally there are
so you can continue the series there are lots of there are there are many
series of of groups that people have studied there are also individual groups that are
of interest for particular reasons for example this one
which is famous for its approach which you might not otherwise study if it were
in the symmetry group of rubik's cube
so if you are not sure how many of you have tackled rubik's cube
not sure if any of you try to group theory
if you were to do that and then this is the objectivity would be studying
this is not the only complicated group
things do you get a little bit here if you try enumerating all groups to
categorizing them and figuring out what the fundamental groups famously the largest group that this
simple in some sense
it has been proved to be the so-called monster group
which has this many elements
so from former mathematicians point of view what's what's fascinating is that captured is like
notions of complexity that is clear from simple simple of composite structures
you can come you can combine simple structures to get more complicated structures are the
best is what other the simple like the fundamental structures and you start enumerating then
you find these families like the symmetric groups for any and there is the symmetric
group concept corresponding to do that and
and then there are these are the ones which don't fall into any categories so
you look at those two and you find one in the other and we get
larger and larger and more difficult to describe to you think it might never end
but doesn't have a certain point although it takes a little bit of work to
describe something that is this page
it took about a hundred years
so that's justified
the the fearful part
before i get into the machine learning by let me just say how to
find a way in this universe of
groups of different types so some of the groups that i talked about some of
the groups that we're going to be looking at in machine learning context of finite
groups many since they are simpler than obviously
and then is the infinite and continuous groups so the cyclic groups fear the quaternion
group the monster and the symmetric groups are all fine
the infinite groups but there are
but some of them are countable so things national generalizes naturally to that case such
as the integers that's fairly simple
things get more interesting
when the group becomes continuous
and the subset the subset in which you can put the topology which matches the
group structure is the only groups so in the continues group round people mostly focused
on these groups in particular
the rotation group SO the unitary groups fall into this category the
the euclidean group so the
a group of vectors with respect to addition and rigid body motions are also lead
this is the effect is tendency thought was much more complicated than to polynomial so
it will capture that
variations capture the model
OK so so that the bias term if you make your model
more flexible and so if you do something like is neural network which is much
more flexible than a polynomial curve then
you can not biased quite a lot because you model
you can think of all the nuances of what's going on
over what people found is because
you have
this relationship
because you can really get mean squared error down below sea level if you started
reducing the bias variance seem to start going was so
so how do you solve various going upwards well
you collect more data
so this is
why this should be in areas of concentrate on in data mining because
we can reduce our variability
by using massive datasets
so we can get
to get small
we can also
complicated flexible models like trees and neural networks rather than straight lines
that will allow to reduce the bias
the problem that people had in the past was they didn't have a big data
so what was happening was when the for the complicated model
the very short because you couldn't get the data set
that's why
we should be moving
towards the end of towards the money into a wider we should be moving towards
these sorts of models because we have the data sets so that that's what i
wanted that to be included in that's the idea that this
these are two components to the error on model what is natural variation and one
is the model
you the wrong type of models we can address the thing the wrong type model
by making a set of possible models more complicated
and we can address the natural background variation by
collecting more data base
and that's why you don't want massive amounts of data so
so these
complicated method complicated models flexible models are becoming more important one part of the word
in the statistics community where they with small datasets
about it
there's one other thing i wanted so
talked about
sampling distributions not about something distributions is what allows me to make statements like
i like this
because if i know something distribution of all the quantities involved in these models that
i can say we have the variances is that relate to the bias and relates
to this
that is the sampling distribution ten about that's all want to say something about the
behavior of the model basically behavior but things in the model that i
i can't measure directly
traditionally these quantities worked out
basically by doing that by the probability calculation was started to happen though is
the taxable looking it of run off the end of what we can do classically
we can
the sampling properties of some of the estimate is that we get from say no
network because we can't even write down what is doing
so what
not in the days of the week after the mass anyway so an alternative which
we're here in order to get hold of something properties
we have an article resampling and
this is basically we do computer simulation to see what's going on and the resampling
idea is
that we
it's a kind of data
and use that as a source of random outcomes from a statistical model
so we repeatedly sample
from our data set
with replacement so we take one observation and and then they that that goes into
our resampling put it back in the sample against so that generate
multiple samples
computers and later by pseudo random selection
so around just because it's it's easy to compute to a random number rather than
real random number
what we can do then is generally what's of different samples that have the same
characteristics as our original data
and we can then investigate what are the differences between samples the variation across samples
is due to sampling
and these as an idea to estimate the
sampling properties
all things like the bias
other thing do this sort of thing that you might have come across cross validation
what do you do cross validation is
you a model is also called leave one out two
the you take a model
u fifty two
all the data apart from one of your observations and then you can see
say what does the model that fitted predict the outcome to be for the one
you left out and then you can look at the difference between what the model
predicts what you actually got that give you an estimate of the error between the
predictions of the observations and then you just what you to all the individual data
points leaving them at one time that we call cross validation
i mean it's given as an idea
well that situation is given us an idea of
this quantity
this gives idea of what's the difference between the
collected data the observed values and what the models predict in
but the things that people in terms of bootstrapping is
is another method of doing this six
i would allow to estimate
say well
the medians
some of not so immediately if you live in
data is in order
from let's same the smallest to the biggest than the medium is just the number
that's halfway along along is so the numbers with the fiftieth ward in order
so is the fiftieth percentile is another way of putting it so so half the
observations below
so let it sit there for the balance of the lecture and maybe at the
end we'll see some of the
liquid oxygen
OK so let that work and all you have are proteins we said there's palmer
so let's see if we can
do something with the with the proteins here
you put the rose roses you know they have glass flowers at harvard
at at a museum
five museum
we have glass flowers here at MIT
OK so this erosion it's very soft
let's go
it's not a kitten
and it only works on roses which do one more scabby scientist you know me
which is roses that do this
so let's look at this one
let's transition temperature
there is
OK so we get the going well at oxygen can condense and let's see let's
go back to the
computer think we're going to take a break and go back to some some more
learning here
OK so here are some
o thing and there is one of the one here i think
right so we've seen this and here's nitrogen with all of its different solid phases
nitrogen actually has different crystal structures and so this diagram shows what's going on as
you as you change pressure at constant temperature here we are still down around minus
seventy kelvin so there we go from liquid to solid it's HCP and then it
becomes simple cubic and then run back and so on so this property that certain
elements have multiple different composition actually multiple different crystal structures is called polymorphism so these
are called different polymers you've already heard that orion has been in some instances bcc
crystal structure and fcc crystal structure in the phase diagrams will reveal when these transitions
here's carbon dioxide solid liquid gas is going to positive slope what's interesting about carbon
dioxide is look here the one atmosphere iso bar takes you directly from solid to
gas so it doesn't go liquid and that it gives the value as the refrigerant
because when it gives up its enthalpy of
of transformation you don't end up with the liquid which can mess up your content
and so this is often used in
in the shipping certain materials
it's got some here
play was drawn from this great big ice cube here but there's some sorry broken
c so this actually OK so here we are this is the big ice cube
i guess crags can one see let's creggan people which the psychologist
now this is minus seventy eight degrees c
and so it's it can go directly you're seeing it it sublime
so we can do some things that just to prove let's prove that it's going
directly from solid
two gas i have some interest in playing
spring water here
non carbonated this is flat
this is flat put that on the edge to of create and then just to
show that we're going directly
take this
OK k see
i also agree
so there you see the bubbles coming on a giant bubbles c
so we're making sio two in water
this is that
one should notice something
you know
you can buy this bottled water
if you can see craig if you can catch this PC these tiny wimpy box
we have a big bubbles
big problems
that c o two
see what else we can go and see if we still have some
very liquid oxygen
i have just a little bit he will be able to pick it up on
the camera OK so
the last thing i want to do is to go back to the
computer image if we could please
OK so we've got carbon dioxide
all right here's a couple of the phase diagram zirconia i mentioned to you the
this is just pure zirconia zero two
and what we find two because the former gives you that full diamond but look
it's stable only above about two thousand degrees c
so if you're going to give you sweetheart that the full diamond it's going to
be too hot
too hot
so we're going to learn next day is how to open up this range of
the way we opened up the range of liquid stability
by adding ethylene glycol to water and see if we can get cubic zirconia stable
down to room temperature
right but normally it's monoclinic then goes to trial goes QB was liquid and so
on that using goes there
here's carbon
mean temperature over a wide range of pressures graphite hexagonal close packed in elevated pressure
it becomes dying
here's liquid carbon
it turns out that by
judicious choice of chemistry people the general electric about thirty years ago reason that
still consists of carbon iron
and if we quenched steel we end up with carbon in the iron lattice if
we put too much carbon the carbon will exalt as precipitates
well if we could example of elevated pressure
could we get the carbon to exalt not as graphite but diamond cubic
and they did
generated artificial diamonds and one of the leaders of the team was course three along
from MIT who i met years later on committee in washington in connection with the
aluminum industry and he told me he was in the team that went to london
to negotiate with the beers they go south african diamond concern they were scared because
general electric reported that they could make artificial diamonds
and they general electric reported that they could make large artificial diamonds well large they
trying to make diamond dust they actually had one is about one millimetre was tiny
but the birds was was nervous
this is the fellow's name was right hand many told me that the thing that
scared him most was not sitting down with the burst because he had the blast
the hardest thing was getting through
british customs
because he had this on this person
now if he's opens up and they see all this diamond
the grammar and then take these counts and normalized them kind of the obvious way
to get a probabilistic context free grammars kind of generalization of hidden markov models
and if you did this
and ignoring any efficiency questions about how you parse
and use this to infer most likely passes you would have to pass through the
has what are called here baseline accuracy
seventy two percent it's this f one score something like how many other nodes are
correct i'm not going to go into the details
so this people have been doing this for a while it turns out this is
a very good number you don't really want your password to make a core made
mistakes record of the nodes are wrong
and as you might ask well kind of are context free grammars probabilistic context free
grammars somehow the wrong model class and the answers are not necessarily the wrong model
classes because your pass doesn't work very well and one of the reasons is that
the kind of the trees in the data that have symbols like noun phrase make
overly strong conditional independence assertions one kind of you probabilistic objects so for example here's
another sense she heard the noise and in the sense that the two green nodes
both noun phrases so that both noun phrases linguistically in terms of the roles they
play in the sentence at some level but somehow as a as kind of a
context free grammar it's not right because we can dramatically swap is we can have
the noise heard she would be the noise heard her side from being semantically anomalous
it wouldn't be syntactically correct
so there's something these are nounphrase are really the same and if we build grammars
that have such symbols are not going to be very good
and o
so this brings us to the task of grammar refinement what's grammar refinement all about
we're observing these trees but they're kind of only the courses description of what's going
on linguistically what's really going on is much finer grain their subjects their objects passive
position all kinds of phenomena happening and all happening at once and they are not
labelled histories
so we'd like to have some description of what's really going on and one way
to do this that one of the earliest ways was mark johnson parent annotation where
we go along saying well those entities are different because one the subject ones and
object we can tell that by their parents eager marking all the nodes with their
this is good we got more symbols so our context freedom assumptions are less wrong
but now we often need more data to estimate anything and so you start getting
sparsity problem
what can you do you can now take an even more extreme case and say
actually this isn't just any noun phrase in object position it's something about noise and
i want to say this is a noun phrase that's about noise because well it's
an object of the verb heard some of her goes with noise and i can
try to kind of get in a little bit of not only lexical syntax but
also some lexical semantics here as well
OK so this is what's called head lexicalisation or you go along annotating all of
you know the actual words was to make them
part sparsity problems you can make the passes in this way but you have to
work very very hard on the whole game becomes overcoming the sparsity problem
so what i'm going to talk about here is an unsupervised approach to the refinements
or how the trees but we're going to find them automatically and try to figure
out an automatic fashion what these true underlying syntactic processes
in this case we might say
that there is an NP one and NP two
but i don't know what that means and i don't know which ones are which
but i'm going to sort out statistically
what does this mean this means that where we used to have passes we observe
passes in our treebank are these properties that have senses noun phrase verb phrase we
observe them at test time we want to produce them but we know that underneath
everything is some more complex phenomenon and more complex phenomenon is going to be represented
by grammars are what are called derivation shown on the right so for example here
two derivations on the right that both derive the same pass
we have these passes that of be capital t we have these derivations is the
lower case t and what exactly are we trying to do
well what we're trying to do here trying to find some grammar over this derivation
that best explains in some sense and i'm being deliberately vague here the best explains
the observed passes
one option is one of the easiest options and we'll talk to here
it is to use maximum likelihood estimation with a briefly mention some other options including
being more vision about this and looking at doing so you could either want to
be more patient and more discriminative or maybe somehow both and we look at both
of those things but i'm going to talk today about the basic case of maximum
likelihood in and
so what we want we want these derivation parameters that maximize the likelihood of the
parties and you look at that and say well that's exactly what you was built
OK so let's
so let's take that a little bit further so what is in mean in this
case it means we're going to see structures like what's shown here on the left
where it senses noun phrases verb phrases there are going to be latent variables that
represent the clusters at each of these points now of course this is like point
clustering or mixture of gaussians are selling clusters are structure the interacting because the cluster
one point determines the probability of reaching the clusters that other points but there are
a bunch of latent variables and can more less on chain here to tree but
the the brackets are known and so on
essentially learning there really isn't much more complicated than it is for each man's and
we can run basic generalization of the forward backward that somewhere between forward backward inside
so we can you use in here to learn these subcategories
what might we learned
if we did this we be splitting stuff everywhere we have lots of kinds of
sentences lots of kinds of noun phrases lots of kinds of our prisoners
OK in particular we have lots of kinds of each of the parts of speech
i'm going to show you lots of them because they're very easy to get your
head around but don't confuse the this is only about word clustering
so here's the determiner category
and the most common determiners
in the treebank are the a and capital
case is preserved
right if we split that into four
and learn the clusters with
number not just learning determine clusters clusters across the whole grammar
we would find in this case the algorithm produces four categories you get one which
is more or less the indefinite determiners
the second one which is more or less definite determiners the third one is more
or less demonstrative and the last one more less quantifiers not perfect but this is
basically what's what's kind of being captured by the distributional clustering
that's great but what if we want to eight
in fact we're going to end up with something more like sixty four hundred twenty
and that it doesn't work very well you get the kind of you basically have
lots of search problems and you've got to model problems when you try to direct
but like this
so here's something that worked very well and
the speech literature and people have been doing in a lot of different places and
that's don't structure once hierarchically
so instead of just putting all my grammar everywhere
i'm gonna maybe say that for every single observed symbol there's two underlying symbols
we might get the proper determiners in the demonstrative
then i will take those symbols further split them
will get this tree of incremental refinements
OK again now we're back to four which is where we started but it turns
out you can go much farther without without hitting problems
so if we do this we're essentially going again ontology of grammars so we'll have
some basic underlying simple grammar that then get split and split and split in a
way that's kind of incrementally structurally clustered until finally gets a grammar that as refined
as we want
so remember we're going to have this sequence of grammars
and in each kind of at each step the symbols get more and more refined
good morning welcome to beautiful sln
it's my pleasure to
introduce here today
jeff dean
was invited to speak
jeff was born in hawaii
and during his early years
spent childhood
in many places from minnesota
two again
climbed back to africa
then he said to in the bay area
jeff is an extremely
the engineers
big dreams
and he pushes his dreams surely very high scale
in google
every time did you get a new engineering
jeff is the buying it
this is the very high level
mind of accomplishment is also
a very easy person
very easy to get along with
and very good
team building
there was no fatherly dept
i'm going to talk today about building large scale retrieval systems something i've been doing
for a while ago
and one of the things i like best about this area work is that
it provides a challenging blend of both unsolved research problems that you know we really
don't know how to solve interesting directions that this work can go in and also
a bunch of challenging engineering problems and if this one thing of of problems i
think is
both very interesting and challenging
it also spans a lot of different areas of computer science to think it's fun
to get collaborate about colleagues who have different areas of expertise
and it's helpful when you sort of expand horizons and learn more about area and
you may not know much about it when i started to google i don't know
much about machine learning have been able to work with experts in machine learning and
pick up a little bit of to bits on the side it's fun
and the scale of
the systems were building is a lot larger than most other systems that one more
common so that's always fun
another thing is that i think small teams are able to do pretty significant things
that can be used by for example hundreds of millions of people
and that's true
testament to the power after that's why i love this field because
new york can be used by
what people
OK so when you're building a retrieval system there are lots of different parameters that
you might need to consider
for example you might have some target of number of documents when indexing your system
o and maybe have some target goal of number of queries per second your system
needs to be able to handle
you want to be able to document summary maybe like to update and document the
second maybe like to be able to update
a billion documents per night
the sorts things you like to respond quickly to users
you need a certain amount of information to be kept about every document in your
index or other data structures that you can be using for running retrieval algorithms and
then you have some
either simple or fairly complicated retrieval algorithms are going to be trying to run the
and all of these factors and parameters contribute to sort of the difficulty in engineering
task interface to it if you have
you know small values in all the dimensions it's not that challenging if you have
a very large
values in all dimensions that increases the engineering challenge significantly
and it's kind of equivalent to the product of these things is it's easy to
have a very large index that you never updated it's harder to have a large
index that you have little time
and these all affect the performance of the system and what you really care about
is an engineering performance per unit hardware cost america
OK so just to give you a sense of the scaling of these parameters inside
google i joined in nineteen nine and give you a rough sense of how these
parameters to scale so
when i joined we had an index of perhaps
a few tens of millions of documents and today we have many
you know that's a hundred x
queries processed per day
the next
kind of rough measure but we're basically
keeping a lot more information per document that we can use to do ranking then
we did ten years ago
are update this is kind surprised me when i made the slide
it's actually gotten better by a factor of about ten thousand we have some pages
and we the index then
and editor chair
and is really kind of push to batch update of our whole when x once
every month or two
while these parameters have been changing we've been able to drop the average growing season
now of course even
a little bit by moore's law
and by a larger capital but these days
but you notice that
the improvement in hardware resources is not really kept up with the changes in all
of parameters
that's just to give you a sense of graph
the other thing i think is illustrated by the previous slide is the but all
these parameters changed constantly over time you're always getting more queries per month than you
did last month
your always wanting to annex more documents than you
did yesterday
an important point to make is that the right design at a given design given
might might be wrong to design very wrong
when that parameters scaled by a factor of ten or hundred
so a good rule of thumb i would like to use is that whenever you're
designing a system you want to think about what would happen if that parameter scaled
by a factor of up to ten but beyond that it's really difficult to sort
of have the same system work for
x a hundred access that point you probably gonna need to review
significant pieces of the system to
deal with you know hundred x more queries one hundred x more documents the tree
next get the same designs may not make make sense anymore
the other cool thing about web search or search in general is that
you can sort of replace the entire back end
serving system without users really noticing and we've done this many many times over the
last ten years or so
you can sort of devoted new centre
or in convert one existing data center to a completely new serving system run you
know some fraction of user traffic to that for a while
and once it seems to be stable when you convert over all the other ones
and users
depending on how visible the changes are that you're making on the retrieval system
you know sometimes it just seems faster users sometimes that as large index but other
the met sort of three and a half million volts maximum would become seven
so if i try to
make a drawing of that by the time here
prices low here
then you get something like this
so this
omega is no twice
this one
the maximum value of the EMF
the show that year
right to improve on my lights
you see their current meter redesigned sensitive can go to the right to go to
the left
and i'm going to rotate this move
when you rotate the loop in a magnetic fields
you can even rotate it in such a way
but you get no EMF
i can show that to you easily
this is the law
and if somehow the magnetic field came in like this
if you're OK this now
around this axis
will never be EMF because the a and b
always be perpendicular to each other
there was never any
flux going
through this
no flux changes
but of course if you rotate around this direction it will be fine
think about that
fall in that trap you can rotate in such a way
that there is no flux
we don't have that problem at all because the magnetic field
u on earth in boston
doesn't come straight from heaven down but it comes rather steep
there was never any problem you don't have to worry about that
so here is that
forty two windings
the scale varies in micro mps
if you want to you can calculate what the resistance of the loop is when
i rotate that's really not my objective
i want you
you see it when i rotated it again alternating current
very moment
because i wrote it very slowly
now i rotate fast than proportional
so if i rotate faster
you get a much larger maximum
the induced current
large you may have a larger current
i don't know how fast i can go to about as fast as i can
it's always up to four micro mp is maximal
and so we are producing here
a c
we're stepping context here so that the system doesn't break
we could put the light bulb is somewhere in this line
and then
the light bulb may grow
united states
what comes out of the wall
is sixty hertz
so that means that the current
for libel
becomes zero one hundred twenty times per second
on the fly twenty thousand per second do you go
if you have sixty hertz
does it mean that a hundred twenty times per second there is no light from
the light bulb
no it doesn't mean that because elements get hot
so they still glow
even when the current
they don't call that fast
if you take fluorescent
then indeed fluorescent two
goes completely off and on
on the twenty times per second
and therefore you can use them very nicely astrophysical of course the frequencies fixed and
change the frequency
it's funded
and twenty years
so now
you're getting the ideas of an electric generator or what we call
if you want to
but uses
a c
the turbine
the turbine rotates conducting will magnetic fields
and that according to fire they
will then
you left
and that runs our economy
however permanent magnet
you rotate
conducting loops
the windings
in the magnetic fields
the highly magnetic field the higher the EMF
the first rotate the higher the EMF more windings you have
the higher the math
and the larger the area of your
hi human
as you can see
on the equation that i keep
that's where it is
united states we have sixty words as i mentioned
and we are committed to a maximum voltage coming out that has the maximum
value that you get from the alternating
of holland ten times the square root of two vols and we call upon the
in europe
we have fifty hertz
and the maximum voltage there
the oscillation is two hundred and twenty
find the square root of two
you cannot change omega
go faster somewhere where you generate
this electricity because that would have major consequences number one
in the math that comes out of the wall go up so you might blow
the circuit
but besides that
you will change also the frequency of the alternating current
and there are many systems
that run in such a way that they locked into that frequency for instance many
electric clocks and certainly
record players if you still have one
i walked into the
sixty hertz
so if you were to increase omega
the record label go around fast you clocks
will go faster
a long time ago when i came over from europe
i brought my record player with
the record player requires two hundred and twenty fold so i want to transform here
that one hundred ten volts
my home would become two twenty that was fine
and so to record player was happy
extracted as the city five times the question is five times out of ten sentences
are five times out of one hundred million sentences that's very different probability so
this expression is actually an interplay between these two exponentials and it turns out to
provably give
the right probability now why why do we care about the fancy math here well
if we compare the performance in practice two previous approaches so so this graph showing
the urns model compared to turn is pointwise mutual information based model and compared to
noisy or
which is another model that was previously used in extraction work in you see this
is for example for relations
here and on the
y axis you've deviation from ideal loglikelihood so this is a log scale and lower
here is actually better idea how far we from from the right answer and you
see that in dark black we have there is modelled very close to the right
answer in compared to the others were getting an order for fifteen hundred percent improvement
or more so this is much much much
better than the previous work and again no hand labeled data completely domain independent in
other words methods the scale to trying to tackle the the full web
now it turns out that this model works great when you have lots of information
when you have this kind of redundancy so if we want to know whether we
believe that michael bloomberg the mayor of new york that kind of thing tends to
be correct and if you play with textrunner you'll see that the statements that extracts
at the top of its results are often correct but when things get sparse all
familiar with this of distribution we have on the order of fifty
percent of extraction is the only occur once
and then what do you do that and you find that in those there's a
mixture of
stamens that are rather obscure but correct like dave shaver is the mayor of some
small town called content and also statements that are blatantly false like ronald mcdonald is
the mayor of macdougal where we all know it's
thank you appreciate that so
maybe not everybody knows that but it's actually man wrongly that is not the mere
them less so
there's the don't say you don't learn anything from my talk right so so how
do we choose these apart how do it is the
the good ones apart from the bad ones and in more recent work by doug
downey and stuffed schumacher's what they said is instead of just looking at these extraction
patterns these lexicosemantic patterns why don't we when we're considering an entity look at all
the context that occurs and so on
effectively for wondering is shaver mayor
why do we ask the question because he behave like a mayor and what does
it mean does he behaves like an area means if we take all the sentences
that shaver appears in do we see
statements like he was elected and you know he
i blocked the motion and he attended the city council et cetera et cetera right
so if we see
him in the presence of the right kinds of strings they're going to be more
and more likely to believe that he is the mayor and the same for bringing
jennifer see streets of america thing to get more and more likely believe it say
that this is not
an explicit computation what we do is we build the language model in fact language
model is captured by hierarchical model markov model is built once per corpus and what
the model does it really takes the entire corpus and projects it into a twenty
dimensional space to lower dimensional space and what happens then is each string is the
point in this lower dimensional space and what you can do is you can measure
distances between the strings and the distances are really referring to their behavior in context
and to the statistical properties of their behavior in context again and glossing over a
lot of technical detail here to give you a flavour so the idea is from
trying to figure out of pinkerton is the city
i'm gonna map into the space and i'm going to ask what is the proximity
between thinking ten and other cities that earns theories model tells us are known cities
like seattle boston and so on so using them model like this i can tell
the pinkerton is relatively likely to be city certainly compared to other strings
again more of details in the paper but the point is by using language models
over the corpus we can handle the more spark his cases as well and that's
that's very important
OK so let me turn to the last example inference and this is the compositional
inference in this work very much work in progress so just
give you one slide on this again our ideas to get an implicit information or
looking for is very short inference chains again we're not going to prove fermat's last
theorem using the simple mechanism i'm about to show you but we would like to
get some basic facts that aren't in the in the corpus so let's say textrunner
notes that turing was born in london
and let's say we know from wordnet could get this from textrunner is well easier
to get one in london is the part of england and furthermore let's say we
have a rule that says born in is transitive thru part of what that basically
means is we can conclude that touring is born in england
OK even though the corpus might not say this in in fact in one hundred
twenty million web pages that are in the textrunner corpus it says that he was
born in london but doesn't say there was born in england right so if you
just a simple question answering thing as good hey
was turing born in england also know was born in london
that's not the behaviour that we want out of these systems so what the mechanism
that we build doesn't it instantiates a markov logic network on the fly
based on
the extraction and knows about based on rules learned from corpus what i'm about to
show you actually the rules were coded by hand the automatic learning of rules is
is actually future work but we get inference simple system
then hopefully i can show you here
for confinement
a lot
the law
that that
these are
people in
a lot of things that
you said
there is
using the three
of the
thank you
you know of
press release
it has
and very often
you more
as you
there are very
we you are in
i don't know anything about
if you like
process is
five or
there is no
i think
james james remind me how
it seems to be the
the notation
the number of goals here
is this core
the score of the work of the word
and the words in order here
the first one the first words of the so-called display the last one of
so thought guess the highest score five
this course is coincidental is just one two three four five
it could be this course could be ten
fifty and twenty just
do less confusion
but so you get a score five four thought
well they get score one which is the worse
it seems that
and then he gets
four here for
for effect
and if there is a theory
the score of four
so when you read this you have to read the scores so this is the
first one is the second one in the ranking
so the let's finish
before one is dreams
the rest of so your training has
it's the small
my that
they have
i felt
so this is the order the
the the order of the words as they
i have shown that
and people were asked to give up and score for each one
the high school scored closes the idea word idea
so people
gave it
five fold
i mean it's the majority of people
they gave one
to a
here's my two
four two theory
the dream
in attention to
so these as i was trying to say
in my
and that's the way to toward these things to me would be
this one the right
that was my my choice that's if it's too hard to different
the ordering this implies
the better one is thought
which is one
the second one is not the second one is theory
which is
the third one
the other one is
its attention to the right
number of ancients five
and then
play is the last one
and a number two
i got the right
so among there
but there are some of course this psychology model not everyone will think will agree
you know
play and attention
quite far from idea right
so flipping that thing doesn't mean that you are not
you know
this is just this is just one of the ironies
a low activation energy for diffusion
a high melting metals
has a high bond energy therefore high vacancy formation energy
there's such beauty in this graph
this completeness here ties everything together
it's really
so elegant
and we can also look at diffusion by interstitial mechanism that's what shown underneath here
the same idea
the only difference is with interstitials there are so many interstitials they exist we don't
have to pay to form the interstitials the interstitials are there by virtue of the
fact that we don't have a hundred percent back the closest back structure we have
FCC and that's seventy four percent atomic so therefore it's twenty six percent three volumes
we got twenty six percent play with and it's unlikely we've got interstitial willing to
consume all that so in the case of interest shells for interstitials the q is
simply equal to delta h
of migration in the case of interstitial you don't have to pay
the formation of vacancies
so now let's get to the question of random atomic motion
this is
well conventions that we have random atomic motion
let's look at are very clean experiment let's look at this when we talk about
radioactivity last suppose i make a diffusion sandwich that consists of the following
i'm gonna put cobalt
cobalt it's all pure cobalt
the only difference is the centre of the sand which is going to consist of
radioactive cobalt
and the
the two layers of bread
cool cobalt
there is no concentration gradient here because you know that
radioisotopes behave identically
the fact that there's radioactivity does not
affect the chemical bonding capabilities of
cobalt because it doesn't affect the electronic structure and as far as the mass effect
goes it's so tiny they can be disregarded
so what happens over time
if there is no concentration gradient according to fix there should be no diffusion
but what happens is this cartoon shows
if we have a centre band here that consists of a mix of radio cobalt
and regular cobalt over time we find that the cold war is uniformly distributed throughout
the sparse
and if we stop action and measure the rate of dispersion of cobalt through the
specimen we find that the rate is described by fixed laws
so we have a random
at the atomic level
in accordance with
six first law
in accordance with fixed first law
so this is a demonstration
we have things occurring at the
at domestic level
random jumping in to make the case for
the actual curve here always gaussians
which is exactly the
random walk problem you know the drunken sailor walks out the door takes one step
forward two steps and so the chances that he gets five steps wear vanishingly small
chance study
falls after one or two steps are higher so you'll get gaussians curve here for
the distance that the cobalt is gone as a function of time
what's wrong with this cartoon by the way
we talked about this is called jumping through cobalt were discovered after jump to
just to jump into
the vacancy housing vacancy here so the chances of this cobalt jumping
and exchanging with the adjacent called now we're not talking about a tiny fluctuations
to allow cobalt discord into a vacancy we're talking about a fluctuation like this to
allow to cobalt to crisscross and i mean that's just not going to happen
maybe once in the
life the universe but i don't think it's going to happen so we really need
to have vacancies in here and and ultimately we have to recognise that diffusion is
heavily influenced by
influenced by defects
no vacancies
four diffusion any vacancies
better diffusion
let's take a look at some
evidence of this
this is the plot of diffusion coefficient as a function of temperature it's an arrhenius
plot in accordance with
called in
they are not
right now we are going
you know what
this should be a
shows you
it is
after all
this is hard
we're not sure
and all that
i think that's all
i right issue
i call
they were we know that you are
seems me i
he said you know wrong
got some
my life
why not
i feel
these are
these people
well we
our station
five years
well you know
all of the
problem is
the reason why
the station
and then
from you
will be special it'll be symmetric positive definite so this'll be its eigenvectors and disobedience
eigen value and the eigen values will be positive because
this thing positive definite
can I just now it's OK so this is my method this tells me what
these are
and how am I gonna find the use
1 way would be to look at a A transpose
put to multiply a by a transpose in the opposite order that will stick them
these in the middle knocked them out and leave me with the use
so is the overall picture there
that these are the eigenvectors of A transpose
the use the eigenvectors of a transpose which a different
and the sigma
the square root of the
and the positive square roots so we have positive sake let me do that for
that example this is this is really what you should know and be able to
do for
that the SVD OK
let me take that matrix so what's my 1st step
compute a transpose
because I want
it's eigenvectors OK so I have to compute a transpose A
so a transpose is worth
minus 3 3 and a is for
minus 3 3 and I do that multiplication and I get 16 I get 24
get 16 minus 9
is at 7
and that better cannot symmetric and OK Americans out 25
I won its eigenvectors and its eigen values its eigenvectors will be the these its
eigen values will be the squares of the signal
OK what are the eigenvalues and eigenvectors of this guy
have you have you seen that 2 by 2
enough to recognize that the eigenvectors are that 1 1 is an eigenvector
so this is here is a transpose then I'm looking for its eigenvectors
so it's eigenvectors I think are 1 1 and 1 minus because if I multiply
that matrix by 1 1 1 0 again
I multiply that matrix by 1 1 I get 32 32
so which is 32 1 1 loss so there is
the 1st eigenvector
and there is the eigen value for A transpose A so I'm going to school
taken square root is
in the
it forcing
OK what's the eigenvector the goes eigen value that goes with this 1
if I do that multiplication what I get I get some multiple of one minus 1
and what is that multiple
looks like 18
OK so those are the 2 eigenvectors Michael
does the moment I didn't normalized
that to make everything absolutely right ion and normalize these eigenvectors divided by the length
square root of 2 so all these guys should be
unit vectors
and of course that normalization didn't change the 32 in the eighties
so I'm
happy with the visa here that
so now let me
put together that the
pieces here here's my
is my a
let me
let me write down again
this should therefore
life is right
we should get you which I don't yet know
you I don't get no
signal do now no
what sigma
so I'm looking for you know segment of the transfer of you
the diagonal got and the transpose
OK just to see that come out right so what's what are the what of
the segment
there the square roots of these things so square root of 32
and squared
but the
0 0
1 of the
there are these 2 and I have to transpose maybe that's maybe leave with 1
with 1 over square root of 2 in that row
and the other 1 is 1 over square root 2 minus 1 over the square
root of 2
now finally have gotten know the
well actually 1 way to do since I now know all the other pieces I
could put those together and figure out what the user but let me do it
the A transpose way
OK finally used now
but but you wanted you to
and 1 the
I look at a transpose
so a is supposed to be used in the transport
and then I transpose that I get really is saying that transpose
so I'm just doing in the opposite order times A transpose and what's the good
part here that in the middle of the transpose v is going be
the identity
but it is
so this is just you
sigma sigma transpose that some diagonal matrix with sigma squared and nutrients
so what am I saying here
I'm sitting here again a symmetric positive
definite or at least definite matrix and see its eigenvectors and its eigen values
so if I compute a transpose
it's eigenvectors will be the things that go into you
OK so I need to compute a transpose
I guess I'm going to have to go
but me tonight
can I move up just a little maybe a little more
and do a transfer
so what's a 4
minus 3 and 3 and what's a transpose for 4 minus 3 and 3
and when I do that multiplication
what I get for get 16 32
but that 1 comes out 0 so this is the likely
and how much in memory they have to use
so here is the performance comparison between four methods - mofa, gspan, ffsm and gaston
mofa uses a free extension gspan uses depth first right most extension
ffsm has its own canonical labeling system
and the gaston uses
a specific search order. it tries to
find is tree patterns first and then based on tree patterns
more complicated graph patterns can be constructed as the same time gaston remember all of
the embeddings of subgraph isomorphism of
previously discovered patterns
so you can see that
running time of time of gaston is faster than just gspan
and faster than FSM and the mofa.
and the next slide we show the memory comparison between these four methods
as you can see that because gaston and FFSM
have to remember
embeddings and there's about isomorphism of discovered the patterns
so it cost a lot of
it uses a lot of main memory
than the gspan method and mofa method because it never do the
sub-graph isomorphism recording so it uses less memory so you can
you can choose either of these amazons based on your application
so so far i have introduced the basic design principles of the existing graph pattern mining algorithms
however there is a potential problem existing in frequent graph pattern mining
this problem is not related to the algorithm design but is caused by the definition
of frequent graph patterns
if the graph is the frequent, then all of its subgraphs will be frequent so you can imagine
that if there is a large graph pattern existing in the database so it is
impossible to enumerate all of the subgraphs
in this larger part
so here example we actually
try to mine an AIDS anti-virus screen was around four hundred chemical compounds and we
set the minimum threshold of five percent
it will generate are one million frequent patterns so this problem actually
existing for all of the
previously discovered graph pattern mining algorithms. since they have to enumerate so many graph patterns.
so that's three problems
caused by this phenomenon first we have interpretation problem basically giving you
was one million pattern set what can we do
second in many cases if we lower down the
pattern minimum threshold we might have an exponential pattern set and the search
we need some mechanism to
determines the minimum threshold
it is very hard to actually
so in the next several slides i will show you how can we overcome these
three problems
which will further advance the graph pattern mining algorithm further
so first of all interpretation interpretation problem
as we know too many patterns sometimes really confusing and in many cases it all
the way will lead to poor results for example we can use all
of the three principal discovered and put them into a graph classification
framework and we will find that the classifier will be soon so will be
so we we we we make conclusions that actually is in many cases a small
set of representative patterns
are good enough actually if they can preserve most of the information so we propose
method to
extract those representative patterns from for example one million discovered patterns one method is
clustering if we are able to define a distance between two graphs then we
can do clustering and extract the cluster centers and use these cluster centres as representative
or which we can use top k
pattern mining
for example we can first to generate all those frequent patterns and is then calculators
there significant scores and choose the top
OK most significant patterns and
present these patterns to the end-users
for the clustering method basically we need to do is define a pattern distance between
two graphs
so there are two methods to do this
pattern distance measure
in the first method - method one we actually can use existing graph edit distance to measure the
distance between two graph patterns
in the second measure instead of measure the distance of this while patterns directly we
can use the dataset that contains these patterns and user similarity between these data to
appear to behave in some cases
like the particle
and not away
in one of those cases this observation here
of the photoelectric effect
so what we're going to do is going to look at both tracks of observations
and we're going to see
how these observations
made it
such that it was
impossible to explain
how an atom held together how an electron and the nucleus held together
the classical way of thinking within the newtonian mechanics mechanics is going to be looking
at this semester in eight o one
you can use their mechanics to understand how this electron and the nucleus they together
you can use the mechanics to understand how to the atoms are bound together we
need a new way of thinking
and that these two tracks of observations
that led to
the discovery in the sense of this new kind of mechanics we're going to be
talking about
so let's start with one of these tracks
and the attractor is the
attractor of seeing the name is not the most basic constituent matter
and the first observation done by this gentleman JT thomas
the discovery of the electron
so i'm going to need my son again
all right
so what you comments was interested in doing was understanding
what the discharges were made
right so he had
i last two that was evacuated
and that she had
what we're going to call you can hold
here here at all
they said well after all
from out
and it builds up with the hydrogen h two
and what he does is he puts a large negative potential on this
ninety and with large positive potential any claims that the potential difference here
he keeps creating an
until at some point
the gas begins to glow
at that point it is this charge here is a nice
and this kind of plasma
and he wanted to understand what's in this class
it's just curious he wants to know
and so
what he does
is there any pokes home here in the
there's a whole lot south
a little of this discharge
and let it out in my talk is great
and we here
he has some kind of a screen for screen
so they not only
does this discharge here
glow is moving along
but when it hits the first screen lights up
and that's nice
then what he does
eight two
the parallel plates
any points at all in all
this woman is being
and there's a pop chart one of these negative charge on the other
and on the whole when
increases this potential difference delta b
what happens is
that this woman as being some of them be
it's actually deflected
a little bit
so now
here's another very bright
we can measure this
we're going to call it tells us
since i was going to be
it was deflected toward positively charged plate
kind of particles
five world in this has been
negative articles because they're attracted to the positively charged plate
so we call this deflection delta x call delta x minus
now he knew enough electromagnetism at the time
to realize
the amount of deflection
so which is particularly relevant to this summer school of school
so many people want to text mining because the amount of tax information available in
the internet is just a huge and it is impossible for human being told that
this information out
actually text mining has become a very classical incubator for new machine learning algorithms and
techniques and of models and you will see
many of such development in this autumn school
so much and is playing a significant role in between text mining such as ranking
document in the web all understanding the topic aspect of documents
cummings was also using machine learning to do cool things such as according what are
thinking when you're reading something for example when you really not your bring may show
up a special wave pattern which can be actually recognised by a machine learning was
therefore if i your brain hopefully can decode what you actually thinking about of course
this is something in the future which we can do now is some simplistic classification
and the machine is also playing an important role in bioinformatics for example if i
show you task like these were have give you
screams of little characters and want to ask you were in this character there is
the gene
actually there are much and i was
which is exactly doing this job these days so that human being don't have to
do experimental
and for such things
machine learning council
ask not only engineering problem but also scientific problems such as i evolution
if you see say DNA sequences or other biological traits of modern
organisms such as human being all models which are supposedly to be derived from a
common ancestor
you can actually run the statistical learning was and to infer
what is the ancestor of the heart and said look like and highlight takes to
grow from ancestor toward the individual you see nowadays
so these are some quick examples of one machine learning can do for you
and that comes to a more technical definition of machine learning which i personally come
up with a just want share with you because the street your definition is kind
of vague
and it is very hard to
for those who probably guess what is exactly were doing for example in these
autumn school
so i summarise machine learning this single slice
which says that
machine learning six to develop those series
and the computational systems
doing certain tasks as it is the following
it is for
o classifier clustering or recognising objects
for reasoning and uncertainty
offer predicting unknown in the future
all four reacting to certain environmental stimuli
which is existing in the complex real world data
and also it is based
sorry you start to read it is based
the systems own experience with data rather than i tell the system what to do
and also hopefully under a unified model of mathematical formula
such that the system we developed or the theory that it was it was developed
can be formally categorized and analyzed
and also we can take into account the common prior knowledge due to some of
form or principle and
the fundamental mathematical techniques
and also can generalize and that across and domain so that you can learn from
this part of the data to do task in the other part of data which
is called transfer learning
and and also can operate automatically and autonomously without human intervention of our minimum amount
of mentioned
and also can be interpreted and perceived by humans so when learning about box which
can do things want to actually understand why
it was performing well
and what true actually can be covered all learned are inspired from the performance of
such words so this is my
slice of summarising what machine learning is about of course it's not just your personal
so there's a great deal challenges
in machine learning research
in order to develop computer systems that can automatically improve with experience
and also
and also to uncover what is the law governing the learning process in general
and it turns out that tool
so such changes
we need to integrate expertise all knowledge is from a lot of different domains and
typically these three domains forms
the pinnacle of machine learning which is that it's computer science and the human
and animal learning study
so in statistics we want to use statistical models and theories
to infer data
and also to characterize
the reliability all
performance of such early i would
and in computer science we want of course developed cold true
so this problem automatically
and i also want to study the complexity issue involved in such learning problems
and of course they want rules
i understand why why learning well
so how we can better using a computer therefore ontocat motivation all inside from
no studies in animal psychology and in the human learning so that we can you
know can kind of get a ground all research into a more general
human perceivable basis
it is exactly because of all these motivations and these need no we actually renamed
our centre of automated learning and discovery into discover this torrent of machine learning
which is sort of to be you know time to serve as a protein four
people from multiple disciplines to interact
in very intimate sense and also to do research on today and also to develop
curriculum and to teach classes and supervise students and they're very unified goal
but with a very diverse set of approaches
and maybe even philosophy
we now have a very strong group of core faculties
horse names are
listed here
and then
this presentation is delivered by the stanford center for professional development
let's get started with today's material
so on welcome back to second lecture
what i want to do today is talking about on the regression gradient descent and
the normal equations on and i chose to lecture notes had been posted online and
so you know if some of them have a go over today of my goal
rather quickly if you want to see every equation written out and work for the
details also yourself because of the course home page and download some detail lecture notes
that pretty much describes all the mathematical technical content over today on
today i'm also going to delve into fairmont some amount of linear algebra and so
on if you would like to see a refresher on linear algebra of this week's
discussion section will be probability is and will be a refresher on linear algebra so
this is of some of the outer right talk about today
seems to be going by quickly or if you just want to see some of
the things i'm claiming today without proof if you want to just see some of
those things result in detail on come to this week's discussion section
actually establishing a fun video on remember at the last lecture the initial lecture i
talked about supervised learning
as supervised learning was this machine learning problem where i said we're gonna hold the
album what the call right answer is for you ever ever for a number of
examples and we want the album to replicate more to say so the example i
had on the first lecture was the problem of predicting housing prices where you have
a training set and we tell the algorithm what the code to write housing price
was for every holes in the training set anyway algorithm to learn the relationship between
you know sizes of houses and the price essentially produce more of the quotes right
so they pay for you video now i wish the big screen
so think video now
there was from dean palmer who want somewhere he did carnegie mellon
on apply supervised learning together called the drive itself
this is work on vehicle known as alvin was done about this this was done
for about fifteen years ago
and it was all
he was very elegant example of
the sorts of things you can get supervised learning algorithms to do
on the video you hear dean palmer use voice mentioned an album called neural networks
was a little bit about that later but some
the the social learning algorithm for this is something called gradient descent which which actually
sort of data in today's lecture let's with
the video
alvin is the system of artificial neural networks
learns to steer by watching the person drive
however is designed to control the nevland two
modified army humvee equipped with sensors
and actuators
four autonomous navigation experiments
the initial step
in configuring album this training and we're just here
during training a person drives the vehicle
while alvin watches
once every two seconds
alvin digitize is the video image of the road ahead
and records the person steering direction
this training image is reduced in resolution to thirty by thirty two pixels and provided
as input two albums three layer network
so two comments very one is on this supervised learning because learning from the human
driver in which a human driver shows that you know we're on this segment of
the road was steered zango the second row is the this angle as the human
provides the number of calls correct steering directions to the car and then is the
job of the car to try to learn to produce more pieces code correct steering
directions that keeps the car on the road
glucose metabolism
it has it has as its there are generated from metabolism it has the end
products of nitrogen metabolism which is chiefly urea
and ammonia
and those and and that blood is indicated here is the blue
now we usually show these blue blue-collar vessels usually show as red and blue indicating
locks of oxygen red not very much oxygen blue but it's not just oxygen is
changed right the chemical composition has changed dramatically there's a lot more common outside there's
a lot more
there's a lot more of other things coming out of the of the in it
through the veins
the small veins called the
merge to form larger veins eventually very large brains like being a cave which come
back to the right side of the heart
the right side of the heart is anatomically very similar to the the left side
there's a tree and there's the ventricle
and blood flows out of the ventricle
through the pulmonary artery
to the lungs
now notice that there is something different here
but on this side of the circulatory system the part where the blood is going
up to the rest of your body the artery
contains oxygenated blood
on this side play you
the pulmonary artery
is an artery
it has the same features as
a systemic artery like the order has the muscular wall for example doesn't transport nutrients
so it looks like an artery but it carries d oxygenated blood
it's carrying it only one place
back to the lungs
and is collected in the
collected on the other side of the long now with oxygen and returns to the
point where we start
it's not just that it's not just a closed system is to closed systems
it's too close systems one that we're going to call the system
but that by the left side of the heart
we're oxygenated blood goes out to the whole periphery of your body
and is and is collected back by the right side of your heart that's one
closed system
the second is
it is
the pulmonary
vascular system which is
which is
the forces generated by the right side of the heart
the flow is generated by the right side of the heart blows only to the
to the lungs and oxygenated blood comes back to the left side so it's sort
of like a figure eight right
one loop
a second loop
what's the
if the rate of flow is five litres per minute through the order
what's the flow rate in the pulmonary artery
the two independent systems
so what's the rate of flow in the pulmonary artery
it has to be five litres per minute because they are not independent right the
there there there really i described them as two closest is really one closed system
with the with the loop right
with the loop so the flow has to be the same everywhere
the flow has to be the same everywhere
OK so let's talk about blood flow in these vessels for a moment i have
this picture of the overall of the overall composition of the circulatory system let's think
about a very simple
a very simple
problem that engineers have thought about for hundreds of years now it turns out to
have a lot of relevance in the cardiovascular system but has relevance
everywhere has relevance in terms of
getting water to all the
forces in this building
this you have to solve the same problem and that is
generating enough pressure to allow
fluid to move through the length of
two being
and so will think about a typical length of tubing i'll make it as simple
as possible it's vessel has a constant diameter radius and online
and and fluid is going to flow in one into this vessel is going to
flow out the other
this is called internal flow through it two
and it turns out to be one of the most well studied problems in all
of engineering i'm just going to tell you one aspect of this that over a
certain range of flow rates
over a certain range of flow rates so this is true all the time but
this was
the first
this is
these are all
so the whole
we are just
this is
it i
so all
well it
there you
the whole
the first one
o point
that is the
what will
so called
he has
the point
four years
and the
in this work
that is
it's like this this this and this
this model
of my brothers and
like this
yes it's true that there are there in principle question there if you had let's
say you had no fifty data points or something like that then the difference in
marginal likelihood you might might my
often be in overwhelming so that you know
you know the one parameter is not gonna is not going to really
change things the right could well be that fitting in data set inside this model
it uses a very large value alpha
o point
which is a simpler model
and but it can choose a simple model over over
over more complex one even if you're even if it's allowed to to cheat a
little bit on one parameter right
well BIC
it's it's often a terrible
approximation so but whether terrible is worse than ignoring the problem
you know
i don't know so typically typically anything you do a little bit better using a
lot more work
right so there's there's trade off their i
nineteen ninety four
well i think it matters quite a lot of what covariance function using it so
let me show you an example of
a real data set right and so we'll see things that you wouldn't be able
to do if you just said you know let's just use
you know
let's just have
so let's come to an example and look at that
OK so so so up until now we've also been looking at very smooth functions
you can also be also families that generate distributions are functions that don't necessarily have
all derivatives so you can choose functions that have say two
so the partial derivatives but not
primitives of higher order than that
and the covariance function for that look something like this where k here is a
modified bessel function
not sure what that is but i can certainly plug so here you sample functions
of the covariance functions look like this again you get the gaussians
a special case and you can get rough and for functions of functions that have
less and less derivatives and again you can see here the green you have sort
of a smooth function and right
in black you have something which is a little more interesting behaviour and you can
get you know quite quite scary behavior out of this kind of thing is well
quite so we are not just restricted to to working with with smooth functions
is not a little trick which domenici i to me a long time ago so
you can get periodic functions by instead of looking at covariances between points themselves you
map the point assigning call signs
of the of the points in the new measure the distances in that space so
because the distance measure is now periodic the function should get are also chaotic and
here another example for simon that if you you can write down you know quite
your comments pages like this and then you could pick random functions and you see
they're all exactly periodic right this is quite amazing like so these are periodic functions
but they are not sines cosines right
just random functions which are which are periodic and inside the period here used the
squared exponential covariance function of the this smooth periodic
and here had chosen long lengthscale lengthscale which is almost the same as the period
so we get something which is close to sinusoidal
here chosen the lengthscale internal links which is much shorter
then the period so i get a lot of behaviour inside the period right before
all right so
it's a very unusual name
know the covariance function actually strictly positive
i'm putting random functions drawn from
well no it's not having shown the covariance function
i'm showing you random functions drawn from the process without going over the next
yes so
i think all the ones i've shown you
no they the the one
as negative covariance right
so there's no
you don't have to have a strictly positive covariance functions and this is something that
worried me a lot in the beginning that when you're looking at when your modelling
functions in your covariance function says that you only have positive
covariance and it turns out that as it turns out that doesn't really matter very
much unfortunately
it's hard to give
it's a good intuitive explanation about so if people are interested in that i should
maybe offline because always make it might bit it might sound complicated but there some
good reasons why it doesn't matter so much it has to do with the fact
that it is very easy to infer the low frequency components of the function
all right so
now let's put this all this stuff together right so i showed you this example
before we started although it was a little bit of a sort of a toy
example at least at some some real metadata so how do i use accounting process
to make predictions on this dataset
the way i'm going to do it is that i'm going to i'm going to
i'm going to cheat a little bit because i'm a sort of pragmatic basis right
so i look at the data
i don't know exactly what the i don't know much about about sort of sort
of chemistry of the atmosphere chemistry but i can look at i can certainly look
at the data right and look at the data and i say well
there are certain
trends that i can but i can but i can pick out here and how
could i have a model that could model trained so the first ran the simplest
one is that there is a long term seem to be equal right over fifty
years you know is that the the
concentration went up so
and we know we can we can get no smooth trains with with a squared
exponential covariance function right so put that in there
i'm saying that i don't know what the magnitude is so that's free parameter
and i i don't know exactly what length scale this trained happened but that's not
a free parameter
OK but there was more stuff in their right
there's also those seasonal component you can see that these are monthly data right you
can see there a very strong seasonal component there's also some very good reasons why
you have that seasonal component so maybe you should try and model that as well
so one way of modelling that is using this construction that we just saw where
you can get periodic functions so here's a covariance for for for periodic functions so
i say i don't know what the magnitudes of my period
i said here to one year because
because of because of my prior domain knowledge