so we can celebrate yet
we have to wait
civic party
there is always a little bit of an issue about
the direction of the a
i will explain to you how the convention goes but
it really is not
so crucial because lens always helps you
to find
the direction of the EMF but if we are trying to be
if this is
my conducting
and if i catch
a flat surface to this if i did that
and if i go around a closed loop integral you don't pl
violators doesn't county which we have to go i can go clockwise i can go
we will then do the same thing that we did before with MP's law
apply the right
and corkscrew rule
and that is that if you mark around clockwise
will be in the blackboards
perpendicular to the blackboard perpendicular to the surface
and if you go counterclockwise
and the a
welcome put you
the surface
it doesn't have to be flat
it can be flat nothing wrong with it
but they can also be a bag attached to it
as we also had earlier i have here
close conducting wire
and i could put surface right here but i can also make it had like
this is perfectly fine
nothing wrong with that
that's a open surface attached to this
that's fine
you have a choice
and the convention was the eighties then exactly the same
if you go clockwise
then the DNA will be in this direction
using the right hand corkscrew
locally here if you went counterclockwise
the able to flip over
so what is now a recipe that you have to follow
you have a circuit
electric circuit that determines then
you know of course you can take a look anywhere in space but that's not
the we need to be taken into your
and so you define the look first
then you define direction in which you want to march around that circuit
you attach
an open service to that
closed loop
and you can determine on the entire surface
the integral of e dot
everywhere on that surface locally you know to be a local you know to be
the reintegration and you get the magnetic flux
and then if you know to try change of the magnetic flux
then you know the EMF
if you go around in this
and you measure every really electric fields then the integral of e dot
if you go around the loop will give you the same answer that connects the
the magnetic
flux change
it's connected
which the integral of e dot o when you go around
have a minus sign to come
how come it doesn't matter
whether you choose a flat surface
whether you choose a bag
i think of
magnetic field lines
as a flow of water
if you like that or flow of air
it is clear
that if there is some kind of the flow of air through these openings that
don't come out somewhere so it always comes out of the surface
and therefore
you are free to choose that so you always because surface
that is
the best one for you
all this looks very complicated
but in practice it really isn't
because you know is always the conducting wire
in your circuit
and the minus sign
it's never an issue
because you always know was lens law
in which direction
the EMF is
in fact when i solve these problems
i don't even look at the minus sign i ignored completely
and if i calculate the magnetic flux change and i always know in which direction
the current is so i don't even look at the minus sign
now i want to show you demonstration which is
very much like
try to do
i have here solenoid
we've seen this one before
we can generate quite a
magnetic field was that
and we're going to put around the solenoid
one look
like we had here
like fire they did never going to close to switch
so we're going to build this magnetic field and we going to see the current
in that
and so if we look we make a cross section straight through here
then it will look as follows
and you see here
the solenoid thirty magnetic field is really confined to the solenoid magnetic field outside the
solenoid is we discussed earlier is almost zero
so is only a magnetic field right here keep that in mind in what follows
and now we're going to put a wire around
was an interim there
if the magnetic field
comes out of the board
and is growing
the current will flow in this direction
lens law
if it is decreasing
the current will go in the opposite direction
now keep in mind that the magnetic flux
through this surface
my surface which i attached to this
closed loop that magnetic flux
remains the same
when i make the movies big when i make the loop very crooked
like so
because the magnetic flux
is only confined
building blocks for those
for these images and you can see actually they're pretty simple patterns that not specific
instances of sharp high-resolution eyes or nose are so on wheels
so these become the building blocks for
here's another example so
no we have to represent images how do we represent our images we basically take
the building blocks and look at every single specific image look at how many english
a slanted line dispatched does this image have
so we give it to frequency counter probably normalizer saw and this
and this is the way of the the
of the dictionary becomes the representation of the image
again this is very analogous to the text document research
people have been using
so now we have seen how to put these images through the global dictionary into
the into the bag of words let's look at
the core
into this algorithm are these models probabilistic models and here i'm going to use
two case studies one is the earliest paper that have used the bag of words
model representation and use use the naive bayes classifier to do very successful recognition another
one is actually this series of papers that built upon this recent events in text
that rigour actually gives a good introduction to so these probabilistic and semantic
and as is PLS and the latent dirichlet allocation LDA models so
here are just some some notation what we're going to call is that we're going
to call w patch in the image and and w actually also indicates
dictionary vocabulary this patch of the image comes from so
it will be represented as a vector of let's say are dictionaries three hundred number
of vocabularies and vector of three hundred and then let's say the hundred fifty s
is what this patch comes from so there's a one here and the rest is
zero so this is our basic description of the image patch and the border w
is the collection of these patches so you can imagine as as the matrix and
in text text community we call this a document ending vision we call this an
image and then
and then we have the is
d j indicates the j document in image collection c is our category label and
z is
what we will see later on the latent topics you come across in all these
so the simplest case is the naive bayes model that tucker and her colleagues proposed
and very successfully in fact that the model is very simple what we have is
that for every class
models a bicycle we have we represent probability this way the likelihood would be given
this class
the likelihood of the image and then we have a prior probability for the for
the class
and then to even simplify our lives better what they do is they
assume independence of all patches within this image so what you end up with this
is actually a product of the likelihood of each patch given this class
so we expand this into here and then
then the system
react very strongly will going to residents
build up huge amplitude because you keep feeding in
waves and they keep coming back to the whole thing starts building up
and that's the idea of resonance
and residence normal modes one and the same that's the normal mode of these
strings fixed
both ends we also referred to them sometimes as
natural frequencies
these points here
the name
they are called notes
this is no
this is an old
and these points he also here and here are the ones that have the largest
amplitude i called and nodes
and i call the time is very strange
recall the bike about is this
so the boundary condition leads to discrete values
of the
resonance frequencies
and if this recording mechanics we will call these i can solutions and i can
so if you want to write down now
the situation for you and smote
in its most general form
then you will get
the function of x and y
in the and small
would have its own amplitude
they and whatever that is
you can take that for different
values of and
and then you have to sign
and by
i'm excited by l
during the cosine
of omega and c
meets the boundary conditions
four two fixed ends
any linear sort position
any combination various values of nancy and and various values of a that satisfy
the wave equation so this strain can simultaneously oscillate in a whole series of these
normal modes and when we do music next thursday you'll see that actually i will
demonstrate that to you
what i want to show you now is that if i
take a strange
and again assistance
even though it has spring-like qualities we will treat it as a string
then i will show you that if i drive this at the end of proper
i can
it generates the residences and i can make you see the normal modes
always willing to assist this time you're dying last time also write but
he called on the battle then
holding your hand firmly
just walk back at nothing
just walk back or back you tension on their OK that's fine
so i'm not going to wiggle this is really a fixed and you will see
when i read residence at my hand is hardly moving at all keep bumping waves
in and they keep coming back at me in the amplitude build up
and then i have to search for these resonances and when it what i know
you'll see why i know i feel it in my stomach i feel it in
my time here
in my hands and my whole body knows i present
you'll see that
there we go this is the
this is the lowest mode
this is an equals one
the nodes of my hand is hardly move at all
and they all fall
practical reasons is really a fixed
you get that solutions
i will now try to
find the second harmonic
which would end up then and a as a node in the middle
in addition to nodes at the end
that it
and again when they then resonance which is the normal mode noted in my hand
is hardly moving
what do i think really no i'm always
i can try to third one
in which case you would see two nodes in the middle
with the and
this is the third one
good today and why not
very clearly points then still
normal modes
i'm not supposed to do that
all men
reporting my demonstration
now i will try to generate the highest frequency normal mode i can so you
can't the number of nodes in the middle
and if you find five and that's the six
you make
i think i can do that
but it's not so easy to get very high frequencies so you do nothing because
you would really ruin it
get him getting there
get it going to the art of mike i don't know
you should have moved to see
it wasn't your fault tried again
i can not arise in the got
and the going resonance can please count how many features
i counted twelve nodes in the middle
what's your name
all right so this is the way it works that you see
normal mode
it's either result
which will be standing waves
the demonstration speaks for itself
i have here a rubber hose
which we are going to excite interface harmonic
let's see how that works whether we were close
anyone touches table
there than the tension changes and immediately of course the
the resonance frequency changes because the resonance frequency
notice has this thing it
one which chased different it's not bad
so now i will
throughout this one for you
because you
i have no idea here
that's what is happening is going like this is going too fast for you
so i make it easy on
turn the lights off thank you
so i'm going to struggle between u
and then
i can more or less make the
rope stands still
but i can also offset the frequency of my strobe light a little bit
so that you actually zero
move very slowly
so i can purposely
give the
strobe light a slightly different frequencies
so that's what i'm doing now
this is just like
so you have no doubt anymore but fact
no doubts
that indeed
i think we can actually
so next
speaking in my experience has
it's not for
community but only everybody
most of you
we're using his contribution to facebook so
friend suggests we should by fifty percent last year
because of his way to the peace talks classes
finnish pg
and that is very visible
searching the area of
the social
network analysis
so many times and so have joined a facebook and so
but the difference this
but if you have anything that you find in dollars
so how we deal with
it is structured and unstructured data that we have
it's also just beginning
this is a major component of all the data we have work with they can
it all together and go to use
the house is a kind of the a product built around and then in the
limit are also died in two
work the most which is mountain is the front suggested about how the uses of
the relationships between people to make suggestions
so this is this is the first about the work is going here
so this is a graph showing
how many active users are about to start
i think that the people have sort of
i got tired of sending out press releases about how many millions of users are
the five million number is real now it's still going up you say can say
with the numbers
this page is huge sort of still going in the right
and so those million-plus users
there are also very active in the accounts of all the time it was for
a month or have them come every day
and all the people contributing a huge amount of
and sharing with friends and so there is over thirty billion pieces of content shared
this is the thing that i think
links now we're doing this check the places
this is actually the largest photo-sharing website now
it's so surpassed all the exclusively for those websites like flickr go
and currently there is over three billion photos being uploaded every month
and finally this is able what to connect with third-party developers
and not only are the other million websites he is one
don't have this sort like buttons all over the place but it's also the RDF
is the game
that is on the second the people
doing this by spending all the time that he began
in two thousand eight was only after by the data
not to say september two thousand ten which six months ago
the see almost hundred by today
you can plot the the trajectory imagine where it is today
it's big
so also to give you some idea of the scale of things work with you
can imagine all the problem is that you can use
one of the things that have happened in fact is the trend towards more and
more structured data
so if you go back and look at what people like two years ago in
two thousand eight
it was all this freeform text
these things are all links
but didn't really go to and is located just want a page about that specific
and this is what you get people make spelling mistakes in the typing all kinds
of things that are exactly the same people are expressing their own ways
so international viewers if anything better than to go for more structured
with the profile like
is this and you can see that there is no almost no
the act and is no one's place can then
well there but the most fact it's all very structured and things are linked to
other entities that are
just to highlight a couple of examples
i say
science university
and this is the link to some page about university and everybody on the planet
a student that for all of us are never in the field of information in
the profile is now similarly to the set of
similarly here
this movie
which i got like
i actually like this on IMDB
and the building this for my profile in related to
it has like that they can be extracted that a that
what are structured and we're not going to a few examples of
what these things that you don't
typically like famous tech today
when right so there
two different objects
that some way
so the most obvious way is the first principal every
friendship edges connecting to people
has some innovations things like who created it
what i missed a
but then so all the other
content if it also has
imposes some relationship on and so for the tags for instance example a person who
and then also the for the two
the owner of
and if you like the page and first that is forming a link from u
to that page
and now they don't like the pages of in this larger sets
people have in common
and so
we think about this
well the same thing as is just
all this structure does once you
all of these things are known to have a but there are no pages and
people and
and then there different sorts of edges in the different edges first have different meaning
semantics to them and their and in different ways
and when it comes down to it's all this is what a huge that with
so that's how would think constructed
was 1 way I can prove
we have a proposition last week that gave a sufficient condition for a direction to
be a descent direction and then my remember what that was
the direction is always going to be a descent direction if it satisfies case
that what you mean by that that the
it matters but yes it makes the corrected the product of the gradient of this
that something with gradient related anyway to borrow a phrase from the frequency so
it might
if my direction makes a negative inner product with the gradient there is going to
do it must be a descent direction so I need to prove that the transposes
it is less than 0
as I need to show you that that's somewhat straightforward what that it that
1 of the Board's here and we try something
the or
of the slave Woody Allen version of the
OK everybody see the bottom of the screen that you are interesting part so thank
you or to watch this so by definition I will have that my new direction
that would could gradient is minus the taking the transpose minus the gradient and the
inverse of the Hessian times the great right now let's
this would be
negative under what conditions
is the inverse is positive definite
right if the universe is positive definite this is going to be negative about this
whole thing is going to be
OK will we said that they tested positive definite
the largest I show you that the Hessian is positive definite if and only if
its inverse is positive and that's really easy so now I need to show in
order to complete the proof that this will definitely true here the age of x
inverse is speaker
but now why is that so what's this so I know that h effect existing
in the genetic any vector v there's a picture of
and then I know that for instance I know that there was less than
yes it what's the effect of being a direct interest is equal to
a heroin and we do this
0 yeah yeah meeting inverse community in which takes effect of in and that's true
and then this I know it's part is strictly positive
I want to prove this
yeah this is equal to this and this is positive this is strictly positive because
this is just this vector here with the Hessian it with the same vector
and so that's the 1st OK so but now what I showed you can if
applied shall use the new direction is the direction decrease I haven't shown you get
my point is going to have a better objective function right
everybody see the difference
right announced talk about rates of convergence and this is actually this is important not
just for this lecture but actually for the rest of the costs because
we improve a lot of things about that I prove for a lot of algorithms
that they convert you might think industrial on and convergence and so when for example
suppose the convergence rate suppose I got this wall I'd like to walk through this
wall of the following released at a distance from the wall is
of 1 over square root of k
how many iterations is going to take me
so clearly exposed to 0 as K goes to infinity case that distance is 1
over square root of k positive statements element in say 10 to the minus the
of the
whose home up to your name from credit
granted licenses community is 10 to the 6th and I don't have time over a
million iterations OK located on the other hand
right if they 1 tends to decay originality iterations is
yes 3 3 and so is when 2 different iterations at different rates of convergence
so will say that this series of a of k converges much slower this year
but we have general classes of convergence and so let's talk about that permit so
suppose I have here
so I have a series specified
OK and say that converges to some s
OK and this is just the latest scalars
so that also a
that my series
exhibits linear convergence in the limit is high goes to infinity of as survive plus
might as well over test is
equal the sum of delta that strictly less than 1
OK so what does that mean that means that
you can think of the numerator being how close online at the next iterations compared
to have survived the current iteration
and limit this riccio
is some number less than 1 we call that linear convergence OK
that's a linear convergence and ambiguity example of linear convergence for example possible
1 intended to the art of him or any number less than one recently I
power has exactly this this convergence rate and as Site did here in all the
only example by the way test for you
so as i plus 1 over SI is 1 tends to the eyeballs 1 divided
by 1 intensity light which is just 1 10
and so we cannot linear converges with the
what what's a much different phrase you might used to characterize the rate of decay
distant peak
which i find a searchlight back
the first one
his peers
both the princeton here at MIT
i found his mind extraordinarily
exciting as well as outrageously eccentric
one of them called him
a bad boy but a great
he had an enormous effect on the people around you
even in their dreams
donald newman
who was
a graduate student at harvard while nash was an instructor here
tells this wonderful story in the PBS documentary
it's donald newman was famously fast everything that he did
i was working on the problem all day long
what it wasn't the proof was not working i was working in getting absolutely nowhere
is terribly frustrated
and finally
i gave up
and i went to bed
in history
johnny cash
in is
the next morning
gets up
he goes to his desk
and for the rights it down
maybe you could try that
so by the age of thirty
nash is magnificent access
of creation had one mathematical starting the prospect of a full professorship here MIT
fortune magazine singled him out as the most brilliant
of the younger generation of mathematicians
he also met and married
his gorgeous student
we should large data
now we show was described to me
by some of her contemporaries here as
call in el salvador princess
with the sense of noblesse oblige
she was one of sixteen women this is in the early fifties one of sixteen
in the class
eight hundred euro two
she was a physics major
and somewhat incongruously cheerleader
her girlfriends
described she wore these very high heels
and these bouffant skirt swirls inch waist
her the photographs
show that she resembled elizabeth taylor and butterfield eight
but her girlfriends also also
emphasise that the ethereal
need to we should
i always had
quote an agenda
that she always exhibited
a certain steele
in fact just like in the movie she first got
national attention
in his classroom with this
calculated act of defiance
anyway by thirty two all appearances john nash had adapted pretty perfectly
rebecca west's loss of life
but underneath
there was
chaos in contradiction
a neglected illegitimate son
abandoned mistress
an ambivalence towards
his new marriage
and his new wife's pregnancy
as for so many other
very gifted
extremely ambitious individuals
there was also this nagging sense of doubt
i probably don't have to tell the people in this room that
four mathematician turning thirty is about as bad as it is
four athletes were dancer
h is
the enemy
of creativity
so despite his stunning successes john nash
as you approach thirty
did over his perceived failures
the fields medal
that he had one
offer from
princeton our
you see MIT was what it is today
the offer from princeton harvard they hadn't got
the solutions to
these mega problems in quantum mechanics and in number theory
that he had found
the first signals of his slide from extreme eccentricity two
right so courses
were so cryptic so fleeting
many of nations colleagues thought he was simply indulging in one of his usual
private jokes
one new year's eve
in nineteen fifty eight he showed up at a costume party
wearing a diaper
and spent the night
sitting on leashes lap
alternately sucking on a pacifier and taking swigs from a baby bottle filled with urban
and now
one morning
not long after he walked into
the common
here at MIT
carrying a copy of the new york times
he said to know in particular that
the story on the front page contained encrypted messages from the inhabitants of another galaxy
messages moreover that only he could decipher
one of nash's graduate students was
so intimidated
fine ashes ferocious intellect
then he said nothing to anyone else who department
about the fact that nash had taken him aside and offered him
not only an intergalactic
driver's license
but i see on his newly organised world government
in february nineteen fifty nine
john nash gave a lecture at columbia university a much publicized highly-anticipated lecture
in which he was going to tell the audience
his idea of an idea
about the solution
we might
remember processes
the lecture which turned out to
which became the turning point
in the movie
that lecture started
normally enough but very soon disintegrated into a disjointed series of non sequiturs
and at that point
it became
impossible for the people around you
i wish to continue to deny
that something was terribly wrong
at first
we should try to keep her husband's increasingly bizarre behavior
but very soon she could no longer handle it on her own when she turned
to psychiatrists you're at MIT
she was told that
normally don't improve it because you are you know
your cards fraud
and even if you do improve it only work on one idea only
it's not that they would give you another idea in another primarily with another idea
and then you know in the group of then you would get like ten or
twenty ideas but you're all debating about one idea
it's not bringing q four
and of course then we are not using the capacity of everyone in the team
or we are using it in the wrong way
the results that the
born with some other companies
are enormous
and i think that least in slovenia things are getting
quite similar with those companies that are persistent of training
making their meetings much shorter
are getting much much more ideas because that's
are the most common problems
we spend all our day on meetings and then we don't have time to work
on meetings we have only few ideas so we don't really know
what to work on
so it would be much much used useful
to change
however the best for you
and i will be quiet like three minutes no
i have my
santa claus so i know in three minutes is
and you will try to think about your thinking which is a terrible because i'm
suppose nobody ever
i thought about their thinking is it
you know because this such subconscious thing
like breeding
you know that you are breeding colony when you're out of
otherwise you
but maybe you know
now reading to relax reading
four swimming reading format on
the band collie breed
you will get the results in the same which you're thinking
how you would think
that's how the results would be the end so try
to describe
you're thinking skills so far
its heart you never did it and you don't even know
which is what kind of language to use
use any kind of language
in most common words there are
and then try to find out what do you think it's positive about the way
of thinking about it is that is negative about it
how are satisfied with it
and then
maybe the last question
where on what occasion
what what time
do you think you do your best thinking
can you do this
every training needs to start
you know it's the
analysis of what we are having now
so what have we found out
what we found out
about yourself
so there is no but so well together
how is it working for you
happy with it
i hope everyone said something about something that they are happy with their thinking
is there someone who didn't write they're happy with thinking that they're unsatisfied
well that's very rarely
because i would say if you manage
to leave
by yourself
with the money
if you produce with your brain and your work you should be happy
with the way of thinking
but this thinking is something that the bomb had another expression he founded out last
year it's caught in the net
but not enough
because that's how it is
what do we do
how we do it that's all excellent
maybe just not enough
and you gave me the idea to say something something else from
the bonus teaching
and this this this is the car
and you will see this is the symbol of something and one of the biggest
thinking skills that we learn that it is in our culture it's about judgement
analysis on one hand
and being critical
and the other is knowledge you know in school is all about knowledge
knowledge information
and maybe also the experience
but the one that says this is
you know
like the
the system
and in another car
but what is giving you know where all this cargo
this is something you know excellent this is excellent
but not enough of this
in the sky
so clearly this is also very pleasing
if you do the experiment on the moon
with the same initial speed it will go much higher
so you also happy to see that these g
uris is downstairs
for that makes sense
at what time
well the object b
point s
now there are two ways that you can do that
you go to this equation number three
and you ask equation number three when i use zero
i will give you two answers
will say i'm zero here at this time
and zero at that time and those are the two times that you want and
this is the one you pick
that's perfectly fine
i think is a faster way to do it
and that's the following
this is a perennial asos completely symmetric about the vertical about p
so to climb up from o to p must take the same amount of time
has to go down from p to s
so i claimed
at the time
we want as
must be twice the time
to each point p
and therefore it's going to be to visit rome
sign of
if find it
by t
we want to look again whether these errors the sign of have the right place
indeed if i increase the speed
i would expect it to take longer
before it reaches as
if i give it a larger speak
it will come out for
and obviously
time will take longer
if i do it at a high angle
it will also take longer
and if i do it on the moon
it also take longer
so this makes sense
these equations
a pleasing in terms of their
the rate is zero and sign
p equations
now comes an important
o point which i'm going to use rogers lecture
i want to know what ROS is
the distance OS
i showed up and it hits the floor again
what is the distance that it travels
well for that
i need equation
number one
it is the zero x times the time
and the zero x
the zero cosine of fun
we get the zero
cosine of five
find the time to get it that's too few zero sign of
so we're going to you
again a sign of
and i got to junior
and i have another
he zero there
and so the answer is
the zero to create
time the sign of the double angle
remember two
the cosine of the sign of phi is the sign of two of
divided by t
and this is o s
and what you need is a lot
this reminds me not to
remove it
i sort of wonder
and you should too
why is it that the highest point in the sky
as zero square and
and why is the farthest point
also what is also have zero square
what are you waiting you can reason that
why should not just be zero by be zero square
well i'd like to argue about the highest points
i give you a good reason
for the
distance OS
don't look at the equations
the simply
i think
four change don't look at the equations
the speed
if i don't know the speed
it's quite reasonable that the time that it takes
forty object to reach the ground
real w
while the time that it flies has doubled
the horizontal velocity has also done
and so did this and that it will travel in horizontal direction
four times that
twice course the time is
has doubled
another factor of two
because the horizontal component
has also double
that's why you see the zero square there
completely pleasing
this tells you immediately that's
the if you want to throw the the ball as far as possible
people who played baseball know that's
you should do it at forty five degrees
because if you throw at forty five degrees
this angle
ninety degrees and that is one
of course
in reality
baseball player knows better they give effect to the ball
the deals and drag
expendable the ball
and then these equations
i'm not valid this is only in case we deal with
was vacuum
and i would like to
some of the results that we have here
we have worked out here
i'm going to shoot
metal ball
i'm going to shoot at various angles
thirty degrees sixty degrees forty five degrees
and i'm going to make a prediction
if i showed up from there
we're looking to table
the measurements
it's meaningless
the uncertainties
but as the first thing we have to do this
the first thing i want to know is what is the velocity
of this
but when it comes out of the spring
and does it very well if i do with three five six times in a
it's not
twenty thousand dollars
so it is likely to very
anyway i'm going to do that is as follows
if i should an object
vertically up
that is the maximum
value that it can go
one of five
he calls ninety degrees
then the sign of phi is one
and the height is the zeros create divided by two
in other words
if i measure
the height if i should up vertically
and you can measure that
for me we'll see how i'm asking you to do that
then we can calculate
the zero square
and pi j here our
i guess it should be k
so this table
should be the mixing proportions is the probability
at any particular data point will belong to
mixture components k
and should component is given by gaussians with i mean me OK
and the covariance of sigma k
again we might want to ask questions about the weather
we want to be restricted to this promontory class of densities so do we really
believe that the true density estimation of key components again unlikely
not to be the case
and even if we do believe this OK companies how many major components
do you want to use right it's kind of hard to pick k using model
selection of
something needs
yet another example
so here we are we want to do latent variable modelling so
say we have an vectors of
and that observations x one to x and
and we want to model it as a linear combination of k latent sources of
of features or something so x i
it's going to be some from
FK from one two became
of basis functions lambda k
times y i k so why he is going to be only source
plus some nice to epsilon i so examples of this of latent variable models include
things like principal components analysis factor analysis in independent components analysis
so this are pretty standard techniques in machine learning and statistics
again we might want to ask
how many sources there really in our data right do we really believe that the
case also in order to
and how do we find k even if we do believe that is the key
and another question might be what prior distribution should be used for this also
finally yet another example of
parametric model that you now
i know all about the the flies lectures is that topic modeling with latent dirichlet
allocation right so here we have the task is that we want to infer topics
from a document corpus
topics now being can set of words that tend to co occur together in our
in different documents
the model basically goes as follows
so we have out the place here
they that do not
document and pi j is going to be a distribution over topics for the
document j
and then for every word in the document what we'll do is we first pick
a topic
by drawing from a multinomial given by
pi pi g
and then draw word given the topic indicated that j
from a distribution given from distributions q parameterized by theta k so i think probably
the notation i use is to be different than the flies lecture but we can
easily translate into them and again will try to be bayesian so we will place
priors on
and of course pi itself has the dirichlet prior and will place the dirichlet prior
on theta
again we might us how many topics can we find from the corpus
we even believe that
only has k topics maybe has more than k or maybe has
infinitely many topics like possibly
right so this'll parameter models
so now we're going to have perfect actually is any questions on the models of
it's pretty simple stuff like this so i will will in fact see that for
each of the four examples that give will try to
derive a nonparametric models for each of them
you're you're already know the answer for one of them right so for the regression
case is a constant process
the bayesian nonparametrics
that's kind of a few
philosophical that
o points about bayesian approach is why we want to do bayes nonparametrics firstly
we we tend to believe that models are almost never correct for our real data
and what happens if
what happens if ten is not correct how do we deal with model misfit we
can try to do things like the following so
firstly we can try to quantify how far away is our
model from the true model some some measure of optimality of fitted model
secondly we we might want to do things like model selection are reaching so we
i have a sequence of models of increasing complexity and we define the model of
the right complexity to describe our data
or in the case of averaging we average over this sequence of models
the bayesian average thirdly we might want to do not restrict ourself to a small
set of models right so we too small model class we might want to increase
the flexibility of a model class
and bayesian nonparametric models are basically parametric models whose flexibility has been increased a
so that they are in a sense able to capture almost any
the that's said we might encounter
and they also good solutions from the perspective of model selection or averaging infected if
that is that there is a different way of approaching this problem of finding a
complexity for
four model
in fact it just stays
in degree everything out and not worry about overfitting
so you don't have to do model selection or averaging something they make life much
so let's think that go into
a bit of detail about why we
might not want to do model selection averaging a list from the bees in perspective
so let's imagine that we have beta x
so x one to xn
we have a sequence of models and k
each parametrized by theta k
k because one two entry and so on
to do
model selection are reaching we might we'll
we want to compute the marginal probability of the data so p of x given
mk is simply the integral
over theta k
of the probability of data under our model and also parameters and there should be
PDS of p of data
given mk sorry for
paper was again so is the the likelihood multiplied by the prior over theta we
integrate over theta
so that's the marginal probability of the data integrating out of parameters and then we
might want to do model selection in which case we want to find the model
and k which maximizes
the probability of the data
given our model
so if we want to be more bayesian we
one two
computes the posterior over
model index k
and all parameters theta k
by this
multiplying the prior over theta k
by the likelihood and normalising
don't x
has been equals zero
well the normal to the hyperplane is w hat
just that different from plains OK
i'm saying
the margin the singer black
is given by the projection of this vector
o two the onto the w had
that's the normal to the hyperplane
if i project
this vector onto the green
i get the margin OK
just plane geometry
projections nothing mysterious
so that's what i do now
i will project w one w two
on the normal to answer normal OK which is just given by
w one one w that's the normal to the hyperplane
and i observed for the projection just from plane geometry
will be x one minus x two
times this w
so started with w one w
just coming back to my previous equation
i had already established this quite separately
so the projection of this
onto w over w will be equal to two
over a model w
just divide both sides by w
and i'm really looking at the projection of this vector
also known as a hyperplane
and hence
that the margin is equal to two
on one w
so you've been
following what i've been nattering on about
and actually argued
the margin
is given
well values
is this
is two
o more w
actually if i define the margin i should really say the margins between here and
here is one more w OK
i'm saying
in the day
the distance myself here
the distance
the separating hyperplane
and the support vectors is actually given by one on one w
if i want to maximize the margin
then i must maximize
the subject here
make as big as possible
now maximizing one w
it's the same thing as minimizing more w
maximize this is equivalent to minimizing just this
we've got
the following
maximisation the model of the margin
it is equivalent to minimisation of w
well minimizing more w can be same sort of thing as minimizing
sort of forgot square somewhere
but you can therefore imagine if
trying to maximize mum mum margin is equivalent to minimizing f of this thing
but subject to constraints and the constraints i already had
and i had
if i'm
this object here
was a plus one
when y equals plus one
this was the first one if the support vector
and if it wasn't support vector and i'm not so the same side of the
hyperplane is greater than plus one OK
so this is a pos one
this same will be greater than we could pass one
if i'm on the other side of the hyperplane from the support vectors money minus
and if it's and non support vector it'll be great minus one
for the case of y equals minus one on that side of the hyperplane
the end of the day
that dictation of my my canonical hyperplanes
can be written down as this constraint equation here
so in the day and many losses how i got either these two
we can define canonical hyperplanes that getting this
define maximize the margin which gave me this
i now have a constrained optimization problem
because i'm trying to minimize some some something subject to constraints became that major league
sensible flag my brain
constrained optimization
indeed most people familiar with optimisation if not doesn't really matter but just this so
i now approach it from the viewpoint of optimisation
i said that was called the objective function and the objective function has this subject
which are trying to minimise
and this is my constraint condition
OK which i had just now
and these alphas are growth multipliers which introduced because is constrained optimization
he wanted her to go on all of multiply so this is totally obvious we
have in which case you lost
right so
so these are logos multipliers so this object is my primal objective function
now again
if you find the optimisation you say all a primal formulation of our problem an
equivalent dual formulation of the problem and is going to be the dual formulation on
the go for
and that if you know anything about that doesn't matter because show you just some
derivatives to find a solution which will take you there
this is my object arrived at primal objective function
i'm going to just going to do to up operations
which is
i wish to find an optimum actually minimum of this l here
the optimum what are the suspect is dl by DB equals zero
and the other variable i have which is the l by the w
to be zero
b conditions on my gradient and inspect the optimum
let's have a look at those
so so the optimum i want dl by typical zero let's any b here
that gives me
this constraint here
secondly i do deal by the w
by w can quickly check
that gives me w is equal to the same here
my next thing is to substitute back this w into my previous equation
if you to be familiar optimisation this is all striking obvious because it's working at
a move dual
not well just
so i put back the w i just arrived in here
here and here
and that would actually give me
the following
it gives me the other day this expression here
which is the jaws special
the deviations being implies there exists choice
here for which the deviations
and in particular for a given l
you know we're not able to construct a bad distribution wanted her to write we're
just setting the existence of it through this policy
OK so why is the expectation of this deviation large
the intuition really should be clear i'm not going to go through
any detail but we've chosen the distribution of the axes to be
concentrate on the shattered set
so the functions in class contains
OK can can compute all possible one valued functions on that shattered set around distribution
like so somehow for most points in the set
you know depending on the particular distribution we set things up so that for most
points in the set we need to come up with a function that can guess
where the conditional probability of y
being one is greater than half or less than half
and if we don't guess get that right for most points in the set then
will file will be epsilon far from the optimal thing
you know it turns out in estimating these probabilities you can't do any better than
you know we have sufficient statistic is just to count up the the number of
the proportion of points that you saw
it took a particular value
and had signed one
and then compare that to half
and now we're very familiar regime we're just looking at
tales of the bernoulli distribution we can't have the error in this estimate increasing faster
than one of group
so i epsilon has to be of that order
right and the d arises because we have no way
the VC dimension arises because we're having to simultaneously estimate these things over
essentially all off the shelf
OK so so that's
why the minimax right
right so just to summarise that's why the minimum that that's why we get this
OK the minimax
estimation error is at least as big as or VC dimension n
and the
the minimisation of the sample based error
over over the class and
the minimisation of the empirical risk exhibits this upper bound of square expansion mentioned in
these two just a constant factor park
right we can see that but this one of the square of and is the
right right in this case
the VC dimension is the crucial quantity
you know if it's if it's infinite then you know we can reduce the estimation
error to zero
if it's fine we can we know things go down like one of the square
and then the optimal thing to do
it's just this very simple minded minimize the
the empirical risk
OK so in this in this on estimation in this minimax estimation setting
how when where
you know this this captures the
the VC dimension is the right notion of complexity the class
but it is a little strange right it's setting it's easy to criticize because you're
looking at the worst case of a probability distribution and if you think about
the proof of this inequality
right where
constructing for every
sample size n
when constructing a probability distribution
that exhibits this lower bound
right so
and we're constructing it in a rather strange wiley's have conditional probability that's
i didn't write it there right here that's really close to half rights within epsilon
one of the two half so it's really hard you know we're looking down at
this epsilon level
we doing uniformly badly across all the wise to the optimal thing
is very close to has has risk is very close to two half which is
is terrible right so
you know where exhibiting the minimax optimal right that that this right we get is
the is the minimax optimal using distribution for which
you know we probably we've we've got a very hard problem to solve here
OK so
you know it's not
it's not such a natural natural distribution
the that exhibits the slovak
OK we can look also
the restricted case
here we can worry about the
the case where there is some
function in eq class that always
does well
this is because we can define a particle is zero risk minimax estimation error
right the subscript zero here means that there is some function in class
capital if for which y equals f of x almost surely right so you know
this is a very strong assumptions about the probability distribution some function gets things get
things right the bayes risk we the optimal
risk is zero and is the function class that
make the right prediction all the time we have a deterministic mapping from x to
so this is a
this is kind of the classical
the PAC setting
you know for people who are for the history way where where you know you
know that there is some function to get everything right and you want to be
approximately correct so within epsilon of
of the right thing with high probability
so just just to go over so what we're looking for here in the in
zero risk minimax cases for the best
right what's the how how close to zero can we get a risk
we're like
we're going have no laws at all
it is russian to women give birth in russian musicologist and any two experiments on
the babies
and it's terrific
and this is like one of them where they compare babies looking at
the first is this
baby's life
one of the face
these are newborns
there some preferences with humans and other primates the favor faces
babies are also social animals too
so the natural mimics
andrew melts off for instance has found that if you go to a newborn baby
and if you get if you find a newborn baby this is the first thing
first thing you should do
stick your face right up the newborn baby boy boys
and stick your tongue
and no self lines
the baby is more often than not
stick to tons of back
suggesting some sort of social connection from one person to another and then later on
babies are mimics babies
more often than not will copy the face maximum
the nature of these responses
preferring faces this sort of mimicry is a matter of debate there's a lot of
research going on asking how smarter babies can we see you some of the same
that we've looked at the physical world look at the social world and illustrate one
of the studies i tell you what is the idea
without recall mire and karen when
and so we tested was nine-month-old and twelve models
we show the movies sort of sitting down to singer movie
where one character is going to help biology of gold and another characters and hindered
and then we going to see whether they expect the ball to approach
the one that helped first the one
that standard
this is what the baby was this is literally the same movie baby would see
in the experiment the thing is
for these sorts of experiments there's a lot to control so something that's the square
in one movie will be a triangle another movie something that's in the top and
one movie will be on the bottom and another movie so this is an example
movie but this is what babies with c
and if it is over and over again and the question is
with a suspect babies with babies expected one to approach to want to help the
or approach one
that hindered
and what we find is statistically babies look longer when shown in movie word approach
is the one that hindered versus helped
and we just we take this preliminary evidence that
they have a social interpretation they see this movie as you see this movie in
terms of helping and hindering and somebody going to somebody that help was hindered it
you could then ask this makes a prediction
the baby should themselves prefer the creature who is to help reverse to hinder
and to explore this a graduate students department kylie hamlet
i started a series of studies where they wish they show babies three-dimensional scenes
and then give them the characters and see which one they reach fort so here's
video so you can see how this experiment is that
the next trial from different study different being used and the baby is given a
what one thing to note methodologically is the person giving a choice is blind to
the set and blind here is the technical term meaning she had no idea what
the baby source
and the point about this is to avoid either intentional or unintentional sort of trying
to get the answer you want he couldn't do that because she didn't know what
the right answer is
so here's what the baby would say
this suggests that some social understanding
maybe there from the very start
this evidence is tentative
very controversial
now i want to raise a huge developmental puzzles
phenomenon together with several people including versus assembles others did a series of training studies
in which they showed that this is likely to be learned because they were able
to teach it to kids in the lab so here's the kind of training city
they took seventeen month-old kids about a year and a half who very very clearly
don't have this shape bias
and they brought them into the lab
for a period in the six different different ways and replicated the number of times
but typically six to eight weeks one session weaker about twenty minutes and the kids
would play with these four pairs of objects
and and just just an informal interactions so the adult would take the kid and
it's a introduce this parents say hey these are these are two wins here's your
we here's my way let's let's play with or without that school you can start
this on top of that and then after a little while ago to these and
say OK now here's here's the log here's here's my login let's play with those
for so they just introduced in a casual way
the fact that this word can refer to both of these things and the key
part of the stimuli are that course they matching shape but different other features are
different sized are different color and texture and so on
and after about eight weeks of training in this way the kids which we're now
nineteen month-old had acquired the shape bias which means you could bring in these other
objects which are not the ones state
they don't
trained on and
and they would show this preferential generalization from just a single example based on shape
so this is this is this is sometimes called second order generalisation because they were
also able to solve first-order generalization problems namely given a new one of these kind
of rectangular arches they could call that wins they could generalize from these two examples
of the label with but they also acquired this this instance a kind of constraint
on the hypothesis space which they can generalize to new concepts of the same sort
now the most striking feature of the data for this experiment is a different set
of data with the same kids where they looked at the effect on the children's
real world vocabulary so none of this you know we observe stuff with funny objects
but this is a real words in english it's it's interesting to look because the
age at which they're they're getting at is just a joke which kids vocabulary really
starts to take off the kids coming in seventeen months no this is the total
vocabulary was on average about twenty five words this is in the words i think
these are words that their parents judge they understand which is the standard and repeatable
reliable way to get measure rough measure of kids vocabulary and of those twenty five
words about half of them in little more than half were labels for object names
now then after two months what happened was the effectiveness of this training well for
kids who were who were in the group that describe how they learned about three
times more
object words and they came and so they came in knowing about fifteen and by
the end
i guess is actually more than three times in other over about fifty five words
so that's a very huge
growth now kids at his age are starting to learn a lot of words so
it's important there's a control condition which is somebody's dashed lines here and those are
kids who had exactly the same experience with the same objects but they didn't have
this this preferential this didn't have the
the objects labelled they didn't they're just like here's another it was play with our
things they did they didn't specifically introduce novel names that correlated with the shape based
categories and those kids will
i learned many fewer words i mean the difference between the control group and the
training group is certainly statistically significant as you can see by the error bars but
it's a huge effect separate from statistical significance in these kids learned about three times
more words than the control group over that period and it's an effect that was
specific to learning object names right so you can if you look at the the
the mean number of words in general the kids were exactly the same so it's
not like these kids are smarter somehow learn something generally about language they learn something
specific about how object labels work
so this is this is very striking minutes if you if you think it's interesting
to say well how does the person learn a concept from just a few examples
here we've got the same thing at a higher level of abstraction right we're learning
how to learn concepts of a certain sort from just a few examples of those
concepts right just just four examples of shape based categories each of which only saw
two examples for you're solving the first order and second order generalisation problem how does
that work
well the intuition that smith method all had here is that get something like a
kind of learned attentional bias kids are learning to pay attention to shape for this
kind of task and it you can think of this sort of saying that she
is is a diagnostic feature one along which the relevant categories cluster
and we can capture this in a very simple kind of hierarchical bayesian model this
is again basically a textbook model the will extended in some directions although you've probably
seen things like this before of show some some very simple illustrations with bags of
there's hidden states
and the state evolves as this
matrix values of the current state
it has in the past
this prior over the initial prior distribution over the first
in the emission model is given by these the south pole
from another table which gives me observations
four downstream is continuous observations not all hidden markov models and state
my the phonemes in speech recognizer
and then the samples are the
graph the vector of coefficients the capital corporation from the gaussians centered on four
and similarly for the centre party after linear dynamical system common filter and here we
have x european continuous vector
instead of a discrete state vector
and now this thing also falls down here
given my past
i sample might pass that's one of the gaussians model
something like this
which is linear function so this is good for
things like tracking or
flying planes and
things like that
it's not good for discrete types of
hence the problem
and given my sample also in image
so there are two classes of things that in
the framework to look pretty much the same as turns out the junction tree steps
the junction tree structure with the months same as well
so what we done one triangulated moralizing the message passing pretty much the same for
the other
we just need to do some easy integration summation
is the state transition model
i don't have to stick to gas
two other exponential families
but things do sometimes get nasty few young girls in model
if it is to make sure that things might blow up with the church so
complexity micro
if you're doing a mixture of gaussians each time propaganda message
that makes of gases may go from ten thousand to one hundred thousand with each
step propagation
so that's an open problem right now is how to mitigate that
exponential growth has been gently to message passing when you nongaussian distribution
you could move away from the gaseous emission model and there's things like the kernelized
common filter which is a nonlinear calcium
it's another space and then you have few
so we started doing things like that as well
now also helps avoid
putting nonlinearity here which
the junction tree
so these are all active areas especially in
modifying these models so adding these mixtures are nonlinearities extended kalman filters and so on
people in the control literature doing some of these people in the
and the markov random fields of insurance also there's there's in physics as well variations
of these nongaussian mall
hard to keep track and everybody
we're can also going there and modify
the graphical models so one thing we want to do is to look at two
person interaction
and so there's two people tracking
what we learn about two people person why the the same person as so use
personalized was annexed they're interacting in we can
track person and synthesize them
caricaturing them to this person and they're just going through the virtual interaction or internet
we like to watch the people that can model
the the behaviour of y given access phenomenon enough about this distribution
then i can make this person
basically distribution
and predict what's the most likely why say a
for this
human starts and this one
what was the most likely wife's response with x
more generally simple and stimulus response behaviours so what
these two people applied markov models
well we can just take one more three person
and then model this person with an HMM on this person HMS
but there's no come someone try to predict this person's behavior from this one well
this person is
so it's a game one of these things are probably need to
so look at a few times before you will
he completely happy
OK so
so we're going to take this step
moving from
the probability were interested in to this
probability over the double sample
and the point i was making is that why we do that is because now
because we are only interested in what a stars on x and y there is
true error in this
expression on the right hand side
we are now able
two just considered
a finite set of possible behaviors of h
of this class
and so we're down to a finite
set of events that we need to bound
the question is how large can be
this is where we we start getting a little bit combinatorial because we're going to
start looking
at binary valued functions
we're going to define
what what's is known as the growth function
as the b h m as the maximum cardinality of the set of functions h
when restricted to end points
so remember we can in our case
respect to two points
the sample and the ghost sample
and we're interested in how many different behaviours can function class exhibit
so we might consider as a linear functions are uncountably many but we've restricted them
to look at what they do on just two hundred points or two thousand points
whatever it is how many different functions can they actually exhibit on that two thousand
points and we'd like to show is that that is
it's quite small clearly
it can't be given to the to the end because there are only two to
be impossible functions binary functions on n points
so it's clearly finite
no question that
so we have a lot to the base two of BH fans less recalled and
but for the statistics to work we want the number of functions to be much
more than this
we need to
look at how that behavior
here's an example
so this is linear functions in a twenty dimensional space so got three dimensional input
and you're looking at linear functions
you're asking
on you know certain
training set sizes
how many functions can this
class of linear functions
all what fraction of the the all of the functions can
the class realise so i'm actually posting here the ratio
of the number of functions that can realize divided by
the total possible number functions to to the end
so clearly when you have a small number of inputs
typically you can
get every possible classification of those inputs
you can do whatever you want to be like with those inputs in terms of
but at some point
the fraction starts to two
taylor off
and really relatively rapidly
it it tends towards zero fraction of
the number of functions
when the number of functions to be an is growing exponentially
so the
the property here is that that exponential growth thanks actively kills off
the growth in the h of function
and this is the kind of property that will give us
remember this will show the BH and
is actually much much smaller than the total number that could be
and that's
each of them is effectively the number of
the size of the union bound the going to have to make w union bounding
over all possible behaviors
and that's going to be a chance
and so now it to you know the next
key concepts
the vapnik chervonenkis dimension so we see you know this is not the
venture capital etc etc vapnik chervonenkis dimension
basically it is the point at which that
graph here
cuts away from one is the point at which
the ph of then ceases to be equal to two to the end
now in the case of linear functions is actually twenty one
there are two twenty one
dimensions twenty one so that at that point i mean all you can't see it
this curve actually separates from the
p o one line that point
that is the
VC dimension that form of the
a class of linear functions in that case so it's the maximum and
possibly the most important day in your life to
certainly in our kids lifetime up to now because i eight nine ninety five small
startup company in mountain view california
it went public
and the world has never been the same since
give us two two basic flatness change the world
the first was netscape invention
this simple point-and-click device
called a browser
and what the browser did
it was actually
give us the tool
that brought the internet to life
it was really the netscape browser that brought the internet to life because it allowed
us to illustrate on computer screens everything locked away in internet files
and thanks to tim berners-lee
soon to be
it's actually the netscape browser that made the internet this incredible tool collectivity the grammar
grampa grandson and granddaughter not just MIT computer scientist could all
use together
so it's really the netscape browser that brought the internet to life
but that wasn't the only reason netscape was a huge flat it's because netscape IPO
let's keep going public in the morning of a nineteen ninety five and nine AM
is what actually started the dot com boom
and that triggered the dotcom bubble and that triggered the crazy absurd ridiculous utterly
how rages over investment of one
trillion dollars that's trillion with a t
in two fiber optic cable
in five years
and what that crazy ridiculous absurd massive over investment into fibre-optic cable in five years
was accidentally wire the world
with nobody having planned
so all those individuals offering their own content in digital form
could suddenly send their bits and bytes
anywhere in the world
basically for free
it was that fibre-optic explosion that accidentally but nobody having planned at made beijing bangalore
and boston
all next-door neighbours
how did it happen well on the morning of a nineteen ninety five escape went
priced at twenty eight dollars
their investment bankers morgan stanley one of the stock to be price to thirty two
bit jim barksdale netscape CEO at the time did not know if this fails
i wanted to be remembered as the twenty dollars stock
netscape open that morning it seventy one dollars close the first day fifty six
and we all looked at that and we said well there is gold over them
and we went out and we what we every dotcom boom moved we we want
every dot com moved called global crossing in nextel and GPS unit phase where you
can form and i was in your four one KZ was born in nineteen was
last night and when we did
we accidentally
funded the massive over wiring of the world
with fibre optic cable so every individual
authoring content on their PC
because suddenly send the digital content anywhere for free
thirty flat there was a quiet revolution was a revolution in transmission protocols happened across
the nineteen nineties it was the alphabet soup of TCP IP in HTML and HTTP
and XML and soap and hx you don't need to know even though most people
here do what all the alphabet soup meant
it just meant one thing for the flat of the world critical
this phenomenon
it meant everyone's computer in software became into up
we forget today
what a revolution
that was
we forget today what it was like with MIT's administration first got compute
and if
bookkeeping department government of the abacus many machine and the
computer and admissions got computers are very exciting day around here at MIT when i
have there's just one problem bookkeeping got SEP and administration got windows
they didn't connect
collect any more than you were on your compuserve could connect with your wife on
well what happened thanks to all those transmission protocols is that we make everyone's computer
and software inter operable it was acquired revolution i called the workflow revolution because it
truly allowed work to flow
and when that happens when you could suddenly sit at your computer terminal or someone
in india and not have to think for a moment
what is the computer and software that opencourseware is running out and what computers software
do i have
what i meant was we could all suddenly become
so put it all together first like author my own content in digital form
and i could send it anywhere in the world for free
and thanks to the workflow revolution
suddenly everyone could collaborate with everyone else on their digital
what we created
right around the year two thousand right around the time of the millennium
was this crude flat world platform a global platform for multiple forms of collaboration
suddenly more people could collaborate with more other people are more different kinds of things
and more different kinds of ways from more different places for less
than ever before
is built on this
now this flat platform then give rise to a whole new set of collaborations outsourcing
offshoring to me the most interesting one which seems critical to open course ware i
call uploading a term coined by kevin kelly wired not uploading in the conventional sense
you see when the world was round
you download as an individual
but when the world is flat
individuals can now
upload and globalize their own content
uploading comes in many forms open source software
are the most was the most early variant and probably still the most popular
open course software you just uploaded you're university online
it is in the old days if you want opinion on foreign affairs and redefine
the dead like me not anymore now i go to iraqi bloggers
see what they're uploading as individuals from baghdad when i want to know what's going
on there
youtube uploading video and of course the mother of all of those wikipedia
the people
are now uploading their own encyclopedia
it's not perfect
or all you have to do is the subject of wikipedia to know how imperfect
it's OK and anyone who thinks the network will get it all straightened out doesn't
have their biography on wikipedia but nevermind we will go there
but the fact is
we're going for world where when i grew minneapolis in the nineteen fifties i remember
when the encyclopedia britannica salesman came with all those but was inside and put them
down in the living room and then we got the coolest thing
we got in card
and you could
download an encyclopedia
i think carter to two thousand seven had about thirty eight thousand entries
wikipedia today
has about one point three million eight hundred forty eight hundred forty six
exactly how they do it
and there are sort of you know more emotional types knowledge and so
for those of you that that's lost question you will have looked at this whole
argument you know what's the difference between belief and knowledge so for us we not
going to
making a distinction between belief and knowledge for us we can think of the you
know the the sentences of the knowledge that we write down here is really just
representing the beliefs of some
system more recent that's in environment and then when use representation to reason about the
environment act effectively
but as i say the main idea is that we're going to take the world
in the knowledge that we write down is going to say that we view the
world to be one way rather than some of these are the things that we
consider to be true the world regardless of whether they
there are in fact rule
OK we can use symbols to do that we see symbols in everyday life symbols
for us have some intuitive meaning first a restaurant bathroom and so on
o much astronomy
in sort of a random letters
so in knowledge representation is really about the symbolic encoding knowledge explicitly writing down
things that you know is a two things you take to be true of your
environment right next and some sort of support
reasoning part is that so once we've gone to all the effort of writing down
all this knowledge in as symbolic form
we want to do something with so the reasoning really is manipulating the symbols that
we have
training at new symbols and those new symbols represent knowledge not that we have explicitly
written so implicit knowledge
o was simplicity and what with explicitly written down
OK so we might say well why is the knowledge based method good
why do they always said if you look in particular at
a lot of the research that is carried out in in computer science is a
lot of people sort of reject this idea that you should
explicitly represent knowledge this really think it's a waste of time
and that really bugs you down
you know if we look at systems that every that
you have to reason about recently complex behavior and so on
a lot of times we describe them in terms of beliefs goals
could be some emotional images like these and so on and intentions so for instance
if we've got a chess playing program in particular
movies made
we might try to rationalize by saying well the program believe the queen was in
danger but still wanted to control the centre of the transport and that's one way
of explaining what trying to rationalize
sometimes we might actually use way just describing it so we might say well the
program has this you uses minimax procedure which is often used in game theoretic
the systems and return values seven and it was this position that was the best
said this idea is called the intentional stance it in another way to describe the
behavior of the system by trying to describe its intentions what is intended do
so the question we we might pose cells will is
OK i really just a way of being able to
i explain the behaviour of the system rather than a way of actually
implementing such a system
OK now this is knowledge representation and hypothesis and i'll just wait it out and
we're trying to understand because every time i read i can never understand what's going
on but it's really when you trying to break apart components and it's really straightforward
so brian smith suggested this thing around
early eighties and he said that the
you know if
applying this knowledge representation idea the idea that we're going to symbolically represent
the things that we believe to be true the environment and then manipulate those symbols
in order to
in for new knowledge
well a hypothesis that underlies that particular way of going about doing
and it's that any mechanically embodied intelligent process will be comprised of structural ingredients i
we use external observers actually take to represent a propositional kind of knowledge to several
but by this point on maury laws like i don't know what he's talking about
and be independent of such external semantic attribution play for causal an essential role in
and in the alpine space
i didn't write down nature this year did i here is the age of s
it's the same sort of idea made up of the same elements bx all the
best in the world one of the best and so on but are arranged differently
this time in six by two
matrix and you can easily check for yourselves these things are all of nodes anyway
that when you multiply
this measurement matrix by this parameter vector you do get out the fine transformation which
we first thought of which is
which is here
so we've got this nice linear parameterizations
of course they don't do everything that we want supposing i want to take a
on structure
they find this fine results about the history of freedom is is good for playing
structures were now
supposing i draw an outline around the non plane structure
and i moved non plane structure well
the leaves individual leaves and this plant pot close to play so what what i
might get is that if i can insist on the inside find space that one
of these will be tracked by the contour outline but the other one will be
thrown off because the space simply isn't big enough to
the capable of tracking these non plane
we could still assume that we have this i find projection approximation of the words
that was seeing the world through a telephoto lens but clearly the six degree of
freedom model isn't good enough it's a bit annoying because we know what's happening as
in space is still only six degrees of freedom i mean there are no more
degrees of freedom to be had out in three dimensional space
so i mean how many degrees of freedom you think one might need to represent
this space
perhaps can't even be done but it could be done what degrees of freedom would
you need
that in mind i mean there are two planes in this example but i could
have drawn an example with three planes of four planes in it
and so you know the question is is the size of the space going to
get worse as i add an independent planes what you think yes or no
not obvious shaken up
the qualitative
perturbation that
what is the colour becoming who thinks yes
things that get bigger every time i add another
another independent plane
and i think that the two things it won't get bigger
one person thinks that
by majority the won't get because habit
i suspect may be
he's right
so it turns out the answer is only eight degrees of freedom so that really
is quite a piece of luck that you can take a on plane
object and move around in space with six degrees of freedom you don't get a
linear six degree of freedom parameterisation in the image plane but you do get a
which is not that so if prepared to give away
two degrees of freedom in the interests of any arity you know we're losing a
the constraint the linearity is valuable and when it comes to come filtering as i
said before
you know really makes life a lot easier
so there is in a dimensional space which is being exercised here you see i
started with one dimensional model
and just flex a dimensional model and it was able to fit all of the
configurations of this non planar object
and finally
there is the business of non rigid deformation but i am
we also
wrote the book my friend michael isard whose hand this is
you may not recognise it but it is
we wrote a book together which is a reference to it at the beginning of
this set of lecture notes and
all of these constructions for making spaces to fit jim very symmetric assumptions are given
in more detail that in particular the last bit which are not going to go
into detail here what if you're allowed to flex your hands as well
i mean you can imagine doing something like principal components analysis in this parameters in
this blind parameter space
if you did that on sort of a training set of hand positions that would
be kind of wasteful because you you're wasting data data relearning these two dimensional and
three dimensional affine spaces so that a little bit tasteless if you when you know
perfectly well that this object is allowed to to move in three dimensions and you
already know the answer to that the problem so a nice thing to do is
to is to do
what you might call residual per principal components analysis we take the data factor of
that compound the data which is explained by this analytical model you already have and
then apply principal components analysis two
the residue of the data as it were three each of those residue vectors which
now contains variation only that is not only the variation is not explained by fun
so that's a good thing to do so that's a general methodology for building a
reasonable models that can do
some rigid transformation and also some
OK so now we've got a family of curves and the problem is how to
curves to data
supposing you have an approximate position
for the cover starting position this one is extremely good starting position and now suppose
new search
in various directions out from the starting position so suppose you
so it's still proportional to p of q
right so because there are numerous ways of doing monte carlo including markov chain monte
carlo which was which you've heard about which will such a little bit about
tomorrow and particle filtering context simulated annealing is an example of monte-carlo importance sampling which
is the fundamental building block behind these particle filters a quasi monte carlo and so
but sequential monte carlo methods here
and just a trick that gets used throughout monte carlo inference which will play a
part in my particle filter derivation in a minute
monte carlo cells difficult integrals what i wanted to build itself nicely is the marginalisation
in go up automatically because
if i have
the two quantities save the state and the nuisance parameter in this case drawn from
the joint posterior distribution
for those unknowns
given the data y
then it immediately follows that by simply extract the samples x from that joint draw
draws from the marginal effects
similarly the features are draws from the marginal
the theta
informally you can see that drops out just from the factorisation of the joint in
terms of the marginals tied the conditional so that's the model for that's the marginal
the theta so bear that in mind is because we use that in the basic
particle filter derivation at the moment
but now
and we define the state space models and the filtering and smoothing objective basic particle
field OK so state space models are quite general way of representing time series models
they include things like hidden markov models on a discrete state space is most of
the standard time series models things like autoregressive moving average models we don't apply to
some of the integrated models that appear in finance because you can represent those the
finite dimensional state vector but also all of the special models that we can try
for applications in tracking computer vision finance communications and so on
we need more of the text oh yes yes yes so i'm going to do
all of this derivation in terms of of markovian state space model in fact is
that's not necessary but simplifies than the notation so for example in the right blackwellized
particle filter that we hear more about tomorrow you're effectively dealing with non markovian setup
and it does work the notation more
the notation are used is
column vectors will be standard typefaces lowercase so for example the state at time t
will be x of t
and the matrices will be
just standard typeface capital letters
just to avoid the need of heavy heavy typeface
and we consider a time series with states xt t on some time at the
north pole got never noticed that before no one to take
the states evolve in time according to a probability model so this is a stochastic
state space model
and we assume as i say an markovian structure so that if i look at
the distribution of the new state at time t plus one
given all the previous states up to that time it only depend on the previous
state x x fifty and i'll always know that here is that density is the
probability density function of the that as f of x t plus one given x
that the dynamical model
all the state space model underlying the state evolution
we assume partial observations again a stochastic observation of the state
there some observations sense function or likelihood function for a set of observations y t
which are assumed to be independent
conditional upon states
so again that's the kind of markovian assumptions about the observations so new observation
conditional upon any of the all the whole state sequence out
the time t plus one and any of the previous observations but only depend
on the current observations so that's markovian assumption about the observations always label the observation
as as case g
so i got the dynamical model
the observation density
these what it will be assumed
i will be specified so we're not learning the dynamical model or the observation model
in this it in this set-up although of course they can be parameterized by extra
define all the melting point of the two end members say copper nickel
and i want to know what's the melting point about fifty fifty
copper nickel alloys adjust the halfway
temperature between the two orders the temperature goes through local
maximum order to go through a local minimum or is attempt to go nuts i
mean the question is how does temperature of some critical feature very with composition
so we need to look at three-dimensional
stability maps and this pain that because the three d and its
it's messy but
this is the real line one
and three o nine one is three nine one is concerned about solid state chemistry
so in three o nine one we care more about
liquid solid equilibrium
instead of liquid vapor equilibrium because we don't process too many
in the vapor stage
we don't use too many materials as vapours this is the
equilibrium this most important so we we know that equilibria
equilibria depend upon
depend upon
pressure and composition
and it turns out that when it comes to the liquid solid equilibrium liquid solid
equilibrium is strongly dependent
there's a strong dependence between the temperature transformation and composition
where as
the relationship between the temperature of the transformation and pressure is weakly
weakly dependent
there's a weak dependence between pressure and
the temperature of the transformation of what we saw that last a these are not
to scale
in other words these lines are nearly vertical for solid liquid you would have to
apply geological pressures to alter
the melting point of water substantially
all right whereas we saw doesn't take anything more than just a rise in elevation
several thousand feet to move the boiling point
so that means that i can throw away
the pressure dependence
throw away the pressure dependence and just focus on the two two-dimensional relationship between the
temperature of the transformation and
the composition
so that's what we're going to do we're going to look at three different types
of of binary systems and in each case we're going to assume that the pressure
is one atmosphere and we know that the dependence of the transformation temperatures that we
write is going to be negligible in terms of the impact pressure might have on
so let's look at the real get three different types of systems and there are
all dependent upon the extent solubility and i've given them the
what's the word
very catchy
very catchy distinctions of type one type two
type three right so let's look at the type one type one type of binary
OK and type one binary system has complete
complete solubility
by this i mean complete solubility the two components complete solubility in solid
and liquid states
so that is to say if i makes a and b
they will mix in all proportions in solids and all mix in all proportions as
and the second thing is we're looking at
change of state
so this diagram applies to a change of state and since we're talking about
solid liquid there's only one way
we need to document
and let's think about
what's the relevant chemistry here i mean i've been telling you that phase diagrams are
stability maps and you can just look at the moment and consult them but there's
always some basic chemistry embedded in these diagrams so for example if it were metal
system and i would tell you that these two metals a and b
mix in all proportions as solids and liquids what would have to be the characteristics
of those two models
they would have to be either very nearly similar or maximally different
they have to be very nearly similar and in fact that's good it's sort of
a take-off on like dissolves like
so complete solid solubility liquid state with respect to metals
when it comes to metals there is a set of rules called the human rothery
the robbery was a british metal are just he enunciated
a set of rules for