control the difference between arcade just normal function and its at and finally the approximation
error so that
OK so I will be fast and firstly show how to the estimation error this
is just an implication of theory from Scotland Steinbach in the article frustrates for SVM
with Gaussian kernel so here we can just grab that are are entries in the
restaurants and nothing more there's no there's no trick
and so that is the only work we had to do was determining the smallest
functional subspace where we know for sure that the estimator of signal lights
so of course we know by definition of sigma hat that it belongs to the
arcade just speech signal but what we can show is that it belongs more precisely
to the blue subsets which is up to this multiplicative constants the unit ball of
of this part of the subset
so true to see that the instances like representer theorem that we used to show
that the solution of this and can be expanded on
this kind of functions where it's only belongs
compact subsets
and it's really interesting and so is important for us to have a compact index
here since it enables them to nicely controlled the covering numbers
of the
of this set so
here we
took a result directly from going straight up so we bound to the number of
this you need both with respect to the entire recall as not still t is
the training sample and in this case is that we're interested in and so we
get a bound on the covering number will you be able have time interval
so more anyway that's not where I want to put the focus so
it turns out that
still directly using the removed from school in China but we have the following by
on the excessive summarized OK
so I just know that this bound is parameterized by
2 values that key that you can play with we can take its between 0
and 1 and also
all I forgot the reserve number of delta that we consider as we want you
just have to be a positive quantity of course playing with B and that that
affects the constant K 1 so here k 1 is a constant
well it does not depend on the aren't any there and signal that depends on
all other quantities
so that's the way we the estimation error so that's really
there is no surprise you just use the theory is so we've got to more
terms to belong to a solicitor regularization so to control of this term it's very
convenient to work with the following characterization of the Gaussians populations so that's what understand
say here
we can say that the Gaussian architects in the set of continuous functions vanishing at
that are integrable on on the
and which have a fully transform that satisfies this integrability constraint OK so these constraints
means that the Fourier transform vanishes at infinity exponentially fast and this has to be
in general so we don't old the frequencies
and so this is the correct transition of the Gaussian Park H S and the
just norms is precisely
this quantity here we have this multiplicative constants
OK so from this characterization we can show to interesting properties 1st
when sigma until all the this way than the corresponding are older and this way
that means that the when the signal gets smaller and smaller
the associated architectures H sigma gets larger and larger forms of nested collections of additional
spaces at the end we almost reached as to
and the 2nd property that is more quantitative relates the arcade just normally signal to
the market norm in H for 2 different values of the mind so to pass
from 1 to another we have to
to pay this price sigma squared over 2 0 squared this is way to pass
from H signal to edge to it
and so from those properties
we can know gonna see here how how to bomb the regularisation so this is
the regularisation error so this is the difference between the arcade just Norman as to
1 of these functions so can just use the images go back we just use
this inequality we told
and what's interesting
what's interesting to speculate is
if there is more space for this kind of
biological complex structure what's the equivalent idea before
engineered structures for buildings for software
the operating rules of the hospital
know got this notion that we can take inspiration from biology from that we can
apply ideas that we find work there in in the engineering realm so could we
so could we make use of this idea of more could that tell us about
what's possible in architecture for example
OK so taking another step down downs we start off with
colony of organisms then organ inside the organisms the development process that generates the organ
underpinning all of this is the process of evolution that has designed the developmental processes
or steers the developmental processes such that we see the organisms the we
and this is another for me
you know perplexingly wondrous sort of thing that you can say about nature which is
that you can in this single line here you can sort of encapsulate what it
is for system to be evolutionary and yet
the potentiality of
natural selection
the ability of natural selection to generate such a huge variety of well adaptive forms
just does not in order to do justice to was nice
rather politically incorrect
i mean there's hundreds of these cartoons of like evolution
starts here and ends up there
something that i've found interesting
to speculate about in in the book
fifty years ago
if you or a hundred years ago
if you want to talk in psychology it would be full of
words that had been adopted from physics
but the nuclear family fission fusion processes critical mass
chain reaction
and now if you go to the same lecture theatre it will be full of
words that have been borrowed from biology cells
the ecology of this
and i'd really evolutionary biology biology but really evolutionary biology is is now the organising
metaphor war of choice throughout
i would say
it's a bold claim but really we're in a kind of biological era where biological
processes evolution come evolution
are being co-opted taken
and we used it everywhere
they and they bring a certain way of looking at systems
but sometimes that's very useful
but it but with the within within evolution within evolutionary science there are some important
unsolved questions which implicate complexity
evolution is typically characterised as a gradualist process
so mutation in this small changes happen to genomes as people have as offspring are
generated and the offspring which is slightly better than their parents have more offspring and
over time the population changes to reflect the environment the organisms found themselves in but
there's also
within evolution
if you look over evolutionary history major transition so where
we see
major evolutionary innovations so the innovation of sexual reproduction the move from cellular
so multicellular to multicellular creatures you carry carriers language sociology there's lots of them how
did they come about via this gradualist process of tinkering
is the big question
what the genesis is another name for development
we start somewhere people know very little about how development works
and a big the big elephant in the room is the extent to which we
can understand human behaviour via evolutionary thinking
which is politically highly charged
moving outside of evolutionary theory
within AI
with this is strong desire
given how simple
the evolutionary algorithm is to state i grew up i mean i'm part of the
generation that grew up and read the selfish gene and then they read the blind
watchmaker and extended phenotype and they wrote a little program that involved a sentence and
just was seductively easy
you know if richard dawkins says that's what evolution is and i just coded it
in basic on a ZX eighty the world is my oyster
so there's been this idea that you could harness the power of the creative power
of evolutionary design ever since then i think that it's proved amazingly frustrating
this proved far more difficult than dawkins led us to believe he really led us
up a blind alley well it's not a blind alley but i think it's proven
to be
much more challenging and i think it kind of reveals slide wrong headedness about the
way that we think about evolution if we really
we really understood evolution then when we wrote a computer program
surely we would get better results than what we do
what's last on the list
and we can move even further away from biological evolution
and and talk to people across a ridiculously large number of disciplines now who are
applying evolutionary ideas models borrowed from evolution to other kinds of system so when i
was finishing off my phd
you know i would do is i got to the point where i would do
anything other than write my thesis so i went to the library and i counted
how many journals had evolutionary in their title
and that really was this profusion of new journals called evolutionary linguistics evolutionary psychology evolutionary
cosmology people i don't think they had a journal
the same sub sequences appear in both sequence in the bow strings right and then
we just do the same thing sort of that's what the feature is going to
appear for one string for the other string so that enumeration of the little dots
do you mean that there is an infinity of them there is a need for
an enumeration of all things possible
over this alphabet sigma
and then we're going to count how many times does each sub sequences appearing here
remember we were talking about subsequences yesterday and i was put into two their whatever
all over the place saying the things we exponential so we're walking in murky waters
here so
this is my future lectures which i'm showing the factor saying hey it does exist
now remember its implicit we don't want to play with it and the result is
that when we want to count it we look at it here we're going to
obtain a six in this case so how do compute six well perhaps i look
at this from the the decomposition so we have got several
because i got the one letter words is a which are three of here two
of here
so that's three times six
and we have but one and one seven that's for the one letter words now
if i look at a large one a another a another a three on this
one of the sites of three times one
and i could be a also and i got structure with a b
and a b
the last two
because are going a be here and i will be a and b a so
that's one here
and i don't have any other sub sequence
if i counted right
OK so seven plus three plus two plus one equals thirteen
there is locally
tricky bit about them string land sometimes we're interested in seeing counted once in each
case and just whatever sometimes counted zero
so it's not going to be more complicated than that
obviously noticed that my way of counting here has been exactly the wrong way of
actually counted the features themselves and if i did this on really long strings and
you get very bored but i mean i get more time before that
so you have find a way of avoiding that we show that in a second
but before that i'm just going to turn into just another one of these strings
just to give the idea of the flavour of it
this all subsequence kernels so that idea remember the kansas trying to measure somehow how
many things in common do these two strings has
OK the the value should be as big as things are similar
the problem here is the way saying that as a sequence
that is very spread out over the strings is going to cost to say so
that way the same as the strings that is actually a substring right that very
close whereas experience might tell us that you know is the perhaps something where the
whether with the different elements of the stream they which checking out already close one
to each other should count more than something they spread out so people have invented
a really nice kernel nice meeting it's mathematically elegant i'm not sure it works better
but a nice good which i'm just showing here which is called the gap weighted
subsequences ideas just say we're going to do the same competitions before
but instead of in the feature vector that we saw before just giving a value
and number we're actually going to give a polynomial
i polynomial where each monomial of the polynomial correspond to sort of the length of
that that subsequent is occupying in the initial sequence so since it may occupy five
positions and three positions well there will be one lambda to the five and one
lambda two three actually not noticed five five three so be multiplied by lambda factor
so for example here is that if we look at c a t we can
see that eighty appears twice
once it occupies two positions and the time it occupies three positions in the initial
string so here
the five the
but the corresponding feature well will be aligned at the squared plus lambda to q
this is just to show some elegant things with here the bizarrely enough not learn
we take it out and give it is zero
in case the inputs are were
we have to do some work in the machine to check with the inputs for
this machine is had the right values
and if they do
we can take put is zero in
and generally follow the recipe here
for every
supposed hold checker s
calculate the new machine or find new using
now we can apply
g itself is true
perfectly good turing machine
it's possible to give the definition of i've given the definition of just indicated i
now in inside silent machine itself has the machine description
so it's part of the sort so it's one of the kinds of machines that
might have
holt at all might not have halted when given the sun machine description is an
so we're going to plug that straight back into some of these definitions
and we'll see what happens
if there was
we ask the question does machine g stop when given its own
machine description as input
if it did
this would be up to one
if this can tell the g when given its own description
went to one
with me
he started the reductio one minus the other way
if s to do we do that
by golly looking up the definition of g
since it's got a value one
then g when given time machine description
must be under four
g when given the time machine description does not hold
but now we go back to the definition of s
we say g by definition of s then
if it does not hold
it's gg
i can write that should get the value zero
so starting assumption that s
equals one
we get down to this
r equals zero
that's right that's just reductio was just logic used to doing that
so we see from this assumption
produce the opposite side the opposite is true
ggms be easier after all
heart not
now we start
conversely from the possibility that STG is zero
go through a similar argument
if STG zero
in g given its own input
by its definition
see definition top line the definition
gg equals zero
g of g must be easier
in particular it stops
but if it stops
that's the definition of s
it passed it's GA gene asking that you want
so from here
we can argue refers to like that
and now we argue that
list counted things
so the conclusion we reach is that there isn't
turing machine
so the theorem says
suppose we have a picture machine is a particular problem that solving
was it's able to observe with another machine
we can do something like diagonalisation
could produce new turing machine
with the with properties
that conflict that
it is
i think that would be fine
i was worried about being known for about being
the two possibilities one is that this doesn't stop OK
and the other is that produces the value one
i doubt remains as you
that can be you he
the whole thing is that is an argument around in
i think you're right that i could leave after preprocessing i i actually can remember
putting it thinking why my doing this
the suboptimal sixteen some hope then you might take those but we would like to
to show convergence for some theoretical properties you should assume the biggest error is minimized
what this is
yes it is indeed so this is part of the collection going to talk about
how one can change other posts such that it was less receptive one less
sensitive to two of outliers so essentially what what i'm going to show you is
all the underlying what i mean my understanding of what it was how however the
optimisation works so trying to understand the underlying optimisation problems
then we can change the underlying optimisation problems and such that the solution is more
robust and then it can generate a new posting
OK so but we need someone to take a detour to the theory to understand
what's actually going on so
of course you could directly go to the algorithm change something i'm also showing you
want to change something that works then it's a bit more robust but i think
it's better to
two something i mean which is based on the theory
overfitting problem but
by increasing capital OK
yes and no of course when you have only one iteration then you have a
very simple baseline this is unlikely to have overfitting so but i'm going to talk
about it tomorrow morning first first lecture that this overfitting was not as strong as
one would expect to have it i mean there which he says is when you
have more
more hypothesis when you combine more more policies so the combined hypothesis is getting more
and more complex and therefore we should see operating as we will see something which
is related to margins that place somehow against it so the complexity
somehow the margin increased therefore the complexities lower and actually this avoids overfitting it OK
so it's not complete
so in a sense
it depends on the number of iterations but not as much as one the me
more cases
OK very good
four fifteen k
OK so the next part that is abusive behavior on the
training sample so that is not talking about generalisation is just talking about the training
so the main sources you are going to appear in ninety six and also
for ship you find part of the ninety eight
OK so far we only looked at the function which is either i mean the
classification function which is either correct or incorrect so somehow we
look at what the actual combined output was so and somehow we lose information by
by not looking at the actual value
so we have these combined the functions of this force this one here
OK on the bottom here
and these htx those plus minus one
these are alpha
the first actually some some to one so normalised so therefore this is one here
is actually between minus one one
OK all alright
and usually just look at the threshold value so serving above zero then plus one
then classifier plus one and it's below zero then it's minus one OK but we
lose information how sure example is classified
OK so we have OK the following observations so we have a higher confidence in
the graph in the example when the output is somehow larger closer to one than
the more sure about the classification
and this what would like to
use this output somehow
so let's say we have a linear classification so we have a point on the
side of the positive points and point of this site the negative side
and then we have this point here which is very far away from the hyperplane
so it's very positive
very confident here and here which is close to the hyperplane me unsure about the
OK so and the idea is that we define something which is called the marginal
that is simply
the product of y times f of x
OK so this is the but this is a zero so
he was threshold
and it's very very much positive and on the right side then the study should
be large
and if it's negative but it should be positive then this this is martin stated
OK and drawing like hyperplane here and this hyperplane can be just
this is the normal person on the hyperplane so the question is why why using
the explain that
OK so essentially this function set eight
this one here is so this
and then we think hypotheses out of this function set
and what we are generating another poster featuring really a linear combination of functions in
this have this this hypothesis OK such a linear combination here
so in these
rates of h they are greater than zero and sum to one so the convex
how of this function class
so the first are essentially the parameters
essentially you can see this as a hyperplane where the others are
somehow determining the rate the direction of the hyperplane so this is a
this is equivalent to finding a hyperplane in the feature space which is spanned by
the hypothesis set so every direction every hypothesis is essentially one direction we get a
picture for that
OK so we have the input space x here in the positive points negative points
and then let's say we have two
functions here so this is let's say the first coordinate x x is cut and
second one OK and what we do is we met these this input space into
a so called feature space we take all the hypothesis which and in the hypothesis
class so here's the positive class h one h two and so on and we
take those just make it into the feature space here
OK so in in this feature space it's just a linear classification so and essentially
the distance which we have here somehow transfers into a distance which is here i
mean here we come we measure the distance we measure the distance you OK because
you well
at the time
so essentially you have a linear separation the feature space which is stands for all
the forces that corresponds to a non linear separation in the input space OK
so i mean that's shown you like an example for example that the linear combination
is something on
and also he is a non linear separation what we do this we achieve this
by actually having linear separation in the feature space
let me go back
so that is the
OK in boosting generate t hypotheses and we have the corresponding alpha TV's so this
is essentially the the distance of the point to the hyperplane
this is this distance here
the case is clear
OK so then let let me to find the
into schools this 1
on the which are populated by phosphorylation has presented by Mr. on all defined to
potential function which are divided on rated by the registered relations on Monday aviation and
also potential function is undefined her Romanian
what and everything on the was after in another a hideout persisting is that 1
of the potential is there really cheap to the accounts of others and persisted
so what is so we have explored the men of information he retrieved led calendar
is given to enact such a strike Germany yesterday's affects the extension of the classic
part demonstrates recovery duty-free into space of mattresses measles is kind of a complex Matthew
Wells the imaginary part splitting editions the book is so a salute to the recall
of what about like at base so in fact
a more modest funds from its positive actions that comes from the God things of
what that they want to eat said on your boss also collect calls for all
which we also schools space assisted by US-based was a unique disk of like I
was makes followed about space is given by well-known domestic foes the history the well-known
point delegates taking you need the 1 with that of WGBH so well that way
we have a that information Jimmy treating these vehicles when you have a picture for
instance you have been using it on to evaluations on the Interfax exceeding might use
a bomb and his career in fact are in the space of about Middle so
you might see on on a L For you are going to gods based on
its official between each for a good is given by excretion and that was that
they must not optical and all the value of anything that 2 of the values
of sea lions in the square of trade between the 2 of you I tried
to a hollow information each which is due Monday to see situation where are the
victory given by immigrants and not are which is due by secretion which is exactly
what the richly goes to work as well as space on Societe GOZ ideas we
wasn't saying that point at can put the company's valuable and she began and lose
no consideration so you you do too complex a valuable and on you couldn't consul
it does some kind of exponential stability
satisfies some kind of exponential stability condition
what does it mean it means that
assume you that if you were initializing
your system
basically at the location x one
if you initializing at different initial conditions x one y
and if you were running the two
basically when computing the posterior distribution
which are subject to different initial conditions if this this and this and one
west converging to zero exponentially
we quickly as n increases
then it means that
you're trying to approximate dynamic model which can forget
basically past OK
if you have this kind of conditions
well you can show
results which are much stronger ridiculous
consider for example
that you're interested in
just computing the expectation
the function which depends on the last component x
in this case if you have exponentially many ascension then you get bones which are
essentially time independent so it means in this case
that essentially
you to provide an approximation numerical approximation of the marginal qnx and even the fields
of salvation
which basically doesn't degenerate over time
so the approximation error remains bounded on this is this result is why people use
particle filters is that in most scenarios essentially when you only look at the marginal
distribution there's no accumulation of
that's what makes the technique attracted
so what you can show this was under the same condition is that basically
if you look at your estimate of the marginal likelihood where
the violence obviously going to increase over time because it only increases increases linearly over
time OK on that night because if you use stone basically in pollen sampling technique
to approximate the
marginal likelihood then typically
this violence would increase exponentially with time indexed so far to resampling you've moved to
buy a from of violence because it increases exponentially with time to violence increasing only
linearly with the time and that which is one of the many basically benefit of
using this kind of resampling
so these are the kind of the kind of basic categories over the past few
years there has been an actually a lot of techniques which have been proposed to
import basically the uris
i'm just going to detail so very briefly
OK so
in the naive algorithm what you're doing is that you're propagating the uris according to
the dynamic of the
on your reweighting them according to the likelihood of this acceleration of this is almost
something which is very naive because it's like shooting in the dark because imagine you
have the likelihood which is very picky
that is the salvation which sheltered assumes you like
would like she's quite picky
OK on you instead of using the salvation essentially to guide the particles in the
region of my life you you're doing just sampling naively according to the point that
sort of this is something that you know you can really important those techniques easily
by simply building a mechanism where the particles are propagated in full while using the
conveyed by deed television one so they have their values were to do that essentially
the best way to do it is simply to sample particle propagator particle fall on
the according to the players back on to this conditional distribution which is simply proportional
to the likely time points is a lot of techniques which have been discussed in
the literature like this on when you cannot so use basically this distribution to propagate
the particle fallout where you can use approximation of it so you can come up
with approximation of this
distribution using set ensemble kalman filter or the extended kalman filter in which case you
need to reweight apart according to different ways which correct for the bias introduced by
this this proposal distribution so the techniques which have been done here i'm not going
to discuss it very very in depth
one thing i like to mention because it be user we use later on
is that there is one stop away which have been proposed to increase diversity in
the number of particles
so we're not
you're doing this kind of sampling was something step after resampling step called capital in
time from the weighted empirical measures to obtain capital in sampled on because you sample
some of the data fitting term and idealisation
then if you consider linear functions of fuel excise OK and you only use on
only only do that for predicting then whatever also cost because the convex not convex
whatever you want with the the dimension of feature so she may be one-dimensional but
if can be infinite dimensional figure no full input space then in the end you
that the solution of the problem
will be always a linear combination of your point
OK so i know answer
which should be your vector your from going into hyperspace to be in combination
of alpha phi j
of of the human genome project the features the jokes of the new data so
the end back from one
former public from the optimisation problem in hilbert space in an optimisation problem in in
rn where n is the number of points
of course if the dimension of f is small is useless but in many cases
this is
this allows you to this allows you to
to two big space at the price of a small space
so want to know that f is of the form you can parameterise using that
so i've often called and what by OK and then if you plot back into
the objective function you get exactly is equivalent problem OK
which we only depend on alpha
as the data x we only into the problem with the so-called kernel matrix
then you just need
to know the dot product between
between x x i and j
so then what this means is that even
if e is very low dimensional OK you can't even write he on your computer
but if you can compute that if you can compute the dot product efficiently then
you can
on functions can be found in the function of the so this is a list
of the awkwardness about gonna methods
this is the so-called kernel trick
so you want to be able to rely on the feet which is very very
but you can't even expressing
but if you can express the product then you take it you know that by
the way you are and what the only thing that you are the new are
needs is set of conditions and with this
and as you to do
is to do
to do an implicit use of very large feature space and of course is allowed
to go from in in the nineteen thirties OK so initially
we always in know the parameters be doesn't mean that you know in the input
so this has led to a very nice but the beauty of methods so the
community is divided into it to to
that people people that worked on algorithms that only depend on the metrics
given the metrics that we try to do classification clustering regression
independently of the other whether kinematics comes from
the people that works on specific sites
people from vision that were designed kernels especially for
why images of people from bioinformatics that designed kernels especially for four molecules or proteins
and in this separation between hope with national issues and algorithms is a forceful because
what everything that people do
to apply with the kind of people designed so that they are very nice but
i t
we should be very important for the last thing years
so it's one slide describe people do is either the class
they just do
you can do all the tasks are presented in the first few slides can be
done using a kind kernel algorithms
many classification clustering and ranking
integration of data like that
and of course all those developed independently of the type of data is going to
be applied apply to this is there is one slide to summarize the ten years
of work from the statistics and machine learning community
so now let's get down to business so we want to to design a kernel
for a given that types
is given an image i want to be able to design a kernel images
so there will be pretty boy what is the kernel is just the way of
the the image and it took about a defining how hard you are going to
predict all the images this would be a space of functions at the n plus
the way been allies
so you have to design principles that you might want to consider
one is to be or nucleon from old going my simple algebraic operations
OK and the man one which i want you to what the focus on is
something else OK if used to positive function you get a positive function
but is a bit more to it
if you assume that you can also features falcon one and features looking to
what does it mean to some together it means that to concatenate the two sets
of features
so in some kernels is like adding features
so of course this is very useful in practice because if you have two sets
of features you can simply sum the kernels which are suited to the features
and of course you have you want to be able to design kernels out of
from scratch
as is essentially you need to be able to do this efficient summing OK and
this is what i refer to this line
so you want to be able to use x which is of high dimension
i think being being like one billion
and of course you want to be able to do the product
between two that the city was x and y in the in the small of
and always will be a very very small or of p in the and that
if you want to be able to do that operation in constant time
OK if can of be very large so he of course you have lot to
to work with and you have two million people to matrix people use the first
one is sparsity in the old sense today despite several times you know in your
in your in your next
and if you can enumerate is nonzero elements then you can compute that are very
these are to have a nice application in
four images by common and but one because it is simply the one of the
relations OK let's take this let's take this kernel
OK so i've been looking
in the end you can expand this dickson
OK as a sort of being the coefficients times
o point one another
then what this means for have constructed the features associated with the following kernel market
for all
set of indices as far some to one
with the feature associated one is simply the corresponding monomial the end
i consider
all possible monomials of given degree as features
of course the if n is very large and so this is a very large
set but you can't even describe the computer but difficult to the the product
it turned out that by the addition can easily
estimate that using a very simple dot product
and the power the power that to to me this example summarizes
all of what's nice with kernels
there large some of many many many many many monomials and then you can compute
the conditions in constant time in a situation of course there are many more many
more possibilities for two nice book but should like this and in
go over all the possible people use but all based on the similar technique
so let's look at how it works images
so let's close it
the case when i want to go to work on the same images so here
so many ways to do segmentations but i don't work in the sense that if
you ask for two segments
you would never get one night segment the the object in one i think man
was about one of is this works if you have a black background but in
practice it will never get
what you want
and many people instead work on the oversegmentation OK so you assume that it is
symmetry that you mention it you know twenty segments that you be cut objective interesting
function class should we be choosing
so we might be tempted to say well we just should we should if we
choose from which shouldn't make a restriction a priority we should take all possible
functions so all functions that take our input domain in mapid into plus minus one
cause we don't know before which one is the right one so we have training data
we use the class of all functions and we let the rest we let machine learning
do the rest or we did our empirical inference empirical risk minimization principle do the rest
and it turns out that cannot work and it's easy to see that this cannot
and I'm going to switch to my later slides for that
okay so I think these are the slides you have and we are now we've now arrived here
so we were talking about the size of the function last give me one second
okay so why don't we take all functions well let's assume we have some training set let's
say names as before defaults and someone gives me some test points and for simplicity let's assume
the test points are this joint from the training points we don't want to see
exactly the same point again but if we have some continuous scenario it's
it's basically the probability that this happens is zero so let's assume this
is not gonna happen then I claim that if you give me a function
F so suppose you
I give you the training points you give me a functions F and you tell me I reckon this is a
a good solution for my problem
then I'll give you a second function FF star which
has exactly the same outputs on all the training points but which says the opposite
on all the test points and it's easy to construct this function because
we are allowing all functions from X to plus minus one so I'll just define
my function to do this
and therefore my function says the opposite in all the test points now the
for the uniform convergence we're interested in the values of the functions everywhere and
if we compute the risk then it's obvious to you I think I don't have
to go through the details that
for this function the risk on training test set is similar to each other
then for this function because this function has the opposite on the test set then for this function
the risks on the training and the test set can be different from each so these
two functions have the F and F star have the same risk on the training set but they say
the opposite on the test set so they might have very different risk on the test set
so if if for one of these functions
if our one of these functions the training and the test error are very near
to each other then for the other function they might be very different from each
other and we have no restriction so it's a roughly speaking in this picture what I am
telling you if you if you give me function that's here for which these two risks are close
I can construct another function which is over here for which the two risks are
very different so it's not possible that these curves are close to each other everywhere
so why it is not possible it's not possible because we were using the class of all
functions from
X to plus minus one
so we need a restriction so this is by the way this is called the no-free-lunch theorem
well this has this was always known to people in to some people in statistics
and machine learning and it was later called the no-free-lunch theorem and so we
need a restriction on the class of functions
and we need this everywhere in machine learning in learning theory the restriction is done in
terms of the capacity
of a class of functions but also in other dom areas like in the Bayesian
community we need to place prior distributions over the class of functions so
we somehow have to restrict the class of functions
either in a hard way or in a soft way and then ideally at least in learning theory we would
like to make statements about how stronger restriction is this what kind of
guaranties does it to allow us to make
to to analyze this a bit let's look at some details and I don't want to
go into all the details because you will have a course next week
by Nicol Cesa-Bianchi who I think will also cover some of this but
I think I want to spend maybe half an hour or a bit more on this because
it's also useful as basis for some aspects of of kernel methods and anyway it's
if you don't know this stuff I think it's good to maybe hear the main
ideas twice let's see so let's not spend ages on by nothing
it's sufficiently interesting so let's define our or let's take define this short end
xi for our loss the loss of point XI YI remember this was our zero one
that will talk about it
the second person i have set up now
because the data on the syllabus online is
going to be changed
is andrew readily
who is a year also a young graduate
and who set up a hedge fund called white box advisers
and has done
phenomenally wealthy
in investing
i think
i have on the syllabus i have a new york times article about these are
very original
and creative thinker
who looks at things from unique perspective of
and i find it very interesting talking with him because
to do well and investing you have to have your own independent view of things
and really be thinking about how things work
and he is someone who does that incident linear content in another article
saying that he was really one of the first person
two clearly
delineate the sub-prime crisis that we're now and
he saw it coming
and i have to say profited from that if you know the sub-prime crisis is
coming there's always way to profit from that
and that's what he did that
he also has a philanthropic sites
it all comes out very
i think in the remaining time
i'll just go through
an outline of the
and that means through the topics of the various lectures
and then i'll let you go for today
this course is divided up is different than the financial theory course if you look
at john john accomplice course and financial theory
concepts are
central to his
outline of the course
but this being in financial markets caused
i'm dividing it up more in terms of
and institutions
but still i want to start with some theory
and i thought that i will i plan to start by talking about
the basic
the most basic concepts of risk management which underlie finance
and so that would be
wednesday's lecture
i call it the universal principle of risk management
pooling their hedging risk
i think it's the most important theoretical concept
that underlies finance and insurance which will also talk about a little bit in this
and the idea is that if you spread risks
they don't disappear there still there
but there are spread out over many people
and the impact on any one person
is reduced so the basic principle of insurances
each persons for each family suffers the risk for example that
apparent father mother might die
which is terrible
blow to the family
but it's not a blow to society as a whole because people die
and it has a certain statistical regularity
so it makes sense that we
families who have lost a father mother so that they can keep going
it benefits everyone to have
the situation in place for that
i want to talk about that with a little bit a reference to probability theory
and so that's what
i will be covering the the
the next lecture will be among the more mathematical
although it's very elementary if you had a course in probability and statistics
you find it easy to follow
but it's self-contained again i feel like i have to introduce concepts like
variance and covariance
correlation in order to talk about finances so that's what we'll do
in lecture two
then the next lecture i want to come back to some basic themes
that the third lecture
about technology
and this relates to another book that i wrote
i'm not signing
i wrote a book called new
in two thousand three
about technology and finance
a theme of that book was there
i've already said this to you but it's very important point that financial technology is
evolving and improving just the way
engineering technology or biochemical technology is improving it's getting better year by year
and in the course of finance
over your lifetime will be dramatic
the financial institutions that we have ten years from now
will look very different from the ones we have now
o thing to we have to understand in understanding the progress of financial technology is
its fundamental relation to information technology
variables was living in sequence
and consider the set of blue groups like that
and there is this is over all of the groups so you will set to
zero some of the groups so what you're left with
it is contiguous but can you remove stuff on the right some stuff on the
left to what you what what is remaining is something in the middle because away
of getting sparsity patterns which can be not anything but from a particular class continues
but terms
we can do the same thing with the rectangles into d so you take all
the groups which are
hyperplanes which are parallel to the axis again those once all the all the other
all the others underwent as well so what you're left with
when you remove some of the album's songs about some of the top some on
the left and some on the right you get back
OK so this can be applicable to also all the other angles
and just like that
you also removed hyperplanes which are not parallel to x is a way to get
get diamond shape but you can go on and go back and you can go
and more angles
to get to get convex but
i will show you in later
five times
how this can be applied to to the primal sparse PCA
so here's the goal is that
we have a way of
of getting
but the prior the different sparsity patterns
again i would like to see how it is relevant to
so this can be done in other ways and for you keys which actually before
so here we focused
on intersection closed set of of seaport support vector
convex sets are closed by intersection
and there is a nice work by jacques
which does the opposite
which is considered sparsity patterns which are closed under union
depending on your application it might be
more relevant to be to have been enclosed to intersection closed
the fact
so this is it for sparse
structured metadata that and then i will go
so very quickly
but mister on march on matrices
and this is to me a very nice topic and i wish i had more
time to do it you can look at this lies later on if you want
the discovery of something which i one go
so far what you want to is the simplest the simplest example is the problem
of collaborative filtering
the goal is to essentially to complete the matrix so you assume that you have
some movies and some customers so this is related to the netflix challange
and you have you observe some of the ratings for some of the customers and
the goal is to
find all possible writing for all possible customers
this is essentially the matrix completion problem
what was one is the parliament learning on matrices multi-task learning
so if you assume that you have k prediction tasks
so you want to cluster to have a different asking you want so for each
of them you might want to consider only our model
we have k with the dance OK so if you stack them in a metric
get p times q matrix
and essentially
what people have been considering is they want to share parameters more the different divisions
these as we show is equivalent to put
sparse priors on the other big matrix of all predictors
OK so this as many applications
in one of them which i think is interesting
just multiclass
you want to share
statistical power between different classes and this is actually the topic of
multitask learning
all the examples image denoising
so here in image denoising
very recent approach which was launched by
got its name because p and later slides
you do know all patches of a given images simultaneously so you take an image
x high although also small patches the eight times eights
so there you
you get a lot of pages and you you want to know them all of
them at the same time we we see that this can be done by putting
a sparse pile
on the metrics of all of all patches
so now what other types of sparsity for matrices so you have to be that
types the first you put zero directly on the elements of the matrix
so the first one is to put zeros all over the place
the second one is to put two all columns being set to zero so this
would be
a classical example for task that we shall so those are
are not actually considering the fact that the matrix OK is just because it was
anywhere for the first case
and you put columns to zeros
the second case they don't use the matrices
i can be multiplied together by the
and the second time we have essentially consider the fact that matrices can be factorized
so if you can factorize matrix as being you times transpose
well as a
you OK you have two types of sparsity here
either you assume that the big matrix can be decomposed into sum of the product
of two skinny matrices this is adding a low rank so n is small
or you might consider the case where
you may consider the case where
you have still being matrices u and v are hired by a large number of
but you want to put some zeros inside one of them
it's all about two different types of sparsity that we consider
one is low rank one so m is small
the other one is you being sparse
so these in many instances of matrix factorisation
you have a
this later became the first task so multitasking told you you consider all predictors
you have to give credit to put in a single matrix now you have two
sets of
two men set works in that city using sparsity inducing norms the first one is
to penalize the norm the sum of the norms
of each hole
of of w
so it's initially
if we try to write some of the most zero
so things all essentially is the weight vector for all possible ask for given feature
is then move future for all
tasks simultaneously
this is often called joint
viable selection
this is this is well by obozinski
and the other type
the other type of
for multitask learning is to consider
john produce selection so here
you would have to be careful about what you mean but to mean by future
so he about what i mean by bibles is just one of the p
well is not viable
and what i mean by future
is there any linear combination of the original variables and essentially what the trace known
we will allow you to do
it cost to construct specific
features and select pond
so in the bible selection you don't create anything in this one you create new
we find that there is a combination for age information in the model
the so age information flow but
so look get information there
but that's not less than five percent sixty six percent so so that was that
does not model therefore my
to explain what relationships in the model
which is called conditional independence graph
then we have to draw a line from that calls
the interaction is in the
the age car information that is not right so so what is this
table and tell me
it tells me
which of these variables are related to one another basically so
i can look at this
perhaps the most important thing that i'm interested in this model is survival people
so what affects their survival
so what you want
what is it that
has an effect on the basis of the number of survivors goal
basically what this is telling me is this
this is the from one of the labels
two survival without going to do anything else than directly
so saying
is affected by sense
so we sent to diagnose and the appearance of the so whether or not it
it looked
all good
if you have these pieces of information and a patient and knowing how
the information status doesn't matter because
in particular information about age is captured in information center that's the thing that directly
affecting the survival
the effects of the centre of
sensors related to information services like right to appearance so it is related to a
but if
if somebody tells me the centre i don't need to know the age to work
out what effects on survival
that's what the pictures tell me how these things relate to one another on the
way constructive table
the songwriter diagram
was i went to
all these terms here
one of the colon
and they
five percent
the last five percent in this column then began line to have having the debt
which is what got here
all those lines correspond to terms in the model
so this is the an idea of relationships across
o five variables if i think survives the poem one the so
the things are are actually directly related to survival as an independent
i find know those two variables that age information tell me anything about survival
but just regression is another
generalisation the services
your outputs is binary
and what is model is the
the chance of being one of zero
so because binary the the expected value is the same as the probability of getting
the one so the expected value which is the probability that one what you all
data point j
this model but
this thing which is
i don't recall
this because the most common just call
this is the transformation of
is related to the businesses
we can use the same data before went after to see what's going on if
you think about the probability of survival
if you think really fast the model think of these patients
otherwise not the count it's the
one if the patient survives
so three years and sierra didn't so we refine the model
so actually actively concentrate on survival rather than looking at the relationship between different levels
then the same idea we get
table that's
we'll bring the terms in and
these numbers are telling us the
basically how models change however what the contribution of each of these terms is we
go after him because
of these
values against a before we call the five percent business
so what we've got here which allows approximately one
that one
OK well known
sensor appearance
have an effect upon the probability of survival
being one also
that was telling us
so we tells us we don't need to include
any of the inputs like to this law
also a ge
with this includes
dummy variables for
and appearance
the source come out of this come out of
then model
we look at all these different data
so all the way in which we try to recognise the people
for the first and then we might put me on the first we can recognise
want recognise we here kick in the image
that that can
that you may be interested party
and also that people look very happy or
so in image recognition they want to do in motion detection the fact
in other media
you can extract the and the mind
and the way he did in fact extraction
ten clubs are competing but
now in the core i will not images because we are not image group regions
in our approach we worked very closely with people
because both sides we can show
but now
information extraction from text
it's quite a lot
it's actually how well we're doing between NLP
natural language processing and information
so from natural language processing you have you heard
the description of the structural properties of the language
the fact extraction which you might use some semantic concept of my company
many features that used the
can you direct can be like the a natural language for
the information in the field that could be not
and more
and the work that is called the blue and from here
in the US organised by the national institutes of technology
you have no complication
maybe you have heard
we are not really aware
but if you look many many times the american complication so the way to semantic
come in the eighty eight eighty nine
they these automatic text content extraction conference
and now we're here to make an alliance
i know
so we can look at the role of natural language processing to
one of the text written in natural language
the might be number of features
which we could use in our extraction you now take that point
so if we look at the lexical
we were just text
we look at more technical features the syntactic structure
this tactic worked class
which might be revealed by morphological like keith
the might
if have these
have the already this name is first point and the might
there are
a little bit more
details about
in the first
four west
the first course information
you might probably no
in other words and information but i mean it into to include
the first four one one
so you have to take
it's just silly
of character
and you would like to the the first thing that you is recognised it on
the talk
used to talk
which are like
so you can work
characters in two separate
language which he limit
so you have to
these are the intuition
between the wars
it's not also simple as it looks
well for
the first one
many languages which you do not have space it's more difficult so
in chinese i find the languages you do not have to be so you have
to have or dictionary
so that you can find this on the talk
or you can be in an automatic could we don't
now if you need to implement
such a tool for talking these you well it doesn't seem to
you need quite a lot language
who think that you have core
when think you have
that was the week
but in different languages at might things
it is
have to oppose
which is that the
the journey before it actually work
don't have the words
the same with your that
you have
this is what
this is not the
you might have
you could also imagine that is a numbers when the eight
and because of that
we can quite uniform
so you might want to take it
more letters
the climate is
of pairwise similarity between
so for first entry i j of matrix similarity between sequences i wouldn't change
and this would be the inputs or so
it sounds like a very simple solution now
but from this already can imagine things
first of all this is that what you need what finally
don't care about what was originally the fact the you
this is to say that you are sequences and you are able to develop
visual similarity between sequences your friend is here you have some features and for some
reason why don't
to make
the first problem we can
during the result of distributions will also be an entry sites
so this is the the algorithm again that
i think this important will be able to process
strings as well as feature as well as the world as well as graph
you've got the nation between indian and what was here
so the solution is the size of the
definition is the number of points you analyse so here three sequences
you would have three by symmetries
one of the sequences with the one thousand by one thousand metrics
there absolutely no need to take
that's this a lot of the time so this is the end
in some cases with have some difficulty to handle large datasets you have one million
you can't imagine the metrics of one million one hundred
so this is basically what what would be the distribution of these countries if you
can follow the
four languages start from data computers commentaries and this is something that metrics so here
is one example support vector machines are one example of the reason that you can
see these were the first to point to the symmetries can all
similarity and that these are the input to the right
but not
OK so now i need to be more precise on the type of supervision we
use the lot entries in fact we focus on particular similarity which i call positive
definite kernels
i mean i just want to give you the a precise definition of what it
is so i can only be a measure of similarity in order to
i feel the entries of the matrix so you could be function k
they need to input that you want to hear we assume that
we focus on that input sequences we call capitalism this set of all sequences so
we don't assume any structure on
we don't seem to be just a set of this film is notable whatever
it can be finite and it continues to whatever
and here would just that can only be sure that these two objects and was
and we want to focus on properties the first being that it has to be
symmetric taken into objects
when you get prime is similar to that of the same
you get
OK you its front
so that's the easy part and the second part is the first time it may
be confusing i would try to spend it is what's called it
so one think is still in these equations
that if you give me any sample sequences a finite set of sequences of points
like i could explicitly said
and if you need any set of real valued real numbers
positive and negative then you should also called a i j k fixates j
this has to be nonnegative numbers
so i think
so that
it is simply to say that if we go back to the metrics
one is a set of points to give me
when you look to the of similarities is that has to be positive semidefinite
that's something we we heard about this morning
and whatever you have function so that it always puts positive semidefinite basically to pursue
so you see that one of the reasons sort of one of the why we
when we end with show that the
now the
function k
has this property then we show that metrics with the positive semidefinite and in fact
can be thought as categories and that they input positive semidefinite
so why why focus on that well it turns out that there are many reasons
for it
one way to solve some of these two provinces opposite the internals to give you
some ideas of what we do when we focus on this count
by semi-definite of second-order cone constraints but still it would be useful if they were handled
directly are there questions about this yes it will be very useful so what's CVX CVX
does actually handle exponential and logarithms so it can solve a geometric programming problems for
example but it'll approximate the it has a a quite sophisticated approximation of these functions as
polynomial functions and then polynomial constraints can be of a form that can be written as
semi-definite constraints so it's not the most efficient way of handling these constraints but you
can do it in CVX but if and the reason is that the reason why they don't
do it directly is that the solvers that are used by CVX don't handle these
two cones they're restricted to linear the nonactive orthant second s second order cone and
the semi-definite cone if the solvers handled these cones that would be a very nice
extension because it would be a more efficient way of handling these constraints yes is it one of the drawbacks that you have to auxiliary variables
translating the problem the exponential or the yeah there are customized solvers that do it
directly but in this general framework that's used in the by CVX for example
it translates everything in the as a semi-definite program or a second-order cone program and
then solves this using general-purpose software but it is possible to exploit structure in these
problems for example and solve them much more efficiently than by CVX but then that
has to be developed for every type of constraint separately as a custom interior point solver
so to finish this section on conic optimization so one of the
advantages of using this conic linear optimization format is that it it's
very easy to generalize from linear programming so for example duality for a conic
linear programming problem is almost exactly the same as for linear programming so if we just
start with just a standard linear programming pro duality so this is a linear program with
componentwise inequalities so that's the dual of this problem so you have an
vector Z of dual variables one for each inequality in the primal problem Z
has to be nonnegative and so they have equality constraints that involve A transpose
and the objective and so on so that's the primal and the dual LP we'll
call the optimal value of this P star the optimal value of this maximization D star
with the usual conventions it this infeasible if there are no feasible X then we
say P star is plus infinity because it's a minimization problem if this is infeasible we say D star
is minus infinity and then we can also have minus infinity as an optimal value
in the primal and that means that it's unbounded below you can just decrease X in a fi
and stay in the feasible set you can increase X without bounds so the main
duality theorem in linear programming is that first the optimal value of the primal problem
is always greater or equal than the optimal value of the dual problem with no exception
that's called weak duality it's actually very easy to show but that's a one-line proof
usually actually or almost always have equality between these two and that's called strong duality
there is only one exception and that is it's if the primal is infeasible and the
dual is infeasible then P star is plus infinity this is minus infinity and you don't
have equality and that's possible you can easy write LPs that are
infeasible and have an infeasible dual but as soon as one of the two
is feasible you have equality between P star and D star so how do we extend
this to a conic li program where these are vector inequalities respect to a
nonpu polyhedral cone well first you have to define so here you see you have the same type of inequality in
the primal and dual this is componentwise inequality and this is componentwise inequality in general for a
conic problem we'll have different inequality in the primal and the dual an inequality we'll have in
the dual is a inequality respect to the dual cone so if you have a cone K then you can define a
dual cone K star defined like this so Y is in the dual cone if it
makes a non-negative inner product with all X in the primal cone and you can show
which are packed with text
labels these are called taxi
now these taxa somehow is a collection of small documents which are textual description of
the image we are looking at
OK so if you have lots and lots of those and we have lots and
lots of text then we can
we can relate these tools
OK in terms of
in our task it is a line
using using this to align
the topics that we build for the documents and the topic that we have for
the images then it is the same set of topics
boost the performance of the models
OK so as a result in this experiment there was a improvement in clustering performance
encouraged by this success we went down to
ask the next question so suppose you have read a lot of
text documents say about lions and
apples and bananas can you help with the classification
OK and this involves supervised learning
so here's an example OK so let's say
we have a few labeled images and and they are so feel that they are
not sufficient
for building good
image classifiers
OK so that test data consists of the
just the labelled images
in addition suppose i give you the tools resources one is just like the one
we had just now
is the tag images say from flickr of from others and other resources
and on the other hand we have a large collection of auxiliary text documents that
are unlabelled OK these are unlabelled
so then
by but putting this together we can still see some relationship between them OK so
for example as illustrated
in this next image we can for the images we try to build a relation
between images and text and those are from the social web right and the documents
which are unlabelled even though there are labeled we we still have a relation between
documents and words
and on the beach because
matrix decomposition to build their relevant
latent semantic models
OK so for example for the images we have these models
image times the latent
clusters and and their semantic model times the text and here we have the documents
likewise in the same way
the only difficulty we have here which is a major difficulty is that these semantic
latent models are not aligned and we can try to impose a constraint to align
them to the latent factors
can be aligned so what the result is if we have these images which c
which are seemingly unrelated we don't know how
similar they are
this alignment then we can have a better
the relationship between them like they are all about exercising and exercising machines and so
so that's the intuition in the mathematical model behind this is a matrix model where
simultaneously composed a collection of images and the collection of documents and in the same
time making sure that the model v
is the same
OK the latent semantic models are the same
then in the end we can accomplish this so
so then you know because there are many unknowns because we we have two
you some tractable to make sure the model is convex and can converge
so that the details will be ommitted now
in the end we did a number of
experiments to see if our intuition conformal to
the experiments OK the first thing is
if three
increase the number of
auxiliary documents that is you know is it true is
the more we read the more knowledgeable we are OK so here on this horizontal
axis is the number of labelled documents that the system really
and we can see that
the performance
which is the accuracy
increases sharply
for the first four hundred documents and then
it flattens out after
OK so this tells us that
yes the more you read
this you are
but it's not true
if you continue reading OK so after we pointed you can graduate that's why we
and you flight out
and in fact
it drops a little bit because there's more noise that are introduced so
you may get a little bit more stupid
OK and if you introduce more tagged images again the performance
after a certain point that is the translator itself has to be
of good quality good enough quality
the more noise you introduced in nonrelevant tag images the performance
we'll we'll drop
OK so these are some preliminary experiments which are
quite encouraging at first and again here we are trying to
use the unlabelled text as the auxiliary data
we use the social web as the brain age and we try to improve image
classification which is a very difficult task
the same work and tried to introduce use
some recent work done by
my students on
using social recommendations themselves
as of
as the source data in transfer learning
OK so so that the target here are people and the relation between people and
people and people and items and products in recommendation systems
because this this workshop is about social
media social recommendation so i don't need to give you much introduction here
but we are we should
b all familiar with recommendation right so if you if you have a query
you come in and there are a number of recommendations
that can be given to you the familiar
workflow of MSR if you're right you if you buy this book these books are
recommended to you
and we all know the advantage of recommendation system is as opposed to search based
system its active it gives you recommendation knowing something about two it can personalise it
can be
up close
now you want to model social recommendation systems we can consider it as a mathematical
parameters and model
and all model selection so if we have a sequence
they have one and two and so on
and we want to figure out which one is the best
so we
to do that we
calculate the marginal likelihood of the data x
given our model
integrating out the prior to within the model
and then we can do model selection by saying that we should choose the model
which maximizes the marginal likelihood of the data
if the more bayesian there but we don't want to do model selection to do
model averaging in this case we could
in the project
case we could say that
the probability of new data has a point x power
given training
set x
is a sum over all possible model
of the probability of x given the model
actually does
x missing in the story
and we
average the the likelihood of x on the model
over the posterior over model
but it was
with the for with the risk of a given by this thing prior and likelihood
of life
but the problem with this
the problem with
the major question to ask is
this this marginal likelihood
OK this this happening here
which is the
the most important in terms of evaluating
both model selection and model averaging
we actually compute the marginal likelihood
it turns out that
the marginal is extremely hard to compute virtually all
which were interested in
so that
that makes it hard to do model selection and model averaging
and of course
both models that can model averaging very important in terms of preventing
overfitting underfitting of models we have to find a model of the right complexity to
fit to data
here the idea is that
if we actually have
and probably not the
it what well basically we put reasonable prior on over parameters and we integrate over
all possible parameters
the model
the method should not be overfitting the data
so what does that mean if model does overfit the data
that we should simply use as last model as possible
we use the really large model they have infinity
and then
so i'll let the data speak for itself
a couple of example
what happens here in the indicates that in the case of a mixture model the
when you are trying to model data with a mixture model
and you have to figure out the number of components and
you could actually take
so when i generate
i have to go backwards and forwards here,
and each time i go down here, i have to do somemean field share, or
in fact when you generate itproperly, update theseoneat athe time
then goback up there
then come back down, update these oneat a time, do that for a long time
and then get sample here
then given that sample there
go down here,update theseone at a time, then go
don't go back up. update these one at a time,
do that many times
and then given that sample there
then i can,
you don't actually,you only have to update these once,because they're not laterally connected
lateral connections are gaussian units, so it's harder to learn using contrastive divergence.
so it's just a bad reason
OK so that's how he generates
but when he does inference in this model
these arejust part of the
generative model, so to do inference,
you just go chunk, chunk, chunk
inference is just feedforward and doesn't use lateral interactions
and that's very surprisingtovision people
so these lateral connections areamarkov random field
it's used during learning, it's used for generation, but is not part of the inference procedure
and vision people hate that because they assume that if you have an MRF, you better
use it forinference
but because of the way we learn this
the MRF is enforcing constraints
these smoothness constraints
and you don't need those smoothness constraints during inference because the dataenforces them.
you only need them during
you need them during learning
you have to run thelateral interactionsas you're learning
but you have very fast inference at the end
and you think about it, when we whiten data, the reason we do it is so
you don'tlearn
higher level models
thatuse all the resources of these hidden units to model pairwise correlations. if you
get rid of the pairwise correlations then you can use the resources in the hidden units to model higher
order correlations which are more interesting
so we remove the second order statistics
but then when you get to the hidden layer, you've got binary units and it's
much harder to see how youwould whiten those
so what we're doing ineffectis widening the learning signal
when you learn these lateral interactions as part of the generative model,
what you're doing is saying if i can correctly predict a pixel using lateral interactions,
then it'll be the same in the reconstruction of the data
the hidden units won't need to try to model anything because there'll be no discrepancy
between the
data and reconstruction.
for pixels that i can't model using the latter interactions,
i'll need the hidden units, and that'll be exactly edges
so the hidden units will get devoted to modeling edges
rather than being devoted to modeling the fact that images are smooth
so you get much better features out of it.
and that's one reason why this thing learns
to generatemuch better images
now i want to talk about probably the most complicated thing i'm going to talk
which is how to make a better modulethanarestricted boltzmann machine
how to go further than just put--putting lateral interactions between visibles
and it's going to allow us to
get multiplicative interactions which you couldn't get so
so essentially
you should think about
in the belief net part of the model
the sort of standard model we've had so far
has top-down effects like that
and then
learningthese lateralinteractions
in the generative model you also get effects like that
now what i want to put in
top-down effects like this
where the state of the hidden unit
can determine the lateral interactions between two visible units
and that's much more power--
much more powerful. that's like when the officer tells the soldiers, you know, how far
apart they should be
and modules like this can learn
better things
well they should be able to
so the standard energy function we're using has pairwise interactions like this
let'swrite down an energyfunction with triplewise interactions
you can think of this as if, if sk is on,
then we have a pairwise interaction between i and j.
if sk is off, that pairwise interaction just disappeared
for those ofyouwho knowabout vision, this is like the game in-game line process
but you can view--because the symmetry--youcan view i is acting as switch for whether
j andk interact too
so you can use things like thatfor example for extracting transformations between images
so here's an image at time t
here's an image attime t plus one
here's some hidden units
this represents three way interactions
so this hidden unit is saying
if i'm on
and this pixel is on
if i've got a bigpositive weight here
itsays if i'm on, and this pixel is on
then it's a good ideato turn this pixel on.
it's also a good idea if this pixel's on
to turn this pixel on
so he represents the translation from there to there
and this hidden unit,
presumably shouldn't come on at the same time, represents a different translation
a translation if you think about it is
a correlation between pixels here and pixels here
so these unitsare nowspecifying not activities of units but correlations between units
patterns of correlation
and if you apply this to pairs of images,
it works really nicely, and these learnto be
to represent trans,transformations between images
like if you, if they translate these learn different translations. if they rotate, they learn
to represent different rotations and so on
but there's a problem
and the problem is
if you write down this three-way energy function
there's three indices here
and that means if we have a lot of pixels
in the first image in pixelsand a lot of pixels inthe second image and a lot of
elements of trans-
formation,then we got a lot of this
cubicallymany of these
so what we're going to do is we're going to factor that
we're gonna say
i'm going to try and represent
what this energy function was doing
by having a whole bunch of factors
this is just like doing PCA
but fortensors instead offor matrices
a whole bunch of factors
and each factor
so as i have these three guys
but now this weight is factored into the product of these three pairwise weights
and there'sonlytwo indicesthere,so there's three
it is in the first two weeks ramp everybody up
some level of software security where you feel comfortable
so they
the first two weeks of this course is intended
to make you comfortable with programming we don't assume you've done extensive programming before
we want you to become comfortable that you're not behind
and that's the focus on the first two weeks exhibit the exercise
if you have little or no previous background if you are uncomfortable please do the pipeline tudor exercises
if you have not
if you
do not have a lot of experience programming if you're uncomfortable
with with the expectation that you can do programming do first
back takes priority over all the other assignments during the first two weeks
in particular if you're uncomfortable
we will run a special pipeline help session on sunday
and if you talking back
you can get a free extension
the idea is be completing the tudor exercises intended to make you feel comfortable that
you have a software background to finish the rest of the course
that's first
we will forgive
falling behind in other things
so that's
you feel comfortable with programming
if at the end of two weeks you still feel uncomfortable
we have a deal with six hundred
the python programming class
that they will allow you to switch your registration from six o one the six hundred
the ban expires
valentine's day
so you have to make up your mind before valentine's day if you'd like to use the adoption
the idea is
we'd like you to be comfortable with programming if you have a program befor do
the python tutori exercises good software lab
good design but work on the two directors actors
the staff will help you with long
you can go of office hours office hours listed
in on the home page
you should try to become comfortable and you should try that set as you going
to be comfortable before valentine's day
and if you are not talk to stack
a staff member of back
so what i want you know operating
well we're gonna use pipeline
we selected pi on
because it's very simple
and because
it lets us illustrate some very important ideas in software engineering in a very simple context
that's the reason
one of the reasons that simple
is that it's an interpreter
after some initial isation
the behavior of pipeline is the fall into an interpreter
interpreter loopy is
ask the user what what he would like me to do all
reap what they user types
figure out what they are talking about the print the result repeat
very simple what that means is
that's you can learn by doing
that's one pointsof today's software lab
you can simply walk up to a computer typed the word pipeline
what you type is in red
take the word pipeline
it will prompt all
so this chevron
that's axes
i'd like you to tell me something to do i have nothing to do
if you'd type tools
i found tries to interpret than in this particular case
by found says oh i see
that's a primitive data item
that's an integer
this person wants me to understand an integer
and so it will echo
indicating that it things you've when you wanted to understand a simple integer
similarly if you type five point seven it says oh i got back that's afloat
the person wants me to remember a floating point number
it will similarly echoed the flow
now course floats don't have any
so there is no exact representation for floats
the solution
OK thanks very much indeed i like to thank the the organisers for inviting me
to this music it's been extremely stimulating i've certainly learnt a lot and i'm sure
what i will then
make a difference to
the work of myself my team and i go back home i hope that we
can have various collaborations
what i want to do to begin with is just introduce the
thing because anything i say which is original today
it's probably done by members of my research group rather than myself
as you can see from this
i've got quite large research groups they work on on a number of different project
i'm talking about fraud detection today and the people in red are the primary and
you certainly see some of their work today
in fact during the course of my talk i'm going to give one or two
examples of the sorts of work we've been doing but fairly superficial level and the
talk immediately following line given by dave weston is going to go into one of
the projects in considerable detail so give you a better idea of the sorts of
things we've been doing
other people in the group work on on different things so for example
the the people in light grey had amount of heating in sand dunes
daniel as if work on particular aspects of the retail banking industry which i do
quite a lot of work in
others in red in green for example work on
royal theoretical problems of multivariate streaming data
with missing values and other kinds of distortions which can obviously apply to fraud can
also apply and a lot of other areas
so a lot of people working broadly speaking in the same direction run overlapping projects
so this is the structure of my talk on going to give some
general background
i'm going to sort of quantify the problem so that we can see why it's
important what's interesting the then i'm going to focus down on fraud in banking because
that's my
the banking the bank here is one of my particular research interests and i'm going
to look at fraud within that area
if i have time which i may well not too
quickly glance fraud in science
because this is
the issues there are the different often they also involve involve large and complex datasets
but the motivation and and other issues are rather different so we see how it
goes and then one of the some conclusions
and given the title of my talk which was statistical techniques for fraud detection and
so on
i would just like to
define what i mean by statistics and i've adopted john chambers definition is
everything related to learning from data so very broad definition
we can argue about definitions if you like it's probably pointless that's what i mean
so i'm going to include if you like machine learning techniques support vector machines whatever
anything related to data analysis if
so let's begin with some background
first definition of fraud
here's one from an important dictionary criminal deception the use of false representations to gain
an unjust advantage
fraud is
from that definition older as old as you like you can trace back was only
like and you could even argue that older than humanity and certainly animals perpetrate what
one might regard as fraud fraud in other contexts through camouflage and deception and so
on so it's all always light
it's not
it's not just the sin of humanity if you like
four because
everywhere basically i briefly referred to the semantic motivation isn't always the same in
many context perhaps most context money
or perhaps power is is is is the motivating
it is the motive so this is the case in banking fraud why what people
the banking fraud because they want to get rich basically and the same applies to
most other areas like telecoms fraud insurance healthcare fraud click fraud or whatever
in some other areas however there is a rather different motivation and as i say
if i have a chance to come to the city and so in scientific fraud
it's pierre garden
which is the motivating generally motivating influence rather than hoping to get rid if you
a rich and you're in science
i think you might say
in in terrorism
a lot of fraud is associated with terrorism in the short term gain areas two
get money to fund terrorism but in some sense the longer the bigger aim of
terrorists is some sort of higher obviously put that in
inverted commas in speech marks is some sort of higher motivation the primary aim is
isn't money it's some other ideological sort of
a couple of comments about
social aspects of fraud management
one of the difficulties in this area is that there is often an unwillingness to
i admit to being defrauded and i was at the conference not long ago
when a banker said no we have no fraud in our bank
sure he doesn't it just doesn't want to admit it because if he
if if a story appears in the papers that his bank lost a hundred million
o dollars last year to fraud it's not going to do is banking shares much
and then there are other issues such as the public beliefs
the bank has a very good system to detect fraud
it's great stopping force this targeting that whether or not it really does have such
a system so the
subtle social issues
and of course is also
a tremendous reporting bias associated with these things in general
a few words about something i call economic imperative which has got several aspects the
first is that it's not worth spending a huge sum of money to start a