large amount explains a very large amount of data that's a good theory
it means you understand
and it turns out if you if you with this model is easy to show
most finite strings of bits about our data have no theory
smaller than than their own size
so this would be the most of was most strings of bits
the vast majority are lawless according to this criterion there is no theory
no real theory because the
sure is the smallest program that calculates exactly
that string is the same size really does not calculation just as just produces an
output you know something directly without doing any calculations
OK so so
so this
so so in this model that one extreme is random or lawless data for which
the program has to be the same size and therefore is not considered to be
understanding real theory the other extreme
is that what the best theory before data which really does file well it would
be the smallest program that produces that
that data that explains the data
that would be the simplest theory
like this you can distinguish this is your experimental data from a physical system
if you use physical system is a finite string of zeroes and ones is behaviour
is a function of time see then
you would say that this is lawless or randomly
if the smallest program to calculate it is no better than is no smaller than
has the same number of bits
well the complexity is measured in the size in bits of the fear so a
small number of bits here means this is actually very simple and if this is
as large as this then this is irreducible complexity there's no real theory
and that's the majority of cases yes
yes it to ensure
well it's a serious problem
that's a very good question it means it means what you pointing out is i
have no way to find the best theory i have no way to decide if
if a theory if data has a theory or not and and i have no
way to know if i have the best theory in fact that is the main
application of this
OK so
it's it's sort of a different viewpoint on
the halting problem so let me tell you
that's so the first thing in this theory is can you find out what this
is what the best areas that would be the smallest program that gives you the
data what can you determine if a string of bits has theory
you know program that smaller the answer in general is you can't
there's no algorithm and there's no way to
to prove it so
so that gives you an incompleteness results based on this notion in other words let
me put it this way
one way to put it is called the program elegant let me talk about elegant
programs so i'm not going to talk about theories
any more
a theory
another program
well defined to be a program that is the smallest
that there is no smaller programs like if no smaller OK i remember i'm not
concerned with runtime
i'm only concerned with the size of the program
the the complete compact conceptual complexity not concerned with practical complexity issues like time or
have just with conceptual concerns
think it so called the program elegant
if it is no program that is smaller than it produces the same output so
this would be the best theory for its output if you if you use programs
as theories rather than equations and elegant program would be the best theory for its
output OK so what if we want to prove that we have the best theory
you know that we this was not a particular program that we're interested in is
in fact the best theory for its output that there is no program more concise
that produces the same output yes you are
there may be several there may be several i could maybe several elegant programs to
produce the same output could be attacked it's true so let's say we have one
of these programs we convinced it's not from we would like to give a mathematical
and the answer is it's very very hard
this is an incomplete result which has a core library the unsolvability of turning folding
problem so the way you prove this incomplete result the proof is actually rather simple
and in some ways even simpler than the original proof of the completeness theorem or
strings halting problem which involves self reference and i don't need a self reference i'll
show you what i need the proof of the
you cannot prove that the program is elegant in general so let me give proof
that you can prove that an individual programmes elegant there are infinitely many elegant programs
of course for any computational task there has to be at least one elegant program
there may be many so so infinity about from what if i have a particular
problem and i want to prove its elegant that you can do that in general
you can see from the following paradoxical programme p
its output is
i i have to explain this but
so let me explain this
this paradoxical
programme p
so here how it works
the output of this program is the same as the output of the first probably
elegant program q that is larger than p has been explained
first of all we are talking about what you can prove
i need to assume that you have what's called the formal axiomatic systems
an idea that i think is mostly due to
u in x one x two
you propose new company y one y two on the way you do it as
new sampled the new component y one the updated by sampling it
according to its conditional distribution given the current value of x two
on basically
you don't modify the component x to this is what i was doing because felt
so this thing to do simply don't modify the company x two then the second
killer considering the considering the following kernel which basically what it does
he does modify the current value of x y on the day the components the
current value
all of this is the story on it and they basically the second component by
sampling according to its conditional distribution
it's very easy to check
that both p one
on p two alpine OK so i can do it for p one and this
value to determine is really really simple to show that both p one
basically pi in the distribution p two as priors in the distribution so the composition
of of those killed as basically priors in the distribution
so i know
that you are you going to propose to leave pine valley and which is actually
something which is actually necessary requirement for intensive
that doesn't mean that basically you convert going on the solution as i said you
need additional condition you need to ensure that basically
said to each other and that any positive mass on the target problem
so you need to ensure that whatever being
the initial point you can which any set of positive point mass the target
on you need essentially tall are also be so OK going OK
this is basically what unit soldiers became a conjurer this algorithm also
to the chase where instead of into components UIP components so let's say that x
can be separated can be divided in like p
corpus of number of valuable x one x two x p
well basically the categories the way the gibbs sampler we work in this case so
as to simulate approximately from the target distribution
is following
at each iteration
i basically you're going to cite call for the company and one to the component
on basically you date because the company xk
i call them by sampling according to its conditional distribution under pi
given the chance
of the
all the components that is in this scenario
OK minus one feels confident have already been updated at iteration i on the remaining
components which are at iteration minus one because they haven't been sampled OK so these
categories by using this try generalisation of what i've been discussing before he's and it's
basically by as in the distribution on you can also instead of cycling deterministically and
from one computer components you can basically so paul them
so called this company components that one the only
according to the distribution a uniform distribution over the set one to p
OK so instead of citing for use on paul ron the basically
the company want to update OK
six j
that's going to give you a return value which is uniformly distributed according to intercept
want to be on your data is distributed so company according to the full conditional
distribution this guy corresponds to a mixture of kernels also using the same argument he
admits basically the wife involved distribution
so i've can back to basically on nuclear pump again i've told you we've shown
that basically these algorithm i was proposing is just a simple example of the gibbs
sampler OK
so i know it that means the light in distribution OK
what about this condition we basically with the additional condition that briefly sketch which are
that basically
i need to be awarded to reach any basically said
o point met opposite point and the target whatever being the starting point where is
going to be
automatically unsure because all the conditional distribution of strictly positive until plus infinity
on similarly
basically my markov chain doesn't exhibit any periodic behavior because similarly all the conditional are
strictly positive so i know this algorithm is going basically generates so important that essentially
as i can go to plus infinity converge toward the target distribution whatever the rate
of convergence well
that is going to be much more complicated on this simple example actually some people
have and establish some results on actually on this policies example is simple enough that
you can get rid of convergence german-speaking is going to be much more complicated
so that's basically keep sampling
so the
you should be a bit careful when you discover
well the point is that it's very nice to come up with this kind of
separating essentially
he said the company short
state vector instead p company innovating one conditional upon the other
but conditioning is going to come out the sales price OK
let's look at the another really toy example
which is essentially unified ocean distribution
so a bivariate gaussian distribution of zero mean on compliance basically
violence gumbel metric given by this guy has always the correlation coefficient here i can
i just assumed that basically this unit unit
OK so in this case
OK i wouldn't use the example
but if you have to use the gibbs sampler on practice sample
from these joy target distribution by the theory iteratively sampling from the conditional distribution of
a given y and then y given x
then this is the form of the conditional distribution
well what you see
he's obviously so this is the question
OK so if you can rewrite it basically you can think that the gibbs sampler
which also just follow essentially so this is the first component you would at time
at iteration and was one of the categories
i will get back later on this
i'm going to explain more in the following if you don't have the answer you
ask again OK
all this kind of query
it's more difficult
so if you want to find the one hundred most frequent IP addresses
the standard solution
is to build an array of all IP addresses
appearing in root
when a new packet musician right
you have a look at your table if it's not there
you add it and
if it is
you increment the counter
if it's not then you have
in this kind of applications you may have several thousands or hundreds of thousands of
different IP addresses
and this
table is going to be very very large and accessing it and finding
the right
place to increment is going to be very expensive
this solution
of maintaining a table of IP addresses with frequencies is not a good solution
for this example
so they may be either of solutions one solution would be to some for the
this is a good solution
if you sample the stream
since you want information the list of
one hundred most frequent IP addresses you have a good chance that they may be
the sample
so this is a good solution
we will go we will i will present you
and not
and the idea here
is that we will not provide the exact solution that an approximation of the
you have a question any question about the
applications the motivation
data stream processing
so now we
we're going to define
more precisely
what is
the structure of the data stream and model
so as we have seen the structure of the data stream is that you have
an infinite sequence of items or elements
one night is structured information
just records
and it's the same structure for
items industry
what you've seen
is that
when you have a stream
all we could
we have the timestamps
the time stamps
will be i've
that is
there is a field in the recurrence
the times
so the break
arrived with the times
or implicit
the record does not having time stamps and when it enters the the system thanks
and is given by the system
or we could have time time
the time stamps can be of two types
they may be either physical
so it's today
all are not equal
so it's number and in tag let's have a look at two examples
in this first example the timestamp
here is implicit
it has been it's
implicit energy called so it's the numbers
given by the systems
when information enters the system
in this
the timestamp is physical
it's the
it was present
in recruit before arriving
in the facist
so this was for the structure the
the elements of the stream
so of course the timestamp is very important
as for not adding the stream
an important
the fact is that
we must distinguish
the contents of the stream
that's the so values information
contained the tree could
two we must distinguish this two
from the
underlying signal
we want to study
and the model
of the stream
it's a relationship
between observed values
and this signal
so as for the contents of the stream
so as i told you before
we have structured recur
we have we received an infinite sequence of items x
with two information
the time the observation time
which if it's logical time just one two three four five
and so
descriptive values which may be numerical symbolic or ID's
of some other object
so for instance if we consider the
this dream
and these
elements it's a short version at the time
one two three four
and the observed values are
the two IP addresses
the duration the volume and protocol
so this is the information
contained in the street
when you model the stream
from the same stream
you may want to extract different information
and depending
on the model of the stream
the algorithms
to process them will be different
people are able to learn
structural forms on relations
or just make one last point because it's just relevant for the general conclusion i
wanna make which is what happens if we look at how
the structural forms developed as we observe more and more data
so here we are back to the animals domain and we're going to see what
have we learned when we just take five features twenty features or the full data
set of one hundreds features and what you can see something kind of interesting here
that with with just
five features we don't we learn a more simple structural form we just learn a
set of flat clusters there reasonable clusters this sort of large-scale supernote categories like birds
and insects and carnivorous mammals an herbivore mammals and aquatic creatures and so on but
we don't have the full hierarchical structure
now when you add a few more features now the model realizes that the extra
complexity of the tree structured
taxonomy is licence and it doesn't for the best structural forms the tree but it
doesn't have the right tree so you can see over here has the tree has
a node with dolphins seals whales and penguins
and we know as adults the penguins up along with dolphins seals and whales
rather they belong something like over here so this is this is what the tree
learning you have the full dataset where now there's there's a distinct subtree for the
aquatic mammals and penguins are over here with the other birds although there sort of
closer to the fish and aquatic mammals
and what's what you see going on here is the phenomenon that that we call
the blessing of abstraction it's kind of
kind of overly dramatic name for
what i think is the basic but really important phenomenon which is the
often learning abstract knowledge is easier than learning concrete knowledge that the concrete knowledge here
is the specific structure in the abstract not knowledge is the structural form and it
you will often find when you work with hierarchical bayesian models
that because because that you
less data is required to
converge on the right
learned knowledge at a higher level than at the lower levels in this case that
means the structural form than the other than the
the particular structure and i think that's an important feature of cognitive development as well
as science where when the first learning about the domain we kind of get the
big picture and sort of the general way of organizing things and that might take
much more observations to fill in the details indeed the that's exactly what happened in
scientific biology and that's exactly what happens in children's cognitive development where he was relatively
early scene seventeen hundred so we figured out some kind of tree structure is the
tree structure is the right form but it took a long time a lot more
data to two
converge on what we thought was the right rate
and this is this is really a sort of a different perspective on
what is maybe the most classic debate in cognitive science about the nature of learning
what's what's called the need disperse the empiricists and you see the same kind of
debate in
a i just
conclude by talking about the
the bayesian in cognitive science it's long recognised that that some kind of abstraction is
important but you have these two camps the natives who say that there is explicit
knowledge of say structural former we we have explicit abstract knowledge but that is not
chomsky being the most famous example and then you have the so-called empiricist camp which
says well we can learn abstract knowledge but it's not really explicit we just sort
of it it's just comes out kind of implicitly from overlaying a lot of concrete
experiences sort of the classic connectionist approach as well as traditional i would say traditional
structure learning probabilistic graphical models we're learning some graphical representation of the structure of the
set of variables but you but you're not learning the some kind of higher level
inductive bias abstract constraint on the kind of structure that's there and what i tried
to argue here is that that both of these things are necessary we really do
need explicit structural forms because you can see from modelling people's ability to generalize from
very few examples you need that the stronger inductive bias but you also need the
flexibility that comes from being able to learn and it's what we what we're trying
to work towards here is really a third way or a new approach to thinking
about how the development as well as how you might say engineer the development of
an artificial system
so let's get my little thing and causal learning
in the summer of two i've given you two case studies on
how we can model human inductive learning used by combining a few basic ideas the
idea of bayesian inference over hierarchies of flexibly structured representations and what in each of
these cases we looked at multiple levels of knowledge and tried as some of the
big questions about cognitive science what's the form and content of knowledge at these different
levels of abstraction how does that knowledge guide learning and how much knowledge itself acquired
in a way that combines both strong inductive biases but also flexibility
and the and there's sort of these bigger picture lessons which i hope
you know i certainly in cognitive science these are important but i hope they will
also payoff for people interested in machine learning and AI
this third way of thinking about development the idea that
in some sense inductive biases abstract powerful abstractions can be learned very quickly sometimes in
a kind of a top-down way rather than having to be wired in or learned
very gradually and implicitly
and maybe the most general lesson which i think many people in machine learning are
already have already learned and taught others including me that we need to go beyond
some of the classic dichotomy is a thinking about intelligence dichotomies of say you know
domain specific hardwired
approaches versus domain general learning based approaches are statistics versus structured representations and as really
the existing one
so this is the motivation
for some estimation of local optima we can achieve based on the current configuration
so here is a graph figure showing how we can we can do this
on the x axis this is number of iterations
of the current procedure of reason
and the blue line is the log likelihood after after some iterations
and the blue one is best solution we have seen so far based on the
previous rounds of the
and if we can derive some upper bound on the log likelihood of the local
optimum here
after every iteration
and if some after some iterations we found
so look the upper bound of the local optima is already small that the current
best solution
we can stop this procedure at this moment
we can save the time for the rest of the iterations
and we know that in current practice many in sincere i is stopped based on
the difference between two iterations however this is not a good good solution y
for example here
you can see that the difference between two iterations is very small
however we can now start here
because we are not sure if we can leave to so much better solution
o upper bound based termination as it is much better than the current solution for
you from what he re
so far
now we have seen the motivation
for the
as the estimation of the local optima
let's see some interesting properties we proving your paper
first let let me define the solution space
the solution space we a point in this space the configuration of the gaussian mixture
and it is easy to do this we just need to concatenate all the parameters
of the of the costumes so we can generate a very high sequence and this
is the sequence can be mapped into a high dimensional space
every every year iteration
when moved the confederation from one position to another
so for example here
the original iteration is it at d and after william iterations to move to to
see that he plus one
here we use a degree level to indicate the log likelihood the configuration can achieve
so the doctors about
so we know that the that t plus one must be a better solution to
see that
so the colour here must be darker and see that
the local trapping is some is some very interesting properties
we can find past fall for every
for every p of configurations across a yemi iterations
we can find past in the solution space
connecting c that you and see that the plus one
and we can prove that
on this past every configuration
can lead to some better solution see that
we prove this by by first finding a new configuration c sharp between that you
can see that first one
present at every
every configuration between that you see that show is that that e
and also configuration between swedish opportunity plus one is better than c russia
you can check chicks
the paper for the data of this proof this part is very interesting
based on this local local trapping property
we can derive some some maximal region on the local optimums
how can we do this
we need to find some some regions
for example
for this one comprises this this country if if every configuration in this country
yes it's no better than thirty
we know that the first iterations can not jump out of this region
so in this way we can somehow down local
local optima in this region we can try to derive some upper bound of the
local optimum achieved by by further iterations
so this is the basic idea
of the estimation
so r
now let me show you some
definition of the maximal region
so i maximal region is some region in the solution space which can cover
so she would fall
is exciting
many different
now i present first and my guests
and then we what you not you want to to know what
complaints anything
you have to
i think about the first lesson for
you try to four forty
o come close
now go ahead
the nice factor which the sort of violence doesn't have many terrible violence
you have play something
the exact
well have no where
i just play whatever you want
o i
hurricane hugo
one more time
joseph guilt
the violence resulted by lack of holy
now we get the violin is a little smaller maybe we can can hold one
next to the other
so that you can actually see that they lies the larger
oh my goodness
why did i invite you in the first place
OK so it since ones are not full five
there may not be able to compare the
three of the file if you have violin right
they showed to us
joseph buildings
ah this war is
i only show you some again
hold hold it up to make them
are there
but it's not the full-size instrument so the total debt instrument will be lower on
average than what this was because the strings are shorter but of course the invention
and to within
makes it much harder to make predictions about
the frequencies
get the four forty
i'll have to change the location again i think
now go ahead
see that same which is the result of the violence
you can play something
are you need the music
go ahead
you can you can use to music there's nothing wrong with that
by which your margin is bigger than sorry fails to be one so if
this is if this is bigger than one then  the xi is zero there's no penalty that
corresponds to this section here at the line but as the margin drops below one
you start to pay a penalty which is linear in the amount by which it fails to
meet that target margin of one  so the ideal is here is this margin is
not a margin in the input space but it's a functional margin and so by
increasing the norm of W you can increase this margin but you pay a penalty here so
this is sort of translating the margin into a penalty on the weight vector effectively
so it looks very similar to the to the ridge regression except the rather than
the xis being the squares of the residuals it's this slack variable which is sort
of measuring a loss which is zero if the margin is bigger than one but
then linear in the by which is which is that margin of one so this
is the thing you optimize and I as I say I claim that's a proxy
for optimizing this bound there are other bounds as well as at least three or
four different ways of proving bounds in terms of the margin of of a support
vector machine or combinations of margin and slack variables of a support vector machine but they
all  tell the same story I just mentioned this one cause I'm gonna
bring it up this afternoon and it's the tightest as far as I'm aware so basically this
is a very sort of ruthless in a sense approach it's it's just saying Look
here's here's here's what I want to optimize I want to  get my test set performance
to be good here's the way of measuring it I'll optimize that quantity with the provisor that
I've slightly adapted it so that the optimization remains convex that's why following this line
that you can't see would have not been such a good choice because it would
have resulted in a  non-convex optimization whereas this because it's a convex function convex loss function
does end up with the convex optimization so this is a a quadratic convex quadratic optimization problem
which  one can  solve now I don't want to you know the aim of
this tutorial was to talk about kernel methods and not optimization methods so I'm not gonna
go into sort of say details of how one translates that into
a dual  or  any of the detailed algorithmics around support vector machines it's a whole
tutorial in itself if if if you you wanted to look into that but the
the the long and short of it is that if you take the dual optimization
of this optimization problem you end up with this optimization and suggestively over the variables
alpha rhi which are very very close to our dual variables that we've been looking
at all along there's a very slight difference that they are actually all
positive and they have to be multiplied by the label in order to get what
we were using as dual variables before so there's a slight mismatch between this alpha rhi and the
previous alpha rhis which were just there was no Y I here so just think of
the previous alpha rhi is just alpha rhi times the the label so this is just the
size of it and the label gives the sign so you optimize this again quadratic
convex quadratic optimization and you end up with a solution vector alpha rhi and you
classification is given by this plus possibility  a threshold which you can compute relatively
straightforwardly again you know all of this I don't know if you ever have to do yourself
because there are so many packages that you can download that do this for you
but it's more to understand what's behind those packages so notice that there's a regularization
parameter or actually one  over the regularization parameter in the ridge regression we had the lambda
here with now  gotta C  here but it's a trade-off between these two competing facts
necessarily monotonic so you can get things like this but eventually it so it
still satisfies this bounce so that's all I wanted to say about gradient methods
are there questions about this so than in the last part of the tutorial I'd like
to say a few things on dual methods so so I'll first start with defining duality something
we skipped yesterday and then we look at some cases where actually it's interesting to
solve the dual problem using a first order method for example to apply the proximal
gradient method to the dual and so on so let's start with the definition of the
dual so suppose I have an convex problem and I'll assume that the equalities
and all the constraints are linear for simplicity so you have just linear inequalities and linear equalities
then the dual is  something you can just derive very mechanically the starting point
is to find the Lagrangian of the problem and the Lagrangian is the objective function plus a
weighted sum of all the constraints you make a weighted sum of G X minus H times
the multiplier lambda  a weighted sum of A X minus B times a multiplier nu and if
you collect terms you can write it like this it's F of X plus a linear term
in X and then something that only depends on lambda and nu so that's
the Lagrangian of the problem and then the dual function is defined as the
minimum of this over X so we minimize this over X and then you can recognize
an that conjugate so if you minimize this term over X you can express
that minimum in as a conjugate but unfortunately because we use people use different
conventions in the definition of a conjugate and in the Lagrange dual you get many minus signs
everywhere so the conjugate was defined as a maximum of  a linear function of X minus
F of X here what we mean need is  the minimum of F
of X plus a linear function of X so you have to switch signs to
change minimization to maximization and that introduces all these signs  right so that would be the dual
function it's not a function because you minimize over X it's a function of lambda and nu
and it's also it's concave right it's concave because we know that a conjugate is
convex where we change the sign it also follows directly from this because the
minimum of this over  X will be a concave function of lambda and nu so that follows
from some of the rules we saw yesterday and then the dual problem is simply
to maximize the dual function over lambda and nu with constraints on lambda
dual multipliers associated with the inequalities in the primal problem are must be positive in
a dual problem so then we have the same types of duality results as we had
for conic LP we also always have weak duality without exception the
primal optimal value is greater than or equal to the dual optimal value we usually
have equality if the problem the primal problem   is  convex but you need a technical condition
it's called a constraint qualification and one example is that if the primal
problem is feasible and for example F of X is dome  defined everywhere the domain
is all of then you have strong duality so constraint qualifications are  sufficient
conditions that guarantee strong duality and that are easier to check than just assuming strong duality
so let's look at some examples suppose I want to minimize a norm subject to
A X is B then the dual problem if you just apply the formula would be
the dual function would be minus B transpose nu where nu is the multiplier for
the constraints and then the dual the conjugates of the norm apply to many
minus A transpose nu and now we can look up what a conjugate is of a
norm and it turns out that a conjugate of a norm is the indicating function
of the dual norm ball so it means that this conjugate is zero if minus
A transpose nu has dual norm less than one an otherwise it's plus infinity so
this is actually the conjugate function you get minus B transpose nu if A transpose nu
has dual norm less than one otherwise it's minus infinity and then normally you would
rewrite this problem in a nicer form  you would say that's equivalent to minimizing actually max
maximizing B transpose Z subject to this  norm constraint right so the dual this problem is
maximizing B transpose Z subject  to the an inequality on the dual norm yeah yeah that's just
the convention and there  exist over conventions but if you maximize than you can say
the interpretation of the dual or the main property is that every for positive value
of lambda this gives the lower bound on the primal problem so that's why it
makes sense to maximize its because that way you compute the best possible lower bound you
can construct this way but there are other conventions that are both as a minimum minimization problem
and then that also works but this should be a maximization and this too so
in norm approximation if you minimize the norm of A X minus B then you
see that actually the dual of this would be quite trivial because yes
maximization yeah but I think you still  want the maximization because what I try
to do here is it's actually to maximize this subject to this constraint but
that's a symmetric set so if I change I call Z minus nu I get
this problem with the maximization so this Z is actually minus nu in this problem and
I make use of the fact that this is symmetric so if I change a sign of
nu it's still feasible but I correct it in the version that's online so
often it's necessary if you want to find an interesting dual to reformulate a problem
so if you took the dual of this it would be quite trivial  because there are no
it should be
they can cause
the the
this one
so much
the which
but the to
you know
and i don't
let's come to
because when they
a little
so way
she know
and what about the play
one thing that can come into play
if one
she began
from it
so it's the small world
hard call
like i the
but what about
the like
that the
home again
the you know
for machine learning
OK so
what i'm going to do
just in the interests of time i'm not going to sort of follow the derivation
for the sort of next part of things right so high level
if you remember
if i can get my slides to appear
what sort of backup and remember where we came from in
trying to figure out where we're going
that's where we came from this we had graphical models we said all these problems
are important in practice
spanish a of time understanding this problem linear programming relaxations message passing algorithms and i
just mentioned generalizations like semi definite programming relaxations there's a whole hierarchy of methods there
if you want to learn more i would encourage you to go to you either
one or both of those NIPS tutorials that i mentioned
let's talk a little about these problems
so these are some asian or integration problems
what i'm going to do this algorithm that i just arrived this
reweighted max product this algorithm makes perfect sense if you replace
max with some
and that's what's known as re weighted sum product obviously and there's many convexified forms
of it the people of studied what i'd like to do is to show you
have very similar ideas to what i just did with tree splitting will be allow
me to derive re weighted sum product
one derive three weighted sum product i can sort of go backwards and show you
how you would have gotten ordinary belief propagation ordinary sum product so i'm not really
respecting the history or the history is that you did it freeman wise sort of
this connection for belief propagation first but i'm just in the interests of
making the derivation clear just allow me to flip the history a little bit
jonathan is a good friend of mine so i don't think you'll
OK so
i sort of remember right so what we did when we were doing upper bounds
the ground state or the the MAP problem we're splitting the graph let's say into
and what was key is that this function was a convex function
so this approach will work for any convex function
and what turns out to be useful for this is that the graphical models the
log likelihood is a convex function of the parameters
so we can do the exact same splitting technique on the log likelihood and if
we do that we're going to derive what's known as the reweighted beta problem data
variational problems
so again
let me work through special case some work the special case but
the slide certainly contain much more generality and also the
the lecture notes are posters well side just let's work this special case if you
understand that if you're interested i think you can go off and read about the
more general ones
well look at
our graphical model with binary variables and just pairwise interactions very simple
right and i before when i was maximizing i called this j or l of
text data
well use that shorthand again that sort of the physicists would call that the energy
function of the graphical model
what i now want to focus on i want to focus on this quantity
before i was writing always the one over c and we haven't said much about
these so far i just said that the thing that makes the distribution normalize
what i'm going do is instead of one overs and moving upstairs and take
i put law here minus log of c
but i was going to call it something else i'm going to call the function
field data
so the function of these parameters if you change these parameters you than the number
that you need to normalize the distribution would change
right so explicitly it's it's this function it's
delete even talk about log exp functions
after lunch session
i would be the session chair i'm rich and i can come from the investors
ltd and and the
first order decision will be given by professors when shimmery
and the title of the talk is information geometry and its applications
thank you
and the title of my talk page rather than here
so you promised to do with the topic
but i would object like to forecast of something
the other
what is the information geometry
eighteen thousand
the remaining form of probability distributions
i told about it
what not are you make
in the name the situation
and this the
i don't find it to remain
some think the time
i've got a little bit
and also it can be a lot of applications
i not
not much yet
nothing much put a few
i want to know
about that but i in the
so i guess i'm not that much
but then you know the i'm really looking to
you have to deal with any and all four
the application to the
the system is the CID off that discounting around on around the like
and the reason to something you they have to you
well my nation
the the upper right
so in the model
very simple
for example you can think of
having name mu
so that's what happens to
the two into
one hour and
and i like this
so the thing
the problem is
four come
both in the
how to find out what they done not
we have that in the future
maybe you have a
between two guys and
and so
and of course if not at time to go
parameterized me
probability distribution
you can see the
so mean
the major criterion
this five years
of course the
what i think
think about
the set of probability distributions where the
so please
the rule of law and of course
she is
and according to a
so we didn't really have on this record
the second thing to say i explain the real
we can change the scale of
so i found
two and it was only
the distribution of y
change in the distribution of y
that's the parliament i just in case
be or the
to be equal equal to the speed
so the next
there should not be in
on page p
and i'm sure
it does seem
now that we can have unique
the deal
to be introduced
one made four
parameter estimation
what we really mean it
OK so the
think about that space
probability distributions
and you know what i mean you all
up to point to see
so in essence name
we have a been
the content
this between two probability distributions
i mean why
parameterized by theta and the space that but i have seen
it can be
it is
can be made at the bicluster out
we need to be
this can be transformed into and i am not all
and have
you can extract
there's also
according to queen
to the naked
it depends on conditional fee
we have the called
by hope g i becomes the idea can make it
that the euclidean
however i i think about this
they don't have that
now what
what they call the house
one going you
i mean
that i to think
the think we go by
they find context
what find connection
i mean
OK so we have right
nine called
we have the look and
by quadratic forms
and two hundred yard
however i'm not point we also the
in august
however i mean for the car
so you have to about the after that we see
about so-called
you can see from the data
let me
OK you can fun with all
that they the
i find connection
and typically
it did you have to buy provided and
evaluation and so about for get the second had
and now
we think about jewish
one of the
they so that they need to
directly into the program
so that when you programming
you actually program with police cynicism talking about here and desires intentions
see anybody well i guess is still running control and things like that but the
programming languages so explicitly has these concepts
and you build your agent programs
in terms of these concepts
is in the sense moving to a higher level of abstraction
this machine
come down here
mid-level level programming languages like haskell whatever else and this may be
this job problem whatever also things
and above that maybe object orientated
and above that nineteen
the the
concept the belief is explicitly part of the programme custom syntax and you can apply
to one
other there are
so experiment language
but the the
the i guess the problem is
the the the the this and experimental languages which of course not widely
quite a lot of years
languages that
use this concept fairly widely used
i mean
into this in very weak sense
so that's almost
inspired by the i
actually i actually rather low level
so the take on some of the ideas
and push the bit in that direction but not with
the size you want
in terms of having a widely used language which is really working at this level
the answer is no
are some experimental languages
i'm not going to
find the mind
so there's another phd
some the likely OK alright so
so here's the world
there's not very personal very helpful but at the top level the
one of the BIA
OK so
the solution
which involves getting a percept
from the per cent
presumably ability should change because
something things changed environment
so there is that when you update your beliefs
as a result of that
you may want to update your desires
for example
you may now be aware some that's true which means that i had just waste
of time
you can do you can two reasons they might decide to do that we might
modify something
and then
this more small thinking that goes on amongst the designers you might keep intention had
before changed when you want
and then having decided that intention you want to achieve
it's like an action plan action government again
so explicitly the high-level this mentalistic concepts which are used to guide
the construction of the program
so it's a beautiful idea
but my experience is it doesn't work
right and
the place that doesn't work is is that
is the goal directed this you want
my experience is that
instead of desires intentions to utilize the idea
maybe this would be true forever knight distance to make it work
it seems that based idea rewards so on
has been more successful getting access to work
on the other hand the beliefs ideas really crucial i places not least to the
knowledge base
there's no way you get do that
the others
desires intentions
given the goal directed the what what's trying to achieve
and it's nice
in a sort of philosophical and psychological way
because there's no doubt that we operating like that
somehow when you come down to it
it doesn't seem to work
so that some
politically incorrect anyway
that was my experience
right more things you should be aware of actually some of you down
reinforcement learning course right
yes yes are you got able to slide away
for those who haven't i just mentioned two ideas
so this is just a listing some concepts that you need to be aware of
and the people widely used and IR are
so markov decision processes
i've got a number of components
the state
typically finance estate
X divided by some other polynomial
well this is plus transform of the end so this is all plus transform of
the solution we are looking for so the final step is to go backwards
by taking the universal plus transform of this guy and what will you get what
you get y equals y of t that we're looking for
it's really a wildly improbable procedure in other words instead going from here to here
you have to imagine there's of mountain here and the only way get around this
to go 1st year across the street here and then go back
and go back
it looks like a senseless procedure you know where they are going around Robin Hoods
born with when I was 1 of my school that but that's what we used
to call not that will plus transform that was adjusted to thing we you have
do something like this or that but
but the answer that it's hard to go from here to here but trivial to
go from here to here
this solutions that is the easiest step of
this is not very hard
it's easy in fact this is easy and straightforward businesses
true essentially
yeah trivial
but that is on
this is where you have use partial fractions
look up things in the table and to get back there so most of the
work of the procedure isn't going from here to here going from here there's a
OK now in order to implement this 1 that we have to do well the
basic thing is I have to explain to you
you already know this a little bit of a reasonable amount of take the stating
that you want to recitation yesterday in practice a little bit this part I assure
you was nothing so all I have to do now is explained it is explained
to you take will plus transform differential equation and that really means anti-takeover plus transform
of the derivatives
so that's problem
what voices in other words a formula for plus transform of f prime now in
terms of what was
since there isn't an arbitrary function and the only thing I can hope for is
somehow to express the will plus transform of the derivative in terms of all plus
transform of the original function
so that's what I'm aiming for
OK where we start well starting is easier because we know nothing if you don't
know anything there is no place to start with the definition since I know nothing
whatever about the function of the
and want calculate the plot strands of transformed through it on the start with definitions
so whatever that it it's the integral from 0 to infinity of either the minus
2 times prior to the
now my looking for
I'm looking for somehow transformed so that what appears here is not trying to
which I'm clueless about but at to
because of this war effort
this expression plus transform of f of tea and I'm assuming I know that
so the question is how do I take this somehow do something clever to it
that turns this into FFT instead of trying to
frequency time phase difference immediately reflects also the time difference between those two channels
and actually
basically this low here
represents the time delay
it's not defined for frequency as i mean how do
define a face
face of four four still frequency
actually in this case it was
either zero or one
one hundred eighty degrees
but here is the face displayed i did not display the time
so that's not the band below that's just the face
so and for this reason i think it did not include the picture on the
time difference
probably because of that reason
i mentioned already that there is the problem with what and conduction and that's what
i want is known to be a big issue in in classical coherence analysis
and for this reason koreans was criticized very much and in the in the nineties
colleagues of mine it and eleven class were criticizing coherence and i guess also others
in the world
criticizing her kerkorian's exactly for that reason
and one possible solution that was already proposed at that time is to use partial
but coherence has includes basically the concept that
if you look at the the coupling of clearance between a pair of channels here
one to two and then we look at the behaviour of all the other channels
we can partial out the activity
of all the other channels on that specific area
so what remains is just the coupling peter that's unique to that p of channels
what you see here is that really coherence
was large and almost everywhere here
much of the clearances can not only in specific areas
we see
still have partial coherence but that's not here
but what about something i want to point out here two is that queens is
also symmetric measures
that's budget clients from two to one is the famous has from one to two
in analyzing the coupling between different areas we are not only interested but the two
areas are interconnected but we wanted to know
which channel which area is time which other and whether there's a backlog connection to
one not so the question is whether area one is driving area two
or two is driving one or is it a little with connections in both directions
this could not be
analysed by by the semantic measures but we need some kind of and symmetric measure
and one of the first proposing such kind of
not actually the first about earlier works
going back to to granger and then later in the eighties kbk but something that
was proposed also by article in from russia
kaminski north scott
proposing the directed transfer function
to analyse this coupling
what you see here is that
the DTF
it's it's not symmetric so you can have here coupling that is large in one
actions here in the other direction
this was not the only one proposing something like this
there was a mesh another measure was proposed that the so-called partial directed coherence
it's motivated by using the partial coherence as introduced earlier
but including also some kind of protection information so that we get in or something
and symmetric measure what we see here is
here we have a connection between one and two but no connection between two in
ponce so that's that's clearly not symmetric at all
this is from the coat of parklands machine
proposing this in two thousand one and then the first paper there active actually put
describing also the second kind of the BBC the BBC have
which is defined here
which reflects all the
make sure of the instantaneous causality
whatever that means instantaneous causality is
causality is usually mean something that there is a relationship in time
and if something is reflects that is an instantaneous correlations so
that's the somehow
doesn't fit well well
basically what i will continue to talk about this the PDC in itself
so if you go back to this is to the original model
and look at the various capping measures
the question is
which of the
measures of the coupling measure the suitability to identify the underlying structure of the model
and so
or we can phrase the question is in the way in which the coupling measures
to distinguish between direct and indirect activity
and which
distinguishing between is able to distinguish between being forward and backward connections
and if you if you make and looking at the slightest earlier then you should
be able to answer that question and if if you're looking at this set a
set of
coupling measures ten
only the BBC for free all of these requirements
so so far for the for the for the
background for the theoretically part
we've also
is that so you have an autoregressive process to try to
when the the most
and you could try to estimate this
in the mouth they put it on the head the saturday banged on it and
they tend to pull the levers independently
so what it looks like and they made the claim in their paper that really
doing experiment designed to understand how all the levels in the world works is an
intractable problems like that bayes optimal exploration problem
but maybe can running something like a quick like heuristic write something that says i
don't know what the right thing to do is but
well it would be what kind of make me happy to see what would happen
if i pull this level by itself
but that just i something about this box intrigues me still writing drawn to it
may be that i have a real detail plan about what they're going to do
when they get there but it's still kinda curious about it in the condition with
a solvable the liver spots separately
somehow it just lost its charm the box is no longer find that and so
you could try to explain this with that they know what they seen to know
what they have seen this want to see more than used
so these guys could these are psychology they continue to do all kinds of really
need studies with
kids and learning
kapali going to learn any more
i don't know maybe just can't get funding for growing
and then back to the you know it's already in the literature the cartoon literature
this is this is also deals with the problem of two people explore this is
an xkcd cartoon which have not really show because it's the nerdy is find the
funniest narrator by it's it's ninety and find the same time so the main character
you could tell is the main character because doesn't had the main character walks up
to a podium that has lebron pulls it and instantly hit by lightning
and now he's since standing in front of the podium and now the choice point
i make this terminology normal person versus i this is what's in the cartoon he
said personnel says well i guess i should do that
what a scientist says i wonder if that happens every time which is for the
less so
we're building our algorithms may be a little bit more like this because it seems
like that
the people i know but you know maybe there's something to be said for this
perspective as well
so so just to wrap up i told you about model based reinforcement learning i
summarise reinforcement learning for you and talk about the model based approach i spent a
lot of time talking about quick learning efficient exploration and i hope that that some
interesting because i spent a lot of your time on a little bit about bayesian
reinforcement learning how the difference between near bayesian PAC MDP may actually be really interesting
to think about what's the right
problem to be attacking
and a little bit about planning and how we actually can take the models that
the learner and model based RL setting and use them to make decisions in the
world when things are some inefficient and how this may or may not connected with
people and that was the story that i have to tell you some things like
three times
now it is are lights that can come on to anybody know
co i can be introduced to really bright lights at the back in the shining
right at
episode of star trek i see five lights
i can i can vaguely see websites see the hand standing just just call out
i can hear you
yes no
well yes
so i'm i say yes absolutely yes i don't know that a lot of existing
what does that because they were really keeping track of uncertainty bayesian or in the
black and white quick sense so they just use it as the best guess with
it and have gone off and to try to get better data and make sure
the exploration solved better though sometimes have people
demonstrate the task for them so they get the right kind of data in the
right part of the state space but the algorithms that really nicely with those cases
so in particular like like a UCT learner it can give those exploration bonuses if
get transition state transition that doesn't know well they can a little bit to that
in the plan so that when it comes back and actually tries to act that
derivative of something
with respect to x see the motivation for that if this turns out to be
the derivative of something because i've chosen you so cleverly then I'll be able to
solve the equation immediately just by integrating this with respect to x and integrating that
with respect to X you just integrate both sides with respect to x and equation
is solved now the only question is what should I choose for you well what
I'm this if you would think of the product formula
there might be many things to try here there's only 1 reasonable thing to try
try to pick you so that is the derivative of times Y. see reasonable that
is values the product rule on this in the 1st term is you
times y prime the 2nd term would be you prime times while I well I
got the why there so this will work
works if what is what the condition that you must satisfy in order for that
to be true well it must be that after I do the differentiation you prime
turns out to be P times you
so a clear we want this is something we want to be equal to
and mind the thing I'll try to do it is by choosing you in such
a way that this equality will take place and then I'll be able to solve
equation now so here's what might you prime must satisfy we can solve that but
please don't forget that p is p of X it's a function of X so
if you separated variables here I'm going to do this
so what is it the over u equals P of X times dx
if I integrate that so separated variables integrate
and you're going to get the EU over you integrates to be the lot of
you and the other side integrates to be the integral of p of X T
X and you can put arbitrary constant they're all you can think of it as
you already employed by the indefinite integral well that doesn't tell us that with you
is what should you be noticed I don't have to find every possible you which
works all I'm looking for is 1 all I want is a single you which
satisfies that equation well u equals the integral each to the integral PBX that's not
too beautiful looking but by differential equations can things can get so complicated that by
the you know and a weaker to you will think of this as an extremely
simple formula so there is a formula for integrating fact there we found
we were always be able to write integrating factor don't worry about the arbitrary constant
because you only need 1 such you so no arbitrary constant since only 1 since
only 1 you needed and that's a solution the way we solve the linear equations
OK let's see
take over and
actually do it I think I would be better to summarize is a clear-cut methods
are so let's do that
yeah so on on the system method for solving why pointless p y equals cute
well in the 1st place make sure it's in standard standard linear form if it
isn't you must put in that form notice the formula for the integrating factor
the formula for the integrating factor involves the integral of PDX so you better get
the right he otherwise you some OK so put it in the standard linear form
that way you have the right piece notice that if you in that
and all you remembered was integral
the yearly integral PBX the P. would have the wrong sign that is good right
that the shouldn't have to have a negative sign there
do it this way and no other way otherwise you get confused and get wrong
signs and as I say that will produce wrong answers and not just slightly wrong
answers with disastrously wrong answers from the point of view of the modeling
if you really want answers to physical problems so here's a standard linear Leopold then
finally integrating factor so calculated each of the integral PBX the integrating factor and the
then multiply evolved and I'm putting this system goes to underline that as many times
as you a room in your notes on multiply both sides by
this integrating factor by the EU the integral Pt
and then integrate OK let's take a simple example suppose we sort of the equation
x y prime minus y equals 0
I had excluded execute someone that executed think yet excuse
OK what's the 1st thing to do output in standard form so said 0 will
be to write it as y prime minus
1 over X times Y equals X. squared here to standard error let's do the
work 1st and then I'll talk about sex our well we now calculate the integrating
factor so that
I do it do instead you can integrate
was 1 of negative 1 over X right that integrates to minus log X so
the integrating factor is he to integral of the dx so at each of the
negative log X now in real life that's not the way to leave that was
the year the negative log X will think of it as you need to log
X to the minus 1 or in other words it is you log X is
X so it's x amount so it's 1 over X so the integrating factor is
1 over X
multiply both sides by the integrating factor
o group is the value of the last significant terms and good sentences that just
to send to deceive non correlated start the people and so then if you make
an histogram what you get it is not going to should get the flattest because
you have no no
no timing which is better than the other
so it should be completely flat like that after after after once you have to
get rid of the statistically and then you have something which is going on in
the in the two
you will see the
that's what shall i do not understand which means
this difference and idea not good
so that that's one for the for two d and now i want to move
to the to the ADC
goes work introduction and then what the difference is that you get it questions what
are the different types of another candidate converters
what are the trends in our applications
so is
what he's is doing is that he's just
looking at the
it that you know i don't seem to use it will just text
it will give you a given time
did you seem so we should take thing and seeing what you would get if
the condition is
a world know axis
you can imagine that
what will be important to understand how
besides your sampling
if you sample sale although you get the same results
and then one is also the older jamaican on the measurement so now if you
same signals also we have some political i don't know
you want to make
delta convention so that it means that you want to go detail value in the
to convert to
what you would get out
so it's been actually what this is doing to be seen from this
continuous stuff in between
if you use this that and the quantisation
the addition of an ADC is relationship between the islands and the number of bits
so you've got a
you've got an n bit ADC
and if you if the maximum amplitude that you can get code with and it
is is a then the last significant bit the have this value in terms of
the the maximum divided by two to support and so for instance if you use
it and a bit ADC
you have one world
full scale
you know solution to this one point nine million people the minimum values that you
can measure also
o point about the fulfilment
the maximum quantisation normally should be hyphenated and be divided by two which we use
this kind of noise
so something which
we should not confuse is what is the solution and what is a dynamic range
the dynamics and interaction between the minimum and the maximum amplitude to be measured so
so it can be can be a very large for instance fall
can i met with generally maintain hcs has to be able to measure signals from
ten in the
to two t so that's a lot of sometimes you want to measure also don't
high precision with large
in any kind
in the system so you have completely in system than the
as dynamic and is related to the number of bits for instance if you have
a bit ADC u have two hundred fifty six in any change because you have
two hundred fifty six
possible values
now we can see what you you need to to have a large dynamic range
linear systems cannot be used because
for instance for for this kind of of dynamic and you would need a twenty
one bit linear ADC so something that you can get but not in quantity and
the reason i speed so we cannot use that so what you
what you do that you introduce some nineteen eighty which is that you will you
will not just a linear
compassion but you will
you do some trick is always an amplifier before the CEO the things
so what we have is that you should be confusing so for instance when i
went to a set because
if i didn't detect a sequence depicting going in hcl and in a lot of
that year because of unusual
and and out of of that circuit also and you want to be able to
good morning i'm going to talk about you when the temperature is low but you
want to be able to know that the temperature is twenty five degrees c for
instance we should just take your resolution things that i want to go from twenty
five degrees c to minus thirty with the same is what you wish for
when it's called then you will get very large dynamic range and that's difficult expensive
extent so it's
when any obligation whether it's twenty five of twenty four games you don't get so
so that's important not to fire so in terms of the solutions the there is
kind of between the sampling rate
and the number of bits that you can so
so we have the ability this on this absolute go from six to twenty two
o twenty four
and this is this which saw how you can get the job done so you
want to know
and you see that the higher the frequency the lower the number of bits and
and and then you be found technology
i also want to know that in terms of where the ball is going
is increasing this way so you you can start shooting what
but i when when force law one but if you wanted to get very fast
it's it's of what's which is not always
easy to two hundred that the choice of an ADC we learn is that even
of course by the application that you have you have to know whether you want
to be fast
all extremely precise something in the between
so it's
construct the
ideal things is like that so you have your signal which is just not only
i mean max and then the ADC we just use
the is and in fact we have and that some else
like of sets which can be offset by that you can have integral nonlinearity in
films and on
so the idea that the maximum difference between the best linear fit
that you can do and the and the with the output of the system and
the idea of
in particular so
then there's disease little fluctuations
like that's so if it albeit with a single length scale
and it's trying to do that's actually is you observe more data in in in
the bayesian case peter sollich study this
you're learning curve will be slower but eventually when you see in the data it
will come out with not balance scale but the small in scale and it will
interpolate exactly through the function at the limit of infinite data
but i rarely get given infinite data size and wanna know what happens
in the case where i've got less data and i think i'm gonna give you
any prose but i think the danger is what happens
is you get effects like this
these small fluctuations hear
but you get a global effect like this
so this problem okay you have to account for the noise if you don't have
the right to noise than uh it's
is indicative that your smoothness term
is wrong you're obviously is only smooth verses to what's going on in the function
you only see that's law
it's the it's again this is why i think that the saving grace is normally
you don't see enough data to expose the flaws in your model you only find
out that you decided the system is much smoother is in one day where you've
got a lot of data if you've got sparsely distributed data you don't even discovered
this flaw in the model and it gives you a nice error bars but as
you get data very close together
you get numerical problems the data that you become overly confident about your error bars
because the real smoothness is larger than that's
is real smoothness is rougher the map but you think things are infinitely small you
get at collapsing effect i showed u
an example i showed
any other lecture
that's the end result
after only observing data hear hear
and here there
so the error function that's smoothness was actually correct in this case
you get this collapsing effect even if the smoothness is in fact correct and your
error bars are much tighter than they should be so
gaston processes are a big help but actually one of the problems when you work
with a bit you just push the problem to another level
and the worst things the smoothness you can deal with matern covariance is an rational
quadratic the worst thing is is jumps
if you need to start putting those in as well so then you need a
markov jump process on top guassian process
and they're difficult to deal with so
as you start adding all the components you need someone what you really think is going on
the model becomes much more complex
on and that's a headache for people who do bayesian inference
on the
and i think that's okay
so that's perhaps an area i haven't thought about so much in bayesian learning there's a lot over the
subjective decision so
the statistics community
the bayesians and the frequencies fallen out so much that they don't even go to the same conferences
so because you have to fall out over something and so the bayesians fallen out
over something and what they fall and now it is subjective bayesianism an objective bayesianism
and objective bayesianism
as opposed to objectionable bayesianism
objective bayesianism is when you think that there is a universally correct prior for an
inference problem and that everyone the priors shared subjective bayesianism says well
these things just about believe so where does the prior come from that's a big problem for bayesian inference
and subjective bayesian you've this personal
idea if your prior
which you put down and that's specific to u
so it's still
i would say um
that's interesting
i don't know the answer one possible answer is subjective bayesianism is
pushing everything to be a systemic about all uncertainty ends objective bayesianism is trying to
be aleatoric about all uncertainty i don't know
fundamentally uh
i don't identify worry that much about it
because in machine learning
i think we worry often about empirical performance so
i think the answer to all these problems you know you can spend a lot
time arguing about it the right answer is they have a community where everyone
is looking at similar things talking about and showing their empirical performance on data
so it's an addict and i think it's it's an interesting question to which i
don't know the answer but perhaps the answer for machine learning is um
who cares let's see who wins on them this data
or whatever all in reinforcement learning you know
i think there's lots about from questions there let's see if you can get a
robot to make a cup of tea
and on
on the
right i mean
and the
corresponding of more
all the people
what is the
so you're not these
you ones
are you know just like right
well it's interesting to they actually make an i i d e
empirical risk and was an interesting point
where the idea because what i was claiming
and the you know maybe this reveals a hole in what i was claiming is
that cisco learning theory people don't make an assumption about the noise
um so in our case it's funny to then say that making an idea assumption
but they must be making some assumption in order write the expected loss down must
be where the idea assumptions coming in the
potentially the loss is called
you know
and on
yes in fact that's a good point yes i think one thing that is very
powerful it sometimes it's so we just wrote aom recent review papers for foundations and
which was looking at multiple output covariance functions which some people call multitask learning structured
and it's got million wonderful night but it's using kernel methods and it's used in
i'm guessing processes and myself and my student mauricio alvarez and lorenzo and i should
say mercy and lawrence that most of the work
work hard to pull together
what the statistical learning theory viewer these multiple output covariance functions is and the bayesian
view and what was introduced that's because what philips driving at is that often clear
for bayesian how you expand your model to say the right probabilistic things so
i don't like the term multi-task learning because from probabilistic point of view it's just
a more complex model and in general if i wanna learn across different tasks i
it's an minus one
which is that term there
times q of w one which is this term here times the gas intensity
that's the gas in density for w one
which is one over square root of two pi is the normalized invariant but has
a means of alpha sort
so what's this
OK well the next thing we have to do
it's either fiddle around like mad
or look at this
if you remember one of the things that you did i think in the previous
homework you passed in
you found the band on q
looks like this
that's just the tail of the gaussians distribution tail of the gas distribution
is upper bounded by this
for w one
greater than or equal to zero is upper bounded by a bunch of other things
you find this problem
the other bounds are tighter
this is the most useful bound to the gas in distribution areas
because it works for all w w greater than or equal to zero
and it's exactly w one is equal to zero because you're disintegrating over half of
the gaussians density
it is convenient and easy to work with
but but what that says
is the QR w one one w one is
anything greater than or equal to zero looks very much like the gas density
so the thing that you are doing here is taking one guassian density
and you're multiplying it by another calcium density
and the one guassian density
sitting here looking like this
some scale factor on it it's zero
the other jealousy and density
is here that alpha
it was awful wasn't there was a camera
thank keep my
gamma alpha straight
OK and it looks like this
if you take the product of two gas intensities
the same
amplitude and everything in the same variance
what do you wind up with
what you can go through complete the square you can sort of see from looking
at this from the symmetry of it
the what you're going to get is the gaussians
from there
over two
OK so so these two things when you multiply them
look like this
this has the same variances these two things to
it is centered on alpha over
if you want to take the fourier transform and multiply the fourier transform we take
the fourier transform of the gas you get the gaussians
and then so here we're here we're multiplying
up there in fourier transform space you're convolving and we combine the gas in with
the gas and you get gaussians so when you multiply calcium by carcinogenic get as
we do anything to account for you get to gaussians OK
so this thing
and if you don't believe me just
just actually take these two exponent simply square
and see what you get so the mean is going to be alpha over two
so here you have the term
which is one tale of the gas distribution
senator alpha minus gamma
here you have another one
centered at alpha over two
when you see these two terms
something clicks in your mind and says that sometimes this term is going to be
the significantterms sometimes this term is going to be significant terms and it depends on
whether gamma
alpha minus gamma
is greater than or less than alpha over to
so you can sort of see what's going to happen right white
i hope you can see what's going to happen right away because i'm not going
to talk to you anymore of this and you can you can look at the
notes to find
to find the details but you know sort of see what's happening because because you
the sum of two terms
we're trying to upper bound this we don't we don't much care about factors of
two or fact is the square root of two pi
or anything
we're trying to look at when this goes to zero
when you make and bigger and bigger and when it doesn't go to zero
so when we do this the probability of error is going to be less than
or equal to either of these two terms here these two
alternative so we spoke about
namely when alpha over two is less than or equal to gamma we get this
one of over two is greater than gamma we get this
and this involves using gamma in the right way
so the union bound
is about equal to one
that gamma
OK well that doesn't tell us anything so we said okay
what we're really interested in here
it is as an is getting bigger and bigger
we're spending a certain amount of energy
per input bit
and that's what we're interested in is for shannon's theorem is concerned how much energy
you spend to send the bits through this channel
and this gives you the answer that question
he led log will be
m is the size of the signal alphabet so b is the number of features
namely the energy per bit is just the total energy in these orthogonal waveforms divided
by the way
so that that's the energy per bit OK substitute these two things into that equation
and what you get
as these two different terms
you to the minus p times this
and a to the a minus b
times this chuck
what happens when n gets the
when n gets big holding a be fixed
so the game is
we're going to keep
doubling our
orthogonal set
being able to transmit one more bit
and every time we transmit one more bit we get a little more energy
but we can use to transmit that one extra bit so we use an orthogonal
set but using a little more energy and that are orthogonal set
what this says
is that the probability of error
goes down exponentially with the
either one of these terms
are possible
and this
and looking at the biggest of these terms tells you
which one you want to look at
so any time that be over four zero is less than or equal to log
so you put
to discriminate one with the highest threshold which is the value above which you want
to fire and another one with a very low threshold so so that it will
it will give the as
formation very close to the to the yourself so you see here
what will happen on the signal is that if if it
it's faster or slower you are you are making the timing threshold other less was
he was about this time he found between these two signal is is as low
as possible so the point that that you cannot go
two groups to deal with the we the rule spatial
i have no problem
these are the benefits signals which are of the form so the amplitude times of
if you if you apply a formula like that which is that you take a
fraction of the signal and you compare it with this
the same signal dealer
and you will find that this formula for this expression is
it is
it is it is going is new
it is your for a time which is independent of it because of course have
a huge impact on both sides
so we apply
to make the following so we we take the
we take we have the input signals and we just take a fraction of the
input signal and then we apply this thing which is that we take a fraction
of the signal added always attracted to
the signal delayed and then you can this for any shape you when you have
an negative signals and because the only goes up and the answers your causing is
independent of time so you can
get very good results with with that
and the way
don't is again you have to
to combat
one which is for the i spatial that you want to signal to exceed and
that's all the time in the u
on the one side input delayed
and the other input the
the fraction of those who were signals
equal you will get
a change in the output
and this was used by signal will be phase
with that but it should be independent
the opportunity inputting and you can get quite good performance without which is basically no
time will come when you are you when you have seen going from fifty one
to one hundred again the limitations are coming from a limitation in the second part
the diocese of that you have to compose it follows that but the main thing
is to know that you cannot get real zero crossing where you have to be
just to know always this thing is always oscillating
and of course the simulated probability to that so this effective
mister albert but
so it's a
having if a is independent of the amplitude
then how do we make time so one first met method is to make it
time to amplitude converter so far that you just
but you flop so when was
you would make that you want to measure the time between start and stuff
fire on this floor
and from the stock felicity and
as the number of this flow fire which is between the prime start and stop
you could switch on the rich deposits account with constant around
so if will get voltage
on the capacitor which is
just proportional to the time he found between start and stop
just then
and opened fire with some again if you wish anything and we
you have to have i don't see because you don't want to have the capacity
to be discharged
and you will to energy
kind you can you can get a very good resolution because
there was originally just dictated by the
as a
according to the capacity of the values according to the council six thousand so you
can can be a few people so one solution
a way of making them to digital conversion which was heavily used in the past
is the we send it could argued also what you do is again
you you have the time to
to digital converter that we've seen so here
in addition to the two of them
councils which is the low values and one
which is able to discharge the capacitance and you will discharge the capacitance when you
start conversion
so what you get the output is you this is the time between the spartans
document devoted to the capacitance which is going down and up to
and and then when you start the actually we stopped
MTV's capacitance with
this course council you will get all going down but slower
and then what you do
is that you
you look at all on how much time it takes to go
the value to the also was
which in
combined here and then when you to see all you just start stop shouting the
and and
this scenario is the duration of the
child and you just call to number of clubs during this time since then you've