now i am a little weight wt it was i decided to write this
i can
i can write this
class and then i have by definition of art
i have
indicator function of
why the heck
a mistake
this is my
definition of
up here and the
now i can infer this
securities says
so exploited the
the existence of the inverse
function of the gradient to right now i have
now i have an incremental update
have it your way i inverse
of the
of the gradient i e
and for what they get by applied incremental update and then i think we can
compute the gradient of the result
so you can think of it as the basis
it's the basis
so there is a space in which and comparing in which
this is the space of the weight
and this is the space they used to make predictions
and that is the space of update
which is the basis of this art
which is the space that they use
in which i mean by up
OK and then the
and the gradient brings me
from this base of up this based on
and the interesting thing brings back
so all
i can now
i'm not well equipped to
you do things and hopefully understand something of the behavior
and i do that by
concentrating on the
on the morning of perfection
so complexity
the quality
support to very well here
and there is lots of nice properties that we can build on
so now i'm i'm interested in this but they here
i'm writing
just to make it clear
this is what i mean by by that just to be concrete
now it is nice to know that
if you take this to the inverse i want to get the gradient
of q
you see when working with great
where q
is the norm of the
the dual in the
of their
so it such that one plus plus one of the few
it but the one
so in case of equal to
remember people with common
bigger equipment
in case of equal to
the euclidean norm is set to one
either a i get the you w zero
last this thing where there
this thing sums up once the summer
and we only look at those times where the mistake happened this thing some of
the number of mistakes which i decided to be no with the
one the first year
this is the number of mistakes the number of times begins recounted just by looking
at the time
we're mistake occurred because in india that nothing happened and then
i can
here can be generalised because there's a mile
give me just because there's a minor and summing up over all things
but this is the indicator function for summing over all but it's fixing all this
says that how many mistakes happen over all and here's summing over all these
and i have no idea not LP u
this is the
you know it's there
so this is the cumulative hinge loss of u
i have something that contains number mistakes cumulative hinge loss
this inner product over there
so you see the difference is the number of states and this community hinge loss
which is an upper bound on the number of mistakes of you
so now
i finish shop
very quickly
by looking at
an upper bound on the on that on december fourteen
and i
work out the upper bound
very simply that out from again you p
that the
i think i should have that the former big the i understand how things go
so when i went to the occurrence they start from the
which is not transport by the end of the war my way all
the way down to zero
genetically little
OK now let's let's look at the other side
if you look at the other side of the square it's easy use question sure
to upper bound inner product norm
and then we work with the squared norman because we like it better
and you can weeks we expand this using
the at the rules
you seem
and then we just take the
expand the sum of the squares of some
then we just observe
that this thing is going to be negative
this quantity here
the margin
this quantity over here is the marginal
all of that depends on the current example and assuming that the that on the
that the aggregate percent made mistake and the mistake was made the margin had to
be negative but negative so we can lower bound upper bounded by
the recurrence terms
squared norm of x
he OK
OK now we are almost there
so now
i again we by the recurrence
spend the recurrence and so we get that generally get there
we can write it this way
so we have
bill insisting on those that were mistake happen so we expand the recurrence as many
times as many state
but this is
and we
we have this back this
that first year the multiply the mistake indicator function and we take the maximum
cool so now we know that this is the wrong
because they start from the iraq and we also know that this is the right
now we have a nice
the nice upper and lower bounds on the same quantity that takes into account the
mistake indicator function
and the law so we have a square here
we focused square here so we have adjust for the squares but we can we
can of course to solve the this
now if you saw before this what you get
this is the correct action court
thank you
right otherwise it will be a natural or these have proven that is the lower
because correctly
good now we saw
and we have the second equation was always get this bound here
some of the
so on but i don't know how much the function is going to vary within
the period
and actually when i think more about it i'm not sure appears like strictly periodic
is right right because could be that these periodic things actually look a little bit
different in the fifties than they do in year two thousand
that's it seems likely to me that could happen to multiply that by not term
here so if multiply two covariance functions again the covariance function or multiply that together
with the with another question to term which is just going to say well if
the point is are too far away from each other than that the covariance decay
writers joanna decay term say this strictly
periodic if x is close to prime
but if x is very close to very far away from ex-prime then maybe it's
not the same period maybe you forget about the correlation of very long legs and
i don't know what the length is
because there's no problem
OK so
i also when i
let me just so i also i also see that there some this on so
looks a little bit irregular like this a little bit sort of peak here and
this sort of funny trough here right so this seems to be an irregularity at
maybe a much
lower spatial frequency or maybe add lots of frequencies
i don't really know
rational quadratic
sounds like the right thing here so i don't know what they what the magnitudes
of that i don't know what the
what the alpha parameter is i don't know how many length scales that you've been
there and i don't know what the typical length scale of those is either so
there are no free parameters
and then lastly i have i have noise model so i would say well actually
i don't believe that my that my prediction will be right on the target there
might be some measurement noise here so i have an independent noise model with
variance here beta eleven and maybe also there will be some some short-term correlations in
the noise right because it might be so these are measured and how why somewhere
and it might be that you know the the weather that month you might influence
things and maybe if there's been a lot of storms this month you know might
be might be similar well the next one maybe there is little correlation could say
well let's also assume that for some very small lengthscale you also have a little
bit of extra call asian it could happen
so now i just write down my covariance functions to some of these contributions and
have eleven unknown parameters here
and my my
my total covariance function just be just going to be the sum of these different
the weights are just parameters for fight each of them has a primarily telling you
how strong is that contribution
one great OK so
when i use my i use my
my own little optimisation code and it doesn't understand constraints
so basically i square these things too
to make sure that even if my parameter that i can do
unconstrained optimization basically just a tiny tiny trick
actually what i actually what i do is i i i parameterize these by their
by the logarithms instead
so so slightly lying to you about exactly how this is done but you can
do little transformations of these like it doesn't really matter right at the end of
the day
we just interested in what this value is what you just have to have some
something to represent like i wrote square here because actually variance
all right so now you might say well
this all looks very well but this is a bit of a nightmare right because
i have a hugely complicated covariance function with lots and lots of parameters and this
will take me a long time to write down the program to do this
but during the fortunes situation that i read it
so if you
used to package that you also used in the in the practical sessions very
there little package that has the language for specifying covariance functions
so now i've loaded in my my data here
and the next thing i do is i
specify migrants function
and in this tiny language the covariance function is pretty much just lifting exactly the
these specification onto this so i think there are four different contributions here k one
is in this means
covariance functions also always start with c of e and this is squared exponential
isotropic does matter because only in one dimension doesn't the not next time here is
the current product of two terms one is quite exponential in one is periodic
and so on and so forth and my covariance function is just the covariance some
of these four contributions
OK so you can very easily specify things like that
and now what we're do now i i minimize the i find optimal hyperparameters so
i minimize the the marginal likelihood and it's computed by a function called TPR thousand
process regression
and here's the optimisation running on my very slow and clunky
that up here and i told it that he can evaluate the function for twenty
times OK this may be a little bit optimistic if you have eleven parameters so
in an industrial application i'll probably running for a few iterations more
but here in the interest of time
and then optimize in this space over these eleven parameters
in math the one thing about that is useful to follow the rules
so you posted
if x is the zero vector is supposed to take
there are over here
with y for you always get
so we're all
the zero vector is orthogonal to every
what i wanted
what i now want
think about it some
what does it mean
for me to say
that sums of space is orthogonal to some other
OK i've got it right this is where the five
definition of some
a team
i got a couple of days
and what it means for those guys to be or
it's just not sort of what the natural extensions
orthogonal vectors two orthogonal subspaces
and in particular
let's think of some orthogonal subspaces like
this law
i say in three dimensions
so the blackboard extended
to infinity right
playing a two dimensional subspace
it's a little
one but anyway
it's thinking that subspace
let me take the floor level
great stone face
and ninety on the billboard
so so
and of what they are doing right here
so the origin of the world
is the right
thereby giving linear algebra its proper important
one thousand place there's another one the war
are they are
what does it mean
producer prices to be orthogonal and that case are they are right
fifty percent
what does it mean meet
after that know what would
thank you all for coming
let me recap what we did last time
we started talking about source coding also known as data compression
we've been looking at toy examples
one example of redundant file first compress this is something is mainly zeros with just a few ones scattered
random so we at the bent coin
how should we can compress the file like at
well when you think about compression the claims were examining are shannon's assertions that's if you take log
base to
one over the probability of an outcome that's tells you
how much information content the outcome has got that's how long the message ought to
be associated with the outcome in bits as well as speak ideal message length
entropy which is the average of the shannon information content is claimed to be the
right way to measure the average information content
the third assertion that we've got and that we have sort approved last time is
the source coding theorem which says that if you get a very long string around
comes from
a random source identically distributed
then those outcomes can be compressed into roughly ten times the entropy bits
so we sought prove last time we have
did this
proof by counting the typical set we didn't actually do a general proof that's in the book
but what we did is we looked at the special case of the bent coin
where you toss it and times and get
many zeros and a few ones
hand there we all know what the typical set is you expect a get
if it was bent coin with bias if ten percent expect ten percent ones and
the typical set of strings is all the strings that have roughly ten percent ones
so in general
what the typical set means and this a defined concept
if you get a string and an independent outcomes from a source that's string
it is very likely to be in a typical set
the typical set elements all have roughly the same probability as each other
there are two to the end times the entropy
of them so the rest of the proof of the source coding theorem is well
just given aim teacher these guys
the number names
you'll need is to be an times the entropy so the length always will be and times entropy
and they incidentally all got roughly the same probability as each other which must therefore
be to to the minus end times
the entropy
so let's be
rough outline of the proof that the source coding theorem for general source and we did before the bent coin
looking at a long string of and
now comes hand the way we found ourselves at the proof was we imagined playing
the bent coin lottery we wanted to
win the lottery for the mafia boss
how much of his money did we need spend which tickets would be by
we found that big sackful of tickets and then we imagined writing new name for
each ticket on the reverse ticket we counted the number of tickets in the back
and we find had to trillion times entropy
so that's what we did last time i was a proof of the source coding theorem at least four
the bent coin
when i said the number of tickets in the bag is due to be end
times in is to the end of it
to to be
and timestamp plus a little bit
and that's a little bit is that with the fluctuations around these
thee mean that the typical number of old ones
and those fluctuations goes square root event where end is these length of three
the string so they get relatively small
compared to
this is the main term and age to
at his just a picture reminding you what a guassian distribution
looks like and you can get the probability
as small as you like the probability of failure as small as you like just
by adding a few extra square root events
a few extra standard deviations
maximize conditional
likely head
rather than the joint
that gives significantly better results
is the approach that taken
and i want to get to a rule based approach is so
for rule based undirected models
we have
some of the
work here
we had to mark
earlier in the conference
the approach is
we're going to
have a collection of formulas of first-order logic
and were associated with away
and together with this
at least in the basic set up a finite set of constants it defines a
markov network where
you have an grounding for each predicate in the MLN
and a feature for
each grounding of each formula f
in the MLN with the corresponding weight
as an example
if we have
the following set of rules so
we have
and whether or not there
the paper is high quality
whether or not
papers accepted
we have some information about
saying that
co-authors are
likely to be
have equivalent smartness
the definition
they were given the second
alice bob and p one
go through and
we instantiate
all of these
and make the following connections
this is the
underlying markov network
the underlying markov network has
these weights associated with it and now
do in france
and this
combination of doing
what i showed on that slide which was the
knowledge based model construction
together with
max what that
mcmc sampling
we're doing inference
inductive logic programming and likelihood discriminative training for doing the learning since then there's been
additional work should allow
you to put in
we have one an expert here
the only
so then
four discriminative training of ML and we have the
world expert here so
and i should say that there is the
the code for
and alliances available alchemy there's a pointer obviously from pedro domingos this page and also
there's the chapter and
the book on
and lands and there's
i think code and data as well available there
and so
OK to summarize
we have undirected approaches that can cannot
focus on this
symmetric non causal relationships
they support this collective classification
someone asked earlier what about combining these
approaches combining in undirected approaches and directed approaches at this point i haven't really seen
anything that combines them together i would say
there is a line of work on directed
unnormalized approaches
and those are
idle i let nature decide in a random way
one of the semantics of that
there's the same picture and one thing i can read off for example is this
so let's take e you know in the DAG
a variable is conditionally independent of all its non descendants given its parents haven't got
everything is an understandably so is independent of everything what parents it's got to stochastic
parents cindy and one regime indicator parent if
so conditional on those independent of everything else
that's what the dog is one of the things that i guess telling me
let's think about what i said well first of all
there are three the three possible suppose there all binary there are three possible values
for FEV if i put a fetus a zero then i'm setting it to zero
and it's got one point distribution that's that's not telling me anything i didn't know
a one point variable is independent of anything
no uncertainty so the only case where this bites is when f e exactly the
regime were not intervening on e
so in so i'm not in manipulating e and this is think about this conditional
distribution given c and d
when i haven't said a bit on the lower right around and that says that
independent of a and b that something when you from regular probabilistic tag
given CNT but also is independent all these other indicators
so it's not only independent of the values that a and b
it independent of whether any one of the variables for variables a b c and
d with set by me by nature
there's so many different regimes in which they come about which some combination of these
were set by the experimenter and others were just allowed to arise random and being
left to nature
so a whole lot of different regimes and i'm say that any one of those
regimes no matter whether intervention or observational this modular distribution the distribution of e given
c and d
is going to be the same
irrespective of how intervening all those things so that how pearl interpreters tag
it's beautifully represented i think when you put in these indicators because then you just
use the standard conditional independence semantics of dies and you see these things are properly
represented you don't have to write an extra story about them
described because there already is
buried in the DAG and you can dig them out
so the basic idea once you've done this is that every parent child distribution so
he given c and d is like a modular component it's constant across no matter
how i'm as long as i'm not actually fiddling with the itself
then that parent-child distribution is always valid no matter how i mean to be aware
my interview that means in particular that if i just take an observational regime simply
observe all these variables and work at the joint distribution
i could of course work out these parent-child distributions
i don't know exactly what happened in any kind of intervention regime because they are
fixed the only so
whenever a variable is not itself intervened on it just has one of these marginal
distributions that i've taken from observational data where it is intervened on well i know
what's happening anyway because i made it happen so i got the whole picture
paul pearlian DAG still with point interventions
so that's what we talked about so far
you just take going to a variable and you pointed out to value and you
assume that you've been successfully
and it takes on the value
and the whole that thing then suggest indicates how effective that will trickle through the
whole network because i can put that in and see what the overall distribution is
of any other variable
but it's interesting to think more complex kind of intervention so imagine there's your treating
a patient in hospital and over time
you are
observing various symptoms and measurements and signs on this patient temperature whatever
and then over time you reacting to that in deciding on a sequence of treatments
to give
and ideally at each point to look over your shoulder the history of the page
and look at this chart see how we've been doing and use of that information
to decide what to do next so very
toy example of that is where
there are two possible actions that can be applied to the patient a one a
there's an l is some you can observe on the patient so
so here am someone is you you inject so many ECC's some
and then you can observe
some response so much the blood can go down something like that and then the
next day on the basis of that information in my take no action
now i'm going to talk about various treatment strategies you can imagine a hospital drawing
up a plan of various treatment strategies that you might want to try out on
patient says if the additional blood it
so so
a one depends on treatment strategy that says that you know you look down what
might be pointing on the random thing just give so many cc's of of this
and did you could you could vary how many you give according to the strategy
and a two
well also the the dry the treatment you give the next day
well also
it will be determined by the strategy but slightly more complex way it says if
you observe you've given so many ceases of the drug and the blood count going
down below such level in that case you give so many more good at some
complicated formula which is the light both these values
tells you what to do so you can imagine trying to assess treatment strategy
try to understand this is what would be the effect of bringing the strategy in
on the response y
there's another variable you may have noticed looking up here you this is an unobserved
so extra variable and there is a slight problem here in that the data i
guess i just going to the hospital
and it's not putting any strategies into effect the doctors are going around doing whatever
they want
OK what do you think is the interesting thing that doesn't depend on
exactly so that
the size of the output space doesn't really show up right
problem as it could be kind of infinite we don't know
but i mean we assumed its here in this argument right but it can be
arbitrarily large it doesn't show up here
so that is encouraging because it basically means right that even as we get to
very large
output spaces
you know we will this algorithm will still terminate after a finite number of steps
finite beings
small not dependent on the on the
output space cardinality k
now of course
we will not be getting so
you know i'm not claiming that we will be getting correct solution
we will be getting an approximate solution and the solution is approximate in the sense
that there will still be lots of constraints probably that violated just a tiny bit
right so that's important to know and then
you can
you so basically the solution that you will be getting is feasible right it's because
it's violating lots of constraints its solution to relaxation but you can actually
you can basically imagine that afterwards you just include increase your slack variables a little
and basically then you get sort of feasible solution right now then that is no
longer the optimum right now you get a feasible solution but not the optimum but
optimum you know somewhere in between writing the solution of the relaxation and the
projection two
the cimple project into a feasible solution by increasing this fact variables just by it
any questions
and this i have i have little justice get share of the theorem and some
lemma ten propositions from the paper that hopefully i don't have to look at but
if you're interested in what the ideas of the proof it works as follows the
case of the dual objective right so we have the primal problem in the dual
problem maximizing the dual we minimizing the primal
we know for this time for these types of convex quadratic programs that there is
no duality gap basically at the optimum of the solution of the primal and the
solution of the dual they both the objective functions will be the same so
the primal will be an upper bound on
the dual objective OK which is upper bounded by n times see that trivial upper
bound to just get by using zero weight vector right so the norm of that
is zero and then know you violate all margins by one OK so
alex set to one
and then you get and time c
OK it's just it's just an easy way to get an upper bound on the
prime and the prime is an upper bound on the door so this is also
an upper bound on the cases work with this very simple upper bound that the
dual cannot be bigger than n times c
what we show that furthermore is that each variable selection for and violated constraint
will increase the dual objective by some minimum and a minimum that is really bounded
from zero and it depends on epsilon OK so basically
whenever i choose the constraint
that's violated enough
and i included
the duo will go up by
something that is not in our attorney small
step by step that like can bounded away from zero
and that's kind of not too hard and this is a little bit hidden here
right so you can look at things of what is the gradient or the
of the dual projected into a new direction that you optimize anyway and so you
can you can figure out if you include another valuable corresponding to another constraint in
the primal
they include another very well in the door and you're allowed to optimize over that
much we actually game like how much would you go up and then the argument
is very simple right you you need to estimate the step size and you have
a total
and now
you know just divide the total by
so it's great once you've demonstrated once you have proven that this parallax works then
of course you can always use it to your advantage
notice that the moment of inertia
rotation about this axis which is not sourced centre of mass
is always larger than the one through december
if you have this and the great
always larger
there is a second theorem
sometimes comes in handy
and that only works when you deal with a very faint objects
and that is called the perpendicular
if you have some kind of a crazy object which of course we will never
give you will always give you square rig if you disk
but it has to be offended played otherwise the perpendicular axis theorem doesn't work
and suppose
i'm rotating about an axis perpendicular to the blackboard to that point
i call that the c axis sticking out to you that the positive axis
i can draw now any x y axis
well i please at ninety degree angles anywhere in the plane of the blackboard
i think one year
like all these acts
and i think one here
and i call that y
so c is pointing towards you remember i always choose a
right-handed coordinate system might x crosswise y is is always in the direction of the
i always do that
so you see that here
o extras y equals
now you can rotate this thin plate
about this axis you can also rotating about an axis
you can also rotate about the axis
and then the perpendicular axis theorem which you book processing of just a few lines
tells you that the moment of inertia
rotation about
this axis here
is the same
at the moment of her moment of inertia for rotation about x
the moment of inertia for rotation about the axis y
and this allows you
in combination with the parallel axis theorem to find moments of inertia
in case that you have thin plates
which rotate
about axes
perpendicular to the plate or sometimes not even perpendicular sometimes
you can use if you know this you know this you can find that
so both useful and i in assignment seven i'll give you a simple problem so
that you can apply the
perpendicular axis theorem
there are
applications where energy is temporarily stored
in a rotating disk
and we call those this fly wheels
and the rotational
kinetic energy
can be consumed at a later time
so it's very economical
and this
rotational kinetic energy can then be
perhaps converted into electricity or in other forms of energy
and i really remarkably inventive
an intriguing ideas on how these
can be done
of course whether this practical depends on always emboldened sense
and to what extent it is economically feasible
but i have always even when i was a small boy i remember when i
was seven years it already occurred to me
all this heat that is produced when cars slender weights
all you're doing is
you produce heat you lose all that kinetic energy of your
linear motion whether somehow
that couldn't be
used in a more effective way
and this is what i want to discuss the issue now
and see where we stand this is actually being taken seriously by the
department of energy
so i want to
work out was you a
one example of a car
which is in the mountains
and which is going to go downhill
and the mountains are very dangerous
zigzag roads and so he can only go
she can only go very slowly
and then the maximum speed that
a person could
uses at most ten miles per hour
without killing
in more self which is about four meters per second
so here's your car
let's assume you start out
with zero speed and let's assume that the mass of the car will get nice
it just one thousand kilograms
so you example down this road
let's assume that the
height difference
h was given the number five hundred meters
you're right here at point p
and you later have to go back up again
what is your kinetic energy
when you reach point b
you have the speed of four meters per second
and she went down
you've been breaking all the time
one way or another you got rid of your speed
and that's all burned up the theory of the universe
so when you reach point b
you can edit energy at that point is simply one half MV squared
and is the mass of the car
but it is five hundred
i'm sixteen square so a thousand jewels
now compare this
with the work that
gravity the in bringing discard
that work
is MGH
MGH is staggering number
a thousand
times ten
times five hundred
that is five million joules
and all that was converted to heat
using the wakes it actually even gives you also wear and tear on the brakes
so we need is that perhaps way
that you can salvage did or maybe not all of it
may be part of it
and the answer is
there are weights
at least in principle there are ways
you can install
the disc new car which i will call them to fly flywheel
and you can convert
the gravitational potential energy
you can convert that to kinetic energy of rotation
in your flywheel
and to show it is not completely absurd
i will put actually in some numbers
suppose you had a
this in your car
which had a radius of half a meter
that's not completely absurd that's not
beyond my imagination that
the sizable this
and i give the modest mass
sort of the mass of the car is not going to be
too high
two hundred kilograms that's reasonable that will be still played only five centimetres thick
that's quite reasonable
and the moment of inertia of this this if i rotated about an axis through
the center perpendicular to the disk
moment of inertia we know now is one half of the capital and
are squared
and that equals twenty five
units kilograms if you're interested
meters script
so we know the moment of inertia
now what we would like to do is we would like to
convert all this
gravitational potential energy into kinetic energy of the disc
think of a clever way you can couple that people have succeeded in that
then you really would like
one half
omega square
we would really like that to be
five times ten two to six two
so that immediately tells you
what omega should be for that disk
you find and if put in new numbers which is trivial
you find that omega
it's about six hundred thirty two
radiance per second
so the frequency of the disc
it's from the
hundred revolutions per second
i don't think that is particularly
so as you will come down the hill
i implicitly defines a mapping function
but do not need to bother i never know what the mapping function is i
don't care about it OK
it implicitly does it OK
so i'm saying about representation of that data can be achieved particularly for not separable
by mapping across the high dimensional space and that's why mapping function and what i
must do is mapped a dot product OK
know we're not being not necessarily five
there is there's an assumption be talking about
going to do it this way i going
x goes to phi x
there is a requirement for me to be able to do that
one requirement
or automatically is a space map into must have adopted so must be an inner
product space
and must actually be pre hilbert space indeed
because of the conductivity is a hilbert space which was defined earlier
so there are restrictions on the space can map into so i can't have total
the reality in doing that have a high degree flip liberality as point actually
OK but
o to convince you can do this mapping the mapping functions fi
and i've just said this high dimensional spaces in general to call the feature space
and must be a hilbert space because there must be a concept inner product can
in some places they actually could be pre hilbert space OK in the product space
but i would just say help space
what is the mapping function just said you don't need to know
what it is because
this match
dot product the subject here
all set equal to the kernel kernel will just be
the mapped
data that x is OK
now i can define
by defining those kyle's i'd implicitly define a mapping function
but i do not need to know what a mapping function is in some simple
cases like if i do a polynomial time mapping i can actually work out what
phi is generality i don't know what it is i don't care either because it
provided some restrictions on the choice of kernel
then then it's all OK
so what is the mapping relation as a here in fact we do not need
to know the form of this mapping
because is implicitly defined by the choice of kernel
like that
yes it's it's some sort of what is function functional
a function which maps my data one one to some that high dimensional vector
in some sort of unique way OK
i don't know
yes data
i data is mapped according to functions
five acts to this high dimensional space
a lot of people get disturbed and i really need to know what the phi
is i'm just saying
that no because
the i don't have total freedom of choice about what kernel there are restrictions on
coming onto shortly
i suppose i define my kernel to be the subject here
x one x two
is equal to gaussians
OK have premature and talk about later
but if i choose that is why kernel
they're implicitly defines what the phi is
but i need to catch
one is OK
now there are various choices for
kernels OK
i'll give you a typical example of the kernel
and also the restrictions that apply to kernels
if i choose this kernel
this is a good choice usually often uses the colour cast in co
michael an RBF kernel
this is one choice popular choice
another type of kernel might choose might be a polynomial OK
the lights source
other popular choices
now when you notice if i choose a kernel
and this again as RBF time kernel
indeed what i'm doing is implicitly
giving you an RBF network probably heard of RBF networks
if i choose a polynomial kernel
i'm give by some statistics
another choice and go for really use actually even give it is attention choice for
so there is that it is divided by the sum of the desert is
and i thought those
and i'm going to use those values in my computations when i do radiation
so this is what we do here
and regarding the rewards which is really the rewards
with that's it
don't have to do anything and then we call the iteration
so the iteration is going to be around for kentucky iterations to capture that he's
going to be tuned in some way
and on this
the discrete problem having and and
the discrete states
and the transition from this therapy had nice computed situation
so far so good so
we are going to get some values
at those spots right so value iteration is going to return us
value function that is defined for
finite problems
so we discretize the problem
we computed let's see
a good approximation of the optimal value function for this this that problem
now the question is what's next
so if you want to
like the first thing that you might want to try it just to see if
you can break the curse of dimensionality
just to compute some values and some other parts of the state space
because that's required
if you
so you don't forget we are not interested in the values at this point of
interest and the values
anywhere in the state space
so you pick some other value
sorry you pick some other states in the state space and you are interested in
the value of that so what do you do
you just do one step further by iteration so this is what you do right
so this is the game
the same idea
fusing weighted importance sampling
and these are the values that we have computed so far
OK so this is the value function return for the discrete problem here
so that we live in in input is very
just do this
approximate about one of the right
just a single look at computation
and so that's going to be the value that we return that state
and the question is if this is going to work
so let's assume that the state space is just the unit call q for the
sake of simplicity action space is finite
and to be on the safe side
let's assume that p and r are lipschitz continuous and bonnet so this is kind
of the same set of and the piece that was considered
by showing and tsitsiklis in the lower and
and then run proves
if you do the computation
but the previous are given and the desired
at a certain state taxes denoted by greek the
so and that's
and you can disagree on the difference
this aspect of the state space and an expectation of that and then this is
bonded by an expression that looks like this
so what you see here for the good news and the very striking feature of
this is
is that the
dimensionality doesn't appear in an exponent right
that c constant is that so that's probably dependent then let's talk about that later
but the dimensionality is just appearing in a linear manner
so this is really good news so
it seems that these are given six keeping the curse of dimensionality
the other side this is denoting the number of actions so if you have a
the i just use this model is not patient in the north the number of
elements of the set so that
the size of the actions at least part of
five four four
and you get the stopping this was usually you see one over one minus race
to some
the the entrance to the good news is of course that the is going down
two or zero if you include is the number of samples
so that it does not superfast but it's good enough so it's not one over
squared off and that would be
the rate of montecarlo it's somewhat slower but seems to be OK
so it seems that there is no curse of dimensionality
can go to the beach
OK so
quite a few questions so
this is going to so why is history so can we have result for planning
OK so now i have two
look up if i opened
i opened the representation so i two two actions of this presentation so i have
some slight
there's nothing the printed proceedings
for good reasons because that that's agrees
i'm going to use to test your knowledge what you want
my name is that all the time will be used in the
in nineteen
there you see
you use the shares
four presenting my work
is related to these this machine learning techniques
we study the summer school
my you might want know
falls which very by
more on the on the back
so so i think it's very interesting for
at least some of the people in the audience to see
as many as possible of
thirty years of research
such different techniques are used
so my my searches old standing
the motion so replacing the emotions human emotions based on the
on the environment on the current site so kind of context of emotion recognition what
does it mean when
imagine that
we should also have some
it is
through which we get different the information from the one so we we can communicate
with the environment and what we also get
feel so we provide information get information so
if we think vision and a new what it is
i don't know
such an
and assume automatic approach for
emotions would have take into account this kind of projects so
basically we need to revise emotions from the problem of human emotions from one video
well and secondly we have to utilize emotions from most speech from the of
this would be the
some of the areas
such automatic systems for recognizing emotions b
very useful after sonication said control
solicitation access control sort of
so there are no
you will be
the human interaction in washington nationals
user friendly
o interfaces interfaces are are are are one
so know that
this is another project b
what was it
it was the
behaviour of fulfilling the in the same way as something the behaviour of the drivers
while driving the car also the behaviour of what
to the
the army
when the behaviour of such and such by this was that it already
earl behavior that might be made according to individual
OK so
i was trying to do all the state of the much
these the most important it would be
one of of
our approach is for last
was in favour of fish expressions
for from the things
a face detector is
o thing
one sequence of people
there a step by step frame by frame coalition
it is necessary
for each frame
this kind of
so far does
i wanted so far
the faces
are needed to be
detected so the location
the size
for each face possible future
artist is exactly
for the models
i i've on and then
this this approach i mean
this is that what we don't stand four four o
of faces more than there are some
some some landmarks some points on the face key points on the face
based on those
points on the location the action vision expressions can be normalized
it's the same thing
from the
i i think the point of view the technologies that use
it right the use of force
the original features
the size twenty four one four
if we have to get all the
one seven four o for the entrance to just be to have the size of
the DB size one hundred
sixty two
thousands more than these features
so i think it's a very very big so of features
speaking about this
the religious features
they are quite
efficient there's
having started his recently and i consider the issue
to here and that will be in the original canonical form and i said so
there's just slightly simpler to get here with i want to completely fill the screen
with three parameterizations but you can take this is homework for yourselves and see that
yes you can easily get the by two and the by two in each and
then we're back with unit directly with omnidirectional line
OK so there is this limitation on regularity so we should probably worry about this
we should go back to the problems that we were thinking about yesterday
and ask well actually do those problems meet the regularity
conditions so for example we have the icing prior
on binary variables neighbouring binary variables here so
that satisfy the regularity condition or did not
or you reckon remember the
think about the off diagonal cost that cost when
the two neighbours different in the diagonal cost off diagonal cos got beat
the diagonal cops seven a
all the diagonal cost here when the two neighbours
the same have the same label
i'll cost
what it in this
zero isn't just zero because it xk and co-founder equal cycle cost given easier what
about the off diagonal cost
what are they
one gamma or whatever
so the and provided cameras positive
he was in our original models
then the off diagonal costs of each gamma i also zero so
some of the optimal cost to go in the summer i dug across is zero
and two gamma is indeed great here
here we can use the ising model
without fear of reprisal what about the was the more elaborate
ising model you remember the one that has
costs modulated by
contrast so now we the contrast you this is this was when the prior
because the icing was surprised i got messed up by bringing data into it which
means it's not really a prior anymore
and so now we have this modified so what about this one
does this meet the regularity condition or did not
what you think
we take a vote on it
and we think it doesn't meet the regularity condition
how many think it does meet america
and the constraint on this voting process which is that the sum of the s
is in the nose has to equal the number of people in the room
so how everything no
it doesn't make
think yes
i know her and i think that this is you know to state problem not
well because it because i mean this term here just has the effect of modern
modifying gamma
four you know on the site by on five basis
and since this exponential still positive
then it's it's as if i had a gamma kk primed inside the
the sum here that would make it
so yes it still find it was done in good shape
OK so
we will come across problems where there are interesting and whether submodularity condition is not
met yet
is this a well
the ferromagnetism is
captured by this energy
and then and this energy we now seen is
submodular any
i think you know it could mean using using energy is the energy represents a
mathematical ferromagnetic any ideas about i as a physical paramagnetic to do some more fancy
things but you know this is a mathematical idealisation of experiments
so now a little variation on the theme remember
how we did segmentation earlier and
resisted the temptation to see
the image is here in the segmentation
so is a try map style
and you do the segmentation you get ahead
with some of the stuff and remember previously with the the guy who was playing
the rows of A. and this
3 by 6 matrix have 6
and components of the the column spaces in R &
and the null space of A transpose
I see that this force space is already getting
2nd goal
second-class citizen treatment it doesn't deserve that it should be there it is there and
shouldn't be squeezed
the null space of A transpose
well if the null space of had
vectors with components the null space of A transpose will be in R and I
want to draw a picture of the 4 space
OK area therefore space
the but
OK let me put
n-dimensional space over on this side
which were the subspaces in R and the null space was
and the row space what
so here we have the following
can I make that picture of the row space
and can I make this time a picture of the nullspace
that's just meant to be a sketch to remind you
that very on this
which is at the heart of what
type of vectors are unit vectors with component
over here in that in in society
consisting of vectors with an components is the column space
and what I'm calling the
null space of A transpose those are the ones with an example
to understand these spaces is are is our job
because by understanding those places we know everything about this half of linear algebra
what 0 I mean by understanding those
I would like to know
a basis for those
for each 1 of those spaces how would I create construct basis what systematic way
would produce a basis
and what's the dimension
the effect that's of it
so for each of the 4 spaces I have to answer those questions
however I produce a basis
and then which has a somewhat long wants a
and what's the dimensions
which is just a number so it has a real short answers gonna give you
the short answer 1st I shouldn't do it by
I can tell you is the dimension of the column space
I may start with this guy wants its dimension I have an M by M
the dimensions or
of the column space
what is the rate of
of the
we actually got to that at the end of the last lecture
but only for an example
so I really have to say
OK what's going on there I should produce a basis
and I just want to see how many vectors I needed on that basis and
the answer will be all
actually do
before I get the the others
what's the basis for the column space
that we've done all the work of row reduction
identifying the pivot columns
the ones that have pivots the ones that end up with pivots but now I
the maximum likelihood is
basically reinterpreting these are functions has probability models now
maximum likelihood them
we start with an error function like this is a quadratic function
and we
what we imagine is the
we reinterpret
what's going on as that we're seeing data given by
why which is a function of x
be equal to this
again this basis function class at ceylon where epsilon is some noise now i think the the
the history the development of this idea of noise is fascinating and really the main person
is class
he is the person that i mean i guess when you were a mathematician or
physicist whatever you wanna call him in those days
you were interested in everything that was going on so he's not only interested in
probability theory and he does this crucial work in the eighteenth century on
deciding wether guys english or not
but he also
he is interested in
what really i think is driven forward a lot of research from the plants certainly within
europe is this nasty split between
new kaon europe which is centered around like it's a new claiming priority for calculus
and you're really
you can really
loses out from because a lot of the really interesting mathematicians at the time are in europe for example
you've got the new release an oiler who are also inspired by light it's
um land a what those people are interested in is taking this new understanding of physics
and inferring things about the data newton doesn't really do then you can doesn't say okay now i described how
these things work let's
for the massive this let's do i mean you
he doesn't know about the people really take it forward i think in particular are low class and gas
and le plus is particularly interesting because
they got this problem and in fact i've got this
slide a few steps ahead
it is probably more interesting the slides there
this is the problem
so they want to do in fact linear regressions may be linear but we can
think of it in linear regressions
thereby basis is taken from newton's laws so they are often working with a sinusoid
or a cosine basis that they
so newton's equations for some planetary oscillation and now they want to know
what the
right weighting these bases are so they are doing very often
linear regression system but the basis there is physical it's coming from on understanding the universe
so they got these two data points in a linear space
so these might be to observations so counts is famous for
predicting where this
dwarf planet
i astronomers said well astronomer common name the astronomers had identified answer is but it
passed behind the sun and was lost
there with this hunt defined series again and gauss predicts where it should be a year later
and they look there and they see it
and the way he claims retrospectively potentially in order to claim priority at least squares
he did is by least squares
so he's trying to fit the parameters of this orbit inspired by
newton's equations some observations
the original discoverer series fragment
so he did make observations you just got these observations
now i can't remember how many
three parameters are are there's probably the massive planet and a few other things
some unknown
but the basic idea is
in this case let's assume this is our model we got to free parameters
offset andy gradient
we only need to observations
in order to determine the gradient of the line
andy offset so we can fix our model with two observations
but he discovered series made more than two observations which is very inconvenient
because this is the third observation there question then was and this is a big debate how to deal with
this third observation because you have three observations ant
two unknowns
they did things like compute the parameter for every couple combination the observations and take the median they didn't know
they didn't believe for example in the mean they didn't believe that if you just
sum up a bunch of error-strewn observations
that you should get an answer that is better
because they didn't know
the principle that if you some
across variables the variance reduces
they that's clearly wrong thing to do philosophically
if you've got a series measurements with errors you should try and work with the
measurements we have the have no errors
she should pick to measurements the one which have the best no errors and you should that those two only
and the way they talk about doing is stating every possible combination measurements
and seeing
taking criteria like what the median values were from bat and then using the two
sets that gave the median values these sort criteria
so what missing
they were missing models the uncertainty
and i want to use this a lead-in to bayesian inference later
but for the moment because it's where you put uncertainty that key is undetermined an overdetermined system sorry
it's an overdetermined system and we're going deal with an overdetermined system by introducing stochasticity
interestingly we're also gonna do with underdetermined systems where you may only have one measurement
associated with linear regression by stochasticity later
but where we put them and what they called somehow seems to be different
with two unknowns and few observations you've got these formulae hear
and you'll learn how to do simultaneous equations and solve them and see
the third system the formalism overdetermined system
and here's the trick
slack variables
as robert my call it
so someone know this is a corrupting variable that comes from the fact that you
are acknowledging that you're not taking account for everything that could possibly happen in your
so you're not taking account in the case of observations planets of the
different motions in the atmosphere which may be corrupt or perhaps some set up here
experiment which is wrong and so this is
the error
which is how things departing from newton's equations so these bits would be representing newton's
equations in this series case and these bits are representing all the crap that happening
that is not part of your model
because we recognise as noise but it's really important acidic go back to the beginning
i want to talk about light
light is an electromagnetic phenomenon
and already in the sixteenth century
way before maxwell model studies were done
of the interaction
i was wondering
and with glass
the kind of experiments that were done
it follows
so this is rare
i call that medium one
and this is water
for the medium
and light beam
that strikes
this surface
light comes in like so
and i define
this angle is the angle of incidence
and i call that they don't want this is the normal to the surface
recall that the angle of incidence
i will say now that some of the light
is reflected
reflecting originality lion
and some of that light
goes into the water
recall that the refracted
refracted was an arts and richard
and this angle
we'll call
data two
and it was the dutchman
billboard smell is
who in the seventeenth century
i found three rules that govern the relation between the three
light beams
the first one is that
there's been this beam and this being in one plane
as you see
this is my plane on the blackboard
the second thing that he found this angle
theta free
which is called the angle of reflection is the same as the angle of incidence
that was known before him of course
and then the third one which is the most surprising one which is called after
it is called snails law
although his name was snell
is that the sign of one
divided by the sine of data two
if we go from air to water
and that ratio
it is about one point three
to go from air to glass
it's a little higher like one point five or so
he introduced the idea of index of
fraction which i will call
and so immensely
four vacuum index of refraction for definition is one
but it's very closely the same
in air
always treated as one in air
and in water
the index of refraction
is approximately one point three
and in glass depending upon what kind of glass you have
it's about one point five
and so we cannot amend this
small snails law
by writing here
and two divided by n one
and one being the index of refraction of the medium where you are
you incident beam that's why i put one here
and to being the index of refraction
of the medium where you're travelling through
you refracted into this medium
so you see indeed that since what is one point three
and air is one
that this ratio
four after water is one point three and this is called smells law
and it is immediately obvious that if you go from air to water
or you go from air to glass
that angle theta two is always smaller than the angle theta one
because this number is larger
then one
but if you go from water to air
and the situation
and that's what i want to
address now that's actually
quite interesting
so now
my medium one
is now warmer
and i mean two
there's no air
so now
i go from here
two here
so here i have my angle of incidence theta one
and here have my angle of ray
the fraction that is if they they're free
and now here
i have my
angle theta two
so if i write down now smells law
and i get the sign of data one
divided by the sine of data two
is now and two divided by n one the n two is one
divided by one point three
if we go from here
from water to air
and what is so special here is that
say that two can obviously never be larger than ninety degrees
so if you substitute in here
there are two ninety degrees
and you will find that they no one then
it's about
fifty degrees
and if you apply this equation
you substitute for one and angle larger than
fifty degrees you're going to find the sign of data to being larger than one
which is nonsense
cannot happen
so nature ignores
snails law
and they just story i can do it
and the nature now do does
if the angles
data one is too large in this case there is one larger than fifty degrees
not there anymore and all the light is now being reflected of that surface
and we call that
total reflection
total reflection happens when data one is larger
then a certain critical angle
are the same variable they should always be equal
right that's the same random variable it came from here and it went there and
also went there
so it should always be equal
but the message passing algorithm has no way to enforce that there's
there is no consistency being enforced between these two copies i'm sitting here doing my
stuff with my copy of x three e you're sitting there doing your stuff with
your other copy of x three and they're not the same
so the algorithm which computes something would be something correct but for the wrong model
so what this sort of says is that you you can be so naive here
i this kind of
very cavalier about i said OK this clustering sort of make it read
so it says we can just be naive but it turns out there's more principled
way to do this that is guaranteed to be correct and that's that's what the
junction tree formalism is
statistical definition
let me just state and then we'll come back and understand the intuition
so just to be clear this thing right here we call this the clique tree
the reason it's likely trees because you started with the original graph and you took
the cliques
one three
one two
two four and three four you put the separate notes
so it's a tree on the cliques of the original graph so a clique tree
what we're interested in is clique trees that satisfy
a certain property it's known as the running intersection property
and what this means is that if you look
at any two clique nodes c one and c two
then because you're in a tree
you know there's is a path you can walk along the path in the tree
from c one to c two
and what we're running intersection says as you walk along that path
anything that's in the intersection of those two should also be on that path
so here for instance
let me see
actually is
it's not really a non trivial example of it in this graph of one or
that's certainly works for these two you've got to cliques their intersection is too
there's not really anything to say as you walk along the z certainly two is
what sort of key here is that for node three
but when you intersect discrete with this one
you get three
but three does not appear in this clique nor does it appear in that cliques
this pair
for c one and c two they fail running intersection
so that's the motivation this this kind of lack of communication when you don't have
copies of the random variable talking to each other by the local algorithm then you're
in trouble the new algorithm will not compute the right thing that you're after seeing
need to be quite careful when you make these clique trees and this is the
key property you need to ensure that you always have the intersection along the path
and it's this intersection property that ensures that i get consistent results i don't get
strange answers that don't really mean anything in terms of the original model
OK so i
what you can show i won't go into details but you can show that if
you have a clique tree where you have running intersection
so if this property holds
then if you go off and you apply this message passing on such a clique
then you will get the correct answers for your original model
so what sort of saying is that when you form a clique tree
not just any clique tree this is not a good clique tree but one that
has the running intersection property if you can do that
you have to be careful here
then you can describe the standard message passing on that tree
and you're guaranteed to get the correct answer for your original model
so this is known as the junction tree when you have a clique tree that
satisfies running intersection a junction tree
you want to think sort of you're looking at the interest actions the junctions between
adjacent cliques so there's notion of taking junctions here
OK so this sort of key question here is what kinds of graphs actually have
junction trees
for instance does this graph have a junction tree
i remember junction tree is a clique tree that satisfies running intersection
this is a clique tree but we saw that fails running intersection because of node
three appearing twice
but not appearing along this path
but i do something else to the graph i mean to follow up on the
question that we had back there
would help for instance to eliminate different edge to try and make a junction tree
if you think about it a bit want
symmetry is the reason that doesn't really matter which would you remove you're always going
morning to darrell
world knowledge and rui costa i'm going to talk about active learning so
OK good morning everyone this is
make sure you have enough
play in the score
so that we can talk about active learning
and the
tutorial be divided into three parts and it will probably take a couple of breaks
so will do the first part
during the first part of
can have an overview of the idea of active learning some motivation for why it's
interesting in the number of different fields and set some of the
the basic groundwork for the kinds of questions that are interesting to study the focus
here is going to be
of our tutorial overall is going to be mainly on the mathematical theory of active
learning and
less emphasis on actual applications
but i will say a little bit about places where it can be applied where
we apply to other people have applied it as we go along
so we'll have about one hour
or a little less of this kind of first part of the introduction then really
we'll talk and he'll be doing a bit of a case study if you will
look very carefully at the problem of active learning in the setting of binary classification
and then we'll have another break after that and then in the final part will
discuss some other applications of active learning
or or
settings where you can apply active learning also talk about some experiments with humans and
how humans use active learning techniques and then we'll conclude with some final remarks and
so forth i'd like to ask that all questions be held to the very very
at the end of right now i'm just kidding of course and we can ask
questions whenever whenever you like you can interact to keep this is informal as possible
and so i encourage you to stop me and
ask for clarifications and so forth OK so
when we get started
so the idea in active learning is really
sort about closing the loop in the learning process so rather than a conventional setting
where we just have a whole batch of data somewhere and then we feed that
data into a computer and have the computer grind away on it and try to
learn some sort of classifier or estimate function of the data or something like that
in active learning the idea is really to close the loop so that the
data analysis is actually informing how we do the data collection how we do our
sensing how we
the inquiry may questions about the world and so that's that's i think in a
a good way metaphor to think about this for kind of closing the loop between
data collection and data analysis
and usually
active learning would actually operate in a sequential fashion where you take some measurements or
observations from the world you
the computer
four person would study those data and then that will guide how they go about
collecting more information in order to try to come up with a good model for
whatever it is there are study
and this idea is very old and i mean mean
who knows how long you people are doing this but it was kind of formalized
a little bit by little class who according to chains use these kinds of ideas
to help
when he was working with his astronomy colleagues try to decide where they should focus
telescopes in order to discover new things in astronomy and so the idea there was
basically when there was ever large discrepancy between what their predictive models said in what
they are observing that was an interesting place to dwell in focus their scanning of
the sky
and that is something that he credits with some of the discoveries they made
so what is active learning we can just try to describe it in a nutshell
the idea is usually
we have data that were examples that come to us pairs features and labels and
so x is a feature vector y is say label in binary classification label would
just be zero one or plus one minus one
what we'd like to do
his select
unlabelled examples
just raw features with no labels and request labels from those particular samples that seem
to be highly uncertain so for an unlabelled example like this will have some predictions
based on
past information that we've gathered so far in that prediction is something we're very confident
and then you might think well let's not bother requesting label for that example but
if we feel that we don't really have a good sense of where that label
know what you do pretty much all the time and then and then you have
a pretty good declarations and finally how the formulas
so it's actually you know quite simple
to write basic mln
here is the most basic ML the you could write
it's the empty MLN
no formulas
and in tamil and actually represents something meaningful represents a uniform distribution
what is an empty MLN representing from distribution well let's look at the example of
flipping coins
let's assume that there are unbiased
it is that the most the simplest thing you could possibly want to model how
you do this in aachen
well you declare type called flip that ranges from one to an infinite number of
flips you want to have
and then you can request single predicate heads of flu which is truth if it
comes up and if the coin comes up heads and false otherwise
now what is the probability that you get hands on any given flip
so now i notice i have no no formulas right so the argument that the
exponential is always going to be zero
right no matter what happens
so the probability of heads is the property of is the is the is the
value of you know of the MLN distribution for heads
over the valley for the alpha tails but they both the same
they both e to the zero
times the partition function so the result is that
OK so the empty MLN represents a from distribution well
let's go one step beyond and see how well we represent the binomial distribution it's
the next simplest thing about one
let's suppose the euro coin flips biased
right so calling has more probability say turning up heads and tails
this can be represented using an and with a single
unit clause unit clauses clause containing only one literal
so here's here's a that typical relation an outbreak cooperation and i have a single
formula heads of f
this formula saying it's going to come up heads
the weight to this formula
is going to be just the log odds of getting it's this is a very
well known thing in statistics log odds of an event it's the log of the
probability of heads
over the probability of tails which is one minus the probability of heads
why why does this work out well let's see
the problem that you get heads
one of the times e to the w right because if it comes up heads
for history and you get the weight w
over the probability that it's true class this if it's false
right if it's false and the features are true receive get zero
so what you get is it to the ovary to the plus one
which is the same as one of one plus e to the minus the bear
and it's easy you know this is equal to the probability of heads
and it's easy to see you know you can do the elder and see that
these two expressions are called
so you can represent the binomial distribution by having a single class
where the weight
is the log odds corresponding to the success probability
and unit clauses are so useful that by default
when you learn in ML and the unit clauses for all predicates are included
among other things the unit clauses allow you to capture the marginal distributions of the
and the other clauses can focus on on modeling interactions between them which is what
we want to have
the question
means is that think that
so if you have another formerly called not heads of that if it had the
same weight
the two weeks with cancer
if you have a different way than what you get is the distribution instead of
the here have the difference of
next the most complex thing let's represent a multinomial distribution for example let's say we're
throwing die
OK how would we do that
well i could have two types throw
again from one to twelve we want to happen face
which in the case of the dionysian enough so we have one to six
and we can have the predicate outcomethrow face
that says you know on the and throw the face came up
and now what formulas do we need to represent this
well now we know what we need to represent the fact that the outcomes are
mutually exclusive and exhaustive like the that can only land on one face
so how do we represent what we can write are logic we can say
if the outcome of t is f
and f is different from the phi then the outcome of t is not a
OK this exclamation mark means negation
this is the you can have two outcomes at the same time
there exists as such that outcome of t is that says that
you know there's always one
and these full stops here mean that these formulas are hard
i deterministic
they have infinite weight
so full stop is a shorthand for infinite weight these always have to hold
so you could represent the multinomial distribution by having this formula
however this is very cumbersome
when we go about you know their applications are interested in we're going have multinomial
distributions all over the place and would be very boring to have to write these
two formulas for every single my you know predicate that we have
luckily there is a nice piece of notation
that will make things much more succinct
and that is the exclamation mark notation
is just this when you click the predicate you put an exclamation mark in front
of the value that is supposed to be unique
so what outcome of through face means that for every value throw there is exactly
one value face for which outcomethrow face is true
and the general semantics of this of course is that
his multiplicities and without multiplicities
then we calculate the integral
we conclude
the number of zeros multiplicities
but when the columns and on changes science
because the heroes
without multiplicities
so it is zero accounted only for one zero
w zero
will never be detected
because on both sides of the plants have the same sign
and so
just like that
although there are also five a simple
in the first part of his newspaper
during describes this technique
but what new was done by humans
he introduced a new methods quickly enough to
very different from
what i
i mentioned before
and then he adds
the paper is divided into
two parts
the first part is devoted to
then is connected with problem
all the results obtained in this part
a little bit
the initial initially calculations for the same amount
but the carried out on the manchester
computer all by
other means
and that is really true
and to link message is used up to now
and now i will try to reduce the outline what was the
but the idea of student
if we believe in ground floor
then the number of zeros would be approximately
equal to the
number grumblings before
given limited
and this number is easy to calculate
fasten it is monotone so we can rewrite it this way
by definition ground point this is just by multiplying by
so this is equivalent to such inequality
so the nomogram points approximate this is ritual
and we can write that
the number of points inside
the rectangular area
is this the main
plus along because it started militant inputs from minus one
plus some function which you might expect to be small
and in fact
levels proof that this small on average
and student and this is based on these
serum of little
but little himself
did not so
results can be used
for checking the hypothesis
now has its own attitudes who made for the calculations
and don't do it
found very
to use
this system of little
accelerates chicken
that among reporters
by itself
little theorem is useless for computation
because it doesn't tell us anything about any particular
because of this
capital o notation
the first thing done by student was the following
captain quantitative improvement of little theorem
he found exact balance before
the average below this function as
and given interval
and here is
part of
his paper
here is a statement of
the serum
and then
there follows
five pages
of a typical numbers typical kind
is an accurate estimation of different some something the growth
so what was
they deal student
you want to know
if there also below some people lie on the critical line
for this then we would need to calculate a after
but we could say that
different value of do agreed abandon ship
the same with a great ability
and that this
my turned out to be more convenient for calculation of this function as of today
and technology changes order things
he said
let us try to find some to zero
which is it is indeed
say that you want the value of as being equal to zero
so instead of starting from you and go into the
if you predicted the value of has
and london just defined such that is zero
battle for such a team
if it is zero
then this history
this is integer so this is an integer
this means that
numerator is
a multiple of pi
so the front and sides with equal to zero
this implies that these are all should be our
gram point
okay so we look for such a two zero among gram points
and now we can do this all
and that it was more than
the ground points
two days