and the real events cluster sort of like earthquakes with the aftershocks
and in fact the more a lot of aftershocks in earthquakes has been used by
the on line ten you to describe the aftershocks
other big events such as black monday
in fact if you look very carefully at this stage using equipment that i'm not
going to say that mister my mother said be trying to contribute to eyes
you can't count the number of times more than five standard deviations and you get
sixty four
you think of the number of events more than ten standard deviations and you get
eight thirty eight times fewer
and you can do a number of events
twenty standard deviation again only one times fewer
that's obviously a power law
because each time we don't x axis we divided by age
the y axis so that only a power law with exponent is
two q minus three
so you can see with your eyes the power law the inverse cube for these
data but that doesn't convince anybody that the
this is one way to look at real data in the real breakthrough in my
opinion came when was a month
had the courage to analyse
so the data
that existed at that time which was one and a half million data points of
this as the p five hundred index
and what they found was very interesting distribution is a distribution that was leading in
the middle
but after about five standard deviation was truncated by what was the public approximating exponential
introduced the concept called truncated flight which has become popular not only physics but also
in economics
in this work of was followed up by coptic christian would be even more data
instead of one million data of an index they looked at each and every individual
stock in every transaction that so there going to particle physics where instead of looking
molecules look at every constituent of the molecule nuclei some degree and so forth and
a lot basis but the most relevant one is the in quotes database for and
what they specifically looked at was the files
larger stocks but every retreated so instead of going the two hundred million records that's
a staggering amount of data and because the staggering amount of data they could study
events that was rare is one hundred standard deviations attributes x axis is one hundred
ten editions of what they found was truly remarkable they found that there were no
outliers at all
the concept of outliers
the that exist
that's one hundred standard deviations from the same curve as
the events before
of everyday events
and and that line is a straight line on the paper so minus three is
really just by
using our i two minutes ago
so this is the economics fluctuations law financial fluctuations has been already anticipated by the
work of thomas looks
the data set two years before we did our work and has been confirmed by
by roughly fifty other
calculations using looking at data from other markets and it seems to be quite universal
with a few caveats which we can discuss privately
before we and that that's why should this be like statistical physics problems and we're
going to say now is not to be blamed by collaborators it's more intuition which
is a little like religion something little personal but it is a personal that's all
about my mother to say something a little bit of speculative
how can we think of this financial
the system is complex system about which we know so incredibly well
this approach religion they
fundamental background who we are what we experienced so this approach this very very awe-inspiring
see when people say
well there's a lot of you know that
we have a u
o thing is
there were one
well one thing
this is the
the game
know the
you know
on right
on the
o five
all of the protein
on the product
you are approved by
the model
he was
or right
we are
the problem
she was you know
from from
one new
nothing wrong
so all
so you see
and course
all along
are there
are they
all of
after that
so all this
wrong was
from the graph
rob hall
it turns out that you can do much better at test time
if you have this additional modalities the training time because what happens is that it
turns out that you can regularize model with the model is able to learn much
more reasonable embedded images by looking different sources of views of the data
and the missing the nice thing about these probabilistic models is that the way you
deal with missing text is you basically do inference over the missing text
so the model fills in the missing tax and then there is the recognition of what it sees
in each
you can also do things like
winning from lips
this is what can be done by number of groups wear
basically look at you have been modality
as well as
o forty images as well as follows the sound you can feed them in in
you can have a pretty reasonable
this is particularly useful for doing speech recognition in noisy environments
so in the last part
the tutorial
let me just go into another development that's been happening in the deep learning communities
is trying to look at slightly more challenging problem
and the challenging problem of actually describing complete description of images were trying to basically generates
structured output like this sentence
so ideally you know you look at the image like this and the system automatically
selects a man skiing down snow-covered mountain reductions going back in the back
with the dark sky and in the background
right so how can we do not
one of the ideas that have been evolving in the last couple of years is the idea of
representing words
in terms
we are in the semantic space representing words as feature vectors in some dimensional space
right so what you gonna do he's gonna be embedding each word in the dimensional
real valued vector with real valued space in your represented as a vector so the
hope is that
you know table and chairs will get put together
dolphins and whales because they semantically similar will get put together in november will get put somewhere else
in that space
right so representing words is basically points dimensional space
one of um
one of the most commonly used model for generating sentences is
is will bring a lot by learning in your language model
and the new language model was actually developed back in two thousand three by yoshua bengio his lab
that's what i had a resurgence
coming up in the last few years and it is very simple you basically say well
you have a bunch of words
and let's say
walking on there and you're trying to predict the next one
and the hope is that working on the street would have a high probability because that's
a reasonable conclusion but something like
are block will have very low probability and know what that's like the name of some
um or watching on the zebra will have small probability right
and the way you cannot do it if you're gonna say well there are words
there are context matrices
that u
multiply these words by
and then you get you add is a key by complex matrices and then you
basically these view the prediction of the next word so basically get a linear combination
of the previous works to predict the next word
that's that's the idea so this is the predictive what a presentation and then if
you want have a distribution over possible words
that's going to be given by softmax model
so you're essentially here you're looking at the dot products between feature vectors and trying
to predict what's the next most probable worked
that's the answer
now the way to think about images and text is you can think of images
as an encouraging decorum model
so let's say i think this image
and map it into some feature space
right so sam using convolutional neural network i'm using deep belief network both machine one of the different models
i did the semantic feature space
and then based on the semantic feature space i decoded back to this sentence
so people who work and translations for example is a very similar story when you have a sentence in english
you're encoded in the some representation and then you decode it in a new language
in view
and in coder-decoder is the same the same way they can image called in some
space decoded back into the sentence
and this is one particular mall was done by ryan tears where r u in
addition to the text you have a modality you have an image modality
so you say steamship in and you have an image of a steamship and you
can see in the city for example
so these image itself can bias what was going to predict next
but now what's been emerging in the last couple of years is this idea of
actually what you can do is you can also about words in the same space
you can embed images in one space between the words in the same space
you can combine all conditional anything images word phrases
that is a very natural definition of a scoring function
which is just an inner product between image in between features she just looking at
in the product so cosine similarity between features
which is very easy to to
to do
and you can also use you know some kind of language models incorporate additional structure
into the system here
the key idea is that now you can model images and text the phrase you
can embed them all the same semantic space
they all become features and this
joint semantic space
right so for example how we train a model like this
so one way of training and imagine that you have an image and you have
a sentence u map sentence the space in the image space
hopefully have another image
and the sentence in both image and sends get mapped to these
the same space as well
so what you like to do in terms of
finding the joint feature space is you minimize the following injective function
let's look at this objective function
here you have the scoring function which you can think of just defining a dot
product between two vectors defining dot product between x and
and the idea is that you want this scoring function this has to be as high as possible
because let's say
the dot product between these guys is ten
what's the second time the second term sometimes called contrastive
it essentially says well
if i take the same image
and different sentence
i want the dot product between these two features
to be very small
on the distance between these two features to be very small
so if this is ten
and this is five and it's good
i'm not suffering loss
and you have to be better than your contrastive sentence by
some some margin of
you know the way to think about these models you basically say well i want
the sentence to go along with this image
but i don't want this sentence to go along with image that's the idea ranking like loss
and you're trying to basically find what those embeddings should be
in terms of that's the same story
right you can
are larger than the pairwise distances we're here if i keep
if i keep the order like
so just move points apart in in you don't get it right
this just
no it's not you it's
just do something like
i say
thirty six so i say this this point moves here this point here this point
here so it's not it's not the geometric transformation just making OK on a more
abstract level i just say i a function which maps each of those points to
one of those points
and i'm sure that the distances before like before so measure the distance here and
i measure the distance after i made the transformation and the distances increased
that's the only so it's not a geometric thing you just it's really
increasing saying said no but this
the same is true those
no that's not the same but but i mean the axiom was
it didn't say anything about how you
how you are allowed to shrink distances it just says if you expand distances between
points which are in different clusters
then the clustering does not change
and the idea of course is that if you have
that is it
it's hard to say
so so it's it's it's much anything it doesn't have anything to do with geometry
it's it's just the the notion of
of clustering someone says OK maybe we
based on clustering distances and we want the points which are in different clusters
clusters are similar to each other and then if i make similarity even larger than
it's the should give it just in different ways
well OK why we need sex and that's why OK
of course that's not what that's not exactly the question of course you can start
to remove accents
actually what turned out to if you remove any of those axioms the rest of
the two other ones are consistent season
three four
because forms or
what is just one
it was red
OK so OK so there's one hundred and didn't really explain so he doesn't work
actually and configuration of points he works on distance matrices so the input is i've
miss the distance matrix you don't have any points you have just the distance matrix
someone to give you
and then you so you don't and then just i think the idea is just
if you have a distance matrix and cluster like this
and now you are you have made zero point one that's that's
so there you have two points in different classes but they have some small similarity
now if you if you
lord this one to zero it should not change the clustering
so essentially if you decrease in the similarity matrix if you decrease the off diagonal
terms it should even be more obvious the secaucus that somehow would be what you
want to do
OK but of course
you can you can you can start debating i mean this is also problematic acts
because maybe there's this stupid clustering simply don't want to get or
i mean in learning theory you always learn that you never should work with the
function space which can generate any function because it would fit somehow why do you
have this year of course can debate about
the point remains here is i think he came up with axioms which all of
them sound pretty harmless but then it doesn't work so well
and of course and
i think didn't say that those are the only extant to see justice there's the
axioms and on the first glance all of the input and now it doesn't
and i which happening
o that's OK if you're interested in that
that section of the paper to talk you can download from shows so he discusses
all this stuff so it sits atop which i done workshop so
if you are interested just look at it
we i can i mean i don't want to spend day on axiomatic points of
view because namely my point of view is that somatic point of view it's pretty
problematic because
it depends on your choice of axioms and first of all it sounds very fundamental
you define accents greater mathematician now you solve the problem of clustering and it's in
it's pretty around the right to come up with a few accents and then
whatever and of course the second thing is i mean
xim xim nice but in practice
they don't really help you here
but this is i i want to present wanted to present because it's really not
so there was a time when everybody trying to define clustering such away because of
the advantages some if it would work it would be elegant because you avoid to
define explicitly what clustering is
just properties and then we show that there is an idea which does what you
want so
by my hand
i have to keep moving because otherwise this will go to pieces i must be
doing this
all the time
at that frequency which is exactly
the resonance frequency of the single pendulum theta omega zero
i must keep doing this
this one
there's nothing this one
double the swing of this
and is out of phase
then you go even higher
then you will see that the two two
object will go on to face
one will be in phase with the driver
and no one will be out of phase with the drive and then you get
that second residence
when things get out of hand
and you get that ratio
minus o point four two back of course
i want to demonstrate to you
this situation here
in this situation
to see whether
they make sense
so now i'm going to
user double pendulum
and drive it
with my
o frequency which i determine
i'm the boss
i determine omega
not looking for normal mode solutions
and i'm going to first
private with omega zero
was only guys is about zero
in other words
i'm going drive it
what you're going to see
is of course
it's hanging straight down o
and i'm moving it
over distance
one foot
at the zero is one foot
c one is wonderful
and c two is one foot
and there are in phase with the right
if i go a little higher up here
i go somewhere here
approaching resonance
then you will see that too becomes larger than c one
this is to see why
and you get to see a picture which is very much like this
now try that
drive it below but
not too far below
there you see
c c one
it's more
c two
no longer one was one this was one
you see one of the two
this one
there is no longer the case
really city two is going to go ahead
i had nothing to interface
but in terms of them
now i'm going to attempt to do the impossible
and the impossible is
try to hit this point
the point value of one standstill
and rabbi
the lower
we'll have an amplitude which is twice that of my hands
but out of phase with my
how on earth can i have
drive this system
reason that frequency omega zero
which is the frequency of a single plant
maybe i can't
but i will try and the rain i'm going to try this is the following
i know
the resonance frequency of a single pendulum is
that's this
i can feel it in my hands i can feel it in my stomach i
can feel it in my brains i feel it all over my body
i can confirm this frequency into my chips here
and then i can close my eyes
well you are looking
and generate that frequency which was burned here
and drive the system is the double pendulum
if i succeed
you see the article on standstill
in the bottom one will have twice the amplitude of my
so the success of this depends exclusively
on how accurately i can run this frequency
into my chips
we have to be quite
i'm going to come one
three i'm burning up
four closing my eyes one
let's say anything you see this one sentence
it to
but you also see that the other one
at twice the amplitude of my hands and out of phase with my hand you
can see the right image you didn't see it
because you're not looking for it
especially for you i'll do it again
so you have you really have to see
number one and this one practically standstill number two
that this one is double the amplitude of my hand
but out of phase
OK final earning
is only one minute so i have to burn it again
one way
these things happen you have to start all over with pruning
there we go
i see it
is it ideal moment before the break
many queries
and we will reconvene i'll give you six minutes this time
so we could even stretch your legs
and i would like some help
and in this out
and then you bring it back and put box is out there
so if you can help me
finding similar items we have we have s
small data it's very easy so
find similar
data record
let's say if have
a hundred thousand documents and we get a new one we try to find similar wrongly
brute force would work and that's it
we have billions and billions then this would work so
multidimensional indexing all data this is very important to just to access and together similar
items so there's a whole set of classifiers that
incremental updating of models in the small that the world
we took the data we build the model and that was it then when the data changes we
just changed a little bit just ran the whole thing and was okay
here with the big data we cannot afford it so we we need to be incremental so small
changing data and
we know that produces small change in the model and the algorithm is a support this
so this is incremental updating
it's very fundamental set of techniques so linear algebra which you'll probably all
know from
undergraduate courses
so need to be properly
you know this this uh
and its surrounding this distributed fashion and this is this is what google has sought is big
search engines
many of these big the data providers
so these are
type of
operators which we need to
happened then of course then we can deal with
a bit more like traditional way of dealing with the data so the public this previous operators we just
i do the usual stuff that's in the data mining or machine learning sense this would be
supervised learning and unsupervised or semi-supervised is that traditional machine learning classification regression and so on so
if you have these operators properly implemented on distributed infrastructures them
everything goes is then the same so this is
that's why i said the beginning
big data this almost the same as
small that
so the same intuitions that we need to be careful about the scale
to learn about the
these techniques which i just mentioned
this book
recently came out is downloadable from the vet
mining of massive data sets so it's
from geoffrey ullman ants coauthor
it goes through all this
segments and provides good
good leads at least hard to design algorithms are to actually algorithms
so we can learn a lot from here
and this is
by my
knowledge the only book
which is technical
which is technical and the great thing sites nowadays on the market
okay so we have just a few more minutes savages growth
quickly through some up of applications which
are happened in my
circle are which we were
princes one big data application which
with it was
so far bloomberg website recommendations so the open article on bloomberg com
would get this set of recommendations which
we generate based on
who is reading what is reading what was history of this person and so on
and this happens like two hundred times per second
why recommendations
important because good recommendations can be like
and father on
the final step
it can be done
two weeklies emotions the visual expression
this would be the one
he should step another told not to
to this
two tool
two slide the the slidingwindow on all the possible locations some more some improvements can
be the process of applying
some of the point to point detectors
according to the corner detectors like we use a commission for
cases like
and this is what what we actually use
OK so
this would be
if i have more than two three minutes and i can also say something about
the evolution of emotions from from the speech
OK so i
this is one of the approaches that we
so far we took another two
to create to develop such a system automatic system for for legalizing the emotions speech
i wanted to find out which part of the
one of the responses
is the most important for four
giving the dominant emotion from the ottomans
that maybe
we speak something
maybe we say something about this
we want to know exactly what you want
what are the
keep he or you what is the key information that gives the relevant information that
their emotions from one of
we initially had some of databases
these buses we used building dataset
one is for german language another one is for the image they were actually recorded
and mating for this one
they have this for us to be used for
in this kind of research is sold their of the content contained
o audio speech and those the labels for the emotions
we use the gentleman
with maximum two hundred training sets so it is something that at each step it
the the most relevant features
that that represented the
that level
it that
not only do that can differentiate well
emotional plants
for evaluation we use ROC rock graphs
i think this would be one very efficiently
making this information was
when the databases are
on the side other
the structure of the data set
from the structure of the data see that for instance one class
we have lists
let's so much sort of the simplest form
simplicity before
for another class then
it's good to make an in-depth analyses for
in terms of evaluation
so these are
for one of the things we split
of the ten different segments and make light of segmentation we want to see
which frame gives
is a representative for the motion of the all utterance
so we speak in light of the interval and we took a so one
the order of ten
singh was split into three five and so on
and in total
for each such state each such a combination we
this is the information
specific database
so we have in then the
one thousand
sixty four sixty five datasets
i spent thirty and they take
the values of the features
only from the first and third
for between three and they take information about the features one from the first and
the third because if i find this to be
the most relevant again among other
combinations of spitting then i see the first and the third frame
friends would give me the most eleven one four four
it lies in the emotions we used some parameters
we use
and five cross validation they need
we the again one to the rest
and then you see some
the result
we use the so
of gender-based
o analyses i mean
we took separately made
lectures supplement which goes
four innovation step by step which will convince you that indeed
this is
what is happening
why we can't digest this so easily is we don't know how to handle non
conservative fields
if you have a non-conservative field
then if you go from a to d
of the adult yell
or from the two a for that matter doesn't matter
the answer depends on the path
it's no longer independent of the path
and so on
if there is the
and here is a
you go this way
you find o point nine four class
if you go this way
find is o point one four five they has no problem with that the is
what has the problem with that
who cares about his role
five the more that matters
because fire there is not always holds because if we find it zero
then again he sells his house rule is simply a special case of fire this
law and fire this will always holds
the took each of is for the birds
and and fire they is not
suppose you go
from the
eight and back to b
we know that
if you do minus three eight
if we go
if we go this way
two are two
we note in three d minus the a
plus o point nine holes
now we are in a
and we go through the left side back to d
so we now have a minus b b
that of course is now plus o point one four because remember
if you do you mind a mine o point one
NVA minus plus
so we add them up
and we find that the d
mine in three d
is plus-one vote
this half said has to be zero
because i'm back at the same potential where i was before
fireplaces are
i'm sorry
you can do that
that's one fold is exactly that EMF one
that is the closed loop moving the goal of each LTL around the globe
it's no longer
and therefore whenever you define potential difference if you do that
in the way of the
the integral of e dot pl
keep in mind that was non-conservative fields
it depends on the path
and that is very normal
and i'm going to demonstrate is now to you
i have a circuit which is exactly what you have here
five nine hundred falls
in a
copper wire year nine hundred twelve UL here is the
so all in all we can switch the current in the solenoid going to blast
of coming up
and the system is going to react
by driving a current
in the direction that you
see there
i'd like to be even a little bit more
quantitative studies you get a little bit
more for your money
the magnetic field
thanks for the element of time
to reach the maximum value in this course
we will be able to
he made the time that it takes
for the magnetic field to build up
we didn't get to that you have to forget that part is not so important
i just want you to
i appreciate the fact
the magnetic fields
as a function of time
will come up like this
and will then reach maximum
no longer changing is constant is the maximum value is very high seventy eight from
the guy so for this unit
we are not interested in the magnetic field we're interested in the change of the
magnetic fields
so the change of the magnetic field b
it's going to be something like this
of this curve
and that is proportional
with the induced EMF
and that's important for proportional with the current to flow
if we now plot
the voltage
this figure actually illustrates this kind of
distribution some nodes are highly connected have so many edges as compared to other nodes
which have very few edges
and the next one is a hybrid model which is a mixture of preferential attachment
and around the model so
here we try to give other people some chance to get creature
there's also tries to solve irreducibility which is physically strong connectedness
with fewer are subgraphs by basically providing random walk and random jump to non connected
or isolated nodes
and then there are some other modern summer study temporal patterns
like how often people create blog posts hopelessness and popular this blog is
how these posts are linked and modelling density
this is basically the develops SIS model which is susceptible
on infected and susceptible models
there's another model which uses etc
generate network within blogs which is increasingly the blog have links have the articles blogs
which are related to this blog so that's assumption and then they use this kind
of assumption to create a network of blogs
i don't want to block clustering
as you can see in this figure it is basically
the blogsphere for bush in politics and
different things so you can see they have they have cluster different blogs and persian
domain and you can see different clusters of blogs lay
all it takes on different things and the kind of according
o signifies the relatedness of these different topics
so if you have you can see persian poetry and politics as far apart as
compared to
if reformist politics and conservative politics
so it's a very good nice we to visualize different blogs
and how did they at hopes so different there
so basically you can use doppler strings that immediately and automatically organize the content it
also helps inconvenient accessibility by optimizing search engines because you don't have to search the
whole block just the cluster in that case
you also can no focused crawling based on the different clusters you have and then
it also helps in summarisation of different topics have different clusters you can also identify
topics of these different clusters and this can also help in extraction analysis of trends
one motivation for this is to use the information because there are so many blog
posts appeared per second
so we don't want you don't have that kind of thing that was region and
blog posts so you just go through the relevant which are interested in then read
the blogs
some of the techniques which
he string they use the PFID if
they find
three key words from the blogs and then the class of these models based on
these keywords have compared this to david are fact based clustering and reported some improvements
over the fact that it's really
then some of the research they also try to to assign different weights to different
components of blogs like different weights to title body and comments of blog posts
but they need to address high dimensionality and sparsity to do
keyword based approaches
is it
from group which focuses on collective based approach
it uses generates category relation graphs based on the user assignments of tags and categories
and then using that now we compute
similarity matrix
between the categories and then this result in a graph
and then we use this graph to cluster different of this is recovered later in
the second part of the tutorial in much needed
now let's move on to
blog mining
it is basically
the interaction between producers and consumers
so nowadays
not to mention that there are differences as from the two point o environment that
you have so many are so much interaction between
consumers so
this has really changed the way of previous appeasement would used to be done for
to all the matrix form and to the recursion and everything
and and you can see that it's
lots of applications are blocked right diagonal the new state
comes from the old state but it doesn't come from ten old state
or doesn't go all the way back to the very beginning state
it's just it's connected to the previous
it's like you know we have a differential equation or a difference equation connecting new
state it will one i'll come back to that
in the in the second lecture course when we really get that OK
i just don't want
all i can what i can try to do in these
like his is the highlight
what seems like to me the key points
we're going to need we're going to have formulas and i will get them all
on the board
but those can be looked at
those would be in this chapter the goes on the web and and there are
many other descriptions of them in the references
and i have begun to give all the references
but the idea is
are always not so many
and one of them is
blocked right diag
there blocks because
new the new
the new
in this recursive stuff
this is a block of bees is another block b
this is a block of a this is the rest of the
this is the block picture
you want me to write that as of what picture
the block matrix is a all
a new
and it multiplies u
and then you use
not changing like that we have a newer and newer number and no block
in the recursive
set up
we're so keeping the same you
in the kalman set up
we're also getting a new you and you are you on a brand new you
so the
that's the difference here the recursive
if you could say that in matrix language
recursively squares were adding new rose
in dynamic problems
we're adding new parameters or adding new columns too
we adding new rows and columns
so as i say i write that down to get on the board recursive
this stuff is new rose
new rose
and the dynamics is new
columns two
new unknown
but this lecture is about new roses about this problem
is about this problem so now i'm ready to
turn to that problem
but first i didn't make the
the most important comment about this
never read such a long ways to work
as this one for sigma
which is turned out to be PE which turned out to have this need answer
what's the
the point i haven't made but the it's it's the established in the textbook
is the reason for this choice
the reason that choice
the right one
is that it makes
this matrix p
as small as possible
we get the best estimate
in the sense that the variance is is the the the the the variance covariance
matrix is the smallest possible
by making this choice of c
this choice are this choice of c this by taking that particular weighting matrix it
produced this answer and we couldn't have got smaller
we couldn't have gotten smaller sigma u
than that
and that's that
that's one way to say why it that
so there is an optimal property of this
this way
and that's one way to
the choice of that
that is there waiting make
i'm ready to tackle this
this recursion
so what's the idea
we solve the old problem
then we get
new measurements
we have
part of the corresponding new part of the matrix a and i want to get
i want to solve the problem again
and the point is i want to solve the problem again
i don't want to start from the beginning
that's the that's the recursive idea
i would like to be able to say
i would like to be able to use my
the calculation already made
so i would like to
have update formula of this time
i would like to see the best u
for that
combined system
as the best u
for the original system
some matrix and that's going to be
the kalman gain matrix
multiplying this quantity
now there's that seem like
reasonable goal
before we
reach let's see if it's
let's see what we're aiming for
you will
what happen if
what would happen if
these new measurements were perfect repeat
and this was the repeat if if you know is the same as a old
and the new is the same as the old
so we just ran experiment twice
or just copy the answer and notice or something
what would we expect you knew the perfect the best you to be for the
maybe the same right
and you see that that's what happened with this formula
that you know would be you all
would be
if you still those results you can you can use them
they are
there's an efficient implementation
as you know colorado university them so it's being used
so people are using these things for solving in many NP hard problems like satisfiability
problems and so forth this representation giving them phenomenal speed ups
and scheduling is done using these representations in typical scheduling problems
and they're using in computer vision that out and all that
i mean it's data mining also they have not been used
OK in the case of zero suppressed binary decision diagrams what you're trying to do
is that
it's a it's variance
it's a variation of BDD
and what you do is you simply
ignore part of the negative log and we'll see how this happens
so first thing is you have to impose an order in all of these things
and the interesting thing is the order
that means which is the root node which is the next node
can can make a huge difference in terms of the complexity of the representation
so like i told you here earlier right
by having a certain or you can get a very compressed three so one of
the things you want do is that you want to have a long speak and
the brush like this
like like a brush
that means lord branching have like that
that a very efficient representation
and if it is brought together where then then you have a lot of stories
required and not much action take place that's why choosing the right kind of frequencies
can make it might make an interesting thing so my belief is low density estimation
should be done quite nicely using these kinds of structures
so here is a as the representation of from
some data
so here we have let's say
one instance which has values
ABD and so forth and let's assume we chose in order see the baby
so first thing is that this ABC
using this order would be c comes first because it has seen
followed by a
because that's a the next one in the sequence of with respect to this
and then followed by
he and then last thing is because is the last one so
so initially this is the structure
if you only given the structure
this is the
the representation of binary decision diagram
to this one i'm adding
and the one so from point of view this is there another
truth to value all boolean expression
so that i construct this way again using the same order the you know in
this case the
is the highest as far as far as this ranking goes so you build this
one so now i can join them
by using this sharing
and then you end up this these two structures like this
you have a nose CAE
he be as before
and if c is false because it doesn't have in which case this is the
node you come here
so this is about an hour
and then you
and then you see the rest of the structure is shared because c e b
and then you have a very concise representation
and then to that
adding the third one which is BCD again
we know that if c is a higher rank than
then then
then c
sorry sees i and b therefore c comes first and then the
and c then b
so now when we do that
joining of these things then this is the structure
so so you can see that
in all the nodes seems to end up
like this and this gives us the
compact representation
so once these are presented then what happens is when you're trying to
the pattern mining
basically what the structure
walking through the structure and looking at the other datasets with this pattern is present
then you can generate very very quickly all these emerging patterns and because it is
this disjunction as well
you can do the distinction construction also quite quickly using these structures
the actual algorithm is a bit more involved and we don't have time to go
through that there is a paper reference if you're interested you should look at that
so one thing i wanted to say is that there is a tool available if
you're interested you can download from the university
and recently we use this structure to study
schizophrenia it is one of the mental disorders generally
i think age group
i think that was
are and works here that the the gene
it's a
and of course
or one
right before you on tree
really four
three or
and how do we decide to the truth
we trust also
you can
i don't know know if the test from
they are
now decided to bring site
francis when you get e to the test small proline rich
one hundred and
so we only
let's try terms your
very small
well the i is true for
how much
it's still you
the first three cm to use
he gets
the challenge for free
the only problem is that and
first british
it's is
so this was
that was one of the
three years
one of the current
one aspect of this
they think about it
the right
it's really using the
is doing
much higher here
right before really really
three suppose
we were yesterday
i've got a a
so i will
so when we were
eight year
you say well how would you were right
i mean
he said he
how many trials
what you
we're trying to
well how we have a well
so what was
you know what
for all
three four
what mean
so what
and we all
no well how to brain
mean what fraction on the
so all in all
they must
you all
you're one is also
one thousand so that you know you
well were
this model was well
here ten two
it's a one
generates one two
so it's
it's true
i'll show
of two one hundred results
there are two
it is
if we have
the roots of
you should do
are exactly the same as non negation rules for classical logic
classical logic and intuitionist logics do not have the same
negation free theorems
so what are the rules
well the usual sorts of rules for
so if we have a we have been online for a and lines are proof
within the same depth within the same subproof
we can
include a and b that's that
and the action
and our and elimination rules are if we have a and b
we can conclude a or b
introduction rules same as usual
search like this
OK so we've got a or b is the disjunction elimination
and we can get was subproof were
starting with a hypothesis
we get c
we start with being gets a we knew we had a or b we can
conclude c because either way
that's sort of proof by cases is not very non intuitionistic about that because we
know we have a or b we should know which one we have
let's let's face it intuition is a lot of natural deduction and buy into this
i'm not an intuition is that to defend them do doing
an implication rules of usual tens of the first one is modus ponens
error minimisation and the second one
as from
a subproof
that gives us the from hypothesis that a we can conclude we can discharge a
include aerobic
actually sorry
i'm using the arrow
i should be using the hough
throughout the
i do that that's
and the reason is because i like to reserve the arrow
four out of the area
so our precious that when relevant logicians
that makes me feel better and it doesn't matter you make me feel
we have our books and in place not so these are the the the same
as the classical rules
now the interesting thing is that in in intuitionist logic when we have the negation
rules they don't give us any new theorems
in the non occasion fragment
so they don't give us any new
formulas and theorems that we could state with the negation
in classical logic they do
it what it's called intuitionist logic or in way in intuitionist logic at indication is
conservative or conservative extensions
non negation fragments
in classical logic it's not and what you get
that it's the
yes in in base out course
when i went
but it can be computed
and have been copied
the brothers have been studied
OK so what we have to define a dirichlet process DP mixture injured
we have to have this family of fungi of the
basically for the mixture components which are parameters by peter
the cluster membership is sampled exactly like before
no matter what i have got of something else
and i have to have prior distribution for the parameters theta are
and this is the only have some parameters of it all
like that sigma
so the the the model the parameters of the model two
outside the controls cluster sizes and beta which controls
prior to the parameters
which can be set independently
very flexible and then sample like before i'm sorry for being to different pages basically
example for the clusters
labels that
it's a new cluster sample parameters for the new cluster
and once they have the cluster and the parameters i sample the data we can
plot the data
OK let me see that questions about this matter
all right
then i will remind you that this is just a mental model of the data
being produced
what want to do is now
now is two
that from the data and go back and find them all
so we want to invert this process
so the problem of clustering is
he i know
the following things i know the model
in the sense that i know what kind of clusters i have
and i know
or i assume
so all the assumptions
you have put in
but the assumption that come from europe
as much
from what you happen to know about this process before you actually try to fit
the parameters
so what this is actually what the clusters do you know that
distribution of the parameters together that are likely to appear
and just like any prior cell serves also for some kind of regularization
but for example i can tell you how separated clusters should be
or how o
what are the variances should be sort of
almost equal or you allow
clusters of different shapes and different variances if you think about nature is that that's
what you put in practice
and then you have to control the distribution of
all these
the input and output and you also have the data
and you want to get the clustering here is that the parameters the model data
and you know i they want to
because when you can do in in that each point is
you can think of findings of the
the except for the one that in the same cluster they have the same
but if you it is what would be the implicit
and so you ask for this and then get a soft clustering from the data
by repeating the model
which is here or you can get hard clustering by just taking the clusters
in my opinion one the problem the bad news is that there is no closed
form solution
and what we do is actually the sort by what is called markov chain monte
carlo sampling
how many of you
you know what this is
OK then we say so
because i'm going to explain very short
so there is monte-carlo and markov chain monte
one colour means you have a distribution you drop point from it and then you
told the next point independently and so on
and you get the large sample and then you do something with it i compute
an average
in markov chain monte carlo
you want to sample from a distribution but you can't grow independent samples because
actually you can do independent samples from any distribution
there some from which you can sample from it you can
and then you the following trick
because construct the example
from the distribution so and then you change it selected with random walk through the
and these additional moves compensate for the fact that he is the weaker player and
under japanese rules again these stones have to be placed on particular points of the
board and
those are the points that are markets
here are called stop points partially
and these handicap stones must be placed on these particular points in a particular order
so that's that's a very nice property because after you've practice for while i could
have a game with you and we could have a really exciting game if i
gave you nine stones
of handicapped because then it would be quite hard for me to win and you
would have this compensation if you're beginning for example
there's another interesting thing which i would like to mention its ranking system in
and it works in a way entirely differently from the low system for example in
chess and the idea the idea you have these hugh grades and don kind of
student and master grades and
the trick is that this system is calibrated at least for amateur players against the
number of handicap stones for two people so if for example a ten q
so let's higher humans
worst player ten q playing against the five hu then the five q would grant
five handicap stones to the ten q because the difference is ten minus five gives
five so
one rank is exactly equivalent to having one less or one more handicap stones that's
very nice system and if you meet someone you don't know their strengths you have
the game you can pretty easily calibrate the system and from then on play with
the correct number of handicap stones and have fun and open game
so let's talk about computer go on computer chess
in a certain sense you could argue that computer chess
i mean many people in computer chess wouldn't agree with that but i think it
was in nineteen ninety seven there was the match between this deep blue by IBM
and kasparov
and people who was able to pull off the victory now there were
various arguments so because was the world champion at the time there are various arguments
you might bring forward that's a maybe people who wasn't as good as kasparov or
he wasn't well prepared and that this is probably too you see it
the what we can really conclude from this is that computers are pretty much at
the level of the
world champion of chess of the human world champion of chess and if they're not
there now than in five years time with additional computation time they they will be
there now state in computer go is entirely different and that can serve as another
source of inspiration and motivation for playing this game because the best computer go programs
at the level of weak amateur players so if you practice for half a year
or year then you may well be able to be the strongest computer go programs
at this game
and the various reasons why this may be the case
one reason
it may be best to understand this if you understand how chess works how computer
chess works we've talked about these game trees so computer chess is all about enumerating
the possibilities for for each player's moves get all these leave positions evaluate them and
use minimax search over the street to find the best move now obviously that requires
two things
you need to be able to explore this tree
and in chess you typically have maybe twenty different moves per side of the good
but in goal of course the entire board available so you have more like two
hundred moves available at any any move so that's one reason why this is so
hard but the other problem is that of course in in go all the stones
look pretty much like i mean except for their black and white cells but the
blackstone's look alike they don't have different values per say not like night or a
in chess but they only derive their value from the position on the board and
from the complex interactions between stones and that's the reason why this much harder to
find a good evaluation function and the
the evaluation function is the second ingredient if you want to approach this problem like
computer chess because at the bottom you need to evaluate all the leaves so that
doesn't work really well and that's the reason computer go is struggling a lot
one interesting observation is
that's a good human players can make moves
the car
and there's a model
called the dependent dirichlet process
which is
extremely popular in nonparametric bayesian statistics
it's not used so much in machine learning but
i think that just as a matter of
topics that people focus on
machine learning
one big application of nonparametric bayesian modeling for example are topic models and natural language processing so
the through to the get used a lot of things like direct directly processes
because topic models in the pitman yor process because this power-law property and so on
whereas a nonparametric bayesian statistics
people are interested in in all kinds of applications where
you have this covariate dependence
and this model is
you know and in some sense is actually maybe a bit of a hack but it's it's just
you know it's just hit nerve and it's it's
maybe the most popular modification of of the iterative process nonparametric statistics
what we do is we have these
we had these
the cluster sizes and the cluster locations
and i said you know making them functions of the covariates right hand
we know that these
cluster weights
that they are between zero and one
and now they take as input the take a parameter they take a covariate value so say time
and so that becomes a function from
time from the time axis into zero one
can and we have to
think about how we can model that function
and similarly reported that the parameter values we have a function from time into the set of possible parameters
that's the parameters
okay and now the idea and the dependent dirichlet processes
if we have we have to
we have to model smooth functions here
so why do we use a gaussian process
and this
four hour
four these
cluster weights you that's a bit of a problem because as john told you this
morning when we use a gaussian process
and we
we look at one particular time point right the girls process gives us a random function
and now we fix one time point and we look at the function value at that time
what is the distribution of the functionality
the function is random so that is a random variable what is the distribution
it's a gas
because it's a process
galson is a distribution on the on the real line
what we want to hear something that is in zero one
right we don't want something that's on the entire real line
so we have to sum transformers
and also we want to have a specific distribution you if we want to have iterative process because we know
the process stick breaking construction these weights have to be the variables
otherwise something else is going to pop up
we have to transform this calcium to have
these these girls variables at each time point to have a marginal distribution that speed
so you have to and that's why i said it's a bit of a hack because you have to
sample from the gaussianprocess and then put it through a transformation
that turns it into a beta
that is possible by means of cumulative distribution functions but it's just a bit
computationally intensive
and then similarly
similar we look
so i
what we do in specifically is that we use the stick breaking construction we sample these
these proportions if you remember that we used to construct the weights we sample the
proportions on the gaussianprocess can be variables and then apply this formula for
for computing the weights from the stick breaking construction
and so the idea is
make iterative process dependent by looking at the components that occur in the stick breaking construction
and turn them into functions that vary smoothly and time
these functions have to have the right marginal distributions at each time point so that
directly process comes out
so if we do that what do we get we get
it we get a distribution that is if we fix time point
and looked at the margin clustering the distribution of the clustering that we get at that time point
say one frame in the video
the distribution is actually iterative process
these clustering solutions very smoothly in time
and house mostly depends on how we set
the covariance function of the girls in process
all right so the
kind of
this is specific to the during process of course right that uses this this very
specific construction definition of the stick breaking process
for the process
but but you can
if you just look at this idea you can really
you can generalize this and the general theme is that
we have
some some random object you that has a certain distribution and then we have a
covariance random object is say the discrete random measures then we have the covariate space
time space or whatever that is supposed to an extent
and we have to turn this
in two
a random function that maps into
the set of possible run amok you know this kind of a general the general idea
so now we have seen
my talk yesterday and john talk this morning
and what actually so far what we have seen as we have seen a bunch
of models we seen the dark process that you're process
the new buffet process
we've seen some process
and we have seen ways of how we can combine these models together in
and with that we can
that accounts for are actually
for most of the models that we have in bayesian nonparametrics in one way or another
end when i
when you attain idea even if the trio on this last last december
u i made this this list here
because he feared it would be nice to just you know
just have a list of all models and and relate them to
the applications and to
to what type of parameter we are using
so remember in the bayesian model
these kind of these intuition that try to convey yesterday is that the parameters some
kind of pattern that play explains the data
what type of pattern to use and what do we get
so we have a classification and regression models
in that case the parameters function
and the political model for the girls process right
then when we do clustering the pattern is a partition and so the model for that is
the chinese restaurant process are directed process but this is an
we can also use the director process for density estimation and so on and so
forth right you can do this hierarchical
what you can see is that the
if you go through this list there's a certain
there's a certain set of of
of basic models that we used to use to generate all of these these different models
i want to
what i want to do next as i want to talk forum
but first i want to use a few slides to talk about what we can
possibly do you want to go beyond
what would be involved in how difficult is that i can tell you it's not easy to do
so that's basically enough
now what i was trying to show we're trying to show
that this
is minimized by something in FS
right we were trying to show that the minimiser of this lies in this
some of bump functions on data points
i suppose it's not
there is
and this
so f study the solution to this right it as
after as plus f perpendicular
then for each point
after that affects is equal to f as of exile right because f as effect
size was so before has the same value f f star affects i hope you
this fact
then the loss function
is the same because it's only depends on this one
on the other hand we make that thing short for this
so this is the same for fast
and this is
at least
not long for short maybe maybe small
so by going from left to fester the decrees
this whole some by leaving this first part to be exactly the same as before
making this possibly short
so OK so that means that when for this thing became smaller but it cannot
be smaller because it's already the minimum
so that this
therefore the minimum has to lie in
this space
in s
so the minimum is actually the sum of the parts
again this is
important argument because this is actually what makes this algorithms work
so finally this is basically repeating it f stars and as the first time this
it's a linear combination of the pump
former fast so you can you can think of this as being gaussians e to
the next i minus x squared
o so you maybe that's a good point
i should say that directly
so for the gaussians it's OK
x y
he calls
let me just say it was the x minus y
and you can do you think about it being
or they can be vector does not
let me just make some simple real numbers
make it as simple as possible
now what is the norm so k
door so this is the function of the dot x is fixed
and k
again this is a function of the dot
not all wise fixi fix x and a fixed like this is the function now
i want to to compute the inner product
in the corresponding space and this is just k of x
so this is the definition of the product for this functions
that's what
the product
and you have to play a little bit of this to make sure that somehow
it makes sense
right so basically with when you have three guys what happens is that because they're
quite far
k of x minus lies close to zero so they're almost orthogonal then you just
have three of orthogonal that three
i the it's just the somewhere in theorem saying that this one plus one plus
one square so if you have an bombs and they're quite far from each other
users does get square root of n as you know
this is just an intuition you have to be but it's
i think it's a good
OK so
so this this this is the case for the gaussians
let's not talk a little bit
about algorithms
so here is the first algorithm
take f
to be this more specific thing
i just take least squares fit
so at this point i just feet f of x i minus y i
plus i had this penalty so it's basically the same as before i just to
the loss function to be square
i know that the solution is of this form
that that's what i shot
so that's really is a bit of the of the subject but this is something
we developed for fun but it ended up being put in microsoft
image editing product which is out on the shelf near you
so now let's
get onto the the real business which is
how to model consoles
this should all work
so first of all i just can give you a sort of brief pointed to
the history of contour tracking
then i'm going to talk about this business of how to make the state space
is that represent both the variations the expect because of rigid body motion and the
variations that you expect because of
various deformations and then finally i'm going to describe how a curve fitting algorithm with
these models might work on it in this section i'm going to talk about the
deterministic fitting model but then in the next section will start reinterpreting everything as a
and see how that works and i mean the benefits of doing things probabilistically is
that also gives you then a key into how to learn the parameters in the
models that
we need to use
so outline models why for one more application just for the fun of it here's
some work was done with medics in in oxford where they wanted to track the
outline of images of the heart
and if you've had a heart attack
then a segment of muscle on this on this contour effectively has died and it
it doesn't stop moving so it's not as easy as it just detecting fact we
start moving body moves in a kind of lazy way
but it's being carried by ninety is neighbours is not really doing anything itself and
built software to analyse which was the lazy
contour and that
OK but yes one thing i want to point out is that there are no
distinguished features on this contour also there are no corners will be so so much
easier to solve the tracking problem if part controls would go around with all you
know tags on them or if they would please agree to be polygonal or something
so that we could we could catch on the vertices of the contour and track
them as they are but they just won't do that
so we really have to try to make things that will
track tools so actually there was a revolutionary idea
i was very excited when i this in eighty eight from cast openness and we
can the idea of the snake which you know the time computer vision was little
bit bogged down trying to use two-dimensional signal processing methods image analysis methods to make
structure emerges from images so was very popular at the time to take an image
invent a filter perhaps non-linear filter that would pull out consoles from the image that
was supposed to correspond to important physical contortion because what happened was
either you were so stringent field so stringent that missed important contours in the image
and everyone was upset all the
the filter was so generous that pulled the consuls but also a whole host of
other junk which humans can see we're not important so it becomes very frustrating and
they work with paper after paper about optimal edge detectors each one slightly more optimal
to have that than than the than the last
so this was a breath of fresh air because these young chaps i suppose there
in in the fifties now but they were young chaps had invented this method that
you know smelt of
computer games kind of made this live curve and they would drop it on an
image and it was kind of move around in the image of a lot of
the things if i really felt like a lot of fun and they provide a
toolkit to help manipulate these curves so they work because the naturally attracted to object
to call contours in the image but also you could sort of place above the
next one to sort of saying no i don't want you to look over here
the o thing was refreshing because it seemed to do away not just because it
was fun because it did away
with this mindset about and analyse images from the bottom up only and expecting good
structure to work to appear and people have lost patience with that and just in
the nick of time these people quite not with this idea that in principle would
allow you to come in with the strong object hypothesis
and sort of apply this hypothesis to the world so if you're a squirrel knew
looking for nuts that you would have a snake
one of these active condors in the shape of the outline of not and you
can drop it into the world and sort of see where
not work you know maybe an extremely efficient but it certainly contrasts with the idea
of taking the entire scene and analyzing everything in the scene including the branches and
leaves of grass and in really spending a lot of time on things that we're
not going to be interesting so here's the formalism you have contour are best which
parameterize from one zero to one and the feature map f of r which is
built yes using signal processing i mean image processing applied to the image to a
to enhance
important features but there's a big difference between enhancing features and actually detecting and detecting
was to have been announcing show you pictures and it is perfectly reasonable and now
we define
they defined and energy
which was the integral of this feature map f of along the
hypothetical could are less so now you can imagine moving the curve of our best
around in order to score as highly as possible on this feature map function f
but that might not be enough so
the gradient of this this cost function or energy we can think of as being
forced that will pull the curve distributed force that will pull curve towards features in
the image
and but that might not be enough for you because you probably want to impose
or prefer some kind of regularity in the curve so how about including some
regularizers for length the first derivative and the curvature of the second derivative that will
the when you omit minimize balance all of these these forces will
give you a compromise between regularity of the curve and adherence to these features and
this can be computed in practice by approximating curve
the curve as as the finite element chain or using finite differences
differences for first of design in second derivatives and turning this whole thing into a
numerical scheme
here i said i j the feature maps here are
the sort of thing you might get feature maps is something the top right something
that is supposed to
he doesn't show up very well for you i can see that you can
supposed to enhance edges in the scene respond to
areas of high contrast and here are ridges points of maximum brightness so you see
this highlight here has a rich following it and then
right well thank you very much for the quick
thing here the organisers and
indeed talk about is to allow the his sorry
so you have to talk about human travel patterns and
there is no better place to start with monkeys tigers
and why do we care about these monkeys will of course one reason we care
about them is because there was a group of researchers from from mexico
who had been tracking very close their motion and it's kind of one of the
issues of course the trick that
becomes interesting is how do you tracker monkeys motion and probably the best guess we
all of us have is that you would actually put the GPS on that
and it's true it's all that actually gps involved in that but rather the GPS
was not in the monkeys but undergraduate students
so there was always a distant under each monk in the forest and they would
rather than twenty four hours essential that would change each other and the position was
tracked essentially and that's how do we know where the monkeys
the end however is that they ended up getting trajectories like that that indicate how
the monkeys moved around in in space in this big forest on different scales and
the conclusion was that the best way to describe this trajectory is not random motion
but the think that this is actually really what matters
in the way the fact that animals may finally before but was not
new idea at the moment but rather the idea came from a seminal paper by
richemont on it'll just group nineteen ninety six track trusses and they found that the
again the trajectory follows a kind of this lady pattern and then he two years
later they came up with an explanation that it's very much to the kind of
the community was interested an emotion
because they found that
the reason why animals follow such only pattern it's because it's actually optimized for finding
food so if the animal is tries to find hard to find patches of food
then the best way to do that is to not to kind of searches around
the one but rather to do big jumps occasionally and in many many small steps
so the ladyhawke actually is really an optimal strategy in that respect and that's pretty
much the problem and there lots of work and then in the community who have
from that type of trajectory really follow really kind of describes many different dimensions many
different species
then of course for those of you who followed some of the field this year
there was a big surprise that the group was actually done the original owners have
gone back and analyse the data and they said that not as much the sources
don't follow around the world the fly but it's just hard to conclude on the
existing data there was some problem with how the data was collected by the biologist
so therefore kind of the idea became somewhat shaky whether really animals follow that but
if you still there
and and kind of a few months after this paper indicated that may be of
course is that the floods came out the very detailed paper by seems that has
many many different sea animals and they found very strong evidence for this living type
of motion so what i'm showing here is something that formed from the same set
of people this is the basking shark is the trajectory they looked at other sharks
but they looked at sea turtles and stingrays and so on and for each of
them the best way to describe the trajectory was to assume that is actually on
the flight
so what are the only reason i'm telling you this is the kind of understand
that there is a very good growing body of literature now
in the emotional community and then biologists is very interested in particular subject that animals
do not simple around the world but rather actually follow this limit trajectories
now the question comes up is what do we do because obviously one of the
reason that animals do that is because they are searching for food
and just kind of a summary you know like do any necessary for flight or
not was just the conference a few weeks ago in stockholm which was focused on
this problem and i think the consensus in the community is that really there's very
strong evidence they do
but of course is yes or no and i think the question is not is
much more about data there are other they follow it or not but the question
is what humans do i mean obviously not searching for food so that the pattern
is not determined by the need to kind of go and find patches of food
that are hidden somewhere in the fits
so so therefore we would expect that perhaps there is no reason for us to
have nearly trajectory
the surprise came about two years ago when there was a study indicated that is
not so and and indeed we do follow the path
and if we go
this kind of summarise so what is the difference between the random walk on radio
four and the simple random walk everybody committee knows what is that a moving forward
the roughly the same distance in every time time frame
three something what you see over here this is nothing but around the world however
the difference between the two is that the the size distribution of the consecutive jumps
not gaussian that function as an around the world but rather comes from power law
distribution and you can talk about lady flights only works and there's a wonderful because
papers by actually discusses the differences between them but the point is that when you
look at the leaf
visually you can see very very different from around the world because did was striking
it is very very long jumps in the trajectory
so the question is what do we do humans do we do really reflect what
you see over here that we do and walk what we see here or something
and so so
the first thing back came about two two years ago on that
and can very interesting direction
there is there was there's about site which is based in boston that is meant
to attract money had so you think about the bill and you want to visual
i'm not telling the model that uses image specific priors images should look like this
insight is just the standard algorithm so if i played
apply exact same algorithm
two hundred character recognition
and at the local level he discovers these little strokes at higher level
it figures out high-level strokes and this is again just by looking at the data
which we think is the right representation four modeling handwritten characters
and if you look at the type of
structural classes that discovery
you know it's basically saying all these hidden characters get put together in each one
of them basically shares the same distribution high-level parts and each one of these had
defines a distribution over low-level parts
so it figures out on its own different alphabets if you if you
think about we see no groups together reasonable
characters in terms of performance again these models do much much better in terms of generalizing to new things
but one thing you can do is you can ask them all to generate new characters
now that understand something about characters let's say
this is the real data that's it one particular so cause
and i can ask the more can you actually generate new characters that have the
same statistical properties it is these characters
right hand because it's a generative model yes indeed we can simulate from this model
if we simulate from this is what it looks like
so these are completely housing it that is nothing like that in the training set
it just makes things up
you know if i give you this self about is what generates
causes and again
this is very different from what you see in the training data so really i generalizes
obviously something like that is much more difficult to generate
but the same model can be applied speech text video in in in any other high dimensional data
in fact if you apply the same model to modeling motion capture data
principles i showed these these two different
right so one is known as the work one of them is the drunken walk
right so the data here is just the time series each
motion capture is characterized by its different points
through time
now let's say you know you're looking at these different walks in now
i'm gonna show you a sexy work and i'm only gonna show you sixty frames of sexy work right
so this has sixty work looks like
i am
basically by just you don't need to look at you know thousands of examples of
sex work for you to figure out what sex workers right
and indeed if you apply this model to this kind of structure we're trying to
grouped together different works and figure out what's shared between those different walks
you can do much better in terms of recognizing sexy well from all the other works
right so this is again the same thing can be applied to sort of modeling time
time series data which is which is quite exciting
now in the last part of the tutorial so we've got so far about
both machines one shot learning learning structured models
so now we're gonna look at the related problem of multimodal learning
so if we could be
datasets today
is basically
you know it's a collection of modalities right images associated with text if you look
at robotics applications you have lots of different sensors how can integrate all these different
modalities together
so that's a very exciting research directions in
in the machine learning and deep learning communities
right which is like the is you'd like to get modality free representation given image
and text like that some semantic meaning from both of these modalities
and obviously this can be useful right so he can be useful for maybe one improve classification
the fact that
you know you have a word that says kangaroo island
might be
a very useful thing for you to actually recognise that you somewhere on this is somewhere in australia right
so it could be useful for classification it could be useful for filling missing modalities
given an image can you can describe what's going on in the image
it also useful forty true also if i show you a bunch of words actually related images
so if i can model these different modalities i can do a lot of
a lot of things together
so one thing you can do is you can cycle on the joint distribution of
images and text or tags in this case words
age here the latent representation will be diffused representation
the semantic representation of both of these modalities