little subspace and it's true subspace then
there's got to be some more in right i have to be able to multiply
that by two
and that and that double vector has to be included
i have to be able to multiplied by zero
the vector or by
or by three-quarters of all these vectors or by minus
or by minus one
i have to be able to multiplied by any number
so that is going to say that i have to have a whole line
did you see that
one side get a vector in there i got the whole line of all
multiples of that vector i can't
can be a vector space without
included without extending to to get those multiples in there now i still have to
check addition
but that comes out OK this line is going to work
because i could add something on the lines
there's something else on the line and i'm still line
so for example
so this is all examples
example of a subspace
our example is a line
in r two
actually not as any
if i took this line
with that so all the vectors on that line so that factor and that factor
in this vector in the vector
so in end
i am
drawing something that doesn't work
it's not a subspace
the line in order to have to be a subspace the line are two
must go through
the zero vector
because why is this line of good let me do it dashed line
because if i multiply that vector on the dashed line by zero then it does
not on the dashed line zero is going to be
every subspace has got to contain zero because i must be allowed to multiplied by
zero and that will always give me the zero
now i was going to
create some subspaces
well i mean are two
why we think of all the possibility
are two there can be that many
so what are the possible subspaces of r two
i me list
so all those so i'm listing now the subspaces
of the art
one possibility that we always allow is
all of our two
the whole thing
the whole space
that counts as a subspace of itself
you always want to allow that
than others
or lines
any line
line meaning infinitely far in both directions through
the then zero
so that's what that's like
the whole space is like a whole two d space
this is like one is that is this line the same as or one no
i don't know
you could say it looks a lot like are one
our one was just a line and this is the line but this is online
inside our two that the vectors here i have two components
so that's not the same as are one because they are the vectors only one
very closely
but that no
about the same
and now there's a third possibility
there's a third subspace
that's a far too that's not not the whole thing
and it's not line
it's even less
it's just the zero vector alone
the zero vector along only
often call this subspace the just for you
here's the line l
here's the plane all of our two
you see that the zero vector is OK
you just to understand subspaces we have to know the rules and knowing the rules
means that we have to see that yes
the zero vector by itself
just this guy alone satisfies the rules wise that out too dumb to tell you
if i took that and added to itself i'm still there
if i took that and multiply by seventeen i'm still there
so i've i've done the operations adding and multiplying by numbers
that are required and i didn't go outside
this one point
that's always as that's the little a subspace the largest subspaces the whole thing and
in between come all
whatever is in between
OK so for example what's in between for our three
so if i'm an ordinary three dimensions
the subspaces are
all of our three
one extreme the zero vector at the bottom
r and then
a plane
so this is interesting for several reasons
what did he
managed to pull out information why
from using these relationship and actually to do this he made a few more observations
the first which i just stated that the deflection of the negative particle was just
far away are more extreme much much larger than that of the positive particle
the other assumption that he made here is that the charge on the two particles
with equal
so how could you know that the charge in the two particles with equal and
actually can exactly know it was a very good
the assumption that he made and he could make the assumption
because he in fact know that what he started when was this hydrogen gas so
he was starting with hydrogen if some the negative particle was popping out from the
hydrogen then what he must be left with his age plus
and since hydrogen itself is neutral the each class and the electron had to add
up to be in neutral charge so that means the charges of the two pieces
the positive and negative particle must be equal in terms of absolute charge
so using this relationship you can actually figure out by knowing which she knows how
each of them were deflected he can now try to think about
whether or not he could
make some relationship between the masses between the
the mass of the positive and the negative particle
so this relationship he was looking at was starting
with the deflection
and the absolute distance that the particles were deflected so what he can set equal
to if he knows what x is proportional to in terms of the negative particle
so that just the absolute value of the charge
the mass of the negative particle
you could divide all of that
by the absolute value
of the charge of the positive particle
all over the map
the positive particle
and as we said he made the assumption that those two charges were equal
so we can go ahead and cross those right now
so what that told him with if he knew the relationship between how far they
each displaced
you could also know something about the relationships
of the two masses so essentially
there was an inversely proportional
the relationship between how far the particles would place and what the math that you
it turned out to be
so because you have caused the observed that
the negative particle traveled it was deflected much much further by the way
what he could also assumes and make the conclusion of is that the math
the negative particle
is actually larger smaller
much much smaller exactly the the mass
of the positive particle so essentially what he found here is the relationship between the
mass of an electron
the mass of the rest of the out the rest of the hydrogen atom there
which is an iron in this case
and in fact it so so much smaller than it's close to two thousand times
smaller that we can make the assumption
that essentially
the electrons take no massimino take up a teeny bit essentially when we're thinking about
the set up of the and we don't have to call for them using up
a lot of them as we're discussing
so thompson came up with a model
for the atom due to this and this is called the plum pudding model of
the atom
and he was said english so plum pudding is kind of british food is anyone
here had one putting
a couple people OK
i've never even seen so that's good must
but travel than i so the idea that he had here was he treated the
whole of the atom sort of the positive class are the positive
so the majority of the and was just kind of this could be positive stuff
that you can think about with the winning he had all these negative charges
which were the electrons
they were the ravens are the ones that were in the pudding
so this was a revolutionary model of an atom when we thought of the fact
that before this experiment understanding was an atom could not be divisible into smaller parts
and now here we are with subatomic particles with electrons and this wonderful plum pudding
so for those of you that have actually had plum pudding which myself included i
drew picture up here this is my first place upon planning and i guess you
and is related to the question did the universe actually have a begining I won`t speak
about the beginning because there is not yet been established any observations that would give us any
answer to these questions there is an end to inflation and the at the
end of inflation the universe is frozen it is an extremely low entropy universe dominated by vacuum energy
somehow the universe dominated by vacuum energy has to be changed into the
hot universe dominated by radiation the energy density driving inflation has to be extracted and
converted into radiation how this happens we don't know the universe has to be defrosted
and whether it`s heating preheating reheating we don't know we have names for various ideas that happen
however we don't know how it happened but it's possible there were observable consequences of this
phase perhaps baryogenesis occurred here perhaps there was phase transitions or dark matter produced I won't
have time to talk about this phase but it's something that's amenable at least in principle
to observations the middle of inflation is what I would like to talk about where density
perturbations in gravitational waves were produced and again we imagine this is due to the
fact that particles are produced due to the expanding universe now we're going to
envision the dynamics of the expansion of the universe during inflation as the dynamics that are driven
by the action of scalar field and we're going to employ everything out of this information we
know about scalar quantum field theory so scalar quantum field theory is going
to be the tool that we use to connect fluctuations in a metric density fluctuations
curvature fluctuations to quantum fluctuations in a scalar field and the reason we do
this is that of course as I mentioned before there are so many fundamental scalar fields that are known
so why not use everything we know about scalar field dynamics
however the thing to remember in this demonstration is that we're using scalar field dynamics is
a tool and if a hammer is your only tool everything looks like a nail
so we don't really know whether it was driven by scalar field dynamics because that's but that's
the way we model it because scalar field scalar quantum field theory is a well-developed
tool that we can use so in scalar quantum field theory we imagine that
there is a scalar field and we have a wonderful name for the scalar field we call it
the inflaton but of course naming is not explaining we just have a name for it's
a cool name the inflaton and there is some potential energy associated with the inflaton
the potential energy of a scalar field you can imagine as the energy of the infinite wavelength mode
the zero momentum mode of the inflaton field and if you would ask in a particle language what is
the particle contnent of the universe associated with the vacuum energy it would be a condensate
infinite wavelength particles of the inflaton field so you can imagine for some reason that
the inflaton field is not at the minimum of the potential which is conveniently adjusted
in this case to have zero vacuum energy zero potential energy while the inflaton is displaced
from its minimum it has an energy density and effective cosmological constant dark energy
but component contributing W equal to minus one then through just classical equations of motion you
can imagine the inflaton field rolling down the potential relaxing to its
minimum where the potential energy is zero magically radiating all its kinetic energy to form radiation and
inflation comes to an end so this is the classical picture of a universe that's dominated by
inflation and then evolves in such a way that inflation ends when the field reaches
the minimum of its potential however if there is particle creation due to
the expansion of the universe the expansion of the universe will create particles
of the inflaton field the particles of the inflaton field created by the expansion
of the universe have a finite wavelength so you`re creating finite wavelength mode to the field
and the distribution of the field will not be smooth so in addition to the classical
smooth background there are fluctuations in the field as a result of particle creation in
the expanding universe which lead to fluctuations in the field since the field dominates the energy density
fluctuations in the field amount to fluctuations in the energy density curvature fluctuations and will
also appear as temperature fluctuations so that is the it's something we described word calculus
there's no equation gen just words but a physical feeling I hope you can get about
the origin of the density perturbations and one of the questions that`s related to high-energy
physics is we have this scalar field we have this inflaton who is this inflaton
what where does this scalar field come from no one well maybe people who believe in the anthropic principle
but no reasonable person would think that this scalar field exists only for the purpose of making
nice perturbations in the universe so we can go out and see a nice sky at night presumably this scalar field
is related to some particle physics models and phenomenologically I want to
captured and i the number of samples captain and is the number of samples
for the base points and capital and is the number of samples used for the
next state of those they those based point
and you can prove born in this form
and i'm not going to go into the details of this the good news is
that this bald
goes down to zero is and and and goes to infinity
this is an interesting guy so this one has to terms this guy here
are actually see terms this this guy here is called the the bomb and the
estimation error
so since you are using monte carlo
everything you do is is more is little bit so you have some variance
check out two
reduce the variance the way he use a very interesting is the number of samples
so the other turning the ball
is this guy here
so this is a distance between
the image of the function space the bellman operator under bellman operator
so hard to imagine that so you take your function space
and you pick the function there are
and you compute its image under thirty so maybe
the maps this function outside of origin of function space maps here
you do this for all the functions here or it's function space
and you get he
so the image space
and what you do is that
well you say that
well i am doing value iteration my target function so i'm going to become from
this set
and what i'm doing fitting
my functions actually coming from this set
so if i can keep
so the distance between these two sets small
in then in each iteration my errors would be small so the
finally should be small as well
so what you do is you compute the distance which is defined in the following
way so you begin the function
you pick up you pick the function that's farthest away
from f in
so maybe this functions and is going to be the stuff
so you want to design
this function spaces such as such a way that this sense is small so
that term is depicted in the regression it is required that call the approximation error
so this is a little bit different here
because we are doing good reinforcement learning and not just regression but otherwise is pretty
much the same so you have the approximation error
you have the estimation error bars
and so you have this other term here that decays exponentially fast is the number
of iterations
and so you know there's the truncation error so after k iterations you stopped
one of the resulting error is proportional to the government to the power of case
so this is
for the same reason as
i've shown you before this just that works
OK so the next question is how to choose
the function space and
well it seems that it would be a good idea to to use the latter
function space but if you use the latter function space and may be heard about
you you run the risk of for fitting this user more some less
but if you know the number of
some persist fixed
well you're not allowed to increase the number of samples in other ways
then if you increase the size of the function space then you are going to
off the
the moment of or if anything is a termite hall reach their function class is
and there are various quantities
how two
quantify that saying
and i'm not going to go into the deaths of that
but the thing is that the fingers are function space
to go back to the bond i was not
very very not explaining what turned here
we have this absolute got here so this depends on the size of the function
so if you increase the size of the function space this increases
this for degrees but this increases so there is this trade this
sometimes called the bias variance tradeoff because for certain is approximation error that sort of
the second term
bombing the
estimation error
and that's sort of the very same
and so
you have this dilemma of how to choose a function space f
it seems that their myspace of choosing the function space so
for example you could have this archaeologists spaces and you could
user in particular function space like that and that he is
the capacity after as could be bonded by
just the lower the number of samples in this case so that studies by chance
and so
the good news about this bond is that this is independent of
the dimensionality of phi
so you can really use this bizarre creatures which are infinite dimensional
so the only
lacking detail is that
well i guess no one really understand what the corresponding class family for which this
method would work pretty well
would be
that's again an open problem and
good topic for period is this may
OK so
this is all what i wanted to say about planning
and let's move on to learning
so its contents so first i'm going to just define the problem and then i'm
talking about
it's the end of it
that are accessible from either pages found
but the official website is going to be updated with
the newer slides from
so i'm going to define the problem first and then
the first stopping is is learning optimally allowing fast way
the have scanning it was too rare and still to this day very very expensive
so now he's moving across
the transition metals he gets to copper and you can use zinc for reasons i'm
going to show you very shortly namely that the energy in that to be so
high that is going to melt physics so he says instead of use brass which
is an alloy of copper and zinc
and so this is this is the data from
this study
and so here's the first one of the first page of the paper the author
intends to make a general survey of the principal types high-frequency radiation
examine the specter of a few elements in greater detail
results already obtained showed that such data have an important bearing on the question of
the internal structure of the atom
and further support the views of rutherford and of bore
this is what he is
this is what he's putting up here for us
what i want to show is that
when he took his results
this is what he found he tried to
get out a better functionality of this relationship between
wavelengths an atomic weights
here's what he found work best
he found that if he plotted
not the wavelength but the wave number we've seen before the wave number as a
function of proton number
in fact the square of the proton number
he got a linear relationship
and let's just say this is this would be l alpha
l beta
o k alpha
let's say you're copper
so copper would be twenty nine
square so he would get he would get data for the l alpha line of
copper they'll be copper keil full copper KB line of copper he might not get
all four lines for every element but he would take sets of data and plot
them only found that if you plotted the reciprocal of the wavelength versus the square
of the proton number the points lay online so over here would be eliminated
and over here would be
over here would be gold
and this was extremely important this changed so much because look at what he's able
to conclude here let's let's read his
this paper here we have you're proved that there is in the atom of fundamental
quantity which increases by regular steps as we pass from one element to the next
this quantity can only be the charge on the central positive nucleus
of the existence of which we have already definite proof
and i remember when mandalay have enunciated the law of periodicity he said that the
properties of the elements are a function of the atomic weight
the function of the atomic weight and people were perplexed by the fact that potassium
less massive than our but no one would put our gone under sony here
but mandolins law is that you arrange things by atomic mass
cobalt and nickel
i reversed
what to do
here's mostly we are therefore led by experiment to view that and and his capital
and is what we call proton number
is the same as the number of the place occupied by the element in the
periodic system
this atomic number is coining the term this atomic numbers then for hydrogen one for
helium two for lithium three four calcium twenty four zinc thirty et cetera
we can confidently predict that in a few cases in which the order of the
atomic weights a clashes with the atomic or the periodic system the chemical properties are
governed by and
while a itself
probably a complicated function of
this is brilliant this is a graduate student in nineteen thirty
correcting mandalay if
what are the implications what are the implications of this proton number we're now going
to give it its do we're going to call it z
the atomic number this is the social security number of every atom
the atomic number
atomic number
what's the significance of
this paper first of all corrected mandalay
not to say that mandalay was
back and the live was brilliant and what he did but there are a few
things that live couldn't account for so now we know
in the post mostly world
that periodicity
periodicity that is the periodic variation in properties is not a function of
mass it's no longer function of atomic mass as per mandalay have but rather a
function of atomic number
the function of atomic number
OK and this
now resolve the problems with are gone
cobalt nickel
to learning and iodine
these three were known
these three were known in mandalay have kept saying going measure them again the atomic
masses are wrong
and he was right in certain instances they did find a number of
in the incorrect values but these were among that group and lastly appear that they
wouldn't have known uranium
and that too many more in the wrong
he said OK well that's that's cute but let's show something else
by understanding that the atomic number is the critical factor in determining where something belongs
in the periodic table he was able to
place the land finite if you look at most periodic tables from the early part
of the twentieth century they don't know where to put the there their try valence
so they tend to put them under alone maybe understanding they don't know what to
so with this he was able to place the land tonight's
and more importantly he was able to
predict that there are fourteen of
there are fourteen all
how do you do that
it's really simple
it was discovered in nineteen thirty nine
eleven was discovered in nineteen thirty nine
it has an atomic mass
one hundred thirty eight points
nine one and there are various other landslides knives that had been discovered
and i'm going to put in the TCM which had been discovered only recently in
nineteen o seven
that's cheque
much happier
that is
all rights which
persons law
that should be
that we get that
she become more apparent
in in classical logic we don't get that intuitionist logic OK so what's the difference
in difference is going to be the negation
fragment racer systems
in case is wrong and i will leave it up to the next person saying
as personal i think lookup chris long google
and you find the statement of charge anyway that's what you get with classical logic
and not intuitionist logic i should know these things i'm inclined lag
OK now what else
it's the intuition the intuitionist negation is what's going to get to us OK which
the negation rules
OK the negation introduction rule
is fairly straightforward
the negation
elimination rule that i'm giving it's not the usual
straightforward to
he said OK
all those that we actually many another rule
what are the world we need
i mean
o point which instigation
we introduce this thing called as
we know the rules to govern it
so rule which i think would you use ref
f is also to foster
anything follows from that
OK that's coming important thing for us and the
and that's in intuitionist logic so anything follows from a contradiction f stands for the
because in intuitionist logic unlike relevant articles with say
all contradictions are equal
are all equivalent
any contradiction leads to everything
so it is intuitionist logic is like classical logic
now what happens
OK sorry that's are that f elimination and f elimination rule
with the introduction rule
we think
well this is actually kind of the same story this is the introduction rule
usually what people say there isn't one introduction
you can never actually get to a point where you can
there should be also there but it's true this is really the introduction
so we don't need any more rules
what about that one
let's get rid of the person
if we get rid of that we actually get a different larger corsica different logic
if you have rules
one in which f does not
give us
that logic is called minimal logic
and that's something you should have written and you know it
is intuitionist logic minus
and so courses
a huge body of
research on a news about that when it converges in superlinear convergence it
and so on and so forth and
all that's research is a special case of
interior point methods
and so
it doesn't always converge this only converges if x is
less than or equal to one
now you can make newton's method converge by not being so bold as taking a
whole step but shortening the step
so you have to try to do something like that
one of the things that
some people
of of
implemented is is is a filter type methods
to help guide the choice of the steplength
anthony tried it briefly
give some hints as to what this is about
we end up with this hash and matrix
plus a transpose w inverse why eh
well i guess
you can see that when i saw when i solve these equations at least one
the ways i got something very much like this
i got
i i this works see what this was my matrix this was my passion matrix
so x inverses my
o so identity and the way that the dual
this is done by the dual i guess like all the dual form matrix
do that
but it anyway use all
over there that i got something that looks like this
if you go in the other direction and somebody other variable first
delta delta x and so delta why here
you get a image a matrix that looks like this multiplying your system equations
you get eight transposed times eight with the diagonal matrix in the middle
the piece that was up
are were was
yeah appear age
the hessian matrix
and so that's the matrix that you have this invert
to get your delta x is in this case
because it's the dual it
end and so this is the matrix that determines everything
and if this is positive definite
then than than than than has a unique inverse and you can
calculate your delta
x and u delta one delta w
so if the so what we see with this theorem say exactly suppose that this matrix is positive definite
if the current solution is primal and feasible
the delta x
delta w the step direction and the primal side
is a descent direction for the infeasibility vector not for the measurement is ability the norm
aged x minus w
and so far invisible
and this is positive definite then one step improves the situation with respect feasibility
if the current solution
is feasible
then delta x delta w is the set
direction for the barrier function
that's all the objective function with the very terms added in
and as you get smaller becomes close to the objective function
so when more feasible
things improve with every iteration be infeasibility gets smaller with every iteration would once we get feasible
the barrier function gets better with every iteration and if we decrease mu at every
iteration the barrier function gets closer and closer to the actual objective function and this
all this says it all work
but it always has a descent direction
that means initially for small enough
step it will work so and i added do the line search the figure out
how help
how big a step like you can take that still maintains that you have these properties
so from linear programming that was
descent direction and
and it continued to be a descent direction causes linear nothing there is no curvature
to it and was going down it was always going down
you know it's only initially good and so you have to do a line search the
figure out how far you can go before things start to go bad
so you have to take shorter steps
that's for convex optimization
works just fine
so this is the paper on shift and rotation invariant reconstruction but again it's either
shift or rotation invariant actually this is the thing is quite useful
in time series analysis like e g PG EEG signals people actually use this sort
of representation when we want to
recognise patterns in that gained what we're interested in is generalizing this theory
to the case
of noncommutative groups for such as translation and rotation together
and this leads us to one music by spectral
so the idea
is that
what drives classical by spectra
it is still present in the noncommutative constraints in the world when we talk about
the general properties of harmonic analysis on groups we saw something very similar to what
we have to except that now of course we're are dealing with matrices
what you know this fact
we can
we can prove that these proposed the theory of
power spectrum by spectral even on the music groups so
for example we can write down a power spectrum in this form
which is just the product of the four
transfer matrices with complex conjugate
translation property
it's going to be invariant to again
maybe i should
i remind you that under
left translation
so it's the same thing here is that we have a function
so the complex numbers
then we
to its fourier transform
it's going to be a bunch of matrices indexed by the irreducible representations
and we knew that if we translate the function of effect on the fourier transform
is going to be
left multiplying this by
representation matrices
so just as in the euclidean case if we take the fourier matrices and multiply
complex by their own admission conjugates
we we call this the power spectrum which they use the q
then the power spectrum of translated functions
it's going to be the same except that we have these representations actresses appearing
the same is also a function
but we have the representation matrices appear
and then provided that we started out with unitary representations and our set of irreducible
representations representation matrices and so
and we see that
power spectrum is invariant
but again we lose a lot of information because if you take a matrix and
multiplied by its omission conjugate bringing us get positive definite matrix so these positive definite
matrices can't possibly capture everything about the origin of fourier transforms
the question is how do we generalize this idea we introduce the concept of by
spectrum so how do we now a couple of the different noncommutative
forty components together
so we started out trying to do something very similar as in the euclidean case
we start that we know that we're going to be looking some out looking good
looking at cubic
things in the original signals so we
to try and combine
three forty components and not just to performed by spectrum and think about how to
get the same sort of
in the
translator and the translation as we had in the original
by spectral so how do we combined three fourier components now in such a way
that the combination is going to be invariant and in such a way that also
captures all the relative phase information so now that we so we have completeness on
noncommutative groups
in the classical case we just multiply together the first two components right in saying
that the classical bispectrum look like
one three components that k one
times another african k two
these two conjugated and multiply by
the k one
and this was not because these two
behave in a complementary way to this
individual for companies behave in way prescribed fashion under translation and then their product behave
well two
if we take these
matrices now
three matrices in the noncommutative case and just to ordinary matrix multiplication unfortunately that's not
going to do the trick that's not going to transform in simple way
instead we have to take the direct product because again the direct product of representations
is game
representation so
the direct product of fourier
component is going to
transform according to the corresponding direct product of representation matrices so on the one side
we're going to have the direct product of fourier matrices the question is what do
we multiply that with on the other side so as to get invariance
and this is the same
time sort of problem as we had
just before the break which is fermented harmonic analysis in the first half of the
this is how to
decompose as direct product
representations so this is the questions
how to take two representation had to take the two REP representation through one hundred
multiply them together and then decomposed into a sum of irreducible
and we know that this always exists might be difficult to compute but since this
is just the representation and we know that representation is always reducible into sum of
irreducible as we know that
some matrices c
like constant matrices will exist in some sequence of irreducible here exist such that this
holds for any x
we can just
like take
together big but from representation theory from library look up the corresponding text gordon
so that's what do recall color these guys
and get
ten which is red
get eight which is black
eleven which is black
these things to change
everything else doesn't change really fifteen red it's no longer in violation
fifteen straight announced parodies black
we now have new violation up here with the team
eighteen is also read
the only violation we have in general have most one violation any time
so we fix it
and we'll have zero emissions
now we have a violation between ten and eighteen
somehow always counterintuitive
you have to look at the youtube again
OK good and so we can re colouring more
now that so
what we'd like to do is again look at the grandparent of ten which is
now so the root of the tree it is black
but one of its children is black the other red so we can play the
same game of taking the black seven and moving down to the two children never
mind that the response to stay black will ignore that property for now
we can make these two black this one red because then we get an imbalance
this was already black
so now
has going down here will have one fewer black then has going down here
so we can just three color seven as children
so i said we've got to rotation better be near the end
so what i will do is rotate this edge
i'm going to rotate eight
to the right
that's the next
the only one more operation after this so
we're right eighteen so there it stays the same seven three
its children
now the right child of seven is no longer now ten
eighteen becomes the right child ten
eight over here too
eleven and team that subtree in between ten and eighteen
so it goes here
eleven fifteen
and then there's the right subtree everything to the right of eighteen that goes over
twenty two
and twenty six
we're not changing any colours during that operation
i did let me know
looks good
so i still have this violation still in trouble between ten and eighteen but i've
made this straighter
that's what we want to do it turns out is make the connection between eighteen
the violator and it's grandparents straight
connection to write sort to less
here we have a zigzag right left like to make it straight
it doesn't look like much more balanced tree this one fact it looks a worse
but what we can do is now
i rotate these guys
or rather
protect the search
can rotate seventy two the the left
thanks to ten the room
and then things will start to look balanced
this is a rotate left
and i also going some recovery
the same time
just the same injuring one more picture
because the rule has to be black i'm gonna make ten black immediately
make seven red
that's the change and the rest is just the rotation
so we have eighteen over here
i think i actually have to rotate in order to keep some red black
this year
eight comes to be between seven and ten so goes here
eleven goes between ten and eighteen
so it goes here
twenty two and twenty six come after eighteen
if i'm lucky i should satisfy all the properties of that one
every node is red or black every red node has a black child and this
is the last place change have headline children and all the black kites
should be well defined for every node
the number of black nodes along any road any node to leave
is the same
and check that was true before and i do a little bit of trickery with
the re colouring here but it's still true
you can check that is locally around
this rotation
OK will do that a little bit for now
it's just an example
probably not terribly clear where these re colorings and rotations come from necessarily but it
these convinces you that it's possible
and now i will give the general algorithm for doing it
any questions before we go on
it's not exactly
we just running down the algorithm is not terribly intuitive
it was red black trees the sort of thing where
you play around a bit new to you say OK i'm going to just think
about we colorings and rotation let's restrict myself to those operations what can i do
try to re color that works great pushes the problem of higher
and there's only logan levels or order level so it's going to take a look
at the time at some point i'll get stuck can color any more than it
turns out a couple of rotations will do it
always two rotations will suffice
and you just play with it and that turns out to work
and here's how
function right so here is the influence functions of the first one of the site
when it starts when you mention information and then i have the one of the
real and i have the one of the w
the way i can predict the volume in the future is just a the the
influence the mass of the influence functions at this point in the future i want
to make prediction some to sum them up and that is my prediction right so
really what i've been trying to do is i would say OK how can i
estimate the shapes so that whenever i want to bring them all and in the
future this this this shapes of this influence functions will add up to the to
the value in the future right so really that is that is the thing that
they want to do and as i said my prediction about the popularity of of
an item in the future we seem to be that you simply be the sum
of appropriately aligned influence functions right and what i mean by the line because different
sites mention information different points in time the function starts at the time and the
site mentions information and information to more people times of course to get more deeply
influence functions put together and so on OK
now the question is how to how can i figure out the shape of this
influence functions so the way we will do this is to use the following right
as as i said right this influence functions are not observable need to estimate the
way we think about we do this is we make no assumption about the shape
of this do this in a non parametric way so really what do is we
will be able to say we will put together some kind of character and try
to optimize it and discover what the shapes of influence functions so the way to
go is we will assume that influence functions just as sets of numbers let's say
twenty four numbers right so every influence gets to zero after twenty four hours so
i can measure which characterise the shape of the influence function by by a set
of twenty four of twenty four numbers right so the value here and i truncated
let's say at twenty four and then what you want to do is i want
to find the the shape the should this twenty four numbers for each website such
that the following expression is minimized right so here is the the
here is that the
for a particular piece of information and for a particular time this is the true
number of mentions of the is of information in the future and this is my
estimate reckons the sum over the web sites mention information in the past and it
is the sum of their influences right now i can ask how should i how
should i said these values by such as this this summation
this character is the smallest possible and so what is the point is that the
point is that this looks like a least squares problem and it really boils down
to the squares problem right so idea and and doing nothing else than a big
interestingly quest to show you how i can put everything together to to solve a
big least squares problem the idea is the following so instead of working with one
contagion one piece of information i work with k pieces of information so each
i mean come and i will now composed these things in the matrix column vector
in another column vectors of this column vector of equality and these are sort of
just stick together volume time series of each of my k
different pieces of information and then i had the influence functions that they want to
estimate and then this matrix here is sort of like it's some kind of indicator
matrix ritual process called the web this particular piece of information in the past right
so sort of the set
this an element of this matrix to one if no one gets infected by by
a particular piece of information k at time t
for each of these pieces so this is a simple binary matrix that sort of
says half the volume in the future is the sum of particular influences of particular
websites and now i can go go
so solve this matrix equation
to figure out what influences are this is something that is called nonnegative least squares
there are super effective methods to do this so for example if you have a
matrix of a hundred thousand times for four thousand you can do this
in less than a second also then how we make predictions is just add influences
together and we have to have the prediction so here is here are some results
so the setting but i view
no no i'm doing everything together so the idea is this is this is this
is the volume of a particular piece of information so i have cases of information
here i have influence functions for each website so the question is this is some
kind of indicator matrix i want to figure out this so that so that what
after i multiply these matrix with respect vector idea this time series as close as
possible so really my optimisation problems be
and here is my prediction
exactly half
i mean
that's a good point so so the question is what what happens if information gets
old or if you know sort of order of sites is also important so what
i'm showing here is the basic version of the model you can add this actually
in the paper the sort of there are these extensions are also try to account
for how all of this information and things like that here it's sort of the
most basic the essence of the model but you can very easily and those sort
of penalty so it's a good point OK so here is here is the setting
and i'll show you how well this works so the point is the following i
will take top one thousand quotes by by total number of mentions and this one
thousand quotes in this case got mentioned three hundred seventy two thousand times across a
set of sixteen thousand websites and now
what i want to do is the following i want to predict what is the
future number of mentions of a particular quote based by only one monitoring one hundred
highest volume websites right so the idea is i want to learn a hundred influence
functions to predict what is going on at the overall population of sixteen thousand different
websites right so i'm monitoring a small set of the media space and i'm trying
to make a prediction about what's going on over sixty thousand
the media sites space right and the way i want to compare against here is
a standard time series regression models like and auto regression and so on the right
and the
my best maybe will be just sort of in the future for whatever is happening
at the present sort of what i call one one time lag predictor and what
is the point the point is that time series prediction around seven to eight percent
amongst the observed variables this is actually the causal DAG right
x causes the y causes w
h is an observed variable right so it's not in the causal DAG
so the causal DAG containing the observed variables
c and w are independent
but they not independently observed distribution
so since we observed distribution does not satisfy the markov condition with the causal DAG
containing the observed variables
the markov assumption is not warranted see this
so the causal DAG concerning
the observed variables and we only observe x the one w
the observed distribution
it's based on this causal there
independence is that satisfy the markov condition
with this causal DAG
and the problem here i think i have another in the same area the problem
is there is a hidden common cause
so she sometimes
in certain situations
we can make the causal faithfulness assumption and our results show us has to be
a hidden common cause i made a mistake by assuming there's no i ended up
with the goal
for waiting aero going both ways
it's so in certain cases the data will show is this
but in other cases they will not show is that in other cases if we
make the causal faithfulness assumption
it could be a hidden common cause in the data will tell us that and
will end up making causal
conclusions which is incorrect
so what we want to do is is
to relax the assumption
this is the
trained the slide i hate putting up here
because i'm not talking and you guys that this is in hand
and that's my website so you can you can read this later i think i
mean i was appointed me saying this because it is not going to do about
the good
so i'm just going to skip over this
go to the next slide
i can give a better intuitive feel for what the causal embedded faithfulness assumption
basically what it means is
we're assuming the a causal DAG
with which the observed distribution is faithful
but then you might contain hidden variables
so assuming is a causal DAG out there
and the observed distribution is faithful to it but i don't know that doesn't contain
hidden variables that could contain hidden variables previous should case one must contain
so if it
we allow for hidden variables
once we do this
can we still learn any causes
and i'm going to show that that we can still on some clauses but we
as money
it's alright let's look at how we learn causes
if we make this
i mean you revisit all the examples
i suppose
we find that x and y are independent with three variables
we find x and y are independent
apps what i do here
from ireland that would
the probability distribution is embedded faithfully in both these dags
our before when i made the faithfulness assumption i
i learned that from labeled krazy and i was happy because from from from only
these three variables and i was able to learn to causal relationships
but the problem is
if i assume that could be hidden variables each one of these edges could be
a hidden variable
these also say x and y are independent
by the way just mentioned there a noted that the separation implies that's why is
the a number of the markov condition node is independent
of its non descendants given its parents
the markov condition strict police
state practices act
is independent of the y
given h right
the the statement of the markov condition does not say x and y are independent
the from the markov condition you can
to do so other independencies
and those is called the separations
and so the set of all independence is entailed by the markov condition from the
set of all these separations and gag
and for this particular one you can see why this has the whole
one is independent of h two
right it's like the earthquake
burglar example
well some since these two variables are in the independent intuitively you can see that
actually have to be independent of h two
what if the if h one and h two independent how could the factor of
depend on h two n
that's the kind of h two then x would also be independent of y
again i understood intuition but it can be proven mathematically
and if you make the
and the markov assumption
then you can conclude that x and y are independent
right so let me just go on with that in just
getting intuition point
the point is is that probability distribution is therefore embedded faithfully in both in stances
so you can't really conclude that causes the you can't really conclude why causes the
because both of these could be due to a hidden common causes
so the causal relationships among the observed variables may be
that's basically would need to integrate over
slightly intractable seem you definitely shouldn't want to drive up
in some cases
we might not necessarily
i want to the density estimation but just novelty detection
just to find out with an observation is
and you looks unusual or not
we do not necessarily need
to get the normalisation
so for instance
if i wanted novelty detection so if i want to find unusual observations and if
well the
green line is my density then well what i would do is i would threshold
is based here
so here
and in this region there
the region out there
and that region would be considered normal
if i wanted to be a bit more aggressive
well maybe
i would pick i threshold
up there
OK i could do something like this
in fact
what's happening
there should be another few slides in there that might just try to the whiteboard
it's actually quite easy to get intuition for it
say that's my domain
and this is the things that are trying to estimate
and i going threshold here
now what happens on top there
doesn't really influenced my novelty detector
so if this function instead of that were to behave
like so
and then maybe
it just remain completely flat
i would not really matter for that level of
but for the threshold
so the high density regions don't really matter so much work with this but the
novelty detector
you're interested low density regions
now is the next thing that doesn't matter
here is that
the next thing that doesn't matter as well
i could scale this function by
one half
OK it's not evinced any more wanted integrate out to one
but if i pick the right threshold
treating my way through a little bit
OK OK and cheating but
i think you get the idea
if i didn't have something that's the proper density
and then we adjust my threshold i'll get the same region
so neither do i need to do particularly well in high density regions
nor do actually need to get this normalisation that several pain in the neck anyway
why not try doing something
that a does away with the normalisation he doesn't care about the high density regions
and also you is that if you design
an estimator based on those two strategies
departing from
density estimation
will get exactly burn of novelty detector
what data
the first thing is
well so that would be my max foster estimation
i go
and look at rather log p x i look at the ratio between p effects
on data
in some reference things
should be using
then you just then you know that this is just a fancy multidimensional version of
this one
OK so don't be scared to talk about my ten kernels
so this is really just the names that chaos
you can actually draw from such a stochastic process
so that
using gauss in RDF common just
taking some state and trying to values
that's what you get this like a simple function
another sample from
so what this story tells is that
well if i have
like regression classification system which behave like that so that by might be one class
to another one and it's the uncertainty region then actually using this kernel is going
to give you something fairly reasonable
it another one
see i told you
some of the slides is not very scary
the RBF kernel
it's not silly
this see the difference
basically gives a linear gradient here
the one
so it doesn't matter which can be
it doesn't like matter
eugen months
it's more important to get the scalar right
but obviously such
very kindly not going to be very good if you have a circular structure sitting
it out
it was not
i basically stop here and tell you will everything else is now left as an
exercise to the reader
all you do is you pick some so suitable sufficient statistic phi x and y
which describes the conditional dependency y given x
for instance conditionally multinomial distribution
i will give us casting process multiclass estimator
we get the distribution over in different classes
well we have to do is to find the right parameters
and the kernel will tell us how smoothly the distribution can change
if we take
conditionally normal distribution
o to get that process regression estimator
and we
get some
normal distribution over random variables
which just depend on the location
if you want to
play both the me and the variance
well then you will get heteroskedastic estimator
and this is actually was going to solve an really interesting problem
so until recently people have been trying a lot of heteroskedastic estimators but none of
the optimisation problem is convex
i don't know why
it's actually very easy
you could easily do that
you can have normal distribution member of the exponential family
condition on it
still in the spanish family
so they
we will get a convex optimisation problem
and this is exactly what we did actually be based in matters so not new
it is actually the name
sorry about that
conditional puzzles diffusion
this just leaves look you look very
some process
and this is what's called special plus some models
it's crisis book is full of that
and you could use a conditional discharge you could use the current conditional additionally whatever
o conditional gamma
or conditional beta distribution
and this is where all the flexibility in the estimation procedure comes in
say you want to estimate some y given x
y is defined on some
you might have some idea what the distribution roughly should look like
and then you just going to estimate the conditional
it's very straightforward
and don't be scared if you end up with some estimated that nobody has three
written not yet
actually good news
there this implicitly sensitive to the right priors they know
somehow something about the the distributions of these different classes of events that enable them
to make the right predictions and you can get this unless you plan to write
priors in particular given that they're such different shapes across the different domains and people
seem to get exactly what more moral as the right form of the prediction function
not just
the actual values
all right so
i let's us pretty much the end of the of the sun
first unit and i can take questions on that if you want
or i can
the point
it was
yes there is
so a point prior meaning like they just think all poems of the same length
well well OK so that's a really good question and it's somebody published a paper
arguing version version of that mike mozer and how powerful are published a paper saying
hey you could get the same thing probably not with the point prior but if
people just how it just people had in memory only a few poems or a
few examples of movies they should you could fit this data pretty well just using
like two or three examples in memory that's interesting i think there's something interesting deep
right about that also something wrong there's lots of other evidence we have an thomas
a response to this showing that people really with even within individual subjects you can
show evidence that people have these
you have not not exactly that not everybody has the same distribution for actually but
people have very much like a full distribution and he used this very
clever all remarkable method that adam sanborn and who i guess atomism here but some
of you may know him he's post-doc at the gatsby right now and in time
developed the so-called human markov chain monte carlo to just to show within individual subjects
so we're using MCMC within individual subjects to map out the prior and a show
the individual subject to have prior that look like this
but i think there's also something very much right about the point which is that
in this kind of study and a lot of other
studies in bayesian cognitive modeling things the data are are often consistent with and sometimes
when you look really closely individual subjects which which we can do here
there are consistent with the idea that people's inferences are based on taking a very
small number of samples from the posterior so i would say it's not the case
that people have in mind are the implicitly in our long-term memory we only have
two samples but what we might bring to mind one case might be a very
small number of samples from the posterior
and that's that's the thing that's that's emerged across the number of different places and
a bunch of us are interested in exploring this idea that
the way people might implement bayesian inference and learning first of all might be a
kind of monte carlo sampling based approximate inference but also that they might use a
very very small number of samples which
you know to a normal statistician would seem crazy statisticians work really hard to get
to get very large numbers of of independent samples
empirically in practice
machine learning people have found that often very small
samples were actually work quite well actually the first time i remember seeing that was
talking to engage back in grad school
remember in year pretty sure was in your factorial learning
o thing you're doing this really really fast gibbs sampling like ten gives samples or
something like that what made impact on me but anecdotally many of you have done
you know MCMC based on
learn your learning where where there is an inner loop of of MCMC inference might
have noticed something like that and i
again out of i was planning related to to dwell on that but i'm happy
to talk about it and i think it's quite an interesting place where human human
learning machine learning can meet up sort of thinking about mechanisms for approximate inference and
thinking about when you might actually be able to get away with and maybe even
when a cost-benefit analysis where you take into account the cost of sampling might actually
favor working with very small numbers of samples each subject was given only one question
in for each of these topics but across subjects the that you different subjects got
different numbers plugin for these different topics
and it was just the one page questionnaire and they
you know they
road number next each line
i mean like in the graph or something i'm not sure
yeah i mean in general so as i did mean to laugh at the i
mean it was a really good question in general that's something that where you know
it's really
something to worry about and to think about right but it's it's sort of it's
both and good thing like i think the the brain makes sense to think of
the brain as a kind of intuitive statistician and also makes sense to separately think
of the visual system as an intuitive statisticians sometimes the visual system might be a
smarter statistician then the rest of the brain the more linguistic higher-level part of the
brain that's often why is very helpful to graph are data like we i mean
good statisticians and learning people know this don't just compute numbers don't just look at
tables but plot your data and look at it because you're able to to use
it's you know the the
very smart unsupervised learning exploratory data analysis stuff that's basically built into your visual system
because of
read the way you want
one of
we need more
one of the more
yeah there's a few papers like that i wrote one of them are rather konrad
kording ronnie one of them when he was a postdoc with me and i see
my name on it in marie also had had a nice paper like that recently
NIPS with with resemblance and a few others and people like david at rochester have
there's a bunch of models like that alan newell has
proposed models of basically multimodal sensory fusions sensory integration
i guess actually is a little sort on that this thesis from a bayesian standpoint
i mean yes is that that's that's rich rich literature and not sure
i mean i think roughly it's roughly i would say it certainly similar to these
things konrad actually quite come according described it actually has a causal influence the way
fifty percent is not terrible in this case using only data again we're plodding here
it is function of the number of training examples using only data
the area look something like this
and if we combine
both the prior knowledge and the data
and we end up with
the curve like this which early on in the case we have a small amount
of data is doing better than either one
so another problem we came up with this one there was talk about quite a
bit in the tutorial yesterday morning which is the problem that the labels themselves are
quite expensive compared to the other data
so getting once the system is deployed
getting examples in general is cheap because you just have to record what the person
is saying
the getting labels is expensive
because label any one of these utterances
a human actually has to annotate has to sit there and listen to what was
an annotated
and that's expensive you can only afford to get a few hundred of these in
the day
so how can we reduce the number of labels needed
well we can use exactly the kind of active learning techniques that were talking about
yesterday morning
so the idea is the same we can use selective sampling to choose which examples
to label
and then we want to focus on the least confident examples this was kind of
the general principle that was talked about yesterday
after boosting we have a nice way of measuring confidence we can measure confidence using
the margin or the absolute value
of the marginal so we can just apply these general active learning principles
boosting where we use margin
as our measure of confidence
so the idea is something like this so you start out with a pool of
unlabeled examples which is usually
quite large in the tens of thousands hundreds of thousands
then we choose a five hundred examples of random
and labeled those
to get things started
we run boosting on all of the labelled examples that we have so far
that gives us the combined classifier as
linear combination of the weak classifiers and then we choose an additional two hundred fifty
examples for labeling where we select the examples
for which there is absolute value
of the prediction is smallest because this is proportional to the absolute value of the
and then we can just repeat that process we have these two hundred fifty examples
to our pool of unlabeled examples
we retrain and repeat this process
this kind of mimics what could actually happen in real system where you could have
overnight train the system
and then during the day could have the humans
annotators label but two hundred fifty examples that you act overnight
OK so here here's how well that works
so the red curve is showing the error rate as a function of the number
of labelled examples
where we choose the examples at random rather than using this active process you just
use the examples for labeling
and the blue curve is showing that same error if you choose the examples actively
using this method that i described
and you can see the beginning a big improvement in terms of the number of
there you need so for instance to get a test error rate of twenty five
you would need all forty thousand random examples
but if you choose the examples actively you only need about thirteen thousand so that's
the savings of about sixty eight percent
so yesterday in the tutorial for those of you who came to the tutorial they
were talking about getting
exponential improvements in terms of the number of labels you need
i've never seen that in practice certainly not with boosting but these kinds of improvements
we get
a big constant factor maybe it three to one to forty to one improvements are
quite common not just for boosting but other methods also support vector machines and so
the thing that comes up i don't think they talked about this yesterday but this
kind of
interesting that this curve goes down and then up again
this is partly a result of the way we set up the experiment
that in this experiment we were using a fixed pool of forty thousand examples so
eventually these two curves have two
converge when you get out here what's interesting is that the curve goes down and
then up again
so it seems to be happening is that early on you're adding
these highly informative examples but that at some point because you have a fixed pool
you have to start adding the other examples and the other examples would seem to
actually be
kind of this informative they seem to be hurting
the performance rather just leave them out
here's another character you don't get this step on this one but do get these
big improvements in terms of number of labels
OK and then finally the last thing i want to talk about is an application
to boosting to detecting faces this is really nice work by viola and jones so
the problem is to find faces in the photograph or movie
all these things based on very mundane
but if you're in business during this is is going do it
you shouldn't be doing
that's just just formula for just one right never
you're not being serious about doing this correctly
techniques at twenty two
this is the whole database actually had his license well but unfortunately like above-mentioned is
tools out there that actually have been built to address this very crucial problem
pragmatic grand challenge five
effectiveness measurement
if i had to give examples of public someone
and metrics
how important it is to attach
success metrics to the project
that takes the value of world
keep people alive
six tell you want to kill
that takes a few minutes
measures for success
so the people doing the data mining that gaming the system
and the people working with the star
there's also politics and the with start denying the truth of that stuff
coming up with framework methodology for how do we come up with metric
the we make them
other distributed to business people are doing that
study the source of all that is very
as much technical challenges
two cover today and their families give
i would probably highlight some of them in my talk
on tuesday public public benchmark datasets but worked on this
i agree to pushing for a a long time we still don't have decent public
benchmark datasets
truly know test with that
thank you
one of the electrodes
right big databases just become big by random sampling
they actually collected over years
the market underneath them is changing the population drawing from is changing
all sorts of things that in make invented all sorts of statistical theory
how do you rid complexity and understandability had been
interesting as i mentioned in the beginning
and hopefully they will come up with some examples they
x was reminded something ronny kohavi told me
a few years back so i'll use an example here
which is when they were st
and they
the first thing
frequent itemsets
so stationary was on
absolutely is
in the u s five thousand animals per household
those were were work it came back and
is the rule told ninety nine point three percent accuracy
all has been said to me
it took you less the second ground that's silly thing right the machine friendly reasonable
and actually some very very powerful
correlation that you may not be very interesting
would love this semantic syntactic
scalability beyond large datasets but dimensions
he was talking about that someone on tuesday
and here is what we do
and want to talk about that this is this is the beginning
there's a lot of data mining activities we just do that without even knowing how
do it
what problem trying to solve hard solving what does it mean
what is the effect you know change all that stuff
so my summary of the magnetic challenges i exposed
as with the data
but the data mining inside the process
but in domain knowledge in many settings where you can do
very very much better humans
life cycle maintenance and met
hopefully they will just some of the technical and to give you some more examples
in the meantime i go back to this last item
which is
that is
i don't our ultimate users don't understand data mining
but they understand it and business and our responsibility to figure out how to type
i talked about his slide before i think
it's basically is the mapping of the capabilities enabled by data in driving the business
integration of data driven capabilities in driving the business
and addition of metrics are you managed business
that is the area where
that actually brings me be
near the end of the story of the it's not the ultimate
so the mixed group actually probably the happiest of my life
so why join you
o thing
after many many months me saying no matter what appeared to be acquired really
this is what I'll show and it sort of follows a timeline from like ninteen sixtees
to pretty much today
and we'll start with the simplest one so the one that I already introduced at some intuitive level the
the erdos-renyi random graph model, right, where we have N vertices and we'll connect each pair I I D with some probability P
and there are two variants to the model, one is called G N P and the other one is called G N M G N P
is the is the
is the formulation up here right, so we will we will have
we will have
we will have each edge appear with probability P so
in ex this is the this is the
the probability that we will have M edges in the network, so here here and in the other one we fix the number of nodes and the number of edges and we are just throwing them in, so, right, this is this this one would have some variation in the number of edges we've seen in the network, while this one
is exactly specified
as I said these does not mimic reality because because it has poisson
degree distributions
but what is nice about it is that you can analyze it very it's you can analyze it easily so to say
right so for example you it's easy to show that it has a poisson degree distribution and you can just ask what's the probability of a node having a degree K right, and it needs to have K nodes that K K of the edges have to succeed and
and N minus K edges must not succeed and this is the number of ways I can I can choose
K K nodes to connect to out of N that I have in the network and if you play with this a bit
you get the the form of the poisson distribution, again
what you can be interested in is is to say okay I have N nodes, now I'm throwing in edges one by one and the question is
how is the graph being connected as the edges are thrown in and
here is the result, right, so what I talk what I'm interested in is the size of the largest connected component, what I mean by that is what is what is the largest number of nodes that are connected
and what turns out is that when when my average degree is less than one, then all components are are small, right, they are of size log N but but as soon as my average degree gets just a bit about above
one, I will have a giant component that pretty much spans the whole graph, right, the giant compo I will have a component that is of linear size and all other components are of size log N and they are pre they are a tree plus an edge, right, they are they are cycles and you you you can easily easily show this
let me skip this one, what you can also do and it's the calculation are easy, but it's sort of impressive, is you can calculate the probability that in a particular graph you will you will have a particular subgraph
right, so what I'm showing here is
what are so
this would be the increasing P
so P is if I have N nodes, P is proportional to N to this power Z right, if Z is minus infinite, then I have my P zero, I have no edges, so my graph looks like this
if if I have it two minus two then I mostly have just diods like two connected edges and as I as I as I am increasing this
my graph gets richer, richer and richer and my
my structures in there get
get more and more connected and what is nice is because everything is independent, we can easily calculate the probability of suc struc, of such structure existing in a particular graph on N nodes and, I don't know,
probability of an edge being P
okay so
all I want to illustrate here is that
a lot is known for erdos-renyi graph and the reason why a lot a lot is known because everything is independent, so the math works out nicely
so just to finish up about this
why they are good is because they are simple and tractable, right, there are these
phase transitions on the size of giant component right as I said before if your average degree is less than one or a bit less than one right your graph is disonnected, is just trees, as soon as the average degree crosses one, you get this
huge giant connected component that is linear in the size of the graph
what is not good is that
they don't necessarily correspond to the real graphs or they don't have the properties that we saw in the real graphs
and there are many extensions of this erdos-renyi or poisson random graphs and one of them is called configuration model
this is
how how you can think of, so this would be a way how to generate graphs with a pre-described degree distribution, the idea is that I will have some nodes
at I will assign a degree to every nodes sampled from some distribution and this is this is what I mean by that, right, this would be a node of degree six this is a degree three, so all I need to do now is know is
to connect these spikes or viscers that are pointing out of the nodes and
the so this is one way to think about it, the other way to think about it is to say every node here
has, so I have these supernodes, but then have then have little nodes inside here, right, so this has degree of six, so there are six nodes six nodes it has, so what I can do now is I can generate a random graph on these blue blue notes
and if an and if everything is fine, then
most of the edges will go across inbetween these super supernodes and I will get a random graph with a pre-described degree sequence, right, what what would what
what is what what becomes a problem in this model is that it can happen that you will connect nodes inside the same supernode
or that you will create selfloops
but if your probability is small enough, then then this error turn gets small and you can sort of neglect that
so another model that is
coming from more social network side is called exponential random graphs or P star models
and this I think also comes from like seventies or so
so what is the idea
the idea is to to take a graph and measure
some properties of it, so like this epsilon be some measurable property of the graph, for example, it could be
number of edges in the network number of sta structures like this, number of tristars, number of the triangles in the network and so on, so and all that you do then is to say
probability of observing a graph I have is like
is is a linear combination of my properties times some weight, right, so I am having this exponential distribution
or a log linear model, right, where I have where I need to figure out these weights when I'm fitting the model and I'm given these properties
that that I can that I can define
from just moving the parentheses
it's it's like and it's not like that
easy to
i mean the
to prove it to prove that this is correct after
go into the gory details of matrix multiplication do it both ways and see that
you come out the same
maybe i'll leave the
after do that
there we go
that's how i so there's a single matrix i could call it e
now all what we're talking about these matrices
tell me one other there is another type of elementary matrix
and we already said why we might need
we didn't need it in this case but it's the matrix that exchanges two rows
it's called the permutation matrix
and you just like tell me what that
would be
so i'm just like this is a slight digression
and with you so let me get some me where i put a permutation matrix
you'll see i'm always squeezing stuff and so permutation
or in fact
this one like exchange
so i exchange rows one and two just to make life easy
so if i had my matrix images due to by two
suppose i want to find the matrix
that exchanges those rows
what is
so the matrix that exchanges those rows the the role i wanna cdns is there
so i i better take one of it
the rule i want here is up top so i'll take one of their them
so actually i just
the easy way this is my matrix that i'll call p
for permutation
it's the
actually the easy way to find is just do the thing to the identity matrix
exchange rose exchange the rows of the identity matrix and then
that's the matrix that'll do
do ro exchanges for you
could i suppose i wanted to exchange columns in
columns of hardly got into today's lecture but they
they going to be around
how could i if i started with this matrix a b c d
that i one
i'm not even write this down is going to ask you
because it because in elimination would we're doing rose
but suppose we wanted to exchange
the columns
of the matrix
how would i do that what what matrix multiplication what do that job
actually why not all right it
so this is like just
all right under here and then
did get
OK suppose i had my matrix a b c d
and i want to get to
AC over here and be the here
what matrix does that
can i multiply
i caps matrix
produces that answer
and you can see from where i put my hand i was really asking
can i put the matrix here on the left
exchange columns and the answer is
if i'm on this i'm just bringing out again this point that when i multiply
on the left
i'm doing row operation
if i want to do a column operation where do i put a permutation matrix
on the right
if i put it here
where i just barely left room for it
so i'll exchange the two columns of the identity
then it comes out right
because now i multiply wine column at a time
this the this is the first column and says take one take none of that
column one of this one and the guy
over here take one and this one and this one and you've got a c
in short
to do column operations the matrix multiplies on the right
to do operations it multiplies on the left
OK and its role operations that we're really doing
and of course
do it
i mentioned in passing but i better say it very clearly
that you can exchange the orders of matrices and and that's just the point i
was making in here
eight times b is not the same as the times
you have to keep these matrices in there
gauss given order here
you but
but you can
and your q never lasted big jam
then you can be trapped
so your
at the end of two thousand a million samples or
five million samples you're that happens in practice
we have these transitions
are still there
if you make you too broad
then you get a lot of rejections they tend to stay alive in the sense
and this also can happen from
with these things are useful for signals ising models
you know it's quite common that you could perform market share with takes a ten
to the fifteenth steps
to make the transition
choose the right heu
well i everything works well
so next will also see throughout this hour how to come up with good cues
that this works well
to answer your question
this is how you
it's not as bad
this is the transition model suppose you're currently state x
and you want to jump into a continuous space
you want jump to a subset of the space called b
capital b
so we're looking at the probability
after that if you are
if your current status here
what is the chances that you will move to the set of the state space
and essentially that algorithm i wrote it is an algorithm but
what that this is really a conditional probability
you can write to conditional probability
not on this table you can actually write it in terms of number of mixes
and what it does is this
when there is acceptance
the probability of moving is just the proposal probability times the acceptance
weighted by the acceptance probability so in blue is what happens when you get accepted
so you start with x
you propose to move to the space the if it gets accepted
then that gets weighted by the acceptance of x given b
so like an important so proprietary from q in your weight by the weight
eight in this case
when you reject
that is
and by the way i the way i wrote x does not belong to be
is because i want to avoid the case
because if you start here you end up here and it's because of the rejection
still in the same place
rejection is the opposite is one
minus the probability of going anywhere else in the space
excluding b
and we can
right is not compact notation
i'm actually going to leave it as an exercise another thing you can ask me
to break
well you can take that
and using indicator functions you can write it in this form and if you pick
any book on markov chain monte carlo
this is the first equation you find describing metropolis hastings
and this ensured telling is
with this is the acceptance probability and this is the rejection problem
and this is the way of
this is the conditional probability the probability of b given x
and that's the
transition matrix
courses in the country in a discrete state space you this gets replaced by some
and you can rewrite the some matrix
in the continuous case you need to know by two hundred
as an exercise you can take that expression and you can show that the expression
satisfies detailed problems
and because of that it's about
the first time there was proposed in the forties by the way
random walks are random walk is symmetric
if you if this is the gaussians
because the constant of x star minus XI square's the same six i minus six
times square
these two terms castle
when the council which we have something called the metropolis algorithm
the first one that was proposed in the past
in hastings in the seventies
them up with the idea of using an arbitrary proposal distribution
is zero
so we only need to keep
we want
the probability mass that's above that line
and that's what this this that's the situation is going to be
two clips multivariate gaussians
and so to do this project have to find the mean and covariance matrix of
the clip multivariate gaussians
so sounds think it might be a lot of work
chris bishop pointed out in his lecture yesterday
you can find moments of exponential family distributions very easily thing derivatives of the normalizing
in fact that's the trick that i'm going to use
but in fact the trick i recommend you should always use one could when doing
EP updates
and for this particular problem is actually quite simple to use
by the way if you want the
if you want the
you want the general form of the DP updates
you can go to my what web page you find this any document called EP
quick reference
and it gives you all the equations you need to give you the the equations
for dividing multivariate gaussians month-by-month gaussians
and also gives you the equations for computing
the moment
of this
function fw thank you might
and the former is actually quite nice all you do is compute the normalizing constant
take it is the normalizing constant
and you can directly compute you
you should do some linear algebra and you get the mean and covariance matrix
OK so for this problem
all we need to compute
try this again
so for this problem we just need to compute the normalizing constant and then take
because there's so what is the normalizing constants the normalizing constant let's make sure i'm
using red here
it is normally called that z and it's going to be a function of ni
in not i
that's the integral over w
my factor
q i w
so is one integral
an integrative that i don't need to compute the
in two rule the mean of the interval the variance which would be very complicated
so what does that also that's just the integral of w
this indicator function
y i x i transpose w
one zero
and we have a gaussian distribution
now here's a nice trick so
this quantity here
i can call you
all right and the only thing random here's w
OK so the just taking a linear come a linear
operation ww w
so i can get
distribution on you
so if w is distributed
according to this multivariate gaussians
what's the distribution of u
if i knew the distribution of u
this integral is just comes down to what's the probability that he was going zero
so one way to interpret this integral is just what's the probability that y times
actually transfer of is zero
and so the final decision view i can deduce that you want to provide the
user interface
so in other words
this whole thing is just the probability that user
where u is that is that quality there
so what's the what is the distribution of u
anyone remember there
gaussian identities
so if i have multivariate gaussians mean
and not i
and i want to take the inner product and i think the inner product that
goes in very well with exi transpose
what's the mean
it's all just linear and everything is linear so
the mean of that is just going to be
and the covariance matrix is also easy to work out is was going to be
thanks i transpose v not i x
and the way it is america's it's only plus or minus one
OK so that's the distribution of u
the whole antibodies was and it was probably the user and zero
and we know what to do that that's just the in CDF
so the answer is
the goes and this is the this is the symbol used for the gaussian in
and we just take the mean
of that variable
divided by the standard deviation of that variable
i session drummer should i say OK let's let's go to a different page
so the probability that used in zero
is a gaussian cdf
first some the general form it's always going to be
the the
i mean if you divided by the standard deviation you
so is the case for gaussians
in this particular case
that is why i
transpose that i
over the square root
x i transpose v nine
x i
OK so now we have essentially closed form
formula for that normalizing constant
and now to compute the mean and variance that the PRC and we just take
and i won't go into all that there easy because of the gaussians here is
got its report completely serves
so if we all that's it's clear now how easy it is to compute the
the moment
the distribution p
coming back to the problem
and what's the performance on this problem so
what i'm showing here
is that i'm showing the
different ways of doing bayesian inference for this problem again which is that those three
data points
just very synthetic problem with the data points if you want if you want
you know running times accuracy and sort of real life datasets and you can find
those in my thesis by robert results here is going to give example of the
so what i measuring years and measuring the computation time
first is the air the air is
the distance to the true posterior mean
it's the same sort of error measure been using in the previous slide so is
is arrested the posterior mean close to the true posterior mean
albums and went to compare against
first of all the SVM
secondly which is maybe you you might put on their secondly there's a monte carlo