what i want to get from this and here is sort of what you say
you want to the first part of the reason what kind of veterans or called
in statistical properties basically what kind of statistics show that measure network data and the
session why do i want to this is because they want to understand how the
data is what is the intuition i want to be able to easily find design
principles and i want to find one so i want to somehow be able to
do what is some indication what kind of data in my working and because of
this i basically want to understand
wired networks networks are organised the way they are so the funny thing is in
a sense that when you look at many different kinds of networks that all in
some sense similar they show they share this that global statistics on one side only
the what you want to do is to say OK can i design that can
i designed by so if i know how my data is going to explore that
to something and that's what
we see today all all of you
so what's the plan for the rest of the talk
the plan for the rest of the talk is what the cluster structure of networks
and what i mean by clustered or clustering structure of networks is you know this
is a cluster
and you know this is closed and
how we
usually think of clusters is that is a set of nodes that have a lot
of connections from the inside or between the nodes of the cluster and so few
connections to the rest of the or to the rest of the network
this is the one question to be asked the second question is how does this
clustering structure scale of the network it or how does it scale with network size
and how and then we lost it how they think about this this this and
whether this ten
about that same what kind of body scan around over such
and the overall idea would be that you know let's use computational you know in
this case approximation of items too hard graph partitioning problems
some kind of experimental approach
to the to the network structure so the idea will be the using you know
computation as a tool to analyse things because
i mean one way to analyse how the system to shut down most applauded our
networks to be right you don't know the pixels on the money so we have
actually compute all them and then
right reason for those computations
if i go back and ask so now i basically want to get to a
bit more so
one one way out growth in into the number groups of that is to look
at social networks where nodes explicitly defined group memberships so what we should think about
this for example on facebook connect you say
i'm a member of the set of these particular set of groups
for example
but publication venue for example if you have a collaboration network then we could say
science is the best school his group membership by publishing the confidence of a you
because say that this publication then you can define so
then the question is basically the idea is that we can think of groups as
the kind of node can right every every node in this particular set of colours
they belong to
and then
the question is how many scholars
spread where are they right so here are two different example
for example if
if people would recruit friends this would mean that group membership should spread along the
right so the idea would be if this guys yellow then these guys should also
be allowed for you know if these guys been sort of his neighbours are also
more likely to be one here i just sort of just colours
the edges and so
if you don't agree then the group memberships spread
and why do want to do or what i want to measure this is because
i want to figure out what kind of what factors influence a person's issues decision
to join
and here is how to think about so basically as i was saying because i
think about this as diffusion propagation of the scholars over the network so the idea
is that there are some people who are already members of the group and now
there are people who have connections
inside the groups and they need to decide whether to join the group
so this yellow squares they they may join and what we will be asking is
the probability of joining
you know of these people joining the group depend on how they are connected to
the the members of the group and the first the most the first question to
ask is you know what is the probability of joining how does it depend on
the number of friends who already have been in the right basic question is what
about this is to be the more and more friends having to group the more
likely to be drawn to
and if you go measure these
four livejournal which is an online social network of like this
we know one million users in two two hundred fifty thousand explicitly defined groups
and similarly this network is basically DBLP
i have four hundred thousand papers one hundred thousand authors
nodes of my network
connection means that people call for papers and they have two thousand conferences speech
which i think of us groups and of course i know that these groups are
overlapping and every so that's that's no problem just asking
how likely people to join the group published articles and in both cases i notice
that you know the height the higher the number of friends who come into groups
the more likely you are you have to join the group
the other thing is that get is diminishing returns property where you know the thing
is monotonically increasing but the marginal increases the partial pressure of the function gets smaller
and smaller so
i think if you if you feel like a parametric function like a log a
logarithmic function that seems to be able to to this right so it's always increases
but increases get smaller
so that's the first one so
the more the more forensic evidence network more likely to draw
so then we can ask him some questions and say
you know
how the connectedness of our friends in the group depend on
o on the probability of joining so what i mean here is i have to
two two nodes that the what they are here join the group
when he
all o
we more
radiocarbon dating and so the c fourteen calibration can also predict age of an object
given its radiocarbon age because the c forty one c in the
atmosphere hasn't been decaying changing constantly as the radiocarbon dates suggest a sort of machine
learning example i think this is true there's something called TDN one which is really
early reinforcement learning approach to playing backgammon which was
a big famous success the machine learning community but i think the competing approaches to
TD gammon when it was
released or maybe even the best performing backgammon player currently is you basically get expert
backgammon players to score the quality of a bunch of different moves so they give
some sort of school
and then you train the computer to learn this mapping the backgammon players
has provided and then you
get the computer to recreate that you could also consider that something like goes these
complex games you can't explore the whole state space these games you can't do the
the way you do chess so this is the way of doing learning
i should say that i mean a good examples of what was i would say
the main approach to
artificial intelligence applications from a machine learning perspective up until the turn of the twenty
first century
i was very much the if someone comes to you with the problem
something needs to be solved you have to work out how you can convert that
problem into a classification problem or regression problem and then you fit that has a
component you take your favourite regression and classification approach and then you use that to
solve the problem and i think that's the
it's an engineering approach is perfectly valid and people will continue to use it today
and you know the main and they'll continue to use things like support vector machines
instead of neural networks if they're up to speed but it can't be the right
way of solving all these artificial intelligence problems to just work out a way of
making classification regression has to be something deeper and i think that's where reinforcement learning
comes in
so these are examples of where that's being done you basically work out how you
can convert go playing regression problem by making the computer we create expert opinion on
these moves
OK so predicting now real value of y given x and and we're going to
really simple value regression so prediction will be f of x is just MX plus
is linear
so one dimensional input one-dimensional output and we also define an error
the area is delta y i is the difference between a prediction
and the actually observed value of the regression so we can look at things like
this and we can come up with potentially an algorithm i want to do in
the same way we did the perceptron we can a portion of this arrow
two the bias so
one thing to say is that you initialise you'll find some way
and then what you do is you take one of these learning rates
and then you had
some portion of your error to whatever your biases rights
is you're error defined now by substituting f of x into here
so what's going to happen if we do this for the bias of the two
components to the regression a slow
and by an intercept bias so where this goes to the y axis is the
set x to zero then this is just say so we want to set the
intercept so that space moving the line up on the sofa positive error
c and therefore f of x
become larger on the this learning so if we if we got a positive error
then based this learning also makes see large
corresponding that makes
f of x larger
but this makes the area small so that changes they're in the right direction so
the negative error seen become smaller and error magnitude also become smaller so the magnitude
of this error will reduce if we change in in this way
we can do the same we can try to come up with a learning rule
for this sort
and we can do we have to consider for cases because x can have negative
input and you can go through all of these cases and show that the error
will become smaller
in each of these cases if we apply this learning
i think this is very for me this is and was
an attractor way of thinking about learning rules when i when i first started in
machine learning and you can see that something sensible was happening and if you have
interpretations of these connections in the brain which there is no to interpretation here you
can see how those connections are changing but you can see even a simple case
it's becoming quite complicated to write down the justification of the learning rule i come
up with i don't think anyone's invented this learning rule in this way of trying
to justify it but you you can draw and just what you can look at
learning rules and say what they're doing
so if we apply that we can present data points compute the current error
and change estimate of m according to those we presenting one data point at the
and this is sort of an interesting way working we were very into this machine
learning and i think maybe we should get more into it as we go through
and in each data point we change very slowly
and the regression becomes more accurate while we into this because it is an adaptive
learning scenario right we called the online learning in those days but i think now
you call it stochastic gradient descent because we say online people think you're on the
internet so
what we were interested in doing is presented each of these data points one at
a time and then slowly converging towards
a solution that takes more iterations in this example in the perceptron so already iteration
ten and then i'm jumping through this iteration twenty thirty eight
OK seventy got some convergence criterion is converted around seventy so that's way estimating that
linear regression as is much much quicker ways of doing that
i wanted to show you that because it's similar to the perceptron idea presenting data
point and then you're adjusting your gradient and so on and so forth
i want to use this opportunity to make it and add something in a simple
concept is that certainly seems simple when i wrote it down but it took us
a while to see things perhaps in this way in learning statisticians have users for
a long time so the problem with those regression things is the problem with the
learning rule as well but i'll come back to the that sort of more in
the next session but this problem with these linear regressions this x may not be
linearly related to y so i think this is true and maybe anyone who knows
better than you can correct me if i'm wrong
but you know i think in the brain you don't really take the pixels of
what you see coming in and multiply them by an inner product and threshold them
before you pass them to other parts of the brain what you actually do is
used to process them in some way and
one way of making things so this is a linear relationship we've been looking at
but what we're really interested very often is non linear functions of x o one
way of making a nonlinear function from model
by introducing basis functions
what is the basis functions so it's a way of taking as input
and then representing them by a non linear function
in the input space so you just have a bunch of these and you some
are linear combinations of those now an example that might be
the case of images we are just using pixel values and there are a huge
number of them very clearly we could be a bit more certain
that a lot of these coefficient values are zero so we would say that the
the prior standard deviation to be quite small which would include evidence of certainty or
strong bias for a simpler model
so one of the things that will do today
in the labs is actually play about the south of value and see just what
sort of effect this has
on the predictions are made
the qualitative predictions made
now again
if you remember yesterday we had a very simple linear model which are parameters w
norton w one
because we
i have no strong
preference otherwise
we can
also assumes
that the
the parameter values are independent
of each other so each one of these parameters will just fall
a univariate distribution gaussian distribution center visio with
variance of alpha
in our view modelling situation we may well have an alpha tied to each particular
but the principles are the same
so that means then that our prior off
conditioned on
the prior variance which share overall
parameters is not just the product of gaussians which you know it means that we
have this
spherical gaussians
the center the zero
with with an overall radius
identity multiplied by this
scaling coefficient alpha
OK so there we are
we have this this prior to in courts preference for
it's simple
and that's fine so we don't know
i should also point out that if we really have a very strong belief
that model is going to be sparse then we would probably put rather than using
goes into the probably something like double exponential we is the
the tails are much heavier but the
the probability of zeros is far short
but again just from our teaching point of view let's let's use this this goes
in here
that includes our
are modelling assumptions
and our modelling beliefs
before we've actually observed in the data
so what will know to israel make some observations
and in the later those observations we will update our prior distribution on the model
to the posterior
the the the likelihood
as we saw yesterday the likelihood is just name dimensional multivariate gaussian
and we want to posterior
so we have our likelihood function
we have our prime
and then we have a marginal distribution here
which of course is integrating over w was integrating the likelihood with respect to the
someone mentioned yesterday that these bees in situ synthesis to what these big integrals and
then everything comes very beautiful and in this case it does
but but but tomorrow
your call i think you're behind won by this candidate is having we actually get
some models which is a far from straightforward
but the beautiful thing here
the nice thing here is that the product of two gaussians as was previously seen
for every pair of nodes the statement a node is independent of people small hole
for any
of nodes in america from the field with no
isolated nodes in order to
that's a bit too strong i mean what
i mean these but i mean by that is you may have all the nodes
and assume that you don't have any conditioning
i mean this will depend on the other
i mean the right way i think is really the neighbors
it is those that if you condition on both
you still get the same conditional probability as if you condition on all the ordinals
so that that's what it is
if i suppressed this one for example let's assume that i only conditional on these
three and the condition these one
that one four
because if only conditional on the street immediately all have passed from below twenty ordinal
which is unblocked
and there will be these ones holding more
OK but i think we need to try to figure that out so
the exercise the full me
you need to show
we need to show that right
show what's the markov blanket of
a of bayesian network ensure what's the markov blanket of markov random field
so how do go about
so that
i mean
so that's basically the conditioning it to show that p
x y
given x more are
all the other not
is equal to p of
x i
even tax let's say a blanket of five
these molluscs
so it said
how do show that these four months for bayesian network
co parents
and she'll
and four
markov random fields held show that uses
what what what to be the approach
right the reason is correct
OK so
it has to do with
in the particular case of
bayesian network
basically say well
another four have the
in the conditional independence to hold
because this is basically a conditional independence statements right
what you're basically saying is that
probability is given all the rest is only equal to the probability of a given
the lack of link
but for the conditional independence statements hold in the bayesian that we need the separation
we need
the separation hold so basically these viable units be separated from the rest of the
given the markov blanket
what we use
in the cold
is immediately blocked because
these is head to tail nodes
whatever is here is look at
whatever is his book because this can be only
taylor the tail to tail nodes
whatever comes here is also block
in effect here from the good news or the also be ahead
because all had so has have already been observed but
i need to compare slightly deeper parents because he failed so these guys this is
not observable
these past few years and block right
doesn't work
let's hope that that's the right answer in terms of
i mean the intuition
the same happens
but you can do just your greatly as well
i mean
how the these or to break
now we start to see how
graphical models are really powerful we've just solve the problem only using
graphical art
which is completely valid
because we have proven already the mapping between the algebra in the graphical
language and now it was using the graphical language only
was that's enough
but you can go through their order as well
so what would be the algebra
you need to write this thing
you need to write these things
and if out which is the that makes the things e
i mean you can do it so we can try to do it for example
assume far ahead of bayesian networks account so what's the probability distribution of a given
will be equal to the product
of all j
of p of
parents of j
so this is the the overall probability distribution
of x
let's assume that
u of x i
given x
will be called
to this quantity
which is here
x five
divided by p of
well this conditional probability
i will be given by this quantity
divided by p
x love
but p of x not is exactly equal to the sum
o or x five
of p of x i x by margin is a
so we have few effects
because of
now just take this expression here
in this expression viewing here
what you have here
here you are sunny only on x i
so all factors that involve the exercise here
let's open
right so this is to trial introduction to text classification
and a a lot of what we to be talking about has to do with
text classification of text to sort of one of the fundamental
so this is kind of an ambitious tutorial that kind of slides and we'll see
how many of these actually can get through everyone feel comfortable you in asking questions
others to o point sitting here three small crowd there's no point in here for
if something is is is
not clear you should you should certainly raise your hand and
and and
and that's
OK so basically
they're going to be two parts of this tutorial so let's kind of slow talk
what is text classification where the applications of it
and then i'll talk about some of the really basic on
techniques and methods for text classification start with naive bayes which is very simple practical
generative model and then i'm going to talk about some other models some discriminative models
for learning how to classify text which also very effective and very practical fast that's
not going to move to some more advanced topics so my talk about other types
of classification task
i guess are less well understood from a research perspective
that's basically the plan so long
but that with the definition of what text classification is
so you're classifying objects have an input which is the object you want to classify
and the output is the predicted class you know so maybe good or bad higher
from some label from some fixed set you've determined in advance
the experience learning from here is a set of examples with their
associated correct classification
right and what you're learning is the function
that maps to from
from an input x which in this case the document to an output which is
the class you associate with that so there are lots and lots of examples of
so one been pretty well studied is classifying news stories so maybe you want to
the stories that pop up in
some news aggregator like google news and put them into categories like world u s
business and so on another topic which has been investigated this classification of technical articles
in biomedicine there's an enormous number of biomedical articles are published on there's database of
fourteen million of these you can look at
r one way that
people make these on
more accessible
two scientists is to classify them according to content area in a very large classification
scheme classification scheme sort of like the dewey decimal system of library of congress system
so when you basically you be adding terms to abstracts
in this
a large set and the terms would talk about things like conscious sedation e o
three that two five so if anyone's suffering conscious sedation right now
it could just be launcher could be e o three to five all
there are many other categories instances of this particular problem why classifying movie reviews as
favorable or unfavorable classifying jokes of this funny not funny
so that the things that problems that satisfy this basic interface
on a document and the class out
now technically this have different characteristics we're going start by talking about one of the
best editor of these things which is a classification of news articles about the topic
associated with them and that's a very well studied benchmark that contains several thousand newswire
stories are classified one ninety categories one the categories is exemplified here the things about
me to green
shipments so here's an example article
that's very interesting categories you get here are grain and wheat so there are ninety
three binary classes that still associated with these articles
and this all came out of a project that would had
many years ago
where they wanted to automated indexing system for their own articles
let's start out with how do you
automate this process
so the first thing you have to do is you have to choose a representation
for the object of
going to classify
what we have here is we have a long string right that's the original representation
of the document how do you actually want to represent the classification while the simplest
useful representation
basically to represent as a list of words so
an english language
particularly when you're looking at
you know the central topics
a about that a document is about looking at the words gives you a pretty
good idea so
you start out by taking the individual words in here there might be a few
refinement so for example
a very common words like and then tend to not give you a lot of
information about the topic of on
of the document
it's often the case that things like you know registration versus registrations oilseed versus oilseeds
things like corals and other morphological variants can sort of be easily compressed
so these are these are two things that you almost always do when you're looking
at article text classification
there's a lot of things we talk about the second collapse in multiple currencies into
one personality noise
let's just consider document as a list of words
right so is a very simple way that you can
build classifier
so the idea is for every class y
all right
so we've got some examples
great way to consider this binary classification
i don't have a probabilistic model of document acts look like given that the class
that's the
map of the documents in this category OK so what's the probability that i get
this particular list of things given the categories we need what's the probability get this
particular list of documents given the category is
so i want to do this sort of probabilistic problem then to classify
classifier documents in these binary categories of wheat or not we need
well defined the class we were not really which is most likely to generate x
according to
this probabilistic models
OK so basically want to find out
the most probable y
why has the highest score for the probability of x
given y
and so we also want to consider the prior probability of y so that the
category is very unlikely to occur then we want some help he was so this
is a very natural thing to do
all right so how do we do this we have to build this probabilistic model
how do you
how do you describe the probability of generating this particular list of words
given the category
so the simplest useful process again
is the phone you pick some words according to some probability of generating a single
and then you repeat that same process for the next four the next one and
the next word so you're you're ignoring the order several each
the word is generated independently of all the other words so like a lot of
the structure of this document
all right now what you end up with this if you do this if you
make this rather naive assumption that the order of the words doesn't matter is the
probability of this list of words is basically the product of the probabilities of each
word given y
so how to model this
the simplest
useful thing to do
to estimate this probability
by just looking at the council in the data
so you can look at
the number of times you saw that word in the category
what about the total number of times he so anywhere in the category
right so if
o would like well see it occurs very often in the green category then that
would have a higher weight and i would like to be
stocks which may be when the critical category
so this is a little bit of a problem because if you run towards that
you've never seen
i've mislaid the actual value of
but it's actually a little bit bigger
then one point five
for any other suggestions
possible things we could do at this stage given that this was the first outcome of the first way
any other suggestions
yeah well
well good
really like
so that's
could balance it could
i think that
this way
right we've left on the table like to
possibly added
so what's the probability
that gonna balance
which i
because if any invisible possibly organised in your
and it's about this
all right
what's the probability
and all the
the right hand side down
left tied up
because the only way that could happen
is that you know is this
particular it should be put in
and what's left over a three-day s
so as yet another
probability distribution
do you think this is got
the biggest entropy so far
all these options
so we could just imagine trusting shannon
if i give you
and of
o size on
and i ask you
he was defeated
appearsif you get a free choice
all those probability
and your goal is to maximize
it's about
the end it
rejection neighbour
the math problem
what's the answer how to maximize some the i
this e
one the i with respect to the probability vector
what it be
so it's all in the middle was over time
okay so do
some cake
and i say
in this case consists of it
this is
and you've got three children
and you've got to share the cake has fairly well we can between the three
children that you can't cut up the pieces
once they
the best way to do that you get a zero
two one child that this is a wonderful to another which is what we're doing here
you will be
well that's the rule actually you do have to get all the case to children
is the most uniform way of showing the case no
thirty two
three that's
we seem to be pervasive side
news opinions rumors that
legends police
the this community
got taste of some of the positive
the work of
everything else emerges two thousand one
and may seen
from the new york times we actually about the epidemic of obesity
in the US
stars and felt that obesity is contagious direction pathogens but the effects that if your
friends are becomes p c ten b is ready to social contagion and so on
this year also has been failures even lower
collective action the way in which riots break out
twenty people throwing rocks through windows doesn't tend to
sort of course content but
so it's more people jump in the things snowballs
all this to be examples of contagion that something that want can build models and
it's it's hard to observe something is needed in the experiment to really
what's going on the the really satisfying but it's an area where he
really contribute ideas so that the model
social contagion is not really like
it is not like to particular sources where
so this may be random jumble having some of the used you
here some more complex decision making process going on which is what your friends doing
something really what we're going to find life and eventually
after people do doing you
and so
based on these models social science teaching
nineteen sixties
is this notion that this not from the notion of where
i mean
friends or something and y the probability that you're
right presume many problems
pressure measurements were sourced
but there's also some of these very what
and the key issue is
one of is
so for example from united to try first because i find myself makes the biggest
impression on you the second next expression
that's it
you know
for simplicity
after probably much
right so the first people use these very
personally but only one
forty people doing something you want to do something
after that when you look at the text in the first stage
i have consequences matter population levels
so this is the way
i more data make things
again are invisible
this is because
although these terms have long been
for the conceptual basis of local model
how you measure cos especially given the training get standards
significance of the video
watching million people engaged something which is happening so
and it's only
really in the last twelve to eighteen months starting to see a proliferation of these
kind of curve
appearing to secure some action
so are is that actually do like something
fourteen pictures
this line namely the same notional
and that you talk
are roughly one
some of these the name of
this approach
opportunistically try things you mention right
you're probably
but regardless it's becoming obese with a truly consequential but the thing is that is
the world measure was your choice
community and that's why i like funky number references is you probably purchasing
DVD of function
number of recommendations tracked distance from earlier
this work was the
and this is sort of
twelve minutes apart to give you also an idea
factors can change here is very dark and very bright
changes are quite dramatic
i want to talk about superconductivity
it was discovered
by a dutch physicist
his name was commenting on this
and he discovered
and if you call mercury
something like four degrees kelvin
use liquid helium for that in fact he actually discovered how to make
liquid helium
that was an incredible thing and then use the liquid helium
cool down substances among the mercury
and he discovered that
mercury would lose completely all its resistivity
sorry electrical resistance would go down
two zero you got the nobel prize for that in nineteen thirty
you can only understand
quantum mechanics
and even quantum mechanics has a major problem nowadays to understand
all the phenomenon
about superconductivity
the problem started in nineteen eighty six
two scientists in zurich ruler and
that noughts
discovered that silicon alloys can be made superconducting
and the temperature is highest
thirty five degrees kelvin
and theories earlier
have proven
that it was impossible to ever get superconductivity thirty five degrees kelvin
so this will such as as
in the community
that these guys got the nobel prize was in one year nineteen eighty seven they
got the nobel prize i don't think there's any one example that i recall
o by discovery
was made and within one year the nobel prize was awarded
if you're still cannot explain today forty wider is what's called high temperature
the record today i checked yesterday
with professor at MIT to record is now hundred thirty five degrees kelvin silicon alloys
can be made superconducting
one hundred thirty five degrees kelvin and and since you probably noted liquid nitrogen has
a temperature of seventy seven degrees kelvin
anyone can now play nowadays superconducting
cereals even high schools because liquid nitrogen is very easy to come by
if you make power lines
other superconducting material there will be no
of energy people are thinking about that you can imagine how costly it might be
but in principle you could transport
electric energy without any loss without any ohmic losses
no i agree articles are zero
also if you have zero resistance in the material
you can run extremely high currents with
you can therefore get very strong magnetic fields
superconducting coils
you can get very strong magnetic fields and these colinas that we talked about earlier
the atom smasher is
like we have from eleven
in geneva
they are going to make use of superconducting coils to get
magnetic fields
as high as
this lower so even higher
no electric field can exist in a superconductor
you can very easily see that because if there were an electric field in a
superconductor and there is an electric field say in this direction
there would be a potential difference over the superconductor
ohms law
vehicles i are
those then immediately
but this is not zero
but this is zero
but i
go to infinity
you cannot have any
electric field
in a superconductor
if i approach
eight so
conducting disk
with the magnets
so it is in the north pole and the south pole
so we have an electric
field configure a magnetic field
configuration roughly like so
if i approach this
superconducting material
the EMF
generated in here because of fire the floor because this the change
magnetic flux coming off the EMF
remains zero because you cannot have an electric field inside
the superconductor
and this of course is i are
are is also zero
so i know
can have any value
completely legitimate
so you can have a huge current inside the superconductor
but no about
and so as you approach was this
any current are going to run inside the superconductor
in such a way
that the phi beta
the flux change
in here
is always zero
thirty eddy currents will flow
two never allowed
any magnetic flux because there was no magnetic flux to start with when the magnet
was hired
so can never be any change
and so he antique current creates a magnetic field themselves
which if you vector only added to this magnetic fields
always make sure that there is no net magnetic field inside the superconductor
so if you now
make a drawing of the
of the two fields the one that is produced by the eddy currents and the
one that is used by the magnet
when the magnet comes very close
here is north yourself
you superconductors
the superposition of those two fields and
in exactly comes down to the fact
this magnetic field
it's completely repelled
another way of looking at it
get discrete field here
but that is the superposition of two two magnetic fields one
despite any currents
and one from the
the magnet
and what you have here
such as grease magnetic field
the magnetic pressure
we know what the magnetic pressure because north
north pole to repel each other
but we never expressed that in terms of a
quantity and the magnetic pressure
equals the square which is the magnetic field strength
divided by
two two museo
divided by two museo
i'll get back to this later
in the lecture
this is pressure
but this is a new conper square
two new concepts the vertical distance in the horizontal distance between
between an existing edge
u are two
it's a nodes in the graph
s and t are two nodes in the graph that are connected by a by
a positive or by negative constraint and we define
the vertical distance
the UV eds
two the
to the axis of the constraint
and the course of time the
horizontal distance between
technical details in the paper
and here we see that
the intuition is that if the vertical distance increases
then the effects of the constraint
to the to the it decreases both for the negative and there
positive cases
if the horizontal distances distressing distance increases this means that the goals
outside of far away from the constraint
this is for the negative constraints
whereas the horizontal distance has no effect on the positive constraints
so you see here
a small animation house
the vertical distance
and the
the horizontal distance effect
the cases
here we have
the definition
of the escalation ratio and the reduction ratio
i remind you that this coalition the issues there
is the degree to which
the weight increases in the case of the neighboring
negative constraint whereas the reduction ratio is the degree to which
the way to finance
thus increasing the similarity between the two nodes because of the positive constraint that is
in the area
so here are the
huey for instance
it is the weight of the coupling constraint to what is the weight of must
link constraints
and these are
simply formulations of intuition
here is the
the edge
for which we want to compute
the combination of the reduction in pressure and this is
the pair of nodes of the course things that are connected with a with constraint
so finally every constraints
potentially all other vertices in the graph right
and the closer there a
the kids to the constraints the lands of the effect
so the overall ratio
or the overall effect
of the constraints
on the weight of
o that is given
by the way
normalized some of the obvious correlation ratio
from all the constraints
from one of the positive class trains
was there
the normalized reduction ratio
from all the
negative constraints
and then four
even more normalisation reasons we
we come up with this final formula that gives us
the weights between
as it results
because of the effect of the other things
and then
the objective is to the clustering
and we have three phase
framework the first is to
to create the graph from the original data
and then
on this
we would like to modify the weights according to the scheme that i've presented before
and then on this modified weight a graph
we apply
clustering and we
to evaluate the results
so this is the electromagnetic field based clustering the EMC framework
so this is the acronym that we use in the following slides
the graph construction
another straightforward one
we extract a
in fact you cannot effectively counter example where you cannot stop but for most practical
purposes only the examples we tried
this this seems to work seems to work just fine you feel like saying something
i will
and yes
so there are many many ways to make more efficient
importance sampling like any ideas from principal component analysis ideas so that action approaches all
those things can be done to
the place is very simple conceptual idea
with so that just get caught one of his students apply PCA
try again
like this
i think you get stream or what is the is about the first
how do you get more than one sample
of the same history because i never
the time how do you only seriously what you know since more so
two at these this to answer what i is that respect
which gives you can back the history
if you can't be history energy which is you
i assume the mixing time and then you in fact have a reset
that was not very meaningful
and all that but it just means that you assume somehow that if you if
you are
look back far enough in time that the system would have mixed and so effectively
we started to cheat by assuming mixing time notion of restarting OK
so how would someone like that would have done the discovery park figure out what
the and court are how we learn the parameters you can use gradient algorithms to
do that or you can do a slightly clever algorithms which basically which we call
the suffix history tree algorithm essentially comes from the fact that we know that predictions
all one step extended tests
are linear functions of these parameters
so we can find
enough histories that we make a linearly invertible system whose by by inverting which we
can get this set of parameters
you this is very quick and very rough
but it turns out that
the learning part is actually much better the learning parameters part lacking much more systematically
handle that the problem of discovering the core tests to begin with OK i want
to not spend too much time we have done some results probably OK
o point out something i call the rank the linear dimension of dynamical system what
i call the linear dimensions and angles system because in some sense
it is not the smallest notion of sufficient statistic right called the rank the linear
dimension because it requires that every other column be linearly computable
from those and columns
but if you allow nonlinear computation then you might be able to get less than
rank less than n as the dimension of the system so for example if i
allow my
my prediction of some past given history as some non linear function of the prediction
of my core tests that it's possible that i can get representation that even more
compact than the linear rank based based
representation in fact i want
present this but we've we've shown for certain classes systems that in fact you can
get exponentially smaller representation and the linear rank based representation if you allow nonlinear computations
of if you look for non linear sufficient statistic the linearly sufficient statistic but i
just wanted to add tantalising talked out and not so much more OK so now
i want to do
it is
deal with the case of continuous observations
all i did was so all everything it so far was discrete observations so now
i think about
continuous observation so
i was system
let's do the uncontrolled case somewhere uncontrolled case uncontrolled case simply means every discrete time
steps i get a continuous valued observation
time separate m step i get
continuous valued observations
let's assume scalar observations from to a single dimensional observation but continuous operation
the phone content provided by MIT opencourseware under a creative commons license
additional information about relations MIT opencourseware in general is available OCW MIT to view
OK so we're starting in the last unit
and so we're going to be talking about genetics for the the rest of the
the last the last class is a bit of a review of everything we've done
all but this is this is the last the last topic it's mostly in chapter
thirteen but there's little bit in chapter seventeen so if you notice on your problems
the best for is covered bridges is in chapter three transition metals in chapter sixteen
kinetics in chapter thirteen and nuclear chemistry in chapter seventeen so you're jumping back and
forth between a couple of several different chapters in this last part of the course
so the rates of chemical reactions and rate wars to today's introductory lecture to rates
and will introduce you to a lot of terms that you that you need to
all right so a chemical reaction
so in addition to asking whether the reaction is likely to go
as it is written
which is the thermodynamic questions
we also want to know
how fast the reaction will go
so kinetics is rates of reaction that's what it is and the kinetic experiments
measures the rate at which a concentration
of a substance taking place in the chemical reaction
changes with time
you're talking about changes in concentration
with changes in time
so let's take a look at the chemical reaction
this is the oxidation of glucose
glucose and oxygen going to carbon dioxide and water
so is professor sara told you in the first part of the course
this is the reason why we need we need glucose for energy
this is this is what drives our bodies how we make ATP
which is our source of energy in our bodies so this is the reason why
we eat
oxygen is the reason why we
ceo two is the reason why we
and water is the reason why we
yes so you know this reaction quite well really important reaction
professors there told you about the thermodynamics of this reaction she talked about delta g
and delta g not equals what
delta h minus t delta at
so you can consider sort of how much what you get out of this reaction
how spontaneous help favourable it is considering delta g
which depends on the value of delta age and delta s and of course also
what temperature the reaction is
so in this case
delta h is large negative numbers so what type of reaction is that
delta as not as positive
so that's very favorably always want to increase entropy
so delta g is very large
negative numbers
so this is a thermodynamically
very favourable
so that's true
if you move around one might expect that when the glucose is sitting in a
and oxygen
then would be forming sio two in water
this is the really favourable reaction
so i brought them glucose with me to class
in here is some of her she's kisses
there's chocolate and there should be
so this is all field up away from oxygen
but according to this thermodynamics
if i open this up
this is really capable reactions are into to the bag and sio two
should come out
so i mean i'm mean open this up and we'll see what happens
of course if you do this on your own safety glasses might be a good
all right i don't really see much happening right well let's let's
observe this reaction over time so what i want you to do that is going
to hand this out during the course lecture i want you to carefully study your
versions yes
and let me know if the and if you observe any sio two
coming off of this and will watch one
of your points are perceived as one here which we can take a look at
and also takes part of speech and the meaning
so joke about clinton
be done with compoundstring it doesn't happen to be in the KB
so i think
beat this horse to death so i won't go through that site in detail
that should be
easy enough
to remember but it
you want to have it even easier you can use the dictionary assistant in many
you can just go to the KB in click on
dictionary system if you i can
we've been
give you alive
demo of the dictionary assistant
it's a term we want to exercise
if ever constant
apple juice
is is that in there
and use five
four six
which is fine for fun apple tree
at all other OK
OK maybe we can get to the dictionary system by clicking works if i
so far it has apple juice
classification we could add
yummy apple cheeks
complicated and
apple cider
so i
class of apple juice
that's the thing we can do
OK here goes i don't know if this is going to work but i hope
is the phrase cos about what is the name no
if i said yes then that would
create an interesting assertion
OK so
this is
to find out whether it's a mass noun our count nouns
we want
should say many classes
well certainly glasses
apple juice is better than some less about which is so it's countable
this is not a good way to refer to apple juice class apple juices
wasn't was to happen
a reason to be in the loop but i don't know why this is working
it should have asked me next is classes of apple juice is the weighted
OK let's say it is
OK that's OK
it appears that the most common way
that that makes these lexical sertion into our preferred lexical assertions
OK now we're done much to find out about which but i don't want to
see what we just made
if i go to
good history
we can see what the assertion looks like
when we
you can find it by looking at lexical info
right OK yeah so
we've got
multiwordstring with
it uses the head unfortunately
that was not the intended
modulo bugs
the dictionary assistant
well choose the appropriate
predicate to use
the red
one class of apple juice is is certainly not the plural of one class of
apple juice
of the last that long
the classes as the head
so much to change and
i have and it is a one and let's apply adult male human this guy
first it says this this OK guy also means these are the things you say
this guy in a as a no
which sounds best many guys yes and then it it will say
it should ask
are guy
and guys
ways to refer to
i don't know humans
that's why anyway so the dictionary assistant
is at least designed to make these decisions
to make these decisions for you and guide you you through the
so that works
you know maybe it's average was
thirty two minutes
we been our travel time to work on average per day
we compare that to the best fixed
right we could take in hindsight which might have been twenty eight minutes performances our
we want that to go zero
right so
so that's what we were talking about
OK good
there are actually some some
number stronger things you might like to do just to give one example maybe
suppose that all the sudden some construction comes along and somewhere out there was good
turns out to be bad now
and so you might like to say to compete against the best fixed rate in
maybe want to compete against the best
sequence strategies where i use one and ran for a while then switch to another
one for a while and maybe switch
the another one for well maybe then way you switch back to the first one
from i want to compete against the best
you can't do that if you're are competing in things like this which arbitrarily
so we saw like in this
example here in know the world is the random between half the data rate and
the top one is that the bottom of the good and happy days random
the other way around in hindsight should have gone up down down up up up
down there there's no way to to figure that out random urine
they on average one half every time but you can compete against the best strategy
they don't switch to offer
we did explicitly talk about that but you can take these algorithms and basically by
not allowing the weights to get too small
you can have the property that if all the side and the best choice the
best expert switches
then you can start
you're probably will start moving over to that and you can get to guarantee that
if there's is a strategy doesn't switch too many times but that does quite well
then you also the
two pretty well what happens is that log n terminal we had it's multiplied by
the number of which is so
if you ask how well
how close my doing to that
they that get caught up numbers which
so we talked about
fish that should child
i me i want to do
the couple of albums with the weighted majority algorithm so this weighted majority of very
natural where
for free
i think you choices as no option but as a predictions
rules like different experts telling what they think the stock markets cooperative then we combine
them by taking majority vote by weighted by some way we apply them in a
natural thing to do would give everyone initial weight of one and then as they
make mistakes to penalize them
new that lowers the weights is a cutaway have so that even point time you
have a weighted vote based whether weights based on their performance
and then we show that if you do that then you can factor to do
nearly as well as the best
you analyse the
we've got two point four bound we have all the randomisation and all the changes
in the following we got that point four bound down something nice
we can get the multiplicative bound is close to ones you like
it's basically a one concepts i found times number mistakes the best expert
performance of the best strategy in hindsight bias in and the ERM because so these
to get rid of
you have plenty of the areas it gets closer to zero
this is better but it is taking longer to figure out what the right way
a stochastic
and and that's where the controversy lives
i don't think it's to control the controversial in machine learning
but it was very controversial in any statistics and i think that's because they needed
to have things subjective and when you're introducing this prize you're introducing thirtysomethings objective and
they weren't using subjectivity and the still be debating statistics integrating statistics is you know
we joke around between frequencies about
whether the bayesian frequentist right and
make fun of each other a little bit in a friendly way
in statistics
as far as i can tell the that really talk frequentist and they fight amongst
each other about is right objective bayesians all the subjective bayesians and objective bayesians believe
you can come up with priors completely objective and subjective bayesians belief prior is always
a personal thing and you can't have fully objective
i don't even want to stop that but one could very well binomial distribution with
one trial so there is also talked about the
but when you talk about the band
he considered like at the table and you see rolling the ball billiard table on
the ball and somewhere on the billiard table potentially uniformly let's assume uniformly between these
two sites
then he threw another also that land
and land either to the left or the right
this first school
so you can do that then try multiple times you can keep rolling the next
ball the red bull multiple times and so the next time it comes out there
so if you believe it's ready also lands uniformly and that's assumption he made then
you're basically
using all one shot using the newly distribution for multiple trials and if successful to
land on the right you're using the by the binomial distribution but the key component
about this and what fisher hated about his fate
was the fact that he was treating the parameters are random variables so he sampled
the parameter by rolling the first ball that can you imagine how their bases right
in this stuff thinking of this of his were created binomial probably thought about it
for two seconds and just is that i mean he didn't really died before this
was published so didn't really
i believe in one way or the other for all the controversy is just based
around the fact that in one case you talk about
with a fixed number of black and red balls that's another thing that's not around
one thing it's another thing you know there's a fixed number of black and red
and here
you generating the front your binomial
sampling from uniform so that makes the parameters stochastic variables and fisher hated that and
fisher invented the sort of term we use the term bayesian is an insult to
people they used to call it the call color
inverse probability or something and he invented the term bayesian is way of insulting inverse
probabilists and another name system but it's to do with this is not to do
the bayes
the naive bayes method is not very easy for example
OK so
what's going on in in bayesian inference so these different components
the bayes we had is of this form posterior is equal to like times prior
eye marginal and just to show this
so the prior distribution is represented as a probability distribution belief about these parameter values
before we observe the data right so somehow we don't observe where black line it's
but we know it's uniformly distributed mass approach
the likelihood gives the relation between the parameters
and the data so it's like
what is the relationship between what we observed and what we didn't observe
the posterior distribution represents an updated belief of what we
i think now about the parameter once we observe the data
marginal likelihood very important because the marginal likelihood it looks just like normalizer here if
we were thinking it is what we want to know about the parameters it is
that as the start state and that's and say this is why this is really
interesting for cognitive science because you can keep processing is you can plug in the
posterior in the back and here and keep learning more and more in online where
it's really nice way of
seeing how your beliefs evolved
but the marginal likelihood is very important because it actually assessed
i mean
it's it's unlikely that in some ways it's unlikely with some of the parameters integrated
out and you can sort of do maximum likelihood with the marginal likelihood but it's
the best thing to do because you removed a lot of the parameters you're less
likely to be overfitting and the ratios josh was talking about we can we talk
about the bayes factors and their ratios these marginal likelihoods is also sometimes called the
evidence particularly by people from the maximum entropy
which is an important community in physics that in the days when bayesian inference was
almost completely dead in statistics these physicists were using it suggesting it
sort of
one i think was in the manhattan project which sort promoting it
across all period died on statistics
so they called the the evidence when they talk about it
OK so amazing example of the sort of thing you might want to do and
i just think it is one of the most natural examples and in fact it
sebastian thrun has taken this sort of approach to robot navigation and you have written
entire books about it as a bit more complicated i'm talking about here but as
i understand it this is state-of-the-art in the way you do robot
localisation of map so imagine
the represents
a robot state let's just assume that its position on a one-dimensional line
the robot makes readings using its sensors so it could be multidimensional state could be
position velocity rate of termites from and you can just think positional one-dimensional line and
it makes reading sensors it may have multiple array of sensors may have so nelson
mandela's sensors it may have all sorts of things but they can be sort of
we can think about sensors one-dimensional we will
now the idea here is that we any time we might have an idea of
where the robots everything the robots in this room
and we have a map of this room
given the
different locations in this room
we have a model of what the sensor readings should be
because we know where the walls are and if we got the direction they're all
pointing in actually pointing so we know like if it's got so in a sense
you know in the robot here face in this way we know the
the centre will be reading with some accuracy the distance about war there so might
have some noise associated with it but basically that's so
so we can combine initial picture that location
with sensor readings to get an update the picture location using bayes rule to get
serious so this is what got an initial idea when the robot is
we make an observation of format sensors and then we update that two when we
think what afterwards
so this is facts
this is our prior belief about where the robot is minus one x
now it's important i'd rather like that is normalized along x right
this is not normalized in normalized y so this doesn't have to integrate what actually
happens to in this case because of all
properties of gaussians in general it doesn't integrate to one
so we can draw about these things was is a function of x it's not
a probability distribution with respect because given x so that the likelihood and the likelihood
is saying
this is
likely we are to get each reading given at position x
to get the posterior we multiply these things due to two things together
and then we we normalize so what's going on here is basically
the primary saying that
we think the robots that
the data is maximum likelihood solution we be there right that's the highest likelihood where
the robot
OK but there is uncertainty
so the maximum likelihood you don't reflect the uncertainty so
two regions that on communication so fast that by gibbs sampling over here it never
gets over there and i get the wrong answer
it's actually a long-standing problem in they are
we actually being able to make very good progress on using not surprisingly a combination
of MCMC
with ideas from satisfiability testing
so we developed the so called MC SAT where
the next sample
instead of being proposed the where i just described is generated by sets of
and so i'm able to very efficiently jump between month because this is what satisfiability
solvers to
and of course there are some care has to go into making sure that you
still wind up with the right distribution and again i won't go into the details
here but this is orders of magnitude faster than gibbs sampling and again is one
of the things that actually makes this all feasible in practice
OK so now let's talk a little bit about learning
you know where where do these markov logic networks come from the formulas the weights
of course you could just write it all by hand
but most of the time that's probably not what you want to do
you might have formulas that you or somebody wrote down and you might want to
learn weights for or in the most general case might actually want to learn the
formulas themselves or just take for people contributed to you can think of something like
the semantic web that may not be entirely wrong but need to be refined and
maybe you can find them by by looking at the
you can think of the data that you can learn from as a relational database
if you have a relational database you can apply markov logic wanting to that before
you is unstructured information and we're going to see an example here what you can
do is you can represent it you know as the database this in the most
simple-minded way you can think of like for example you can think of free text
is just being a sequence of packets thing that still appears in this position in
the document
so this is the data
and here in this talk for simplicity i going to make the causal assumption which
is that in every
at every ground predicates that is not in the database is assumed to be false
this is the standard assumption in databases often it's not appropriate
and what is not appropriate what's going to happen is that we continue to have
e versions of the albums and talk about those are available in the software but
here to simplify i'm going to ignore them
so the two main tasks is always in machine learning learning parameters in our case
the weights learning structure in our case the formulas and the parameters can be learnt
generatively and discriminatively and i'm going to briefly look at each of these in turn
so how do i learn weights generatively
well learning which generatively means
finding the weights that are most likely to have generated the data that you're looking
at the maximum likelihood
unfortunately there is no closed form solution right i nominated an optimisation process but fortunately
the likelihood is a convex function of the weights
i mean there's a single global optimum i don't have to worry about local optimum
i don't have to worry about initializations and i can use
you know in the gradient ascent algorithm is fast second or the quasi newton methods
like lbfgs to find the optimal weights
and the key thing of course is what is the gradient
here's the great is the derivative of
the log likelihood with respect to way
it's actually very intuitive forms which is the following
it's the difference
between the number of true groundings of the corresponding class in the
and the expected number of true groundings according to the model
so what happens is that if you model is predicting that clauses should less often
than it really is the weight of the clause needs to go on
if it's predicting that's true more often than it really is the way is to
go down and when all the weights and when all the accounts lineups
you've learned the maximum likelihood which and you can stop
so a very simple at some level very intuitive but there's a big snag here
the big snow usually when you have a powerful language there is this next summer
the big thing here is that
computing these expectations required inference
and your inferences too costly no matter how many tricks we do
but if you know how to do inference at every step of the gradient descent
procedure this is going to end up being very very slow
OK you know we try it was very slow so we had to look for
alternatives fortunately there exists
one of the alternatives is changing the subject
if you think you're trying to optimise is too hard to optimize optimise something else
that's easier and that hopefully has some
correspondence with the first k
and you know in markov networks there's the standard approach of what's called so likelihood
so the likelihood is just the product
over all variables
of the probability of the variable conditioned on the state of its neighbors in the
and the great thing about the likelihood is that you don't need interest to compute
this right this is just a markov blanket right it's like gibbs sampling
and if you combine this with something like lbfgs you actually get quite fast learning
and it's a consistent estimate so it has some my statistical properties so for many
problems the the likelihood is the way to go
it's widely used in areas like vision spatial statistics some natural language processing as well
and so forth
sometimes the the likelihood will give you a better results
and this is not surprising because if you think about it so the likelihood is
only taking local interactions into account
it's not taking long-range effects
see for instance for money to infer from some variable over there this some variable
over here i'm actually doing something that this will look likely did not optimize the
parameters for
OK so for some problems this might give good results
fortunately for those problems there is another thing that we can use which is very
popular in machine learning which is discriminative learning
what is cognitive learning
discriminative learning is something that you can do
when you know in advance
which variables are going to be evidence and rituals are going to be queried and
that's usually the case
and people discriminative learning in the main reason for this is that it just has
to get better results
for us it's going to have additional mass effect that we can you know there's
other approximations that we can exploit
so now what going to do is going to maximize the conditional likelihood of query
given the evidence instead of the joint likelihood
and the idea of state something here because i don't need to model dependencies among
the evidence variables because the cretan and get any normal and that would be a
waste of time OK and i can just optimize what i really care about so
i had this formula that is pretty much the same as before except that it
depends on x and y instead of you know all the variables undifferentiated but now
there's another nice thing that we can do about this
difficult terrain you
which is the following
the thing that makes inference part is that there's usually many modes
but then you need to find them on average overall
but when you condition on evidence what usually happens is that many or most of
those modes go away
in fact condition on more and more evidence eventually probably one up with just one
very large amount
so what we can do is instead of doing a sum over all possible states
so the example is learning the structure of deep sparse graphical models
so we can use an IBP matrix to really a bunch of observed variables
two layer hidden units
we're going to do deep learning here
OK deep learning but in a slightly
so the first word
using bayesian nonparametrics
so let's build a deep network by having
the layer of observe units of the body
it infinitely wide is not just the this why is well in italy why hidden
units layer here
and this binary matrix represents
which units are connected to which observed units
there really happy with
observer unit one
is connected to the first two hidden units
OK etcetera
so we can stop this
by drawing multiple cascading
draws from both process
and so in this work with ryan adams and had one
in the end the IBP uses uses the building block to define
infinitely wide
that works
three or e
of course once you observe data you sample from the distribution of structures given the
you can apply this sort of thing to the kinds of image data that deep
belief networks have been applied to
here for example is
we can then say OK
that's pretty about half the face from the top half
in this sort of thing
fuzzy chains and things like that
and you can look the
and you can see
one day and connecting two
the force
conductivity pattern from the hidden units and the observable universe
is learned automatically by the model
OK this is what i mean by automatic the number
hidden layers
seems to be around three for these data
the number of units for hidden layer seem to be around seventy
and as far as the conductivity of units we observe units
all those things are learned automatically simply by taking our prior
and then conditioning on the data
OK so
then you can move to higher level units and see fantasies of the model with
the please
specifically faces
see what happens when you get
the activations of higher level units
this is scary looking faces lurking d
inside the
nonparametric bayesian
do you like network OK
i think i
ready for the reality check
OK here's reality check i just told you model
that does users by movies
this sounds like a fantastic collaborative filtering model
did i make a million dollars out of this or that would be me anyway
to be able to work and make a million dollars and if it did we
win the netflix prize
now we can win the netflix prize
our our high
infinitely y
really beat
nonparametric bayesian networks
it would be the best in this test results
compared to
other deep networks
is that fair i
that's right
why not right
i think as as one of the workshop organised better as it this
OK this is the reality show this stuff is is beautiful is elegant it all
falls from the sum and product rule and a bit of clever MCMC
has made humungous splash
but still beautiful the we can think of
well you know it could be something to do
with the the kinds of projects i get involved in
i had a look around and it seems that you know none of
none of my bayesian nonparametric things of
be anything
maybe i should worry about that
but there are success stories apparently
not mine unfortunately
smiley face because i can talk about the
i'll just give you a few examples of it's not always it's like you know
you can have a beautiful models that have very elegant properties that perform quite lousy
but occasionally they are beautiful models the elgin they perform state-of-the-art
that's what gives that gives me hope
so here's a few examples
so again borrowing from some of the examples in the tutorial
here's working on
segmentation of motion capture data by emma frost and colleagues
you can get
can bring them and say these might look interesting then you can look at different
visualization and also well here is where the outliers are
this is stuff that you can
do yourself in matlab and that's what i tend to do
if you're starting out i wish that i spent more time learning how to use
the software
the teacher says here's an example of some features you might see and hear is
the output you're expected to produce an exam and here is another example of the
feature and the output expected to produce
and then
in order to get these systems to work
we might have to do a whole load of manual stuff like representing features very
carefully visualizing the stuff maybe it seems like about and maybe we're excited about this
area because we want computers to do things for
so just as the supervised learning there's another whole error machine learning called unsupervised learning
it's not about
very carefully looking at the features of the data that might be interesting by hand
it's about getting
algorithms to discover structure for you and and give you what interesting features of what
interesting representations and that sort of much more exciting
this sort of method is what really got me interested in machine learning that
it's much less well defined so it's much harder to come up with
sensible objectives to do this if you talk to practitioners in the supervised learning problem
is a well this is the output expectations reduce and this is the sort of
our and prepared to tolerate
if someone gives you a lot data they don't understand
and then you produce something interesting from
PCA is an example of an unsupervised learning method you say had produced a map
of europe from your data OK that's great but you know what that greatness six
or seven it's very hard to quantify
whether these things are doing something useful
so in
i'm not going to go into as much detail
unsupervised learning
partly because of time
i just can give you a couple of examples of the sorts of things that
unsupervised landing
and so
once again we return to the data set of oranges and lemons i should say
i first
made this data for a long time ago when i was giving a talk to
some philosophers they asked me to talk about artificial thinking and they wanted to know
that meant and what artificial thinking was i wanted a very small
data dataset that i could explain so they would know exactly what it was when
i was talking about it and i was originally intending to talk about supervised learning
created classification dataset and then told her classifiers work and that of the talk i
find given to you
but when i posted this was sort of the first plot ideas and quite got
around to writing line the colour points here
and when i looked at it was just immediately obvious
that the clusters in the dataset you know there's a group of points and may
be easy
five groups of point
and that pops out to our eyes when we look at this image
that's something that can be useful for us because without looking at this maybe we
know that whatever it's also for these are probably all the same
and maybe the different one of these other groups there's a lot we can do
without the supervision
by just looking at the structure within the dataset
on the last day you're going to see a recording of a lecture about clustering
but i'm going show you one of the simplest clustering algorithms that out there so
just the perceptron was a simple
procedural way to classification there
simple procedure always doing clustering
so this is an algorithm called k means that
you will find k clusters you specify k
so i'm going to try and find five classes in the dataset automatically
this is the way the algorithm works
you just randomly come up with a bunch of points there is colour crosses are
randomly drawn and i randomly drew them so they would be around the mean of
the data set i didn't actually do that i randomly chosen to be around zero
and and i sent to the whole dataset when i ran it and then project
back so
that was the lesson from earlier we write OK so that it works around the
origin and some predators
OK so i sent to the point and then
i look at
all of the points in the data set and i say
which of these five centres of the closest to
and they take the colour of the closest and
so all of the
o points around the red cross and now being coloured red and there are some
point not near the coloured red coloured red because the narrative to the red center
than any of the other centers
so now we've done that we noticed the red centre isn't actually very central
compared to the red points we can move it so that it is central so
we need each of that k means the means of the clusters that they are
and once we don
now from the assignment then look presentable so we can read colour given the new
location of the sentence so this is something that we can iterate we can move
the center so that they match
the things are responsible for and then we can change the coloring given the new
if we
he showed that algorithm eventually will converge when nothing gets free coloured and say nothing
and so the algorithm automatically recovers five
five clusters
if i'm honest it and actually do that first time so this thing depends on
random initialisation the answer you end up with will depend on the initialisation
if you run this thing multiple times you can potentially get different answers
so just as with other methods in machine learning
different things can happen and it's not sure what you should do you come up
with an objective function so there's an objective function for k means which is
the sum of the squared distortions between
each point in the dataset in its centre
so that that's a measure of how good clustering is if
everything seems to be close to its center then it's a good clustering
so what i actually did was rerun several times
and i picked the solution had the best objective function so that i can automatically
come up with a good clustering rather than having to look at it until it
does what
he wanted as the human because that's not removing human
so this is in the algorithm and its use
variety of sort of
image systems for sort of clustering colour space and write applications
one really neat application which combines ideas from unsupervised and supervised learning
which was used in
this car called stanley which
trade across the desert so stanley was project from stanford and
the this vehicle one challenge we had to drive autonomously across vast distances in the
desert so
by drive autonomously is correlated computers on board and it just has to drive itself
it could you
you can
and as long as you like programming before the challenge but once the challenge starts
carries on it saying you're not going to be able to intervene and say no
two layers like this
you might be in trouble
in the sense that the number of units you need could be
exponential in the input size to represent some functions
even though
the same function could be represented more efficiently with the deeper architecture
in particular
has that came up with classes of functions that can become representable
very compactly with an architecture that k
but if you try to represented with k minus one levels
you would need exponential size in the graph
of course these are very specific kinds of of
you can think of neural networks with positive weights
but still it's kind of
signal that we might want to investigate
training deep architectures
before two thousand six
researchers in the neural network community
i had tried for
please twenty years to train your networks with more than one or two hidden layer
and the essentially failed
and one of the things i'm going to try to talk about in more detail
today is
explorations the to try to understand why
the first paper that really made the breakthrough here is the paper by hinton osindero
into a fast learning algorithm for deep belief networks
two thousand six and a little bit later in the same year
paper two papers came out one from my group and one from young's group
about using similar principles
to train
deep architectures
and i'm going to
a bit more about these algorithms
first of all the algorithm that
hinton and his collaborators presented
it is not good for training
a so-called deep belief network and then
tuning its parameters that can be used for
classification task
the it goes is like this
we can take our data i'm going to use their data to train a simple
one layer model called a restricted boltzmann machine which i will
tell more about later but you can think of it as finding a transformation of
the data into factors that are good at explaining the data
once we have learned that transformation
how to get from inputs to these factors that we're learning
we can transform the data into that new representation
and we're going to take that
new was observation as data for training a second
rbms second restricted boltzmann machines
now we can be done in a number of times
and then we can add
the final layer which may now have extra
variables for the
classification we care about
and then the final step we can
forget about the fact that this whole thing is is a probabilistic graphical model and
just use the forward pass in order to compute probabilities of classes given inputs and
then fine tune do gradient descent and fine-tune all the parameters of this big model
optimize the
the classification error minimize station or more precisely
maximize the log likelihood of the correct classification given inputs
one thing we did in this two thousand six paper we produced
the results with the deep belief networks and we try to see if the principle
this principle of greedy layer wise initialisation could be applied to other classes of of
learners and we tried to autoencoders so an autoencoder is is a neural network with
an input and one or more hidden layers and it it's target is its input
to its trying to reproduce the input that's why it's called one-quarter we encode input
into some representation and then we try to decode it
you can see that if the number of units here is is large and here
we might be in trouble and we might look to learn the identity and not
learn anything useful
this book is going to be intuitive later
let's look at the question which is another famous for disney channel question can define
between two point two victories is inexpensive and as essential minus their squared euclidean distance
by to see square
what are the typical functions of the RKHS items that sons of versions of this
just sums of cash and so a typical function of the catches would some of
advice potential mind it's six a squared
this is a typical functional RKHS
and by definition of what is the number this function
just a few questions this quote numbered definitions would be the sum of a and
phi i phi j
can between exciting journey so there's a small table here is special minus excitement exchange
OK this is supposed to be day of site is j
so this is the direct competition in fights you can play a trick
that is a bit specific to the version can also
and write in another way so there is pretty between this and something a bit
so we need to be a bit familiar with free energies and things that we
would keep it fat but imagine that first if f has is this form that
you know that if
as the fourier transform in fact double sword can be written as
an integral over the
the spatial frequencies and the fourier space
OK of the fourier transform
time especially assume that square omega square where get frequency
so what wanted to show that we can get here
first you might know that there is a famous equality holds in this case that
says that the
the function sine function as the norm as two norm get integral of square is
is finite
and you know the antonym of f is equal to the sum of its fourier
transform this is come on a pretty
and here you see that you have something that would like to estimate the fourier
transform is said that you had this term especially he must me square
so these will be larger than the number of of of
and in fact you see that for first for this to be finite suppose you
want to to have a function with a small army version RKHS for you see
that for this to be financially two the fourier transform of f decreases at pieces
with the frequency because they differ from times special
on the square
so this thing has to go to the web to two zero very fast
OK and if i can you can be sure that the government saying that it
has to be infinitely differentiable ways to the ravages holders so this is the first
international vicious of division occasions is made of functions with an infinite number of derivatives
and second what is the number of of functional RKHS we see that the norm
will be small basically if the fourier transform
doesn't have to much
and actually doesn't have to two
many national versus when omega is large so this means that
number function with this morning there was an RKHS
when most of the frequencies in the composition of small
OK because
you have ever heard from again which is large for large omigod you motivated by
its initial opening square city as soon as well
when you compose finished three transform yes energy in high frequencies this will be multiplied
by the expansion of the african seems to be very large so if you want
to be smaller than the energy to be to be located in sport consists
so if you give it shows that having a small number of the vision RKHS
i mean being small enough and and and small in the sense of fourier transform
the of the spectrum being close to the
located support for cancer
so this is an international next
OK so this was a fat and suggests sufficient conditions can also i think what
i presented
can be considered to be technical
but the the RKHS is not always presented but i think it's going to be
useful later in his forest to the right the kernels
real spaces
now so that we can also
the thing to remember also that to define can all you don't need to make
any assumptions on your space of points OK you can make can between people between
sentences between
victor between whatever
we don't assume any prior o thing on the on on the space but you
you assume things about the function itself you need to be able to design efficient
k that has some properties and as soon as it has good properties then together
we can overcome the idea of embedding space in hilbert space
then comes the idea of building the RKHS