be interested in the simple model study
find out what it's all about but at the same time
for pete's sake ask yourself the question what does this have to do
with the price of rice in china
with anything else
and ask those question though don't let those questions interfere with understanding the simple model
but you've got to always be focusing on how that simple model
it relates
two what you visualize
as a communication system
and usually will have some relation but not complete relation OK here the problems are
in this binary interface
the source
you might produce
but the source might produce stream of data
in other words if what you're dealing with
is the kind of situation where you're where you're an amateur photographer you go around
taking all sorts of pictures
and then you encode these pictures
what we mean by encoding the picture determined binary digits
and then you want to send your pictures to somebody else
but what you're really doing is sending these packets to someone else in not sending
a stream of data you have ten pictures you want to send those ten pictures
and the output of the whole system you hope you see ten separate pictures you
hope there's something in there which can recognise
that out of the stream of binary digits come across the channel because some packet
structure there
OK well we're not going to talk about that really
i mean whenever you start dealing with this problem the source encoding you also need
to worry a little bit about the packet structure what are the protocols
for knowing when something new starts when something new ends
those kinds of problems are dealt with mostly in the network course here
and you can find out all sorts of things about them there but at is
two general types of things packets
and streams of data
in terms of understanding voice encoding you can study them both together
why you study them both together because the packets are long
and because the packets are one because they include a lot of data
you have a little bit the fact about how to start a little bit of
and the fact about how to end it
but the main structural problem you'll be dealing with is what to do with the
and in this edit
i added piece that comes at the end to worry about
how do you how you don't know the beginning and the end
and that's the problem we have with with stream data also because training data does
not start time minus infinity
i mean whatever the stream data is coming from what is coming from the not
starting time the was invented you just think of it that way
because you recognise you can post the problem of how do you started how do
you and the
and hopefully you can postpone somebody else has taken over the job
what the channel except as either these binary strings are packets
but then queuing exists
OK in other words you have stuff coming into which channel
sometimes i'm sitting at home i want to send
long file i one send whole textbook i'm writing to somebody
he was up it takes a long time to get out of
of my computer and into this other person computer will be nice if i could
send it of optical speeds
but i don't care much i don't care much whether
it takes
a second or minutes or an hour to get to this other person
we one reason for
for a week anyway if he reads it all
so what difference does it make
OK but anyway we have is q in problems which are again separable
the dealt with mostly in the network course
what were mostly interested in is how to reduce the rate
resources how do you encode things more efficiently
data compression
is the word used given to this how do you how do you compress things
into a smaller number of bits using the statistical structure of
and so
i to say that this was which together in the one i together in the
tool but that under the label so that together with other
however here the together and one but together these guys together with either so maybe
brought more of the coherence of the cluster
so some people may find it ended that the thing some people might think
this is close to the end of the track to the original
and if you have
many points and many clusters there are very many variations which you can
change the one by keeping this
the classification of the thing
very much
which can which basically so
there be many
clustering that would be at equal distance from the origin
but i will look very different
and practically many other businesses to make this distinction so this one is one of
the least discriminative distances you would choose
this will be equal when that could lead to different things
that's what i mean that you may not want to use it in
it went enough
let's go now to different distance however it's very very intuitive when thing like us
which is much more complicated to describe
but i would tend to because
it is located to scuttle
the information theory which is the cause of the cell and also because it has
some nice qualities and also
that's a compliment to
so this would be more appropriate for
many clusterings and last
or many clusters are relatively large distance
so this this relies on
probabilistic interpretation of the data center
he played the following game
again think point
and from the data
look at its label
in one clustering quality
and itself
we ask ourselves and killed why now is the label of the point is like
a random variable
so about service k
the label in the first in clustering what
much like no came from the label in the last
can this k completely determined
they no information about the game or something in the middle
that can be this can be handled in the formation during the
and here a one-page introduction to information theory
so the entropy
is the quantity that measures how much and randomness this is in
now that may seem a strange question but you can make a random variable that
is deterministic takes over with probability one that has no
and you can make a random variable that takes
value with probability
ninety nine percent and have some randomness
and you can take a uniform distribution over many values and that will have a
high degree of randomness which means a high degree of uncertainty of what the outcome
will be
problem LSQR is really one of the most effective ways for solving this problem
and these are large-scale proper for large scale problems
OK now i want to talk about total least squares
and let me just say a few words about that
so remember
here's the strength
this is a risk
the usual ordinary least squares as he had a zero
and now we want to but here we have here at entry so we're going
to do
so i'm going to move b to the right-hand side
and i'll move are together so this equation here is replaced by this equation
so this is now a new system of equations
method by p so this is the rose by
n plus one columns this EM rules by plus one columns
and this is the matrix we don't know this we know this is in our
in our knowledge base
but this is unknown
i can use the notation c
that's this matrix here plus half that matrix times e or that i should say
maybe equals zero
OK so we have this perturbed system of homogeneous equations the last component of which
is equal to minus one
so now
this may in order to have a solution to to this
the rank of the system here see process must be less than them and plus
one right you can only a homogeneous system of equations it has less than full
rank so when we ask for is how can we perturb this matrix c
so that its rank
is less than n plus one
and the answer is given in terms of the singular value decomposition
so i'm assuming everybody knows something about the singular value decomposition here
so here see it has a singular value decomposition is you are orthogonal
sigma has n plus one singular values
the transfer is an plus-one by plus one right now
the answer the closest matrix
of a given rank in the frobenius norm of the euclidean norm is by setting
the smaller singular values equal to zero if you have an m by n n
matrix or PYP matrix
and you want to make it into an matrix are less than p you throw
away the smaller singular values that's the best matrix approximation you can make
so it's really very useful and and then you can use that if you get
a few data is contaminated has noise and that
all right so here's the answer to this problem
you compute the singular value decomposition of c
and then you look at the
the vector v connected with the smallest singular values
all right so then x minus one
it is equal to the c said
and then you normalise it so that the bottom element of the vector v n
plus one is just equal to minus one so it's very easy very easy computation
you just have to for computer really the smaller singular value and its corresponding singular
and know this of course the assumption is that this bottom element
is not equal to zero
so total least squares solution does not exist
at the moment is zero
or are close to zero and that comes up when you when you have orthogonal
rick problems who where the data is orthogonal and you are liable to get into
problems of that nature
TLS is used very often for doing data analysis
OK let me just go on a bit about TLS and say some other things
so here's
a structure that sometimes comes out
the matrix e
the air matrix has the first k columns have no apparent it after you have
a column of all ones that has no apparent so there are some columns that
had no nowhere and some columns to have air
how can you handle that is are totally square solution so the combination of
ordinary least squares and total least squares and can you combine the two together
and the answer works out quite simply
namely one does a orthogonal transformation
this q on the c plus
because you don't see
and the length of the surface charge unchanged multiplying by an orthogonal matrix so
you can see if i construct this q to make this into an upper triangular
this portion is left upper triangular and this stuff here there's
the sea is changed by the orthogonal matrix as
originally this was changed to
but it's only multiplied by an orthogonal matrix as i point out here
let the norm
is the same as the normalized transport and that it it in some way so
the answer is quite easy now so it in order to solve the problem we
need to do is find the SVD of c two two
this problem before
and then once having it computed that then we can solve for the the part
that's uncontaminated the original part of the system so one program can give you an
ordinary least squares solution and total least squares solution or you could be on total
least squares are called ordinary least squares it would be very easy to assemble the
program of that nature
now i want to talk about something that
currently developing this on regularized total least squares OK so
if you look at the total least squares problem
it's equivalent to the following b-minus a ax we know i don't know how to
minimize that and that makes total least squares of the interesting divided by one plus
the norm of x squared so ordinarily you can see the norm of x is
in whole these two with this would be an ordinary least squares problem so that
the total least squares problem is in some sense
better relative that measure of the of the solution
and then i take being augmented by a that c
and xeon x augmented by one that c so
this problem
here is equivalent to this matrix here
and the solutions given by the small singular value of the matrix c
OK but now
when you realize that totally square then we have
people might say x amount you see we have one plus extra holes vx
examples like
arranging molecules as regular crystal structures and the problem of properly temperature this distribution or
this is the motivation for our methodology called simulated annealing
that is
also natural or biological evolution which is which has led to the development of
evolutionary reasons
so following this sources of inspiration
we will discuss
two groups
of techniques mainly one thing is simulated annealing and then evolution used
on evolutionary algorithms is a rather diverse area
which consists of many techniques and we will touch
three of them
evolution strategies genetic algorithms and genetic programming
start with the simulated annealing
so maybe just
short question how many of you are familiar with this technique maybe help you it
yes one two
three four
not too many OK
we really need to start from scratch i would say
so the idea is very simple we observe a certain physical process and this
is then used in a simplified way in computer model this process with a certain
purpose that is with the idea
to exploit that computer model of this process to be used in problem solving so
this is exactly what we do with any
either physically or biologically inspired search techniques so what is the motivation what is the
source of the inspiration in this case the simulated annealing
so if we discuss annealing as
physical process
then this is the process of cooling certain matter in modern substance and the effect
of this process is condensing matter into a crystalline solid so i think at least
intuitively we you are familiar with this
now this is
for example that metallurgical industry like hardening steel which is done by first increasing its
temperature and then carefully decreasing it so that the appropriate internal structure is achieved
you know way this process can be
viewed as a specific adaptation process
where we are trying to optimize the structure of the structure of the solid to
get at the end of this process
one thing that is important with this process is the way how the temperature decreases
we we we can think about this matter of
of a system of particles
that at high temperature they move around and the lower the temperature less movement with
the particles and the we say that they have less and less free energy so
at the end they stabilize within the certain structure
this was described in physics a long time ago
we don't boltzmann distribution boltzmann was a physicist who studied these processes
so he
i propose he found this formula for the probability of a certain
particle system to be in a certain state of the given temperature
now what's important here is that these e of s which is
the free energy
so what does it mean that we see
as this with increasing
free energy
the probability for a certain state minimizes this is just a background that is in
a very simple form used
in in an algorithm
that was proposed by metropolis and quarters
this physical process
first of all and then this was found very
currently as an efficient way of solving certain optimization problems
so this structure they seem this structure evolution
officers substance at a given temperature so they assume
a certain states of the system of particles at a given temperature and they perform
certain simulations for certain
a number of steps
to understand how this
leads the search to the search space it's important to note that the key step
it is
being in a certain point in this search space
then we generate a new state as new
we evaluate this energy difference which is
free energy of the new states minus energy of
previous state
and then accept the new state with probability depends on
this difference
the very few step is really here how these acceptance of the new state is
this means
the probability of accepting state is one so we definitely accept the new state if
this is that that energy is
and negative which means that minimizes the energy
so if we found a better solution than we say OK
this will be our new point in the search space
so this is one step however if
the solution that was found or the new state
it is
well talking in terms of the problem that are solving in the solution is worse
he has a certain formula here
tells us that in some cases
even worse solutions are accepted
but the probability of
decreases as you see later as the temperature
also decreases
what does it mean
and the problem is that if we want to be in the region n
of the state space and the parameter space that allows to store
bits of information reliably
we need those derivatives to be less than one we need those eigenvalues
the have we need the spectral radius to be less than one we need
all the eigenvalues to be less than one
because this is the condition that we're allowed to store information
reliably but at the same time this condition
makes it so that these are this derivative
this matrix which is a product of all the intermediate jacoby matrices
converges to zero exponentially fast in terms of the length of the
sequence so why is not a problem because now we have this
some some of the terms will be very small because they're exponentially
smaller than the other ones so the terms
that regard the long term dependencies in other words how
the state in the remote past some far in the past top
influences the current t those terms will be very small compared
to the terms that some corresponding to what's happening
when tall is rece very close to t right right
so we're what's happening is that the total gradient is the sum
of terms some of which will be much smaller and we know what happens
numerically when you add a large number of small number
basically a small number loses you lose that information i mean
if you if you and especially to think about the gas green descent
this kind of noise happening in this gradient
and so what we could have is
essentially that the the long term dependencies are going to dominate
is going to be easy for the network to learn to shore term dependencies
but it's going to take for ever for the network to learn the long
term dependencies and for ever be really bad in some cases
all right so this is this is really really important
and i want make pause here so values ask questions
yes yeah a try it yeah where yeah but the problem we scaling is
that yeah then you don't have to guarantee that is the correct
gradient anymore
so if you're lucky maybe all of those terms have the same sign for
example and then it would be fine but let's say some positive
some negative you changed weighting of each of them
and now you might going the wrong direction
yes i'll come to that as one of the directions to try to solve this
problem but note that it will solve completely would make it easier
because we're trying to reach between a taught eighty through some
steps better somehow less nonlinear and have
less yeah jacoby closer to one basically
but that's that's very important direction in as a
yeah i think so yeah i don't have a like
math to support this thing but but intuitively it's just a matter
that the total gradient is now how you know
has important terms from from a statistical point of view but they
numerically these terms are very very small right so so in principle
you now you would first kill off the you you would learn short
term dependencies and then those terms would be small and eventually
you should be able to learn the long-term ones
but in practice because you also have noise in the gradient coming
from the fact you're doing sgd and
know yeah all kinds of infections
or even numerical precision issues becomes harder and harder
yeah but that really here the argument i made doesn't really care
about the shape of the attractor it only depends on the
fact that we for it to be an attractor the eigenvalues need to
be less than one around it
yeah w i don't care where i'm on the attractor with
yes yes so in general when you store maybe bits
says you're exactly going to be desperation detractor isn't point
right otherwise you would need like one
attractor for each value that you want to store
it's much more efficient to have a kind of this would represent
the where the attractors actually multi-dimensional object
and you can store many bits sort of componential way but anyways
doesn't matter the point is to store information reliably you need
these contractive mappings but contractive mapping equals
hard to learn the longer term dependencies
yes that could be a problem to and in practice when we train recurrent
nets we see this happening so rarely no it's not necessarily mean
that would be one instance but simply the fact and you go in those
places where the eigenvalues in some regions eigenvalues larger than
the main
the one
you see around
the video screen that
OK so so it's not linear
probabilistic PCA
we casting process model
if you view the talk i
so the motivation for things inspired me to look at this sort of area
probabilistic visualisation algorithms include probabilistic PCA density networks and GTM the generative topographic map
i believe in very smoothly to model want to talk about today
gaston process latent variable model which i think you can genuinely say is a probabilistic
non linear version of PCA
there is a linear probabilistic
i'll talk about
the station and
well i'll talk optimisation but then
the problems associated with optimisation our reviewers pass algorithm for doing that
then i will show the model
in some visualisation applications in some inverse kinematics with discussion of other issues that arise
along the way
OK so this is bit of notation
we can even think of this as a latent variable model or models trying to
find an embedded space
so q is the dimension of the latent or embedded space where d is the
dimension of the data space
and will be the number of data points be dealing with friend data set the
data of interest y
which i have in the form of the design matrix
matrix i mean guy and and the
columns deep the dimension the data space
the was within the same form q dimensional
o canal disk icons
instead of discussing
the notation old and innovation from
matrix like
most commonly used i think it was in genes work i saw first
the vector from the ith row of the matrix in a way that bacteria brackets
around a vector from the ith column of a so i that makes things that
the final thing to say because someone
make when you see this because it centred data within and minus one for the
covariance matrix exponential covariance the data are interested in knowing when you see this is
the inner product matrix so that the sort of metrics to get kind people very
excited because they think oh i can nonlinear eyes that suggests
but even political very that is on the outside its inner product matrix
so here
but we want to represent the data we give them with a very active
well we want to assume a linear relationship of the form y equals x w
i'm interested in probabilistic models
so basically we implemented in the following way to these graphical notation simple graph
i still think even simple graph this help
familiar with the connotation and now with incoming arrows is indicative of a definition of
probability distribution of that variable
and the arrows indicate that those guys conditioning variables so this in the indicates the
probability distribution of y given x commodore of the joint distribution factorizes that we can
find the distribution
this article
distribution with no parents
so this is the fact that this black it is my notation means that we're
going to do
the distribution of that but it is sort of a parameter or variable of interest
the graph is that there node is observed so we've got some of the latent
variables and some parameters which can relate a latent data to the observed data
with prior distribution over the latent variables and then simply guessing that
then if we place likelihood
which is of this form so the mean of the output
why is this linear form WS and the noise is beta minus one i then
this is known as probabilistic PCA all will see in the moment the solution leads
to probabilistic PCA which the model by
chris bishop mike tipping
what we do to to obtain the solution is we model the latent space x
and then we have a marginal likelihood of this form you can simply see is
a product the gaussians over each point with a particular form of the covariance matrix
now what we want to do it maximizes with respect to w with respect to
beta but the solution the doesn't depend on the test some w
the maximum likelihood solution
i mean what we maximize my likelihoods
so the maximum likelihood solution turned out to be
we should maintain the first q eigen vectors of the covariance matrix
with the corresponding eigenvalues lambda q we do that then w is given by
in fact as we maintained
which is strongly related to the idea of the covariance matrix the these arbitrary rotations
et cetera solution can be distributed all over the place certificate taken to be the
identity matrix
and if you were doing PCA what we would see how it is equal to
the queue
so if we take that as beta minus one goes to zero
that's what we see
is equal to the square of land q we would see that lambda q
that q is equal to well in probabilistic PCA what tipping and bishop were able
to show of proof that this is the solution even if beta is nonzero is
infinity i beta minus one is nonzero we still retain the eigen vectors of the
covariance matrix as sort of probabilistic interpretation of PCA
that's previous work
and the general
so i just statistics
so that's why
that's what i'm talking about the linear embeddings be talking about
data which may be in three dimensions with just plain
people talked about
data in high dimensions lying on on
it will data pipeline along dimension embedded space and there's no reason why the embedded
space should perhaps be nonlinear so what kinda really interested in
but what really interested in is a non linear embeddings
so in this case we want probabilistic non relationship between y and x
the difficulty is that propagate propagating any distribution through the nonlinear mapping can be very
so in practice the way people have typically solve this is to try to represent
distribution by some points
so what we're going see is is in the middle the
some kinds of graphs more general graphs and trees can actually be solved quite efficiently
and then moving on later when i see that for more general graphs you can
start thinking about approximate methods to solve problems like computing huge summation like this
and we want to approximate methods are fast so we can actually apply them in
OK so let's let's move on to the elimination algorithm is a very simple algorithm
essentially it's just sense exploiting one idea it's exploding the fact that the sum and
the product operations are distributed
which just means that you can move sums and products around
so let's imagine that we have this graph here just got six terrible so the
toy problems
and what this graph is telling me is that the maximal cliques are one two
one three three four three five
two four and there's three clique two four six
right so
what i've learned is that this model says that this distribution should factor into a
product of local terms like this these are one term for every maximal clique in
this graph
and what we're thinking about here's let's imagine you want to compute marginal distribution let's
i'm sitting here this node
this might be a sensor network
you might have a bunch of sensors these could all be sensors that are measuring
things in the environment i might be interested in for instance i i'm giving a
midterm tomorrow and
i have a pile of photocopied midterms i might ask
and so my students are
it's a more dishonest than studios
and they'd like to come in and steal one of the midterms to make photocopies
of so i could for instance require office with sensor networks at various junctures and
maybe the midterms are sitting right there so i'd be very interested for instance if
a student manage actually managed to get to the midterms i'd like alarm to go
so you can imagine i'd like to compute something like the probability of student appearing
at this place that could be one interpretation of the marginal
so what's going on here is you have a big summits over many random variables
looks kind of unpleasant at first but what you can see the boundaries you can
just start pushing the sum inside
and for instance six the sum over x six i can push it all the
way there is only one term this last term that depends on six
similarly the sums over x five there's these terms
so i can keep sort of pushing the summation further and further inside the product
so this is the distributive property and this is what can allow you to save
substantial computation
so this useful way to think to think about this actually in terms of of
graphical operations
we're talking about something over variables
but it's useful to think about it as if you've summed over variable
what you're allowed to do is you allowed to sort of cut that variable out
of the graph i can eliminate from the graph
that's where the name elimination comes from and i can strip these edges off
so once have done the work of some this guy that i get i get
to get i'm allowed to get rid of this part of the graph size the
graph shrinks submitted it's getting reduced
so that's one step elimination
and so i eliminate
and if you sort of look analytically what happens i get rid of this node
i get rid of these edges and if you look carefully you'll see that there's
a kind of modification to the compatibility of potential function on this edge
so it is and if it gets tweaked a little bit by the operation
but that's OK it's still on the same graph to slightly different so you can
use the twiddle for
and then i can recurse this operation i could for instance some five
and strip five
i could then some four
and strip out for and down to triangle graph and
i could some that out and at the end of the day i'd have my
you can do a little calculation you see exactly how much do you saved in
terms of
exploiting this distributive law and doing the elimination in this way
does anyone have was anything special about the order in which i was eliminating notes
anyone have any intuition about that
so if you remember i eliminated first six then five then four
then three then two
it was that important
could i have eliminated three to start with
sorry mate but the microns
well why could night to some up three right away
i would do well to the graph cuts
well you worry that five which split off here
what i five would actually get three coupled if
i do
it's funny
right corner and that's what said
and more space sorry
really unhappy two by two matrix on the left inside thank you
i compute this
and the power of the matrix in log time i take the upper right corner
or the lower left corner of your choice
that's the end national
so this implies
and or login timeout with the same occurrences as well as two binary search
and that really there
recursive squaring n
logan fuzzy concepts long
so this prove that here
suggestions on what techniques we might use for proving this there
what technique singular
induction very good
i think any time as the question the answer is induction can for the future
in this class
a friend of mine when he took an analysis class whenever the professor as well
the answer to this question the answer was always zero taken analysis class that's funny
will try to answer some questions that are
as answers are zero just for our own amusement
so we're impact on and
it's pretty much the obvious thing to do
but we have to cheque some places so the base case is
we have this to the first power
and that is itself one one one zero
and actually ends at least one
and you can check that this is supposed to be f two
after one and zero
and you can check it is
zero zero one is one of two one good
in this case is correct
so case is about as exciting
you got to prove that you are in the works
so i suppose
we have
this is what we want to compute
i'm just going to sort of
there's many ways i could do this on this with the fast way because
it's really not that exciting
direction to
one is induction on n
so i want to use induction on n
presumably actually use what i already know is true by decrease and by one
i have this property that this thing is going to be one one one zero
to the power n minus one
so the society now
by induction hypothesis one one one zero
the and minus one so presumably i should use it in some way this in
this equality is not yet true
OK so i need to add something on what can possibly add on to be
correct another
factor of one one one zero
so this is
proof by
i mean the when developing this proof is the only way it could possibly be
some sense you know its induction this is all you can do
and then you check indeed this equality holds
so for example FN pos one
is the product of these things so it's this road
times this color
that's fn times one plus and minus one times one which is the the definition
of the ten plus one could check call for the entries this is true
that's true
then i just put this together that's one one one zero to n minus one
time one one one zero
which is
one one one zero to the end
and for very simple proof
you have to do that in order to know this algorithm really works
yes thank you
in the lower right which if n minus one
this is why should really check your proofs we would have discovered that when i
checked that this was that road signs that column
that's why you're here to fix fixed my box
the great thing about being up here is
in quiz
but that's a minor mistake
this much better
right so
the divide-and-conquer algorithms
still we relatively simple one so far
in fact the fanciest then merge sort which we already saw so that's not too
exciting the rest of all the log n time so
let's break out of the log in world
well you all the master method memorize right
so i can race that's good
good us
next problem is matrix multiplication following right up on the two by two matrix multiplication
let's see how we can compute and by n
matrix multiplications
just to recap
you know how to multiply matrices but is the definition so we can turn it
into an algorithm you have two matrices a and b
capital letters
the i j th entry i cut my throat column is called little AIJ jair
that'll be i j and your goal is to compute the product of matrices
i should probably say that i and j
range from one to n
so are square matrices the output is to compute c
CIJ which is the product of a and b
for recap
the i j th entry of the product
is there some place the inner product of the i th row they with the
j th column of b
you can write that other some
like so
so we want to compute this thing
for every i and j
so what's the obvious target for doing this
you compute the sum to compute all the products to compute the sun says like
an operations here roughly i mean like two and minus one whatever its order and
there's an squared entries i see that i computer that's and keep time
right this
just before
the programmers at heart
here's the source code is read all write occur this is simply not going to
write and gory detail
and so on
so you cannot use this phantom
grace puzzle
can you see the founder one
but here's a beautiful fountain that you cannot see i don't know why
but fortunately maybe you can see this which is the duke some kind of reconstruction
from under sampled data
and again
disastrous results
again why they will look at these pictures the geologist and say well under undersampled
nyquist by factor fifty you come in an enormous crime and that's what you pay
and so the radiologists are puzzled because
we're puzzled because
what this suggests is that maybe we can really speed up more we cannot sample
OK i want to emphasise it is very difficult project because the problem so that
one kind of
accuse anybody so we have the phantom which you cannot see
we have fully acquisition strategies that you can see
and so
what we have to do is we have to interpolate in the fourier domain because
there's some location in fourier space like this white pixels where we get data as
black pixel we don't get data only to interpolate
this is a very hard interpolation problem because interpolating the fourier transform
it is extremely difficult to show you how difficult this is
here what you're seeing on the right is the cut through the fourier transform of
the fourier transform
through a radio line a sort of horizontal line going about here
and so the blue curve will be the real part of the fourier transform and
when this line meets the white pixels it so what data point that you have
so it's indicated by red dot on this curve
so your problem is that of interpolating the right points to get the blue curve
and some people know how to do this and i'd be interested
knowing your ideas because i have no idea how to this
OK so really this idea of being able to recover images from undersampled
measurements is very important because for example you could
why don't you applicability
of m are very significant
OK so now i will explain compressed sensing and compressive sensing relies on two tenets
of the first sparsity which had we have discussed heavily so the second is incoherent
its sparsity we're gonna go quick and
so here we take an image rather complicated image of the comedian it's a megapixel
image and this image is obviously not sparse
but if i look at it in a different domain for example in the wavelet
domain the way the domain is just an orthonormal transformations
think about it as a generalized fourier transform if you will if i look at
the coefficient sequence in the wavelet domain i see something like this which is i
see that if you were the coefficients are very large
a lot of them are
quite small
and even though
here in this portion of the wavelet spectrum they look like they look large in
fact they are not
because when i blew up these things alot of coefficients are zero
and only if you in a few places announces
all right
OK so
what this says is that this
the image may be complicated but in the wavelet domain is approximately sparse because a
lot of its coefficients are very very small
sparsity something we have discussed already you give me e major signal like can expanded
appropriate basis for example
that's a super position despite a superposition of sinusoids a superposition of wavelets and so
on and so forth and we're going to say that
expansion is sparse
if when i look at the coefficient sequence x i see something like this last
your coefficients a few nonzero coefficients and we can say that nearly sparse without telling
too much what that means if instead of being exactly zero
the coefficient r
small not exactly zero but there are just small and so if you coefficients seem
to capture most of the energy of the of the of the object and so
according to his definition
this image is only approximately sparse or nearly sparse
in the wavelet domain
now the fact that images have sparse expansions or nearly sparse expansion has tremendous consequences
because it says that we can discard small coefficients without much such loss
so i'm going to make an experiment that will just
and for sizes so here we have a megapixel images what i'm going to do
it is going perform a very simple operations were going essentially do
three things
calculate the wavelet coefficients sequence of these objects
which is
OK that step one step two is going to set to zero world
all the coefficients but the twenty five thousand largest
and then step three and one for the wavelet transform
so what the same calculator where the coefficients sequence set to zero almost all the
coefficient but
top two point five percent largest coefficients invert transfer
so as for those of you who are like electrical engineers when describing is essentially
a proxy for data compression
if i were to data compression there will be one more step which is you
have to quantized coefficients and address
and so
you know quantized coefficient and essentially transform that into bit strings but roughly speaking is
you know fundamental physics that
if you have some sort of
energy associated with the vacuum
it should be a hundred and twenty others among which is larger than what we
now where cosmology for many years has been the science where you know that were
not even our but spent a lot about hundred and twenty order of money this
kind of a lot
and also and then we're going to philosophy rather than science but after to mention
it because again it's an active idea
if the cosmological constant was much bigger than it is today
probably wouldn't be here because you remember perturbation don't grow if you in london dominated
so in order for us to be the only the but for the perturbation to
grow for enough time to the go non-linear
and the conformal stars and galaxies and former head element that are heavier than the
lightest element created in the big bang you need to have supernovae who can build
elements that are heavier than i don't you all these things so we can not
be here
she was much bigger than it is
so there is some sort of
food for thought the four philosophers also
what is it
since it's so tiny could be
a dynamical field maybe
or something even more dramatic why now
these are all of questions
so remember this is the only animation a show you before that on an accelerated
expansion here arise and sharing
two point starting side rising
and then the
by the end of the animation it end up outside but this is just the
hubble horizon is not the actual physical arising it doesn't
into the description the entire it's function is to is just start time is one
but this animation is simply telling you that at the moment the where the universe
started being dominated by the cosmological constant the things that are inside your eyes and
say you far away galaxy in the future may you may as well not being
able to see it anymore because
it's on the outside
transition between they matter dominated and cosmological constant that can dominate the happens very quickly
so again
why not
since the transition happens very quickly in the life of the universe
this is the logo of the scale factor and this is you know the percentage
of the universe is dominated by what cosmological parameters what call component you see that
the transition happen pretty quickly and we happen to leave exactly here
here we have the standard cosmological model with these compositions
ninety six percent of the universe is missing we've seen this slide before and they
have two major questions that can be addressed exclusively by looking up at the sky
what created the primordial perturbations this is something we discuss
remember in the last lecture what were again we need to postulate the period of
accelerated expansion called inflation and then we actually solve all these problems of the standard
big bang model and also these present-day accelerate this function
that makes the universe accidentally today in this question may not be related because you
know all the time you postulate an accelerated expansion
the theoretical physicists to study the vacuum tell us the cosmological constant should be many
other the of money to larger than the set of and also the vacuum energy
is uniformly distributed
so to give us an idea idealist to follow
if you could transform all the energy of the vacuum enclosing the volume of the
earth in electricity
this would correspond to the quantity of electricity american uses in one day
now you're in europe we always say that american is a lot of electricity but
imagine so its own small
you need to transform all the energy of the vacuum enclosing the volume corresponding to
the earth in the city
and that may explain you why
you see the effect of a cosmological constant vacuum energy only when you go to
scales that are compatible to do rising size today
because the huge volume
remember that for cosmology is galaxies are point and you know the error is much
much much smaller than the galaxy galaxies is made of a
many millions of stars and yet is much much less than fun and so you
know what's case i'm talking about
so be good if we could get energy out of this but we can't because
it's uniformly distributed as far as we know so it's useless
can solve the problem of pollution except so what what do we know
it's mostly distributed as an fall into galaxies and clusters and affect the universality of
this larger scales and it was almost constant density doesn't really dilute as the universe
expanded now it may be that value so little bit you know if it's w
equation of state parameter is not exactly minus one then it means that the value
is a little bit but so far we have no evidence for it to be
significantly different from minus one the error bars around the parameters and those are about
of the order of one percent level also
but still is consistent with cosmological constant that's invisible that's why it's called dark energy
because you can see this effect only on the expansion history and geometry of the
universe and it's possibly associated with the vacuum
is nothing but honestly we haven't got a clue what to do
these two people
that means you replace it with kernel computation it is that they were living in
the input space
the other that the same way
so that's nice because maybe
the data
so maybe the data was not linearly separable in original space that is linearly separable
in this new space
OK and here's of classic example
stone from someone else's
where this particular
dot product
in two dimensional space so if the original data was in
in two dimensional space and we took one for that so i b
pretty close to
that corresponds to a mapping from this two-dimensional space three-dimensional space where here separating boundary
was left
and here
o eight years
could and somewhere over
if the data is linearly separable by a good margin
there we have a nice
generalisation bound to tell us that we only need sample size comparable one where the
margins where they get constant are believed generalise well so i mean by being linearly
separable by margin gamma i mean is that in the simplest space you're looking at
and let's normalized things so that everything is contained in the unit ball years the
origin everything contained in the unit ball
OK so so given that the normalisation
and we have forgiven separator how
how much margin
separation that we have so separator altogether we cannot explain all the positive them that
way that separate margin gamma
it a linearly separable in the phi space by margin gamma
and we need sample size only about one of them
he did the this normalisation because otherwise the question is whether you can help me
you should be able to just by scaling everything to make anything
so data is linearly separable in this space by some margin gamma then then you
need sample size only about one of them
a lot of factors
are being
he o ignores the concept to tell it gets rid of bugs
OK so
his great kernels have been found to be useful in practice for dealing with all
sorts of different
so maybe there was a linearly separable the original space you player kernel
and you're hoping it's still linearly separable and furthermore by large margin
and that's great because even if the new space is very high dimensional which could
were you as long as the margin is large then you have to worry about
dimensional space
OK so that's the quick
recap of kernels
so there's something a little funny that i want to get out which is that
on the one hand operationally a kernel just it's function someone wrote
that plug into object aperture number and scale everything says between plus one to minus
that sample everything was nine involved the thing is that some right kernel function that
given two objects x and y for them between one minus one where one means
we think there really similar negative ones i think are really does
with these extra requirements of positive semi de
a theory that was talking about margins implicit space
this is so
OK so the cartoon picture i have
this is a little bit of the gap year so so the kind of the
issue we want to get at is that
if we're thinking about using learning for some new problem one class protein structures
we're trying to decide
of different similarity measures were thinking of which one should we use
it's a little difficult directly
to say well
the similarity function usually positive semi definite and it should result in data having a
large margin separator in the implicit space
so it's not so in other words this is it's
it's a nice properties it's definitely and i
i mean it
very nice theory
question whether we can change this kind of answer to something that might be
may be more helpful in trying to decide whether i should use one similarity function
and of course given data you can always try if several similarity function you can
try one trying to try another you can test to see which one works better
if you try to come up with one maybe you're you're coding up some new
measure of similarity among that maybe we can have some alternative views of things that
might ideally get some more guidance into how to come up with that that's that's
what we're trying to get there
and this
OK so
so i'd like to try to bridge the gap that and is also a little
bit i mean the first time we see that a little bit of the something-for-nothing
feel to the standard
here is all the power of the high dimensional space and pay for the when
you start looking at you realize that this is not quite true margin really is
maybe we can talk about alternate explanations that don't involve implicit spaces
OK so that's when i get asked to do we need this notion of implicit
the back room up to the shared that's apart they are interesting
so based on this i give you a simple example to see how we can
compress the data what we to data warehousing and data mining
suppose we get it redirect that were marched against three thousand stores everyday selling ten
thousand items
so suppose each item in the whole lifetime of going you only be read
ten times on average actually is much more if you really see the real case
every hour so the store manager RFID taking take the reader goes to restore once
or something
then you can see that the the bottom you can generate
four these three
and in many
two parts per day is really huge by the people who actually want to do
all that c
for example the one answer question like this every time of all the items small
from the warehouse to the checkout counter in march two thousand six off as it
could be
but you can see there are so many of our items and there are lots
and lots of data in our body you want and so the score is almost
response immediately
it seems not
so then we discussed this warehouse
the first thing is to look at the data
but they actually if you look at this EPC location time
that's the raw data
actually this raw data
in many cases they the the command sitting there may be read many times before
they even more
so you can see there
the same
same are RFID
aaron same location
but it would be read t one t two up to detect very simple compression
could be
you just say instead of
giving me ten records
the only one rec
so what's the first time you read was the last time you read
i mean it's just in time and all time what i need just this in
the middle
everything can be gone because you assume most commonly this is there you read many
times even today it's raining is well sometimes miscarriage some signal once or twice
the commodity or not downhearted and coming back
so they you now use this record you can compress
but that's a very simple compression
but the major compression is when you do the data warehouse you can think about
you can think the data warehouses centre constructed by integrating the data
into some
you know that q then you can do all that
but the problem is
if you say i use the same way as the number of data cubes
i have
this warehouse farm they may have a data cube truck shipping they have a few
the shared may have added to the queue
the problem is
some important information could be missed
for example if the milk goes back
if the miracles that you want to che which track
you know back to the track or to define
the problem is once you compress the RFID if it's gone
if this
a gallon of milk goes back
you cannot blame all the male OK it is this one because they usually
you're not everything goes back to this jack o'neill back
if you
summarized high-level you miss all the traces
you're not you find was the problem
what we really want is we want to consider data cube
i want to compress them
but on the other hand is the loss this compression
the misinformed trace back
which milk
what unleashing goes back why the is the shipping province storage problem distribution centre problem
of farm problem you actually would try to use this last this history
a compression of course sometimes you want use lossy compression for example are you to
training some rolling you may see the lossy compression is OK i'm not exactly examine
every jug of milk and exacting the whole you know the whole flow
if we look at this the first thing
i'm going to discuss
this the lossy compression means how can i compress data a substantial way
you can think about this in the factory
produce a lot of things
the distributed usually in about way two different distribution center this distribution centre for further
and now with a linear chain
which are the most common sort of CRF in the sort of going to be
talking about
we have that
let x
is an input sequence
and y is an output sequence
the simplest
cases where the output sequence
is of the same length
and so
part of speech is an example of this
but another example
is hyphenation
so the
the input might be
x equals
and then the output
it would be y equals
zero zero one
and then maybe
zero zero zero zero
and because the way this word can be hyphenated his bees
hyphen love it
and i'm not sure if you if it really legal to have a hyphen after
the v certainly not only could have a hyphen
anywhere else in this word
and so
the input here would be a sequence of letters
in the output would be a sequence of bits
and each bit
it's going to work
whether or not a hyphen
whether or not a hyphen is legal
immediately after the corresponding letter
so the last bit is just a placeholder
and in fact i'm going to
i'm going to use a placeholder for you the the position before the first position
the position after the last position
because it's going to make describing some algorithm simpler but more you know in
in this particular case actually you know we know maybe the rules of english say
that you can't hide after the last letter
and the thing that also say that you never hyphenate after the first letter
actually maybe you do like a model
maybe you never hyphenate before the last letter but so this this is a representation
so feel that this trait is that
there are some
some lies in the output y
they should have a low probability regardless of the input x
but that's something that i can try to learn from the data rather than a
like so
actually so the let's look at some some so every feature function
f j if x and y
one feature function might be
you know
number of nonzeros
and why
divided by the length of x
and so here
it would be
one out of seven
and more
we could use this feature function to learn
right and this legislative means i bring it on slashdot and i also evaluated translation
and what is what's the observation the observation is of course when i no layers
of than predictors letters that i get a really good performance ninety three but when
i think less of and evaluate on opinions my performance is ninety two percent which
basically means that i can i can bring my model and how people how people
denote someone is friend or foe in this model predicts whether people trust one another
as well as if i were to train on pastors and you see the same
thing for wikipedia identify train on wikipedia because wikipedia my perform my accuracy eighty
if i train on one of the two datasets and the predictions on wikipedia my
accuracy drops forty percent right so i again i can train on how people vote
and or how people how people vote and predict who people trust as well as
if i were to train on how people trust so basically what is the point
i want to make here is that this very simple one has this list was
an amazing generalisation property which what seems to hint is that regardless of what is
really the meaning or semantics of these positive and negative edges a b and people
tend to use them in the same way meaning the same what works equally well
regardless of the data identical so you see that sort of wikipedia just harder to
model now what i can also do is i can look at the sixteen different
features of the head and i can now sort of see how these different triangles
vote for for the for the sign to be positive or negative so what i
mean is that my
sixteen triads where the the
and gets created from the first to the last match right so this would be
four classes this is the four classes in the form of minus then new edge
created from here to there right so for example balance would balance theory would say
this vote for four plus it says a friend of a friend is my friend
so support the blood status theory says that this would be a positive relationship and
what if for example here is that if you do logistic regression the coefficients k
positive which means that they do these kinds of prior to stand down to the
world four four four that for the third edge for the triangle closing that's to
be a plus
for example here here is the case where the balance false negative and you want
see that all the all the edges
sort of the brain coefficients correspond to the balance theory and so on and so
forth so what is the point here is that even this machine learning models correspondingly
well to the combination of that theory meaning friend of a friend is my friend
notions and notions of status theory which is the greatest edges bystanders
so just to
two to summarise what sort of what we see from this is that we see
that both theories meaning status and balance agree
well with the learning logistic regression models
we see that sort of backward pointing triangle triads have smaller weights than forward pointing
triads we see that balance is in better agreement in epinions and slashdot while status
is more of has more of an effect on wikipedia
and we see that
balance in the data
it consistently disagrees with his enemy of my enemy is my friend
so what i want to do now
is using this
which is sort of if i take now the wikipedia example i want to make
this a big brother and say OK how do people evaluate other people how do
people evaluate items that were created by other people OK so that extension of my
of what i've been doing so far right so what i have really began writing
social media is that people tend to express positive and negative attitudes or opinions right
and what is web sites have some form of feedback when people say yes i
like this no i don't like the rights of people and products people press like
buttons plus buttons you can to sentiment analysis things like that but at the end
of the idea is that sometimes people exclusively to tell you what they think of
something and sometimes they may be right that view and you can sentiment analysis to
discover what they think about
there are different ways how can people express opinions so for example on if you
look movie review or productivity website it's really that people right to express opinions about
about items right so i express an opinion what i think about the particular microwave
on that is sold on amazon dot com people also express opinions about other other
users right so for example opinions not culminated such example we're now
people don't rate items but there other people who i think it would be a
good administrator i think you won't be able to ministry that sort of a bit
different set and then in for example question answering websites in particular here we looked
at stack overflow data which is which is
sort of programming questions about programming type of website that you have you can the
same thing is the following right you have people who are a your answers and
then that they just sort of say was the contributor of the answer right so
we can people operating items but if these items are being created by what one
of the members of the community so in some sense when i read your answer
i'm also rating you OK so those are sort of three conceptually different ways how
to think about people are eating
items or other people online
so now if i want to go and sort of just focus on these dyadic
this means that usually will get accepted at the conference
they solve the optimisation problem and that's we you might have to use all of
the developed world agrees to turn it into something that you can solve efficiently
but all you do is really consider choosing kernel on the axis teachers the carbon
dioxide like s
this all sounds really abstract you will the concrete thing now
namely we start with classification
look at the feature map and some examples
maybe if you have some questions now good idea that just go back
any questions here
so everybody asleep or
there is a very
also has some questions
OK good
let's move on
the classification
i'm going to do the simplest thing i could imagine and then to pick for
fixing y
before fix
outer the product was EY
so why is just
one minus one value from the
in this case
the trying karl
china is the next prime
time well
the delta function one like right so in other words if y equals y prime
this is one of the licence you
but it really means is i have one set of parameters for class one
in one set of parameters for class minus one
that's not very smart ways to do things in binary classification
multiclass it doesn't matter so much because you know but
when is it came with come from
remember when we started
i started with this binomial model
there's a OK we relax of parameter constraints
and then all the sudden
i said well look we have now two parameters to model this additional events
and this relax asian
is something we have to pay for very clearly if we don't do things in
a smart way here
this is my dinner with twice as many parameters
this is going to be an expensive optimisation problem
so classification
this is a nice pedagogical model
you might want to do it more efficiently might just want to be
this thing to be
just why
so you y so that you would have scale the next prime
why time by prof
all the math go through in the same way
just going to do it can be slightly inefficient setting
in order to show you
that there is no inherent reason to delete any other way
by the representer theorem well in this case it's easy to solve the y one
minus one
to get out by life of exile by
and if we have more than two classes
the end have
the scale is to maintain one parameters to many isn't that much in comparison to
the overall cost so you might as well just period
the optimisation problem is
not too messy but you may just have to plug all the terms in this
and i on problem
you know it's not particularly deep you just prior to that
so what does it look like here's about the point of one class
is and place from class
and then you just find optimisation you get something that's convex problems
and then all this is the line of equal probability
that's a lot of the probability point six seven point four
you might have seen that in this the people that talk about the marginal
in fact this what is very close related
so when somebody talks about the margin
this is actually can be viewed
as a log likelihood ratio what you want to make sure that the log likelihood
ratio is greater than some number
and if you that number i don't care about the exact value is less than
the number i care about it
and if you do that you get exactly the same
if you say what you care about low block dress
about the conditional probabilities overall
you get us improve classification
that's really the link between those two
OK question like that one does a decent job as well
as you would expect it
just to be some points of the margin
so just to recap what
of events
so what i'd like to do now is i want to show you a few
demonstrations and in years past they had some come in here and do this
but she since graduated
there's a whole bunch of other factors involved so
what i wanna do is i've got some video footage of the demonstration it was
so what you're going to see is several things first show you is the synthesis
of nylon
and this is bigger synthesis of nylon six six it's conversation polarization and we're going
to use
x methylene i mean so that's the base and a diptych acid which is obviously
and as it so as it plays bass gives water plus in this case the
neutralized the polr this is only done for demonstration purposes it in in industry park
and i was not synthesize this way typically go got around three hundred degrees c
so they're going to take each of these ingredients and they're going to dissolve them
in different solvents
in one case we're going to dissolve the
hexham math league i mean in an aqueous solution and then the diptych as it
is going to be dissolved in hex a text saying is
it's not polar it's invisible with water so you can see two liquid phases in
aqueous phase and organic phase so one ingredient is in the aqueous phase the other
ingredient is in the organic phase the only place they come in contact with one
another is at the interface you going see nylon synthesized at the interface between the
two liquids and here's the
here's the reaction
see if
this is heidi burge speaking
like a lot of times
training diary
i'm going to show you we had a close up of the previous year which
she didn't actually camera focus right on the the to get better seeing of the
formation of the nylon it's happening right here at the interface
between the vaccine
and the aqueous solutions so the forming right here
and as soon as the nylon forms it seals off the reaction more reactance can
get here what she does she pulls this up and she pulls the nylon up
she exposes fresh interface
so the everything's occurring at this interface self-limiting reaction
then we have to
i feel the missing data in some way
in our case
it seems me that is related the money
the very basics all the missing most of the missing values with zeros meaning that
the amount of money is little
for that person for this very well
and as you also know that the cult is also very important and the
if if we can identify
as we have two
clean them differently
so they can be important input variables is also
is is and you important factors
in addition there are some conflicting
results about
comment remove you should use
some researchers claim claims that using less
he very
can be better
not also on the first model
one the process
but also
they claim that the model can be
what i cannot
more precise
on the other hand if diffuse use many variables the modelling process with this slope
and maybe
the traditional interpretation of the models
could be a little bit
more difficult
but you know if we have
models with higher accuracy
the question is how
should be that one right variables
how many experimentation
to get the answer this question
and in the summary of experience is that
if one is using neural networks
we have seen that favorable
could result in higher accuracy
if one is using decision trees
that using as many variables as possible
it is much more
but this
internal focus
now the question is how we should use the input variables
should we use them in their original form of should be
the transport
them in some way like getting a transformation of
some discrete categorisation as
we see this example
for example here
the average for in the care they can't is categorized into five
discrete values
starting with zero mean is all no money in the account
and it it get it takes the highest value for meaning that there are more
than ten thousand dollars
in the car
so our experience in this is also
depends on the
and we have observed that if if if we are making clustering
categorisation variables is quite useful
but if you if you do
for example process modelling
and then using them in the
or in their original form
it is much better
for example in of the first
some preliminary experiments we have observed that if we use them in their original form
the perfor gets
twenty five percent better
then the next question is home issues for the training set
who should we should take place in the training set should be
select samples from the whole customer base
should this senate
potential targets from some clusters on
if if if using class is
but there's
then the question is how we should
cluster the customers
of should the cluster
and this is this is
one of them
the most important success factors in our opinion most of the
spirit comes from this page and the the previous page
using the input variables
and we believe that in clustering one should avoid
using too many very
so far the user should be specific and use as many of the as possible
that in the course of modelling
he or she can use much more very
to differentiate between the
usage of of the product
among the clusters
at infinity so that it would be a finite mixture model with k components
and we
the approach which
referring to here involving and it's a mixture model with an infinite number of mixture
and that has to be artificially process
if some examples of
he was a model selection and averaging which
OK so
was left
so that the question was
so that's kind of two ways in which you get really last model m infinity
the first way is
you take
mixture of mixture models
where the mixture is over
the number of components
within the mixture model
so you
a mixture model involving one component of two company evolving p component and you have
average over all possible
model and that of course
that gives you an infinite mixture models
but it's actually different
what we're seeing here is that we actually have
a mixture model
in which the mixture this one mixture model in which the maximum number of components
is infinite
rather than
and in the number of finite mixture models and are somewhat different
the question was you
which is OK so the question is kind of like
you have
now a mixture model in which you have called mixture components everywhere in your space
possibly everywhere in your space
and then that of course if just space is really big and you know in
number of mixture components
and then
even they you with the model
when you do with your friends you would
the lack of
the mixture components which are
useful effect in the data
and that is the
and i said
not on the mean you could always use them
yes but you could always face the prior distribution on the mean which is not
uniform distribution
you're using a uniform
the first
the question is why is called prior not appropriate for this
in fact there are people who looked into
then the estimation where the prior
with girls in process in the prior
you need to make sure that you know that is integrable and
the other they commit to design a kernel process so that
you know the better the
it's actually group you can have a uniform
distribution of things
and yet that that global but it turns out to be computationally
i should be the head so
the first
the first model selection averaging thing is a clustering right so in the case of
the mixture model evolved look like that that the question is the sequences of the
well maybe one
on may be alright we need to figure out how many of the
that's the model selection average
question two
in this
this this
this sort of problem occurs all over the place so another
o thing which occurs is in fact something to the years
that that you want you
put electrodes into
the brain of
among you
four months
let's say that you have or
and this is the signals which are coming from
that either the
the set in the fact that you assume
probability distribution generating the data
you know it just these facts that we write that there exist some distribution generating
the data already
we restrict considerably
what we are looking at all considering
and it
it's not enough and anyway because it has a lot of implications
but you know
the framework that we have chosen to work with that
i agree it's
and we will see maybe being a bit more
and maybe it would be here but
i mean it's definitely not enough support
although it seems so
OK so basically can write anything
so the the sort the problem already with these simple algorithm is ground-based things
well no because no
given that they are
what is the boundaries
the question is which one is the best
is there one that goes faster
the best functions
that goes in certain
a better way
so we're classification case
and the same kind of single crystal for regression or other settings like density estimation
so we can restrict the classification and that would be fine
so the problem is
there is this notion of both large which means that
unfortunately there is no way
tell apart
two allegories
by looking at how the converse the best
so here's the first
definition of this
of french algorithm here right
that's the most cited version
and the most classical one although it's not
the most interesting ones
but OK let's start with this one
you can be what is called the out of sample error
so which is
the probability that you make a mistake
on the samples that are not
in your training data
so x is that you have not observed so far
we have seen that you know on examples that you have already observed is easy
just count how many take majority vote and that is so
this is saying OK let's not
i worry about the example that you will let's look at those that we have
not observed
then what you do is you can consider this is kind of bayesian in spirit
you can see there some kind of uniform probability distribution
not easy to define you have to assume a lot of restriction but it
keep the intuitive interpretation
we consider from the solution of our problems
which means that we assume that
many possible
seeing can happen uniformly
any possible distribution is equally likely or any possible data generation is equally likely
how to define the system we can do it
so this uniform distribution
then of course that the given instance
the expected value and the distribution that
the label would be one will be the same as the one that
people is zero right because what seems can be equally likely
if we have this then
for any possible reason
the expected under uniform distribution
of the loss
the out of sample loss
of languages would be
it's going to to be easy to see because it just says that
on this new data that you have not seen so far
the label can either be zero one the distribution of the problem
the losses have
and then we observe some data
so this given by like point here
and one of the data
the posterior over that is now i think it has changed
it's basically a bit
i figured out that that's actually cool
one over here and one of the
so there is higher than the idea that the would be in the middle
the red line here is that is the mean density
in the posterior
well again the grey area is now the region over which we have
high posterior probability
so this is quite similar to the cotton process
coming through the second application which is that we have a parametric modeling
so here's the idea is that
that's that's why we care about it
functions so in this case is linear regression where interest really in the the
coefficients are linear regression
but that's the part of the model which
which we're not really interested in and as a result we want to be respectable
as possible in in terms of modelling
here's a little example so
let's say that
i correspond to the subject of patients
each patient i have multiple problems
indexed by j
so why i j is the outcome of the trial on the ice station
we want to predict y i j outcome even predict
x i j and i j
x idea could be things like you know the
the medical treatment which
we we give patients
and the idea could be things like
the height of the
the presence of the patient
and what we're interested in is
whether the
whether the treatment which we give the patient is effective or not
so given access
that and what we want to
in what the value of beta i what the posterior over theta if the posterior
part that we know that it is somehow
and that's the part of the model which we have
but that's also other parts of the model which we have
well this part is now the effect
that effect on the
on the the efficient on the opposite
effectiveness of the treatment which depends on things like
the general health of the patient
and of course this but we don't really have much about what we are we
what we want to know is is our new method which is the new treatment
that we're giving the patient effectiveness
since we don't
this we don't really have
the patient specific effects
are held at the
the not
on the night
that on the
on the outcome of the treatment so we
instead of assuming like
gaussians prior over the ninth of all over the
the random effects b i
we simply say that the we we should model the noise in the nonparametric fashion
so and when the model is again with a
drawn from this nice distribution at
and since we don't know what it is we say the attribute of the dirichlet
so we model the night
distribution in an automatic fashion
and this is able to
and things like overdispersion of units which is often observed in clinical
it's also possible to model for object specific random effect
a lot money perfect the nonparametrically by saying that the eyes drawn from some
distribution g
and we don't know g so again replace the prior which is a dirichlet process
prior to g
so this is called semi parametric because
this two part of the model are not perfect
but what we have is that i which is a parametric how have
so we simply use the nonparametric model of the way of
bringing flexibility to what model but we
kept the promontory part because they're more interpretable
if the inferences we make more more interpretable
so in machine learning the process used mostly in model selection and averaging so can
go to the limit
so here i would be
it consists of sequence at
x one x two and so forth
and the model
we have a prior
o model here
we have a parameters case
and this is the prior over parameters in the model class
and we also the likelihood term which is the probability of the data given our