organs updates perceptron algorithm will find a function that is again on 2 approximation all the function of we
started with the way the trick here is that the you know about the perceptron
algorithm solution has this nice properties of the dual form remember has integer coefficients Ermina's Alphas were just
changing by 1 each time so they remain integers positive
integers and the son of the offers is actually less than
are going to ask what we can have a task where the Gaspard
because each time we updated the function we only increased the
some by 1 of the things and so that why as the star almost the definition of all the cover for you just take
the cover is wall of those combinations of all of the training examples that you can get the positive coefficients for which more positive for the positive examples of negative the
negative examples but you the positive offers from for
which the uh some of the health as his so but at most some valued the set of for us that we can do and that
their use your cover and all you need to Dooster of that set and you can do
that and you can either with a well the log of it is used
this quantity here so it's k log 2 leads to impose k minus
1 of K which is a task for a 2nd square so you can imagine that this is sort of like placing you got you know a Jasper ongoing squared bowls and you got a problem in
June and sorts or 2 ends lots of and so you just go to count it's a common motorial thing
of County memory words you could you that are different ways to do know going to carry what together and you get a Band of
the following form wanna generalization which is something
that our formal and cases a gospel of Dallas squared into game we've got this
very familiar formentation like that we see the mentioned
but we've got a lot of fact a um log factor involves and but the you to carriers also in the denominator of we
got the log in Mondale as an end in here but that's not to severe penalties of and the that is the bound and notice it's better than the
old at all because it is only 1 Lord factor Olmert all of
you would have a 2nd factor from the course we don't worry
about the fact that he had so um so that actually is quite a lot time on
the generalised which about 4 ASEAN's and you can see that the the gamut is
actually controlling as we suggested generalization this
actually is already be we've done the structure was
minimisation of account this really is a holding out for
the grammar the user we look at it from so now what I want
you as the exercise is to reconstruct the bound on the
cover numbers so that was the man on the cover and numbers
of ways to this quantity was that's or equal to the
quantity which he was that's so the idea is that some of
you would have might be enough get through the night
obviously in common I want to encourage you to work in group so am I going to
make sure that it is going to be some points so what that
is that if a group get to write an old members of the group
get all points so it's a bit like the papers you if
publisher paper with 3 authors the credit derivatives tool for every maybe there's a way
of sort of log factor in that you know like a V is the value of the
paper the by by the log and plus 1 more in this number of
authors may be something like that in the but blog factors don't mean a thing to do here is so we can have the as a constant here but also everybody gets all the and string courage you
know because I mean really the fun of doing research I
think that too large extent is working groups and the
working people who and you cannot help but the if I give a
significant of information that also of . from your group on at the
end of carrying I'm in this line of work with will see that there is a case of a free pass so the 1st
part is the is more like a sort of book work to some extent in and you can see that if I screwed from the Internet if you want to but you have to
try to reduce that so is to prove the convergence the
perceptron convergence or more Acosta their own for the
number of updated the perceptron algorithm is bounded by
Austria chemist word it on where X i is the hour is the
bound on the norms of the training examples and gamma is
the modern over correctly classified classifying hyperplane normalized weight vector w stop and it with the 2nd emotions algorithm you was assumes no special
so there's a structural as you can see from selected and you a hint that there were 2 things you need
to do you need to play an upper bound on the value of all
the mean moles almost squared over weight vector after T
updates remember we started with the weight vector being
zeros norm starts Europe and essentially we have to do is
show that it dozen increase that much at each step and that when you have to pay so all the value of all be
in a product between WTD and W. stop so you have to show that it increases of by a certain
amount of W 2 dozen increased too much of between in a
product increases by a significant amount of each time and uh putting those
this less complex system the about the systems that recognise antigens and make antibodies and
so on have all these complex networks
which are much more complex only so the vertebrates
does that mean that the vote
it's or
we at the pinnacle of evolution with increased complexity really better than the bacteria and
and in fact it is an complexity increases we have increased fragility the the the
simple creatures
don't get cancer they don't have a lot of community they don't have inflammatory diseases
we who have
even these more complex
immune systems
suffering in a certain way from one fragility which i think is the general principle
if we look at
complexity over evolutionary time and take fitness survival and certainly the bacteria
as for as you can get
or imagine they have survived all the
evolutionary pressures
creatures such as dinosaurs and rather than the sun
we are here the pinnacle of complexity and just starting to see how much survival
have the case
this is the the emergence of complexity which were which is something that we
as physicians and in analysis
have to deal with this physicians and want to deal with this immunologist it's not
and if one cannot conclude that the most sophisticated complex systems are better adapted are
more fit more fitness if we look at the footnotes as survivors
and one of the questions we
i want to raise looking at all this is what what drives this
development this incessant development of complexity despite the
crashes that occur from time to time one
keeps its evolution of complexity going if it really and in the long run does
not generally creatures that have much more
survival capacity then we're ready
a billion years ago with the bacteria
another point
that i
show you some
to say that i
if you ask the question of how
the immune system
computes the
what is it
transforming body information into its own information and so there is no one to one
so what we see is the
the development of patterns
one of the kinds of
o devices that we
we developed in in my lab from looking at patterns of the immune system is
that the robotics and labour and laser
machinery for looking at gene expression and saying let's
take this these machines and look at
of antibody expression in the immune system in various states so people know about the
technology of
gene expression
well understand this people down we don't have the time to get into it but
what we do we're able to look at thousands
of interactions in this case
the interaction between
body molecules and immune system molecules or the binding of antibodies
the body molecules
a thousands of interactions in turn that into numbers
we can quantify and analyzed
and if we look
various segments of the immune system we see some interesting things in this study were
we looked at
the repertoires the antibodies that can bind
molecules from the body
in mothers and in
the newborn babies
and we can look at the two kinds of types of antibodies there's the type
of antibody
that is transported
in the uterus from the mother to the baby this is the empirical correlated
is true that would be one hundred years
this is
so this is strictly
the reason why
first of all
you only get one or
we express the role
and also say
so o
you can see that you want with that
there's always the first
so in
the same thing
he said that
and you for now
nine two and and a three d example
when we think about
some of the past
past that
they are and threshold
and what you want
for women
and as
the label
it is possible says that he also
an important is
four years
some say
this is a
and i
the same
so what he
well i used three
we're going to the same
which was
that is that this is
it is
i mean
we are
we have
you occasionally see patients
you know
one man was not
one hundred one
the reason why
traditional work
in case
this is
once again
to get some degree
we can
the students
just you that
meanwhile that
i think it's time
so far
as i know
what's the name
stand by
four and carried
well let's see
by this as
you know some termites some
so for instance
that's what
you have
so what
there's no
thank you
single current wire
it's coming
fortuyn goes into of course it is the wire it goes like this and the
reason why you see
here is because we have to get the current in somehow
it really is the y like this
and this platform i'm going to show you
i'm going to put some island final-round around this
and when they see magnetic field
they will try to orient themselves
in the direction of the magnetic field going to see circles
but appreciate the fact that you need huge currents for hundreds of years we do
that's why we have a car battery remember that was capable of delivering many hundreds
of mps
so i closed the current now
i have
you can see the circular configuration
you can see that
look like circles
i want to do the same now
a little bit more exciting perhaps
why are going into the plane
and the other one coming out
even though it's not a circle
the idea here
is that you get a feel configuration very much like
you see there
it was red hot cable to really hot like
one of them is
OK let's do it this way
so you're going to see if field configuration similar to what i have on the
similar to what you have here although not this one
similar to this
actually it was also one of the this is nice properties
so we have won why going in and won why
coming out of the plane
all right
that first put some iron final
now if you want them you through it
you can see close to the wire that goes in
and here
the circles
one of our relationship they dominate the magnetic field
a little bit of imagination you can see these
field lines going like this just like i have the on the record
we don't need it anymore
we don't need them
so does give you a a little bit of insight
into the magnetic field configurations
that we have about these
why is when we won the current
i will return to magnetic fields next lecture we will expand
we all know
techniques to calculate magnetic field
in a way which is highly superior
your survival
in fact that will get us
third next article is almost
but i wanted to relax a little bit because they may already have been a
little rough on you
and so now i want to discuss something entirely different
something very practical
and it has to do with the
or electric energy
so we have the power station somewhere
location a
they deliver
electric power electric energy to boston
here in boston
location b
and and a is the location of the power station this could be
a thousand miles distant
because the cable going from the power station to us
and the potential here in this line
a few people
user cable for the return current current goes like this
and the return current is in this direction and
here you use this energy
you will here
cup you're
like the portion and what have you
TV station everything
so you're you the consumer you
take the energy that is provided
by this power station
i will
called the potential
this line zero
and so this is where you have a higher than
this line here
according to
o as lotfi a
is the current
capitol are which is known of radius but that is
resistance in the wire
this wireless cable
however i think it may be
has a finite resistance
so vv
that is the
potential that we receive in in boston
he calls me a
mina xi are
if there is no current going through the wire
no one is using any
electric energy than b is the same as you
now i want to know
if we
consume energy
so we're dealing with lower
so the power that we take off in boston
is i times you've been
that's the number of joules per second that we are consuming
so that any
eight times i
minus ice cream or
one is this
the shortest path
this is an ally
hopefully it was worth waiting for
reminder the quiz
coming up soon you should be studying for no problem set
two at the same time as the
this is studying now
to take on exams
it's required to come class on monday of course
your comment but everyone watching how should also come
next monday
to get the quiz
this it's the the required lecture
we need to recap in that
trilogy so far so the the last two lectures the first two episodes
we're about single source shortest path
so we want to find
the shortest path from source vertex to every other vertex
and we saw lots of what we saw a few evidence for this
here's some
we can recite in the unweighted case those are the easiest for all the edge
weights were one
then we can use breadth first search
and this cost what we call linear time in the graph or of number of
vertices plus number of edges
the next simplest case perhaps
nonnegative edge weights
in that case what i really do we use
dykstra are
several years what's great
OK so this takes
almost linear time if you use a good
keep structure
so we live plus e
and in the general case
general weights
with this film for the song
and the costs
which is quite a bit worse
this is ignoring log factors dexter's basically linear time
bellman ford is at least quadratic if you
i have connected graphs on the sparse case when is or v
these are
this is about linear this about quadratic when the dense case one is about the
square this is about
this quadratic and this is cubic
so thanks to a four separated by about a factor
it's pretty
in order to factor which is pretty bad
but that's the best we we know how to do it for single source shortest
paths negative edge weights is that the best we also saw
recitation in the case of the DAG
and there
what you do
topological sort
so you can topological sorting and ordering on the vertices then you run bellman ford
one round
one way to think of what's going on
bellman ford in the order given by the topological sort just once
and you get a linear time
so the DAG is another case where we know how to do well even with
we can also do linear time most the time there will be
so we should keep these in mind like in the quiz when you get a
shortest path problem or what you end up determining is the shortest path problem think
about what's the best algorithm you can use in that case
OK so that single source shortest path and
so in our evolution of the death star initially was just nonnegative edge weights then
we got negative edge weights today
the death star challenges us with
all pairs shortest paths
well one of the shortest path weights between every pair of vertices
OK so let's let's get some quick results locally according to in this case of
for example
suppose i have
an unweighted graph
any suggestions on how i should computing all pairs shortest paths
between every pair of vertices i want to know the shortest path with
the fifteen minute started on
some people at stanford university that have model
of specific one distribution he that show that this is indeed what could happen
things like that have not been observed in the practice that you know some of
you may recall like
two thousand one to thousand four there have been major war outbreaks that have shown
very rapid growth proliferation
so another problem
symmetry metadata ideas and this is
it should has already been raised here
other applications
the false positive rate
the problem is that one might think that this image of it it's not really
sensible defaults for because they only detect what is absolutely
but it can happen that you want to
one is trying to develop a general statement for general expressions
that would attacked
you know the the value of different variations of the security
that could also
be sensitive to
normal data set
there will be some by chance there will be patterns are also present in north
so what's wrong about one i think the case
sometimes this happens cooperation is not really not really
the problem is
again the scale of the data that we have to deal with
so this is and takes like ten ten along today's from an idea you know
stop trusting
do some calculations
how many
what a lot of the great one has to happen in order to have a
false alarm they have
two hundred megabits per second
forty four to dealing with actually
packets day
it suffices to have an extremely low false positive rate in order to avoid system
i think about reading this problem but you really
radically rethink the the the
at the false positive rate actually
they are common in the machine learning community
one of the largest cities actually not that are reliable
well from the range of false positives and not going to get anything like five
so i percent of all this is completely out of range
performance is also make sure so actually you know doing this pattern scanning is
nothing else can each take again
a large number of things so this is what
census signature matching string that problem
one think a faster computers can do better but eventually one runs into some physical
problems that
you know the systems
really consume a lot of energy and cooling down
to some really if you seen major network infrastructure
this is confirmation
so what
why be so what can we do with machine learning in order to
address problem
one thing force you probably seen this
many times or in this meeting the machine learning we understand what it means to
two to
general so
what it means to have to get to their
it is also the case that
machine learning learning some compact representation
the semantic based approach
there is in fact nothing else memorizing dates
and trying to do some very good classification by
comparing two packet with something that we have already seen exactly instance based
classification that have exact match
you know what we do have a long
machine learning officer major
reduction of the complexity of the
concept of the building and that's why
we can hope to have a performance
finally with a very important
the true anomaly detection we can detect novel
and it turns out that i has to do fundamentally unusual thing
we have seen both flows
requires some strands binary information and this is inherently
and usually very specific behavior
have a good reason to believe that by doing the knowledge based on the fact
that we can detect novel
so the causal issues in machine learning that i have to dress by applying
but dealing with non victorian structured data so that
they're important extract meaningful features
how to be able to pass the features into
internet states in order to run algorithms
it's difficult to get
and we use labels for the state again this is
we have seen that this problem is also
typical four
other applications of machine learning semantic security problems that
in order to get have to analyse and really very complicated information look at
the role
content of network packets it's very difficult to really understand what's going on that so
it is a very
time consuming process might also be
and we use the tower
rather than attack pertains to impact
because might be part of an attack president once again another
i be really
very carefully distributed
malicious noise
my try to
this guy is activity
four tried to subvert the learning process
in order for an algorithm to learn
different concepts
that is less robust to detect attacks
and we also have to deal with hybrid animals that's why
it's very important to have
efficient algorithm
and many of my talk i will present a structure chosen algorithms
our learning basic ideas have developed
and show some
applications that from machine learning techniques that had to developed in order to
make this system work
so don't structure system basically follows the typical
architecture of intrusion detection system two main components being
the feature extraction
and the detector components model
concentrate will show you some technical details of
those two parts
so essentially the
feature extraction
the question now out information
three ways to to do this
detectors can in principle be any
learning methods that
no anomaly detection classification clustering and ranking third so i will present some of the
anomaly detection
so how to extract features from the
the title
it's still looking you forty one translated from m on eight fourteen
so if you have a lot of four here for the this is entry twenty
different amino acids and this translation like this one here
always been looking tied together if one can encode one i mean we at together
it fought with the power the different possibilities right sixty four possibility and each of
these possibilities caught one i mean
so you can make the chain on a we can make a chain order of
and this is the translation
there some special
called on a special people which terminate the sequence b this course
OK so this is the structure of
so one part which is twenty five
this is what is copied to them on then there are other things which are
controlling when the transcription started depending on the different conditions in the cell when the
plant maybe beliefs would need to run in different
programme as the rule one
the need to express different proteins then under different conditions
these conditions i actually encoded in the promoter region
this is like a lot of small which is which control
he i mean the amount of expression over that is completely silenced
on the twenty five regions several parts
essentially the
it contains exonintron intron are removed
in the process which is called lighting the only the x eleven
in the five months
so the first copy
when you remove all the front
and then you get the back one
this but on a part of that is translated
this is a vector
actually quite nice illustrations of transcription splicing and translation like movie which you can with
explanations which just watch
maybe in the brain
OK what you get is b
the protein sequence
and here in the protein sequence consists of
i mean it
on the twenty different of them
and this just on long chain
but it
not just chain this chain can form structure
and the sequence the sequence of amino acids just the primary sequence
the primary structure then
secondary structure that not remote like he
so you see that
they can almost expect a
hydrogen bond between green position then
and what we also have a beta strand
completely different structure and you can
put them one on top of each other
OK so can build like what
so this is a secondary structure of the structure elements you can build a much
more complicated structures for instance just give you some idea
o complex these things can look like is just four beta strands which are stacked
next to each other this is
just to the combination of the to spend the the strengths and opportunities and you
see all kinds of different shapes here
corresponding to the shapes of the different functions associated
so functions related to information processing
like extracellular sensing so that the first which are outside the cell wall on the
cell border and they can
recognise that certain conditions
they can
and proteins which are just there for signal transduction can
if the information from one according to to the next
and signal transduction is part one then the regulation of gene expression
so depending on external conditions you might be able to switch on and off the
in control things like cell cycle one hundred twenty different range
so you can have different issues in the
so there other proteins which are involved in metabolism so
to get energy to synthesize proteins on a b a
and also for the biogenesis of cellular components like hell all these things
and other proteins are just there for the cell structure or send out
so what you
so it's not i mean what you see from that the
amount functions is quite broad so it's hard even to describe what about the function
of the protein and they have different maybe conflicting aspects of function so in certain
biological reactions function might be like catalyze something but on on the cell might be
involved in energy production or in
regulation of
of the cell cycle
so there are different levels of description what
but also the function of the protein might depend on the context
so the protein function and depending on image so this might be two different things
so the function classification that is to a certain degree the arbiter
so it is often described the tree but even that is not the
OK i have a question for the baby basic things like
the central dogma
first go at
we do it or more
well we're looking the vision that like the white
there and read it like you
and let it slide something on it
right of you
so yellow thing
now we don't need further
on the left really
all right there
i did not we find the global right
so that's
now when we draw
they point on the green
is only a very small chance we
what they
the above red
what is above the red lines are rejected they no longer there
and with drinking water yellow
now make another of the green line
and that's that
so he stayed home in one piece
now i do thing
make a proper up there
that we are one people another
and we could have done no matter how low the values that
not really across very very
well feel you value and very will be being in the way
and yet we can
the property
they god one another
now we look whether you know what i think it's really really know what
you know on the now when we do you think you very rule we
growth that's
will be on left
thank you
why don't know all about the hopping between the
andy that was applied on
if we run along
if have will be
well why don't you
that's why sampling
and in particular there and read mail
in book published free software that implements this
it's not
and it's
very very general all you need is the ability to evaluate red
when you are
really nice thing to note about like it never
ends up rejecting
overall proposal it it worked and worked and what was in the end
you've got somewhere and that somewhere will be different from where you got
in contrast the standard published the way you might do a huge amount of hamiltonian
monte carlo simulation finite element will learn that
project and you just throw it all away
and have made any progress
it your link will move
only a very small this about maybe the right we may be dealing with a very small
so it never get another beauty of
slice sampling is
that's why w is not a crucial parameter
if you're w is accidentally ten times as big as it needs to be done
about it only takes a very small number of points shrink down
that the correct way
and if w small it only takes a small number setting up operations which proceed linearly
over small we think
only small number that will be required
in comparison with the red region
w is crucial it's still a good idea unit but you don't have a catastrophic
failure if you get your w two small and large
and slice sampling doesn't have the property that typically
you will make
there is a big at the with the dealing with
so it
the final step
is all
roughly the optimal size
that's why sampling
and i would like to
finished with today is the about
exact sampling
how long you you need to run a monthly column the four
i'm gonna tell u
what feels to me i
really quite amazing breakthrough be among our community for decades they answered the question how long running around all
well i long
bring you don't really know that you you get a better value make diagnostic will
get belong answer the question how long run of the newly founded by
there was a breakthrough and it happened in approximately nineteen ninety six
with the invention of methods that are all i call exact sampling the alternative that sampling
and the the whole family of different
sampling methods
and i'm going to describe to
mean if you want to explain probably
the paper one
but maybe hundred
how long should we run the simulation or
exact sampling based on the idea that should
rather different long time you
how long
infinitely large
there for
you might say
like all of it
but it be feel
you can establish the outcome of an infinitely long
the finite amount you are
and we're going to run
the simulation
from the pack
from infinitely long and that's
up to
the president
had about how
well let me explain
let's imagine that this is the they they all
and for simplicity
call let's imagine we're talking about these lecturer flipping a coin
determine whether you go right or left in the like that but it faces is why that they
like this
and now i'm asking you to imagine that an infinite time ago
a little army and twenty one
all started
at i might be
twenty one that location and every one of them
then started
running the monte-carlo simulations what
so imagine that happened
and imagine that they use the same random numbers
random numbers
all of them are shown here in the first one
had had had found no
so the plant
and any time we imagine we can consult the little encyclopedia
outcome we can say at time minus one thousand seven hundred thirty two
what the you have
in the right itself
help when come back to that sound like he did tell me again what would
become one of them two it will tell you
right all not going along
had one of them
you know
all this phenomenon with a very small set of actions of principle then you're happy
and you know it
so you want to explain many things with
if you see
and these principles are these actions of postulates they i mean they can be called
assumptions axioms and postulates or in it
an example of is the only one
principle of relativity the laws of physics are the same in all inertial frames of
so this is really something that
you can't really prove you just say OK let's assume this is true
if this is true what can we derive from that what are the consequences
that's the important point here
these assumptions you can never who
you can only you know
i cannot figure out what are the consequences of these assumptions
and then going the nature and try these things and test whether that's one of
the consequences
and of course
a good theory
would have few
we define what serine knowledge define what is learning
so learning i mean you all
three could envision what is learning
but the mixing precise
definition you can find in a dictionary
to gain knowledge conference in factory
or mastery of
through experience of that
the study is kind of the easy case study something you know it
so we focus on this part of it but more on learning
o experience so you do something
as you do is you
kind of gained knowledge comprehension my understanding
so you know where you you build your own mental model
interestingly is the interesting part is when you don't just accumulate observations but you really
create your own representation of the world and you have some
into the model that allows you not only two
account for what observed but also
it allows you to make predictions about the future
so i mean all these works
you can consider them as meaning the same thing in the context of this lecture
so this leads us to an interesting
i mean if we look at the definition of learning and definition of series
we we get some kind of
weird circularity here
so we have say what is serious and what it how it should be constructed
in series really
making observations and constructing a model of this observation
the question is
why did i tell you all that
actually building story is really the same induction which is the same as i said
as learning learning
you observe things learning from experience is
you observe singing you make
a kind of internal model of these things
and building a series of the same so
you know it's kind of
circular here i'm i'm telling you that learning is building series and i'm i want
to this
on the here so let me rephrase that a bit to induction is the process
of building series
learning theory
the main focus of learning theory is the phenomenon of induction
so how can we
in this variable
in the series
so i mean i i will go more into the details of that but it's
just too you know emphasise that
this whole thing is
involving a lot of philosophical issues
and i will touch upon some of the some of them later on
try to further now
so OK now you have the a wrong idea of what is it that we're
trying to do with learning series
now why is it that we are
thanks to do that
i like this quote
i mean you can find it in about six book
and i think it does and doesn't say that it's from her
well i don't know why i look on the internet and that's the kind of
reference that is given most of them but maybe it was reduced by many people
i mean
what else can i say
no i mean more seriously
these are the things that i think are important
first of all we want to understand what's going on when we learning right
and we want to
study the properties of different learning algorithm and be able to say OK this is
better why in this context is better
these so the idea in there
not just by
you know trying it on on various kinds of data but
by being able to say i mean to make some general statements
that should lead us to you know
a way to design better algorithms for certain
so again this induction version that's the
i mean kind of repeating the same thing over and over again
very flavours hoping that you will get the message here
if you compare induction induction but really
what is kind of most restricting about studying induction is that
action is can can can be easily justified i mean once you've agreed upon the
then you
one of the right
and the rules for combining these actions then you derive the consequences you your here
and nobody can easily this area is correct
provided that everyone agrees on the
before induction is exactly the opposite you can't really
justify anything
you know if someone comes up with one action about some observations you can only
test the consequences of these actions so make deductions from that and then
take that is true i mean take that corresponds to local relates to your observation
but you can't really
you know full boarding school
and actually and
you can't really argue about the the
proofs of of some induction
that's it
i mean let's let's make these
now people can create and i will give you some examples two
you know for you to reason about thing
here is an example
so let's say we observe the sun
every morning and we see that its
rising every morning i mean the usual
example is europe whether you son is writing from the east of on the west
but let's let's just say
we observe that the sun is rising every morning
for a number of the day
and the question i'm asking you is OK given that you observed that forty days
what is your estimate of the probability
that the sun will rise again tomorrow
this is a
suppose you have some integer points in the latter
and then i have no relaxation of this
it's an easy thing to
the point here
and so
the point of the integer things that really interested in that so
so this is isn't some two-dimensional space and doesn't respond to exactly k and what
i'm doing is optimizing a linear function in terms of use
right and the question is one of the function i'm going to end up some
because it and the benefits as well but
let's think about monday degenerate case when one corner
OK so if all the corners are discrete
then and guarantee that i can find
an optimal solution is discrete
OK so if face is not a problem why because
well basically it means that either this or or this one
solution have the same score so just pick one of them
so you can show
this this polytope right this this kind of a set of linear constraints in the
space of these makes
structures such that all its corners
are discrete
so we want to optimize a linear function
over that space is going to end up in corner
and getting into solution
OK so this has to do
so can come back to that in certain graphical models why that's easy why that
happens but
you know
so i got maybe i'll come back to to white why that happens but but
this is kind of
the common
so there see if can sense if you can do something with dynamic programming
you can write it down as a linear in some senses the linear as a
linear programme as well
in the linear programme is going to give you integer solutions in the dynamic programming
integer solutions
this is not true if we have more complicated now network if we have an
arbitrary network and no
constraints on
what the potentials are
right then we cannot guarantee that this is going to give us
and entrance
so what happens that if we get a fractional and say
what happens is in a maximizing right that means we get some zero doesn't correspond
to y
and usually that's going to mean that
this is going to be
bigger than any real life
so this is going to give us an upper bound on their real life
let's look at this
associative markov network ltd
so there is that we have these variables e j
which are you know
for each position then fuzzy take turns out we only need to track the ones
that are on the diagonal
because everything else is zero
well i wanted to log there their one slide to the log
the thing was zero
so i just have variable and that all it says is this position and disposition
and they both on
prec and then if labels on i get this bonus
that we have the
so that's you writing down linear objective
to write down the constraints
you do
the thing we did before
zjn equals one meaning that
each position has only one label
and the edge something slightly different and that's because you assume that this weight
OK if that way is positive
what happens as the optimized
z jk is going to become
the minimum of the two
because it's trying to push against both of them as you get stopped by
the smallest of the two
if they are
actually integers
red zero one then the minimum is going to be just the and the
so if everything is happy and images are all integral
then i j k
written down this way and with these constraints
and the maximum is going to mean exactly one and we wanted it came to
end of these two things
and so
this is the linear constraints this is the set of this is the objective if
she calls two
right so we have this to binary problems
then you can also show that
this thing has integer corners
this is something that i'm i am not claiming that i did this right so
this is this is the well known fact in combinatorial optimization it has to do
with the constraint matrix
OK so you can show for the other one is well there's a different condition
for the matrix a
it's called telling to talk to you know what
that's one way to read
and that means that every if you take a look at this matrix area basically
blind always disease in vector matrix sitting there
vector and then you have some constraints and
less than or equal to b
and as long as the integrals
and a set modular meaning that every seven determinant of a
is there
minus one or zero
this is something you can you can
for this matrix and for bunch other ones
every sub chairman things
is that
it turns out that for any objective whatever q is it doesn't matter
the corners of the guy going to be in the world and the way this
works is because
the solution
right now i'm going to have some of these constraints be active
so there going to be some some semantics of that matrix is called the
that hit
with equality
and you know if this is full rank setting everything full rank then you just
if this is integral in the terms of the one minus one
and zero then is going to go as well
this is the
that if you want proof of this thing about recognising the matrix is due to
you know totally unimodular
it is actually hard problem but we know that these kinds of problems the ones
that arise from
of course
i can use of the internet
represent any distribution or market or anything
i would say we should invite
it's just that
the number of conditional independence statements implied by network
i mean
sorry the punisher state by by the vision that
may be smaller than the number of conditional independence statements really
the reason for this
likewise from my view
not exactly what you need
like which is the case
it's not
that is
then diagram
show that
so there are grounds for example that you can construct by combining information that might
however what people call a chain graphs and then use chain graph the rule is
somewhere in this area
you do not necessarily cover
so let's see what michael i think it's
to markov blanket forgiven
the markov blanket of a given observation x one
this is the markov field
the markov blanket of a node
is the smallest set of goals
when a condition is violated on the walls
i have the the same distribution this condition for all the other
in other words the neighbors
in quotes
hopes for macromolecules
the neighbors
the markov blanket is the set of direct technique
when the manage
four bayesian networks
the markov blankets are the parents
the children
which are connected directly to the north
but you also need to include the co parents
those that are also parents of missing children
and you yourself why
link about
one exercise could try to
try to show that the markov blanket of i
in the bayesian network is given by human parents
and sure the markov blanket of alignment is given by its name
you time to think about this problem
that's all
what's remarkable when
because of what's called the markov condition which is that these
which is the probability
given all the other five
is equal to the probability of only given name
the markov condition
our local conditions
defined by the graph g
the conditional
o insights about this question
so there are there is a simple complicated depends
what you
child head to head
with respect to parents
yes that's true
parameters for example the right hand sides
because for example this could be a resource constraints in some
application and interested in how
well this function looks like the change the upper limits on resources
how quickly
this the
the optimal value function change
so one thing we can say of course we can always compute this function by
solving the p
for a given x we can solve this to find your facts
they also know that it's a convex function of x
and and again follows from the minimisation rule and to apply this we have to
define f
so in this case f of
x y would be just see transport y
and as its domain of the function and we take the pairs x y
that satisfy the inequality
outside the domain we define a function fs plus infinity
so this is a convex function jointly x y
because its domain is convex so that's just linear
linear inequalities in exile i
so many is convex
and on its domain it's linear
so it's also convex
so this function is convex jointly in x y
and here we minimize over
with no constraints actually online
so the result is always a good necessarily convex and the remaining variables x
and the last properties
called perspective
so suppose i have a convex function of f of x f of x
and i can define a new function
g of an x and x variability
by replacing x in the argument of by x or t
and then multiplying fifty
and that's called the perspective of a function f
and it has the nice property that if f is convex
and i restrict this to positive values of t
then this perspective is always called
and for example allows us to immediately see that this is quadratic over linear function
and give us an example is convex
because i five take f of x just cesspools access convex very replace x over
y x over t
and multiply routine and just get access was actually for positive t so that's convex
another example from information theory is the negative entropy
the negative logarithm if i use
f of x
minus log x is a convex function of x
so far uses apply this construction replace x over by activity and i multiply the
result with t
then that is is this function
p times log of t of x
and so because of this that's convex jointly in xnt
it's called the relative entropy
and it's not immediately obvious because the first term is convex t lochte is convex
because that's the entropy but the second term separately has no interesting convexity properties
but the combination of the two is convex because of
this because it's the perspective of a convex function
so that's all i wanted to say in a theory of convex sets and functions
there any questions about this
so the next we look at some
definitions and examples of convex optimization problems
so we define a convex optimization problem is the function of the common problem is
a convex objective
convex inequality constraints and the equality constraint
so it's the general
mathematical optimisation problem that started with that fifty if i is restricted to be convex
so obviously the feasible set is convex because
it's the intersection of
and that's fine set a solution of the
in equations and then sublevel sets of different convex functions so it's a convex set
also a show that locally optimal points unnecessarily globally optimal
and so the most important property of this is that it's easy to solve theory
in terms of complexity theory but also in practice because there exists
more and more
is obtained software for solving optimization convex optimization problems
so the
the simplest examples LP if we restrict all the inequality constraints to linear
the solutions so that looks like this is supporting here and defined by different inequalities
and then the constraints is the objective is to minimize the transpose x
so you can easily see that the optimal value of the optimal solution would be
at the boundary of the polymer
and it is typically one of these extreme point of the body
and you can find visualize solution by just considering
the level curves are sets of constant value of c test was exposed the
so these
the level curves are hyperplanes it's a normal vector minus c
so those are the sets of constants objective value
they decrease in the direction of minor c
and then we look look for the point in the output here and the smallest
value c transpose x in this case that's the opt
so in practice it's not too difficult to recognise convex functions
so if
linear optimization linear programming problems in practice
so typically there arise from
it's not immediately obvious BLP stuff typically
go from piecewise linear functions
for example if i want to minimize the function f of x that is defined
as the maximum
pointwise maximum of
linear functions of x
then we already know that it's convex
because each of the french is convex
it's not differentiable so it's not
immediately obvious how to solve it using gradient descent or newtons method
but it's easy to solve the LP
using a very common trick introduce new variable t and minimize the this new valuable
subject to
the constraint that the trust was exposed by susan t
for each i
and that's an LP in two variables x and t because the objective is linear
all the constraints are linear
it's easy to see that it's equivalent
the easy for example these history to see this is two in this problem if
you fix x
and you just optimize over t
and that's a very simple LP because there's only one variable
you minimize the subject to m lower bounds on t
it doesn't example
so maximizing the likelihood that maximise the log likelihood
this is
as minimizing
that's there
you get
on because as minus sign maximizing this because the minus sign is same as minimizing
this is the function of data
this is of course just
this a quadratic cost function that we had lost time j of data
and so
well i've just shown is that the ordinary least squares our on that
they we worked on the previous lecture
it's just matter likelihood
this probabilistic model
i'm assuming this are assuming i calcium errors data
one thing that will actually revisit on
in the next lecture notes is that the value of sigma square it doesn't matter
somehow no matter what the value sigma was squared sequester has be positive number
the variance of the gaussians but no matter what it was great is
so why is this positive number
the value of data we end up with
will be the same because
minimizing this
you get the same value theta no matter what c square so is as if
in this model the value of sigma script doesn't really matter
on wall just just remember that in the next section will come back to this
questions about this
the king
another cup reports your questions you have
here is
the the first question
but this is
because because the problem
for example
i think you asking about overfitting whether this good model i think
that's the thing it is distinctive mentioning are on
maybe deeper questions about
learning algorithms that come back to this the come back to later
then we went against no
the question
this an dolls on a linear regression with a probabilistic interpretation
and i'm actually going to use this problem will use this sort of probabilistic interpretation
in order to derive unix learning algorithm which will be on the classification
recall that i said that the regression problems are where the variable y the try
to predict is continuous values
now we should help for first classification problems where the value one trying to predict
what the discrete values can take on only a small number of discrete values in
this case at all for binary classification where on
why takes on only two values so you come up with classification problems of trying
to do the same medical diagnosis and try to decide based on some features on
the patient has the disease or does not have the disease
or if it holds an example may be trying to decide what this whole cell
in the next six months and the answer is either yes or no either be
so the next six months it will be
i understand examples here but the spam filter is this email spam and answers yes
no or on if you know so my colleagues are interested in predicting whether a
computer system or crash so you have only have to predict what this computing cost
crash the next twenty four hours begins yes or no answer
that's that's why
and some classihcation problems
white a fun
two value zero one that's fine conservation
on so you do one thing could do is take linear regression as described so
far in applied to this problem
so you you know given this data set the straight line to
dean and brian matrix just a case of true i j is equal to the
kernel function is applied to two of my examples
it turns out that for any vectors e this n dimensional which she considers each
answers kesey
actually this is an export
we should considers the consuls kesey
and by
definition of matrix multiplication and
and so on
on k i j is the kernel function which time to so that most people
but i assume that k is a valid kernel function so there must exist such
a social value for phi
on this is the inner product between two feature vector so let me just make
that inner product the explicit
on some of the elements of the vector and when use five
i subscribe k this to denote the k elements of this vector
like so
and just giving sums that some of the k
so this may look like this makes me look familiar to to you
which is just
and therefore
this is the sum of squared
and they must therefore be greater than equal to zero
to stick to do is take a minute and look for all the steps in
make sure you buy them all
if you
o this is all the sea in this that this is a shared the inner
product between the vectors five exciting five exchange
d in product between two vectors is the sum over all the elements of the
vectors of the corresponding
here here is that if you just transpose some of the KB so that's that's
just this is the sum of k of the
OK elements of this vector
think doesn't make sure it makes sense
the question about the
so to summarize we show was that
on training vectors e
z transpose cave
is greater than equal to zero
and this is one of the standard definitions of the matrix
the matrix k
be positive semi definite when the matrix is positive case because here
and just to summarise what we've shown is that
if k
is a on
valid kernel in other words if k is a function
forced air force there exist
some by such that you know of xi xj is the inner probability five excited
five exchange
so k is valid kernel we show that the kernel matrix
must be created must be positive semidefinite
must be positive semi definite
it turns out
it turns that you're the converse holds two so this gives you ten
where a function k is valid
so this is a
this is theorem due to mercer kernels are sometimes also called mercer kernels this means
the same thing this is a valid kernel
the can exhibit
k is valid
no this is a mercer kernel
on i e
you know there exist five such that
one the rules
if and only if
on for any set of m examples and this really means for any set of
n points not necessarily your training set is just any set of n points you
might choose on it holds true that the kernel matrix
have to OK fine just now
it is
on symmetric
positive semi
and so i approved only one direction of this result proved that it about kernel
then k is symmetric positive definite but on the conference site and show that it
turns out that this is necessary and sufficient condition
so the thing use to test
whether any function you might want to choose on
is a kernel
just as a concrete example of something that is clearly not so
valid kernel
it's a really really good guy
it's even better than your average maximal consistent set
it doesn't make any existential claims unless is prepared to tell you what which thing
is an example
and then
in terms of this set
we can construct
the interpretation
we're after
we want for the interpretation
we wanted to mine
that's got to be a nonempty set
and we want an interpretation function
and we also want evaluation but we can
they that for the moment
what are we going to choose as domain
the ninety cents
and the one we like
is the set
of our primordial double prime whatever it is we're up to now
the set of all the ground terms of the language white ground
means no variables
in the term
we can be assured that this set is nonempty
i suppose the fact that we threw in at least one constant some point
if we didn't well let's do it anyway right we we just
do all we have all the domain has to be is not empty and this
is easy to arrange
well i mean we throw in denumerably many constants some points so with real is
that is as good a nonempty set as any
it can serve as the domain for an interpretation
what else does so what does the interpretation function has to have to do
it has to assign
a function to every function symbol
and then it's can sign relation to every predicate symbols
how we gonna assign functions to functions and so
we going we've got
a function symbol
what is
i of the interpretation of it
going to be
on this to my
suppose we got some ground terms t one
appropriately the right number of them
OK these are objects in the domain OK this is it is this is the
double of objects from the domain what is the result of applying
this function to those
it's going to be
t one
to t
and this
is the term
the ground
the language
you just got it from by taking these
symbols these these terms
you which are all ground and applying a function symbol
two so it itself is
an object in the domain
so we cheat
wheeler every
we interpret every function symbol
in effect does itself
so the effect of this is that every
refers to
o denotes
OK the notation
t is t
provided the no variables in t
i haven't said anything about valuations here
an interpretation with that property
is named after yet another logicians
jack abramoff
belgian i think
abrams here of today
you know in canberra if you're famous you get a street named after you and
if you're a prime minister or something you get a suburb named after
if you
queen adelaide you get a city named after you
around the universe named after the that
the bright universe
is this
the mind
bring universal language is the set of ground terms
however interpretations
is one such that every ground term denotes itself
we could be off
something like
maybe two millimeters it's not so not too easy to
get that whole imprecise
so it's forty centimeters
plus and minus o point two centimetres
so that is an uncertainty of about half a percent
i have upstairs l square and the square
and downstairs b
that makes the error there was is a bit complicated
if i stick in the numbers
then i find the period
which will be very close to one point five six five seconds
that's taking the exact numbers that i gave you
four l
and i take for g nine point eight and i take the values for b
since i prefer to be on the conservative side
i would love for an uncertainty of about o point o one second
and i would like to make a measurement
and show you
and show you what we get
so we have here the
the rule
good isolated
small angle
we can be a little bit rougher make it a little larger
stop at first
all started when it stops at my side it is always easy do
look on the button
way was in the air
i mean isn't it
that's us
complex systems can be so easily
dealt with in physics
fifteen what is the point seven one
my reaction time
it's always point
one second thirty agreement is absolutely fantastic
i'll show you once you've done this
with your
you can now apply this knowledge
way more interesting
and that is the
the hope
will take the
and we're going to do the same thing for the whole of
and the system the approach will be exactly identical
we have been through the rule of law
this is the
this is point p
this is the centre of mass
it's not like this
a little later
the centre of mass will be here
and this angle will be data
the mass of the rule of
it is and it has radius are
i know will be forces sort of point p
but i couldn't care less about
all i worry about is this and g
in this position vector r p
and the whole thing goes
i'm going to get that to work
about the point p
equals and g
and i'll fill filled in for this immediately radius are
times the sign of fatah
and that must be equal minus the moment of inertia about point p
thank fate about
what is the moment of inertia about point b
well that's the moment of inertia of rotation about the centre of mass
let m are square the the parallel axis theorem
moment of inertia for rotation about this axis
it's clearly square because all the mass is distributed at the conference a distance are
so it is the summation of all the masses times the radius squared
so this is going to be m are screened
plus and minus grades
so that's two and are screen
so we bring this to one side
so we're going to get data available dots
g are
we make this the small angle approximation provided by IP
well zero
the involvement of oscillation data was exactly that same solution
now we get as a
period we get two pi
times square root
i p
divided by are
two and are created
he i'd be divided by MG not be but now we have and are
cited by
and we are
it's real
and the complex number this particular complex number
comes out so one we call that i'm not going to write this down because
it's sort of pompous and takes too long but it is a complex valued function
the real variable
got that
up to now we study real functions of real variables but now real valued functions
of real variables of the kind calculus is concerned with the now it's complex valued
the variable is real
but the output
the value of the function is a complex number
in general
such a function
well maybe a better
complex valued
about about complex valued function
of a real variable is changed the name of the variable fees always the real
we don't i don't think we have complex time yet although i'm sure there will
be some day
the next einstein appears complex valued function of a real variable t
in general would look like this
he goes in and what comes out well a complex number
which i would then have to write this way in other words the real part
depends on t
and the imaginary part depends upon t
so it's more a general function looks like
a general complex valued function this is just a special case of it
variable is a different name with you but the first function is coast would be
cosine t
and the second function will be signed t
so my question is how do you differentiate such a thing as well
i'm not going to fuss over this you know one can go to the death
the general definition is an with deltas and what not but
the end result of a perfectly
fine definition is you differentiated by differentiating each component
what's the reason you don't have to work so very hard because this is the
real variable and all i already know what it means to differentiate the function of
real variables like you write it this way
if that the derivative
of you plus i abbreviated that way
this means the derivative with respect to whatever the very decided to tell you what
variable and these functions were was i i
i don't have to tell you what i'm differentiating with respect to
it's whatever was there
as you can see
and the answer is it will be the derivative of u
plus i times the derivative
differentiate it just the way you would have these were the components available lots of
a motion vector e
you we get the velocity
by differentiating each component separately and that's what you're doing here
now the importance of that is that it least tells me
what it is i have to check when i checked this formula but so let's
do it now that we know what this is
we know how to differentiate the function let's actually differentiated that that's fortunately is by
far the easiest part of the whole process
so let's do it
so what's the derivative well let's go back to t
our generic variable
i want to emphasise that these are
in text that these functions
when we write this function is the data will almost never be the variable
outside of these notes on complex numbers it will only be time or something like
that or x neutral variable like x so what's the derivative of EDI data
i'm hoping that it will turn out to be all i need to the i
th data
that the yellow law may be true just as the green one was OK let's
calculate it
it's the derivative with respect to
unfortunately i can convert these the data has been updated cities
so the OK
times the cosine
was i sin t
and was that well the derivative of cosine t
differentiating the real and imaginary parts separately and up
it's a negative sign t
plus all i
times cos t
let's factor out of because it says
is five factorize the i would like to get
the first is the real part of what's left we'll be cosine t
how about the imaginary or
you see it will be i signed because
i times i is then gives me the negative ones
what's that
the acting
guarantee that the
getting the best case for the impression that it is going to be getting the
best for the at the money
so everyone participates in the option all together
however the problem is that
since everyone who's using different
revenue models
we have to convert all those bits and all the one
four like
how do we do this conversion
is an open problem no one really knows how to do this kind of
so currently what people typically do is
they enforce that you have to everyone has to be on the same sort of
and this is obviously not what necessary one
so converting the one given a common denomination is the challenge
it's still an unsolved problem
so that
this system close on the background for online advertising you got what online advertising sort
of what actors in the system
what are the different models with different advertising settings
what is ad exchange and all of these how did in fact features and now
we can move on
the statistical aspects of the problems
and this the but they are here to discuss the fundamental statistical problem that
that shows up in competition
i will now go
a little bit more mathematical and try to find some mathematical problem
based on the introduction that the beginning
so first again and start with the display advertising so before i go
into the side
i would like to mention that some of the problems which here
there has been progress made on those problems recently there are several papers that either
under submission or have been published in those references are not on the
tutorial so
after our tutorial is or provide a link to those references on our website which
can download but still getting them back to this example the new york times health
page netflix that so clearly the ad is not relevant to the
the content of the page and really the main goal here is netflix targeting a
certain section of the population school they probably want to reach out to a certain
section of the population and that's the reason why this is here
you know that's that's what is called display advertising is one thing to note is
in display advertising
the publisher takes risk
so with publishers pay per impression so there is no risk and publisher side of
the by the advertiser so one question to ask would be the war
why would the advertisers take the risk doesn't even work
that have not been a lot of studies done two
and so this question concretely there have been some exploratory analysis done like for instance
there was an article in the harvard business review according the study done by con
score when they
looked at users who were exposed to and add-on users were not exposed to that
then they did some exploratory analysis and found that the revenue for people who got
exposed to that was much higher than those who were not exposed to but you
know that's a relational study it's not you can't assert causality mister
maybe they got exposed to in that particular kind of hardware problem particular age group
and you know more than those kind of so so that you can't sort causality
based on such studies however recently there have been a study
using experimental design
and this paper is going to come out in economics journal so it was done
by some colleagues yahoo so what they did was they did for the study and
called it the highlight of rules that they were
the large
and the match to use records from the whole database with the retailers data is
and then they found a bunch of matches matches were done based on
it is
the area
you know
of error
get rid of
he worked
all right
all three
she is
six the
so far
we are
the model
i think that
and if
and that
you are
and yet
very easy
you are
four days
he held
it's getting on the
we have
here are
are all
these are the
well the
you really
by these people
i one
i did not work well well
three hundred
he went
do you
what you are
he was
for that's all
he really
right of
one or years
or a
and one
i very
where you are on the
want to be able to
what we
three so
here and there are no
he is
or i see might three
i i not
one reason
o thing and they
the school
in the future