OK good morning welcome to the
the second picture of the day my name is thomas hofmann i would currently at
in switzerland
i think in the program it says google research but that's not quite true i'm
actually director in engineering centre and while i think we have interesting research problems and
some i want to mention here
my work these days is really more about building systems and working with engineering teams
actually putting things in production
OK this is what i've been doing the last three years so some of the
work i will present here sort of pre-dates my google time work going on structured
prediction and then
cover that and some recent work with other people have done in this area as
you will see hopefully
i want to talk about towards the end when i discuss so the first part
of the lecture this morning will mainly be
about the methodology
and then
formal setting and then in the afternoon i will talk more about applications that that
most of the applications will be in information retrieval so you have an
you might imagine sort of you know some of the connections between working at google
and working on this specific
problem we might have in the end enough time to either you know finnish literally
or if you have questions about google things in general use of machine learning in
an industrial setting i'm also happy to answer this
so let me begin to feel free to
o interrupt me and any time so
of course we know you know just two
wake up after the break that supervised machine learning
you know is is a wonderful thing to have where we can learn functional dependencies
between inputs and outputs and we can do this based on training data
by using inductive inference and its most basic form of course we are facing classification
problems and you know you've you've seen probably many examples here you know many examples
in your work classification problems such as optical character recognition where we give you know
given an image of the character map to you know one of the possible digits
all characters and things so for instance in the context of information retrieval probably the
most important application things like document correct the document categorisation we're given
a particular document represented just by the text or some additional features or semi structured
data metadata that we might have to map it to
certain categories so here's an example from my toes where we might not be enough
to things like location code and to certain
provide some topical annotations for instance that this document is money markets foreign exchange markets
and so on
of course in document character is a categorisation
you know just to contrast it with other things you might other approaches that you
might see the advantage of machine learning is that
we can basically harness
the knowledge that humans have like an expert like this one here on
given a particular classification system or particular taxonomy that people might be interested in and
use these training data to feed into mechanism learning machine of some sort
two then actually output using an inference mechanism complicated are now that in practice has
turned out to be more
efficient than say the traditional approaches that you've seen in this area
for instance that have been based on what's called knowledge engineering where people have tried
to design like handcrafted rules of how to classify things right so
so it's interesting to note that right it's not clear priority that for particular problem
machine learning is always the best technique to use but in text categorisation actually has
been quite successful and much more successful than other methods based on knowledge engineering the
advantage of machine learning is pretty clear whereas knowledge engineering right the knowledge that resides
within an expert
to get that out and to get it formalized right is very
difficult task is very hard to achieve good coverage very very hard to achieve good
precision the indirect approach through actually creating training examples has the advantage that really you
know we can just let the expert do what the expertise good namely
you know categorizing things using whatever knowledge he has and we don't have to worry
about the formalisation but rather than we can use an inference mechanism to come back
to get really something that generalizes to new data
and i should also say sorry i should also say that
text categorisation i'm not going to talk much about the plain text categorisation example but
has probably been one of the most successful applications of machine learning in practice and
and if you look at today's systems they actually do reach human level accuracy
in the categorisation performance that you see over realistic taxonomies
often what you notice that the precision of human annotation might be higher in the
sense that if humans has belongs to that class is more reliable typically than ever
machine makes a prediction but what machines are much better
at is the recall aspect of it by taking document water all the annotations that
the document should get if you think about huge taxonomies with many many classes humans
are sometimes likely to
basically omit certain categories because they don't think about it right which is very natural
if you have a huge categories systems machines are usually better at that
part which you can think of as i recall part
OK but this is not what i would like to talk about here mainly i
would like to talk about
problem called structured classification of structured prediction
so by that what i what i mean is really a setting where
what we're trying to predict is not the class variable binary variables or
not even a multiclass problem
but it something more interesting so to give you an idea of what we will
be talking about here and many more examples will follow you can think about all
kinds of structured objects such as sequences strings trees and so on and so forth
and what if you have a machine learning problem the prediction problem where this is
you're doing is effectively asking everybody in the audience too
sample from their prior on what random sequences look like and what you get if
you do that is data like this
so this is data from an experiment i did with kids at the canada USA
which is
run by the mere appearance in my life of their mathematicians whose
attending here
we played this game and this is just a histogram of binary for five binary
sequences that kids produced in this game we can call to get a sense of
justice sequential dependence we can collapse over parity so just you know one one one
one one zero zero zero zero zero same we get data set like this and
we can compare with the original versions experiment which was done not such as an
experiment but is an actual test of psychic powers by zenith radio network in the
golden age of radio they play this game over the airwaves and how people write
down on on postcards the five bit sequences that were being transmitted centers in here's
the data from the zenith radio experiments we can line up with the math camp
data and you can see what is shocking correspondence i think i'm pretty shocked by
this you know my main strength as a scientist is on the theoretical side of
this is this is just one experiment i did has replicator classic result but so
i think this is some of the coolest data that i have collected at least
which maybe isn't seen very much but i think it's amazing how close you know
it's smart map the high school students in the early two thousands come to the
randomness intuitions of typical people in the nineteen thirties
the only difference is the sequence here
the math kids for some reason put down way too many zero zero zero zero
zero maybe they were just being cute or
pains and that any so except for that
a bit of you can imagine the meta cognition they might lead a clever math
kid put that sequence down when you're supposed to be writing down random sequence basically
the same really suggested something deep about how the mind sees patterns here and we
want to try to explain that the way the way i would suggest we explain
this is is very much in line with same what nick was putting out there
in terms of the introspection works or what i think many of the example i
was i was talking before the visual perception example roger shepherd tables show which is
that when we introspect on cognition
and that often means just judgments were asked to make you know in in real
world context and experiment what we're introspective on of the output of the computation not
the intermediate processes are representations so in this case
the out the computations our minds are designed to do i would argue and many
others have argued is some kind of causal inference we were interested in the causal
processes that give rise to data we see
and it's it's a slightly different computation then the question might be
asked if i say which is more likely to have come from original is more
likely to come from a fair coin is more like the question which of these
is more likely to to have been produced by frequent which of these is the
fair coin the better call saul description of so in a sense it's not what
i'm asking about the likelihood of the data given that it's a fair coin were
saying given to hypothesis a fair or unfair how which which of these provide better
evidence for a fair coin when you're going in reverse and doing the causal inference
so this is a nice problem because we can capture this in a very simple
form of bayesian inference which if we just have to hypotheses than bayes rule has
this nice odds for me you just divide you write down the posterior probability for
both hypotheses and take the ratio of this is called the posterior odds and it's
just the product of the prior odds and what's called the likelihood ratio the ratio
of how well the data are predicted by the two hypotheses so we can see
how these analysis would work here
and also how we can use this the basic idea of base to work backwards
to figure out something about the priors in people's heads just to say are why
second recording did in those other studies in perceptions sensorimotor ones
looking at behavior in sort of trying to fill in the black box assuming bayesian
logic so here let's say we have these two pieces of data heads heads tails
tails heads heads heads heads they consider just two
this is just you know it's not very textbook toy example two alternative hypotheses are
fair coin always heads coins and then we can do this analysis with a much
bigger space ultimate hypothesis but then for those two hypotheses what is bayes rule in
this art form look like well
for the sequence heads heads tails heads tails the likelihood is again one of thirty
four fair coin and zero four always had one right because there's no way and
always heads coin is going to produce any tails little in that sequence what about
the priors well those are less accessible on our point here is actually try to
say can we can we can we look at behavior the introspective outputs of this
computation and make some inference about what the priors were well if we plug let's
let's call it along the prior of the fair coin i guess i should have
that's one seems like something small so maybe i should have put the other way
around whatever epsilon to some number between zero and one
then we plug that in here and then we can say well what
what about that's one would produce the judgement that when you look at heads heads
tails heads tails it looks like a fair point it seems to provide very strong
evidence for fair coin to high posterior odds here on quite well this doesn't really
tell us anything because since the data are incapable of coming from the always heads
coin that zero here then this is going to the posterior odds going to be
infinity is going to provide an infinite reason to believe in a fair coin under
this very simple hypothesis space no matter what that's like this but becomes more interesting
if we look at the sequence of all heads because now
depending on how you set one you get a different posterior odds
so if we had more time we could play this game and try to you
know i guess what are absolute values are we should be stopping
right so we will place but six minutes no problem we will not play that
game but instead of just just observe that from for many people when we look
at the sequence of all heads it's slight coincidence but it's not enough to make
us think from o in most cases that is really some trequenu element requires are
pretty rare so if you plug in the value of let's say nine hundred ninety
this is not upsetting that we have to have zero zero one one costs for
the binary potential what controls a zero
OK i think that's just about everything about this
graph is a little fragment of the graph separated up here but everything is just
the same the caicos where gk costs
the canonical form in the way he said
OK so now
we have we associate
and assignment of nodes and the
cost of that assignment with cut the cost of that kind
or equivalently
now we invoke the
i think forty or so years old
ford fulkerson algorithm mincut maxflow which says that
that was not consider all possible cuts through this graph
the the rules are only the cut has to pass between the source and the
sink but otherwise you can rotate you
and then i asked well we have always possible cuts is the minimum cut that
is the one with the minimum cost
and the ford fulkerson algorithm says that
the cost of that car
is equal
so the total
hello that you can force
diagonal that was time hunting ln
you know from
siberia here and you know it distributed across some pipeline to you know germany into
poland and coming out in somewhere near london
here i want to know just you know forcing is much flow through the network
as i can you know that the oil take whatever it did it once i
was going to increase the pressure to make sure that all the pipelines are fully
utilized as far as possible because there might be some transverse pipelines you know like
this one here that use the tall or don't get forty years
but nonetheless i'm going to push and push
and get as much flow through this network as i can
well then the ford fulkerson theorem says the total amount of flow you get by
by pushing as hard as you can see is actually equal to
the minimum cut
but you get by considering all possible cut the network does this make sense
it sort of does because the minimum cut is actually if you like searching for
bottlenecks in some distributed fashion saying you know where you know tell me on aggregate
what is the bottleneck the aggregate bottleneck in this
in this diagram and that bottleneck determines what's the maximum amount of flow that you'll
be able to get through the diagrams of this kind of duality
between the minimum cut the the maximum flow
that's going to be very useful because now we could we have the option of
solving the minimum cut the the energy minimum cost simply by pushing oil through
network and seeing how much we can get through
and more than that we can tell not only what is the energy of the
minimum cut by measuring simply the total
maximum flow we can also get the minimal configurations
simply by looking for all the
links which are saturated
whatever link is
that means that the cut passes through that link
and so the the
note will be assigned to the opposite of the sourcing
i i simply you know i've marked in dark blue here in some putative flow
all the
links which are saturated it could include also
i guess it should have included should but separated these links as well they should
be in dark blue
all of the things which are saturated coming in dark blue
then the couple passes through this link
so you can actually read out from the maximal flow from the quantity of the
flow and also where the flow is saturated you can read out this the solution
we want is actually not the energy that we're interested in the configuration we will
know solving segmentation you want actually which nodes in the foreground and which ones are
OK so that's just you know play with this little bit simple tutorial examples
so i've dreamed up
a problem
in canonical form
so that
the cheese
as i promised have the here and one one values zero and the off diagonal
value set equal
and for the efforts
the you re potentials the only rules are that the
weights have to be positive all these when positive
so i'm solving this problem
one the simple problem i can think of the form former we're interested in
but i'm doing it in the new way
now let's see if i've done everything right
this should be
f one of zero
or maybe roman
i said i could swap inside
cutting this arrow here should be the cost of assigning idea
i think you forgot to swap over the cost of the thing that you do
that actually should be seven that one of the attributes or alternatively the problem of
solved this f one one equals
and give you an interpretation of what's left
so what is left is
so let's assume a special case that
we have a kernel
which is goes in the normalized goes in that has integral one
so it's a valid density model
if this is the case then
this thing is still normalized because this sums over the number of cosets which implies we divide by and plus
so this is a density model and actually says it's as simple as a well
known density model is the so-called parzen windows density estimate of the positive class
this is a parzen windows density estimate of the negative class
and the overall this gives you a classification rule which is
one of the simplest possible classification classification rule to basically you just estimated density so the two classes
and to just check whether all the
density is high
four your test point
under the one model or in the other model so that's
one possible way of classifying data
in the
so that's nothing
no deep methods to classify data but this was when first noticed this was somewhat surprising that
this turns out to be such a nice simple geometric
so it's just
and a nearest mean
classifier if you want
and in the feature space
and also want to say of course
and this construction also works for other types of kernels they don't have to be normalized
they don't even have to be positive so it goes in a causes
not just a positive definite function but it's also
positive everywhere the values that you get out was positive but if you take a
polynomial kernel it can also get negative values
so a positive definite function doesn't have to be positive and we we prove that is positive on the diagonal
but of course of diagonal elements for polynomial kernel can be negative
for the girls in the company but anyway so this is something that's
from that point-of-view modelling past winners but then from another point a is less general because
parzen windows you can also use window functions that are not positive definite kernels that
as long as they
positive and normalized are nonnegative normalized
so it seems i was actually
thinking of not going into
he sees for integrating that's
so let me first just give you the brief idea thespians
and then maybe tomorrow i'll tell you more about experience
this is the map
so i
i'm not sure if i remember correctly but this is the so this is the only volcano
that sorry this is a new one this is the
as the old one
and i think this is the so-called win-win but this is a completely happy
that's that's the old one but that's the one is still active in it
well maybe
here's the inheritance behind this the
and here says new okay
thank you
we always
whatever yes and which is the part that they would talking about film
yeah so that mean maybe some well
so i think they were talking about that they were talking about the company behind you
this said it differently
but so i think that talk about this will come here and this is the one that's still active
and there have been some eruptions
i think the most recent one was down here and the one in the fifties was probably somewhere here
then those nodding his wife is from the canary islands
and i think it is this land is relatively new
and my recollection is that they they worried that half of this thing here will
slide into this ocean and then the big wave will start from here and move in this direction
it might also move into other directions but discovery i
discovery channel it's important that moves in this direction
president is much close of course but then nobody worries about people in brazil there
if they are in this direction
one should be doing about this
and so
so this is a
this is a very short
very short summary of what it means to i'm not sure maybe we'll talk will talk about multi-task tomorrow
but now using this these mean classifier and we can
we can do something slightly more clever so we can stick with
using a hyperplane
the reproducing kernel hilbert space which is what the main classifier was doing
typically by hand
but if you want to use one of the tools
go ahead but then you take what came out of it so you may be
you make the b
rules of the alignment of this is the same as this and this is the
inverse of this business into their own you know into adopt into part of the
documents so in your RDF graphs you have your data
plus the mapping so i'd say about ninety percent of the ones out there right
now we're just OWL same
and in fact they are not even use necessarily
it it really should be called
OWL kind of the same as
but i'll just give you a kind of the same as it only gives you
a formal simplicity ignore the model theory and those are the same as if you
you guys in the i community one live with it they don't really care
because they're using it
behind the web applications works
because they don't need a hundred percent
OK so in in the linked data web so for example DB pedia has been
very popular thing in dbp
is wikipaedia
whenever you have one of these boxes
this is you know this person here's where they were born in this in this
and this is very easy to turn that into a semantic web representation so you
say that a person named albert einstein and it says here he is a scientist
use a subclassof scientists and then says he was born in such and such a
town in germany and so you say
the city was this and that the
the country was with germany and he won the nobel prize and nobel prize that
is awarded nobel prizes nobel prizes and awards
things like that so
and there's a lot of other stuff which essentially the links in the pedia labels
have in which wikipedia has
a fairly large dataset used to be about a million and a half triples and
it's now much larger than the triple against the RDF graph you see a lot
of people's lives
o thing here and then link with the label on it and that three your
eyes or whatever you want to think about but all of these ontology things even
seeing can be realized in that model
so they can build built on top of this so
as an example musicbrainz music ontology
a lot of information about
performers and things like that so maybe you're looking at the performer there
and you say in this guise interesting from me is wikipedia personality asserted these links
to go get the DBT pt information and then you say
all of that says he was born you know you're where i live
what other
people were born near where i live where you can use germany
for that you go over to geonames which turns a lot of countries and cities
until at long's and then you use the lat long reason so conceptually you can
take something like this and imagine a lot of really interesting queries that could be
answered if you had some kind of
front end to this and a lot of people are interested in the front end
to this many people are building browsers so you pointed something and then you follow
but the problem is this thing is growing so big so fast that browsing is
clearly problematic
without some way of or just like the web we can write to once upon
a time when i first use the web
you went to
the web page and then it linked it was just the page with about one
hundred links on it but sent out to the hundred other things on the web
right in their local is that thing got bigger and bigger people came up with
new ways of organizing that information
a browser like tabulator which berners-lee coined by ora lassila there's about a dozen more
that you see a lot of demos on tuesday night at the
poster demo session
those things are starting to get overwhelmed and now they are starting to look at
well how do we do reverse indexing and pagerank so so if it once upon
a time you came to my photo file
and found four friends so it didn't really matter what are you show the
my facebook can be done to to my livejournal can be done to have lots
of other things certainly
i have thousands of people and in fact linked to me and you want them
altered you don't have to go through saying is this is this is this is
this is you like sort who some kind of ordering so
so a lot of the question this cloud has been how do we use it
but the interesting thing from an application point of view
so this is open this is available you can start playing with it tomorrow
if you're sitting here you can't because the conductivity is in good faith that you
can play
this the website but what's interesting about this thing is
it was a couple of hundred thousand triples a year and a half ago
a couple billion triples at the beginning of this year and twenty three billion last
time i heard the number which was i think beginning in the summer
so it's growing by orders of magnitude as people dumb stuff now i don't know
if it's still growing at rates
what mean you can get your hands
and more data
then you can put into any of the tools you're likely to get your hands
on right now very easily
so a lot of stuff so a lot of people who are worried about
the chicken and then what will cause them so there's a bit of a mess
out there you hear a lot of you good to database conference say oh haha
there's RDF store still have trouble with more than a million triples
in fact that was true in two thousand six
right now there is also upstairs on tuesday night you also see the billion triple
challenge where we made one point one billion that's ten to nine
available one of the UK companies said they were very disappointing
because england a billion is a million million ten to the twelfth and they thought
that would be a challenge but they
routinely host for other companies tend to the nineteenth onto the triples now again there's
not a lot inferencing there's not a lot of ontology in space we're still talking
about data level
the other thing going on
is this always coevolution and technology
so at the same time you've seen this you know we we go up the
ontology and logic theory that was an interesting idea
and conceptual right but if you come out to the real world nowadays there's a
lot of other stuff happening
so OWL is one of several different ways of doing sort of knowledge is stuff
but also when you have RDF you need a way to query so there's the
standard called particles
some other things i show you main i just thought this was when i was
for another talk i was giving
this morning i was pulling through small slides but no one had ever seen this
before this is the first layer cake diagram
whereas in normal distributions with rather flat but if powers norovirus so you know that
everything just pick to the mean when right
so you have a big issue up here
that means that you're pretty much certain
about what you guys OK the prediction
it's rather reliable
you have this kind of
spread parameter set
you can do a lot of sense
for example
we can all modify this correlation and regression trees
to solving this label ranking problem
two major modifications as well
it's about the speedy criteria right how speak the tree
so in the regression tree this is based on this standard duration
and here
we can just using special permit instead
we can define goodness of fit
in terms of the set of parameters
that you just speak the truth
using this goodness of fit
a second what application is
above this stopping criterion for partition the tree OK
we now
so far currently with stop two
partition the tree
even first the tree is pill
OK all
the number of labels node is too small
OK because he the case is made those says two parts for any
OK that was studied in the
if you do the whole training that to
labour looks
approximate look like this OK this
quite similar as a regression tree the differences in the in the leaves you rankings
instead of revenue numbers
now i will show you some experimental results the here is that the site or
the resulting one big table
we compare our local politics namely this
no coupled with label approach
this label ranking trees compare them with this
constant complication
there are too many messages here
we found that
if they decide is rather good
if the ranking is a complete
the meta labels and also high
we found out of this
it's based label ranking
is significantly better
the second observation is
we found love with all of that
so the size of the neighbouring country
isn't that big
this is the columns
after this they were tree
it is the relative size of the neighbouring country compared
so convolutional decision tree which is train only on the top label
from the size is not
this is a rather go essay
so here
it is
but to the learning curve
of the local polish compare with this constant classification
we found that
one local poachers of local metals
a more flexible
so it can exploit more information this information
compared with a model based approach
while this model based approach
has some home
the stronger bias this see this
so it's lack of flexibility
and i pretty much done here here's some among conclusion
we have introduced
and it's this approach
for label ranking
well we're using published model namely the models models
and once you give this label ranking problem of four probabilistic treatment you can gather
all the news useful information for example
this set of parameters
so the set of parameters
i can tell you
how reliable your prediction is
OK and our approach can deal with complete and that's where this incoming rec well
OK we can deal with pose case
there are of course
some future work we want to
namely it is
approximation for this
in country ranking case we want to make this inference more efficient is is rather
complex problems
they're always space to improve
the second is
the approach i propose here
it's not only
useful for label ranking problem
but it can some other type of problems as well
so we will we also like to see
what we can do in the future for the type of problems
OK so basically
this is all from my side
and if you have any problems i like to answer
it just makes you speak any of questions always try that before
they are really remains
one is my
we more of
o with a
you were
very easily
the fact that we're beginning because we don't have very explicit pruning strategy for the
we somehow expect that
the size of the tree
this the big
and i think is this question right well that was one of
but in fact with it turns out that the size of the tree
not as because we imagine
right you can see here this the relative size of the tree
it is rather save comparable with what is true
OK so
overfitting is not
all this is not a little bit of experiment
as well as for the news label poachers
because many labour voters you just have to control how big your neighborhood is
OK if you have a good control of the neighborhood then is also not the
likely you of video data
but it does that of question
OK the question is why
it uses models model
first for that
this model is more is kind of the standard also golden standard statistics to dealing
with the ranking data
and there already had been done
on this model is more
this is a somewhat simple reason
but of course you could also use some other type of models for dealing ranking
this is not a problem
you could also try some other model of course as well
OK so
so to called
sample so time essentially the same particle in this weighted empirical measure
so that's the idea
one thing which is nice but that is that if you were to use stallman
sequential importance sampling on whether sample before that you add your son paul where
distributed according to the policy distribution qn
on the weights with correcting for the discrepancy between pi and you know if your
son paul OK
you obtain this new approximation
of the time solution that the new sample you ever up for immediately essentially distributed
according to the target distribution pi
there are statistically dependent was going make the analysis of such algorithm much more complicated
but basically
at least one done by doing this for sampling is that you managed to eliminate
particles with low weights multiply particle evaluates on obtain approximately distributed according to the target
so one way to arrive at the beach
prod small
to clear away
it is to set essentially what you've been doing is that if you sampled
capital in times from these discrete distribution
build this associated on empirical measure
then this corresponds simply
to approximate the original target distribution
by the following day OK so what does it mean here
so remember that before resampling i was editing as as i was associating to each
i await which was essentially wn OK now what you've done essentially when or so-called
capital timeform described empirical measures
essentially corresponds to
the particle exercise basically
number of time which is given by NI OK i have been given to each
of these could p
o weight equal to one of
basically this is one way process to be clear to for two two
to think about the reason why we've have been doing is that essentially at time
and we've attributed to particle one
two on and we've attributed number of copy of spring if you want which is
are in one and two and capital and on obviously because it's still there have
been sampled capital and they've been sampled from the discrete distribution deal distributed according to
multinomial distribution of parliament attempted to land on portability given by the normalized OK so
that's essentially what we've been doing
only in the sense
these kind of
approximation or something positive some good properties in particular
it provides you you into a bit of multicellular when you do this something step
but because of the property of the multinomial you can see that essentially the new
multicolored approximation you get is an i is essentially estimate of the origin or is
unbiased and sense the expectation of these respect to distribution of the mean value the
divided between them is basically the original version so we do
we do basically this kind of
chilling particles
well multiply particles but we do you know kind of clear away such that essentially
this property satisfied OK we see that a kind of there is an unbiased operation
with some
so it seems when you look at it
for to decide or is it looks a bit silly
you have an original
o point two measure which is a weighted sum of the time as
on you approximated one small bar something capital and and time from so
basically you introduce some kind of a world in time because you just add an
additional approximation was basically
the benefits of of particle images there are some things that is that for most
point of entrance like the baseball in particular is going to fall beneficial for future
time steps so given time index samples of particle ten times OK
but the important thing is that the following time index this ten particles are going
to evolve differently so that's why basically it it's actually
kind of useful from the particle on that rhetorical point of view as potential
so they are better sampling scheme actually which have been described in the literature or
being essentially by a single in the US but having like actually la vie and
so you can basically follows the description of them in the book by happy mood
for example
which was published in two thousand five
now let's basically
not every honest onto this is something operation that's basically looked at
the the resulting so it is going to be very
small modification
what i've been doing before
so i'm interested to solve for a sequence of target distribution pi and compute the
normalizing constant on i'm going to use the importance sampling
on essentially at each time step i'm going to use this was something operation to
get rid of particles with low weights on multiply particles which so get at time
i saw old capital and particle according to chew on
on our way to get to exactly the same as before
now what to do
OK when your at time one
so you have your approximation
the target distribution
pi one
the next one which is a weighted sum of the as
what to do
you're so called capital and particles
for this
weighted empirical measure
to obtain capital new particles which for the sake of simplicity i also do not
x one OK because i don't want to overload notation so i call i denote
the resampled particle as the result articles so don't forget that basically in the said
this is the set of so-called father called is a subset of the original set
of particle because of the particle have died on some of them have been copied
multiple times so you have something approaching
when you have time to
what you do
use sorry when you have time and what to do sample important component x
according to the UN
the conditional
basically importance sampling solution
and then you weights
the particles
on the where you're a damn is a little bit different from what we've done
that is your away them according to what you're write them according to
gamma and the the ratio of successive target normalise target distribution
time to OK
so this is the
problems which considering at time
one is the case or remember what we have think we for sampling when we
will not resampling i had the importance weight
what the in the
so i should clarify
great looking for
is not a solved problem which you agree
OK so another another problem that people have have been trying to work on and
in natural language processing but haven't really structured prediction for yet is learning about linguistic
types so we often talk about tokens words in text
for example in the sentence barack obama likes to talk about barack obama there are
two instances of the token obama both of which instantiate the type
getting a little bit metaphysical here but the question is are the things to say
about the the word obama on its own absolutely refers to a person name its
canyon there are lots of things we can say about words at the type level
and so we often call these things in these collections of knowledge lexicons are ontologies
and people would like to build this from data as well and you can do
that this type of structure prediction but nobody really has
maybe maybe started but i i would say that we haven't really figured out how
to think about that discourse structure dialogue structure learning world knowledge from text these are
all problems people are thinking about but structured prediction isn't really that older using right
now for that but it might be
gonna skip that
take a quick fires
any questions at this point
this is the quietest rule of thirty people i've ever spoken to
so i'm going to go and talk about the coding
here's my notation i'm going to expand it a little bit
scrimtex is going to be a set of possible inputs often it sigma star like
and we use big bold text to mean random variable of the inputs and i'm
going to use script y again to be the set of possible outputs and these
big bold y to be the random variable of outputs and h is going to
be a prediction function that maps access to what
a decoder is simply an implementation of x sorry image
the texan accent and returns your one and the reason it's called decoding this may
be puzzling so i'm going to give us a very quick history lesson so nowadays
in NLP we like to talk about structured prediction it's you know the heart metaphor
that we love to use to describe everything we do at least i am in
this talk but before that maybe ten years ago the thing everybody used was what
source channel models
everything was seen as the source channel model
it's not a bad metaphor
the idea is that you you want to model jointly this these two random variables
x and y
x happens to be your input y happens we output and so the way you
going to do that is going to model first the distribution over y and then
given y you're going to generate x to you know little generative model we haven't
really done anything fancy here it's just the just the chain rule so there's source
model generates wide channel model generates acts
given y
and our job is to decode
we want to find the accent marks there is most likely given sorry we want
to find the one that is most likely given access to all the major backs
and so we use bayes rule
we ignore the denominator because the marginal is constant and this is decoder
that's the decoding usually refers to this sort of balancing of the source model the
the channel model
and this this metaphor you can get you can get so much out of it
the classic example
had kicked off its use in NLP i think part from a part of speech
recognition awards it's widespread was this great story told about sixty years ago by warren
weaver about translations of this was back when the goal of the goal of all
natural language processing in the united states of course was to
spine the russians
and so the story was that they're speaking russian that's what you hear that the
observable that's the axe
but in fact those pesky russians there actually thinking in english course because that's what
everybody thinks
of course so so what happened is that they thought this thought in russia devious
sort of course in russian and then it passed through their broken mechanism i'm sorry
getting myself confused they had this devious thought in english because that's the language of
thought and that pass through this filtering came out of structure and so our job
is to decode it recover with the original message was as it as it existed
before i got garbled so why of course is the is the english the true
the true language underneath
OK so i'm going to keep the term decoder because people and hope you like
it and it's sort of
abstract away the problem of decoding from what is often called inference but that's a
very loaded term in machine learning so i'm not going to call it in fact
just going to call
so generally what what you want to do
you know this this equation at the top sums up a lot of different cases
of decoding but generally it involves finding the y
that minimizes sum expected risk some expected loss
given some distribution over the true value of y so we use l y x
y to be the last
when you choose the cost that you pay when you choose label lowercase y and
the true value is the third argument given input x
so we're going to say that that the true value is distributed according to some
distribution which we may or may not know
and we want to find the y that is the least offensive under the distribution
and if we take the most common case
with the loss is zero one meaning
you lose one point if you get it wrong and you don't lose any points
if you get it right
zero one loss then what this gives you back is just find the most likely
white x
that seems that we have a probability model over y given access which we don't
there's more there's a more general framework that
it encompasses almost everything that people do
in NLP which is to use linear models
so i'm going i'm going to use g
know a feature vector function
it takes x y maps them into some euclidean space
this this is probably familiar
you have to remember here that this is a mapping not just the inputs and
mapping both everything works better if you read this way to get input and output
you mapped into this this euclidean space and then you take an inner product with
and thank you very much for that introduction i think you'll city here again the
other organizers this meeting which is obviously about this meeting
as i was
walking back from the
equally fabulous dinner last night
my mind was
of complexity and i
felt as though withdraws being pushed into my head
as i walk through the old city of dresden back to my hotel
and i almost felt like singing beethoven's ninth because it is amazing
particularly of course
for somebody
from england to see
extraordinarily well
the city interesting has been reconstructed it makes them feel extremely good
so thank you very much for the invitation to come to
systems biology
can we get this to work
well you fix the problems there are stop talking
i can use to compute but does it work
it's not going to go forward right OK thank you thanks a lot
almost every university
has a
caught on this password systems biology even harvard university now has department of systems biology
the only problem is the person if asked to head it doesn't know what it
and i think very few know what it is
because it's a buzzword got going over the last six seven years the buzzword of
course but ten to fifteen years ago was sequencing the genome and then it became
bioinformatics there is an urgent need for to try to define what on earth it
because i tell you i sit on many of the grant committees allocate money in
this area internationally
and ninety percent of the work that is happening is simply for genomics for bioinformatics
we are urgently needed for some kind of definition
of what the subject is and that's what i'm going to
trying to do here
and my first point is that it's not a new subject
for systems biologist
to my mind was closed
who in eighteen sixty five published this remarkable
critics limits in experiment
in which he
enunciated in one of the first examples of assistance biological approach
where he wrote that the living organism doesn't really exist in the media extensions but
in the liquid media and
a complex organism should be looked upon as an assemblage of simple organisms that live
in liquid media anterior he had this concept but the internal environment in which all
of ourselves are drenched is kept under control to be constantly referred to as the
constancy of the internal environment in new therefore the control mechanisms operating at level of
the organism as a whole
and i think this is one of the reasons why one should regard him as
perhaps the first systems biologist and he also made comment is very relevant to
a meeting on complexity and the many mathematicians are here
which i'm afraid is misled everybody because he wrote in his book the most useful
part of physiology and medicine to follow now seek to discover new facts instead of
trying to reduce the equations the facts which science which possesses
the emphasis on that statement which incidentally has being used in british and american physiology
has a kind of anti theoretical stance the journal of physiology one time even used
to reject theoretical papers i think it was hodgkin and huxley the only ones who
managed to break through the barrier before i managed to do so i just followed
in the past that statement is the basis of
this and theoretical stance within within physiology which i think is damaged it
but it's a misconception of what they wrote
because the emphasis on that statement is on the word now
he meant in nineteen sixty five we don't have the data yet he went on
to say
the application of mathematics to natural phenomena is the aim of all science because the
expression levels phenomena should always be mathematical so simply a temporary point was saying at
that time nineteen sixty five we didn't know enough indeed we didn't have to do
very much useful mathematical analysis but the time clearly because when have
i think the time has come for very good reasons which is that
in some ways the problem we face today
in analyzing complexity in biological systems resembles that thought that because the reason why he
insisted on this systems level concept of the consistency the media tell you
was that he was facing the challenge from the organic chemists who managed to synthesize
organic molecules the molecules people thought only existed
inside living systems where there was some special forces vital force that enable them to
do what they were doing and of course the organic chemistry is completely wrong
ben response those
to the reductionism the organic chemists who as it were claiming that one day reduce
life just to the number of organic molecules which we can make a response to
all right thanks for coming everybody
really this is going to be about the very basics of monte carlo planning as
i see them and we'll talk about some of the recent progress is for example
the UCT
algorithm l committee and so if you really waiting for that you can take a
break and wake up when i mention UCT again so so we
the left just giving a few preliminary is about markov decision processes
mainly for the notation
and then we're going to try to motivate monte carlo planning why is it useful
what is it
and then basically i'm going to talk about two classes of monte carlo planning techniques
as i see it's one of call uniform monte carlo is not going to be
very intelligent about how
it samples the environment
and then we'll talk about adaptive monte carlo techniques at the end culminating in the
UCT algorithm which you might be familiar with because it's been so successful
in go
more recently other problems
so i
and the peace we're going to model the world is a markov decision process will
will talk about that in a minute but the basic model is we have this
robot or
and and
he can send actions to the world possibly their stochastic actions in the world gives
us states and rewards back or if you like observations and rewards back and we're
interested in what's going on in this guy's head he wants to maximize his reward
so we're gonna stick in monte carlo planning techniques
but an MDP is basically composed of four things the first thing is going to
be a set of states
these are the states of the world that sort of completely describe how the world
is going to function if we take an action we have a finite set of
actions and the thing that makes a markov decision process has been a markov and
it is because the transition distribution p of t is the first order markov process
what this means is this is a conditional probability distribution that tells you if you
take the a in state s
what's the probability of ending up in as prime
so that's what we mean by transition distribution and its first order because it only
depends on s a right now
the reward distribution is also going to be first order markov chain for any state
it tells us if we take action a what is the distribution over real valued
rewards and for the sake of this talk we're going to be assuming that that
this has finite
the rewards are bounded within some finite range
so those are mdps
pretty basic stuff that's just for notation
so if we have an MDP what is the solution
well it's not good enough generally to output a straight line planned action one action
two the action three because once you take action one
the transition to some state that maybe action two wasn't so well suited for so
you really need to form a plan that can handle or whatever state you end
up in in any moment we call center plan policy
and right now we're not gonna compare we're not going to care about how we
get that policy can be computed online as you're planning or offline before but policy
is simply a mapping could be stochastic from one is pi for policy from states
to actions
basically it tells us what to do or in state s
this defines a continuous reactive controller for this agent in every moment is in state
takes an action ends up in a new state looks this policy and figures out
what to do next so that's sort of policy is and the main question is
how do we determine whether policy is good or bad and intuitively policy is good
if on and the chief the high reward when we executed in the environment
so specifically in this talk we're going to talk about finite horizon discounted reward it's
amount for but we're going to denote this function by v pi s h h
is our horizon that's how long we're going to think ahead that's how far into
the future going to think ahead and what that function tells us is what is
the expected value we're going to get following this policy starting in as if we
follow for a h steps possibly in county and so let's think about what this
so what if you run the policy for each step starting in s
you're going to get a sequence of rewards for a sequence of eight rewards and
this is really a random sequences of random variables because the dynamics of random the
reward function is random
was the random sequence and what we're going to be interested in is the
the of the sequences so the expected value of the discounted sum and we discount
later rewards more than earlier rewards so beta t
is the discount factor
if you set it to one that all these rewards are equal to our sort
of treated equally and so it allows us to trade off how much we care
about the future usually is just there for mathematical convenience sometimes you can motivated by
economic principles of the probability of dying and whatnot
but in the end what we're interested in is the optimal policy
so an optimal policy is one that dominates all other policies across all states in
terms of its value
i'm not going to cover the slide in detail of the say
if you really like infinite horizon
problems so so in many cases you might have a continuous controller and you plan
for the infinite horizon
and they have to introduce the discount factor to make things well defined a really
finite horizons results are going to be good enough and the main reason is that
we can approximate the infinite horizon value function with a finite horizon
and if you choose your horizon long enough the approximation error goes to zero quickly
so basically everything that i say here will apply to infinite horizon problems you can
refer to this slide
again if you care to care to see that so so the basic results in
MDP theory is a pretty old results
optimal policies are guaranteed to exist so there are optimal policies is there is not
a partial order on policies and
we have algorithms for computing that
all IP addresses
and then we have to compute the size of the story
if you have many many many IP addresses
it's a problem to maintain this
is the same another example and it was the first proposed in this paper
this algorithm
if you want to have an idea of the number of different distinct work
in the text or in the
the idea is the following
there is
of and
which is going to be maintained incrementally
this structure here
and is equal to weight
is initialized by zero
then you have the a hashing function has functions
we which
each element
of your stream of the stream
in two
and b
for instance this IP address
in two is b
since it is a hash function
this has function distributes uniformly the elements of the stream
on the
two power as a possibility
the method is very simple
it's to maintain and update
this a bit
for each new element arriving in the stream
it is ash
so for instance this element is ash into this
the position of the leftmost one
in h
a bit strange
as carrier
it is updated and
there is zero here if it wasn't there are here it forced to one
very very
the reason
is that once a sufficient number
of elements have been seen
it's possible to have an estimation of the number of different
already seen in the stream
it seems
selecting the leftmost zero in this
and the world
and with this position are
you can compute the number
seven estimation of the the number of different
that use appearing in this period
the idea is that
for an element
already seen we expect
on the
left here
there will be
half one then hop
during those
and here they will be
divided by four
and so on
so the probability a very small number of and the probability of
having all one here is very small so this gives an estimation of a number
of different
you have
very nice results
so this this is the first
so the idea here it is
you have especially specialized tasks
you would need a very large
to maintain some statistics
and you have this marks structure which
maintains incrementally exactly
the information you want which is summarized information
without storing or
the elements
another example is the count sketch allegories
the goal of this sketch
to find quickly
the k most frequent elements industry
a large number n of distinct values of course if you have a small number
of possible
IP addresses
there's no problem you have your around ten
a you addresses and you you can find the
the most quick
so this is one
nice solution for the one hundred most frequent IP addresses going through a router
so you have here
an input stream
with different
elements arriving
what you want to do
is to be that the distribution
of the elements the frequency of all the elements and then extract on the k
most africans
k most frequent elements industry
standard solution
maintaining this array
of all the IP addresses incrementing counter
and providing for when necessary
of course these arrays very large
the idea is
i'm going to introduce them
concentration inequalities
the tell us how
sample averages
converge to
two expectations
and how concentrated these things i guess with more generally
then just sample averages we're looking at a concentration of other
more general random variables about the expectation
and then
we'll be using these these ideas
improving this bounds using a measure of complexity call rademacher averages
will get onto those in a moment
OK but just for stability
i believe intuition
if we think of this
the framework is i've outlined we have
a class of functions capitalist
and we'd like to choose some function from that class so as to minimize the
of the loss of that minimize the risk
but we have these these competing issues if we were to choose
a function from a more complex class then
we're going to have to do better in terms of the approximation property right that
the infimum over the class that the minimum over the class of the risk
for classes is something that will be smaller but will suffer on the estimation side
the more complex class and we only have information about the class presented to us
in the form of these
this finite set of labelled examples
the key issue here is trading of these two properties the approximation properties in the
estimation problem
so coming up with estimates of the the risk
in terms of for instance the sample size in some measure of the complexity of
that tells us how to control the complexity that for instance using some method of
sieves some approach where we say for a given sample size we can work with
the class that's this complex and is the sample size grows we can choose some
function for bigger and bigger class
an approach that's very
very closely related is the regularisation approach for instance
you know control introducing an extra
parameter into an empirical criterion
such as the
i regularisation parameter in the SVM
OK so
these are two general approaches of controlling controlling complexity
so let's think now about suppose we have a case where we've got very rich
and we split up into some hierarchy
right so we're thinking
choosing functions from this class but it's way too rich to
to estimate some function from that class near optimally using a finite sample so we
split up we come up with some hierarchy we represent functions we represent this class
as a union of of simpler classes
f one f two and so on where for each k
what we're going to do is choose the best efforts of k in the class
capital k
OK and for instance we might do that by minimizing empirical risk
and then will choose
and if k
right one of these optimal guys
so as to minimize the complexity panellist empirical error
OK so this is a generic approach that we might take you can think of
you can think of this
hierarchical representation for instance for things like decision trees came might might be index k
might be the restriction on the number of decision nodes in the tree
well for the
a reproducing kernel hilbert space the index k
might allow
and increase increasing radius
football in RKHS right if some k would be
a subset a ball in the RKHS of radius r k where k is increasing
with k
and then with thinking of so is is one
so i think of
and that
you might want to see
prior work
he served as a certain member of the committee for the defence of
these are
doctor the
where i see
looks at the station was seminar
he thought it
like here
we start to collaboration with his or you know
with four years ago within european
training and e
and he proved to be very fruitful collaboration
in all the participants are operations so once it's very much like work
this ensures
question thank you very much of course it's also my pleasure to to come to
my second visit here and unfortunately just for one day
but hopefully it will not be the last one
and today i will give you a brief introduction about the
activities that we have in my group and high work during the last
now more than twenty years on
liquid crystalline
parliament networks and this was all and is the title of my lecture
let me briefly introduce
this lecture
with some
i suppose lights
i think
o quite well we
you all know
i think you all know robust
they everywhere they are used everywhere
but i think not all of you
really know these exceptional properties
of the conventional rubber
and how to describe such material
this decision for example might be such conventional rather
that you can get everywhere
and if you look at the chemistry of such a system it's prepared from
a matter of linear problem
and the amount of linear polymath is
cross linked to three dimensional pull in the network by a chemical reaction and then
you end up with the rubber
and this crosslinking reactions for example can be take place in the norman isotropic many
of the problem
and when you
at the change of the properties going from
the following are made to the polymer network
then at least the typical liquid
is not change if you look for the mobility of the single chain segments and
such a robot
it's the dynamics still remains essentially unchanged
but due to the three-dimensional
network of course football brownian diffusion is prevented
and you obtain material which resemble the properties of the solid
in other words you already have two interesting properties on the one hand side behaves
like a solid
on the other hand it behaves like a liquid
interestingly when you take such rather than when you make a deformation of the rubber
band you retracted
and this rate vector force can be simply described with
so thermodynamics hand for an idea one can say that this we expect the force
is simply given
by the change of the
with the deformation
in this way the description is very similar to that of a gas
well when you change the entropy of the system for example by by changing the
because here
on our task now is
to solve
differential equation
and that of course
you can do
three seconds
you recognise this differential equation
it is axed global got
plus something
times x
so the
the new frequency which i will call all got plus
new frequency omega plus
is the square of
of two
omega as square
was omega three
and what you see is something that i really anticipated this was consistent with intuition
it is larger than all because zero
because this is the effect of the spring
so omega zero is the one
and omega plus now
this grammar
omega as
squared loss omega zero
craig omega as
square is defined
this way
so if i now turn my to my
the general solution for now you accept the fact that
that is the general
solution the superposition
the normal modes
the key point is
that independent of your initial conditions
omega minus that was discriminative deal fell
i never reported any initial condition
independent of the initial condition omega plus that is what i never put any initial
it is independent of the initial conditions
is this ratio
which is plus one
independent of the initial conditions
this ratio
it is minus one
in other words if i didn't tell you the initial conditions which i haven't
i can predict
this ratio is plus one
and i can predict that this ratio is minus one
if i give this one
if i make these three and this is my three if i make this five
and this minus five
ratio is minus one
so ratios are independent of initial conditions
and the frequencies independent of initial conditions if i tell you the initial conditions then
of course you can also
the individual
suppose no
i start this system of
some way at time t equals zero which i can choose
and i choose the following
t equals zero
i make x one
just some number c
we can choose three centimetres whatever you want to choose
but i may be one zero
so as i release it
and suppose i make excellent
and i make the two zero
if you don't know what that means of course i'm going to demonstrate it it
means that this one
o one i offset this all i do and i let this one go
my hands off
and then i want to know what's going to happen
right because i release this one with zero speed
that's what you see there that is one of an infinite number of
initial conditions
that you
they choose
so this model has to be
substituted into my
general solution
so you have to take the derivative
x one so you have to
qx one got
put equal to zero
i leave that you're competent hands
then you have to take x two you have to take
x two
but you have to make that equal to zero and early that interview your competent
hands it's easy
and you will find them
in this particular case for this particular example
if i minus e equals zero
and phi two
and five plus
it will take you more than a few minutes
to find out
i didn't want to waste your time on taking the derivatives of such a simple
so if we take this
right now then i will substitute
these results in the equation so you did the hard work
you did the velocities i will do the position so i'm going to substitute in
that equation t equals zero i know already that the phi sign all there
and so then i get that c
time equals zero
it's going to be x zero minus
x zero minus
he is zero so this is why he is zero so this is why
plus axial plus
this initial condition
then i got to the second initial conditions zero
it's actually minus
x zero plus
minus sign
but what this high dimensional data started saying that in high dimensions
the prototype
is never going to be observed
because you always be corrupted
in the shell
some distance away from the prototype
which is kind of an odd thing
how does not go on so i suppose used you hear this nice thing okay fine
and people would prove things about it but i never had intuition so
this is an exercise in trying to understand the intuition and is based around the calcium echolocators another exercise
these are curse-of-dimensionality
exercises in the old bishop's book
and what i want you to show you see in this a one-dimensional egg and i'm showing
identity across this sick yellow in the middle is the yolk
and then the white on the outside is this development and then
i put a green that
right at the interface between the young
and now and the whiter egg
so green there is overboard during like a
some places do
you see on the outside it
the green covering its very iron sulfide and it's my eggs smell bad because they've
got sulfur them so the green there is no more than
it's got a relatively thin layer that makes a case bad actually so
you shouldn't over water x
on the
it's been boiled and way we set it up is that
the iron sulfide is between point nine five and one point o five standard deviations from the mean so between
ninety five percent and one hundred five percent and the standard deviation from the mean
so he looks up to that point nine five the standard deviation and the white
goes from one point o five to infinity this is a big
i mean what really would be a square density right so here with fitting a gas intensity across it
so that's one dimensional leg so if we look at the one-dimensional and we find
it's really nice could the yoke is my favorite the egg that's nice and running
in tasty and sixty five point eight percent your egg is the tasty bit okay
the why it is a more healthy it's got protein in twenty nine percent over
your egg is
so near close to thirty percent if your leg is protein and five percent vegas's
nasty iron sulfide that you don't like
okay so what happens in two dimensions you can compute these
volumes again the volume that's obviously a probability distribution so that the total volumes hundred
percent and in two dimensions you get sixty percent fewer actually you've lost five percent
i am seven point four percent zurich is now the iron sulfide and thirty three
percent thirty acres is now in the white
okay the reason right obviously because this high density here low-density here so even tho
you're sort of saying this is now
the viewer probably egg and this is a guassian x services higher peak is a
mountain bike there so there's more density in the middle and there's only outside
okay but now got three dimensions the density outside goes up a bit ten percent
the density is now in the science of i fifty six percent so we've lost
some of the
how does behave as we go higher and higher dimension
well the nice thing so we've seen this sort order but that's seems to be
going up white goes up yeah
you goes down and iron sulfide goes up so does not continue to be the case
well what it turns out is we can actually compute
the density where the probability masses
if as if we're thinking about this and in high dimensions all i'm doing is
i'm thinking of gas in distribution well i'm sampling independently across axes with a fixed
variance so that the variance the gaussians is sigma squared
what it turns out is the distance from the mean which is obviously from pythagoras
theorem the square root why i want plus why i to squared so his sample
one his sample to
that's where we are not that's distance from the mean yet so the distance is given by the square root
now i can't do much with the square root what you can but it's actually
easier to work with the square of the distance and that's gonna be an ongoing
in everything i do
so it turns out that the square
all this distance is kai's square distributed yes that's a statistical known
o thing
used quite a lot
so each of these samples their length is kai square distributed
so if you want the square
the distance of the whole thing is just the square error but
then is the sum of some kind i squared distributed
so that's rather nice
because it's analytics so
a year after being is
you see
it's just a sequence of integers edges
will define what the block and that is
you have pay attention because is sometimes keep
a blocked path
is about which contains
the following
and the surface
tail to tail or head tail
one of these
i mean
is that contains
are these
these these are this or
i had to
the tale tales
i had failed
head to head
or had
no which is not observed
not observe not conditions
not any of its this descendants is observed
so again let's let's go to the image
i have that
for example this path here
a e f b
OK the
let's cheque whether this is blocked or not
for this they have to be blocked
either of these two conditions
it has to hold
one or the other
i checked the first edition
these that has
an observer
it you know
they have an absurdity know
because it has an observer html
not by the way doesn't have any observed
is that it doesn't have any observable
so the first condition is not met
now let's check whether the second condition is met
must contain
h h and also had to have no
well the only has two has molding this that these
must contain has which is not also
this one is not observed
nor any of its descendants are observed or is same
doesn't satisfy the second condition idea
say again
g if if she was here
and then there was an arrow from j to be
because the bad ending b
not all if you consider the that
eight the change
then it's back
i will be blocked
you have a child
which is not observed
and and that suffices
and it's not observe big if there is no children this condition does not apply
if i had just one notion of this
there is one
the idea is that there's always something goes wrong in so that the issue 1st
start up work for for project is
if like does come where you're going to do to be ready in Howard you're
going to be ready now another another website that I used kind illustrate how to
solve the problem that another full life-cycle someone in small among is run by a
guy named Don Mccaskell who happens to museums on history or storage service and he
had a scaling problems like 2 years ago
In his problem was
that he had saturated in storage area network
now we was lucky and we launched Amazon history in the week that he had
the problem so he was able to deploy solution but if you think about it
you know some things you can't just throw money at us all into can't just
go down at the computer store and buy a new storage area storage area network
and plug it in and of course go problems not that simple
so you really have to to think about that
here's another
this was interesting in several ways 1st of all those 2 lines at the bottom
of the same 2 lines we just looked at
In the green line in this case is Facebook
I people in the room here have a Facebook account but case so that most
of you so I thought I think it's interesting on several fronts 1st of all
you can see that the portion here
it is however its servers fast enough to keep up with demand so this is
a different kinds of great kind of problem but it's still so where you're going
to come up with servers fast enough you know I we were going to order
the following is going to take to get here or you can argue with when
they don't show up on time or the truck
you don't get a bump in
they crashed over and decide on that broken on yet to bolt the man all
those problems you have to deal with
but it also shows something else that I I find fascinating above those of you
who have faced bitter Facebook users any of European like since the 1st stopped using
a case of some of the amendments but because I find this fascinating to which
is you know they had a big drop in traffic now interestingly it looks like
the story for all that
all the less than a grafted hadn't started but that brings up another issue and
I'm not saying that this is what happened Facebook it might be a glitch in
graft but
sometimes brevity sets in
and then we're going to do let's say for example you can see that's not
the case but let's say for example that the traffic was down here for the
war in state you for what you have to do with all that
your immediately big investors so that other thing to think about
and then finally I just shot I just this 1 the 2nd 1
now you can plan for the worst
now this 1 is interesting actually could you plan for it this is Mozilla that
comes the download site for Firefox and I would say that they're doing quite well
the black eyes
would you know you don't need all the server capacity here I really don't know
what this demand is going to be here so
you know if you only have integrated needs or in a case like this all
the doing his downloading maybe you really don't need a Web servers such a tall
but these were all the kinds of things that you need to think about
it when you're I've got plenty of
the project known
we didn't surveys him
inside and we talked to our project teams and we discovered that pretty much across
all of our product teams and so that about
70 per cent of their time was spent on these infrastructure issues
that I took that much time to negotiate data center space to line up the
server fleet to make certain the server showed up on the nature of the service
work when they showed up on bolt the Minnesota etc
this is we call this the monarch
In what we're saying here is that you shouldn't have to do this you know
this is a lot like job were like that when job net came along
you were able to do away with some of level
work that you step into writing code in C plus plus so now you don't
have to for example manage memory the idea of a little control but maybe that's
not a bad thing
but you're able to be much more productive and so the same it's basically the
same idea again this time infrastructure pockets so
I want to do is just surf through a few and certainly not all of
these Web services if I did we'd be here all nite but when going to
His talk a little bit about the infrastructures service appear in the left corner but
we have
a number of other services that I'm not going to touch on tonight unless somebody
really wants hear
any questions or at other ways and just an indictment
but they so the 1st like talked about in Amazon simple storage service otherwise known
as Arizona 3 not like all these Web services it's the 1st and foremost is
the weather service meaning that
there is an XML will request response protocol going across the wire so the idea
here is that when you push data into the club
the store DataClub the club really lands and an Sunday
and we knew pushed it into the cloud your making an authenticated our Web service
called using a public key private based on the show of hands at the most
of you already know that I'll ever get to create a signature Though the consists
of a pretty complex Hashim the name of a bucket in an object in the
API method you're calling time time live on the production but
the point is that people win this data lands in the Amazon data center it
works a lot like a rate that is that there's mobile no rules for the
Dayton strike across insider data center in the idea there
Is that if something happens inside our data center for example racked goes down or
something like that
you never see it
you never see a because just like reading the other parts were still the others
images are still available and you and I I we just make you know you
just get served the data and you're not even aware that we had a problem
behind the scenes and of course behind the scenes we do things like take the
defective Rakoff bring in a blank cracked revealed the status of its always available
all we take it 1 step further
we actually replicate the data center in real time so that the mobile
real-time data centers all synchronized with each other and that way
if there's a problem with the interrogators and so for example of somebody cut the
fiber in the parking lot were you know the switch to the data center goes
down something like that
you data is still available
and in separated into what we call availability not talking about availability is always a
bit more interested in something I don't want to do well on pricing because I'm
not here to sell you something here to tell you about the technology but I
really think I can't ignore it simply because this is like a 50 per cent
of what seems to be that people want
In excited about
all these Web services so the 1st pockets got people excited is the fact that
my god
it's too early to hear myself
which is not good for
so have figured it out yet
you could say that the good
all right well it turns out the
nice friendly people google provided the tool for us to be able to answer questions
like this
you know like all questions we go to google
the tool they provide it isn't just the plain google
there's there's something called google that which is in the google labs website is an
experimental tool not really meant for any
commercial purposes
and it's really fun cool so that
and you few items from the that of things
and then next press one of these buttons down here
and we'll try to predict other items in the that's OK
so we entergy
and darwin
we press one of these buttons
and here's the list that google comes up with
darwin g the
god will
downing curtain with the cavendish william the crime
king and corpus christi
most of you that says
but these are actually it turns out these are
the name of the college of cambridge university
cambridge happens to have college of darwin another college of jesus
and are my best guess is that there are a bunch of lists on the
web of
the names of colleges in cambridge
and what google that
it seems to be doing is finding those lists saying
there are two elements of this list
i can predict the other elements of the work
anyway i invite you all to play with google that it's a great tool it
works sometimes extremely well and sometimes the really don't work at all
but what it did was it made us think of the really i think interesting
machine learning and information retrieval problem
and this is
the problem that i can formally in the following way listing more abstractly
and imagine that
we have a universe of objects the
now i've shown you pictures of things like the yellow train car london by the
side centre
but i don't think of those pictures think of any kind of object you might
want to search for
the universe of items could be documents that could be
mp three
whatever you want
it could be a mixture of objects of different kinds
as long as there all represented in some common
four which is tricky if you want to represent documents and pictures the form
but you know you could imagine saying
maybe having a representation where there's the like this that the picture and then you
have got the picture features that doesn't have any document features or something like that
but that is the basic requirement is that all the objects should be represented in
some common space
we can think of this problem in several different ways one of the ways we
could think of it as clustering on the band so one thing you could do
the universe of of objects is run your favourite clustering algorithm right
but that's not really what we're interested in here
well we're interested in is the following question
given a query
which is
that our universe of items
like for example
the red car and the blue car
we want retrieval algorithm that will return a larger set
of our universe divided
it is a good generalisation of
this marks that that we gave the given red-carpet car we would hope that could
give us back
the cars
well given
redcar tomato we would hope that it could give back maybe the red object
and the basic idea the reason we could call the clustering on demand is that
we're trying to find the cluster right
but instead of being completely unsupervised what we do is
as a query we give it a few points that we
search belong to some cluster concept that we're interested in and we want the algorithm
to infer what other objects belong to that work on
and we can think of this is the problem of generalisation from a small set
of ideas
so the query is the set of items
the the the the meaning like cost cluster concept
and the information through method should rank other items x
by how well x fifteen with the query set
so imagine we now represented are objects in terms of some features based on measured
features of the object
and imagine that our query is
all of the blue object here the web two three four five six seven eight
and the
i don't we're trying to score if it here
we might think that it has that it doesn't seem to belong in the query
set that would here it might belong
in the group that so you prefer to read
this idea higher than the item
you want to know about them individually the case
so you like some that continually
the third dimension the process experience
look is often a small cross sectional
you might be more the end of longitudinal
that captures we think of a lot of studies that you can you can do
this is something that is still was still working on right now and this kind
not to talk about a very long something is going to be in the handbook
of mixed methods research second edition
so we still invite as we speak OK
it's just that we have to come up to point to answer to come up
with a inclusive model that includes all everything has been written about expected data analysis
across all the fields
i mean identified thirteen
kind of decisions
so this this diagram represents for decisions that you make
and when you do it makes analysis
so the top there
once you you know you've decided research goal objective research questions rational and so forth
it leads you to the
you know
how times that gonna collect
i gonna collect qualitative data
and qualitative data
or this one because you can actually do make a fist a funicular one time
but transport transformation
western michigan take place where you make those decisions
before the study begins to make all your decisions
during the study
or you can make some
the combination of that
what's your rationale and purpose using can actually agree with the person who opposed evaluators
is it to triangulate
triangulation means that you want to see if he is consistent
so you want to find out your political affiliation
i could give you some some scale that kind of tax that
based on political
philosophy i could also observe u
and so forth so many different ways and if the quality and the core data
give you the same conclusions
you can see the triangulated your data and that's one powerful way to mixed methods
triangulation number with this complementary to complement
OK one to cover the
number times initiation
that's look for contradictions and tensions so
and then after you feel get
according to maybe contradicted the quality
that's not bad news is often good news when you think some of the best
over time so my best
innovations of com
when there are contradictions
the first is i realized that the earth is not flat
that was really important decision
observations so
what's your mixed analysis philosophy
so four
if you were going down this
this map and of course it's much more obvious when you read the article that
space is those in detail
it should help you make
decisions that you need to do mixed analysis
again this is still work-in-progress it's
imagine it close to being the final form
as we speak french
as of the other chapters is about thirty seven chapters in the handbook on different
so it's very exciting
o come out next year
so we moved to sets ten and eleven
and that's legitimation thing that's really important that we always whatever study we do
we looked to legitimate findings
and we have come up with some different models to help you do that so
the quantitative way
you have
this builds on campbell and stanley
similar work with a identified intelligibility raises external validity
but one of the things we notice
in their work was that it was very much for psychology
so there are lots of things for example in education and other fields
that's when the california in the model havoc and it was really good luck criticism
it's just an observation
and i also get the impression that only
they tend to talk about in terms of experiments and you know experimentally so there's
only one type of quantitative design
so we try to to come up with something that is applicable to all these
are very descriptive of course compounded for
what have you
the other thing that we tried to do was to recognise
that validity
can look at different phases of a qualitative study
when during the data collection stage
the data analysis stage
and during their
interpretation stage
so is there with for example issue of mortality which asian people jumping out of
the study
that can happen to data collection stage agreed
people drop out for different reasons
OK belong to the study they die literally when you get tired only do anymore
they move
what have you
that's the more traditional sensory hair mortality
but another way more tightly could come to the fore as the data analysis
you may have the information
but for example you don't trust it
you think it might be an outlier
to use the researcher
decided to move it
OK so that decisions
could affect intelligibility
because if you if they
it should be removed is an outlier that's one thing but you might have an
extreme observation
when i worked for pfizer
we could never ever for our lives and that's obvious
would have to check and down
it doesn't matter what part of the country the where would have to to have
to go back to investigate and get them to find out whether the observation is
about it
because so in something out
actually turns out to be true observation could affect
information about that particular medication
in most of the food get sloppy so you just throw out you know
as a mixed methods research will go further
we would say that we should try out you should do qualitative
get quite information from all those we think liars
because i could speak sometimes be much more important find about people who don't fit
your model
the people for
military modifying
the column of you have in a in a good way
because that's how that works just has about fifty different sources consider
one source the camera standing consider which is really big and lava fields
it's something i call the nineteen seventy matlab implementation bias
the extent to which the intervention
is implemented in a good way in the way that is meant to be implemented
that's really really important consideration
to look at
if it's not
that can affect the internal validity
you have several example it in the top the top end there
to consider
ecological validity is a huge issue in political sciences you know
if you look at voting behavior depends for example
if it matters what part of the country region city look
because people often voting clusters
so there are lots of little things to look at
on both sides
you have measurements of those you know for the quality instruments
newsom essex
of konstanz construct and criterion
the book it down a bit further
into the different types
OK all subtypes
then qualitative legitimation to the same quality we went to the literature
and found what's out there in terms of ways to legitimate your findings
again we will give access to these articles
so population
yes i have the same CC population doesn't that some the quantitative
if your goal is to generalize
the population of the ties in qualitative that's not the go
if it is that then you look at that as a potential threat
the show you this some of that there
but now
this really should differentiate mixed methods for quantitative and qualitative
is that you not only have to consider the individual legitimation issues for the quantitative
phases and the qualitative phases
but first i want to continue the story
so the first thing is that we try to artificially generated is news data and
the idea is to assume that a given user
is this is one of the tricks people playing information retrieval because always have good
data to the experiment you to do so we assume that one user is interested
in one class only
what is unknown but these the label for the user so we assume that a
user is only interested in one of the classes
so we have ten thousand articles
as a lot of them belong to more than one class we generate four hundred
sixty artificial users by choosing at random set of the positive and negative examples
for every user
and the goal is to predict the probability that a user like a new article
which is
and the plot shows we rain
all the unseen articles in the dataset
and select the
and highest rate articles it's like search engine you get the highest ranked on the
first page
and that just shows how many of the top and read articles
actually positive
but truly belong to the class which this user of belong
here some results for the experiment where
the active user
has seen five ratings has done five ratings people
so now
we present the sixth grade for him we want to because of the way
and here's the top and so typically what is that only ten of five
article to him so he left and so this is a content based approach every
individual has its own model performance well
i was this is the this is the one that one this is an i
was based collaborative filtering and here the
the features which essentially what what counts documents a quite strong social content based approach
is better than a collaborative approach but this
well i mean this
usually process mixture model but both so this would mean that if i present
five items ninety percent of them would be in the right
well such as use assumed like
news articles out of his own class
and there a couple of them from the same class
but the first is unknown to us that this has one
he was
from there we assume that each user has one reference in terms of the class
so in this sense
so that is why it is a little bit you know it's one thing to
the chilean andes property of the experiments that led the real world
it was very difficult to get is that
in the second experiment we have
this is a great painting
you set this up to sixty four two images
and nineteen
it's not just the average
the features are low level features describe the images
o four four
getting in the high dimensional feature space in this
but they are obviously not very strong indicators of the fact like it's not so
in the first year the features and by the
again we want to highest-ranked pictures and other members of a lot because i'm great
pictures system to be in the negative class
and put get something that only
now these two
life change order
so this is what level of
the political
is about the size and invested
but in our article which could still
exploit this
the fact was
is also a plus
as well as the fact that they i don't want to get the message here
what but it's actually shows that this satisfies the fact by the fact that
this is true
he said
because i made a mistake
i mean what i believe that this is a list of
a lot of one
so that they can
the only thing later
this is part of
so that of
this the
he did the setting
this was the start of the
and this
you have to do
some of the the law
sorry for the