sixteen minus one
i actually represent
negative to the fifteen and negative fourteen thirty two forty five hundred ninety two to
fifteen to two fifteen one is one that makes sense and everything centered around zero
so i was just as many representations for negative numbers as i have positive
makes sense
OK so let's start doing some really simple code not the code normally right sometimes
you do not very often which is to understand what happens when you do something
like this
the hard variables
c h and i said it was capital
and then i have been very called i actually making a short
as i said it was clear you don't need cast for that
what you really doing it just sitting as equal to whatever number is backing chr
question there
o o
o i just wrong to either and i said you would i wanted this just
didn't change the drawn word
OK so i did not want to this year
but in the composition of the time i thought it was
OK this makes sense to people
certainly that's going to compile and it's going to execute and based on the other
seven borders drawn and you should have some idea as to what's going to happen
in response to this line
printer press the equivalent of a cl statement
but it's in pure c
and i want to print out short
actually limits UCL
western less as less than last year MDL
in response to that i expected to print out the number sixty five
so to the console i would expect that to be printed why is that the
case because the declaration c h
doesn't put capital in there
it puts the
the integer valued that's it
which i will draw that small you know really one zeros and so one time
for you to assign to
that's what happens
in order to achieve the effect the assignment it will copy this pattern and this
is what really does electronically it just replicates whatever bit patterns right here
on the that space right there some years these bits on the this little by
like peanut butter
and sixty five down there and all the extra space
it's just patterns in this case with zero and so that's how sixty five goes
from a one but representation two two by representation
that makes sense
i simplified this a little bit
when it was sixty five down here
and is sixty five and there i happen no that the leftmost bit
it is zero there
it's positive numbers that to surprise OK
the matrix people
what happens if i do
the opposite direction
i do
so we're not
short polymer
programme as is equal to also sixty seven
and i do that
it compiles there's no cast needed
as far as how the sixty seven is laid down
zero one zero zero zero zero one one
two more than sixty five obviously
it has an extra by of zero
and this is as someone CA schizoid and memory
and it is signed as
two by information and sixteen bits can not somehow be wedged astronomically into an eight
bit pattern
so what you see in c plus plus in many programming languages for that matter
do is they simply punt on the stuff they don't have room for
and they assume that if you're signing a large number two is smaller one and
the smaller ones can only accommodate has a certain ring device in the first place
that you're interested in the minutiae of the lower bits
so make sense to people
so what happens is that replicates this right here
and once on this and this is how when you do this right
OK you go ahead and you print out
a c
OK now i'm kind of a borehole negative number fine but negative negative values don't
work to all characters because unsigned cars
most characters are unsigned so you actually do get all positive values in with the
representations you know enough about shorts
to know the two by figures i've already told you that long interlaced in our
world or four bytes to just the four by equivalent of the short
so let me deal with this example
i go ahead and i do short
and is equal to on to say
when we this way now the not longest-running this
two return was to very close to the year that of course is not real
see but is running because i want to be clear about what the bit pattern
for numbering statistical whatever number that adds up to
as being stored in as
OK this is to be a to one zero zero here by all zeros parts
of zero
one zero zero one
by taking in the city called as
the same argument that i made in the car to short assignment
it can be taken here
this is found this is somehow less surprising because both of them represent integers is
all zeros all zeros
lots of zeros followed by one zero zero zero zero zero zero one zero
and that's why does have a lot more space to represent the same small number
trick question
but in i equal to i have thirty two bits available to me to represent
a pretty big numbers
so do that
two to the
twenty third of two the twenty first wants to the fifty
plus let's say
OK to be quite
the liberal in my
power of two
representations numbers because seven always means that the body
OK to the fifty pieces of one right there
to the
so we're where we time last time
they had discovered the radiation and going back to lecture four notes because i think
i have a little bit the last time lecture four notes
we discovered that the radiation
behaves like a particles
and it behaves like a particle as exhibited in the the photoelectric effect
that is in order to get an electron out
what we needed to do was to put our article
of energy we needed to put up a packet of energy we need to put
up wants
and energy
and as long as
quantum of energy packet of energy particle of energy
it was larger than the work function we would get
one electron out for every packet we put in
so that's an example of the particle like nature to radiation this for electrical that
right but
i i also
when i to show
even more
convincing property
the particle like nature of radiation are full-time
and that is the and he showed
a photon has momentum
even though for time
does not have a mayor
four essentially no rest
and of course momentum is very particle like property right
comments from hey
four moments
it is equal to the mass times velocity
if a particle
or if the photo
if radiation has momentum well
acting very much like the particle
right how you do this well
einstein took the relativistic equations of motion which he himself wrote down
and what he showed from there
is there a full-time
here and momentum p here
and the moment some of the photo
was defined by
the frequency of the radiation
that is that moment of which is given by h
again one constant fear that quantization constant
times the frequency
over the speed of light
and since of course we know the relationship
between the
frequency and wavelength
we can write the momentum of the photon
and he
over lambda
so if you have radiation
of some wavelengths lambda one
the radiation
both both times
at this moment some eight
over lambda this photon momentum even though photons don't have their
and the actual demonstration of this took a few more years experiments we took a
few more years
and it was demonstrated
first in something called the and that
which was the interaction of an x-ray photon with some matter
and you could see it transfer momentum
i got to show you a this website from the university of colorado
here this is just a a
you know time down here shooting photons and here is the enemy and i'm coming
at you
and you're shooting this vote and then turned you can repel that the have make
it go the other direction because the photo and at the moment because of the
momentum of the photon
but of course if you
lower the power and you're not really good with your fingers you get clobbered right
so here now i'm going to try this again this is goal
almost too easy
OK so now i will or the power so that the rate of the photons
are coming
much slower and i'm going to be able to turn this guy around
no problem there we go
repel the right off
so if it really is the case that means you can get it here
i i would say well you we better game that i am
it was it's just that number what i'm showing you here
they have to lead to
the experimental feeding of atom traffic
no tracking and adam in space
how they do their well what they did was they took some unsuspecting yet
and they came in with
full-time laser beam high power laser beam
erected in this way and of course there
push the atoms they pushed them down
but now if you come in
with the laser beam in that direction all the photon momentum going to push the
enemy up now you constraint in this dimension
and you do it
another laser beam this way and another one this way and i constraint in this
dimension you the laser beam in this way and always has been playing constraint on
the third dimension eight
he's trapped in the anime in space
the photon momentum
this is what the chewing and inferred and bill phillips next
i did are in the middle nineteen nineties and see the nobel prize for this
atom trapping here
in nineteen seventy seven know nineteen ninety seven sorry
a photon has momentum
and the reason this is so important to reason this experiment was also so important
is because
it is the first
and producing a bullseye einstein condensate
above einstein condensate
where you take
and and don't which has
which is the balls and actually
and new cool it down
such low temperatures
that they can dance
that these items then
so you've got to cool it down very much so you have to get to
the micro kelvin range
and the first thing cooling in and down this
so the problem with this is that this subject here
it is not very well behaved because it's it's it's discrete
and so
you don't become perform gradient descent in all sorts of things and that's what people
have been replacing the subject but other objectives for example the sum of the absolute
values of the WI which people called the the l one norm of some kind
of differentiable function
that uses
that performs basically the same thing
and so then minimize johnson it the primary the second of the secondary objective
one very popular
algorithm that uses this principle is the so-called and one SVM
and it's a version of the SVM where the musician of the square numbers being
replaced by the
minimisation of the one norm so the sum of the WI
and so it can be considered in some way in embedded method because
it returns in the end
predictor that gives you a prediction on
a new examples if you want and it also returns
a certain number of
the features that have not been discarded because some of the weights will
be exactly zero
so the difference between the regular SVM
and the other one is the and is that the algorithm drives the sum of
the weights to zero
so how how does this happen it's not always very intuitive to understand so have
a mechanical interpretation
yes thank you for clarifying that it true that this this particular algorithm works for
only linearity
on this figure illustrating
the classical way in which we view
regularized optimisations
we think of them as minimizing the cost functions
plus long that some regularizers
and in this figure here i'm showing two on two weights w one and w
assume that the
the optimal solutions
without regularisation is called w star
and we assume that you have a quadratic
objective like for instance what you doing
in rich regression
in this case
as you go away from the optimal solution
you go up in in the probability
and the regularizer
can think can be thought of as the spring
your solution to
zero with the spring strength of long
so this is the classical way people
usually a few regularisation
now you can
you can change the way you're thinking instead of thinking you know we want to
minimize its primary objective which is to the original objective function this function plus summarize
the primary objective is not the regularizer which is that in the case of the
one norm minimize the sum of the double
these are in the the case of the so-called zero anomaly minimize the number of
this is now
a primary objective plus whatever and
the old primary objective which is really your prediction error
you can represent it in the same way except now the ball you know is
drive your to zero and the what your spring is what
you to your solution
so i i doing this crazy thing was just because it's easier than to understand
what the one norm SVM and the lasso does so the last so
is to the one norm SVM
basically the last was the this square version of the one norm is
the ridge regression is the
this version of the
two enormous and the last so is the
one of reason version
one version of the regression case
i'm just saying that rather than the classification problem because for
again the mechanical interpretation since it's easier to understand
so what you see in the case of the one norm
is that again results weights w one w two
and now
or regularize which was before to no answer was kind of problem now it's the
because of the absolute value
and the other part of the objective is the same as before is this spring
that flows into the solution
so imagine that you have to be done in you know big box and you
have some force
which is the spring here that the tools will be
if you you know you you shake a little bit you know box
what's going to happen is that you will be is going to rule somewhere to
pool of course but by of course
and we're going to end up going to professional you end up on the face
or in on one hand showing corner easily see that you can easily slide into
either an edge or into a corner
and this is what happens in this optimisation was the one norm
what happens is that you end up
the solution that is on one of the axis
most of the large fraction of the of the weights are going to be exactly
zero in that solution
but the does this is not the because if the both zero
you are what we call the prime maximum
one is the first time that this one becomes zero in the downstairs not zero
it is when this is why
and it is zero then goes
and that's why
then of course
i would have my first zero so that the that year
that my first
that is the case
when n
divided by two is by
so that means when delta
divided by
now i go to
this equation
and i put your for delta
two pi
divided by n
and what you see that
that sin theta
becomes lab divided by
is now
that divided by andy
in other words this point here
in terms of sin theta which of course is the same as angle
data in radiance because these angles are small
but it isn't
i mentioned plot
so this year land
divided by andy
and then of course the second one will be twice led the divided by and
and the third one will be three times led by the by and you will
again have
completely destructive
you may be interested
in what
magnitude is looking like intensity i should say is of this little minimax
well that's very easy to calculate
if we know that the sign of theta year is land that divided by andy
and we know that he would is twice that much
and all i have to ask the creation
what is your light intensity
when the sign of data as soon as we go to
the minimax
the first minimax
right here
so i asked equation
what you intensity when the sign theta
is now
one point five times land
divided by and the
then i'm
right in in between these two zeros
what i'm exactly on the maximum i don't know and they were not interested but
i'm sure you close
when sin theta is one of eleven divided by the
and delta
it's going to be three by
divided by n
that's easy because you take this equation one and have left over and
point einstein one and have learned that divided by andy to one times to become
i again and downstairs so you get
delta is three by dividing by
now you revisit this equation
and you just put in there
n equals four
you know capital and
none of delphi's we calculate the upstairs you calculated downstairs
and you will find now that i
it is approximately one point one seven i zero
that flow compared to sixteen
this is only some seven percent
six point eight percent
so this height was only seven percent of that it's very low
so you see now
these are consequences
but if you get zero by zero you get these maximized sixteen i zero
then you get and minus one point about you get complete zeros here but even
these winning maximum
we very much they are very low
in light intensity
and even if you go to an n of one thousand
and today we believe go beyond that was our experiments have capital and go up
to two thousand
if you make capital and one thousand you can we do all this
you'll will see that there's many maximum is roughly four and a half percent of
its maximum that maximum now becomes a million times i zero
if you have thousands of these openings
they will add up to the maximum you get a million times the intensity that
one alone would
the reason is obviously you get a thousand times the vector and they're all in
phase with each other and and the poynting vector is the square of the amplitude
of effect you get real
all these maximum
have the same weight
and if this is land that divided by and the
and this here on this site
bilayers in the plasma membrane and just allow for the passive diffusion
of a an iron through them through the donut hole
and enabling an iron
so if use the lipid bilayer
not trying to do things these kinds of doughnut shaped protein aggregates will allow
the passage of ions in one direction or another
and here energy is not being expanded to enable this passage it may just be
by through diffusion
but if there is a higher concentration of iron once i loved by lower one
on this site
this is the diffusion will allow the iron to migrate through the the bore of
the ion channel from one side to the other
in fact even though this does not involve the expenditure of expenditure of energy by
a part of the cell
the cell may actually use the gating mechanism to open or close these channels
with the tails are close to ions cannot move through
when the channels are gated open then diffusion can take over and ensure the transfer
the transportation of ions from one side to the other
having said that
we can begin to look at other higher level
here by the way it is a better drawing in the one i provided you
this is comes from your book
of what of what they are
vesicle looks like
here's what it looks like under the electron microscope and here's what it looks like
when a talented rather than hapless and hopeless artist like myself tries to draw
let's just say that intro into
lipids and membranes
and let's move on to the next layer of complexity
and the next layer of complexity in terms of molecules represents carbohydrates
and then we talk about carbohydrate amongst ourselves we're talking about a molecule which roughly
as one carbon atom for every
water molecule
and certainly indulge ourselves in talking about all kinds of different carbohydrate molecules
here is really one of the most important carbohydrate molecules glucose
and what should we note about glucose well the first thing you should sees the
glucose has six
carbon atoms and therefore as a consequence it's called a hexose
we're going to talk about pantos is very shortly they only have five to state
the obvious glycerol which we talked about before is also considered one sensor carbohydrate but
it's only a
it's been called by some people
a trial still only has three carbon atoms
and you can imagine therefore in principle
that there are certain biochemical mechanism which indeed exists
which enable the wonder join two
glycerol molecules one to the other to create something like a texas
in fact what we see from this drawing expertly drawn by yours truly
is that the hexose molecule is really a linear molecule
in solution
what happens is that the because of various staring and thermodynamic forces it likes to
cycle eyes
let me just mention i just use two words that are useful to know about
four stereo chemistry refers to the three-dimensional structure of the molecule and obviously the stereo
chemistry of of the molecule is dictated by the flexibility with which participating atoms can
form bonds
whether we have tried a vaillant adam like nitrogen or or tetravalent and like carbon
or model they look like hydrogen
and these structures the stereo chemistry is dictated
both by
by what i happens to present here by thermodynamic considerations which cause this particular hexose
indeed virtually all hexose is to
cycle i
when i six cycle is obvious i mean to form a circular structure
here we note one thing you can see how
the hydroxyl here actually attacks the positively charged carbon here in order for this cyclic
you see one of the six points on this
take hexagonal structure is
is oxygen is not is not carbon at all
so there's one oxygen and five carbons and one of the
carbon is relegated is
is exiled to outside of the size of the
this circle is sometimes called an extra cyclic
because it sticking out from the actual circle
and this is the structure where in which glucose actually exists inside cells
and in fact there
there is in truth two alternative ways by which glucose can cycle is where the
oxygen attacks the car the carbon on the common group underneath or on top and
you see that gives us
two alternative structures
what's different about them
well if we think about this axis is existing in the plane
is where the hexagon is in the plane in this case the oxygen is above
the plane and the hydrogen is below the plane
with equal probability you can have these two
the two atoms reverse right is now
above the plane and hydroxide is below the plane
in both of these structures these alternative structures can fairly be considered to be glucose
let's get a little bit more complicated
here we have fructose and we have galactose
what we see here is by the way that we have exactly the same number
of carbon atoms and hydrogen atoms oxygen atoms but they looked up slightly differently
and here now we began to get get very
the disposition the orientation all these different kinds of hydroxyl and hydrogen and no by
the way that many cases one doesn't even put in the age for the hydrogen
is just implied by this
the end of this line
and here we if you were to look at this you see here now we
have two extra cyclic carbons
here's galactose
which is yet another hexose these are all accesses but there's stereo chemistry
creates a quite different kinds of structures
and it turns out that the stereo chemistry is extremely important
these molecules function very differently one from the other
and for example to the extent that glucose is used in different kinds of energy
metabolism and to the extent of galactose is not
there must be certain biochemical mechanisms
in which one has catalysts catalysts that we call enzymes
that ensure that one can convert
one of these hexose is
through an enzyme
in two let's say a useful less useful ones into more useful one glucose which
can readily be burnt up
by the energy generating machinery
here we're gone yet another order of magnitude more complex
because we've gone from model satirized right i mean one or another hexose
two dice right and here's common table sugar
and here you see that it's form
once again through an esterification reaction
i e there is a dehydration reaction between
this hydroxyl here
and this hydroxyl here
and biochemist take the orientation of these hydroxyl groups very seriously
you can say that there a bit obsessive
attractive women with a tale of a fish as described and represented by the
later tradition but nasty rapacious birds
and there was Priaphus
who was considered ridiculous because of that huge member that was not
thought to be handsome and was defined as amorphous
without form
as ugly icecrown was not
he had not the correct form he was oppressed by loneliness and his incapacity to seduce
a nymph dependent of his hypertrophic possibilities
to the east
even tough the history of literature is full of descriptions of ugly men
there is another interesting aspect of ugliness which is the vituperation with regard
to women
whose ugliness reveals their inner malice and pernicious powers of seduction and that
was a theme that enjoyed great success
so it happens so in the classical literature Horus Catullus and Marshall
had already provided us with the repulsive portraits of women and in the early
Christian literature the problem of cosmetics scrubbed up with Tertullian who remarks with ruthless severity that
according to the scripture the allurement of beauty are always as one with
the prostitution of the body
and apart from moral condemnation Tertullian is insinuating that women plastered themselves with
make up and other artifice to conceal their physical defects
in the middle ages there were many portrayals of the old women as symbol of
physical and moral decay and the acme of misogyny was reached in Boccaccio's Corbaccio
the narrator loves
are unrequited the beautiful widow and his evident resentment is expressed by the
soul of her husband that asends from purgatory to
tell the narrator about the licentiousness and the perfidy of these woman revealing
that she conceals her fifthy years with creams and other revolting mock and dwelling at length upon
the disgusting decays of her physical ugliness
during that's Leonardo the Renaissance female ugliness became the subject of lampoons
containing ironic praise of models that didn't conform to the dominant aesthetic
and let me only quote
in translation obviously these nice verses of Clement Marot on two ugly tits
tit that is nothing but skin scrawny flat limply flapping big tit long tit
squashed tit tit like a bun tit with a pointy nipple like the sharp end of a funnel
you jounce about at every move without any need for a shake toasted tilt tit
hanging tit wrinkled tit tit that gives mud instead of milk the devil wants you
in its infernal family to nurse his daughter tit to be thrown over one shoulders and so
on and so forth later in the baroque period a woman's imperfection
were describe described as an element of interest
sometimes of a sexual stimuli
poems appeareed in praise of women who stammered or were dwarfs hunchbacks cross-eyed bock market
and in contrast to the medeival tradition of highly coloured or rosy cheeks Marino has stolen
the palour
of his beloved I want I want to
Giambattista Marino to read it first in Italian because I find it very beautiful
pallidetto mio sole
ai tuoi dolci pallori
perde l’alba vermiglia i suoi colori
pallidetta mia morte
a le tue dolci e pallide viole la porpora amorosa perde vinta la rosa
oh piaccia a la mia sorte
che dolce teco impallidisca anch’io
pallidetto amor mio!
oh one little sun of mine the bright red dove loses its corals
before your sweet pallor
oh dear palid death of mine vanquished the rose loses its red amorous
colour before your sweet and palid violets oh let it please destiny that I might
become as palid as you my sweet love
but probably the most grotesque celebration of the female ugliness is to be
found in the Anatomy of Melancholy by Robert Burton
love is blind as the saying is cupid's blind and so are all his followers
Quisquis amat ranam ranam putat esse Dianam every lover admires
his mistress tough she be very deformed of herself ill-favoured wrinkled pimpled pale red
yellow tanned tallow
tallow-faced have a swollen juggler's platter face or a thin lean chitty face have clouds in
her face be crooked dry bald goggle-eyed blear-eyed or with staring eyes
she looks like a squis'd cat hollow-eyed black or yellow about the eyes
squint-eyed, sparrow-mouthed, Persian hook-nosed, have a sharp fox nose
red nose China flat great nose a nose like a promontory
rotten teeth black uneven brown teeth beetle browed witch's beard her breath stink
all over the room her nose drop winter and summer with a Bavarian poke under her chin a sharp chin
lave eared with a long crane's neck her dugs like two double jugs or else
no dugs in that other extreme bloody fallen fingers she have filthy long unpared
nails scabbed hands or wrists a tanned skin a rotten carcas crooked back she stoops
is lame splay-footed as slender in the middle as a cow in the waist
so set
and more relevant here
this the convex hull
of rays
upward pointing race
in the convex hull of those of the union of those
i can't tell of the union of those
it is
a b epigraph
polyhedral function which in that approximates
a a a a a multiplicative function
so that's the idea of innovation approximating the epigraph by convex hulls of race
given a function h
and given a finite set of points we form this race
we take the convex hull
in the convex hull defined
upon hill function
was epigraph
in that approximates the epigraph of h
this is just terminology
let me just remind you also definition conjugacy
given a function f is closed lower semicontinuous
it's possible to take the epigraph and approximated by half spaces
corresponding to
and the intersection of all this approximately half spaces
it gives you
the graph of the function
and if you consider this have spaces in new parametrized by the slope
you get
conjugate function so by definition the conjugate functions like this given f
age of y
is a function of the slope defined like so
the graphical interpretation here
in the country to provide us with an alternative view of the same functions the
nice thing is that we have this conjugacy theorems
which says that the conjugate of the conjugate is the original
no information is lost by passing the conjugate you can recover the original
and that's all nice and
and the and helpful
there's also another interesting relationship which i'm going to use in my talk subgradient duality
if y is the slope of ax of
then x is the slope at y
o h
OK this an if and only if relations
so slow in b
correspond to points of contact in the
in in the conjugate in the inversely
and finally here's the conjugacy relation that's very important
suppose you have a function f
this curve function here is to have its conjugate h
suppose we make out the linearisation of f by subgradients
then the conjugate of this afternoon innovation is an intermediate station
and conversely and in the unionization of some function gives you when conjugated
the other linear decision will quench
furthermore you have that subgradients in the linear in other decision breakpoints in in the
linear position and so on
finally note that
the linear decision functions are real valued or finite
and out there in a linear decision functions are called find meaning that the conjugate
is real right
OK let me remind you also what the classical cutting plane method is
we have
we have a number of points x zero up to k
and the number of subgradients and we have this
subgradient approximation
and then we minimize success the the submarine approximation the other this other thing station
and then go up to the original function and pick up the slope and we
add this
two v
linear decision
and i find it so
as an example of iterations we're minimizing here the function f over these constraints
and we have let's say two points one
subgradients we minimize this we obtain this point qx x two
and once we have it we differentiate and we obtain the new slope and we
have the
playing with cutting plane to the
keep going into the classical cutting plane method has many many applications in large scale
optimisation including dancing will composition
and many others
OK now decomposition mechanism of methods
and not much has been done
with recently
like i said to be one of the original contributors
and i asked what has been done to measure the composition is it says nothing
has been done for the last twenty years however even though people don't work on
a very much it has carbon h
in certain types of large scale problems including
i plebeian problems that involve a huge dimension
multicommodity flow problems in there is really the method to use
and here's how it works
we minimize f
all the constraints that
and here we keep f untouched but we
in the linear arise the constraints
the incident angle
of fado one
some of it is reflected
this angle is also say that one as we discussed earlier
and some of it is refracted into this medium
this angle will call
theta two
so disliked unpolarized comes in
and reference
if you want to use maxwell's equations
at the action where everything is happening right here at the service between the two
you'll have to
decompose the incoming light
the electric field vector
in two
in one direction
is perpendicular to the blackboard so this is the vector
and the other direction
is in the blackboards
you have to do the same year
and if you look at this decomposition
and then notice
that both components this component
as well as this component
is perpendicular to the direction of propagation that's always must was travelling electric
never great you see the same year
this component and this both perpendicular to the reflected beam
this component and this both perpendicular to the it
this one
the one perpendicular to the blackboard
we normally give simple perpendicular
recall this the incidence playing
the playing field incident light and the normal to the surface we call that the
incident plane in this place
in this case it is the blackboard we call this the perpendicular component and we
call this the parallel component
and this is of course the incident beam
this one called the perpendicular component
there's one called parallel component
and this is now of the refractive
this is the parallel component this is the perpendicular component of the re collective
the incident light
it's not polarized
in this sense
so if you
then there is no preferred direction
of the electric field
that means and that in this representation
the strength of this component
and the strength of this component must be exactly equal
because if one were stronger than the other
then it wouldn't be
unpolarized then there would be
on average preferred direction
so this component has the same strength is that component forty incoming light
well maxwell's equations now can do for us
so a lot of work
you may see the NATO three
it can relate
the parallel component in reflection
with the parallel component of incident
the parallel component of refraction
was the parallel component of incidents give you two relations took two
it can also relate the perpendicular component of reflection
with this perpendicular component
and the perpendicular component in refraction
with this component so you get four
in this light that comes in is unpolarized
the strength of this component is the same as this one
in general you will see if you applied for equations that that's no longer the
case where there are no longer the same intensity and there are no longer the
same intensity here
that means this reflected light
and the refracted light has now become partially
i will only give you the relations one of those four equations
i will only address today
the parallel component of the incident beam
in the parallel component of the reflected
and i don't imagine anyone of you will try to remember that equation i don't
have to look it up every time
then i deal with this
so he zero it's always represents the maximum possible value of the electric field
of the parallel component
of the
the reflected beam
that's the one
but i'm after going to make polarized light
by reflecting
it is zero
the parallel component
of the incident beam
this depends now on the angle of incidence
and on the indices of
it's going to be an one
time the cosine
if theta two
miners and two
the cosine of theta one
but even after all this follows from maxwell
divided by n one
i'm the cosine
of the two
and two
times the cosine
theta one
and if you apply snails law
you can simplify this equation
in this case
it will help us
so you get minus
he zero
incidents and now you get get the tangent
of data one
you might say that two
divided by the tangent
of theta one
plus they two
these two equations are identical may not be obvious to you
certainly not obvious to me either but if you substitute
south line here
you can show that these two
i the same
keep in mind if you ever interested in the intensity of these lights
you must always remember
that the poynting vector is proportional to the zero square
so you always have to square these numbers when you're interested
in light intensity this is just the strength of the vector
there's something very special hidden in this equation
that's when theta one
plus two
is ninety degrees
and the downstairs here is infinitely large
so that means
the parallel component in reflection
it's zero
so he
in reflection
goes to zero
and if everyone goes to zero
there's only this one left which is not zero
and that means the reflected light is now one percent polarized in this direction because
i have killed this component completely but it only works if this is met this
this condition is met that fate along
let's say that two is ninety degrees
and it follows from high school math
that the sign of
data two is then the cosine
of the the one that immediately obvious right you remember
the triangle
they want to say that was ninety degrees
the sign one angle
the cosine of the other
and if no
remember smells law
which says that the sign
of theta one
divided by the sine
of data two
if n two defined by one
i can replace now only for this special case the sign of
now come on the chance of that that all the copies they would mutate back
months i mean you can repeat several times and this is always what happens
what does that tell you about this mutation in the virus
the notion of the virus
because it always mutation it would be transmitted through
but as a constrained a
makes it loses its ability to grow on strain b
but as i was passing through strain b it can grow in strength
this is not
typical genetics
to south were a lot of this he really worked out what was going on
well so anyway they refer to this as a strain b
having the ability
two restrict
the growth
of the virus
strain b can restrict the growth of the virus
that's where this word restriction enzyme comes from
what's really truly going on here
underneath the shaggy dog story took a long time before the shaggy dog story that
salvatore loria was once really
a demonstrate
i was fully worked out but what turns out to be the case
is that strain b
a restriction enzyme that's how it restricts the growth
it has one of these enzymes that can cut DNA
at a specific place
when the virus comes in
to strain b
injected DNA
and the enzymes
comes along
and cuts the viruses DNA
protecting the bacteria
it's got its own little defense mechanism
pretty cool
so any DNA that introduced
if it has the sequence here it's a GA TTC the the better cuts
the bacteria has its own DNA
what is in the shop of its own chromosome
well i mean maybe so we know what simple possibility would be that
if this thing is looking for the sequence GATTACA
in the genome
maybe it's the case
the bacteria has range that it's all DNA
never has the g eight TTC
be simple solution right
but is it plausible solution one
which is statistically how often do you expect to encounter GATTACA
what's what's the frequency of of any given six letter word in a four letter
about one in forty six
it's about one in four to the sixth positions will be GATTACA and that's about
four thousand letters
so every four thousand letters i expect to encounter GATTACA how big is the e
coli genome four million letters so how many GAT disease will there be
about one thousand of them
it's just not possible to imagine
that it doesn't have the sites
so your idea is that if it has these sites it's got arranged to protect
its own sites
so how's protected sites
composite or something where you could can imagine composite or something that you want you
want to alter your own site so it turns out you're exactly right what happens
is there is an enzyme that comes along and at this position
it modifies the DNA
modifies the DNA
by attaching the math or
it turns out that methyl group is enough to prevent the restriction enzyme from bind
so this blocks the restriction enzyme
so that way the bacteria is able to distinguish between its own DNA which is
methylated and the viral DNA
so it so happens that explain my virus that managed to grow
my virus managed to grow
it would need to have gotten itself modified also be protected
could that happen by chance
what is the methylation enzyme
the math always
which is floating around in the cell
so that we could quotes
methylated the viruses DNA
what happened then
the virus to become immune
so you so so suppose the virus bacteria is pretty clever
and i had a lot more restriction enzyme and only a little bit of is
well imagine that most of the time the restriction enzyme would cut up the viral
DNA first
but every once in awhile
the marseillaise would get there first
and protect the viruses DNA
that becomes an immune virus
because it can be cut by the enzyme anymore
and if i take that on again on strain b
it will now produce artifacts because he was mentally
and i brought again on strain b
forgot downstream it remains mentally because what misleading comes into the cell is not cut
and so its descendants will get level
but what happens if i ever wrote virus
now related virus strain a
strain it doesn't have the restriction enzyme and it doesn't have the math always
so the progeny phage to grow strain a
we are now fully
there are no longer protected
the protection that the virus has is the protection that comes from this methylation enzyme
it's not the sequence of DNA
it's the attachment of methyl groups and so it turns out that if you ever
pass this virus through strain a
passage through strain a
the resulting DNA
is on mandolin
and now
it can be cut
and it can be cut
well this explain the weird results of glory
that somehow bacteria
had a complex defense mechanism of the restriction enzyme and cognate monopolies
the restriction enzyme would cut the sequence chromosome would be protected by manipulating that site
and usually works fine occasionally of bacterial virus would get methylated it would be protected
as long as it continues to go through strains that have this restriction appellation system
that was now the shaggy dog story took a couple of decades to work out
and eventually led to the nobel prizes for the discovery of restriction enzymes there extremely
important because
although bacteria do this to protect themselves they have also given us the perfect tool
to now
with the same equation we started with
what is the point
the point of having done all this was because now
the left hand side is
exactly the derivative of something and the left hand side is should be the derivative
of well it should be the derivative of one plus cosine x times y all
now projected that in fact the case is 1 was cosine x y prime plus
minus sign x the derivative of this flight times Y.
if you have a lot in looking at the equation to save yourself this is
the derivative of that maybe I'll just check right away to see if it's the
derivative of one plus cosine x i know you would have say that on
well you know that gradient of clever anything like that you do it
you can follow your nose and it's just I want to give you a positive
experience in solving linear equations not to negative anyway so we got to this point
so this is to actually now we're ready to solve the equation which is of
the solution now will be 1 plus cosine X times Y is equal to x
squared plus the constant and so why is equal to
x squared divided by the x squared plus the constant divided by 1 plus cosine
X I suppose I'm giving you initial to an initial condition which I didn't but
I suppose the initial conditions so that y 0 1 where 1 for instance then
the solution would be so this therefore I'm throwing it at the end just to
make it a little bit more a problem how I put then I can evaluate
the constant or by using the initial condition what would it be this would be
on the left hand side 1 on the right hand side would be C over
2 so I would get 1 equals C over 2 is that correct cosine of
0 is 1 so that the down below therefore
C is equal to 2 and that would wouldn't complete solution will be x squared
plus 2 over 1 plus cosine x now let's see what you can do this
in general of course get a general formula and of occasion to use that next
week but for now why don't we concentrate on the most interesting case namely that
of the linear equation with constant coefficients that is so let's look at the linear
equation with constant coefficients because that's the 1 that most closely models the conduction and
diffusion equations so I'm interested in instances of the problem all probably its most of
the most important case is the 1 where P is a constant because of its
applications that and many of the other the bank account for example all of those
would use a constant coefficient so but how is the thing I don't work well
I'll use the
cooling let's let's use the temperature model for example the generative model the equation will
be the
is equal to now notice on the right hand side is the common error but
you don't put t you have to put KATE because that's what says you if
you think you you won't have any trouble units have to be compatible on both
sides of the differential equation and therefore whatever the units were for capital k t
I have the same units on the right hand side which indicates I cannot have
T on the left of the differential equation and just T on the right and
extract the units to be compatible with that's not possible so that's a good way
so now first of all let me show you that for baseline
if you estimate the parameters of the time
you see that as you would expect to alpha that you get is actually pretty
close to zero is very concentrated around which is reassuring
if indicates that we know that there should be a social influence subsequent that says
that the thing
for the
influence models
so this is the data generated using the influence model the variety of of parameters
they're all for the estimate
and all for the estimate after which shuffle the time spent as you can see
here in this graph are very different so there cost this here
estimated of us after the first of all the dots are estimated from before the
and as you see there are many different so there is no significant difference at
the shuttle and this is also the distribution so if you look we're all we're
all the
the fact that he
new simulation and the distribution is going to be very
which is also reassuring saying that the influence the data that we actually
generated using one
if you're on this test actually is going to
decided influences like factor
for correlation model also
it has to be working very well again this is essentially the same
we crosses corresponding to reshuffle of after shuffling about corresponding to
alpha before sampling
and as you see that they are very close to each other in fact crossed
and to a slightly higher
and the distributions are also very close to each other
so that's basically saying that essentially that's it
confirmation of the theoretical justification that if you do the reshuffling the estimate that you
get is not to be very different from those original
and finally this is the data for their
in influence model again
you all you have reverse the direction of all edges remembered that there are something
like twenty eight percent of the edges are directed to neutral
the reverse the direction of all edges and re estimate alpha
in the new graph
and again you see the estimates that we get a much lower than the original
and that's also
so that's a civil defense we don't have many theoretical justification but this is actually
one of the tests that are used in the
and that's confirming the fact that this is going to
this is essentially showing that there is this model that you know
actually generated based on
and this is not the distribution of the
same thing for the correlation model here i'm shown in different graph
this is the of estimator of a
when the edges are this is that many of islanders on not and
things are very close to their why complex life is that
after after the edge so that's not
and the distributions are also very close
the result of the happened
know that for data so really tagging data
and they said that they wanted to observed that there is considerable social correlation so
if you measured itself parameter and make your data you see that of something between
one and two was significant
but in fact
when you run this shuffle we see that
you get something that's very very close to the wire that's life so alpha estimate
is not going to change very much if you just reshuffled
time stamp of all actions and the distribution there is essentially remained the same as
well so that's that's an indication that even though we have
considerable social relations in this talk this not from employers
and in fact likely to achieve result of also indicating the same so if you
reverse the direction of all edges again you're going to get this semester of
and knowledge
the distribution of almost the same
what we did here
was that we defined two models or correlation
one of the social correlation one
i had an element of social influence and one did not have the element of
social influence
the objective was to tell the difference between these two two models
and developed statistical tests to distinguish between the two
for one of the tests we had theoretical justification showing that
if you're on the test and one of the two models actually is going to
say that this is not
and also we dont simulation football has
four large number of data generated randomly and simulations are also suggesting that this walking
and then there on the test on flickr data set and the conclusion was that
despite the fact that we see considerable correlation
this correlation cannot be attributed to social influence and that's an important conclusion because usually
what you see in the papers that explicitly or implicitly
one day
draw the graphs and they show that there is some level of correlation
what they conclude is that people are influencing each other and with this thing is
that this is not necessarily the case could be that because
because if you're on the outside valuable that were not observed these correlation
but i can't
on the twenty first of august right ten kilograms per hectare
take bait
there's the b then xpj what if
what i received
didn't see that treatment xpj will be zero so just an indication binary flag to
treatment that we get
and so we can say that's his part one part two part three part four
part five
in that case the five will be one
XP sixty one e
seventy one sixty eight people all the expertise so xp twenty seven what you want
somewhere down here
and in getting there
to some extent
because that's just crucial to what we're doing here so the fact that can use
that encoding
the same thing with the treatment
so that's
by an indicator for whether or not
true but what has treatments a and so on but that's all industry so
measures the things we can do is about things that we can control the about
the treatment we apply
it is about the block so
beta two
x two j
it is that
two j is
one if we want to worry about a piece of land two
if we plot jason that this one
some examples
so for example
here's what to put to is in what to so we have one for that
one but not freezing block three
so don't want to have a set
when you look at this system so has always has the at the sun city
and so we normal variation as before
when you look at this that
of the financial to think that you need
a b to a and b to one but what you actually do think of
beta zero is the baseline for
if quite the first treatment treatment i
so that's
what we think of as a baseline observations here
what want
that's what we expect to get there
is a baseline that compared to other cities so there's adjustments relative to this
what's that
to what we would find out what the model so should get out of that
particular plot
we have to specify the model we have too many parameters without estimating because you
can just change one and changes to compensate
so if we go
with the model
and what what's
and that's fine because this is the key issue here though is
does a change in treatment who different treatments does it make a difference to the
and looking at the table is fairly obvious that does so that we want to
know will specifically how does it very well dressed up like questions the global question
because changing to produce attention to yield
the point about this is this
it didn't make it to make a difference
changing the treatments then
all beaches can be zero
so this is zero
that will be saying
it doesn't make any difference
which treatment applied to the plot
the average is what is an average of this
give enough detail
it's useful to have the average velocity
it is useful to have the average acceleration
which you can find by
it similar differences
but before you even do that
i want to define for you
an important concept
which is the velocity
at a given time
so this is the
the central idea of calculus i'm hoping that if you learn calculus
you learn about derivatives and so on by looking at x
so i will remind you again this is not a course in calculus i don't
have to do with many details
i would rather famous picture
of some particle moving
and it's here at time t
at some value of x
a little later
but this time t plus delta t
the devotees understand always what is small
an interval of time
infinitesimal interval of time market zero
during that time the particles gone from here
that is explicit delta x
and the average velocity in that interval
is delta x
he invented the the graphically
this guy is delta x
this guy is delta t
delta x o delta t is the ratio
so in countless what you want to do
is to get the notion of the velocity right now
we all have intuitive notion of velocity right now any driving in your car
immediately uses sixty that have lost velocity at the
it's very interesting because velocity seems to require
two different times to define it
initial time in the final time
and yet you want to talk with the velocity right now
is the whole triumph of countless is not that by looking at the
position now
the position slightly later
take the ratio
and bringing later as close as possible right now we define quantity
that we can say is the velocity at distance
so b of t
it is the limit
delta t
because zero
delta x o delta t
and we use the symbol
sixty four
so technically if you ask what is the velocity stand for
it stands for
let me drop
general situations
the article goes from here to to here
the vector delta t
and how well you can see in this figure here
is the slope of of the straight line connecting these two points
and that's the points come closer and closer straight line will become had to occur
well as the have any part of the curve is handed to the curve
the point
the standard of the data this angle
if they
then delta xn where delta t by trigonometry stand data
OK once you can take one derivatives you can take any number derivatives and the
of the velocity
it's called the acceleration
and we write it as the second derivative
i'm hoping you guys are comfortable with the notion of taking one or two
a number of
the only the first two derivatives happening
this was the last the second was is acceleration
i was never given a name
and i don't know why i think the main reason is that there are no
equations that involve the derivative
because i a is this fellow here
and nothing else
is given an independently
course you can take a function that take derivatives
any number of times
so you're supposed to know
for example if x of t
is due to the end
you're supposed to know
and to the u n minus one
it was no derivatives of simple functions like science and course
if you don't know that then
course you have to work harder than other people
you know that
that may be enough for quite some time
OK so
what i have said so far is
moving in time
from point to point
can be represented by a graph expresses t
any point on the ground you can take the derivative which will be handed to
the kernel
at each point
and numerical value will be what you can call the instantaneous velocity at that point
and you can take the derivative of the evidence
and call it the acceleration
so we going to specialize
two of the
the limit the class of problems
in the rest of this class
limited class of problems
is one in which
the acceleration
it is just a constant
that not
most general thing but i sure you guys have some idea why get interested in
that anybody know why that's too big
so much time is spent on that yes
but mean
the most famous example is when things fall on the surface of the earth
we all have the same acceleration
and the acceleration that's most common
it's called g
the main point eight
i mean per
second square
so that's a very difficult problem
following the surface of the earth you're describing the problem constant acceleration that's why there's
a lot of emphasis on
sharpening your feet by doing this class problem
the question we can ask is the following
if i tell you
the article is a constant acceleration
can you tell me
what the position x is
normally i would give you function and tell you to take any number derivative activities
this is the backwards problem
you're you're only given the particle is acceleration a
and you asked to find out
what is six
what's your job
is too
if function
well second derivative
is it
and this is called
integration with the opposite differenciation
integration is just guessing
integration is not in algorithm that process like differences i like to be a function
you know how to take the derivative change the independent variable
by the change in the function take the ratio and that's the of
the opposite is being asked here
i tell you something about the second derivative of a function
and ask you what is the function
the way we do that is we guess
and the guessing has been going on for
three hundred years so we sort of know how to guess
so let me think aloud and ask however guess in this problem
i would say OK this guy wants me to find the function
all the theta
of the negative log of p of
next parameterized by theta
as to vanish
from this it follows
i get that
by the way i need to correct myself on
two things that i said ronnie before
so one was regarding a convex function
that obviously
it there is no guarantee
that the minimum value is actually attained on the context the main of a convex
function simple example would be
if i have got a convex function one breaks exist in the domain between
it is in the main between one infinity so in that case a function is
convex they will be in the form and exists there's no local minimum but i
have no guarantee that the
many of the
the thing is actually minimum
you know that
that's the one thing thing is that the cumulants of the moment generating function
somebody asked whether they're just related by taking digs
eight or eight to one of those functions to get the other one well that's
not quite
two other but
that's said well the cumulant generating function is actually give is actually the log partition
so if you wanted to get a cumulant generating function
too quickly
review this
the notion of
generating function theory
what you would have is
in g
of data
just defined as the integral
p of x
and to
i x with theta
just i can define some function like so
and then
d theta
at the location theta equals zero
it is
the expected value
of all things
and the way you could see this quite easily
that well
of data that expression is the expected value of so to say
o point to in but that has to be taken with a grain of salt
because if this survey then you just get the teens of in order to can
be rather big beast where you can see this by looking at the tel expansion
of of the exponential which is of course nothing else but
well five x
course data
two in
however in factorial
in going from zero to infinity so therefore if we
look at this expression here
four theta equals zero
it's the are
and the only time that will survive
it is exactly
well for fixed to the and so to say
yes sorry not quite transparent here so
with this expression here
all the terms
four which
i'm taking more derivatives do not having the exponent here that will vanish before the
terms were
n is greater than
one of my derivatives well i will still have any theta occurring here so if
i evaluated at the tate forcier it will vanish and the only time that will
survive exactly that moment
you can try and identify distributions matching the moments
it's actually quite the popular thing to do
there are probably considerably more elegant ways i can identify distribution and if you want
to know more about how otherwise to identify sufficient talk to me about art
tossing a dice so we had this issue
now before
i will go in lead you down
say the garden path of maximum mass repostory estimation let's have a quick look at
why and under which conditions actually maximum likelihood estimation
can be a good thing to do
so for that well let's first look at the fisher score
the fisher score b c suffix is defined as the log so there are two
of the log p of express trusts by theta
so now the voice words this tells us the influence of the observation x on
estimating the parameters theta
and well obviously the expected value of this quantity vanishes
because the expected value of this
all p fixed produced by theta d theta of low p of theta
now after will be the answer right arrangement it's the theta
that expression here
and this takes into is always one so the spanish
quite like magic
but actually makes a lot of sense because if
you know why
you know the doctor such that it would favour a slightly different value of theta
world and they would have chosen that other value of theta anyway
so you have machine readable descriptions about functionality
the semantic web services basically
the application of
semantic web technologies
based on ontologies applying these to web services components with the aim of trying to
all the tasks associated with creating an application from the various components
through reuse
now if you look at the research of various groups
doing work on semantic web services and they talk about the semantic web service broker
and in fact you've been doing some work on standardizing the architecture of this type
of broker in oasis
and if you remember in the one of the earlier slide i showed where i
talked about the roles in the web services you have the consumer and the provider
these are the two main roles so
if you have a semantic basis for this than you imagine that you have a
client and the client has a set of desires or intentions so here's the client
imagine they want to book a holiday
and the client want to express this in terms so the color
and temperature of the sea
the colour and the temperature of the sky
the colour of the sand the number of people on the beach vegetation
a semantic broker if it had the right descriptions
transform these two the
the area services to automatically find the appropriate services composed mediate if there are any
and in fact
so here we might imagine putting together web services for long-range weather forecasts
web services web services for looking up and booking flights
web services looking up and booking hotels
OK possible today
she told the truth
OK now uses of it's OK like coming through out there
it sounds like it
so i'm going to talk primarily about l so alpha services
before i go into the that wanted to extend slowly overview of this area of
research just to mention that there are a lot of
big challenges in this area and it very active research area and there's a lot
of presentations here this week this week the slide a few minutes that shows some
of the activities later this week related to semantic web services
anyway i think probably the
the the core of the work that's been done today is probably in the first
three top-level bullets having to do with developing a language for describing services
in a much richer way than what you can do with commercial standards such as
was don't say you want describe the preconditions and effects of services you may want
to talk you may want to declare different kinds of policies related to how the
service can be used commitments that are implied by offering a service or by using
a service and reasoning about when those commitments might be fulfilled a lot of a
lot of different challenges related to the clearing and reasoning about the quality of service
or in other words issues such as response time and reliability of services
during execution
probably the most work in terms of
logarithms has gone into discovery and selection of services which of course
the commercial web services primarily done by human intelligence but the objective is my web
services is to automate that its fullest possible and composition of web services and the
other area which has received the most attention to date mention also
adaptation of workflow choreography there's a series of workshops on semantic web services challenge were
that was one of the core problems has to do with adaptation
of an existing workflow which may have been designed by humans but may need to
adapt to changes in the environment and the focus there is to make is quick
and easy and as automatic as possible to enable that adaptation so anyway as you
can see there are many other
important interesting challenges in this space of work
so just go very briefly through
the content of OWL s OWL an ontology expressed in OWL DL
man draws on many
previous bodies of work
as you can see here
it takes advantage of the language layers that you've heard about earlier today was this
it's expressed primarily in l
but it also allows for the use of this world to express things like preconditions
and effects in particular we you may want additional or different style of expressiveness and
so that's also about that so i breaks into three
parts of form
declarative descriptions so as the profile
we can not shell
it is really describe what the service does there's this service model or process model
you describe how the service works and from the centre-right there's the grounding we describe
how to actually access and communicate and interact operate with the service so i just
say a few words about each of those of necessity is going to be very
now at this point in time extremely controversial
there's a lot of well known criticisms and attacks on freud as it is actually
an excellent book
on the memory works by frederick crews
which in frederick crews is one of the strongest and most passionate critics of freud
the problem of freud
go like this
there are two ways you can reject the theory
there are two problems with the scientific theory
one way you can reject the theory is that i could be wrong
so suppose i have a theory that the reason why some children have autism
a profound developmental disorder is because their mothers don't love them and
the popular theory for many years
possible theory it just turns out to be wrong
but another way and so one way to attack and addresses scientific theory
is to view it as just to see whether or not it works
but there is a different problem theory could have
a theory could be sold they
and all encompassing
that that it can even be tested
and this is one of the main critics of freud
the idea could be summed up by a quotation from the physicist wolfgang pauli and
polly was asked his opinion about another physicist and polly said this
bad guys work crap
he's not right
he's not even wrong
and the criticism about fridays
is that he's not even wrong
the issue of vagueness
it is summarized in the more technical way
by the philosopher karl popper
who describe
who introduced the term of falsifiability
the idea of falsifiability
is that what distinguishes science
from non-science
is the scientific predictions
make strong claims about the world
and these claims are of the sort that they could be proven wrong
if they couldn't be proven wrong they're not interesting enough to be science so for
example in psychology the sort of claims will be entertaining throughout the course include claims
damage to the him the hippocampus causes failures of certain sorts of memory
or everywhere in the world men on average one have more sexual partners than women
or exposure to violent television tends to make children themselves more violent
are the two other possible we'll talk about that
but the point here is
they can be falls they're interesting and i
that they can be tested
and as such a big literally might be wrong
but they graduate level
of the scientific theory
this should be contrasted with non scientific programs and the best example of a non
scientific program is astrology sort of problem structure of astrological predictions
isn't that they're wrong
is that they can be wrong or not even when i did when i got
my horoscope for today
on the web
a couple of negative aspects could make it a little finicky for next few days
ago coming watch for that
the presence of both mars and venus just you want to box everything in the
ordered that structured way but keeping a piece of jade are commonly enclosed will help
you keep in touch with your fun side
and starting this morning about my wife will be something i can sort of in
touch with my side
the problem is a few days i'm going to go back to that was wrong
it can be wrong so it's just so think
i got better horoscope from the onion actually
right now the golf are not common and we have a way to police officers
after that of the character was that the murder
that's that's a good prediction
well it turns out to be true
i'm going to say those guys really know something
it's falsifiable
arguably freud
because freudian
the theory is often so
very inflexible
that it can really be tested in any reliable way a big problem with this
is a lot of freudian theories claim be validated in the course of psychoanalysis
so when you ask people what you believe in prior they want say oh because
of this experiment that experiment this status and that dataset was a is it's friday
the fourteenth theory proves itself in the course of psychoanalysis
the success of psychoanalysis
but it's unreliable i mean the problem is freud says patient you mother
is why
that makes sense
i right
for the UAE mother this
not always to discussing
fred says
your anger shows his ideas painful pretty impressive and i am right
the problem is
the same sort of dynamic
plays itself out even in the scientific
the baby back and forth
so freud freudian psychologists putting for you what i mean is well known for his
work will make some claims like you know
adult personality traits are shaped by the course of psychosexual development all dreams disguise wish-fulfilment
psychoanalysis the best treatment for mental disorders scientists respond i disagree therefore no evidence supporting
those claims and fraud in responses
the rejection of my shows that they are distressing to this is because i'm right
and this is often followed
deep psychological problem
now i don't want to caricature
fraud is a lot of stories have tried and made research program of extending their
ideas scientifically
bringing them to robust scientific test
but the problem is when you make specific falsifiable predictions they don't always do
that well
so for instance there is no evidence that oral and anal characteristics of personality characteristics
i talked about above being needed
first is being stingy relate any interesting way
two winning or toilet training
and there's been some effort cross culturally
to go back to the question is young men as before
looking at cross-cultural differences in toilet training and winning which are really big differences to
see if they correspond in any interesting way
to personality differences and there's been no good evidence supporting that similarly
freud had some strong claims about sexuality for why some people are straight and others
are gay
setting but that's what we're doing this question
i mean
OK so the question was if you have a couple of hidden variables one of
which depends on the other one he try to estimate one and then estimate the
other one
and into a back and forth let's think about this so that in fact the
case here
we're assuming all of these variables are hidden
and what what we're not doing here is estimating
the values of the hidden variables we're not saying
fill in a single value for the hidden variables the actual likelihood function when we
write it out involve summing over all possible values of the hidden variables if you
see what i mean that one approximation to that would be to fill in a
single value for each of the hidden variables
but that's
strictly speaking an approximation to the likelihood function
any other questions
sorry the
the general procedure for learning any model
which has parameters and hidden variables there's is a very nice in general procedure for
learning those models and that's the algorithm and i'm sure
most of you have heard of the algorithm but review in the following setting anyway
so the basic idea is the following
our goal is to maximize the parameter log likelihood given the observations
and that involves the log of a sum over the hidden variables the probability of
the observed and the hidden variables given the parameters
the intuition behind the algorithm is the following
we're going to iterate
between the following two steps
in the e step
which stands for expectation
in the east
we try to fill in
the hitting or missing variables that's sort of what you suggested
but strictly speaking we're not going to fill in the hidden variables with only a
single setting of those hidden variables we're going to fill them in with all possible
settings of those
hidden variables
so that's the e step
what we do in the m step is we apply our complete data learning procedure
to that filled in
so remember if we had completed the
procedure for learning the parameters was very very easy
that's what i showed you before it just involves calculating certain frequencies so in this
m step or maximization step what we're going to do is
apply that procedure as if those building values are actually true values
for the hidden data
this is the wrong intuition
for what the algorithm does and it works for
mixtures of gaussians are works for
directed graphs with hidden variables as well
questions about that
let's do the derivation of the algorithm
in a slightly more formal way
the idea is the following
we want to maximize this log likelihood l theta
what we can do is we can rewrite our log likelihood
as the lord of the sum over x
this joint probability that we had before
but multiply each term inside the sun
by some distribution over the hidden variables so
we multiply by q of x and we divide by q of x we haven't
done anything because we multiply all of these terms by one
what this distribution
represents is
our probability distribution over
field in values of the hidden variables
so we can think of
what's the best
probability distribution with which we can fill in
the values of the hidden variables
that's going to be qpix
the log likelihood is the log of the average with respect to q that's this
of these two probabilities
and now
we use the fact that the log function is a concave function
so the log of the
average of something
is greater than or equal to
of the lord of that something
and this is simply comes
from the fact that the log function is concave if we drew any line
connecting two points in the loss function
the law of
average of two points is always
going to be
greater than or equal to the average of the log of those points
that holds for
not just two points but averaging with respect to any distribution in any number of
points on this log function
this is called jensen's inequality and you've probably seen before but not it's very simple
consequence of the concavity of the loss function
so what we have now what we have is
things the parameters we had originally
and the distribution over the hidden variables
OK in this function for any distribution over the hidden variables is the lower bound
on the log likelihood
one way to derive the algorithm is simply to say
in the e step of the algorithm we maximize
this is a lower bound on the log likelihood with respect to
the distribution over the hidden variables
the parameters fixed
and i have the voltage over this resistance
and of course we need to
must be the current i
article so you solve your problem all the questions that i asked you
you have
the system
we could now
have a slightly different
by point eight
now we have resist here which is our long
and we have here are two
this is going
this is our two
the potential differences being is again given
and now i could ask ask you
what now is the current
that will flow here
and then i can also ask you what is the current that go through one
this is the one
one of the current
i could go through too
and i would allow u
to use
on the floor
now you say i have the potential difference from a to b
going this route
potential difference is free to give
must not be
i one
that is why
with his ograms
but of course you can also go
the well around so the saying he
is also i two
and i j
but whatever current comes in here
split up between these two think of it as one or
you cannot
right of charges
the number of charges per second that flow into this juncture
continue on and so i
coral current
is i one was i
so now
so you have all these
gradients that you need to solve
for the current i
the current i one
for the current i two
you can turn it into an industry
you can make extremely complicated
networks of resistors
and if you in course
you should love it i don't like it at all
so you don't have to worry about not going to get very complicated resistant that
networks from me
but in caustic you're going to see a lot of them they're going to
throat and stuff them down your throat
the conductivity
office of substance goes up
if i can increase the number
of charge carriers
if we have
dry air
and it is called
then the resistivity
of cold dry air at one atmosphere
so role
four air
one atmosphere
called means temperature that we outside
about four times ten to the thirteenth
that the resistivity of
but what is in this room maybe little
lower because the temperature is higher
if i he
it up
the conductivity the committee will go up
resistivity will go down
because now
i created oxygen and nitrogen ions by using up here
remember when we had this lightning
step came down
we created channel
four lions and electrons have very low
resistivity very high conductivity
so what i want
demonstrate to you that when i
create ions in this room
then i can actually
make the conductivity of air up tremendous
not only will the electrons move
but also
the ions now will start to move
and the way i'm going to do that is i'm going to port
on the electroscope
that is not so good
no harm done
i want to put charge on the electroscope
and you will see that
and i make the assumption
it is the simplifying assumptions
that the magnetic field was constant
over the portion of the wire which was the only ten centimetres
so i assume you that i have length
which is o point one meter
and that in
during in this range
the magnetic field is constant i just want to get
a rough number for the force on on the wire
so now i can integrate that
equation very easily because i have assumed that the magnetic field is perpendicular to the
the direction dl
l is now in this direction
so to sign of data is one
you don't have to worry about that
and so i simply get the force on this section after section al that force
f of the if you want to
is the current i
which we have there
get the length l which is this link
by the magnetic field
there are no sign i anywhere because the angles are ninety degrees
and so
i find that force
three hundred
times o point one
five o point two
of the thirty time point two
that is about
six nodes
is more than
the weight of one pound
so it's not so surprising when i took this current on
it's something all of a sudden move that while down
with the weighted is equivalent of a little more than the almost abandoned have actually
so it's not so surprising
that the support of
so you see that you can
so this qualitatively provided you make some simplifying assumptions
about the uniformity of the magnetic field
and about where the magnetic field
is present
i want to talk about
you know two
more complex
we're about to start all these great automotive contest
one envelope today
and i'm going to start to tell you slowly about the physics
the goal is ultimately
to build
a motor
i have a current loop
is a current loop
current comes in at a
and i'll try to make it
make you look at it three-dimensional which is not so easy
this is the current out here the
this is the current loop
i could go from here we go from here to here and returned here
and we have a magnetic field
i will assume that the magnetic field
constant throughout
in this area
there's is the force
right here
on this line in the direction i crosby
it forces up
there is a force field this why
which is of course down magnetic field is in the same direction
current is in the opposite direction
so the force is down
if this is why it length
why has an length a
that forced the magnitude of the force
is the current through the wire
the length of the wire
and we feel we just the right thing
is that the integral we just assume that the magnetic field is constant everywhere here
there are ninety degree angles
so the sign of data is one
so that's the force
one is the fourth he one of the force here
but it's zero
zero here
it is zero here why is that
because the cross product is zero
no matter how you look at it you can say dl and we even in
the same direction or in opposite direction
you can also say the drift velocity and b
and in the same or the opposite direction all the same thing
there is no force here and there is no force here
because that equation that we had to give the magnetic force
become zero sign of that angle is zero
so what's going to happen with this thing
well the user talk on this system there is no net force because this force
of the the same as this for
but there is the talk which wants to rotate in counterclockwise direction
and the magnitude of the talk
this of course this fourth
remember from one
times the perpendicular distance between these two forces
so the magnitude of the four
is i
times maybe
been at this moment in time
when the forces that is far apart
now this is going to rotate
and so as they rotated forces come closer
so to talk
we will become less still
want to rotate counterclockwise
there comes time
ninety degrees later
that the talk is
and i'll try to make you see that began in three-dimensional way
it's not so easy for me
now this is the
this has become the current always leaves the
i tried to make you see is
like this
current comes in here
we get this
and we get this
so bad in the magnetic field b has not changed
in the same direction
so the current comes in through a has not changed
the only thing is that the model is rotated
ninety degrees
now i ask you what the forces are
you have to go i cross
i crosby
if you do i crosby here i crosby
can force
which is thought to
that forces which are in the blackboard
we get forces which are not
and you get forces which are down
you have some time
use your
right hand and the the i crosby
and you will see that in all these forces
in the direction
then i put them
so now
is seen in the same language that the language in which we are building ontology
for instance in the ontology now
and we measured it two ontologies and we get about ontology we can import directly
into our system
but it could also happen
that in that case i mean it's not number six
in which he
that we merge
are in another language RDFS for instance and we want your ontology in now we
want to transform after the merging process the ontology into our so after that we
need to go through some kind of engineering approach
so once we have the
or these this morning
and once we would be the new model by using
non ontological resources ontology can
resources we need probably in integration systems
the conceptualisation phase two to do some kind of trying to some taxonomy we can
also extend some of the taxonomies or equal to specialized some ontologies and we need
more convincing enough
once we have finished the ontology because the decision activity sometimes we need the ontology
so indians so
the ontology is in english and they want the ontology and is found in the
space so i can go through the ontology localisation process in order to to to
it all the ontology labors in another way
and of course you all these activities we should carry out some kind of ontology
support activities like knowledge acquisition
but will be higher
the specification and also the conceptualisation activity we should document the whole process in order
to allow third parties to understand how
we have built our ontology
we should carry out evaluation modification embodied edition of the the model that we have
so in summary you can see here
eight it's ideas that we have already e
it to fight for the ontology by means of values and re-engineering of assisting resource
i am going to explain what had the ontology life cycle model and what have
they done the ontology lifecycle so so the more the ontology life cycle model is
the framework that we
i'm going to use for building the
the activities that we have already identified in the ontology development process and these ideas
have taken by from from the software engineering community so when we talk about ontology
life cycle model that we're talking about following waterfall
for instance the life cycle more than prototyping or in spite of all OK
so when but we talk about the ontology lifecycle we
we refer to the specific sequence of activities that we
we will carry out when
we will be our article on ontology so so there
sometimes i in the
into more than
if a use a waterfall if if i if i believe the ontology in an
that if a way
so based on that depending of the model selected i will get seven ontology lifecycle
so now the question is that how somebody peloponnese developers and ontology practitioners select the
ontology life cycle model and the particular ontology life cycle for
i create applications for complete ontology
so the first the first thing to do is to identify which one to use
the second one is to select the ontology life cycle model to use the third
one is to select for from the recommended
recommended that if applicable table i have already presented before
the set of activities that you need for your application after that you need to
match the selected activities into the selectors ontology life cycle model in order to get
the ontology life cycle for the user
the more
you already know that if if you know already the requirements in the ontology requirements
at the beginning
of the ontology development process so probably you can use a water for
life cycle more than the model incremental more or an interactive mother's
the requirements are not unknown at the beginning of the ontology development private or if
can change during the project then you can go to our evolutionary prototyping life-cycle model
you changed they ontologies requirements and these changes in the requirements could provoke some kind
of risk in your ontology project then probably it is more
it is recommended to going to the spiral
more the results several kind of risk would be that properties became classes or you
move from frame to the l or u
plants use new assistant assistant resources that wasn't in that thought that at the end
of the the ontology building process
so in the end you can use this kind of ontology life cycle model decision
tree in order to know which one is the most or the most convenient life-cycle
model for your application
so there you can see that if the a new you don't want to try
to change the
the ontology in a requirements you don't want to produce intermediate resource that the full
model would be OK but if you want to produce intermediate results in in a
complete manner then
depending on that you can use it at the forward incrementally much OK so based
on that this kind of questions can help you to select the ontology life cycle
model for your application
once you know that
this step is to go to these tables they have recommended
four and if applicable or table in order to select those activities but you need
for your application so probably if you have already been several ontologies you can go
through the stable because of you know which one is the meaning of the different
article of the different activities but for
you ontology developers so that we don't have to to many experience in this domain
what we've done is to create some kind of natural languages questions that will help
people to select an applicable activities so if as i mentioned before if you if
people doesn't don't dundonald what is ontology localisation one way of knowing the user needs
to the ontology localisation is to ask him or her
if you do you want to have the ontology in twenty different languages english spanish
french yes then you need the ontology localisation so ontology localisation who here and it
is and
non mandatory or if applicable or activity duplicate there you know to set to to
say OK
this is
this is a selected captivity for
my ontology