so given the index of this state and coating the data using the theta
so with
with length minus log probability according to this peterhead
the total length to get this two part code will be minus log the prior
of the theta which fits the data best minds like the probability of the data
according to the theta which fits the data best and which therefore also give the
small schooling to the data
according to all theta in your model
so no that if we use a uniform prior this is just what you've seen
before for example we have four
distributions and with a uniform prior each one gets probability one one-fourth
minus log one for this two we need to be
to encode
it's possible seat
but again we can do this for general prime
if you compare this to the basic see that the bayes mixture strictly better in
the sense that it assigns larger probability
therefore smaller code to some outcomes and no
and never smaller probability to know outcomes why is it so well
noted with the two part code we need exactly
this number of bits to code sequence
but with the basing coat
we need minus log of this some bits
and it's more equal
then this this is what we need with the two part code
first theta had this holds for all theta in particular for theta peterhead
so this means that here we have a small more equal and if
the other terms in some zero
and actually this will be strictly
the sum will be strictly larger than each of its terms so this minus log
of the sum will be strictly smaller than each of its terms so that the
bayesian coding using the base distribution will give you strictly shorter code length
encoding using the two-part distribution so then
using bayes for coding
so again this works by
feeling the coaches distributions making a mixture distributions and mapping the vector code
it strictly better encoding in two stages
now we've seen that there so there are two different ways of doing this universal
one of them seems to be better than the other
but now maybe we wanna extends further maybe even more ways to do universal coding
and then we should also ask yourself what do we really mean by better in
general and also we might want to know what prior should we use in general
should use a uniform prior or another prior to this depends of course on what
we mean by
what does it mean for code to be better than others
now we're actually going to define
better in a particular way which underlies
much of modern MDL which is the minimax way
if we have a model a set of distributions
we can always look at
given the data what would have been the best CO to use with hindsight after
having seen the data
and that's the code corresponding to the maximum likelihood parameter for the data which maximizes
the probability and therefore minimizes the code length
so this is the code in the beginning i told you suppose encoder just simply
sensor data using the cope with which gives you the shortest calling for the data
doesn't really work because the decoder does not to decode the data but if you
could do so
counterfactual then you would get is called
the this length is not feasible
instead you have to use the real code which can be decoded
and by the kraft inequality we know that that also has to correspond to some
so there must be some peace so so
the code uses corresponds to some distribution p star
such that for each outcome
the code length is equal to minus sloppy star of the data
and because this holds for each code
we have such a p star find the best code amounts to find the best
p start
and what we're going to do is we're going to look for the piste are
such that the overhead you have
compared to the best coach with hindsight is the smallest possible
in the worst case
but the worst case is taken over all data sequences
for each particular data sequence
you can look at what is the worst possible overhead between this thing
because you want to use
and the cost benefit of hindsight after having seen the data
so you can of course constructed called such that the number is negative for some
data so this code
i will give us more complex to some data then the best continuous candidate set
but then it will be very large for some of the data and in the
worst cases must always be positive
so now you look for the peace star which minimizes this
worst case quantity
so this piece star is when you transform into code
is the minimax optimal universal model for universal codes to be used for coding dates
relative to the set of candidate quote
now the question is
can you somehow compute this piece are surprisingly you can at least you can get
a nice formula ford whether you can actually use it for practice is a quite
different question
it's it's called the start of are normalized maximum likelihood distribution
so it turns out that the solution
to this equation the piece to which minimizes the worst case coding overhead
it given is actually there is a unique solution
if this is the solution to all the worst case is not infinite the solution
looks like this
so it's the distribution over sequences
which assigns to each sequence the probability of that sequence according to the maximum likelihood
of course if you have this
well for all sequences you get something larger than one
because for each sequence you assign
the probability according to the best fitting distribution in the model
so if there is more than one
distribution in your model is a set of distributions if there's just one this will
sum to one so there's more than one is was some to something larger than
which is again a restatement of the fact
it you
can not
called by simply sending the distribution which best fits the data
so you need to normalize this and you do simply by dividing despite the sum
over all sequences of the probability of that sequence according to the best fitting distribution
for that sequence
clearly if normalizing this way you get distribution if you know someone over outcomes becomes
now why does this solve this well it's actually quite easy to see if you
like this in here
you get minus log of this probability
and then
minus log fractions minus log of this plus lack of this
plus lack of the the denominator
so then the minus log of this
cancels with this
if minus log this miners mines look the same thing and what remains is the
lot of this sort
so if you like this and here you get a lot of this sort
and that some doesn't depend on the data itself so it's constant over all possible
data sequences
now if you would use any other distribution here
distribution must sum to one if it's not the same distribution it's must give smaller
probability to at least one sequence
and if it is small probability to at least one sequence that for that particular
this must be larger
right because if you plug in this it's a constant
clusters and go back and they them in geometry
that the pipeline is very very simple
so what the local signatures well made
the main issues
the variance the cost
so basically you the two for pruning
factors that of course match
so you know if you think about classic three b
you might have a curvature
the principal curvatures point to prove
next bear
in the case of the butterfly
can think of the normal
for example this point
might be
i propose as
so yes
but if you look at the discussion axis normal this point and automatic
on this axis therefore about pair
so one can
if you take all possible pairs of butterflies that noise that could
the based on curvature
starts to clean up
if based on what kind of user normals
gets better and prominent cluster
can be you seen
as you see on the right
so the flow control point there
for the for more information you can compute
train on the shape
based on the estimation
principal curvature how likely is for this
and typically
we have no
he devotes
and if you do this with the machine so we could all this with semantic
the landscape like this
and then we use
i mean shift clustering
across the landscape behind the dominant peak
and of course there was a
it doesn't follow that peak it's because in the first place this goal
information at all about query this point came from the shape
so they have to be verified going back into the shape we do so by
many of the things i would know i speak
to the clusters i mentioned is related to the size
like just a
that means that we should nice and that
you can take a few samples the next larger symmetries what sample the finest so
and here is this
that show you the algorithm discovery
semantic structure in
there's a lot of it
thank you
so in the end
well you know
part of the castle can be used to generate the rest
due the compression on
it's not that impressive in compression ratio
but the representation of you here is something you can work with for example
i can a compressed for that they can
but this entry because it should have a lot of people use this deflection of
the a
but what he
some other more solid waste like
the geometry
here's an example of a model of the sydney opera house
where the sources stating going on
just more
one can get more organic shapes
like this story i
when you find the left to right in the middle the semantic difference
in the back seat
and quantify how far from symmetry something
it will be important later on
well one few years
the distinction between an extrinsic symmetry that similar to transform of the ambient space
the station is an
intrinsic symmetry one defined purely based on the shape itself for example
symmetric in some polls
most of the time we have some confirmation that is not
symmetric yet we isometric to air symmetric positive can discover
the intrinsic symmetries is the child
that it's possible to do
by focusing on the descriptor based on the
i conductors of the cluster
but it did not fall
and by
mapping each point
from the
two hundred and and stayed on the international space station
so they arrive in the same place close to each other
this point is not correlated with this point
now it happens to be in this case
but that's coincidence could've ended up anywhere along their
this point for example is also not correlated and ended up there so that there
is zero correlation between these points and these points numerically there is really small correlation
but in practice it's zero
i mean beyond american non numerically computer
decreasing things it's zero actually really really small correlation
where does that come from
well actually
let's look at the list
two so one the tricks won the nice things about calcium is how do i marginalize
all point three d twenty five and this is a joint calcium we've already talked
about this when visualizing galcians the marginal the calcium is eh
yeah and the variance of the covariance marginal is just the covariance a those three
elements in the joint that's a really special property
it doesn't happen very often
you see a lot because you see gaussians a lot but it's a very particular
property that you some across all the other dimensions that what happened a discrete model
you know the some across all these additional binary values it would make it a
mixture model from previously being in a mixture model so it's a very special property
against him
and it's what allows against interview guassian process so we're going focus on the joint
distribution for two those points and we can ask the question
if we observe the earth one so this is like observing someone's height
what's their weight okay then we get the conditional
but in this case i think this is a function we observe we've got the covariance
we observe one point in the function conditioned on one point we know the other
point should be somewhere close to it
so this is actually the observation that you see in the sample here
and then that's the conditional
with the density like and the point was somewhere close to it and that's going
on all over the place that's repeated all over here yeah
now the correlations are such that
close these points on the coast more become correlated
if they're far apart
they become less correlated so we observe point now the point five
index five could be quite a long way away from and we again see that's
in the plot here if we move index one two three four five and we
see that even though they still correlated with some like point five
being the correlation coefficient they're quite a long way away from each other and
so the information is all encoded in a covariance and here is the covariance it's
the exponentiated quadratic will be obvious before the squared exponential the calcium
it's thank you don't count the ballots been talking about
and everyone else we talk about and this is the guassian process interpretation that is giving you
the covariance between your data points across the real life and it's also why with
sampling from when i introduced can appreciate and talked about distances in half space and
i said the expected distance in space of the sampling from this thing
joint calcium across how many data points i chose the sample
so you can sample from these things with different parameters
you can have eh
different length scales
and this is a scale that you typically don't see in the support vector is
actually equivalent to the value si
but you remember you'll have to prove alpha times kay was the case with the kernel there
so this is alpha i even use the same notation accidentally alpha times can still
and what this alpha parameter does it controls the overall scale of the process so
if alpha is large these models a larger in the scale processes changed the length scale contains the
how rapidly it fluctuate and in fact you can say from the landscape how many
zero-crossings you expect in a certain interval gives you that's so it's got a real
nice physical interpretation
so here's samples from the covariance and his and samples with a longer length scale
his samples with a
alpha being set a so they go up to
behind so the standard deviations to so they go up as far as before
i noticed course once they hear
the probability that they end not here is high
despite the fact that marginally we only expect five percent samples the fallout here in
this region here conditionally once you're up here you expect to be out yeah
that's been a marginal correlated expectation
this is the linear covariance
so that's a funky thing to do is sampled from the covariance which is at the form
x x transpose
in a product and you just get a bunch lines
so is the what seems like a difficult way
describing a linear model but when you think about what it's saying marginally it makes
alot of sense what it says marginally
if you look
the linear kernel down the marginal distribution
you'll see
in one dimension
like this
this is these diagonal covariance yeah
so if this is zero
the variance is zero
if this is
the variance
is four
standard year deviation is to
so the marginal
i mean it's it is clear
that selling it is telling you what the models can look like and you can
definitely see that's in the samples
the standard deviation
doesn't go up linearly
the variance goes up quadratically
that's what i covariance is telling you
now this is a different way of thinking about data because you used to thinking
about data is independently across data points it you're talking about correlations across data points
but thinking about data is independently across data points is done
because all you are interested in
it's how you're different data points relate to each other
so if you want to use probability properly you should have your probability telling you
how different data points relate to each other
if you wanna be parametric fine and then you using probability for the noise but
the bayesian way tells you to look at the correlations across data points
this is a different covariance function based on a neural network type form and this
is i like this one because it's point-symmetric is based on the neural network form
where all the neural network-based is forced to be
center zero so the force is three point symmetric so you get little things like this
and this is a bias term so this is just with a little bit to
make it positive definite somebody from the covariance which is just constant everywhere
okay so that's just
allows you to take a linear function moving up and down
and this is a combination of be exponentiated quadratic um the bias anderson noise because
you know is a gaussianprocess to it independent everywhere
and this is the ornstein uhlenbeck
i don't know how well i pronounce the ensemble back
the covariance so this is brownian motion in a quadratic
stationary gauss markov process brownian motion in a quadratic
not just recalling
what we wear
so we looked at the show of
query ontologies for accessing data
ontologies already in the first part of the tutorial
well we have t b so that b fifty bucks in a box we we
can clearly a box
take into account the constraints the ontology
fifty bucks
what we will be looking at now
is essentially simulation about
where we have large amounts of data
and this will cover the first part of the time in the second part which
will become edges that that
we will only deal with related issues where large amounts of data are not data
because it a that data stored in external data source that someone gives us which
might be a data also which have no control
and so they should days to establish a connection a suitable connection to these data
sources such a way that we can access and create data
going back to what seen in the first part is that current technology
also based on expressive description logic allows us to to to deal with
quite large aboxes compared to what we
we're able to do a few years ago so we can deal with a boxes
is in the number of individuals that is in the order of ten thousand and
i believe is is quite impressive everything that
just a few years ago we were able to deal with hundreds of individuals so
this is an increased by
more than one order of magnitude higher if you speak to people
talk to people that have to manage data then they will tell you i mean
this is not really
large amounts of data ten ten thousand eighty there's not much we need to deal
with large data sources in certain domains some intelligent data scientific data enterprise data
ten to the four is is that is a game so there we have
seven orders of
of magnitude larger amounts of data to manage so
amount of data and a lot of
millions of billions of individual
and the
the only technology that is currently available and that is able to deal with such
amounts of data is a relational technologies and relational databases
so the question is
that you want to address is how can we use ontologies together with large amounts
of data and together with the technology that is the only one available nowadays to
to handle such large amounts of data and that's what we have is in this
so the
in this setting we have to deal with the well known
between expressive power
an ontology language so interested in having as much
expressive power available to capture constraints and to capture the best possible way out domain
of interest
however we note that we have usually to pay
if we gain expressive power we have to pay in terms of how difficult it
becomes to deal with our information to reason why information so we have to pay
in terms of complexity of reasoning
we have also deal with this tradeoff between expressive power and complexity however we are
dealing with these in specific setting
so first of all
we have an ontology and we want to take his ontology into account so we
want to do inference OK so this is not different from what we saw till
now in the first part of the story
now what's is different is that we have to deal with large amounts of data
and so we want to resort to relational database technologies
and we want to store our data
in relational database we want to access the data
by accessing and using the functionalities and the potentiality of relational databases
we want also to be flexible in querying the data in
people that are used to
excess data relational database they used to SQL which is
expressive query language the query languages that have been considered ppl in ontology ontology setting
essentially concept of class expressions are we can understand
we want to
go towards expressive query language as those that people using databases
so this i would flip the third
with the SEC
but these representations the three dimensional representation it can broke can break this
two by two matrix and another one here
for all the elements of all elements
i j
in s three
what what are those
i'm showing
is that
irreducible representation order two of us three
you have the matrix for each one of the elements
the are representation that you always have
is the representation
normally you will see a lot of these symbols
not getting to the table
but these are
young tableaux
this is
standard representation which is very easy
he is one to everybody
all wrong she
there is another one which right
like this
gives you mean this one for even
plus one four
what i want
last one four
but even in knowledge
it's another result you can always be compose an element
in two brothers
of transposition
of two elements
and so on
so if you have
an even number of these in the decomposition the permutation is even
if you have just one
the representation is odd
that that
element would be on
permutation will be or so you have
he was signed mean this one for all permutations and plus one to the even
permutations and you see this is exactly
this is actually this follows exactly
the same property of the
limitations of the multiplication of the group
if you multiply these
these elements
and you have to mix one which is
one of the
this is a very normal work
in physics is very business innovation they call this
the total symmetric presentation on semantic representation and makes
this one here is that the two dimensional one
which assigned those metrics for each one of them and this is the only one
that has to be more not trivial
so how do you do that
the fourier transform
you use this from here
and you have
a function
you have to define a function over the limitations and this is the card shuffling
it's random transposition
you know
you can you can
do nothing with the card
deck of cards
you can shift then with probability
so the sum of these things has to be one and it is
anything apart from that zero
you don't mess with regard to the same
so the fourier transform of this function here
you have to do this
of first for the first
for the first representation here
you have this is just one for all elements
all elements have
the same representation
exactly the same representation
and here you put the probability
of your function therefore that elements right
applications typically just one replica in each data centre of documents of a particular documents
index data
there are two problems one is
we can only have bugs in our careers serving system that causes a back into
to die when it receives the query you know maybe it's not even depend on
the particular index data that machine has a baby sister blog the query parsing code
but those are not good in any system but there are special about an in
memory in the system where
if you have a group that you end up killing a thousand machines instead of
so those article you figure out some scheme that allows you to insulate their innoculate
yourself from ineffective queries that
the other thing that is that is when the machine fails
they you end up having a period where the data that machine was serving is
completely unavailable you don't have any copies of the index to centre
so for very important documents we ended up replicating them in multiple different shards and
so that we would could be inflated to single machine failures and still have CNN
homepage for example when
machine men down
over time we've
decided that it was better to build our own data center facilities
the picture of our data center and the dallas oregon
you're a big hydroelectric dam
and so this is just to give you a sense of
the kind of so these are building today
if you look inside it still we're we're back to know cases
it turns out air flows better but they look much cleaner in the corporate world
so basically the
the current machine design is essentially an in house rack design that provides pretty good
air flow
standard PC class motherboards still fairly low-end storage and networking hardware
plus a bunch of in house after doppler
i'll talk about briefly
two thousand four we rolled out a another fairly significant change with sort of a
generalisation of some of the stuff we learn from our in memory index one of
the things that
happened is we sort of generalize the notion of the query distribution trees so that
you could have a two level or three level treated ever made sense depending on
what type index trying to serve
we generalize the notion of balance are so there were there was one manager for
doing load balancing across the entire cluster there were much cleanup API so it was
possible that basically use the simple
the this
same basic system and plug in your own scoring function if you're for example implementing
a different product in july book search you want to plug in your own book
specific scoring functions
but you still want to use sort of the nice infrastructure that the system provides
the whole
set of API were designed so that was pretty easy to do
by this time developed a distributed file system that we can depend on reliable use
so i the bottom levels you fast which is the sort of questionable
file system world the index data was mode from the previous system sort of manually
SEP data to local disk sin
the new model GFS sort of assumed to exist in the conservative
it out of that
so on
one of the so to say
so again we rethought are index encoding data structures the walkable index format which we
had designed when we were still in this space index and started still continue to
use albeit with smaller blocks in the
in the in memory next used the two level scheme basically we would encode sequences
of activities and then for each document we encoded sequence of positions
and the ducati deltas of were encoded with rice encoding
so that's fairly
compact bit level encodings
gives you a very good compression
and the block based format meant that it was pretty
good for a is
fairly CPU
friendly as well because you can often use the walkers to skip things in our
the best
that is right we would learn it if well maybe i'm saying will should be
saying different
the best
that if our i should have so i
why pattern
part of what say it differently also what i said
what applied but what i wanted to say was if the new measurements exactly if
this was zero we would make change that that you see one struggling for
that that if our all measurements exactly
davis perfection
in this second
in this new system then we wouldn't want to change of course
but if they don't give us perfection then this is called the innovation is is
the new information
this is the innovation here
and we hope that
there should be some matrix that multiplies and innovation to give us the the delta
you have the that
correction OK could we just derive this formula
that's that's what i plan to do now is just derived from first principles
what do i mean by first principles i mean that all
all right so the answer to this problem
and then all manipulate
to put it in this form
that all right
so that's the goal so what's the answer to this problem
so we see that we see the problem here
and we know all the equation that we have to solve
and we've decided that sigma
will separate into two pieces that screw you'll see that that's a big help
what is this
the left hand side matrix
for this
for this problem for me to do this in two steps
OK so i'm about to derive this
this form
i've got a whole lot of pieces here
i've got this matrix and then got some changes over here let me deal with
that matrix first
so i have a which is
they all
a new
inverse which is a moth of
i think no inversion see there would have absolutely critical
we had a block diagonal matrix
a transpose is a of
next to a new
all i'm finding here you are let's just do the multiplication out
so what do i do i have
i've just got
sigma inverse
a transpose
maybe i had maybe i
but consistent i write all on every
during the multiplication o
a new the right answer downwards maybe not
inverse new
a new
you see that
in my my doing this right
i am a
the transpose have been for certain
absolutely otherwise all wrong
thanks quite right
you can say that i make errors just to keep you awake
but i can get right
well yeah but i would like to
go on record with the truth here
all right and of course i was going to say that was that i was
wrong as soon as i try that multiplication the you're absolutely right a transpose all
and a transfer new
that's a transpose
put together
this is sigma
this is good now
i believe this multiplication
do you believe that
and you see what
i mean it's not important to see
what happens
because this is like the whole point of the lecture were getting new
know stuff here
yes this is right of course i didn't correct the last line either
thanks a travel that agent
living and dying with a transpose CA here i want to get
the transpose the rights but there which is that all right now
actually the way i would see this is
my old columns times rose
it i mean if i suppose a new is just one new a is not
a new is just one new rho
this is like valuable to think
there's a massive for the one nearest neighbour is a set of points i could
just you can perhaps point and then to do with a lawyer cost time
it's a major problem than just
these are the ones
that's a compared
there was
for some one hundred other
preference candidate's friends
so what
we have done extensive of comparison
and the the reason is pretty simple
these various algorithms is putting on should if you want to write well optimized
and it seems like
you need to compare served at the same level optimization
this is optimized
and writing optimise kd tree ball tree or whatever
it seems like a lot of work
i can tell you a a little bit so for
the corel dataset
alex gray tested some of the most recorded and more company work
and i think that they get
only a factor of two speedup right here
on one dataset will be fast
but it all i really know right now to sort of little spot checks
that's being worked on
then she
the reduction would maybe make this being approximate remember the exact
one the positive things can
you want to try to
one small triangle
three dimensions
other dimension that
and it's not people
senior centers and more
but is it possible to benefit
knowing how measure
the newspaper
one of was finally frees you can just get better methods of calculating the distance
so if you turns out you can project all points in the three dimensions without
nicky without introducing distortion
you can get a distance metric very quickly just
involves three
two vectors of links two vectors of length three
that they do vectors of links four thousand eight hundred sixty four thousand ninety six
is it even
the solution
this is what you for this
so she much for
that distortion and you would keep it there
the exact notion shall
because this is the result is dependent upon the metric distance between things
it doesn't actually matter what embedding dimensionality
i said this is optimized before nearest neighbours so the opposition that we did was
computing the that then
measure distance
maybe your computing was all euclidean distance
which means
all the elements of x minus y
it's created
so what you can do is you can add in
upper bound
on on what you care about
and then you can hold the computation as soon as this song
exceeds upper bounds squared
and then
you know you can because it can be the nearest neighbour and said no no
more competition must have
this is what we're doing to optimize the force
and then there is a lot for
this dataset and that this
because for the nation by
that was not done
but that might be a reasonable thing to do
for the
collins so this was
four since the seventies
what this
i want to mister cameron c plus plus
so this is what he means
you this is the mean
the first cover tree were were
optimized didn't do this but
the is
they concise with memory and CPU is much make
it is the loop unrolling for example
it so
so this is experiments
i want to tell you what country is next in all discuss
some background details like expansion constant for these experiments
OK so a cover tree
is level
probabilistic classifier which gives you
hi put teachers and you could keep
a few just one
compute the probability that all that is certain have generate com
and actually
did here
many different concepts because
classifier might not that the concept exists
i considered here in your model
so this is just one of the ways how you can
integrating information in slang
we we've seen in the third lesson
plsv model probabilistic latent semantic analysis
and all the latent dirichlet allocation
you're document is seen
and make sure the topic and each topic is a mixture of
so you could also and this topic they were invaluable which we estimated
which we were trained on which we train on
reference set
collection document collections
so from the document collection we've learned
the word distributions for each topic and also we have learned for documents the topic
distributions which would be yellow the
we need the complete string completely from one training course was for LDA weekend
actually what is that it can infer from document also desktop distribution
also this model can be integrated test examples
into a language model
so we have here again
i think we started from
so we have this probability that's great
generated by documents to the collection frequency
but now
the probability
we could be placed by our
mixture of topics so
that the document generated
a certain topic
and also the fact that the topic generated
query considering the key topic
by which we have which we have defined in our
of course you can also
you could also translate your question
into topically presentation and only considering
the probability is the probability that your document generates certain topics
and considering also again and language model for your query
when you're ready to generate certain topics and again compare this topic distribution
like the kullback liebler divergence to compute
the king
and there are others
in the literature to find some other way
of using this language model
i think a like he
the morning post
so it could be the
you're document structure like
for instance in legal texts
needed articles
section i grouped in chapters maybe some higher level
to find form
these articles are not a randomly
put into
the output
into the same section
when the
speak about the same topic for when you are quite related you put them in
this section on the thing
two those actions
grouped into chapters and so on
when they have
relationship to each other
so you could exploit the
if you do it
your query
not only small were moved you could split it that
something finally
dependent on your
document collection
but you could also take into account
the probability that higher level
section generate your credit because they might seem related to
and so they might be quite related to your information and then you have the
if you have of course training data
you could use
generate these interpolation with your training data
so how does
the ranking in your actually taking into account the structure
a few
and also we have a cluster based retrieval models actually this is the kind of
cluster based retrieval models
you can see the
hierarchical clustering
of sex into
in two higher level clusters
so it has also been shown shown that evening
document that you perform clustering on it
that you can use
clustering information
whether dark about system to belong to
class two
here's a higher level representation take into account information into your language models
so you have a lot of possibilities
two probabilistically models
your information
and new model
in in new use in the document model
and as i said you can also
if you have
relevant document
for instance you can also better models
make the language model
of 12 samples to adopt a resolution before it comes from is very keen on
when you have a very short time series in fact before you transfer could be
approximated existed still belongs on the side of your feet don't want our very cool
on soliciting energy users Hill the real problems in the probability that we trained in
also the All-Pro fully quantum music is a bad very bad
tool for up for local processing when you have a very short time series says
the idea is to build a day picture of which is based on the east
and we have to defend the distance between the 2 Koreas met to match of
the said on doctors on the average met which we a wrote which will be
representative of the never would be ambulance was extremely had a role to a wrong
decision under
so all could time distance between 2 matrices omelets easy average which is about something
all of a mattress is so indirectly treachery livelier walk so the world which has
been the only information humidity by hollow on urgent also growing 945 the Carlo bond
is very well known in setting up a system because there is a well known
in by injured congenial news for made Beijing official information that creates on that's also
the action that has licensed which was questioned him in and ballet in Rochelle also
encountered a Minnesota men's figure as extending the classic got of punk I spaces
only as work on the space of complex closing out of office space of complex
matrices of so of symmetry predicted dignitaries used a symmetry quickly seized
all areas of the she needs all the cases they think extension allows it just
secured a rosy could take place secured a point at states
which didn't exist but were widely used because it was a eager that has a
lot this of kind of of of structural and almost all of the people of
Europe some people in the image demand more college in which we on an sponsoring
trickling 2 of could we extend geometry on and these tools for Kansas space of
symmetry comes
on U.S. some links with the gap on a nominee phone on complete nitwit care
space like its space
Brussels somewhat of a kept all kosher which also welcomed the news that the means
so which is
In 90 per cent of amount committee people used for the news known for the
trust of the difference between to define a distance between mattresses on the use of
test good admitting community are between 2 mattresses on the fact we will see that
it is a good distance is given by basis this 1 which will be in
fact given by the summation of some of the square of the also extending the
value of a good value of this mattress is always a good would is in
fact the geometric mean working you could've says that beneath a Iong beat commute between
me exactly acquired description of the process seeks a Munich is in fact an extension
of the test the geometric mean toward when it may only be commuted to have
exactly the square would be so that the program is at the square will hold
of a his nuts to it because it is condition so you have to use
this expressions to have the probability that the geometric mean is that those triple-digit and
you have also the extension the Accenture although the notion of students each so cheap
varies from 0 to what on what went his acquired 2 1 had you have
exactly the geometric mean between 2 to Methodist Hill guests at various French that for
a valuable should endorse Nina UF convicted equivalence between cemetery which is given by the
inconsiderate thick also to make tweak which is given by the space policy because although
was a military official it which is owned by the official information metric attitude not
always in most cases Madrid and interested metric is different was official met
there should be a few words about myself before we begin some researcher in maths
lab and i do research in in the first thing in applied math so the
goal of today
is to give you some
basic necessary mathematics that you may be using this week or not
what is going to be starting from the real beginning so
you probably know everything i'm going to say to this so apologies apologize if you
know everything
if you don't you can ask questions
well let's begin
so we'll talk about several things
the the direction is divided into three parts the first part is going to talk
about the eyes brian feature spaces and stuff
in the second part of this talk about probability and industry partners token in a
bit about optimisation
and we start with the linear algebra
so i'm assuming that you're preferred vector space
is mining is all too
after is pretty
it's pretty nice to deal with
in OWL two
in take two vectors
and you're able you're able to some them by just adding ve on top of
you here
and getting back to there
you're able to do all this stuff like
but if a new virus skater so you can multiply you by two and you
get a vector that is twice as long as you
and then you can do a bunch of stuff actually you can define
things that are line with
and with
can define what the projection of w on this line
and that would be director there
well that's
so it's very easy to work with our two
i guess
the first generalisation of all two user and is and
and nicky any integer
and there are three for example is your usual space
what you have in all three is that you can sum of vectors as you
multiply them by scaring
you can also actually you can write any vector arena and as the sum of
so i i wrote them rum e one e and which are the basic vector
basis there
and you can figure out that any element in our hands the sum of and
and of those vectors
you to other example of vector spaces
this thing going on here is the set of solutions of second order differential equation
it is the genius
so if you take functions that go from after about twice differentiable
and you
take the set of functions that provide these equations
then you can show that is the vector space that stable by addition that if
f is in the vector
space then its opposite is also in the vector space
and that's we can motivate inmates skater
and likewise for and you can write any function that is as here some of
two special function because the cosine function and assigned functions
music composition there is actually unique
there are spaces for which you can actually
decompose mean
the elements on a finite set of vectors
and those with b called infinite dimensional vector spaces in the example of that is
to our
so the two of are in the space of square integrable functions
if they all my additions by multiplication by a real number
and there's something which
i haven't
that i have not written for the other spaces you can actually define the dot
so actually while we wait for everyone else to get back all show you this
slide that i didn't show this morning
when i had my first slide i was very confused that the slide was missing
it turns out when i sent the slice john i forgot to include it so
there's good reason was missing but it's actually the first slide i wanted to show
the whole day it's also good good introduction to the section i'm going to give
we are kind of missing the slide that said hey something really important happening in
semantic web space so every time
i've given the talk editorial since about two thousand
you know i've always had a slight uptick called the current state of the semantic
you know the very early ones were
nothing's going on but it's a cool idea
then started saying you know there's a lot of research funding this slide you'll notice
it barely talks about research at all this one
i actually
last updated in july and i need to go back to this for five companies
that are
big news not even showing up on it at the moment
but probably the most important thing in this whole thing is this slide is from
an internal talk gave microsoft labs
in july so
that was you know talk under non-disclosure not an open talk
you know a lot of a lot of interaction with them about technologies things so
you know again the big guys are starting to pay a lot more attention than
they used to in fact that was right about the time
that microsoft but at the semantic search company called powerset for hundred million dollars which
formed a lot of excitement
and the top one out there that semantic web companies
this really
again my whole talk was about these two things going on you see it again
that there are some of the older companies or some of the consulting companies are
forming around the kind of ontologies used mostly heard about today
but a lot of the excitement and most of the venture money
is around what's been called web three point
and so what i'm really going to do and in this part of the talk
is talk about the label data
and web three point o and
there's a lot of companies garlic in the UK metaweb radarnetworks has a product called
which is just come out of data has about one hundred thousand users their generating
tens of millions of RDF triple
a year and their anticipating that that's going to go up by two or three
orders of magnitude over the next few years so there pushing very hard on the
scaling stuff so in a certain sense
the semantic web technology has become the database technology of a new
the world of web applications and that's what this half-hour it's about and then also
show you that a lot of bigger companies are playing oracles been supporting both RDF
and some OWL in its main database release they're starting to retrain database administrators to
understand some of the stuff you've been learning about today
for years people said one is microsoft cannot do this the answer is microsoft still
says they don't do any semantic web but they have released in RDF based products
and they do have an open source RDF toolkits
so they just call it something else they
they had a wonderful page for
call for proposals for the use every phrase you can think of that synonymous with
semantic web except that one so the quality intelligent where this a semantic technologies for
the intelligent where
semantic technologies for the new breed of data web services that sort of thing
on and on and on a lot of open source stuff out there now so
again jump-starting these kind of projects so
when we first started getting these
we're talking primarily to people who would have to build their toolkit nowadays you don't
have to build it OK
what's interesting is that also true
at a much higher scale and so that's what i want to talk about in
this half-hour so
i i call this talk to be provocative the dark side of the semantic web
i don't mean
right so about that i don't mean the evil thing what i really mean is
this the part of that you don't hear much about if your research
because we researchers are used to think for the first a lot of the research
community and semantic web came out of the AI community not out of the database
yet there's a lot of people from the database community starting to join the semantic
web research community again because the staff from talking about but more importantly
you know if i had more time what i would actually do is we would
take a poll would have you i'd have you guess how many machines
are there
at the website called google dot com
but no one knows the actual answer we know the number is well more than
a million machines
OK because they've already said they have
two thousand clusters roughly five thousand machines doing mapreduce answers to your query
right so so when you think about running a server farm of million machines that
not typically what we talk about
when we think about
you know how
creating a website but when the real world talks about creating a successful web application
facebook hundreds of thousands of machines all over the place married tributed the largest cluster
running a server farm nowadays is electricity
and cooling not
the cost of the people of the cost machines i heard recently that five companies
account for thirty percent of all the computers sold in the world and i know
it i know google is one
microsoft is one i don't remember what the other two are so again uge amounts
of stuff there that we're not used to thinking about
the semantic web was built from day one to be aware of the technology
i can say that i was yelling about it
many people in this room will tell you i was crazy guy guys kept saying
web web web
it's growing in a few different ways
so one of the things is we basically our language what things are
rdf for a lot of reasons but mainly is
was because they were wed stuff
there that matters a lot of people in the web development community was sort of
looking at this stuff is interesting but was really born
what RDF allows in way that traditional structured databases don't allow very easily is the
linking of things in different databases that opens of course one of the problems is
how do you get people to publish their data since data is still viewed by
most companies are resource
well on the web a lot of company said you know i'm not going to
create web page why would i put my catalog on the web
right well there there
other companies put their catalogs on the web and they were forced to and then
the ones who had
come to the web started doing better and i mean there's a lot of if
you look at the history of a lot of the stuff on the web you'll
see there's a lot of give and take and coevolution lot of what we now
take for granted at on amazon that combines nobles that happened in the sense reluctantly
one of the things that's been going on is an attempt to just get a
lot of useful data out there so people who want to play with the new
kind of applications don't have to go collect the data so
you know it's very funny i keep going to a i conferences where people still
talk about if only we could get a good dataset and i point all of
them at this which is what's called the linked data web services
this set of rules to kind of play but it's basically says you have a
database you make it available in RDF and you provide a mapping to some other
place and so so all of the ontology alignment is done
off line
so this shows a kind of browser view into our database this is the subject
and i object triples
those are actually only a small set of relations that are in are actually there
in our semantic representation and this is just a browser that lets people navigate just
three so you can fill in any
one two or three of those and essentially get back all the results of our
database or list of attention limited subset of restricting the computation here so here are
that's the query about i one whole coconuts the subject and i want to know
basically everything that he does and you know to whom he does it
so you guys know the whole companies
OK so whole cogan
the whole coogan's one of most famous wrestlers in the world wrestling federation
because we've only as the whole cargo now we're getting all of the all the
relationships he that he participates in which the subject
and so those connections in this interface and then all the things that are the
in the in those relationships the tag cloud view here means that in the larger
font in bold are the kinds of things he tends to do more often in
the text
so we have more examples of that
we see the whole kogan abandons things
he announces things
he you know he what he what he does the most of his defeats things
OK and then we see the kinds of things he does things to two two
championships two under the giant bobby king and king kong bundy so if we now
go and expand on defeat
now we have a list organised everything the whole coogan's defeats stated wikipedia
with all the supporting text
so here we see whole coogan defeated bobby kennedy
and a one sentence that supports its hulk hogan defeated and this with bobby kennedy
to retain the worldwide federation championship
so this for different facts and you can look at them and see that they
in fact are the right kind of relationship and you know though in green we're
the actual entities bobby heine randy savage
ric flair roddy piper
and again we can actually look at
OK so it actually worked OK
so here's a organised list of basically just the answers
everybody the whole community to present as actually a table
direct becoming standard database so the interesting thing to note here is that this is
all done fully automatically directly from the raw text there is no knowledge in our
system about hulk hogan nor about what it means to defeat nor about any of
these other people as wrestlers the system is working on
really the the unstructured text and is largely driven by the syntactic analysis you know
how language actually works these are the kind of facts that come out adding in
these other reason this is actually mostly raw adding in the other resources from wordnet
or from other ontological resources only amplifies these kinds of things
OK as
another example the the exact same system we can now ask what the FDA approved
i have to use the federal drug agency
in america
so here we basically have a list generated automatically of all the things that the
FDA has approved in wikipedia
again i bolded or highlighted based on what things are most common
so you see many drugs
many the names of drugs many instances where something is the drug is being improved
you see medications
and treatments
all the way down there and again this is
well let's let's let's look at the question is some someone noted in the audience
that that marijuana
seems to have been approved by the FDA at least mention approval context i was
could take a look
this is the food and drug administration or comparable public authorities in western europe including
the netherlands however has not approved smoking marijuana for any condition or disease
OK so it is about marijuana being approved and in this interface that's what we're
showing up our system does actually tag the context so it is actually tag in
in a negated context in our database
so so you can see that this is not only a this is fun for
a lot of reasons it's an interesting thing navigate database like this in its own
right this is the kind of rich deep information is actually in the system and
also can serve as the basis for creating and extracting out facts and you can
use in you know
managing new kinds of ontologies as well
that leads to another example
we can ask the system what is it that we're dinosaurs the subject and the
relation is inclusion
so dinosaurs including some things and give us back all these different kinds of objects
with the query like that the system is able to automatically generate a list of
basically all of the kinds of dinosaurs
there's certainly some errors in this but it's quite large list
including house or
the answer is yes
antarctica antarctic so and so on
OK if we then go and say look to see what is it how the
system the dinosaur includes the genes up to x
there are three articles in wikipedia
and one is on the origin of birds one is an feathered dinosaurs one is
on dinosaurs and here you see the feathered dinosaurs discovered so far include in this
then the data as i said well this is isn't the nice model the data
because all the the data lies very close to the mean here
as measured by duration they all lie within maybe half duration
so the the likelihood of bigger
that's true but this is also not a very good model of the data
and the reason that is not a very good model the data is that the
variance is simply too big
this is a much better model of the data to be a good answer in
this case is to that the variance
that should get is for the maximum likelihood
then to be just the variance of the observation i just happened to get the
the even the most extreme data points has no
some of them from the so so why exactly is it i think going on
here but they're going wrong because of the normalisation property because this is the distribution
over data to make distribution to wide
then it can explain to many datasets
i this distribution will be able to explain a lot of other things as well
the mere fact that happens to explain the data
so what
if made it extremely wide
it'll explaining data which show
that's not very important
the important thing is somehow this the normalisation constant we decided write out the equation
this is very simple so
just assume there was zero mean
right now the log likelihood
log likelihood areas
obviously the the
in the log i assume independence would be a product of the like terms belong
to some
o like to get
data term
get a penalty term i get the point exactly the same equation that before
so in this case
things factorized things are independent the observations can be treated independently
the one i had before
in the in the in my model likelihood was that i had
i had a
and why
and in the y complexity term had the log of the determinant of k
in this case i just have to
the independent version of this is just
this is just the same as having having y times
and schemas ten y where you have
has been fixed zero which was an assumption here and where the web became matrix
is simply
i think
the the event
my complexity term here is now
a lot of time and the think in the determinant of
the diagonal matrix it's going to be
and time the what
i'd like to read
it's like it's exactly the same thing before
and that this is my data term i tell me how close to the data
point light the mean measured in terms of valuation
OK my complexity term
and it depends on the area
so this guy this model is too complex model can explain too many datasets
the winners winners
two excited about also being able to play out
but whether one of their the the top one is is is too small model
how can only explain
you know very particular data i e data that happen to be all very close
to zero
one four is a
one of the fuzzy
he is
he's on fire was also nice
universities this is tree
the first is
the first is for this
not only is the
you have this issue
you can
build the web site which we
one step further
or this professor was used for that
what i see
we want to find i found myself
OK so
the interesting
i think this
very fine you know if you have a year which
the number of years
the reason why is people because
you know
using this if you're lucky
if you were a certain number of years
but really
these are all things that changing genetic you must
we think this is the areas that i've seen papers so one this paper was
published you might search
well defined
we design
so i actually we want to be
he was us so that was my advisor
it to go down
but if i am wrong answers to the query would be do
all right
is that we can
the easiest thing is
if you want you
our approach
numbers are being
remember some of you are assumed to start at any time
then you have start ranking score is a whole
the first one i that
sometimes that's because some people do have bought licence you can see one find that
you see some people are saying this advisory is quite
and with this we construct the a frame
but a very important thing is we use a small number of constraints
well i went to want for this
you want to use the line
the answer
five one
we this
this was the advisor advisee relationship
for example
this should be the
is really
the other was
ninety eight years before
he is a long process
and also a
you know the rules
in different universities
so it's very hard for about a hundred years ago if you see something
use very simple rules we use only
that's not true
the rules one this
advisor advisee
i thought i
using this
long publication history for more papers
this user this is very
you do this
before he came to
following b
six or seven million
so i mean
but the the
so what you see the light same
the rules
the use of the IPC two thousand five hundred forty years history come back to
the vice prez
other thing is we use and also if you see the whites were not much
you also may be useful but we don't seem to be giving you us see
we have
one of the professor it's because the
he got five countries and the has of all
there are sixty five but
discussing basically piano arithmetic or
or something like that he had in mind a particular formal axiomatic theory
because proof you have to when you talk about something probably have to say from
what axioms using what methods the reasoning but you know it was clear when gold
this work that his methods were very general
you know
and but the problem was
the problem was was
i first went ghetto came up with this result in nineteen thirty one
mathematicians were profoundly shocked
this was like attacking you know attacking everything they believed in everything they thought was
true and beautiful
it was a tremendous shock
ghettos result that some mathematicians like roman vile you know to question if mathematics work
you know what it is mathematics if there are two assertions that you can prove
you know so
so this
this is really
was a terrible psychological shock
but then of course the second world war came the you know there were more
important things to think about like how to survive the war
and after the war
that generation of intellectuals sort of shifted disappeared from the scene
you know after the war people had more practical viewpoint they were interested in philosophy
people like einstein and herman violent david hilbert
ensuring that all people who
who were not only scientists and mathematicians but they
we're interested in philosophy and human culture in general but after the war
people became more special in that they didn't worry about these questions is much
but i'm stupid i worried about these questions
in spite of the fact that everybody said the you know the ghettos in communist
and basically is irrelevant
and that we should keep doing come out the way we've always done it i
felt that there was
the the cattle had come discovered something really
and that it meant that you should do mathematics differently now what do i mean
by doing mathematics differently
well the extreme case of doing mathematics differently and let me give an example let's
say that i have mathematics class
and i have a homework assignment or a question on an exam which is proof
that the search results
or disprove proven or disproven some mathematical assertions
you know when i i work on you know maybe overnight homework or during exam
or maybe i take it home and i worry about it i work on it
for a week or two
and i can prove the results and i can prove the contrary i can settle
the question
well if you really believe in general if you take it as an extreme licence
for anarchy you could say well it's not my fault
probably this result
is a mathematical truth is unprovable
it's not my fault i didn't find approval is just added as a new axiom
you know
i mean that would be one possible interpretation of incomplete results
i mean it would be to say that if
for example you could take the experiment hypothesis remains hypothesis has to do with prime
numbers and it looks like it's true
doing calculations of primes calculating zeros a function the remark about this seems to be
pragmatically it's it's it's very valuable because it explains views of the remaining about this
is you can prove a lot of things about the distribution of primes which seems
to be true but no one can prove itself is would say the remain hypothesis
it is pragmatically justify you know it works
it explains alot
they want care if tomorrow you you you refute to remain hypothesis this happens in
the world of physics
now pure mathematicians are horrified they say if there is no proof
it's garbage is meaningless and they don't care
you calculated i don't know how many cases and all the special cases seem to
follow the law
if you can prove it they don't care how much evidence computational evidence there
they're only interested in approved
but his don't work that way
and since i grew up studying mathematics and physics with equal
you know i find it a little difficult to understand why physicists are satisfied
with the evidence
of this so i mathematicians are
you see
now let me let me say in advance all of these views that i'm telling
you now are just my personal view
and i think it's fair to say
there i say with a little bit of pride i shouldn't but i'm persona non
grata in the mathematics community
i'm sort of in hiding in the physics department of my laboratory
and the physicist and like my ideas because i
one of my conclusions as you can see
is it may be pure map should be done little bit more like experimental physics
now this is like this because pure mathematicians usually look down at physicist
because they say the proof that you have in physics are really not rigorous you
and so i think his i get invited to a lot of physics meetings because
seem to like
you know my saying that you're not is not that different maybe from from physics
and you don't have absolute certainty
is is and maybe should
you should use experimental methods in experimental evidence sometimes if you can find proof
and physicists to be sympathetic to this because they've always been doing this
and you know in physics and i'm saying maybe you should do a a little
was even worse is following dancing because there are many things structure if the data
data laser scale of the data in this way
after mean the way we make totally miss the the war
but there's also a lot of stuff to duality about wikis to help that context and become better
in the literature and many people saying that each tried explain this idea to be
concerned about the model for example in two thousand now we have a paper using
this idea to really concerned about a model for other things
but all these prior work
i purely based on to be addition they usually produce a beta edition that's suitable
for ground level but not necessary for our viewpoint
in this approach we want to impose the regularity over the
global scale you can see
that's all the proposed is inverse yes you are going
the reason is that
has to start with the way going to produce representation for the city
this complication here
by combining silver bullet especially those appear mixed race
i just say in following the author manhattan structures so you can basically use to
to approximate many things for example we have this new this paper
talking about how to be able to work effectively endorsing so i'm going to use
q learning his trade taste artists once more mixtape i'm going to be said q
so the idea is to combine bottom up top down but we want to go
in they are but not just run from there because if it if we call
it by its then we start simple problem and the system tend to be more
so here is a side view of the data point when rectified to the gravity direction
i we can compute the well points along the vertical direction
and then we can size
now for each the size of the data we want to
because of the shaped in
because of the to be shaped to represent the model
i wanted and hope better primitive and choose a subset to represent state
so if it points in the figure rising to poised and from that can go from eyes
and then we tell which was the success of the rectangle today presenter hosting with
start from nothing but one that and go it's time to represent a whole say
we do the same thing for each size we sometimes enable subject interceptor poll
to the space
we want the state to is appended data well to have spent a free space
laser pointer also at the same time being
love you
so far other data points
you say policy space and say they just cannot hear if used to automate the
i mean they involved and they both about noted that tell you the traditional density
location point city okay so that's a city points but he also attended the
it the space is free between the data center and also the between the data center turned
city deploys
so with this in mind we can define an objective function owing to say stop
to explain free space laser pointer regularity well
and now we have a model a model for other to decide we want our
model fuzzy the whole city pikoli's well doing the same thing
the first is used to generate the
this yes to model
new member that we have a conductor to this model but we don't know how i of the
well we don't know the height of those
ten goes so we want to infer the industry by trying all possible combinations of the height
a little of the into the hypothesis space and our greedy algorithm to optimize the same objective function again
together say
this is the if you see
this is studied our
this is studied the other
that's that's only going to be more the deceiving the model
which is we our ideas
i which is actually more that we can do something even more interesting for example
if you know the viewpoint beforehand it can both the
knowledge about facing want to increase the visibility of the space
are you can simply impose the model ontology out features so that you can see the
and the indoor model at the same time
i even superimposing ontology i so there you can see the model and read the text at the same time
so to control way
we have
traditionally we have about image out of bellevue they're fighting against each other
but with the google maji out you can actually
combined low-level navigation on the elbe navigation as well
but what you are saying so far we only have the low-level navigation and this
paper proposes a way to produce album
navigation system playing dancing at time we also talk about how do we combine the
global view and our view in this in this way so they perform as well
to how you understand why this matters of best played this game has to go
to this new you're going to go from this point to the point
in the standard school was image it was conditional bubble by bubble moving around them
in most already few data because well you know i'm not sure that that's the other patients in eventually
he was able to get to the point of inches
but with our system since become much simpler
well our system since the most important thing just in winter the space flying but
julijana all this level that will create new that immediately
so to conclude we have to attend college to contribution in this paper the technical
contribution is inverse yesterday geometry large-scale conduction
the conceptual contribution is in the hotel did this to map what al with alan well-tended show effective navigation
this corresponding to the conduction band these ideas and part i want to add that
maybe we diversity conductor system which also keep in my how it is going to
be used albedo lies in the latest that's what changed things about
this article is corresponding due to major goal computer
missing see human see better
in some money we just try to get a little bit because many many times you may
okay would be my consequent research agenda to make myself become superman
i'm going to say whole matter in amazing people contribute to this party as well
and this is a summary departed wellington will supervise yes full color who is looking
for more intense when the next summer so please stop working
if you identities
well this conclude the first in on friday i'm going to continue the second part
of my talk on the video i was at the time all the way do
in this reason you would expect it to
be able to recover weak boundaries
to give you may be a clear picture of what that would be produces little
diagram imagine we just have this
lattice graph with two seeds red and blue and there's the boundary
which is solid except for a whole
if we want to label
this pixel here
i can imagine that the random walker
has to take one of four steps initially through those four steps
keep it inside this red region
and only one of those four steps brings it through into the school region
when we compute the probabilities
this red this pixels going to say
roughly three-quarters red one quarter blue
but exactly the opposite is true for a random walker starting on the other side
of the gap
three out of its four initial steps will keep in the blue region
one step will bring into the red region
this picks also three-quarter blue one quarter read this one says
three quarter red one quarter blue
and when we do the labeling we pick up this boundary
implicitly even though
there's a gap there
so in order to to illustrate this
on synthetic image
generated this image myself it's completely or almost completely white
and then i drew these black lines to try to
four different regions of different size and shape
this one is concave
then i completely erased
pieces of the boundary
and introduced seeds
some are large summer small somewhere close to the boundaries further away and the shading
reflects the label and produced by the random walker so you can see that the
i don't know how clear it is but the
captures this region the blue labeling captured this region
and green
so this is a key property of y random walks are good for segmentation
key property is noise robustness
it makes sense why this should be true right so if you knew
that a given pixel was likely to send random walker two
red seventy percent of the time and centre in market to green thirty percent of
the time
then you would imagine that if you added noise new randomly perturbed the walk of
that a random walker who was otherwise walking randomly that
if it was likely to get to read first the first time that it's still
going to be likely to get to read first the second factor you can actually
show this analytically
other properties of our
segmentation algorithm find like this is that segmented regions are always connected to a seed
which means that if any pixel gets labelled green then there's an unbroken
passive green label pixels all the way back to green seed
if you take a blank image
this image is completely black
exp the segmentation that you'll get will look something like on
if the image is pure noise the expected segmentation that you get is also for
so to go back to this example of the
two triangles the weak boundary
i said that with graph cuts you have this small cut problem if you introduce
one seed
but you see the
that this problem is is not present with the random walk because it's not trying
to minimize the boundary
the boundary length and operates under different process
additionally even though this is the four connected graph you don't see this kind of
metrication problem
in addition the random walker gives you confidence level on
the segmentation
which is not present with graph cuts graph you just have label one or zero
foreground background
confidence is helpful in many
real scenarios because for example if you want to smooth your segmentation
you can just
blur this
probability map and
that will
smooth more in regions that it's less confident and smooth less regions that it more
additionally in visualization or now formatting you can interpret this transparency parameter
in addition as mentioned with graph cuts the
there's a limitation
in trying to extend more than two labels
you can do it but it's approximative and the different algorithms and it's complicated
with the random walker idea that there is no difference between two labels ten labels
are an arbitrary number of labels
now as i mentioned previously with
the blank image or the all noise image
this you get
these vaughan i like facts
these effects happen locally too
in fact we can interpret
what's going on here as a a little patch of uniform image placed on the
and in that unknown region you get some solutions the centre
you can do the same thing with noise
and you can take this
same situation except now instead of uniform
you can put a big block of noise down
and the segmentation you get looks like this
so no
other words there's no
modeling going on here there's no
filtering or doesn't
i'm not telling you
how to distinguish noise from structure
it does that on its own based on on the random walk process and
it doesn't know it's looking for triangles either
in other words what's going on here is where the data is good
you get a segmentation it fits the data where the data is poor you get
something that
is in the middle
and just to show you there's no
specialization for on axis noise are diagonal lines
you can rotate the situation and you get the same behavior
this kind of
the property of being able to detect weak boundaries is absolutely essential
real image segmentation
for example in the CT image we have a tumor lung tumor
which is attached to the wall of the long
but that the actual tissue composition of the tumor
as far as x-rays go
is the same as the tissue composition of the wall so there's really there's no
absolutely no
boundary contrast here to indicate
where the wall
enough for getting
played by humans so very natural music there are also many other people working on
computer music but from one expressive point of view
roger dannenberg CMU suzuki first well by sharing agreement on the weekends as you want
the pali like what and that they have also been doing some interesting work on
computer music performance
but of course i don't have time to go over all these work
our own approaches the idea is to do
well these were based on rules
is interesting
there are often there are things that are very difficult to verbalize and therefore to
to find rules for the there's a lot of musical knowledge that is not
not explicit on the on in the score
that human musician if you ask him or her
here she will not be able to to verbalize y
what is he what is she or he do it
on the other hand the limitation of using data mining or inductive learning techniques for
is that expressive effects that appear very
are very rarely can not be caught by these techniques
but that doesn't mean something that is does not repeat about an hour some effect
that does not repeat often that does not mean that is not significant as a
very interesting paper raise your hand shows in the journal of machine perception so we
thought that my pieces left out alternative would be to directly use the knowledge which
is implicit in in performing in performing examples
so take taken recordings of human performances and an adopt some completely different approach that
imitating the way a human performer performs computer performance especially music and that's when we
started quite already in nineteen ninety seven with my colleagues articles in javier said
to develop a project called saxex that they will get so immediately into some details
then this was followed by tempoexpress
with some lessons learned from this axis experience
made us to follow up with tempoexpress
with nothing left to
and of course and right now we are involved in this guitarlab project that i
will i hope i will be able to tell you a little bit about way
i within the cost
interesting results to show
not only is i can give you a hint of what is behind this price
what is the difference of you love
well with respect to the previous projects also
just one minute of case reasoning
i assume that everyone
moreno's model what i can get back that that's why i will spend only one
women so problems in case there is no are sold by adapting solutions to similar
problems that have been talked already in the past
so this precedent based reasoning so so you have a bunch of problems with this
associated solutions in in in in the memory of cases
and when we have a new problem
if you look for the most similar problem among those that are already in in
memory that have been shown
you're it if this most similar problems
you extract the solutions
and you adopt this solution to find
the new solution to the new problem right normally always need to that is that
there is almost never the case that the solution as is is is is valid
so there is this user of the station is step
which is also generally followed by the way your revision step
that should validate solution
and when after about after validation
the new problem solution pair
is memorized in the case memory
and ready
for future use for future retrieval
so you the experience of the of the system she is is somewhat is is
now let's go into saxex the first of the project the goal of this system
is to transform
in inexpressive
which is given as an input to the system into an expressive trends so we
want to improve
this the specific
then tell you already know that the in the input
inexpressive melody i should say almost in inexpressive
because the input is given
by human players
playing in expressive
but this this is a very hard task
it's very hard to ask human player say OK now play completely in this presently
this is the first so after that the
sometimes hours of
well we managed to get some input of quite a few got quite a few
don't depend on the test points
since we
i have this in terms of the products we can substitute kernel functions for the
products what you get is the solution here
and that's the decision was made to function of decision function
the function that will take
the value plus one on this half space and minus one on the space
derivation is pretty straightforward
and i haven't gone into detail on it but
actually i would like to have some
involvement of the audience now
because i find especially in the morning if i just listen to a lecture and
getting tired properties so
i'll take a few minutes off in let you derive this
but i would like to like to derive its in a slightly different way so
what i did was actually a bit complicated but to compute the spectre in this
picture of the product
there's more direct way of doing it which is simply to compute the distance between
c plus index
and to compute the distance between c-minus index
to take the difference of these two distances
two depending on whether
one distances larger all the other one is difference is positive or negative
so but this this is different
into the sign function we should actually get the same solution
so i'll tell you get what you can do
and so i'll give you five minutes and everybody can tried and then we can
do it together on the back wall
so what you do is you take to to spector
compute the different distances between
two plus x
and the distance between c minus next
and then you take the difference between the two sisters distances
and as one more additional hint if you use that
we should be using the squared distance it's easier because the squared distance
can be computed using the product easily
OK so any more questions before you
starts to your algebra
and people