so the deed
is one point five metres
and the frequency three thousand
so we do this experiment of
so let them
it is about eleven point three centimetres if you take forty the second one
so we have way monochromatic light monochromatic
more or less
one wavelength and so you can calculate lambda divided by d is
o point o seven five
so you can calculate where now those surfaces are
they i really surfaces
they're coming out from the center you and they inventing the new directions where all
those hyperbolic services are there is no sound
and then you can calculate all those hyperbolic surfaces are
first calculate how many probable surfaces they are
so in order to do that we simply have to
stake in our crazy
the sign theta equals and one that we just put in data is the maximum
value possible
and that is
ninety degrees
so you put theta max
and that is ninety degrees
over two
so when you do that you'll find that and max
that the highest number of n
in that series zero one two three four five
and max
it is then divided by lambda
in our case
is about thirty
it is one of these not
but it means there are thirty of those services going in this direction
but also thirteen going in this direction and we have lots mine so you really
have to multiply this by two
and so to twenty six services no more
and probably no less
in this audience of
contructive interference and then they probably also around twenty six
that's struck interference
now i want to be
as qualitative as i can
and i would like to know
students who are sitting
about five metres away
what the distances between one maximum zero to maximum right at the center and the
to get an idea of where to search for those
for those minima
so i'll go now four
the maximum
so i know that they zero
right here
all of you use it you must maximum display
the question is what the next
the next maxima depends of course on the distance how far you're sending away from
so i think this is what i'm about five meters away
the site of you what
this one makes reference to any one of the first surface away from the
design of data one is then o point o seven five
that translates
in two value of data
i think it's about four point three
so now you can calculate
what the separation is
between one maximum and the next maximum that separation x one
i call it x y
is roughly l
by that point o seventy five
that is about
thirty eight percent
so right there those guys and i'm looking at now
you will have the maximum sound you when you will find it's image you'll have
another maximum and the minimum in between
so the minima and maximum right there
religiosity is about nineteen seventy four you lay in the back it large
and for you here in front it is small
because remember those services like this and so separation is small i just give you
this as an example that you know roughly in order of magnitude of what you
looking for
i'm going to turn on the sound
and then i want you to
we go back and forth
you did when you were nursery school
and i want you to
find the locations of maxima and minima
and i can assure you that the ones with minimum
the ones with some science it's you a
well defined because of course we have done this several times ourselves don't move too
fast move very slowly
there will be points
where you here
no sound there will be when you look for
also you will find
i was able to clearly
this thing with the maximum from the minimum
not too many
the reason is that all you allows scientists
if the difference
is based maximize is nineteen seventy
there is this much
what is the separation between you two years
about twenty centimetres
well actually the actual
so if you have the maximum you would have a minimum there so what have
we have to do
you have to close
then you will be real scientists so i'm going to turn it back on again
i wanted to close one year
and then you will be able
to find those minima in those
again back and forth maybe some reflections from the wall
may interfere with this experiment no
one was an
well that was all the more the other is not
the model
so are now
there you go
all right this is the great moment for the years
many break
many chris
so if someone could help me
o u
regarding them to use the histogram
of example two
what is interesting
anyway helpful to me
it's almost by bimodal
now we have forty seven percent to go in the court
of which forty percent is for the final
so clearly i can't say much about dividing line ABCD is in and
i want to make only global state
and only one those of you who i put in the danger zone
danger zone for me
students whose cumulative assuming that they've taken all the examples
red and black
nature is the red black tree
not every tree can be labelled as the red black tree right
it it is good practice because
sort of thing shows up increases
make a thread
and then everything else black
that's that's certainly solution
because then that basically brings the level of the sky up here
actually i had a more complicated one because it seemed like more fun
so what i did was i mean this guy black
OK and these two guys read
black and
your solutions perfectly good as well
so we don't have any to read zero on any path
and all
the black height from any particular point going down we get the same number of
whichever way we go
so good
so the idea here now is that we're going to keep the subtree sizes
these are the keys there are stored in our
in our dynamics that we keep the subtree sizes in the red black tree
so for example this guy has size one
these guys have size one because the leaves
and we just work
OK so this is size three
this guy is size five
this guy has size three
this guy has five plus three plus one is nine
so in general have
size of x
is equal to
left index
class sizes
plus one
that's how i computed recursively
so very simple
formula for the sizes
it turns out that for the code that we're going to want to write to
these operations
we're going to
it's going to be convenient to be talking about the size of no
so what's the size of no
OK size of no
there's no elements there
however if i
in most programming i i take size now
well happen
that's kind convenient so what i have to do in my code is everywhere that
size of nil
that i might want to take sides if now like to say
or take the size of anything i to say well if it's now
then return
zero otherwise
return to the size field et cetera
there's an implementation tricks that were used
to simplify that scored using a sentinel
seven knows nothing more than a dummy record
so instead of using an ill will actually use and nielsen
we use the dummy record
four nil
such that size
is equal to zero
instead of any place i would have use no in the tree
instead all have special records
but i call now
but it would be a whole record and that way i can set its sights
field to be zero
and then i don't have to check that is a special case
and that's a very common type of programming trick to use two sentinels to simplify
to simplify code so you have all these
boundary cases are don't have to right next to function
when all i want to do is just index the size of some everybody with
me on that
OK so let's write the code for OS select
given this
and this is going to basically give us the
i smallest
in the subtree
so it's actually going to be
a little more general
so if i want to find implement the OS select i have up there i
basically given the route
and i
but we're going to build this recursively so it can be helpful to
r two
i have the node in which we're trying to find the subtree
then the approaches in the literature can be classified look and mobile according to whom
if they look a solution for one pixel without looking there is that the solution
on the rest of the image
or global approach of course the global approach are not good in our framework because
there is very time consuming even if they are better in case of uniform
but that's incident is the problem of local approaches
in the summer of
out of the selected algorithms
as is said the p a g g c and d f that is that
all these algorithms need stronger constraints on the e
two major sometimes they are not good for real applications because they have not alone
sufficient time
as is city the is called for these a goal but is not to go
going the uniform uniform part and in case of local perturbations between the left and
right to
for example
if we have
a uniform but it's not very easy for to matching find the correspondence on a
few of the pixel inside the effect the dynamic programming give this kind of results
that is not good because the object is in front of the world
and it's the
it's not good this representation in another problem
can be in real applications for robots can produce produces mechanical vibration and the algorithm
for example in this case is the
SS city algorit can have problem in the results
time consuming and that's the end we can have
some problem if the two images this therapy is acquired with different conditions like life
focus on the third edition was
for these reasons
our approach wants to all represents the history major as
a as a graph and we provide a graph matching between
regions and not some not yet between points in the stereo image in this case
we we we want to do
use this integral approaches and in order to resolve some problems in uniform idea
in case of lot colour or global perturbation between their steps
so we start from the projection of the region and not
on and on the projection of the points in the scene and we we define
an approximation of this but the properties that these days
this early or is the displacement of a wall regions and not yet of point
fact the disparity map is defined as the autism the displacement of each point of
each corresponding the corresponding point in the left and right image in our definition despite
is defined on marriage and not yet on a point
i want to
represents the stale be as
so we have left graph and the right to have and we provide a stable
the graph matching between these image
yeah it
the fine segmentation process is the it is composed
i'll show you immediately nothing to do with my talk it's not likely to play
and probably we cannot distribute but you can find future
so i'd really like this clip show you this
the song coming up
probably it
can you
you can hear i
can you see it
i just always
the science students telling them what algorithms that you know he's a machine how do
you react two numbers
use that because it is
so you're experts
is what you know a lot of work is taking place
theoretical point statistics
i of course machine learning the dealing with lots of data sets coming from domains
so today i'm going to look at a particular aspect of data mining is called
contrast data mining
and that's what we're going to look at
i have you know when you work for so many years will have lots of
and colleagues who we work with and my main collaborator was james bailey who is
senior lecturer
he was one of my
phd students
and then i was doing he used to be called
melbourne but now he's at wright state university in the US
so what is the contrast contrast is to compare or appraise in respect to differences
so this is the definition of
it within in the dictionary
in contrast data mining is the mining of patterns all models
contrasting two or more classes of conditions
so will will look at more details as we go through
i think in the fuzzy two thousand one
derby s is sometimes it's good to contrast
what you like with something else it makes you appreciate it even more
now is interesting thing is that you know we all
you know very well that you know when you
go to an environment
from different environment first time you noticed lots of differences
but very soon you get it just torso so for example
she came from a very cold country and in one place
the first two days with miserable and afterward it's very not
just to give you an example you know what i my like
colleagues who came from denmark
the first winter
in australia was it's like somebody in
so he started wearing no
now almost like t-shirts sensing lights
was signed for the first three
next winter he was put really radiator causing room in the same danish guy
so we already lost his contract because the transition already took place
the contrast is the the changes that we see that that's the one that makes
you know the
some kind of
a difference that makes us to notice these things and similarly you know we you
know if you look at entropy in know anything highly probable
i tend to have low entropy then
an improbable ones
so so that's where the contrast come into play
so what can we contrast so for example we could contrast objects at different times
for for example it's a
you know one of the conferences i go to these international conference on data mining
so let's say you wanted to see
what are the differences between the paper was later published
during the conference you know the year two thousand six to two thousand eight
versus those
the speed of two thousand three to
two thousand five
so you may be interested in knowing for example they may be
you know when you're looking at this conference the contrast could be in terms of
the authorship for example
maybe in a new place came into into this
this area or
it is not publishing any more you might want to know why this is happening
could that be that ATA is no more interest or could that be something more
so interesting thing is that in the international conference on data mining
around i think two thousand six they introduced the
blind referee until then
when you submit a paper you actually put your name your applications and so forth
from two thousand six onwards double-blind that means you don't put your affiliations i'm you
also should not leave any traces in the paper the paper belongs to you sometimes
it's very hard to make a hundred percent
so i think a lot for the intro guys so i'm coats and as i mentioned i'm
currently post-doc at stanford and also a visiting scholar at
indiana university bloomington
i'm going to talk about here is actually
try to
get good be a little different from the abstract in fact i want to change things try
to get enough inherent amount of time we get
one of the things i'm going to try to go through real slowly as those very basics of
what we want machine learning to do wise deep learning important
try to give you some of the basic tools for actually doing some deep learning yourselves
and there's sort of a story many of you may have heard about about unsupervised learning and feature learning
and i'll try to get to the end
but i want to make sure to go through some of the low level stuff to
give you an idea for how actually use these things so that
when you go home
and look at some of the resources that are going to have a link to the
end of the talk
you'll be able to go do online tutorial and actually play with some of these things even have enough
knowledge behind you reduce real applications
so i want to start to motivate all this stuff
by sort of
time about what is it that we want machine learning to do especially with computer vision
are the basic idea is that we have these applications were some input like
in image and we want to do something like object recognition we want to be able to
look at this low level pattern to make predictions about
what's what's going on so for example an object recognition we want to predict
whether there's a cat in the image are not
for something like detection
the output as a little different we want to be able to
look at this image and figure out that this is the location of bicyclist
and for more sophisticated applications for instance segmentation
maybe went on to look at this image and figure out the outline of the birds
outline of the objects in the scene
it's called f
n one of the
one of the sort of common approaches to machine learning
and other a whole bunch of different ways of solving these problems but a pretty large
number of these approaches
are sort of covered by common pipeline we take this
input example image of a cat let's say
and then we have
some sort of black box system
that extracts features tries to extract some sort of higher-level patterns
and then we usually have some final off the shelf machine learning algorithm that we just drop all this information
into and tries to learn to make decisions
starting from the sort of higher level representation so we might want to machine learning algorithm tell us
is this cat picture in this image
and the the thing that ends up taking all of our time causes a lot of grief
or is this feature extraction piece
because you know we can try to get pretty sophisticated here sometimes
you'll see this box
taking on some pretty complex engineering we're trying to build
several layers in fact
of increasingly high level abstractions
and the way that we do that as we try to take all our prior knowledge
about the world how images work what we might see images
and so forth and somehow wire them into this box
and it turns out that if you do a really good job then you can get great results
but if you're not computer vision expert you have done this before
the you can end up with a really terrible results
so this sort of
starting point for talking about deep learning what deep learning is and why we hope this can work because
we like to do is keep the same kind of pipeline
this basic idea
that we want to take our input image
and then feed it through several modules where we're going to extract higher and higher
level features
so we might start with some low level features like detecting edges in an image
and then we want to move to
sort of middle level features like recognizing parts
and so forth to maybe some higher level structures like recognizing objects and then at the very end
only very and we're going to have some classifier
that make some application-specific decision
like is this cat
where the outlines of object and so on
and the basic idea is that whenever we build these pipelines we're
going from sort of low-level ideas getting more and more abstract representation as we go up
and where we normally build that by hand
we want to somehow train these multiple layers from data
and try to discover representation so that by the time we get to the high-level features out here
if we just train a classifier on the and
we can make really good decisions
so the idea behind deep learning is to figure out a way
to train this whole pipeline systems and i have to engineer them so much by hand
it's worth asking why is it
just upfront
why do we want to even do this deep learning thing
there's a handful of sort of
a simple justifications
one is that we just know sort of
inherently from working on this for so many years that
some decisions just require a lot of stages of processing
it's very unlikely that i can see an image and decide whether there's catenin imager dog the image just
with linear function somehow to simple we know that can be that simple
and all the systems we currently have no matter how we built
involved many different stages of processing
so we sort of know that we want this long pipeline of decision making
but unfortunately
trying to engineer that by hand is quite difficult
we already have been intuitively engineering these sorts of things in computer vision for quite a while so if
we're already building these kinds of architectures a very natural thing to try to do is
them and you even for playing l of last
in the fifties conjugate gradient came around this gave a run time of
and square
the analysis i guess we didn't finish that but because the convergence rate
and then lipton rozen tarjan proved that any planar graph can be done and at
one point five
as we've talked about
vida then gave algorithm using preconditioned iterative methods which is and at one point two
then using low stretch spanning trees bill mnteng show how to get this down to
and log square and
more recently we've shown
that you can actually get the standard linear time so it's known that any plane
linear system that can be solved in linear time
so that's the punchline is that says that if you want to do a forward
multiply an inverse power
up to constants those are all the same so
you should then
and let me show you some examples actually quantify the exact cost of doing an
inverse power forward power but this is in these cases that
and there a cost about the same
so but i should point out that this is a very famous result in this
area and this is this film tag and what they were able to show
is that
if you take any love lost in
you can solve this in time and place and n plus an remember and the
number of variables and the number of non zeros in the matrix and the twiddle
here means that we're ignoring warnings and i think it's film and pointed out
in this talk yesterday
and the number of locks somewhere
bigger than twenty nine right
so this is not exactly practically the some huge number of logs but at least
theoretically this is very interesting because it it says that with more work
chances are the right answer is that it and log in with some very few
laws try and i'll show you some experiments on
we've done with others other solvers OK
so let's let's go back and actually look at
this solver
good is actually developed to solve at CMU
using what we call coming from multigrid and
we compare this to the matlab solver and what's interesting here is that the math
and this is for two d
which will talk about more
you can see that this is slightly better method than the other
what's interesting here is that what happens in the matlab solve at least for the
machines we have
is some is very quickly we end up running out of
two you can see the numbers here and so i think this is about somewhere
o point seven million variables
this thing starts to break down right we can no longer solve these things OK
because we run out of memory that
great seems like the direct methods of anything that's the one downside they quickly run
out of memory
so in three d
again and millions of variables here so what happens is that we can get this
nice linear
so this is in seconds
to solve one of these systems and you can see the matlab quickly just runs
out of memory because again we said if you're doing direct methods
that the film is going to what's going to cost that and three have so
these things run out of memory and crashed right so
these are
see OK
so i guess what i'd like to do and it anyway so that's our solar
stuff and so the hope was eventually try to get solvers out because like and
this an natural community there we should have access to good solvers
but i'd like to do that we spend a few minutes on
how some
one generalization that we have the full posterior
and unfortunately i don't know any interesting applications in one of the reason i want
to do this year's hopefully in showing you this reduction
one of you
are many of you will see how to apply this to machine learning so
let's assume that i
then instead of being a gravel pos in this is simply a symmetric diagonally dominant
system right this simply means that the diagonal then is greater than or equal to
the sum of the soft the absolute value of the soft corals OK
so the goal of the rest of this talk tends to show that these systems
calculate very easily being
with regards to this matter
reaches the neutron star
the kinetic energy one of these grids
must be equal to
and ng over are
we have this equation on the blackboard last lecture when we discussed cosmology with the
same equation
this is the speed
which which the matter will fall onto the neutron star
this is the mass of the neutron star and this is the radius of
you lose the masses you always do so you can calculate
this despite this being is around this
because the ratings of neutron star
so ridiculously small mass of a neutron star is very comparable to the mass of
the sun and the larger
not much larger but the radius is hundred thousand times smaller than that of the
o to ten kilometres
and as a result of that
speed which which the matter it's the neutron star is about one-third of the speed
of light
but it's the neutron stars
this kinetic energy
is converted to heat
it will heat up the surface layers of the neutron star
and increases the temperature to about
ten million nine hundred million degrees
and at such high temperatures
the starwood image almost all its radiation
in x-rays and other optical sun is relatively cold
only six hundred six thousand degrees
and so
the sun
as most of its radiation in the optical but when the temperature becomes ten million
hundred million degrees
a function only of the data but in the but Bayesians can use the parameters as
well because we are we quantifying the variability over that parameter so you you select that measure well we'll
we'll call it D and find it's predictive distributions under the model so what is and that's a
Bayesian numerical computation and then we we actually have some data so
we replace X by X obs the observed data on which we find out where does
that observed value that discrepancy measure lie in that distribution and so we can conduct a
formal test of significance and of course reject if the discrepancy measures is up in the upper tail and
this is this is very are flexible because you can choose a discrepancy measure focused on the
the the act avt the facet of the model predictions that you most you must
worry about that's the thing that's the most relevant to you in the future
you serve a rather you have another choice and that is under what under
what distribution do you evaluate this predictive because there's an issue of potentially doubly
using data and is quite a rich literature taken back thirty years now of different choices
some are which example are rather conservative thate there they are rather tolerant rather insensitive at at
detecting a detecting problems because effectively they are doubly using data so there's you know quite a rich layer
area there and I'm not gonna say anything more about it but this
has you know this has been done but these all these things of course obey
and aim the prediction that that's that's what it's for so they tell you something about the
quality or goodness of fit of the model globally but they don't tell you where there
might be problems and they don't help you do anything about it so much
more recently there've been a rise in interest in methods that are node-based they they they
they they look at a particularly variable in in the model I'd I say no because I don't think in ever
represented on a graph and they try and say what's the what's the problem
around here there are various approaches being considered again sort of getting
back towards P value type calculations which are are local to that specific node
but we we felt that all of these methods were kind of a little
bit uninformative there that there they thay they formally give P value
type assessments but they don't realy tell you qualitatively what the problem is so we wanted to
go back to basics and think about prior likelihood conflict and try to think about
how you could examine that perhaps graphically in in a complex model so the
the simplest situation is this one this is one where you don't need any new
technology okay so you have which way around is it the a complete trivial model
we have ten observations from a normal distribution with known variants and the blue curve
there is the plot of the likelihood function the the the the likelihood of the
data as a function of the parameter theta which is the unknown mean the data meaning was
twelve so of course that blue curve is set to noumber twelve now that the prior I
used in in this particular case was a normal distribution also but we mean eight and that's yellow yellow curve
so the a bayes theorem does it's work and you multiply
these two together and renormalize and that gives the uncoloured curve in the middle
okay so bayesian is really going good you you can throw anything into
it and it will produce some inference for you but how comfortable should you be about that
inference in this kind of situation where really the two sources of information your
your scientific judgments about sorry this one your scientific judgments about the parameter before you
had data are completely in conflict with those after you had the data okay is it are are you
comfortable with letting bayes theorem make that choice when really what it's doing is taking
two functions and multiplying them together and thyy they're almost always something very very tiny
but it's renormalized and you and you get the curve out of it the overlap between the two is
very small and the I've drawn in a very symmetric way but of course you get
the same sort of thing when you vary the variances and the overlap can easily
be even smaller so as a bayes theorem is a bit too good at his job
okay it it it part it yields you an inference without telling you that perhaps something there's something else in
there maybe you should reexamine your assumptions now I'm not saying throughout this section and I'm
not saying you're assumptions were wrong I am just saying saying you shouldn't make that assumptions and not have
it drawn to your attention that there's in conflict so that you have a
chance to reconsider so we want to do that sort of thing everywhere in a complex model
and the language we need to to talk about such things is again
the language of graphical models so graphical models in this context here are graphs
in which the the nodes of the graph the vertices of the graph represent variables and
some of those some of those variables are connected by edges that may
be directed or undirected and then we observe some of the some some
what without and manfred positive
because what you
notice there is one zero one zero
one zero
is forty two in binary
and although
any comments questions everyone with me
so i
but i selection to the game sixty three
and observation we can make is about
if you want to be sure identifying an outcome in this alphabet
then it will take you six binary questions to
be sure about identifying it
we could have a think about these claims at the shannon information content let's call the uncertainty to
the first question he wrong
it is three three four and so on
the answers to these
question is
shannon information content all
each of these answers
each time you ask the question i question
you know what i was thinking of those fifty fifty
well the answer be
be shannon information content about outcome walls
log ways to one over the probability the outcome
which was one of whatever happened
that's lot to
this one bit
the total information content according to shannon you've got
but you're going to
throughout the whole
thrilling game
mistakes that
i mean
the string announces that you got
eighty six
is an encoding objects
call see annex
what that's the string six socio forty two
last one zero one zero one zero so
when making a connection to
the question is if you get outcome you can compress it intersects the
and six expenses and information content and making sense there's nothing very surprising happening here
this is very weak evidence for the idea
john information content is looking promising
why is it a good strategy to split
it into space everything into
some people
sale why don't you ask first is a prime number
why is it a good idea to split exactly into
it's got maximum information content maximum explore the information content if you have any other questions the probabilities
it wouldn't be
of all
in general say you're not getting as much as expected information as you could the
chance the answer might be in the big set out to your in fact is
better than fifty fifty chance it will be and that's and then you need more
than the remaining whatever it would have been five questions
let's ask you one question based on this game and then do another game
and right
such is the question
if i've got a set with the best possible outcomes in it
how many bits long beach name be
if every outcome is gonna have a unique name okay so the question is
i'm gonna draw
on the way home
and i want to be thorough and systematic and give everyone these unique name so
i can record on facebook which clothing and wearing today
i'm gonna write little names on them
and the question is
if i'm going to post on facebook be
namely to these items
and there are
capital assets
different pieces of underwear
how long does it should be these binary names have to be assuming i give
them all binary names are the same
habitat geneva
how long the mine labels need to be
to label my underwear
and outcome from the set can be encoded can be communicated in how many bits
one way to
all this ended up some not any alternative answer
that's what they rounded up a in case this is an integer number sixty four
six which is not can be
in general so sixty seven or something
well rounded up bit so maybe we need to go up by almost one
and we collapse
feeling this symbol means
which means
the number rounded up to the nearest integer
so let's definitely
so the answer after for being obsessive we see longer just to make sure all
we've got the right engine
like saying you need to hurry up to not miss your bus or there's no
parking in this parking lot you should rewrite and self evolving by by changing services
benefits are emergency management traffic management and and mobile commerce
but a location-based advertisment for example so this is all
an ecosystem which thrives on this real time data which is not that today but
we have several cities trying to to invest in that
IBM's smarter planet initiative you might have have heard about so big advertising buzzwords is
going in this direction smart electronic health
many diseases require personalized treatment on real time data so you could have a small
sensors which you wear
which help you by by
processing on on on the a wearable computer to deal with this and and to
like increase of your illness and help you visit the doctor at the right time
there's people developing
a what they called a tense and medical check-up for india
which is supposed to be a little sticker that you stick next to your heart
and it will tell you if you have certain heart diseases and it will save
you the trip to the doctor or recommend you to even
go far distance to the doctor if you really need to
so this is all o
working with sensor data in real time processing fashion to to help really different problems
and the smart grid
which is the the power of electricity revolution is obviously dealing with real time data
electricity coming from renewable sources is not as reliable as from non-renewable resources and you
need to you need to leverage a supply and demand in this network with real-time
so you need a very dynamic system which again
thrives on these events
so the potential of this real-time push information is crucial for many of these
verticals here and this can be very data intensive so i was talking about the
about on-the-fly processing all the time
and this overload will become worse or more challenging if you wish for example the
real time web growing number of resources even on the web move away from this
traditional request response system where website will just sit there and wait until you call
it but websites are updating each other blogs have these being backs twitter has a
an API which pushes data and so on and so on
facebook graph API supports real-time updates and jason so you will get pushed a data
item google supports these modifications to what they call it pops up how about
where you can subscribe for let's say
in rss items and they will push them to you so are as traditionally is
again a request response paradigm that these people changed it into a real push system
html five websockets will even allow it to push data to the browser so the
client can sit there viewing a static web page and and he can get updates
from the server
while he's looking at this page
you can see this with facebook part of this can be simulated today with javascript
with longstanding connections but anyway the standard will formalise this push communication so you get
an even the last mile to the web client
will enable pushchair
there is supposed to be a great outlook for complex event processing if anyone wants
to form a company the vendor market is very turbulent and but application potential is
and mainly improving the real time awareness so there's many systems out there which are
that is you take each of your parameters you're going to add for
each individual parameter some positive constant epsilon
compute what is the loss in this case this
f of x function would be the the complete loss
and also to do the same thing again but subtracting epsilon stem
from your current you know some value of the
issue of the parameters taking the difference and divided by to
absalom so if that's on goes to zero this is
essentially a definition of the gradient
views a very small absalon you should get a value is going to be
pretty close to a correct implementation
of the computation of the gradient so if using things like
you know the know which adagrad and full that's probably not really
necessary but if you've changed some of the components yourself you
plemented some of the gradients you definitely want to that was the
first thing you should do yeah a are
always by default or yeah you can ask yes then usually are actually
procedures built tend to just do that test very easily yes yes
yeah presumably for more yet the question is you should have epsilon
depend on x there are certainly cases where
batch is that give you a very bad approximations
there's no whole obviously way that i know of of choosing epsilon
depending on the value of x unfortunately not that i
yes so so the question was whether you know our other i seem
to have hinted that realize i did but
i had said that there's other ways of computing estimating this
there if you could it could just be plus epsilon and f of x and
divided by just epsilon and that will still
you know most cases give you also good estimate
so and ok and then assuming gradients are fine
and you pass your that check first thing to do
that will debug other potential problems in your
experiment code is to just take whatever there's a replanning on
training on shrink it by whole lot like maybe fifty examples
and just make sure that you can overfit that training set
that you can reach perfect performance if you during classification
for instance on that training set this will allow you to see whether
some units are saturating you're not even optimising properly
whether this will give you some idea of
new popper ranges for the learning rates
it's really good for hours debugging experiment to do that i
personally always do what i could it up something new
will allow you to check whether you're initialization which you know
bad regime and so it allows you to the bug about these different
things this is not a replacement for rach go so
essentially backprop or gradient descent is a very bug resistant
so if you have bad computer laser gradients point stunt some
your brain it's just always zero for some reason
you will see some training you will see training error reduce you
might some overfitting from the engineering standpoint if you're
going to have the bug having to be somewhat resistant to bad situations
as a good thing but scientifically speaking or doing
research that is not a good thing so you deftly want to do both
the gretsch eq if you've you know design or the new
great to estimate or a new module for which you're computing
gradients and do this also
ok other questions quick
yes yes so why yeah so the question is why is
doing expanse of small dataset interesting here it's compute nationally
only it's small dataset you going to be able to
try a bunch of things very quickly whereas like
if you always training full dataset you still trying to fix problems
in your initialization of things like that
just take much more time because you know if you dataset as
long as it's pretty big then gaining performance at each generations
might take a lot of time that's why i'm saying
you know if you have a very large dataset to
that actually want to run the experiment
on first doing like this very quickly small experiment on small
dataset will know the fast to do so that's why
yeah yeah yeah in this case other like you don't care about the
performance seeing beyond like on the training set
because essentially your learning algorithm if it's not able
to overfit on a very small dataset you're probably not going
to do well or anything good on a large dataset because you have
you have more data to fit in that situation to you should at least
pass this unit test so right moving on
in the last twenty five minutes yeah on the
i guess deep learning so trying to
remember in the first part i describe
theoretically anyways we to approximate the function we don't
knesset need multiple layers result only mention using a single
layer have enough hidden units should be fine approximating any
function so why do we actually want multiple hidden layers
so maybe just a quick few words about
deep learning what one might mean about deep learning and what
one might consider as deep learning research
there is kind of a person ole interpret patient but i would say
that generally speaking for me deploying is
broad enough to include really any and s agation of models that
at the core extract multi levels of representations
and specifically multi levels of distributed representations that
is representations where you have units
which are not really mutually exclusive they can represent different
factors variations that are separate that are not necessarily
mutually exclusive so for instance article clustering approach
you might argue as multiple levels but because all the different
clusters are mutually inclusive i personally would nicely think of
the learning thing at the core least sort ically of research behind
that has been label as deep learning
there was this notion of distributed representations which
i think is quite important at multiple situations for
multiple types of data one motivation of course is a newt thinking
broadly about the brain influences the visual cortex where
we know that the stimuli we get from the retina eventually goes through
several regions of of the brain v y on and then be doing that different
levels there's been measurements that suggest that
savy want will detect simple visual forms like edges and corners
and eventually get intermediate more complex visual forms or features
are being detected by these units and eventually these neurons
and eventually i t wy-ghet high-level objects
and faces and so on and so in a cartoon way you
would kind of expect say face recognizer differs initially have
a layer of detection of very simple things like edges and and
points and then eventually maybe edges that combine together
to form a nose or mouth or eyes and actually get a full phase that's
combination of these concepts there are some theoretical justifications
the early ones were relating to some theory from
the study of boolean functions and willing search cuts
so this is the thought of reasoning that happens in put into the plans of
this plan space
OK the reason i brought this up really is to say that well planning is
not just state space search planning can be any type of search which ultimately leads
to apply
again i told you history there are many other ways of yes
OK so that the names again i'm not going into the details but that's it
since you ask me l and you an open condition is so for example q
one is currently in open conditions you have not said anybody is supporting q one
OK so when you said somebody is going to give you q one that sort
of commitments causal commitments o five s zero will q one then output because the
link from q one that's the way the search numbers that whatever happens i want
to make sure that nobody comes in tunisia and it's one of the most q
that's basically or you know if you have an open condition due establish a causal
having put a causal link in this case for example s one is giving to
s three that causal link now we became an unsafe causal link because this tool
can possibly come between these two and killed
and in that case you can actually separate
OK so those are the names that in fact part planning
it has much more colorful set of names in all sorts of fun stuff like
and say things and
confrontation which is if somebody is trying to
say no for example is to say
well if i have a few through before me i will delete b
so here's your enemy and he is happening that they would really be fully they
have queudrue and so you confront the enemy by saying i didn't make not queudrue
before you
and then that becomes an extra goat you what kind of
OK so they're all sorts of this terminology but you know i won't go into
now the important things to note is for the city
planets is there are there are doing search
different kinds of search for the exact became the cancer progression it's easy enough to
understand the search you start from these estate and then you upload possible actions and
then for each of these steps you about possible actions looks easy enough question is
which of the branches that i should go forward and so that i have some
hope of being done fast
OK so i need to figure out the choice point here which branches are closer
to the goal that i'm trying to get
the same thing is true for integration with the tries points which of these branches
will get me to the initial state fast and i'm starting the wall street so
for searches goal state would be the problems issues
and the choice points but this algorithm are different they have actually selecting which opened
condition i'm going to support and deciding which uncivil income going to
you know confront and and and and and then although open conditions and all the
siblings have been that it now it turns out that actually those you have to
deal with every plan
which is finally complete should not have any open conditions and in you have
but the question is one i decided that i'm supporting q one there may be
multiple ways of supporting two or maybe initial state can supported maybe some other actions
supported maybe i can brand i can bring about a new action which was support
q one
and these are all the possible choices and you don't know which one will actually
i mean the end of the that's so those the that choices that you need
to learn about here
the thing that i was trying to make the point of is i love this
search there maybe into search in different places but all search and i'm not actually
going to spend more time talking about the simplest search which is progression and i'll
tell you how they were able to to prove that and you know by definition
sort of more of the other things were done by default so the basic idea
is in field in progress you have this humungous tree and you know which branch
to go on and if you extend and at the and and then try to
figure out variable you get in the regression you know i this with background you're
going in the direction i'm not very good animations and stuff so it and the
animations in this thing that because my students and my best kind of ideas that
is for all i know so you how you know when we have to figure
out which band is going to
take it to the belfast
and remember that so this much all of this stuff is like into one you
know enjoy i into planning you know everybody knew this stuff longest time and people
who are having their various different ideas as to which of these ties is to
take and from the point of view of learning you might say that the learning
algorithm might say
that if your goal is this and you are in this state
hinted you should be taking this action
that that is the way of learning search control from will talk about some of
the first of march
the other possibility is you can just do basically the heuristics based on problem relaxations
and you just the way you learn your is that the discussion in and it
turns out that the biggest break for of came then people figured out that there
is class of relaxations cars approximate reachability analysis that seemed to do wonders
now why did it take so long i have no idea what we figured it
out so that's a good story
here is a way of figuring out which of these branches pick one is i
would say so
suppose there is in state you know there are many many possible states in the
third grade because the number to see whether or not it's worth taking it
whether or not it's worth expanding it one way of answering the question is how
close it with the goal state
OK well here is a number idea which actually works very well in text if
you can ignore the cost of computing which is good and bad progression-free from this
date onwards
OK and then see v if you know until you find the ball state in
one of the fringes
and then you know
what is the length of the path from the state goals
so what you can then do and this is done by and i think you
should always understand the idea before you can appreciate the that you so
all these guys for each of them i do a big progression from each of
these states figured out how far the familiar with straight and which are the same
family closest the ones that expand
you know that's the perfect heuristic for this case and this implies what you want
to do that essentially computing the reachability between states and the goal states how far
is it to work with
and one idea that actually works quite well and in fact you know
in private account that account for most of the interesting planning performance performances this is
really to say about
instead of doing that and that progression
let's do approximated watching of provision there for example this pattern
level is just
you start removing the membrane between the states and you saying well on this PSI
has of which is all the possible values p q and r and s can
roughly again for same that matter plus the cost which is to compare exit the
middle elements is actually one comparison
this has solution
log and you all know the running time but
binary search
here it is
solving the recurrence and i mean there are couple differences here we don't have the
added water and term if we did it would be
the running time better than i can
so we're getting rid of the to bring it down to one taking the and
bring it down to one
that's making around a lot faster both and kind of a surprise there
let's do some more interesting algorithms
the powering a number problem
it is i give you
that is like a real number
one point number whatever
and i give you
integer and
we cerro
i want to compute x the power
a very simple problem is in some sense even easier than all of these
so here it is and divide and conquer is the right thing to do so
the naive algorithm
it's very simple
how do you compute x power and well the definition of x the power i
take x y multiply by
by x n times
so i take x
times x times accessed x were there and copies of next
and that's six to be
big surprise that's
and multiplications are n minus one multiplications
they data and time
that's not the best you can do
for this problem
any suggestions on what we might do
using divide and conquer
for someone has anyone seen this before
so for the rest
on the spot creativity which is very difficult
i was like the challenge
so what i mean random ideas what can we possibly do
to make this problem solved this problem in less than linear time houses sort of
divide and problem
we have two inputs x and and
so we can try to divide on x
he was bit hard to some
we can try to divide and
any guesses doesn't
look actually innovative very good that's
exactly the idea
the divine cockeyed
we'd like to look at x the innovative this is going to be a little
bit tricky now we are going to have to pay attention floors and ceilings
what i would like to say is well next to the
he is
x to the and over two
times xtn innovative two
and this is true if and easy
if it's ok then i need to be will be more careful but let's just
think about the intuition why this is a good divide-and-conquer we have a problem of
size and let's say
we converted into
it looks like to some problems of size and number two but in fact they
are the same subproblems have to solve one of them by computer actually over two
hey i know next the innovative
so there's one recursive call problem size and over to that square that number and
that's one computations exactly the same recurrence as binary search
log time much better than that
they also have to solve the case
and as i
a look at and minus one over two
that's and minus one that be even
and then missing another factor six
so that is i'm going to have to do
one recursive call n two multiplications
same recurrence
a judicious mix of
exploitation and exploration so explanation is
use the existence of the best possible act and so the best possible that
an exploration is
that we realize that the system is not so good outcome for this is not
the best but the more and so we pick out some things that just increase
the knowledge of the space of the space effects
we don't expect to make lots of money right now
but in the long run
we should we hope to get back to model
which can increase the number of clicks
so this is more for long
there's been a lot of literature on this sort of problem combining explotation and exploration
and this falls under the realm of something called multi armed bandits
i look at some of it provided background of
of the literature on this particular
and i focused more on some aspects that would limit the online advertising sector so
in discuss the background and provide some applications to online advertising and then look at
what works what doesn't what are the challenges with open problems in this set
so let's start with the band
you go to las vegas
you see no
there are two slot machines and ahead of you
in the terminology of the literature each of the slot machines is called a bandit
and this constitutes three on bent
associated with each man
is something unknown
they are probably so
if i is played on what i forty five
then with probability p one
i have a success and they get a unit award
otherwise failure and they get no rewards
and now
my goal is to pull arms sequentially one after another so that over time
the total expected reward is maximized
so what they do
initially i don't know the payoff probabilities of any of these arms so go in
and play arms
waterless randomly just to figure out
what the p of property is approximately
and then i tried and i over time
you start to see that because some of these arms and much better than some
of the other and then you start focusing on the back arms and you keep
doing this until at the end you start to focus on what you believe to
be the best
and then you keep playing the best
the hope is that if you figure out the best in very quickly
then you'll get a lot of rewards in the long run
essentially what bandit algorithms try to do is
try to to estimate the
probabilities px
but then you want to bias this estimation process towards the fact that with the
if i know that someone is not so good a low price of probability i
don't really need to estimate is very
great big
i just need to focus on the best need to figure out which one is
the best
and an algorithm actually sequentially pose content placed converge on the best is what's called
a bandit policy
now obviously can have many different bandit policies
it's funny how they
choose to pay on sequential
the way to compare different policies is via something called the degree of policy
so the regret is essentially how much extra payoff would i have to see if
i knew the payoff probabilities from the very beginning
so in some sense the degree is the price and playing for having to explore
the payoffs instead of if i had known the payoffs for the best of all
the time
and learning
implies that the policy was caught it was converging on the best and very quickly
and this is the sort of policy we need
so now
the obvious next question is what is the optimal policy
the optimal policy
we can see something small
obviously it cannot just for whatever one things is the best and right now
because the best and right now might have
given success just you know some statistical fluctuations in keep playing it forever
it might actually does a fairly poor
so it would seem that
in fact even like this time it becomes a dynamic programming things on the full
on ferry huge markov chain where the state of the that each state in the
markov process essentially encodes all the success and all the failures of all the arms
it becomes this huge markov chain which is obviously almost impossible
very nice thing is that
in a seminal paper people in
the late nineteen seventies gibbons showed that you don't really need to solve this entire
huge markov chain
what you can do with that
the optimal policy
for any given band can actually be decoupled into
certain policies for each of those arms independent so what is said is that i
can build up a markov chain
for each part
independently of all the other ips so looking at one compete i compute something called
the priority function for this particular
looking at just this time in isolation and then a computer program for all the
i began which is the highest priority and please
and that's all i need to do this
becomes the optimal policy
and what this is doing is it significantly reducing the state space that i have
is convex
and while this the main caplthy theta is convex
so i can just go
and compute the
painkillers on the dual
of this convex function
this algebraic manipulation i can do that
basically what it does is
that's what it turns out to be the case that this is the negative entropy
it's quite nice connection
so i will show this in a moment
but for the moment this is just
the soup
overall theta such that
this expression is maximized what you will end up doing is well let's just take
the derivative with respect to say to so we get a new one is the
seat of geophysical zero so what we get
is mu r equals the theta chi of data so we're just mapping from
data which is the natural parameter to the corresponding
i mean parameter
there's a lot more that you can do with this machinery then just this small
in fact g star
of mu
to be
soup other
they tend this
happens theta
the don't theta minus gl and this is optimized for
well mu r equals
d theta
g of data which we know is the expected value
up y x
so therefore
i will get
well later
the state tree
of data
function set
functional inverse
so then what i get is that this expression here
is inappropriate to a new
as state of new
of data
now it turns out
but this is
this leads us to the following
well the negative log
probability of fix
prentice by theta
tom speer
given theta d theta so that seem to be quite very definition
right out
it's the integral
express by theta all
now the inner product between fall thinks data
one you
now this will give us
mu of slater
has its expected value of topics
this remains the same remains the same so it gives us
in the process of
mu of data
one is
g state
i could also write this as the inner product between
mu theta of new
one is g
of data
and that's
exactly what we have appear
so what i'm getting is that
the entropy
the negative of the convex dual of the log partition function
so far that's just curious observation but actually want to make use of that now
the way that exploit this is
well first of all you can notice that
if idealise back again them by strong duality
i get back my log partition function so this is the function it may be
hard to compute
by taking the convex dual
overall marginals in the
corresponding marginal polytope
well into inappropriate between theta mu plus the entropy corresponding to the marginals
so basically this is like g double star of data
if g stop is of data
all i've done is i've taken the log partition function which is
which may be a pain to compute
i have gone to the dual
which i know is the entropy
and actualized back again
so far it doesn't look like going anything
but actually gained a lot of insight on how i can now approximate things
and the two approximations that wainwright and jordan made all the following
first of all
i might have an upper bound
on the on the entropy
so for instance if i have a random variables with a given covariance
i know that the normal distribution
it is
the distribution with the largest entropy for a given covariance structure
if i plug in
entropy that i get from a normal distribution with the given covariance this will be
box here
so the colour mismatch apologies for that and we divided by the total number of
crosses and taking the limit as n goes to infinity that's actually frequentist definition of
probability so that's a very
probably the most people have seen before
it's an interesting one because of course never really does go to infinity but
i will be happy with that definition for the marginal will be
the model for axes this box here a really bad got colours mismatching sorry so
blue boxes the limit as we sample the ones in that both as goes to
and the conditional
will be looking at one of these boxes here
s equals x three and y equals for
and then dividing by the one in another box
four y equals forces divided divided by all the totally dividing the ones that give
so the nice thing about the little definitions and i think this is something that
i first saw or when
i was asked in nineteen ninety six and chris bishop use this way of introducing
probability wasn't it's possible but i think it's second actually to do it this way
i haven't read the second but i think i saw in everything
so it might have introducing all these different things because you can introduce the rules
of probability from it so as i said before
typically we should write out the full
definition of the probability right we should be clear we should be saying
x is equal into little x and y is equally little one but in practice
we often use this little shortcut and the implication is somehow dismissing complex equals but
that has this effect so this looks very much like we might write a multivariate
function f of x from y is equal to one the cause x ex-con wife
of x white noise y come in probability is that it's true because of that
the saddle point
it caused to be argument wants the post-doc so to current
i think he did
i realize that because he was a mathematician so i was thinking of that he
didn't believe in that
i had to explain it
OK so
all distributions are normalized and that can be easily seen from the definition seen before
by summing over one of these models is just the sum of all the things
in that marginal divided by the total which is equal to one
and modernization is really important property of probabilities because it has effects has effects maximum
likelihood when you when you push on
the likelihood one region because the distributions normalized it must be suppressed in other regions
it goes down elsewhere so it's like a it's like a sort of tents you
know when you if you want your probability go up here
your edits attention is paid down then it will go down somewhere else if you
live tip over ten other possibly go down and so that's sort of important property
the tent has a certain fixed volume and the probability case as you move it
up and down in moscow down elsewhere
that's very important
the marginal probabilities the summing across
all the axes you should know that the sum rule of probability
and this is probably one of the biggest painter experience it looks so innocent
but in practice when we're looking at very large state spaces
doing these sums can be very very hard exploring
a large state space
this is the one of the hardest things to deal with in probability says the
some probability and then the product rule of probability
it is relating the joint distribution to the conditional distributions probability vector y times probability
y is equal to the probability of
x and y and that can all be seen just by going through those definitions
now the nice thing
the simple definitions also leads to something that some people think it's controversial
and one of the point of introducing in that way you can see this is
completely non-controversial
bayes rule is not controversial
it is true
if you want to write probability this is the way to do it
you can equate the joint probabilities in this way politifact com y is equal to
probability of white-collar x
probability why correct time is equal to appear like given x compared accent
so we can write this basically and then you just dividing time that side and
you get this ability
to inv
the probability go from this probably why
given x the probability of x given y and that's important
now basically right about it and
i tried to read the paper the introduction is really clear it's written by someone
else called enterprise
and it looks really clear
and most of what you get from the papers from and then reading actual paper
is not very clear
read the plastic
his i can't remember the name of the actual paper where he affection he doesn't
bayes rule but he does a lot more interesting stuff with it and i think
a as a british pains me to say but plastics far more interesting than bayes
and he
there's an enormous amount of work on on using this rule
well i have not explicitly saying what the rule is many post states
the poster is based thing which is why people credit based but i think if
your friends you can be might be proud of the class
it seems to me is a little bit depressing the red class because i realized
that my entire
research career was already envisaged by the last two hundred years ago
and it was only through lack of having a computer
that he didn't do
the sort of things that we do but basically he worked out approximations for doing
bayesian inference he worked out to error functions fitting models to data
astronomical models to data
and he also
it was first interested in the example he looks and this is biased coins he
so all these numbers represented by a square white
white squares i mean it they all add up to one
so are what you're feeling this too
independent who says they are
could you write this SP of xm still y
the question is if
if x and y are
what they are meaning a pick x
x is any letter in my links manual text and y is the latter that
goes right after that
and i now believe the joint probability
distribution for these two things right so i say followed by a has some some
probability now now
followed by c
not so much
fair enough
so do you think there's any language
in which
i could sort of factorizes thing in which i could write p of that in
which i could write the joint p of x come y as p of x
times p of y so
the thing is this constraints because although there are some languages
i i think i saw
people from slovenia here somewhere who is from slovenia
how you have more
consonants one after another than we have in spanish for example
so in spanish
if you have two consonants one after another that's already a lot
you never have three as far as i know
maybe someone correct me three maybe but anyway so so so you know that after
you know if you already have seen the consonant then it's more likely that you're
going to see vowel than other consonant it's in spanish
all right in english as well
so they are not independent because it's the latter that follows
so why is really the letter that comes after all right now if you if
you had some text i didn't make any sense some sort of random bag of
of of letters any organised in anyway
then yes then you could actually factor
so if they were independent how would this matrix look like
well i put it to you that he would be symmetric
so why why would it be symmetric
how would you believe what i just told you they would be p of x
times of y
and so it would be it would really be like the multiplication of a column
by a row vector
and this thing is symmetric OK
but here it is not symmetric
however what i can do
is i can actually recover the marginal that i had earlier so
here we only had
a single
column here OK we were only looking at letters
i could recover that in two different ways from here i could either
i up
in the rows or i could add up in the columns and i recover OK
and that's the marginalisation
all right so now we're going to do a practical exercise
it's always
i've been having meaning to figure different exercise four four one because it's it's always
an unpleasant one to to give exercises about cancer but since isabelle has mentioned the
word counts for five times in her lecture now i feel is bad about
OK so there's little little little exercise i i give you this this actually the
interesting thing about this exercise it's based on the real world study about how doctors
i understand probabilities
so let's see what you think and that tell you what the doctors that
so the first thing is a you some facts i give you this following three
facts the first factor is
one percent
of of of women that gets scanned
actually do have breast cancer OK
second fact
that person has breast cancer
then the mammography will turn out positive with eighty percent chance
OK now the third factor give you is
that nine point six percent of
completely healthy patients that do not have
breast cancer
actually also get a positive mammography right
so this would be
the probability of detection and this would be the probability of false alarm or you
for those of you who are used to that kind of stuff
another question i ask you is
a woman
actually has a positive mammography positive in this in this context
is not very positive or very means
the red light goes on
so what is the probability that she has breast cancer
and understand the question
go to the doctor you get the bad news OK
bad exactly are those news
in the light of the of the data
so now i know i have sort of
let so doctor wouldn't sit down and write probabilities OK
so i doctor we just use his or her gut feeling so let's see
who of you thinks that is going to turn out to be less than one
OK we have three people
performers who of you things that is going to be somewhere between one percent and
seventy percent
about five or six people
we have this skewed degree distributions like that then the expression that is used is
called scale free networks than any other
o experiment
OK so this is just just
of land and then also some temporal patterns so what i want to say here
is that was this
which is actually quite fascinating that was this experiment but by nineteen sixties where he
asked people in nebraska to the to the following right so he he asked people
to send letters to some stock brokers in boston right and all these people knew
was the name of the person and they were a stockbroker and they were asked
to send to send letters to the like immediate friends and the what he was
measured is how how long how many hops does it take for the letter to
arrive to particular broker
right and it did not like twenty five percent of the letters that were initially
sent reach the goal but they
but the important part is that the each in about six steps right
so it means that
a random person nebraska can send the letter and the person in boston in about
six hops
which has implications for the businesses in the networks of small and the other one
is that the humans are able to find OK and hot what do we mean
by distances in the networks so this is usually captured by the diameter
so diameter is defined as like maximum so if the idea is the shortest path
the length of the shortest path between iron nodes i and j then just the
maximum order then sees this is like very noisy measure right you what usually do
is they call about the talk about effective diameter which is like just the nineteen
percentile of the diameter or you can i get great like average shortest path distance
right so i just go here over all pairs of path
and i i normalize appropriate for the other one
OK won't go into detail
and for example here here is what you get right so here we have
microsoft messenger network right so we have a hundred and eighty million people talking to
each other over a period of four months and we have one one point three
billion edges right so we have pretty much the whole world and there is an
edge if two people exchanged if people were engaged in conversations at least once in
this one month period right and if i can plot the distance and the number
of number of pairs of nodes at that distance you can see that the motive
distribution is at seven by this means
most of the network is reachable within seven hot and this is log scale
if this would be like one hundred million
o thirty then no here ten million
right so this is like now
almost hundred million people have the right to more than half of the network can
be reached in
in semi at least seven hops and this says the diameter is small
so the other properties degree distributions that people talk a lot about and this is
basically so this is what we mean that so we take to denote like the
fraction of nodes that have degree k
right and then you can just block the histogram of
probability of observing could nobody with degree k
right and
what what would like what one would maybe we expect to see something like this
right if we would expect that there is some need to this distribution in the
we would sail on average person has their friends and then somehow the class and
some have a bit more about that is when feel like there is an average
of that is the most to the distribution what happens is that it's
more like that so it's cute it's skewed towards towards towards the right
OK and
they called this types of distributions like heavy along the institutions and there are many
quantities in the real world that follow these types of distributions for example the amazon
sales for the world land distribution follows OK and to be even more precise
so we said it's it's cute but
what is even more importantly the is that the data does not decay exponentially but
with it because of the power so what i mean is that
the probability of observing a degree of node degree k schemes like the minors house
where i face some
IQ matters
more particularly IQ matters for social achievement for prestigious positions and for on the job
performance and other work related variables of i know your IQ score
i know something about you that matters
it's not irrelevant
just as if i know your score on a personality test big five i would
know something about you that would tell me something interesting about you in the real
on the other hand there's a lot of controversy about why this connection exists on
so to some extent people have worried that the effectiveness of IQ
is a self-fulfilling prophecy
and here's why
if society takes IQ tests important seriously they become important
so it's true they are IQ
is very related to your success in getting into a good school like yale
but the reason for this in large extent is because they get to yale to
give you an IQ test this stating
the same for graduate school gehry which is yet another IQ test
so to some extent is a self-fulfilling prophecy
i could make
society could choose to make how tall you are extremely important for educational success they
could say nobody under six feet tall gets into
and in some psychopaths would stand up and say of course height is profoundly related
to educational accomplishment and it would be because people made itself
so to some extent society that draws highly on IQ tests
regarding promotion educational educational achievement and military status and so on
it's just going of follow that IQ then becomes important
at the same time however
the role of IQ is pretty clearly not entirely a social construction
there is some evidence to your IQ score
you're related to intelligence and an interesting sense including domains like mental speed
o and memory span
so your your score an IQ test for instance is to some extent related to
how fast you to think and
your memory abilities
now i want to shift in the second half of the class
and talk about why
so we talked about two differences one person at one personality one intelligence
i want to talk about why people differ but before i do i do people
have any questions
this one
is also
so the question the question is
this young man took
took i just took a personality test he was he was accepted slithering
is a hogwarts reference i'm i'm hip to that
and that in the but the question is a good one
you're you're you're clever man
and if you wanted to be an slithering how do we know even worse the
i mean you know you got to get his personality tests all the time and
you an as you if you apply for business and one test is i like
to steal from my bosses
o thing so no that's the like you test right there
so the question is how do you avoid that problem on the test constructors have
done so in certain clever ways
instance are often catch questions
designed to capture life
some of these questions posed very unrealistic
phenomena so you might have a question in their saying
i have never done anything i'm ashamed of
now some people say yes that's true me
but they can be liars
unrealistic questions tend to catch liars also you get the same question as in different
ways across the hundred items and they could use the correlations to figure these things
i mean again the proof is sort of inputting
but the reliability and validity of the test
is determined in part by just how well it does at predicting your future performance
on the test in the real world performance on the test that is easily fooled
easily tricked by smart people
wouldn't survive long personality test
so we know that we know the test you've got is a pretty good test
because it seems to work for most people
it's a good question questions about emotional IQ which is something i matching to touch
upon little bit later in the course that people talk about different forms of intelligence
and emotional
intelligence social intelligence is is it can arguably a candidate for success across different domains
the evidence for predictive power
it is not as strong as for regular IQ tests
so you might be right it might turn out to be much better predictive but
it's not clear that we know that you peter saleh is actually done some very
interesting research on this is continuing work along those lines the second thing is emotional
intelligence actually related to good old old-fashioned intelligence
they kind of pull together a lot so it's not entirely separate
but that's a good point and i like to return to a little bit later
in the course
good question how do you determine wondered what good test
and again
it's a real are going through the details of how to do that but the
branches involved reliability and validity
it's good testify test you today
and it test you tomorrow i get the same score
it's a really good test if your score on that task
predicts your grades
are the personality test predicts how many girlfriends you are predicts whether people think you're
a nice guy
so you have to see both the replicability to test over time but also its
relationship to real world phenomena
and that's important again why we know the batman and wonder woman hope
it is about one one answer is
what what i what i how i scorn et test is about anything about me
is not going to relate to migrate is not going to write how long liked
how do we notice it is useful well actually corresponds with other things like great
at around the TV energy scale
that is just to see
he works
so that's the temperature and symmetry in the universe
and i will give you the idea is now being
government health warnings with this
maybe it's not explained higgs mechanism
i'm going to give you an example
the show this is not something that is certainly knew you need to particle physics
it is the phenomenon that is very well known throughout nature and science
and this is just had this manifestation of
so we can the pictures i had to motivate this first let's show again
then to explain it
the idea patterns and structures existing in the cold low energy
this is very revealing different symmetry in the war
if you want
as a glass of water
engineered so
according to the possible for the better
he that it doesn't matter which and rotated through it will be exactly the same
it's invariant under complete rotation symmetry
but if i froze
and one snowflake that's the
only invariant under rotations sixty
one hundred ninety two
the symmetry has changed many froze when it was
we have seen examples of this already in the negative forces missing electromagnetic and weak
which inference the like snowflakes in the cold
coming together at high energies with the z mass can be neglected we suspect that
is true some all forces
we have the standard model of the plant that forces which is the pattern based
on mass cold we suspect that the above this temperature
this mass will become irrelevant you see the real symmetry behind
this is the reason to the real
general the last twenty minutes
what is symmetry is what we liked and wanted to change in
so what
this is really about how symmetries
this appeal change
and i like to think about this picture from it realized the increasing profundity would
the right
the first psychologically we like symmetry
and when we don't see one why
so here's a picture of
because the joined peterborough in my home town in england
and you see
for example you can use in their quest for the things
art on one side that the other but then you look
the top and you see there is the town on one side
and there's nothing on the other
your media reactions
but there's no reason why they should be
but these are the fields but also one of the one on the north side
of the south side
the answer because the money
but there's a reason you see you will be asked you OK
rather more
i think the third the fourteenth century philosopher baroness
home the following month he imagine a perfectly symmetric don't last
that is positioned exactly midway between two identical bunches of carrots
and the philosopher than that because of the symmetry
there is no need
don't need to choose a character left
OK county right
therefore we can say that i do not think this that
if you have also that is what it's all about
but know what happens in practice
the challenge is one i will not happen in practice and you can make it
you can say well of course there is no such thing as absolutely symmetry don't
you can imagine
some of the random event will have small symmetry maybe
four days today
but it's a bit hotter almost no
don't need to go to the shady side
some trivial thing will spoil the symmetry
in the very small way
and have a huge
consequence namely
in two thousand this sign will survive
so that brings us
philosophical example which is now
and now which is getting near to real physical situation that's the problem
the symmetries in the party
but if you someday go really flash in party where they set the tables
so the table
a to use it in a table
each place
and we can set up to use symmetry
midway between you and your neighbors the table
and imagine yourself in these two table napkins you on the and all roads as
that which of these table napkins is yours
and until somebody breaks symmetry the dinner party cannot begin
and of course some rest the graph that is on the right because there's more
to the left interesting asymmetry anyway
OK they red table right
which breaks symmetry
now what to do with it
well this is analogous to what happens in magnets
as i explained
well first of all imagine we had to it
party when two hundred people
around this
so what
imagine the people there
ruby symmetrically placed on the state
and now we have the following all can happen following the over there
general background on his left
which forces all of you have been brought coming around here
now they're laying pig so that you know how right which forces all these people
the right to grab coming around here
so suddenly i have that