talking about
and here are more details about this slide lock market right so now you can
i don't know it's possible
so it so
let's talk more about the viral marketing right now we can ask what are the
product features that make a particular product being invited to come anywhere and so on
so on this dataset of sixteen million recommendations we had for product that we had
books we had a hundred thousand books fifty thousand images four hundred thousand music series
and then twenty six thousand dvds like
and that's half a million products then we have the number of customers the number
of recommendations the number of edges in the social networks and then the number of
people that bought then got discount the number of people that
both then got no discount what you can see for example is the very
met so
i have to do
the numbers of are high
light alone
right and
what i want i want to say is for example here you can see the
average DVD shop made like ten recommendations wired for books there are about two recommendations
per person writes that you can also see that this our social networks are extremely
sparse right there are almost like these right so i have i have
eight hundred thousand nodes and OK million edges here the number of edges is smaller
than the number of nodes
and then seems to me that this contract from books a lot of people got
discounts and few few people
made the purchase and order to discover why the the situation is reversed so you
can ask
what is going on how does the
product every influence
the purchases so here if you look at this
more more categories again i have the for-profit degrees have the number of people that
purchase and got discount and this would be put them forward commanded the problem so
you you seem accommodation you buy a product then you for the comments to friends
and what you can see for example is that people are much more likely to
comment did they just purchased two of their friends that they
two two tool a commendable music CD and so on
more interesting things about like that so
we have we have that
so we had like four million people but then it turns out that less than
fifty thousand people responsible for four two point five million recommendations out of sixty million
recommendations right so as very small fraction of people is it is it possible for
one of the all recommendation and also
as as i'm showing before this seems to be very interesting
i think to command for example
there are there for this japanese animation cartoons time right the the the sixth the
recommendation success was thirty percent right so every recommendation resulted in a purchase
which is extremely high
while for four
the baseline b
two or three percent of the recommendations with the resulting pictures
and so if you look at the
i did you how well connected is the network the giant component is usually very
small so the largest connected component of these networks
we saw earlier in the morning this
the networks
the most of
most of most real networks have this largest connected component that has the most of
the nodes in it in the recommendation network species very small
so this is for david is now we can go
and those simple regression experience so we take every product
so if i give you
value for x on the validation of the boat
when the you can evaluate pointwise there's no problem one can evaluate point what is
because we put the
joint distribution of x on y we don't that the conditional distribution of x and
but you can rewrite also the weight here
as marginal likelihood
time ratio
which is the kind of discrepancy between
the target distribution of inquiry
the LTI
this is something we're going to call the importance weight
what i'm telling you is that once you've got basically
this important for question
you can rely very simply
the marginal likelihood as
the integral
the expectation of importance weights
and two
or what but
so for example
no it's not that
what you so you can do it with the questions
now know it's not going to be actually
so i think that we just like forget about that and that's what i mean
the approximation of equation are just
there there's the colour approximation
OK so this equation
well is straightforward because
whatever simply everything that the marginal likelihood p
of y
is the integral
of the joint distribution of x on y integrated with x
on the using my poetry which is that
a is called a divided by b b
on this expression that nothing
we also have an equation
obviously we manage basically what good is we managed to rewrite p
i simply
the function of this way in the computer and
whenever i know x find importance sampling distribution
so if you want to go
why the poor
that is what what that's ever get it maybe once
so you're either with the distribution of in
of x y divided by p of life
no you're right that
e of x y p of x y divided by two
multiply by q
on this thing is fine because the
these include in a part of you that in that infinite
so this is what find
i do this at the numeric on the denominator on
final expression
the for is wonderful from them until
basically formula
it was used to arrive
as the kind of expectation of w way we normalize
so theoretically
the thing is basically
what we call in the that's the actual point which are the right
can have if you see
what the derivative just basically alright point for nothing
so we this expression
on the way this expression is going be the keep
already the key
so what do we do
well known
everything ever written
there was no more out of the time
i was just rewriting t as a function of
i know what i'm telling you is that remember that picked q
so that it is helpful
so i picked you as an arbitrary point distribution i think he was adopted
but for what think and the realization from you
in particular
this means that i can approximate two
the bombardment the telephone thing i was quite before i would describe the beginning that
is what you're going to do
you're going to fall and that people are one the viable according to
all you're going to build the multicellular alternation
very simple
i know what you're going to do
we're going to do something and try to
well wherever
we have few
in the problem something i don't want to be described his life
i'm going to substitute few it will become approximation
very simple
remember that i written and the marginal likelihood
i think the goal
this in part of weight the two
well what i'm doing to get some of the multicolored may be used i
i substitute to q
these on pure measure
basically everything in big or not of w right back onto commercial street but a
lot and i have been following question four
the marginal likelihood
very simple
o thing
this estimate is not bad actually
at least that they that the property that is owned by the name
of the quantity of interest
basically you can also
the question of the lion
of why you want to fit in
it's not especially for me
well what i want to do what i'm doing with the current equation
i always want
i mean my my system is one that but i want to do it in
a sort of more likely that it massive i can be used for what we're
going so
all could utilize
all could i select two
so basically mean by the violence
of the weight
why do you insist
this article two
the possibility distribution are you get the answers that they
did this the important information that minimize the violence because in these devices with zero
it's basically
doesn't tell us much because
why we use that
well if we use q in the first place
instead of the because we do not
i'm going to work with you
on the new concepts
and that is the concept
what we call
electric field we spend the whole lecture
on electric field
i have a
a charge
i just
capital q and plus
at a particular location
and at another location
i have another charge
the i think that might test charge
and there's a separation between the two
these are
the unit vector from capital q
little q
is this effect
so now i know that the
two charges if they positive let's suppose that q is positive
they would repel each other
q is negative
they were attracted to
that this force
we have
and last time we
introduce girls law
that always equals q
capital q times school of calls
divided by our square
in the direction of our rules
two have the same sign
so this direction have opposite sign
it's city idiotic
and now i need to do
the idea of electric field
which we write simple capital e
at that location b where i have my test charge little q
at that location
simply to force
that fast charge experienced divided by the test charge
so i eliminated tests
so i get something that looks quite similar
but it doesn't have the little q anymore
and it is also effective
and by convention
we choose the
such that if this is a positive test charge
then we say he field
is away
from q q is positive
if q is negative
the force is in your direction and therefore easily direction so we adopt the convention
the field is always in the direction that the forces on the positive charge
what you have gained now is that
you you've taken out the little q
in other words
four here
depends on the q
the electric field is not really electric field
is the representation
four what happens around the chart plastic you could be very complicated charge configuration
an electric field tells you something about
that charge configuration
the uniform electric field
you can see is newton's divided by coolmore
and as i unit
normally we won't even indicate
the unit just leave that
as it is
we have graphical representations
the electric field
electric field is a vector
so you expect
and i have here an example
of a
the charge
plus three
by convention these arrows pointing away from the charge
in the same direction that the positive test charge would experience the force
you notice that
very close to the
the errors are larger than for the way that that sort of
represents is trying to represent the interests are square relationship
which can all be very quantities
the basic idea is of course spherically symmetric if this is the point charge
the basic idea is UCB
the direction of the arrow tells you in which direction the force would be if
it is the positive charge
and the length of the vector gives you an idea
of the magnitude and here i have another charge minus one
it doesn't matter whether it is
mine is one called more
my micro cool
just its relative
representation and you see now that the e field vectors
by reversing direction they pointing towards
the is charged by convention and then you go further out
they are small
you have to go all the way to infinity of course
for the
field to become
one of our square field falls off
you have to be infinitely far away
for you to not experience at least in principle
fact from the
from the charge
what do we do now when we have more than one
well if we have several charges
we have
q one
and here we have
q two
here we have
q three
let's say you have
q of i i charges
and now we want to know what is the electric field
at some point
so it's independent
the test charge that i want to think of it if you want to as
the force per unit charge
you've divided out the charge
so now
i can say what is the field due to q one alone
you can the subdifferential is just the interval minus one one right for a euclidean norm for
example a Euclidean norm would be subdifferent differentiable if X is not zero at
the origin it's not differentiable but there is a sub a set of subgradients defined
like this basically any vector with norm less than one is a subgradient
at the origin and that follows from the Cauchy-Schwarz inequality so the  there's
a calculus for subgradients that's similar to the calculus for just gradients and it turns
out that  finding one  subgradient for an a non-differentiable function is usually
very  quite easy if you can evaluate a non-differentiable function then
you also usually  obtain at least one subgradient the question of computing all the subgradients
or the entire subdifferential can be very difficult but fortunately you don't need at for
algorithms algorithms for non-differentiable  convex optimization only require or ask from the user that
they  provide one subgradient at each iteration you're not interested in the set
of all possible subgradients and also nice property is that convex functions are usually
subdifferentiable at all their points in their domain and the only exception that can
happen  the only points where it might be nom subdifferentiable meaning it
doesn't have a subgradient would be at the boundary of the domain for example if
you take the negative of a  square root that's a convex function of X but
at X is zero there is no subgradient because the only tangent you might make
at that point is vertical and so you cannot find an vector G that satisfies this
but that can only happen at the boundary of the domain of the function so you
don't have to worry about this so what are some of these calculus rules so
so much simple so F if F has a non-negative combination of two convex functions F
one and F two then you can just took find the subgradient of F you find
a subgradient of F one a subgradient of F two and then you combine them
in the same way you would with gradients there's a similar rule for affine transformations point-wise maximum
you've seen this is always convex if the functions F I are convex well it's also very easy
to find a subgradient and the method is  this you to evaluate F of
X at point X you have to determine the maximum of these functions well once you
have the  function that's  suppose F 1 is the maximum then you
can pick any subgradient of F one at that point and that's a subgradient
of F of X and  this is something we'll need later probably
so this should be F star of X that's as conjugate this was our if you
remember from yesterday the definition of a conjugate off a function F Y if this
is F star  the conjugate  of X so there is a similar rule for this
maximization to compute a subgradient of this conjugate you find the value of Y
for which this is maximized and then  you differentiate this function and that's very
easy because the f you differentiated this function respect to X so
the gradient is  basically Y so the subgradient of the conjugates at a vector
X  is the vector Y that maximizes the argument here in the definition of
the conjugate and if there are multiple maximizers any maximizer they're all subgradients
okay so then the subgradient method is just similar to the gradient method
so at each iteration you determine one subgradient of the function at
your point if a step in that direction and you X so it's very simple
and it's an extension of the gradient method to non-differentiable functions there are some common choices
of step sizes that people use so you can use T K constants small enough constants another choice
would be instead of making T constant you make the norm of the step constant
so you choose this to be constant and another one that is usually needed and we'll see
why is a diminishing step size so you let T Ks go to zero as K increases but
you don't decrease them too quickly so you could let them go to zero but
in such a way that the sum goes to infinity we'll see why this is
needed and then these are some typical  convergence results for the subgradient method you need
one  assumption on the functions that that they're lip lipschitz continuous so that's a very weak
assumtion although as a function can be very non-differentiable
and then you see with  for example a fixed step size T the function doesn't
necessarily converge but as the iterates go on you converge to something that's within a
certain distance from the optimum and the distance depends on the step size T so
once we gather all these rules of thumb how do we combine them into a
single prediction rule
that will be very highly accurate
so here we just do something simple we just take a majority vote or weighted
majority vote of the rules of stuff
given the new example we evaluate all the rules of each one makes a prediction
of what the correct labels to be
and then we just take a majority vote of those predictions
OK so
boosting is
a general method of converting these rough rules of thumb into a highly accurate prediction
and also i will be talking about it also has
a more technical definition which is important to keep in mind to boosting starts out
with the assumption really any learning algorithm starts out with an assumption that you're always
assuming something about your data otherwise learning is impossible
so boosting we start out with what's called the weak learning assumption we assume that
we've been given a weak learning algorithm
which can consistently find these weak classifiers or the what i've been calling these rules
of thumb
which are at least a little bit better than random guessing
now if you just talking about a two class problem most of the talk lockerbie
be talking about two class problems
and you guessed randomly
you'll be right exactly half the time
so the weak learning assumption says that the accuracy of these classifiers to be a
little bit better than fifty percent of maybe fifty five percent
something that's a little bit better than random guessing and given that assumption and given
enough data whatever that means a boosting algorithm is an algorithm that can provably
construct a single classifiers
with very high accuracy with accuracy say ninety nine percent
that's why it's called boosting because your boosting the accuracy from fifty five percent to
ninety nine percent
OK so here's what i'm going to cover the tutorial that was by way of
so i'm first going to give a very brief background and boosting that would be
rather short
and then being part of the tutorial will be in three parts the first part
and going to talk about the basic
adaboost algorithm adaboost was the first practical boosting algorithm and its core theory focusing on
analyzing the era of the algorithm
the second main part
it is on other ways of understanding boosting so there are many many ways of
thinking about boosting that have been developed over the years and going to be talking
about three of those
and the last part will be focused on experiments applications and extensions
and i know it's a big group but needless to say you know please do
ask questions especially clarifying questions
OK so brief background
OK so boosting has its roots in the theoretical machine learning model called the
learning model pack stands for
probably approximately correct it was introduced by valiant
back in
the eighties early eighties
and in this pack model
the learning algorithm gets random examples from some
i non an arbitrary distribution
and the stronger
pac learning our model
a strong PAC learning algorithm is one so that for any distribution over the examples
any distribution generating the data that is
with high probability given
enough examples were enough means polynomially many examples and polynomial time
the algorithm can find classifier with arbitrarily small generalisation error
generalisation error means the air on the true distribution which is generating the data
OK so we can drive the air
as small as we want
and the weak PAC learning model for weak PAC learning algorithm rather is one which
satisfies all the same requirements but the generalisation error only has to be
a little bit better than random guessing
OK so in this model you have to be able to drive the air below
one percent and here you only have to drive the air below
forty five percent
and turns and valiant were the ones who first looked at
weak learning
the weak learning model and they asked us weak learnability imply strong learnability if you
can learn in this model and this week model
is there some way of boosting your accuracy
so that you can also learn in this
seemingly much stronger learning model
the first provable boosting algorithm was one that i came up with
it's for my phd thesis and you are throwing came up with a better algorithm
one which is optimal in a certain sense it's called boost by majority algorithm
and there were some early experiments with these algorithms
but they had certain
there were certain practical reasons why these algorithms really did not work so well in
practice were difficult to use in practice i'll talk about that a little bit later
so the first practical
boosting algorithm is adaboost which i'll be focusing on
and again i will talk about the practical advantages later
and since then there's been a lot of work experimental work in theoretical work on
boosting obviously not going to cover
all of this but
and this list is far from exhaustive
but i'll try to
cover cover good part of it
OK so that was a little bit of historical background
so what i want to do now
is introduced adaboost
and talk about and analyse its training air
it's error rate on the training set
and then talk about how to analyse its test air to air on a separate
test set or its generalization there
using something called the margins theory
OK so i already introduced boosting at a high level what i want to do
is go back
and talk about it in more formal terms and introduce some mathematical notation
so as with any learning algorithm
of this kind we start out with the training set
so there are m training examples
each training example is a pair x i y i so
site is the object that we're trying to
classify so for instance it's
the utterance that was said by the person in the example i gave at the
and capital taxes the instance space is the space of all possible instances
and why is the label so for instance it's the correct classification of one of
those utterances
the tree
because again i emphasise this simple example so this might look like an easy job
for this particular example
the more complex sentences for longer sentences recovering these grammatical relations is far from trivial
there's another example his object example so here we have another
syntactic configuration which is shown in red here dominating for pope
and then we can disregard
the object relation in this case
and is that there are other relations in these trees
so that's perhaps one of the primary motivations that this idea of grammatical relations
just to finish the section on background let me first talk about
none of the
the first models prior to machine learning for syntax and perhaps one of the simplest
models many or if you will be familiar with these this is the idea of
probabilistic context free grammars
OK so you have cheese we generalize CRF cheese by adding a probability to each
rule production
and here's what probability one to this is the conditional probability given the expanding the
symbol s
i have seen these particular nonterminals for that and p four p
OK so this essentially
looks like a probability associated with each rule in the grammar
the probability is we can take an entire parse tree
and define the probability that tree as a product
all of these probabilities
so that's a very simple direct model
we start to probabilities of these structures and we can use this to actually learn
mappings from strings to be structures
there's a problem in that pcfgs in this simple form as i've shown you here
we have very small set of non terminals
actually extremely poor models of language
in a couple of sentences firstly
so very badly
and our ranking alternate histories particular input in terms probability and secondly that very poor
in terms of assigning probability distributions to strings
and the reason for that is that these nonterminals
you could very little information about the surrounding context in the tree
let me spell it quite poor models so the
talk will come back to pcfgs
and we'll see some tricks
well by you can consider improve performance
essentially by
exploding the number of non terminals in the grammar that's one approach has been used
quite fruitful
OK so now let's
talk about
i've been using
so i guess the key points here as follows
first is the the general point of how we can use probabilistic weighted grammars in
machine learning and specifically of describing how
so models can be
generalized to learning with these weighted grammars
the second main point in this section is to
the introduced tree adjoining grammars
as an alternative
the formalism to to if
so true adjoining grammars are fairly well known
in natural language processing community but probably much less familiar to the community here
and for some advantages
context free grammars in terms of how they parameterise the parsing problem so try to
describe advanced use these grammars grammars bring
so to sum
so have so let me just briefly
describe conditional random fields i guess
pretty much all of you would have seen these but leads to
defined notation on let's talk about conditional random fields
OK so it's impossible to comply conditional random field two
this sequence labeling so this problem of input x is a sequence of tokens for
example sequence of words in a sentence
and the output y is the sequence of underlying state OK so for example the
output i might be a sequence of part of speech tags one part of speech
for each word in the sentence
so here's is a particular example
we might have this input sentence
and this might be one candidate output sequence we have now
very determined positions and so on
a crucial idea in conditional random fields really the building block for conditional random fields
is that the feature vectors which are used to represent these sequence pairs
so we have a feature vector mapping the following form so
it's a feature vector and it takes as input an entire sentence x
position in that sentence for example made we're looking for position
so a prior is conjugate if basically it gets updated in a neat way so that the
form of the posterior
the normal distribution or exponential or whatever the form of the distribution doesn't change just the parameters
of that distribution get updated
so for one very simple example let's take a take the case of the poisson distribution
for the data because it's a poisson distribution
now we could take various possible priors for the parameter theta
it's a non-negative real number so let's
let's try various things but if we chose the the gamma prior gamma distrtibution which I've drawn
there then and then go through the bayes
go through bayes rules we find the posterior distribution is again of exactly the same form
and what's happened is that the priors got updated the posterior simply by tweaking the parameters
we started of with gamma alpha beta and now we have gamma alpha plus Y beta
plus Y
now think about now
what would happen if you took the second observation
OK I've told you about sequential acquisition of data well the prior the posterior after first observation
is the prior for the next so you can see what happens is that we just get the the new
observation gets added on and the beta parameter get gets added
on again
and that's a very nice idea because it tells us something about how to interpret prior
distiributions in this case because you can see that effectively what would have
is Alpha plus the sum of all the data and beta plus the number of
so that's just like starting from zero in both
zero total observations
you know zero number of observations and then
what we start is to imagine that there are a total are beta observations
and their total is alpha so priors can then be thought of as as like
prior data it's like date you had before you started observing anything
and that's quite a useful trick if
you try to elicit a prior from someone who is reluctant to give one that's
quite a good way of pullout from him or her what the
the kind of uncertainty they think about theta really is
now this used to be a really important principle because you couldn't you couldn't do
bayesian statistics except in this sort of simple situation it's it's become much less important
there's still some temptation sometimes to use
conditionally conjugate prior so in in a big big model
you know a least conditional on some other parameters maybe the prior you're gonna use is
is conjugate and that sort of thing can make computation a little bit neater
but I would say you know really this is history and it's a mistake to
let that kind of consideration persuade you to do you use a prior
that doesn't reflect what you really think
now we can't say much more about priors without distinguishing two different subspecies of
bayesians and these the subjective ones and the objective ones
the subjective ones
are kind of ideally idealist living on a hill and the objective ones are the
ones who have to get on with reality in some sense subjective ones take
the view that
providing we work hard to think about all our probabilities and write things down consistently
OK and we've really done our best then and
use bayes theorem properly then all the probabilities we come up with properly represent our
personal degrees of belief in
the uncertainties we still have
OK very very clean and you know nobody else can really say anything about that if you really believe
the sun won't rise tomorrow or that
you know the euro will go up tomorrow or whatever it is
you know that's your beliefs are your beliefs and that's fine
the the objective view is that achieving that in complex problems is just too hard
Ok you can be
you could be fully coherent you properly understand your own uncertainties when there's a small number of
variables or perhaps you can't when there's a lot
so the objective basyesian takes the view you you'll be inevitably forced into simplifying things you gonna have to you know approximate
your beliefs by something you something you can work with in particular you often
have to assume lots of things are independent when you really don't know they are
and their view kind of leads into saying that
conditional probabilities don't represent ordinary judgments in the in the natural sense but simply quantifying the extent to which
event logically determines another it's a sort of necessity about it rather than
rather than the best guess
so our emphasis now switches into choosing priors to have minimal impact on posterior inference rather then
properly quantifying probabilities so it's a little coming from another different place
I think for interest of time I might skip over this but there's been some effort to try
and objectify the choice of priors in Objective bayesian inference
to make analogy to
compassion is on the detector
of the text
today i just want to spend some time the
and that to be determined
what do we to have a
that are coming from that given time in in binary form can be used to
analyse computer
and in fact we have three type of digitization in you know
the first one is a very simple one like you one bit ADC which is
just to say whether we have got to heat which is the signal
being higher than a given threshold so that very often what you will find the
city contractor for instance we you just have the preamplifier shaper followed by discriminator and
then you just one bit per channel
thing is that sometimes you want to add up an captured measurements you wanted to
know what is the
for the amplitude of a given signal after the shaper
all you want to make
to to get seven point seven hundred and points on your signals which is just
you are
making like tossing dies you are just looking at the value of a signal at
a given at a given frequency and this is done by a and there are
several types and we them with the number of people and which can go from
a few for two twenty four for the best
best of them in terms of resolution
things that we do is time measurements of the instances you have you can measure
the time of flight of particularly in between two
to detect although you can
you can measure
the duration of a signal
of the
now i might be able to time of a signal with respect to a class
what we do a lot for instance with that see in it see we have
collisions every twenty five nanoseconds so we have a clock at forty million and very
often we make some time measurements with respect to the
to the face of the clock
and that the time to digital converter in fact
start with that
so the plan to convert i
short introduction to then
the first thing that we have
do when we when we want to make precise timing measurements to have a good
discriminator and there's this device which is making the conversion between that signal to a
digital one
and then i will go to different
time type of TDC
so again what we have to
simulate time of flight time defenses and and
and and before feeding it to the sea we have to have
physical signal the analog signal transforming in a logic signal so in phase with it
and this is this is all of the discriminant
so the discriminant of an input images and you have an output which is did
you and you want to get the output
we've after the the input with a fixed delay
and avoid any energy to on that
as soon as you exceed especially in in fact
discriminator is like again combined to us again on the fire
so you've got
so you've got this symbolic of an amplifier you put films footage and as soon
as the signal will be i of this i found that you will have the
which we see also you have good input here and after a while one of
the output which is so this one is kick could be any type of amplitude
as soon as it is i have and especially when you get get invited to
attend bit
so example
of commercial device from format to to format devised just for you to get an
idea of the kind performance you can get so you see in the first line
opposition leader this one is quite fast and its two point five minutes
in between the input and the output get something so it's the the
the output is in this case it here which is one of the
normalize the logic level
and this and you have got very
the latest fashions o which is also so good when you want to have a
so when you want to have a good time resolution you have to be very
careful use some form systems so very often will with almost city casino's finds opinion
people i would prefer to play output
we got the shape which you will get all with the same lifestyle and the
amplitude is changing so now let's imagine that you've got
and threshold somewhere on the single you see that
because of this course compiling i've in time all this signal of starting at the
same point what i will get the output of the comparator is something which is
not the same phase
and so what we call that
time walk which is that just
because of the amplitude of the signal
you have phase of the output is changing
and you can get quite a large number of instance about issue of it time
you go from ten to be able to one you put fifty million one special
you you will get the time walk which is close to also which is a
so what do we do
to to tied to get to get rid of that
it a i will come to do that is to is to apply some tricks
which is which is probably the
this is the measurements
this is the phase of the output signal which is called the mean time which
is the fact that
you want to have you will have a zero time single which is something which
is extremely fast despite that if you change the amplitude of the signal u t
some effects and and and the propagation delay which so you see your points one
on this example one
if x is extracted from the pressure of one one part uses that as soon
as you alive
the threshold by more than five million six OK you have always the same patient
but you is lower than that
the discriminator which can fire but then the population has is changed this this one
is good
what part of this one is b
there's good and
you see that you have
even worse characteristics so
difficult to do so we have to do to get to get this phase
but it has to do is to use the
put the bar next year
the bar
basically what you see
is that these independent
given that
x has given
given that this lead to be more technical
i mean of
this course is really for it
so basically we have reliable x one
x p
and have the particular realization is vital for example x
x the
is that the range of his
right so we have the p
x a
musical to
x p
is is equal to
and xing
not necessarily what
if the x is not an unmet medical
this can be anything
this can be the world the probability
bipartite graph
it can be anything you
but of course probabilities and everything zero
these objects can be a
so this is the case for every
x a
x and x
if these holes
we say that
is conditionally independent of x being
given x e
these annotations for independence
so in this case here
we have one
is independent of x b
in this case here we have the vaccines at the end of the conditional
these are exact function only on the on the on the sample space yes
after that they become away
five live
public holiday you will be looking at the probability and they were very very
hard work
i'm not being paid to be here and they had
that's what condition depends will see some examples of conditional independence
and here you have the notation
so x a independent big difference
now let's look at some examples of conditional independence
the weather tomorrow
it is independent of the weather yesterday
given the weather today
that's an interesting example because of course the weather tomorrow is not independent from the
weather yesterday
but if i observed the weather today
then this two things become independent because there is no information from the weather yesterday
can be transferred to the weather tomorrow
it's not completely
president in the weather today
so it's the conditional independence
another condition independence statements
my genome is
independence from the ground my grandparents genome
even my
of course you
the family of grand prize
if you know you
any information about grandparents one held
twenty for we want
this is another example of conditional independence
well i'm assuming well i'm assuming here that all the genes
that comes from your grandparents to you come to your
in most cases in most cases
even so that the system moves
in one direction
from one into another
the alternative is branched chain
british chain
a different type of architecture in in that case you actually have something
so this is not a graph this is actually the
the main
component of the backbone
continuing to grow but growing in
a plurality of pass
you can imagine that one of these is going to pack much better than the
other one is going to have a greater chance of forming such zones of crystallinity
and clearly it's going to be the linear chain these branches stick out and they
tight packing
they prevent tight packing so the branched chain is hard to crystallize
hard to crystallize
and when it forms its amorphous structures it has more free volume
more free volume and also you can think about the glass transition temperature
tg how is that going to work so on so by
looking at
branching you end up with such
there's one other one
and as shown here
that's too
take several changes with
linear or branched i'm just going to draw
several straight chains here
it's possible to link chains
joining them with some covalent
covalent bridges
this is the covalent bridge this covalent bridge
and it actually links one
change to another
imagine the mechanical properties of this material that otherwise there would be weak van der
waals bonds and if we apply shear stress we can cause the material to plastic
leader four but these are strong covalent bonds
so what will happen is i can move this material
sure enough to appoint but then i encountered the resistance of these bonds and this
is i let go of the applied force it springs back so by cross linking
by cross linking this is a crosslinked architecture
by crosslinking
in parts of
elastic this city and this is the fact that the structure of a rubber and
we call such polymers elastomers
elastomers because they will
it will spring back to shape
and what have to happen here in order to allow for the cross we have
to be able to form covalent bonds
if we're going to form covalent bonds we have to break some bonds that are
present in the back backbone
so if i've got it
if i got
o bonds such as this in the backbone and then i come up with this
our group that wants to
somehow attached
it's pretty clear that if i
break one of these bonds in order to make the attachment i cut the change
so by the it's axiomatic then if i'm going to form crosslink i need to
find a set position along the backbone that has a double bond
thereby i can break the double bond
converted to a single bond link up with the crosslinking bridge and keep the integrity
of the backbone while forming a new bond to an adjacent to change
this is the
this is the condition for which
we formed elastomers
and this is the basis for rubber
this is the basis for forever
and i think this next cartoon
shows that here's here's poly i supreme
and you can see there is
double bond in the backbone and by presenting sulfur sulfur is capable as his oxygen
of forming bridges we saw in the silicate in the bar is how the oxygen
forms covalent bonds on either side thereby linking silicate units
well far low oxygen if we believe mandalay have it should have similar properties
so sulphurous forming
bridging structures breaking these double bonds and now linking the one orange back along with
the adjacent orange backbone
so sulphur enables crosslinking and this in fact was discovered here in boston it was
who was working in roxbury
and i i was trying to stabilize rubber natural rubber is very sticky
and so he founded by adding sulfur he could cause the the robert to lose
its stickiness and thereby
developing a synthetic rubber that had superior properties and that it was charles goodyear who
came to boston saw this took the invention licence that it was good you're who
accidentally spilled some of
this crosslinked rubber onto a hot stove and they
the thermal treatment
gave a far superior rubber which gave birth to vulcan is asian and then
from there it's all history
automobile tires and whatnot
there being the same as what went in
so that's the game plan
so we call source coding data compression
and we want to understand how to do this
in order to discuss compression
it may be helpful to
think about idealised sources all
so you can think about compressing things that idealized and and simple
end the first example i'm going to talk about is the bent coin
and then going is going
an outcome and we're going to get lots of articles
now a lieutenant of about
and alphabet has to
character uncle fails called heads
and the probabilities
of those two outcomes
ninety percent chance that tail
and that ten percent chance
my notation is of course random variable
and the probability that x is tales is not quite nice so this is sort
notation are used in the book
random variables
and the
question we want to ask about this
redundant sources redundant because it's got zeros and not very many ones
we to understand better
if we get a file made up say one thousand outcomes from this source
so we talked about quite a thousand times
that's that's a string outcomes have
i found
how should we go about compressing that's string about comes
and finally
what is the smallest possible compressed file size that we should be aiming for
i would like to answer this question before
random variable is just a simple example in general
i use this notation
on sunday
will have a couple of a say ax
is the things
it's a random variable
an alphabet
and the
a random variable
the challenge with a lower case letter
the set possible outcomes
because of
i where i is the number of know about
o set a police
made up people on it
he i
so what
prove it i
right hand these probabilities have the property that the sum of the years
and all positive
so that's
general source of random outcomes
which the bent coin is one example
we're going to discuss
the calling and some other examples
i will discuss the examiner playing missus shannon's
that's the right way
to measure information content
and the right way
to say how much should we expect to able compress things is asked
we define something called the shannon
information content
the sun information content of an outcome
note about just a single outcome for this general ensemble
well we get the random variable it turned out to be
i i the shannon information content of the outcome is
age should have the outcome
level base to
one over
the probability
the outcome
i we measure
well i would be shannon says
that's the right way
the information content when something happens you can say on
i have gained much information
and you that's a measure of information content by looking at the probability
and taking the log
one over it
what does look like
so if you tell me what the problem that the outcome was
shannon saying
plus the term we got if you remember from the of original application of of
the diameter inequality
so with confidence one minus delta the rademacher complexity is exactly measuring the amount of
sort of weakness we have well together with this rather small quantity here
in our estimate from the
so let's just go back and look at rademacher complexity and see what it is
this is the definition
it looks a bit scary but
it actually
has a very natural structure to it because what it's saying is
i'm going to see i'm going to pick a random plus minus one back to
think of it as classification pick a random
labeling of my
function class
and then i'm going to ask how well can my function class approximate that
correlate with that labeling
and i'm gonna average that over all possible labellings
clearly is
for most labelings i can get a good fit
and that's pretty
flexible class and it's likely that it's not going to do a good job i
mean it's like even overfit
your data
because you can pretty well fit anything
on the other hand if it's very small
on average this is actually a you know a small quantity that would indicate that
if we've got a good fit on the training data we must have really hit
on a real
the match with our function class and therefore will likely to
two two
generalize well
log likelihood
did you see
know the cost of loss functions really
you don't think so
i mean it seems reasonable
i see what you mean you're thinking because the labels being in the right place
you point
well if you think of the functions being why i times
f of x i
then multiplying by random plus minus one
is the same whether that's why there are not just make a difference
because you just cancel
you just permute the whole set of
so same
that's true
o point
yeah i agree with that but
not sure but i i d
good point
you should
take it offline i think that's a good question not sure
anyone else any thoughts on that
in size
so the question was it seems a bit strange that you've got
a loss function here which is close to zero zero one and
is measuring correlation with the loss function actually such a good thing
as a measure of complexity mean i kind of presented it is you're just measuring
how well the function class can
actually align with sigma i
i mean
should say that typically what you do is you actually
you see when we put the band together we first found the rademacher complexity of
a function class and then we
and on the loss function
as an extra ingredient in proof about how you can do that i think you
know probably were OK but
it's a good is to get inside much show in fact the correct
i mean the way the way the that is applied in in the support vector
cases actually through lipschitz
so uses a hinge loss and then you have the lipschitz
and there's a bound on the
if you apply a lipschitz function to class then
there's a simple bound for the rademacher complexity of the resulting class
OK so
anyway if we think of this is the function class and ignore the question then
i think it's a very natural measure of complexity
sort of measure how you fit ground was in fact you know some people use
that as a as a way of testing a very nice way of testing
how likely you are to perform well on the test set is just randomizer labels
we run your training and see how well you do
and if you do much worse than
you should be in a good situation
note that the rademacher complexity is distribution dependent because it has an expectation here over
the sample
so we're actually measuring somehow complexity on the sample
whereas the VC if you remember was sample independent it was sort of taking the
the worst case
growth function over all possible choices of inputs
so here there is a slight gain in that respect
but it appears it might be hard to compute
a very nice
the observation that you can further
further application and the diameter can give you something that we i call the empirical
which is the observed practice rademacher complexity on your particular samples so because we can
think of
as the expectation over the value the expected value over
the choice of the particular z
sequence of particular set of training examples if we take a sample
the particular sample we get
that gives us one observation and if we know that this quantity is concentrated we
know that observation it is with high probability close to the mean
and so
we can actually estimate mean from the samples of we take this is the empirical
estimate from the given sample that we actually observe
then we actually end up with this bound
where there some slightly larger constants here three into
coming in here
but we actually replace the rademacher complexity by empirical
so that's compared to here
you notice that this was the true rademacher complexity expected value this is its empirical
value so a second application of the time get
area this is one of the and some of effect size
it's simply a symbol of generalisation what we've done for the drops where f at
this stage was basically an indicator function of the set
so some
large numbers
it's by as all the violence basically
decrease as one of the and whatever basically being the dimension of the space doesn't
mean any bicycles of dimensionality on you have this awful limit or
that's basically what the calumet similarly what is now also about it is not only
you have an estimate of the quantity of interest which is the expectation here but
you can also approximate the value of this system quite easily using the sampled by
doing simply what multicellular approximation of the y so simply simple for once you basically
i dimensional target distribution so you have a distribution with a set of argument x
one x two where x one x two as continue to buy it if you're
interested in conducting an estimate of the marginal distribution of one of the guys basically
so x one the way you do you will become approximation very simple you discard
the song paul the company x of the sample that give you an approximation of
the marginal next
you can learn things that
so that's basically
in chile the multicolored principled come
you sample from places so deep-seated auditioned pi
OK you want to approximate that you essentially in an empirical measures which have the
property that essentially automatically you focus the kind of great problems of fourteen regional by
quality mass once you have these guys you can compute is lean toward you can
marginalize easily integrate easy some some valuable is very simple
so that's quite nice OK but you realize basically
on the abilities to song paul
fall on
the point is a solution of interest pi
so that's nice but think the question is if i give you pointed deception by
so let's say you complex bayesian model
the resulting target distribution is the posterior distribution of the roman five hundred tries given
the acceleration
all the sample from that OK on the answer is essentially
no general way of doing it
the distribution of interest is of stone outperforms ago show gaussian exponential of i don't
know ledge bases whatever
then basically you can sample from it exactly
OK but as soon as typically you're dealing with more complicated scenarios you're going to
have to come up with some kind of more sophisticated techniques on essentially all the
techniques i will discuss essentially based on the idea of proposing samples from
distribution which is easy to sample on tried to use some kind of mechanism so
as to move
your sample from solution of easy to sample from to the target distribution because that's
what we do
in any case if you're interested basically looking at least at some exact simulation techniques
to sample from the distribution
basically our i ask you i mean you should have a look at the blade
of avoid which is actually extremely good
but we will discuss
basically this type of technique here
OK everything is available to begin in matlab toolbox so
i don't know what
i'm gonna basically discusses the scenario where a moving target distribution which are quite complicated
on that at the time you dispel not for
on TV kelly typically
in all these scenarios
i'm going to deal with
i'm going to deal with the case where
i'm going to be important later on
where the distribution
i want
to sample from
he's known only to normalizing constant OK
so i'm going to deal primarily
with the chase essentially where say pi solicit pi x is equal to
a function gamma x divided by its normalizing constant is into integral of gamma of
the war integration domain OK
where gamma is known pointwise but it's normalizing constant is in the typical example would
say you're doing bayesian statistics
you know the ploy on any particularly
you know the likelihood analytically
but the post distribution
is known only up to a normalizing constant is proportional to the point the likelihood
that can be evaluated but you don't have access to be to the marginal likelihood
which is the integral of the likelihood of the point so typically will i want
to admit which are said that was made to simulate from pride but at all
need to know pi the normalizing constant
so the first online models general techniques to do that
to do exact simulation of such distribution is call rejection sampling was proposed by von
having during the los alamos project
OK so
is gonna go for it
regional sampling you want to sample from distribution by x
is proportional to
gamma x OK so you have access to an online version of the target distribution
gamma x but you typically don't know
the normalizing constant we shouldn't ignore of them out the end of the domain of
definition capital that's all they do
in addition sampling
well you say OK
what i'm going to do
i'm gonna
basically sample
i'm going to propose some candidates so important
and now i
essentially proposal poisson distribution on the same space which is going to be doing q
and i also assume that basically
she is known up to a normalizing constant well typically you know it exactly but
let's say for the sake of JIT that i only know q of ten articles
so you have five
you want to sample from pi you introduce the probability distribution q
on this version two has been picked so that it's easy to sample from OK
and then you want to introduce a kind of mechanism which essentially wants to propose
sample from q
is going to do some kind of some kind of feeling like featuring mechanism that's
going to pull you with sample from pi OK
so to do that you need to
introduce i into
essentially the assumption i make it essentially gamma two stop is basically bomb
so he obviously i could have put a prior over q is upper bounded OK
so essentially what this condition means way of is it implied that where if you've
got mass and the initial
distribution unit to have mass and the probability distribution
OK that makes sense but is also make sure that essentially you need to have
a probability distribution
which essentially as feature tails than the tails of the target distributions OK this is
essentially what this condition is so you want basically the public distribution of this figure
so this is the condition we introduce on two
just don't it easy to set up this is the same to make
OK now basically
you might not be able to compute exactly
the step between them and to start
this is given by c
so let's consid
but let's say that even if you don't want to compute these guys exactly you
not all
one there
over here
we are
all o
did all
i mean
so again general strategy
well if you want to estimate y given x
now we have to do is
you pick some topics and why
some joint sufficient statistic
get condition multinomial ones
we get a multiclass casting process
if you pick wine are get regression
in this case we get possible recreation
and this will give us sequences
and then the problem is convex we might not be able to solve it fully
because it might be
expensive to high dimensional
but we can find nice approximate solutions for it
so let's have very very simple example
multiclass classification
so i could for instance because people as we saw how do you pick you
for fixing y what does it look like how does it depend on y
one option is you could pick for fixed and y to be
tensor product with the y
in the morning i was talking about multiclass
but just distribution of and different domains discrete distribution was just picking EY
to be sufficient statistics i'm just blowing fourth example
by one hundred dimensions i have here
just like replicating this for fixed as many times
many times and if y for instance happens to be three
and the first two entries will be zero
the third two will befall fixed and then all the subsequent entries will be here
and if
why one in the first century before fixed and everything else would vanish
now in this case taking the inner product is quite easy
this is just kind of fixing prime
delta y prime
weatherwise to strangers to sit
there might be reasons why this is a bad idea
but computational is actually very good one
is it allows me to store a few parameters
that's the great advantage over it
and of course am assuming that there is no real interaction no real correlation between
different ways
and that may not always be true
the case that get the data
it's not songwriting from one to n
well the wires going from one to n alpha i y for fixed on y
so it's like having one set of parameters for the class
optimisation problem the big mess but it's convex
well to example some dots here somewhat so there
and this is what you get if you want to estimate p of y given
OK you have to go through them as a little bit annoying but it's not
really deep
i can do that quite easily
OK it works for noisy data
these will be probability point four o point six so you've probably seen similar slides
from bernard he was talking about the margin of support vector machines and you know
what this corresponds to are
certain threshold probability
at the moment i'm just keeping that the level of intuition
election turnout this is not just an intuition but you can actually make
considerably closer map between those terms
summing up a little bit before we go to the next set of slides
what we got from the the hammersley clifford theorem
are decomposition results
we got this connection between
sufficient statistics
we saw that for the normal distribution is actually a direct mapping between the graphs
and sparse matrices
and full conditional distributions we looked at log partition functions expectation through tears and casting
generalized across tricks and we looked at one first example of where this can actually
be is
so now
we have a look at
other applications
now we look at the novelty detection
good classification again
and regression
density estimation
well the MAP estimate
so this is what you would usually somebody going back from the conditioning to an
unconditional models
switching is a little bit
but not if you cover novelty detection
so you're all experts in all detection by now
after this you know it even better
maybe it will confuse it completely
well if i were to do density estimation
well what they do is they would just
so for instance the maximum a posteriori estimation problem
the negative log likelihood
that's from
up to constant the negative log prior
now comes the message from nice concentration of measure results
so this actually
some results of the
got with out and that play quite nicely in this context
but there is one big problem
his g of data may be really painful to compute
because you know you need to normalize it this entire domain
so if
say the axes are over the main of images
then well gee theta would mean you would have to integrate over all possible images
that you could
could ever encounter
so if you look in RGB space
then you have
while twenty four bits per pixel
you take a five megapixel the captured image
so you have
between two to the twenty four times five million
this is not a useless model obviously i wouldn't be telling you otherwise it will
be very powerful
for proving that we can do better than n log n
but as writing down and out of you're going to implement something this tree is
not so
so useful
even if you had a decision tree computer
whatever the case
OK let's prove this theorem the decision trees in some sense model
comparison sorting algorithms
which we call
just comparison sorts
this is the transformation
and we're going to build one tree
for each value of n
also mentioned that can be decision trees depend on
the algorithm hopefully does well depends on n but it works for all values and
we're just going to think of the algorithm as splitting into two
of course the left subtree
and the right subtree whenever it makes a comparison
if we take a comparison sort
like can merge sort
he does lots of stuff it does index arithmetic it this recursion whatever at some
point it makes a comparison and then we say OK
there's too much too
has the other is what the algorithm would do
if the comparison came out less than or equal to and this is what the
algorithm would do the comparison came out greater than
so you can
build the tree in this way
so in some sense what histories is doing is listing all possible executions of this
considering what happened for all possible values of the comparison
so we'll call these all possible
instruction traces
you write down all the instructions that are executed
this algorithm
for all possible inputs
input array a one to and
see what all the comparisons are
how they could come out and how what the algorithm does the and you get
a tree
how big of attributes
as a function of n
right if we if it's going to be able to sort every possible list of
length n
at the leaves i have to have all the permutations of those elements
that's a lot there's alot of permutations on n elements and factorial
and factorial is exponential is really big
so this tree is huge
it's going to be exponential in the input size and this is why
we don't write algorithms down normally is the decision tree
even though it's some cases maybe we could
it's not very
it's not a very compact representation these algorithms and you write them down in pseudocode
they have constant length
has very succinct representation of this algorithm here the link depends on n and it
depends exponentially on which is not useful
if you want to implement the algorithm
writing down the other would take a long time
OK but nonetheless we can use this is the tool
to analyse this comparison sorting out we have all these any algorithm can be transformed
in this way into a decision tree
and now we have this
observation that the number of leaves in this decision tree has to be really big
OK so
well let me talk about leaves and in second
before we get to leave let's talk about the depth of the tree
so this decision tree represents all possible executions of the algorithm if by looking at
particular execution should corresponds to some
root to leaf path in the tree
the running time with the number of comparisons made by that execution is just the
length of the
and therefore the worst case running time
over all possible inputs of length n
is going to be
and minus one could be
the president decision tree
but as a function of the decision tree
the longest track which is called the height of the tree
OK so this is what we want to measure we want to claim that the
height of the tree has to be at least n log n
with no megan front
that's all for
and the only thing really is that the number of leaves in the tree has
to be has to be an factorial
this is a lower bound
decision tree sorting
and the bound says that if you have any decision tree
that sorts
an elements
then it's height has to be at least n log n
up to constant factors
so that's the theorem are going to prove the theorem
we're going to use the the number of leaves in the tree
must be
and factorial
because there and factorial
permutations of the input all of them could happen
and so for this album to be correct it has to detect every one of
those permutations
fans were talking about wave function since we're talking about the properties of waves we
don't only have constructive interference we can also imagine a case where we would have
destructive interference just like see destructive interference with water waves with light ways we can
also see destructive interference with orbitals
so let's think about what that would look like so in this case we would
have one a and one b and instead we would subtract one from the other
and what we would see is that instead of having additional
more weight function in the middle here we're actually cancelled out the wavefunction
and we end up with node
so we can also name this orbital and the orbital we're going to call thing
no one as star
so if we name this orbital this is an bonding molecular orbitals so we had
bonding and we're talking about inside bonding
when we talk about
in two bonding
essentially we're taking one as a and our subtracting one b
what we end up with again is sigma one has an important thing
to remember is to write the star here so any time you see a star
that means an antibonding orbital
again we can look at this in terms of thinking about a picture this way
in terms of drawing the wavefunction out on an axis
so we have one a and we're trying this as having a positive amplitude but
since we have destructive interference we're going to draw one be as having the opposite
sign so we have a plus and minus in terms of science so that to
make it very easy to picture that this is being cancelled out in the middle
if we overlay what the actual molecular orbital is on top of that what you
see is that in this country and cancelling out the function entirely
so this is the one at star sigma one star robert all and what you
have in the centre here the node right in the centre between the two nuclei
so again if we look at this in terms of its physical interpretation of probability
density what we need to do is square the wave function itself we square
sigma one star
we let the amplitude all positive now
but again we still have this node right in the middle
so if we talk about the probability density and we write that and it's going
to be sigma one star square
so now we're talking about one and a minus one sp
all of that being square
and again if we write out what all the terms are
we again have one as a squared plus one be square
but now what we're doing is we're actually subtracting the interference term software subtracting the
interference term what we have here now is destructive interference
so let's think about the energy of interaction here
when we were talking about constructive interference we had more electron density in between the
two nuclei
so that lower the energy
of the molecular orbitals bonding orbitals are down here but we think about where antibonding
orbital should be
it should be higher energy
it's increased compared to the atomic orbitals so we would label
are bonding orbital higher energy
then are one f atomic orbitals
so let's think a little bit about what this means for symbolic entropy any time
we see the star sigma one star that's an antibonding orbital
when we talk about that basically what we're saying and you can see that because
of that negative interference we actually have less electron density between the nuclei
then we did when they were two separate atoms so you can see that this
is non-binding this is
even worse the non-binding inside bonding because we're actually getting rid of electron density between
the two nuclei and we know that the electron density between the nuclei
that holds two atoms together in the bond
so what i want to point out is that it creates an effect that is
exactly opposite of of bond you might have thought before we started talking about molecular
orbital theory that non-binding was the opposite of bonding it's not inside bonding is the
opposite of bonding and antibonding is not non-binding
we can see that if we just look at this picture here here's bonding and
here is non-binding in bonding is even higher in energy than non bonding
and the other thing to point out that the energy
that an antibonding orbital is raised by
is the same amount as the bonding orbital was lowered by
so anytime i draw these molecular orbitals i do my best not always perfect perfectly
trying to make this energy difference is exactly the same for the entire bonding orbital
being raised first the bonding orbitals being lower so those should be
raise the lower by the same energy
so now let's take a look at some of these are questionable
well they don't want to go into the higher energy situation
so we'll start to look at molecules and we'll see
if we take two of atoms and that we feel in a molecular orbital and
it turns out that they have more antibonding orbitals bonding
that's a diatomic molecule will never see
so it helps this project will we see this for example h two which were
going to be about to do c
is stabilized because more bonding and antibonding solar project yes there's a bunch of that's
a really good question
right so
let's let's go ahead and do this and take a look at some of the
actual atoms that we can think about and think about them in more in molecules
so our simplest case that we started talking about with molecular hydrogen i want to
well let's go back to the basic that you can walk on any space as
soon as you can the twenty points so one of the
and the
the nodes of the graph so what we need
is the way in the system at the right
into the space and we need to count between any two two
i will not
but i do
so so the question is
how can make can also the rise
so just to match the following here
all the previous contextual the input
find that
OK is not support because strings is just not given rise
so there can be one of the protein that is the story
in i sense as soon as you give me metrics
all size one hundred by one thousand positive semidefinite is defined by count
OK because any counties and totally defined by experts
so in a sense from the visual effects you can make an account of the
nodes of graph is yes
give me any positive geometries
positive semidefinite matrices it's going to be about him
but what missing here is what i would like to is to be inferred from
the ground scientific inference would be well if another function of an underground i want
to infer the russian
another not intuitively if it's not too far away and the graph like the function
to to pass the positron so actually how to the knowledge of the that projects
into the canal
and what you will be able to see the size that's
they can be first
so that's what
the point is that is not one that so the mother
fortunately the distance to say well i photographed
so from the ROC curve is the right distance between his
the length of the shortest paths
this is not a distance because between it allows me for my right to
a distance
in the process
they have the potential find the distance between the gulf
and then can
so this would be the geometric approach and was doesn't work
in in fact you might think well approaches which is also part the
this approach to do is to the other way around
say well instead of looking at the point at this point that the RKHS and
define RKHS functions by defining with what they call a small portion of the
because it would be easier if any given graph the function from the graph the
real numbers i can myself if i call
small steps right in front of
says i i would be able
to see what to prove RKHS
twenty was kernel
which is it is that these are the more
and finally
question that which is
if you really want to make you know
you like to on our and you might say as well
i really want to make the semantic notion that we can do another the way
here is twenty proved that in fact solve some equation
or after the end of the differential question
and it short about the admission come
the result of documents which is the bad news is they
the question is
nine squared distances
are there specific needs to be said by the show the length of the shortest
path between two points is not permitted it
so as usual
perhaps you don't care
is that in practice you can get that
there is something i'm not sure about so don't which is present same way instead
of taking a financial motive for instance i can think function of the distance to
my knowledge
well i don't know my original noisy way to find function five this the
shorter distances was that
in the cases where you can find trails find is because it tells you i
think it is
so i would like know just to give you some phase also what is a
good solution here
let's forget about that
you don't need to say OK if you give me the right
instead of taking initial sparse let's go the right around the acacias and try to
hello from arizona state university to that
so that
what about what is the most of
it possible
this is
in the
well so what
so that the two explain
the support all that
thank you
this was the first to measure this time
OK with the stuff of trying to make a reason as to why i might
be in this group of people were talking to you about machine learning
and partly because i was looking at my CV and the number of machine learning
ICML paper i had in the last year or so has been zero if you
look at probably lost ten years it still zero so so i was trying to
figure out why is it that i would be interested in talking about this and
you know i should give you some reasons
that i believe in as to why you should listen to me and i was
thinking about why do we learn it and you know why do we learn of
these types of different knowledge are if you are anything like me it's probably because
you want to act in the world and improve your performance and so ultimately you
to be able to act and planning is intimately connected to that so
i will talk to you about so in a way i guess the whole reason
for learning
is to the planet and then to action in the world i'm sure somebody else
it's say a it's a different reason for learning but know today and tomorrow users
into so so i'm going to talk to you about learning and planning basically
the fourth of interesting work getting has been done and getting done in that intersection
so there's a bunch of acknowledgements here and i want read them model but you
know you can look at them up
let me see what are the aims of these lectures i think belfast i guess
it difficult to give you a feel for the exciting work that has been done
and he's being done
in the intersection of planning and learning over the past several years and at least
twenty years OK i should say up front that i'm not aiming to give you
a large saturday of a of every possible people that has been in this area
i have done that in fact they they put in a magazine that you can
get to you know from my from the
if you go to this particular
so space machine learning summer school
so this page from my page which has the people which you whose main the
main interest there is to give you a large
so we have all the kinds of work that's been done so you could look
at that there the additional resources which are much more of a summary i what
i would like to do is sort of an opinionated
sampling of the area to give you an idea of where i t plus interesting
stuff has been done with a view to seeing how much of that is likely
to be more and more relevant as new work is being done in this area
so the two ways to
view these lectures one of course as i said as an application area of machine
learning you know so as i said i think has applications go i guess planning
is right up there with the whole reason to do learning decision monasteries for learning
is to be able to improve your performance in acting in the real world
OK so in the end you view that your that way
in a sense i need to tell you mostly
about you know what sort of machine learning work has been done on the article
may not matter planning community of you know they have done work on improving the
performance of the plan also
the main knowledge itself you know also that two different pieces and then there's also
learning strategies which sort of
combine both learning the domain knowledge and improving the performance of the talk about this
more but to understand any of these i have to give you some very short
brief introduction to
the planning if i mean if you want to improve somebody want to figure out
where they are currently so i'll give you
like i guess one third after this talk properly is going to be just a
quick overview of real automated planning is mostly in as much as it is useful
to understand
the rest of the pictures which is you know how to improve the performance and
how to learn them manage one
OK so that's one way of looking at it another way of looking at these
lectures is the following which is that i was looking at the
a set of lectures that's been given in the last several days and i'm sure
will be given
some more days until the end of this week i and the reflect the fact
that machine learning as the discipline of it has been
doing certain types of has been focusing on certain types of machine learning algorithms and
if you look at the sorts of organisms that have been looked at the sorts
of problems that are being looked at currently and look in and compared what happens
in my lectures about the intersection of planning and learning is it two important things
one is much of the work that's been done in the intersection of planning and
learning has been sort of unabashedly knowledge-based OK you start with
quite a large amount of background knowledge and learning in the context of it now
there has been a tradition of this sort of you know learning in the context
of prior knowledge in machine learning and it's coming back into work but if you
look at much of the work that is an outsider looking in machine learning i
see that you know often times it looks almost as if we are apologizing that
we are using background knowledge about and if you want to use it you have
to convert into some sort of the kernel and then
let it too
but unlike and sparse coding model
here if i show you this new image
i can quickly tell you almost instantly tell you what are the features that make up this image
so i can do
recognition very quickly
and then you can represent again this new image in terms of its conditional conditional probability
in terms of learning
you know it's the same story as as in any type of
graphical model
if you give me a set of ideas images
then it turns out that if i wanna look and they
log-likelihood object if i can try to maximize the joint probability of observing all of these images
there is a regularization term typically people use i could be aligned could be able to
and then there's all the math behind these models not too difficult just a little
bit of algebra here but again you have the difference between these two expectations
you know
the first expectation is easy to compute
and it turns out that is that compute the reason why it's easy to compute
it is because when i look at the conditional probability
that's conditional probabilities is computed and then has to do with a particular structure
bipartite structure of of a
this model
this term is difficult to compute because you have to enumerate all possible images
and again that's spaces that space is exponential so
it's difficult to compute in one of
the most dominant approaches to compute these expectations is is is using markov chain monte carlo methods
right and it turns out
you know these insincere methods are fairly easy to to using these models factors before
this kind of model takes really five lines of my matlab code
five lines of arco to actually coded up
you know in terms of computing these expectations you can essentially do something that's called
deep sampling right it's a very commonly used markov chain monte carlo algorithm
and the way it works is that you start
at some configuration you started the data point
and then you just repeat
you compute the probability of observed data given the latent variables and then you can compute
the conditional probability of latent variables given
given the reconstructed data so just doing alternating gibbs sampling it's very easy to do you compute the hidden features
sample the hidden features given the data then reconstruct the data given the hidden features a new precedent
and that's exactly what i was showing you where when you saw these samples generating
right generate different sounds can generating different airplanes that's exactly the procedure that i was
and again
it's it's very easy to code
if you're looking at maximum likelihood learning for these models right you need to estimate
this expectation this is essentially how looks like right
and then
you know what the theory is values that's if you go all the way up
to infinity you'll get the true expectations
the markov chain will converge set eventually end
you'll get thee thee unbiased estimate of of these expectations
now in practice
people actually use something it's called contrastive divergence probably heard the term contrastive divergence um
and what it essentially does is you start with the training data
you update all the hidden units all the hidden variables
you update all the visible variables against you reconstruct the data
and then you update all the hidden variables again and then you just update the parameters by
by looking at the difference between these two expectations which you can compute
so you know it's kind of
an interesting algorithm it basically says instead running a markov chain all the way up
to infinity just running for one step that's all it says
and it turns out to be very useful learning algorithms very quick
it's biased but you can learn
good features
using this algorithm
now you can extend the beauty of these models is that you can extend these
multimodal all kinds of distributions right so for example if i if i'm interested in
modeling images
and i can think of images has been
as vectors in real valued space
and then with a little bit of modification of of
my energy functional my probability here right
again you have pairwise you have you
pairwise terms you have know terms
it turns out that just
this simple modification in the code you can actually learn meaningful features from images