you will grant equation for the dirichlet integral the continuum looks like this and for
the graph problem
it looks like that so that's equivalent
o plus interview because you're the passing of exit
you also the final boss in natively just based on the topology of the graph
i don't think i really need to go through this for for this crowd and
order to actually solve the problem with the boundary conditions you can decomposable policy in
the block form introduction introduced boundary conditions in the form of the vector
and then solve for the unknown
potentials at the nodes
and what you're left with a system of linear equations
indeed so one system of linear equations per
the label released if you k labels need to solve k minus one systems equations
the weights
again is an sure you all know
take a function of the the image gradient or alternately any other feature that you
had in mind texture color
and the
each pixel rich foxholes associated with one node in the graph
and this representation shows the
the edge weights
represented by the thickness of the edges
alternate way of viewing this
random walker problems from the standpoint of circuit theory the same directional actually integral same
combinatorial dirichlet integral
it can be seen as the composition of the three main
equations in circuit theory
khrushchev's current location voltage law and ohms law
if you put these three together
you get this
dissipation on the circuit and the
system of distribution of potentials or probabilities
is going to be equivalent to
the solution of this circuit the problem
from the standpoint of circuit theory you can think of what the organs doing is
the following so we had a four by four image
and we label three
green yellow and blue
if we want to compute the probabilities that
note here centre of a random walker two first label
before the other two from circuit standpoint we encode all the way to the conductance
is the reciprocal the resistances
ground labels two and three establishing a voltage source with label one
and solve for the steady-state DC potentials these states potentials are exactly equal to the
probability is that we're looking for
and so therefore we get a distribution of probabilities at each node sends random walk
the first label
in order to compute the probabilities that a random walker center the second label we
can ground labels one and three
establishing folded source
i was labelled to compute these probabilities and then likewise for label three
for any given node
if you some these probabilities across different labels you should get one another with thinking
about why this should be true is from the superposition theorem circuit there
original motivating random walker problem that we looked at it can also be
alternately thought of
as circuit theory problem for which it should be no surprise that there is a
steady state
deterministic solution
to distill
the last few slides
here's how you operate the algorithm
generate weights based on image intensities or any other feature
the little plus in matrix you solve system of equations for each seed group each
and then use on the pixels the label for which it has the highest probability
it's about fifteen lines of matlab to do the whole thing
and you can find those fifteen lines available on my webpage look at that way
you can
i interpret this algorithm
from several different perspectives depending on what you're most comfortable with
as i have been discussing there's this
random walker
interpretation this electrical potential interpretation
from the standpoint of of continuous peet's you can think of it as the temperature
could say your image was thought of as the a sheet of copper
these edges
could be thought of as a thermal installations
not not allowing temperature heat to pass between them then you could view the distribution
of potentials are probabilities
as the
the distribution of potentials if you were to set up
a one degree celsius boundary here and is zero degrees celsius boundary condition there
this would be the steady state of the art of
temperatures across that piece of copper which would then be thresholded produce the segmentation
another interpretation going back to the electrical circuit analogy
it is in terms of effective resistance so given the same circuit set up
we could compute the effective resistance between this point and blue
or this point and red
and then if the effective resistance with blue
was smaller it would be assigned label blue
an intuition of what factor resistance represents
if there are a lot of parallel paths between this point blue defect resistance will
be low
but if all the parallel for the past had to go through certain
o point
or certain set of resistors and effective resistance will be larger
a final interpretation is completely different and it's entirely in terms of
and completely combinatorial it should be surprised
surprising that there is a tree interpretation of this
problems because
ever since car shops original papers trees and circuits have really been identified
what's the tree interpretation here
imagine we have this graph
and we see
these two nodes is blue and red and we want to label this
green node
if you were to do the following
you could obtain this labeling randomly choose the tree from this graph
and then randomly removing edge from that tree
and you would get for example something that looks like this
in this case
the node in question is attached to blue
but not to read
one vote
based on the street
i would send this
notable blue if you to keep repeating this procedure
you would you would only be able to conclude that things will happen in at
most one over an hour
at least one over and would be the probability
that's also seems reasonable is only made and experiment
how can you then be sure
about outcomes have probability is lower than one already
it doesn't seem you can really gain information about things that happened that infrequently if
you want to make it and that we away
so fix this kind of stuff
so what do you do if you're it if you want to do things in
the same way
the bayesian
thousands the more complicated than more ingredients in how to formalize your problems
but but what i'm trying to show here
is that
in many cases the
the outcome of your analysis
and the actual procedure that you are a fine
black is conceptually a lot simpler in this case
let's let's try to do
so again you have the likelihood function
which is famous for the likelihood of the
the probability of the observations
given the problem
and then you have a new thing here which called was of higher
the prior is the
the knowledge of the assumptions you make about the parameters
before you make any observations
this is called the prior p of high
what you know about high before you start
what you think about the properties of the point
it's not really the observation that five of the priors
i talked a lot more about
of i thought i was a little bit
so i'll talk about
so in this case you have to say what you think about the before you
start and people get people going but uneasy about this
i say well i don't know anything about twenty four
and then the bayesian with a well
and then you can do inference no way
but you can
if you say anything could happen
for aquinas list is a little bit
it's a bit hard to imagine
maybe it balances on the edge of something like
it's a little bit but hard to imagine let's say you're using more complicated in
the more complicated narrative you trading stocks for example is a well what do you
think what do you think the properties of
dogs are
it's a oh i don't know
i just want look at the data
and that's problem in that right
and of course
stock prices are not
and they can do just anything like if you could do just anything that it
would be impossible to model what they were doing
well stocks had a value of you know
have added value of one hundred yesterday and today as the value of hundred one
what think it has more
can you can say well
i have no idea
good the value of b
ten to twenty six
probably not that seems unlikely
we do know something i don't know exactly
what this talk is going to be tomorrow
if you do that you wouldn't be here
the prior of what do we know about the problem before we start
will get back to
what kind of things you could know about it in another experiment a in that
experiment is not so interesting tomorrow i'll talk about inference about functions that we have
prior distribution over functions and things will becoming in
OK and then then we what we will compute is known the posterior the posterior
the probability distribution of the parameters
after we made observations about the probability of high
the observation that we made be
i notice that the difference between the
the posterior the likelihood is exactly the reverse
the property rights like what you need given y
and the posterior you high
what that what the the likelihood and the prior in high
the distribution over
or upon
and only when you want to plug into the bayes rule here by using
this by swapping these these conditional probabilities
to get the
the ratio of the
prior to the that prior divided by
here pp here is just the probability of the data
and refer to model likelihood of the data
so now
the bayesian inference
so the computing what is the posterior probability
start by some knowledge about the data which incorporated the higher
the update that
you draw the samples from this q and you evaluate
o thing in here
there some
some technicalities about you know a lot about a zero sum of at the details
they the concept whatever that means that you draw samples from some distribution q and
then you evaluate the
some of these things that the so-called
this ratio is called the importance weights multiply these guys by the whole
and of course if q is completely different from p
then the importance weights will sometimes very large and very small that's not a good
would be nicer if these things were often very close to one
you're averaging together you get extra variance
you have to get enough samples here i average band and p PS two are
very different and that adds extra bang we have to get good important and we
have to choose q
that's as close as possible to p of positive sample from one
so can just choose the largest
equal to q so the
OK now so the one one one
objective come with here is well this actually frequencies procedure i just take just take
a bunch of
evaluation just hours together
it's all i can be
maximum likelihood estimates that look a little bit closer at what kind of things what
kind of
by the properties that kind of procedure might have
here's an example
where i've compared to have a function here
i want to evaluate what the interval of this of this function is complicated functions
and within school list
i want to integrate with respect to
from distributions p which is given by
the red carpet
so let's try this try important thing say i can't p because it has a
looks scales here is not quite out so let's let me invent similar distribution which
accounts for
q one here
or two
and then
now let me draw samples from the distribution
and then evaluate the monte carlo estimate
let's say i draw
this report the point light
it's three x values
nine evaluate the function here
now in this case my estimate
it would depend on what the q function was
although i draw the same point
it's possible to draw
these three points from both of these distributions are not that different
and if i draw these three points
then my
estimate will be
the weighted average of the of those function the weights will be different because the
ratio between
p and q
the accusative
this is an example
where you can see that the procedure violated like principle depends on something which was
our chosen arbitrarily
but that does that mean something
we're going on here
there's another problem problems related to the fact that it does not take into account
what the x values are just hours to go the value function for example here
two almost identical values of x
which we happen to choose random distribution
but they still played exactly the same role
in the value of the of the interval
then we're right because they both basically carry the same information
why should you take what you think you coming into account
it needs to be down weighted get two samples that are
close to each other
OK there is no prior and here i'm just trying to evaluate this article
and the piece given
but we can sample from it f is given that this is just
this is just the number
we happen to know what the numbers but it's just the
i did not know a priori
that's one of the problems that we actually
or one of the problems with the procedure that you don't actually say anything about
what the function doing this was just about to illustrate here
let's say you're doing an interval
trying to evaluate what principles of this function
but actually in the procedure you
you actually you don't assume anything about the
function that into matters well look like this
the the somehow
you know
you thing to do this in integrating the green function to be a lot harder
then integrating the function but actually there are treated exactly the same
so somehow we're not using the fact that this is actually
a nice function
agreement not particularly nice
a bit about how to proceed it doesn't use that information about
o'hagan wrote a paper about this which is called monte carlo fundamentally unsound
now the question is how we fix it
we can we can we
and then the procedure
that would turn this into
a proper bayesian inference problem
now says yes nuts-and-bolts health property
so this latent semantic indexing
and maybe
present semantic indexing here or
some of the more recent
world that is in a similar vein like the what you mention but i think
the semantic indexing is
the classic
and and so and it's also i think
nice because it has a very clean
matrix formalisation for linear algebra i was
so i would like see about
the composition that the math behind the semantic index
in what way can be used for dimensionality reduction
and then the whole we use that as latent semantic indexing and information
so we start again with this term document matrix
this matrix is the basis for computing the similarity between documents and queries back in
the vector space model here
so there's this matrix and vector space model is the basis for computing the similarity
between documents and queries because the theory would also be
a column in this metric space
now in this lecture goal is to transform this matrix so that we get a
better measure of similarity between documents and queries
so we want to compute transformation that gives us a better measure of similarity between
doctor doctor appeared
to do that will decompose the term document matrix into a product of matrices
the decomposition uses the singular value decomposition
and looks like this
see the term document matrix
is equal to the product of the matrices using my vt
and then use the SVD to compute a new improved term document matrix which cause
the prime
and we'll get better similarity values of supply
using SVD for this purpose is called latent semantic indexing
i'll use the term document matrix c it's binary so it's not really
the matrix use
if you really wanted to do outside it's just simple
to work with the binary matrix like that
so this is a standard document for
admittedly a very small collection six documents five terms so for example the document you
has three times should or should one
OK i'm not just going to go through the three matrices
i get that compose this matrix c
so i'm going to i decompose this matrix c e
and these are three matrices u sigma v vt
that i get out of the decomposition
so the first matrix is you
it's a square matrix times where n is the number of words in the vocabulary
it's an orthonormal matrix what that means is that the rule that this year all
have unit length
that is each column is represented by a vector that has been
and if any two distinct from vectors orthogonal to each other so we can think
of this as an orthogonal basis for the space because
the term vectors are orthogonal to each other
and we can think of the dimensions as semantic dimensions that capture distinct topics like
politics sports economics
that's why it's called latent semantic indexing because the dimensions
if it works semantic connections
for example the dimension two years
is the wall and dimension
because the water
should vote in ocean
have negative values
and i'm going to call this the land that could also have come from the
world or
a number of common the land grants what intrigued the positive values on this dimension
so this has become the semantic dimensions that distinguishes
whatever its inland ports
and it's not energy in the matrix indicates how strongly related to my eyes to
the topic represented by semantic dimension j that's what just said about these numbers these
tell us
in this case for the day or whatever it's that
this is the second matrix of the decomposition sigma months
as sigma is a square matrix of dimensionality many many times minimax
that is the smaller of the two numbers documents and terms in this case that's
five five five dimension
the diet consists of the singular values of c
these are the singular values
the magnitude of the singular value measures the importance of the corresponding semantic dimensions so
i add dimension
has been problems one point five nine according to this
and make use of
these indicators to me
an important dimensions
so i will say this is an important we can
symbolically described numerical data
understanding of complex event processing what's become very clear over the years is
no as using
what we to call pattern mechanism it is now called machine learning and you have
to say what high of data structure do i want to induce o
so for example
for example that that the hierarchical scene understanding system you might know that in fact
the type of rules i have to that need to infer
something being part of the structure
is that there this attribute inside which is part of a given distances from
others might have additional generation of for relational hashing techniques like for example if i
have these attributes
this parts of these attributes and we have to to this part two other
the relationship no correlations example distances and angles between this part of the public sector
such a problem then what
so this
balance on attributes of generalizations and attributes
almost like being for example
support vector machine or something like that you're going to use a mixture model
but then just little little little estimation techniques controlled
but the fact that got this
data structure
so we got this
this control of numerical
merge or numerical induction why this syntactic properties of the data structure you need to
to guarantee
you know the rules that describe the data
in some forms meaningful for example
the head consists of some eyes nose and mouth usually and you want to have
a description because the the the police officer wants to type in something in english
to clear the data bytes
although many many numerical machine learning techniques are provably lovely
they don't often dispose themselves or
initially description
in finite time
so that's the this one trying to get out of this is the different literature
and what you may think of it
traditional machine learning traditional machine learning mean
machine learning in the last fifteen years
present US fifty four hundred years
in traditional
normalisation because you simply this is the type of real you you've probably heard of
if is activities in certain classes
the because
and this is useless
in most
image understanding problems
because when we come to classify
my head all my body moving here in the complex in the what is missing
data and all that stuff
what's important
all the data the thing that part of the class
so i'm going to find a subset of data the classifier but how do i
choose on my goodness is not going to work
so this techniques great if i know what i'm looking for
we have precompiled
the search
to emphasise again so once signing is think carefully about the data structure
you want to infer about or learn about when you're trying to solve the problem
of understanding and predicting about complex signals
i'm going to talk about that more and more
so that structures are not rich enough and generalizations are not relational
my you are pushing extreme case because of my interest to do that cause many
problems with the article was sold by activity induction whatever
and in fact relevant to the previous lecture
how much variance is explained by the first sort of statistics how much is explained
by the second how much is explained by to probably lot
i don't know i don't want to take this is an oversell fully aware
the the first order information is often very very
workflow in fact some professor of english at university newcastle who got towards simply showing
the amount of prediction of of classical authors like actual photos or whatever
milo completed simply by the frequency with
i can't think of the binary is an old man to the freedom in the
so is probably going to try and emphasise the going rate for all how to
summarize relational data
and so summarize what direction that i have to be able to sort of match
things to summarisation
the matching problem in trying to summarise
so then i will probably to want to end induce over the past
there's a problem with missing data
this problem of by the way when you with learning
the problem when you recognise
in our case is usually
what you recognizing even better
in many many other things called the same
it turns out this is the context of the work
so it depends on problem's structure is attributed graphs
this literature over the last fifty years
the most common
this representation of the data structure we work with is basically an attributed graph so
or features you're playing with whether it's my or an edge something like this is
like fifty vertex
and the vertex set attributes for example orientation
hyperspectral signature infrared heat when i was going to be
can a whole lot attributes could including position if you like
not necessarily
so the sentence
she gives a few moments for questions
so what
was this
first thing called SIFT trace
there are various things that can do the same as the last the trace has
sort of teachers based on some of the work
and the idea of what can happen when
that stuff is mostly not yet in the mainstream can still argument going on about
how it should really symbol table
the rest of the
there are various other traits tells
there is a kernel debugger which
this is very funny about dividing tells they tend to live in the moscow
which is also very diverse the debugging anyway
that's almost as easily the most useful kernel debugging tool we have these days for
things that are not part of specific bugs
if we go virtualization
so you can run it can learn something like you have the impression that it
crashes without revealing machine
and you can benefit you get to make the emulator do strange things
in certain cases
people also depends on you've got a funny happening come already does very occasionally
you can write small emulator
from the drive into the emulation
tracy when you press the button
bad things happen
press the button on the hard disk pretends to crash test support
i told that this user but minutes
because all of the
well everything that runs in user space you can actually GDP
so you get the single step a kernel new space running out of one of
which is extremely useful certain kinds of things
the the main thing
the best thing i never driver debugging used area code and occasionally large quantities of
sometimes it is necessary to get into the same state as the guy who designed
the but are pretty much essential because
the documentation for hardware really agrees with what they actually does
so you get but you cannot possibly find any
that's one of the cases where i use the kernel debugging which
it's sometimes one cases where you specialization
at times of even when using the program to just poke around in because you
next PCA space from user space and CPU
so you can see how to read and write it in user space
these are used for delisting this in this space doesn't
maybe try
previously selected registered to get the right answer
and some of it is just magic sorry
we have many better way of doing it
there are several things can not just specific process before
the intel four six
three six
is the only case where you knew you may not have hardware floating point
it also has some memory management differences to do
whether the right protect networks from kernel space
and intrinsic motivation very complicated particularly when threading
the whole set of other cases to deal with things like this in user space
memory which are really are
so in theory you drop just three six four actually doing is dropping
anything below four eight six
and i believe also
the next gen five eight six process
which is so obscure i only ever had one but report
every scene
so it's not like it takes like twenty seconds before
every other press out outlets is and is capable of pretending to to be
well they will have to drop four six foot six love harder because the process
today which are not quite twenty
and possibly fixing the mistakes of the perceptron why not
trying to make an update that the force is large marching on the current that
but every time we make a mistake
on the kind of the example
we making up to that
cost us who achieved the imagine a list of the one if that example comes
so this is people
this is of course i mean more aggressive updates
and there
so you might be interested to see whether it is because
easy to compute the canonical solution
in the
we can view it as a sort of
online SVM and says we are first-order theorem in the sense that we are
imposing an SVM SVM band of solution on a on the single currency example and
not the whole
we're interested in getting incrementally patients
let's see
the as is the following
or being
a large margin
on a single example
so i suppose that
we made a mistake
the the current i
without making assumptions right now
the fact that this is actually what i wanted
i will be correctly referred i said the wrong thing suppose that
know it's it's correct
we want to make it happen whenever the our lives in a small
whenever they have more than one
not whatever make mistakes
which is what i was going to write
this is the condition that triggers an update but now is not a mistake but
if it was more like that we don't have enough
on enough confidence on our classification
this is now the new condition for an update not been made another mistake but
will much more than one
and then we would like to make an update that forces
large and i think i think i
but this is updated
and this is the the
the kind of examples
and we want it because one
this is equivalent to say in our vision that the loss
all that we use the hinge loss of w one
he began iraq
how do we do this
i mean there are
one easy way to get the form of the solution i propose that we can
write the solution of
we can write the
the updating viewers former
we have to use such process update but we add the
a learning rate it
now suppose that we can write after this format let's see if we can
if you can find in a closed form expression for it
so now
we now like this
definition in this condition here
and what we get is why the
WP minus one plus it that they were x being
this is a vector just being the bar
because we are now
and we want to say OK let's say that we want to achieve exactly matching
one so we want to have
the update that
exactly brings the margin of one
for the new vector
so now this can be written equivalently
many we can we can it
at this point so we have the what i think that the minus one x
but it that it
what he and why the square this is one
so we have to be more of x squared
equal one
which now
there is also the solution for
is exactly
one minus y and w one minus one x by the by
x where the
since we make it happen whenever
commission is true
this equivalence can be written as it were
l v
all that matters
by the by norm of x is squared
so now
you see that what she them and you know one
on on the on the same example
it's enough to make an update
learning with which
the perceptron update with the learning rate which is equal to the hinge loss
of the past guy
on the current example divided by the square of
so what is this dramatically how can you help can view this
it's very simple no
you can
we will we
we'll see later in the more general think that this the solution
is that it is up here with
form of
it is equivalent to the
solution of the following
one is that problem
which is
this so w
that the man of one minus the real
such that
and then we read the model conditional on x
which is why
x b
the other one
but this is
this is the
first of all the one and so we have to way
now we could actually
remove that offset and actually
i had one extra component in this vector which would be constant for all the
training examples and then effectively that b could have been wrapped into the w here
that would make a slightly different problem because the b noticed doesn't occur in the
optimisation criterion
but it will be a minor differences in the b would then be part of
this w square here
so the
you know whether you
it's a matter of choice as to whether you like to keep that b
or not if you if you're keen on it
it sort of feels right if you think you of the margins
you end up
with this additional
if not then that constrain disappears
when you solve this you know what the weight vector is some alpha i y
five exercise
you don't know what the threshold is the but you can work it out by
looking at the border examples now i'll talk about the border examples a little later
because i
i don't want to throw too many sort of distractions at you but that
you know you should give you feel that OK
we can solve this problem
by finding the alphas rather than finding the weights
once we got the alphas we can do the classification because we know
how to compute it we we actually
did that
some outcry
you know in about five x five x OK so so for everything we've done
is just rewritten
you know
the problem in terms of these alphas
we haven't got around the problem of the high dimensional space yet
OK so now the crunch comes that
we can actually imagine a situation
rather than
making the projection explicitly of two points and computing the inner product we might have
a shortcut functions
so this might be a function that somehow cleverly
computes that inner product of those two projections without actually doing them
now if we had that
we're going to call it a kernel function k
suggestion that we might be able to find otherwise what we call common methods
let's imagine we had one OK so how we use it OK so
so it's wrong quite well
here we have this inner product between the projection of x i and x j
OK we just apply kernel function to exon xj we've got about
so noticed by doing that we
we shortcut it having to do
and now when we want to evaluate
same thing with just got to use be able to evaluate the inner product between
x i the new example apply the kernel function
we can compute that again without actually explicitly computing in the high dimensional space
so basically we've got this trick if function exists we can now
the support vector algorithm in the feature space
in high dimensional feature space without ever
actually computing a single vector
in that space
so it's sort of magic in the way i mean it is remarkable
kind of
trick you know you're working in this space without actually ever
however using it
i come
one analogy i have not sure is good but anyway is this you know when
someone who was sent to kill medusa and if you looked at
the deal with all makes the hair and so on then you to understand so
you can't actually work in this space because it's too complex you you're just going
to be you know killed by the complexity but you can somehow look at it
through a mirror and
and the mirror is the kernel function somehow gives you enough information to work in
space without actually
you know getting bogged down
so that's the you know what one would like to do and i'm going to
give you an example to show that it does actually
happened in the example we had OK case so here is this
quadratic projection function that we were looking at which takes the vector and projected into
these quadratic
OK well let's look at what the inner product between two
vectors projected into this space is
OK so
i've written it so this is a bit a sort of you know the kind
the derivation but i mean ignore that this is just the outer product matrix of
x next prime do you can think of that
you know putting these into a matrix so x one squared x one x two
and x two x one
x two squared you know below it then that's that's matrix and similarly for z
prime and then the inner product between these two vectors corresponds to the frobenius inner
product between these two matrices
just notation nothing nothing
OK and the frobenius inner product can be written as the trace of
the product of the two matrices while the transpose of one and the other
and then when you're into traces you can
movies around and take x to the end and you just have ex-prime z
times the context so prime is the transpose
so this is just the number of times the number
so the trace is just
traces just justice on the diagonal elements if you only have one by one matrix
symbol number
so this is just the inner product between x and z squared OK if you
don't like the derivation you can write it out and you know just
go through and it it comes out but basically what this means is that
we can actually evaluate this inner product
by evaluating the inner product in the input space and then just squaring
so for mining
thank you
i want to know
we might be better
what is the correct functions are
in cold
and the figure out
language crisp functions
one to tool that is that function
and when you use them all
then you can optimize the
you might not like the fact
sort of
agree to it's quite important
now in its being done more
it was a new for example where you know the
it's right panel
i think that
i think
something is happening in the future is that we have a lot more
grand functions extract information to
modeling work
you don't show you more realistic really is
so you can get
out of the
and you can get
if different models are already known literature
last words
so the final
it was time to get to the just talk about a few people on
minimize the second half
approximate inference for constable constellation
the data on this very very beautiful
for gases
all this user goes what
have of knowledge
the b
so what we're going to do is going to approximately by
things are really think
so this seems to me is trivial thing
but it turns out that the nice
you can
twenty nine thousand
in particular
so there are lots of proposed for classification and what is called the expectation propagation
what about to that this is
there's not a lot of features
is roughly
our goal
all right so quite
question just two
the company
one house was relation to read it
one slide show you
construction which looks very much like this which network
except that about everywhere
not just the french
i do the rest
but model
it's going to be useful in combination
want to
that's box
he said
i over
grows have
we're trying to model
and if we get higher
then he
so what we get
at the
you can do little
iteration to find
well what would the what is the corresponding
i mean what was
four days before constructing
this property
and such
it would take some here comes
now i have these
that is
number of
the next five years
and i just prior in the sense that they all
drawn independently
from about
this just like noise
so i already the fact that the distribution functions
which is defined by the city
it's going to cost
and then compute the mean function is great
is distracted
i mean function
it is
is the average of
some particular location x
so next year fixed
the thing adding more is the process
during the
we have here
so we need to ensure or
that year
so this part
and and ongoing
it is
seventy five
looking up
i don't know
it's just a call for
that year
one of gas but OK lot
but just because symmetry this as much as other ways to make it work
not surprised
more interesting to try to compute the
so this is now
tation times some x
this is the right here
and in this situation now
random fluctuations
it's only too much time together to
these two terms are
because independence
the that you
the only contribution the same
you need to know about this guy
together with
same for
things that
to do it
garcia is
and i just get a
but the ratio of this
but i was in school
e to the process know
and some at times
x five
i can be described
the rest of the functions transferred to get
when you
i assume that have just about
except that it
i'm hearing way follows a little state
depending on its current state
read writes the current square
possibly move to a new state
possibly even shifts its position
so this must mean in addition to the symbols on the type we've got a
bunch of stats
that's true his these states and the usual
terminology the notation reason here's choose q
so is that
is the
the states
then this things that the little true machine can do
move right one square left one square
chinese symbol
all depending on the state of its in
if we had one of these things and we let loose on this on the
it moves around changing symbols may be moving left and right
for all i know it might stop
not have any further states that can go into
it finds itself in the states
reading symbol
somewhere other ones on the type
and there is no further instructions
we call that
we say machine household cats
so long-winded way of saying the machine has stopped
hasn't done anything useful with than
the turing machine device
just continuing for as long as
we look at
might be something the machine is doing
that it just keeps on the my keep moving left on the time it takes
you don't have to go and stop we just looking
we can tell from machines health we can't tell if it's going to hold in
so find out
maybe tomorrow
we can tell general fitz can hold
we certainly see it has hold that just interstate looking to sell
this is not moment
for his little
standard little picture
often jeffrey put little wheels on cell
as if
we really want to make this thing in your computer and
it doesn't matter if it's got wheels
it just cannot appear cell can only move from one cell to the left to
right at the time
but it doesn't happen
in this particular conception turing machine
OK most of finite number square not playing
initially and later stages
and the machine knows what reading
and the initial configuration is part of the description
is mention about stalinism state
so these are the picture
next slide
is you
just that much more mathematical formalisms this
i think that this is just an example
so here's little example running three
simple ones on a blank tape
there is there
the head of the type if you like this we might allow is
right simple one is left
it's another similar left
it's another symbol
and then holds
it doesn't have any work to do
in its description
so each machine
computer programs specific that's a turing machine
in each one
there's some specific description what happened
under certain conditions
is my slides
tried to fit song
it you may not thank me for this is that we try to do
those three things here three ways of describing the very same machine
what we trying to describe machine i think it's i think it's the machine right
three s one and then stopped on the left right time
because i think it is yes
one way to do this just be to put a table of strata title
there are three states q one q two c three
has two symbols
and we'll see what happens
under every circumstance
it under this
particular machine what's about to happen
so reading the first cell of that matrix
and the state q one reading symbol it's zero
it's supposed to write symbol this one
and then changed to a new state
that was the thing
looked like this
it's rating
it's not which is blank
it's supposed to write this one
and next instance time
it's still right here
now to change that
q one before
changes to q two
that's one cell
the other cells to what else can do it
one of the cells in the matrix is display
because it is not going to do anything there
should the machine error
reach the state q three
and happened to be reading as one
wouldn't have any way to go
i'm labouring the point because
we want to worry about with machine stop or not
so we just have to have
good for idea of what it means for machines to stop and all i mean
you can vary around just there's a hole in the matrix if you like
there's something it doesn't have does any more instructions
it it does it just stopped stone state q three
so what you can do this way can have a special state called the whole
moved into the whole state
the flag from
the second technique is the true machine flowgraph technique
which expresses i guess more
a flow chart sort of idea
which now
i guess people may be thought that was very modern
computing to the phi chapter
now we wouldn't necessarily described computer programs that sort of mechanism but certainly quite helpful
for our reasoning
and so this thing here says this is a little bit over here left
which seems which shows
you here is
only one of the
wish i it is transformed to a
he said that we it
and that is
so every time
of the
in fact
so i think
it's just
and they are
the same
and if you want
so i mean
proposition one
this kind are satisfied that means that the score of the correct is the most
of the case is larger than the colorful and correct ones
but if one want to impose if we believe that this kind of thing like
this should be bigger than this kind of on correct one we could either constrained
to that quadratic programming problem
we can solve it by name
iterative algorithms
in a similar way to previous approaches
and eventually in that case when the data is not linearly separable we can relax
constraints by adding slack variables
there are going to be in that case would be nice so we have basically
force that in the first step we compute the moment in the second step we
maximize the call without any constraint then we entering the main loop
and for each input output pair in the training set we compute we identified the
most violated constraints and
as karl suggested to there is a big is larger than the score of the
correct input output pairs we add to the set of constraints constraint that imposed the
discovery of the input the of the car the input output pairs should be given
and so we solve them
we maximize the discourse subject to that constraint
and it would be these until this set of course trains does not change in
the iteration
finally show some experimental results related to the south african to the problem score approach
and to this core approach with constraints i will
briefly show that our method performs better than the order in case of four
i level of noise is what we are doing here is generated random sequences by
starting from around the vector of parameters for the chain conditional random field with HMM
features we consider two
kind of conditional random field one with this when the the size of the
observation alphabet is four and the side of the the ninth of it is to
another one
when the size of the observation alphabet is five on the side of the you
know enough about you three
the sequence are the length of the length of fifty and the training set size
is made by ten to face side is made by one hundred pages or the
results generated by
iterating the process of for one
under the
and we compare our approach with the previous approaches and we plot the there either
and the number of incorrect labels that dividing level of noise and as you can
see our approach are better in case of large p
and p represents the the probability
a mirror represented the level of noise that we generated by flipping even labour in
the training set
and the problem is that the
that we a we consider the learning curve
for them
a second graph here when the level of noise is the zero point two
with the land enquiry
for a or the algorithms that we can see that i did not show any
are the discourse in the performance of are very similar to sort out and
what we have is that our approach performs better than conditional random fields and the
perceptron and is very competitive some are better than the SVM high so that we
use and i mean lots of similar to
may i got the presented this morning by PASCAL
and in this case
we see that the performance in terms of these that very similar
with as VMI's about we analyse the computational cost of learning we see that our
approach is much faster especially for
when the size of the training set
becomes larger
another spearmint means that we need all again with artificial that is that we consider
a chain conditional random field with HMM features and the side of the international but
is the the size of the observation alphabet changes saying experiment we want to show
that with something approaches we can obtain good results so basically it
we compare how we use our approach by computing matrix with dynamic programming about computing
matrix with random with estimates of the matrix we approximate sampling on fifty parts and
two hundred parts
and we plot the results in time of this and we see that
one of the four methods are more or less equivalent but of course using sampling
the time is the much the computational cost and the time for learning is much
more reduced
simulation that we need to get it to featured that is to show
the second condition is that w does not have control converging arrows along the path
so you go this way or that way and w is observed
so i find these two conditions are satisfied then vd separates
x from y
and if you haven't seen this before i don't expect you to look at this
and say aha that immediately makes sense takes a little bit of time to think
about it i'm not going to go into details because i want to be able
to get into the propagation algorithms in the learning but there's a lot of good
material that tries to explain this
including longer tutorials of this kind
that might be online
so the kalahari
four bayesian networks are directed graphs is
the markov boundary for text that is the set of variables that make x independent
of all other variables
the parents of x the children of x and the parents of the children of
x so given those variables x is independent of everything else
that's similar to what we had
in factor graphs
so let's let's look at some examples
if we have this graph
a is independent of b
marginally independent since
a a c b is blocked by c
and a CD b is blocked by d et cetera
so all the paths between a and b are blocked because
nothing is observed
none of these variables have been observed is not true that a is independent of
given c
since a c b is not blocked so given c
a and b are dependent on each other
and this is a very important concept
given the particular symptom
the probability of having this disease or that this is the kind of course that
those probabilities are going to be correlated
OK the
joint probability is
it's not going to be independent even if getting this disease and getting that this
is going to happen with independent probabilities
and and furthermore we can look at a few other things like a is independent
of the given b and c
a and d are independent given b and c on this graph
it's all paths are blocked
so here are some of
useful notation that again you'll see in a lot of papers
you see this these
boxes around some notes with the little
later in the quarter this cold plate notation
and it represents repetitions of some
very so consider n data points generated from the gaussians
we have x one through x and let's say that the calcium has mean mu
and standard deviation sigma
could write down a little probabilistic model where we have p of mu
being the prior on mu
p of sigma being the prior on sigma and then
the likelihood
the corresponding to each of the data points
this is what the graph would look like
for this factorisation right
each node given its parents is represented like this but these are these guys are
are replicated n times
so to make the graph little prettier and easier to look at we can put
a box around one of these nodes and put an index here and that just
means x and
goes from any cause one to big
that's plate notation
all right so that's the summary of the first many lecture
topping it up into lots of little bits i introduced different kinds of graphical models
focusing on factor graphs and directed graphs i got the marginal and conditional independence markov
boundaries and the idea of the separation and placement notation
any questions well i look the next
built up
all right so we introduce graphical models very quickly now let's talk about inference and
propagation algorithms
so what is this inference problem what are we talking about consider the following graph
which represents joint distribution
that we had in the previous
that inference is the problem of evaluating the probability distribution for some set of variables
given the values of some other set of variables
so for example
how can we compute the probability distribution over a given that c takes on the
value will see
right and you could imagine
if you have a big graph
corresponding to
nuclear power plant are big medical diagnosis system you input your sensor readings or your
symptoms and you want to find out the probability that there's a meltdown or the
let's proceed so basically we can also write these
in two different places
the camera is equality like this
because based theorem gives us these
troops in bayes theorem
before in
in life it certainly but in the in the court about
and this is also true here
we can apply bayes theorem
with these other two vials as well the bayes rule whatever you call
so i mean basically these three
are statements are equivalent statements
so let me just
discover we discover that
a given
i will apply
some type of factorizations
for the joint probability distribution which is not unique by the way
i can factorize these way
these way
all these way
and these three
factorizations will give rise to precisely the same conditional independence
that's important as well
o input was the conditional independence the output
is apparently a set of possible factorizations
so we are starting to
more into the
the details
OK so let's try to
navigate slowly here and try to
get all the
so what seems to be happening is that
the conditional independence statements they seem to generate factorisation for joint probability that's what seems
to be happening have studied this for a very simple case of
three viable
probabilistic models
now let's see
what are we going
by using this graphical model in terms of computational
let's see
an example of how expensive it is to compute
p of x two for example
well first let's be naive
as we saw in the beginning
let's compute pfx two by some
the joint
distribution on x one and x three
for every
possible value of x two
i have to go through all the
that is thick
three and x one
compute the
and then to go to the next value of x two
they need to fill out
all these
for the complexity of running this thing your goals
could be basically if you think that the size of three
sample space is the same this could become the size of examples
we use the factorisation
again we have now
in linear order so that means it converges linearly so that means
the objective function at the tth iteration
minus the objective function
the best function
this difference goes down like c
the two part minus t so the c depends on the function
OK so it goes exponentially down
so i mean of course i would like to have this as close as possible
to do
so she sees less than one
these less one so therefore this converges to zero
these changes
you right
OK so these mistakes of making making negative plus you
thank you
so in practice of course i mean when you would like to apply this bound
so then this c
it's very close to one
OK so it's maybe one minus ten to the point something so i mean this
huey so and maybe maybe in practice it would help to show really fast converging
so the other bones which have shown you a much much stronger support this this
shows you in principle these are doesn't converge
OK as a corollary we we can show that adaboost logistic regression least square boost
all these things converge
linearly so with this performance part
so this was not known before so those are only known when the data is
so there we had this PAC boosting property that we have the fast convergence here
with much better constants and here so here the optimisation of in the
proof i mean
the techniques are more difficult into the
bones are not as tight
OK so this is
this was condescend so other questions for that
one more question
OK so now i go to the dual domain again so highly optimized and alpha
domain so we chose one final optimized so now we go back to the d
domain so that's you domain
we optimize these the weights on examples of course OK
so we have essentially seems like so in each iteration we update this deed deep
distribution here and this is the solution of of an optimisation problem here
so this is a generalized projection onto a hyperplane
so you can generalize this this one as well
you can define a generalized distance it's not the distance but so it's called a
distance so it it is called the divergence to bregman divergence a monthly has to
fight to find that
and so the distance between the bregman divergence between dm dt
for a function g
is it just
the function g
at t minus the linear approximation of the function kx in this picture in slide
so and
if you use GSM s i think the time slot the then this is just
that it was setting so special case of this article
OK so and not most one leveraging would find the closest point to the closest
dt so the point close to dt
which is on the hyperplane so that means
this is again the hyperplane
and now we do this project here
so the back projection
if you put the project with euclidean distance they will get this point and here
within it really depends on on the function g
leveraging the essentially doing this projection step
in every iteration
and there's something which is called the great along with that's from things from nineteen
the two for this work the children identified among which of these are
which of the right
classes whether partially with purely derived or partially derived
so we should still concentrate on all the three classes
you can fix all the purely derived classes and start to fix
partially derived classes
OK back to hands on
so what you see
here then is
the exploration workbench
we've got a justification selected this is a i students
and on the right side we see
just we see a justification for the entailment over here
this is this justification has been computed for entailments see here
the number of justifications for entailment is shown in this column here
you can see that some of the the
figures are filled enough because they have been computed you can ask the system to
compute all of the justifications for entailment in this list
so we select these and computes these other justifications as well
you can go down to the bottom here
you'll notice that this lecture taking four courses has three justifications
all the other entailments have one
so what we're going to do is take a look at some example justifications
so let's take a look at this first one i students
no way to read this
is that the first axiom here so you can see such image larger
so it's OK the first scene in this list is that posted entailments i students
opossum nothing the actual entailment in this column we just paying the the consistent with
the rest interface we just coughing that we don't bother to show that suppose nothing
below we got four axioms in this justification
and there's some presentation going on here so we all the axioms using certain heuristics
we also intends from anything easier to beautifully two this one we see that AI
students of class of things
least one professor in HCI as advisors should just point out this is the manchester
syntax by default prior to show uses manchester syntax which
is a slightly different from the description logic syntax but hopefully it shouldn't be too
difficult for you to know the correspondence interviews push before you be used to it
so we see i students subclass of has advisers and professor in HCI
we also see that professor in HCI
is we also see that the inverse property
of this has advised property is advice evolve
and then we see that professor in a CIA i
it is advisable of
advisor of only eighty i student so this means we can conclude that since his
local administration this means that anything that is advised by one professor in HCI
or a i must be in HCI students and then we see that a i
student disjoint a shy student and this is one reason why this class is unsatisfiable
any questions
take a look at another one
here we've got CS department which is unsatisfiable
the game
the tell shown in the first show here
i we say that CS department is a subclass of things that
affiliated with least once slightly
and then we've also got another restriction here that cf library is affiliated with some
and the key thing is that it's affiliated property here is transitive
so this means that RCS department must be affiliated with e library
and then we say anything that was also said that it was affiliated with RTE
library must be
and the department
so this means CS department must be in e department
and these things are disjoint
well the whole point about user interface here is that you're doing uses is based
on heuristics so it is not
it's essentially the best thing all the time
so you might like to change that you can do that you can have a
play about a new vaccines and justification around if you press control
and then use the arrow keys to do this you know
the up and down arrow keys move the axiom of down
and also to press the left and right community
x around so it might actually be preferential here that we have
these axioms close together so we can see that this chain along
and then the inference due to the transitive property
so any questions so far
a little bit about how we actually
compute these things
various ways that we can do it but broadly speaking the way computing committees were
divided into two broad categories
and so do the services are generally implemented as either glass box services all black
box services
you have go
OK OK
so if just go over possible services first glassbox implementations first
and these implementations are specific to a particular reason
so if you want to
this can tracing to compute justifications to these now
you need to an existing these now you need to implement some kind of tracing
and this just to say this requires usually if there are non trivial modification of
the reasoner internals so
if you want to take something like five plus which doesn't currently support
this tracing but it will do
it takes quite a lot of effort track which axioms used because there's all sorts
normalisation going on inside the reason
and so is nontrivial
and examples of this palette
what do you can ask how is gone interface you can ask how reason why
for exploration last entailment you asked about
and also the sole reason here
for so reason can compute all justifications for
and then tell us how just computes what one justification using this glass box technique
and then use a hybrid technique with black partition going to come on next to
computer remained justifications
advantages of this approach is glassbox approach is that it can be really fast because
usually the tracing techniques used just almost come for free
in the case of pollock for example and i don't require any extra resources is
almost noticeable
but it requires actually sources in terms of time
and memory so
the advantage is that when you actually computing
where the sum is satisfiable or not
we also automatically get justification computed so it's very fast and almost cancer-free
on onto black box
so as i mentioned
the with glass box in crisis there are non trivial modification of these entails it's
quite difficult if you want to use it with your favourite reasonable or in your
it's just a tiny detail and
i will call those points margin errors that have a positive side i
remember kci was the thing that is
making this constraint easier
you can already
imagine if that's the point which lies in the mountain or even on the wrong
side so the constraint is violated this so i will start growing but since the
site penalized in the objective function and will grow more than necessary so will only
just enough to make this constraint satisfied as inequality
so for all points which have a non-zero XII
those points would be support vectors in the sense of will lie on the edge
so one can prove this formally that from the KKT conditions follows that all margin
errors are support vectors
so margin errors are subset of the support vectors
but there could be more support vector so there could be some support vectors that
are not
margin errors
but they only support vectors
which are not margin errors are those
the only support vectors which are not margin errors
all those that lie exactly on the edge of the margin
so so we have two sets here we have the set of support vectors
we have a set of margin errors the set of support vectors is a subset
of the set of marginals is larger and one can prove that the size of
the set of support vectors is lower bound by this parameter new and the size
of the set of margin errors is upper bounded by this from to new
moreover one can prove that asymptotically these two inequalities will become quality so this parameter
new which is parameters set by the user
before running the optimisation problem controls the fraction of margin errors and the fraction of
support vectors so it's you know if you want to physically meaningful parameter
so if we compute the tools of these two problems have already mentioned to you
two of the sea
soft margin support vector machine is
the one the same as the tool of the hard margin SVM with one modification
that we now have an upper bound
on the other five
the dual of the new political machine on the other hand is a little bit
different so it consists of maximizing this function which is non homogeneous quadratic form
a little bit simpler than this one which also had this linear term simple quadratic
term is the same
however this
i find some of the finest which was part of the
objective function is now appearing in constraint so we have one more constrained
we still have this lower and upper bounds and five so these are sometimes called
box constraints we still have this equality constraint but now we also have this constraint
involving u
in both cases we get the same decision function
so let me say a little bit about how support vector machines are trained so
if you try to support vector machine you in some problem you are likely to
simply download and SVM package nowadays there so many different packages you can get links
to them on the kernel machines website i think i have appointed down here
you probably will download package but nevertheless it's good to at least have an idea
of what's behind these approaches and this is that the one slide summary of support
vector training
we would like to maximize this thing here
maybe this thing without the subject to certain constraints and if you naively plug this
and optimize from the matlab optimiser you will find that it scares approximately with the
power of the training set size
so that's
essentially because matrix that you have to
plug into you optimise it will be the whole kernel matrix m by m where
m is the number of training examples so it would be fairly expensive this method
and also you will need a lot of memory to plug in this matrix so
if you have more than ten thousand points it's not really feasible on your PC
could be
so the first idea for how to improve this
the situation is that only the support vectors are actually relevant so that i mentioned
before if we knew what are the non support vectors we could just throw them
out and only trained on the support vectors and we would get the same solution
so if you have a problem with the support vectors are small subset in
that would be very attractive
so you don't know beforehand but what you can do something in between you can
in turn
three quotients and numerous cancelled
and we clearly got that
so why do we bother to do this
well once we will start to the right of the bar
then we can
three can play that
so now
we're estimating the probability of these three forces being in the respective positions product
of three independent productions
what's the probability epitaph will be in third place
that will be in second place the river will be in the first place and
we pretend these are all independent other
is that correct or they in fact
know how do you know there the cap
for almost get
because they can be first year so once once we know the valentine epitaph for
in second and third place that increases the chance of being in the first place
so crossing these things are probably actually did
probably actually did reduce the probability
from what would have been if we kept
but you know this but this is not totally crazy assumption in this particular case
we might be able to prove it
this is sort of a general pattern of
how you can estimate lots of things happening once is used channel bodies often decide
what to ignore
so maybe in this case these worth ignoring let me give you the terminology
by crossing these of of the assumption that we're making is the
whether revere wins is independent of whether valentine places and protection
not quite independently but conditionally
so always said if the weather is clear
there are independent of each other that whether you're wins is unaffected
by these two events
if the weather
so we might say it's completely different about it
i'm sorry
completely different if the weather is not clear
then suddenly the data coupled
but there are independent if the web so that's why we say conditionally
i and this conditional independencies in engineering assumption right
so we decided what we're willing to you can test against
well if you enough data to be able to find out whether there something like
in in
practise this is something we do when we don't have enough data to get what
we really want to look
i carla into joke which is that the guys as well
founder twenty dollars sixty sensible
OK so let's get back to language identification
so here we have a real science courses and workshops around the curriculum
and the only reason i knew how to pronounce that was i was doing language
idea pieces of the set
and anybody know who were savages
got invented polish notation
was not prefix notation and since this is hard to pronounce
people actually that also have a slash across
people call police station and if you if you have an HP calculator uses reverse
polish notation rewrite three four class instead of three miles four
so we have to decide we have take a single language
for the whole to what we think the language is
well there are some idea of using and models so do we think that this
is good english
do we think that english dies
will be likely to generate a a sentence or do we think that polish dies
would be likely to generate the
maybe instead standardisation talk about monkeys typing randomly right except of english monkeys and bullish
and there are many many of the monkeys maybe the keyboard type typing
so you know if you're banging this kind of keyboard you're likely to get you're
now the importance for this just is huttenlocher case is the complexity speed up so
searching here is a search the complexities into the p
once you get down to a star model military model then the
both the training and in recognition search is much faster so n here
the number of detections
p and the number of parts so the government of the p twenty
two n times p
much much faster search
that means that both the number of detections number of reasons we we detect in
the first place and the number of parts can be increases of values in six
parts and maybe only twenty five to thirty detections now we can start increasing the
number of detections two
hundreds of thousands and this is very important where you've got texture in the background
and the foreground
because you have to detect many many reasons to be sure that all you need
is a lots regions on the order interested in
it's christmas party
that's learned
that's it
there's a slight loss because the inclusion isn't that was quite so well in this
so in the fully connected to any part can be
you learn how model any in recognition and in learning any part can be included
in this case if it doesn't have any
the anchor parts included the model can't be recognised but any of these other parts
can be
included so i mean this is technical detail but that's that's where we will use
the admin intervention
it's just a
it's true essentially so for each
each detected feature we've got a set of parts as to be assigned
but it it's
it's the same reason any to this tree search
can be done efficiently that you
you have to consider the pairwise relationships to given the way these things always work
is given the choice of one you can work out in advance which is the
best fit of all the other part of that pair that's way these things work
but could not the case in here
you have to do everything else
when you're working at a cost
the first one
so you're saying time relationship between the past and the future
so it's
the ricci flow constrained
it just
so this is the case those who have shown that the world is
that you going to solve this problem
one them does answer question about but this template or not OK so you're right
is the worst case complexity but you say the structure model is very very loose
then you really can't jump out and see if you think the the case of
the spotted cats this the gaussians are very very loose you don't you really don't
have a a a ten place in that case the parts can move very unrestrained
see in fact you in that case you can't jump out of the a star
search very quickly
so that in in the
in other cases the the appearance term might not be very strong so it
even though in some cases might be like templated the
structure term is very very tight in other cases not and correspondingly sometimes appearance is
very very loose
so yes this is the worst case complexity is but
that's all i can say on that
now the question
right and his example of stalking even number of parts small
but increasing the number of detections is recognised spotted cats is a significant improvement
as i said that's because you've got more chance of finding
is species section which is sort of the features section in this case if you
have more detections much more likely that the foreground object cat in this case is
going to have detections on it
we're seeing here all these pink dots actions
well you can see the hundreds of these detections now whereas before the twenty five
because that does give performance improvement
second realization is so far we just talked about one type of pageant and in
fact all the models received so far the the
the parts of corresponded to parents
it has been
after capturing the geometry of the object in the part
i mean the spatial configuration
so one judgement straighter ways to go
four curves which more directly go to the geometry of the part so
in this case they wanted recognise this guitar
we can find the outlines objects
in parts
you know no one in this case one could find the curve or the objective
cut on the background because like get broken but using a canny operator some good
edge detector one can find the boundary subjects we find a scale
scale invariant representation of is not so important but that's done using by tangent points
to segment out this region like is the scale of this curve and then becomes
a part
just on the same standing is the appearance based image fragments we've seen so far
so in fact we're going to have three types apart now we're going to have
the circular salient regions detected by the media and radio operator
around the
you can see very well but because around the fuselage of the aircraft and effect
for type will be
these multiscale harris
detect something called it little about this yesterday as well
OK so we can build in any any type part which for which the detector
gives a position and scale
OK that's all required
when we come to the learning we have to decide which parts should be there
so that the learning data then we put we pull out a six to the
data for validation and on the validation data we compare various models with different
blends of these various types of parts curves or
patches and determine which blend of parties best design best performance
so on motorbikes
this curve is recursive here
is for heterogeneous
model which has three parts which the patches the captain brady detector patches in three
parts which are curves
showing the model so the that's
patch kirkpatrick et cetera
the system is here the here the because being found on the outline of the
of the wheel
OK so this heterogeneous
and this is a increases performance
for sparse spotted cats the passage which first the recursion here are both patch like
regions it's the multiscale harris and the guardian brady not because not important for spotted
cats saw texture blobs
OK listen recognition of those
questions and that come to
right so let's see what we've seen what can we do now in terms of
what you see in the game again dealing effectively with one aspect of an object
the from frontal the rear face from the front all profiles
that's that's what the stage now
when combining learning techniques with these bitola structures we can effectively do this for maybe
ten types of object classes and this is not the number of course is going
to increase
you we can do translation and scale invariance partial occlusions OK background clutter is OK
both recognition and in training
so if you if you find lucene is
almost what you want but not quite
then when you have to consider thinking about
adding something that that's that's the way it works
it becomes what people want to become
so not
is a
another project that i started apache
it's as opposed to just a library for doing search
it's it's a full-on applications
and the forward search so it's a crawler
it has tools to maintain the link graph
which is
use the search for doing like analysis things like pagerank computations
as well as a source for getting anchortext for
the page
it's very useful to know
all of the links that point to that page with the text of the anchors
of those links was
so you need to be able to maintain this link graph
it also does
document format detection passing so they can extract
tag has been abducted by forgetting
turning documents into
text properties that might index
so working on PDF and RTF and ten hml and given the name name word
but also language and characters detection are there are
not things that
unable to match but finding them in a form that is appropriate for web search
what was something we
couldn't find on the shelf so we need to to build these
generic tools
and everything is
is extensible pretty much
it lists around the perimeter down so that the crawler is extensible in lots of
ways of passing is extensible what gets index for document
and how you can how queries are transformed into searches it is also
so we go into a little more detail
not uses lucene
as its underlying search platform
by default it stores
these fields in these fields for documents among among others
so was fields have these properties is also on the property is the basis for
the core one so it in match
there a URL field which is stored
and in the scene story field is one that
he returned with it
the one with the actual the literal values stored in the index
it's index which you can do searches of URL
of the URL field is analyse which means that we break the urals into words
fact analyse your also saying we analyse in text the same with the same the
same tokenizers you talk a little bit more about that
we have a feel anchors services all the anchor text that is found that associated
with links
to each page
we don't store that we don't need to return with him
we do index we need to organize it into words
similarly for the content
this site pages on this is used by various things so we have that the
language that's
the page is written in his also
the index can be search
and these are some of these are these are literals or not
not word strings that
and the
it is this
for showing snippets is a yes much
much i think at this point has its own snippet library there's is one included
with seen as well
so several available to do to exhibit ourselves
the ten axis
basically trying to match
what is the standard for web search
but providing this in in open source form so that convention is that all query
terms that users and are required to have to occur somewhere
in a matching document or an anchortext for matching documents but have always had URL
the projects and the content of the page
and there is the reward for terms being closer together
for proximity
so the way that this is implemented
is when a user enters and match two word query like search engine is expanded
five class
the same query where
there's too required clauses which is
the word search
has to be in one of your all core content and
the word engine has to be in one of
the same field
so that's sort of the basic building requirements in order to call imagine has had
both of those in one field or another and then we also
look for places
we're reward more these are either phrase searches the telly is its proximity operator
there were more when the closer together as well as with these these three classes
do now
i charles size
things x y c
BBC MPEG one or more parameters which
can be tuned
now there their default values there but they haven't extensively and that's something we do
need to work on this is to try to improve the quality
by by tuning all these the up arrow was a
in scenes query syntax is boost operator so whatever number we put here this is
a number which is multiplied into the score of this component
this clause that it's
it's combined into scores
something that has caused this
so if you put two
if you made actually will two then matches on the URL will be rewarded twice
as strongly that matches on anchors kind