well connected through these lines that brings tweedy
OK so
line was already the degree one
we were looking out into
the events and we discovered that there were also using metro line which was these
metro lines
that represents the events so they the red line was also existing out anyone can
be this station
across the red and the green line
what we did
however enough of tutorial was actually understanding that we have to be the blue line
four music style
and we also have to develop
a yellow line
no sorry the yellow and i was there
but they were scheme is about time and place and we have develop the red
which is about events
so mexes here is a is a metro station that use something which was and
is something new
gives a new ontology is
black line which is this one
but i'm loath to query
all the other lines
so it's quite true now i understand also share this with me but this representation
is quite meaningful because shows how you develop an application while you develop exactly like
that of the these that line here use things and what you enable
these black line
and others can put in new
metro station will very to maybe you're using other ontology so that we use or
so thank you for listening so far
next is a sparql and then down into implementation
right let's do that means that you might like to do is
is there anybody out there
that already did this work
so you've write you be overseen chair
you might find our ontology
actually you don't OK but you might find our ontology
but we did for this tutorial
so you can reuse it
so reason why you should use the semantic web search engine
is to look
around and see if actually very easy anybody data the were before you
in a way that you like so that you can reuse
this is a dax
the index of the RDF ice and seeing the also index microformats
so if you have things like the idea of a
or are
other microformats is also
that was the index finger because the world
i mean that i'm not an expert overseeing this you might look around for people
from the galway know
how they did it what i know is that the the index everything using their
the names of the tribes was
these what i know
review of
the new
you was
you been
replace it with me
five of discovery of the
when you do
you could be very few of them yes
i mean for instance if you go and search for music you will surely find
music ontology
which was developed after we did is this tutorial in this it was really one
year ago more or less so his music and he was not really
and yes later on we discovered that they did it probably
if i have have to do it again i will use the entire music ontology
would be much nicer to say look i goes on seeing this i found the
music ontology if you use it unfortunately is not that easy i mean
i think it as a piece of code can not just on blog piece of
code from your blog and others you have to try to doctors in many cases
right OK
and you have a question from the previous part
OK so
i was
call for sparql
because i believe it is useful for what i'm going to
to explain later on i don't remember how many of you don't know about sparql
i really don't know about spike
so it's worth fifty to say something about
sparql is the query language of the semantic web
he twice careers that back in two thousand three RDF was there i was almost
and many of the coolest things with there
but no query language was sparql was
basically put together
in the last year and becomes a recommendation last year
and and this is queries because we want to query language you cannot really the
morning about a
my name is to run the mile
the idea
and thank you very much in the pre nineteen year
falling we're standing
after four days
i was trying to do this as painless as possible
and stable either
very general to join
just for applications
i want to focus on a particular model
using computer vision
which are not about the recognition already been
to build
it's with the full feature space through the representation of the image
also have been used for image classification
outline of this seminar is very simple
i was sent by introducing the field of computer vision
and the challenges
in this field
at least four
the task of categorisation
and then i will focus on
recognition task and most specifically
on categorisation
we about of visual
world model
and then we show so
examples of application domain where the bag of visual words model being
has been used
the main goal of
the same thing
is giving a brain
a very brief introduction of the field
and show how to recognition algorithm is used in computer vision
and to provide some references and pointers
four people are interested in
best thing they like the recognition algorithms in
challenging problems
offered a vision domain
what species
in nineteen ninety two in it as a joke book
the lower friend shark intuitive answer
to the question of what it means to deceive
and according to my
to see means
to know
what is where by looking
vision is the process of discovering from images
is in the real world
and where it is
and this the formulation that express the competition of the
the human vision consists of processing images
i've seen
as soon
make explicit
what needs to be no idea about the same
and on this account
low level vision
recall some information
the basic information of the image and high level vision
try to understand the meaning
of the sea
for instance which object inside
which kind of the scenes
but most pretty well specifically
do we want
by looking only match
we can ask questions like what is in the sequel goal and
well is
and this kind of questions multiple answer
for instance
we can answer that there is a big so
in the december of the cocoa
with brain as one hundred forty three
other the position x y
twenty four
fifty four
or we can answer that
that's part of the match
look like bottom edge of whiteboard showing at the top of the image
the difference in this slide is not just a matter of scale
in the first answer
we're trying to
they measurements remains
the second one
what we are perceiving
in terms of what humans care about so the goal of the computer vision
what where
i'm tens of what humans care about
and what you might care about
one thing we can do
is finding something
that we have in mind
or verify whether this thing is there not
and we call this stuff verification task
well we have an initial questions like this that class
or sometimes we
and we don't know if such object these in the image
by way i look for it
and the key components
the project going to tell you about as
based on what is called by spectral by spectrum is not the venue think people
have been looking for a long time even in the classical case of representation of
signals just on the real line but people not in signal processing may not be
familiar with it so i'm going to gradually build things up from the classical case
there's no group here in the first part and then generalize it to the case
of noncommutative groups in particular the rigid body motion groups and see what we get
that way OK
in the simplest thing is to just look at functions on
the cyclic group cases like group and numbers zero to and again you can imagine
as the numbers sitting around the circle neatly like this function on this group and
you're looking at the end invariance with respect to the natural group action translation from
the respective transition of functions with respect to groups with sorry with respect to this
group with is just like rotating the so-called OK so this is this is just
the classical thing is given a signal eg periodic signal and you want to shift
invariance worshipped is interpreted in the cyclically symmetric way so what goes that one side
comes back on the other side and your domain
let's start with the fourier transform
because we know
this is just the fourier transform and like the discrete fourier transform it appropriate to
this group
we knew
that the fourier transform
or base this translation property rights of the individual fourier components behave in simple
three prescribed manner on the translation in particular what happens here
i think then you have a raised
is that if you have a function f
you have its fourier transform
but you transform then translate the functions so looking
and the fourier transform of the translated function at some frequency can it's just going
to be
two to five times k
of the transfer of the original functions
so this is nice
because it immediately tells you that if you look at the power spectral
and that's going to be invariant
the power spectrum is just
the modulus of the
what like the amount of power in each fourier component which you get by multiplying
the fourier components with its complex conjugate and then these factors that you get get
from the translation immediately cancelled
this is not surprising that if you have a signal and you're not looking at
the signal it's just looking at how much
energy has in each band then that quantity is going to be invariant with respect
to translation so this is a classical thing that people in single processing use to
capture signals in translation invariant way
of course the problem with that is that knowing the
power distribution of the signal tells you very little about the underlying signal so a
lot of information is lost all the phase information is lost right so this is
a very lossy type of representation of signals and and essentially the problem is just
what i said before the the the the phase information is lost you want some
phase information to two
to go away because you want a single translation to not to affect your representation
but you want all the relative phases to be there right so somehow you want
to get rid of one global phase but you want to preserve the relative phases
of the different free components
the natural way to do that
is to start
OK is to start combining
how for
different free components of free components corresponding to different frequencies
and this is what gives rise to the
by spectrum
so the by spectrum is similar to the power spectrum
except that this is a cubic things in the original signals explicitly couples the different
OK so
this will stop the relative phase information from going away because you are still
doing this complex conjugation things and
the exponential factors coming from translation going to can solve for that reason but because
you explicitly coupling different
forty frequencies going to be
retaining at least some of the relative phases
the interesting thing is that it turns out that you retain all the information so
if you
compute all possible by special components let k one and k two independently range over
there are possible values
then this thing is going to be
a complete translation invariant representation of the original signal
so this has been known in
and single processing for wind and so the number of applications in particular people have
looked at using it to
representing variance in vision
with some modifications it can capture scaling and rotation people have used it for rotation
and for translation but people haven't really put these different types of transformations together because
whenever you try to use the classical
by spectrum are always limited to
the translation group
in general abelian groups right so as long as you have just one of these
constituent transformations such as to rotation or translation or scaling then all this classical theory
from signal processing
that's right i wanted to use the next one and a half hours to prepare
my talk
and then i have to remember whatever i want to talk about so
you're ready for quite a lot about nonparametric bayesian methods
you've heard two lectures by karl august in processes
and you've heard a lecture by the way which was mostly about the the dirichlet
what are
my talk on my two talks here are mostly about is first of all they
are basically a better title would perhaps be theoretical foundations of nonparametric bayesian models but
that would be way too long it's just foundations and
what what i would
like two
conveyed here is
the intuition that that ghosting processes inherently processes and other non parametric bayesian called stochastic
process based models
are basically
instances of one and the same
approach to constructing model
and so
i would like to convince you that you can think of nonparametric bayesian models or
that good way to think of nonparametric bayesian models is
think of them as
bayesian models on infinite dimensional spaces
we have to talk a little bit about how you can construct useful probability distributions
on infinite dimensional spaces because usually when we construct the probability distribution just write down
the density
and that doesn't really work when we go to infinite dimension
what i would do today what i hope to do today in the remaining time
first of all i will have to talk for
o forty minutes or something about measure theory
the theory is what we substitute
four densities if we can't work with density
then i will try to
tell you a little bit about bayesian estimation in that context of measure theory of
course levels in bayesian estimation before but in the context of measure theory looks at
then i will tell you how we can construct stochastic processes and how we can
use these measure theoretic concepts to construct the gaussian process the dirichlet process
and then
from there and i hope you
you will start you will be encouraged to start thinking about how you can what
other nonparametric bayesian models you can possibly construct right the girls process gives you distribution
over functions during the process of probability measures but maybe you want to construct
nonparametric bayesian models over the infinite dimensional objects over kernels
infinite graphs infinite permutations of one
i'm not
going to do
very much in in terms of introduction because you've already heard
by the dirichlet process and the girls process in quite some detail
but i think it's it's about time that we write down the definition for what
a nonparametric model is
and you has already mentioned the nonparametric model is not a model which doesn't have
parameters actually it's model which was which has lots of parameters
first let's look at the different of definition of a parametric model
this is the pointer
it is
nonparametric model is the model which is not a parametric models
but what is the parametric model is the parametric model is
a parameterized family of distributions to model is always the family of probability distributions right
in their indexed by some values some number of some parameter
so this is this is what essentially what the name says but then some fine
print and the find princess
the number of parameters does not depend on the sample size
so think of the gaussians
distribution that you fit to data you dataset and you fit in the gaussians with
maximum likelihood saying one dimensions we have two parameters
and that number two is constant
with respect to the sample size it doesn't matter whether you have a hundred points
or thousand points you always have two parameters
nonparametric model is the model which is also
is also a parameterized model
just like this
but one that doesn't match the fine print so
the number of parameters can grow with sample size
and since we already when we are really talking about gaussians
in a way that you can do
nonparametric estimation of the gaussians or
say if if we fit model to data
just to girls parameterize model parametric model what kind of estimation is that
i mean is that regression classification
but what are we doing
density estimation
fitting riveting in density into
so if we wanted to density estimation and nonparametric way
and still use gaussian bell curve function what we can do is part the estimator
so what we have basically do what we basically do is we at each data
point that we observe we fix
the gaussians
one small garcia and then we add them all up and normalized be smoothing over
the data with the gaussians
like a low pass filter
and that means that we get
three that the number of parameters to grow with sample size because we get one
goes location parameter for each data
so that's a nonparametric estimator
in general a good intuition
four for parametric models is that the number of parameters
it gives us a measure of model complexity
and the more parameters we have to estimate the more complex model is the more
data we need to get a reliable estimate
and if there is this complexity is constant with respect to sample size
then it's it's easy to imagine that we get nice convergence properties when we see
more and more data then asymptotically
we get a very good estimate
for nonparametric model that's that's not the case anymore so this the situation doesn't hold
any more but it turns out over the last maybe
thirty forty years and statistics
they have been quite quite a few results which basically say that the convergence properties
for nonparametric estimators are
almost as good as the parametric one usually it's it's not that that the convergence
properties of that much burst is just that they harder to prove
in bayesian estimation
in bayesian estimation our basic approaches that we set up the parameter space and then
we put a probability distribution on the parameter space and call it prior
if you want to do that
where is was a nonparametric estimator like this
and that's a problem because the number of parameters can change the dimension of the
parameter space will change
so can we put a probability distribution on the space
was changing dimensions
and the answer to that is that you
that you use
a space which has enough dimensions
which has more dimensions than you really need it has enough dimensions
for you to explain all possible samples that you might look at
and typically if we don't want to bound the number of samples beforehand
that means that we need an infinite dimensional space
so infinite dimensional space you means
we want to accommodate
sample sizes which are finite but arbitrarily large
we want to be able to invest parameters to everything
so typically typically in nonparametric model is model was an infinite dimensional parameters
actually in some textbooks for example larry wasserman in nonparametric
textbook right said
another name for nonparametric estimation would be infinite dimension estimation
the lebanon war
so you think that news you take your the social and network analysis and you
can immediately find the key people are
i contacted
so you you take the political situation in europe the deriving
the the network involved in the political situation
you could do the same thing for individual person
once you've done this analysis you can then choose somebody let's say david cameron
you can show is network
and in this case we got like the family network likely that is why
then we got the red these are people attacking in
or people who are criticizing him and he's got support network and tony blair courses
and you can see
now you can do this also for microsoft outlook and google
and you can find out who the
who's attacking them who they supporting
and in fact we've got the rest recesses of these companies so this is a
nice way
finding your enemies and friends
the last topic i can go
i'm i'm at the time but i'm going
just quickly go through this
we have been working on a tool for
web mining which is using the same
the same techniques but instead of mourning
this set of mining
the these sites will manage the web in general
so what do we do we decided to use google cause because google was the
best search engine
so we will have tool that sits on top of google
you do a search
you get some results from google
but what's different now is
once you've got the search results which can we take the first thousand an advanced
searching google we take a thousand
URL's and we send out
multi threaded spiders to everyone
we extract the text using the same technique is for the news and we bring
them back to the guys computer
this is the this is the tallest being asked for violence security people and the
law enforcement so it's information extracting information retrieval use google finds sites extract information
eliminate duplicates
don't follow dead links et cetera
OK so you get the stuff back the coarse who hire you can then highlight
the people's names in the looking for
and you can highlight the
the the search terms obviously
once you've got the data
so you've got all this stuff sitting on computer
and you want to do something with it
and the analysis so we have the same software has been deployed in newsexplorer now
sits in this talk
and i will go and
extract all people's names dates
geographic locations et cetera and extracted from the
the text you just go back to the web
what's expected data
it puts it in database
and you can then
browse around
and c
who's related to who now
what we don't have working here is the relation extraction that i was just mentioned
this is based on two people
being mentioned in a document within a
path lengths
there's no there's no pattern recognition on on the type of relationship which we should
add to open the soft eventually
so what you got that you can then create you can but you can read
the documents and you can
you can see the documents et cetera
and visualize
the relationships again this is now using a plugin visualization tools sitting on top of
OK now
that is orchestrated conclusions
and then we'll
OK so
i think i have tried to
emphasise that this security application areas the big
is a big thing is a big growth area
and your data mining tools applied
these are
are in strong demand
five by business and by the sea by national law enforcement agencies are
there have been recently many new entrants into this new material which i think is
that we saw
traditional well
it's our bread and butter is what we do in artemio basically run media monitoring
for the commission
the mobile web is an interesting one because syndication can become more and more important
mobile devices are assessed the perfect for for
so this is this is the second lecture on machine learning and cognitive science
and i have probably
by some counts two thirds of material still cover we're gonna we're going to pick
up where we left off talking about learning concepts from examples going beyond some some
what are basically textbook kinds of models they were doing things like simple kinds of
mixture models last time
two more interesting structure knowledge and just kind of scalar hopefully get into something that
looks like an intuitive theory at the very end
that's mostly
but the the into intuitive theory land is actually mostly open research frontier
i'll say you know one of the reasons why one a little bit more slowly
than i thought i might last time was when i started to explain his experiments
to people who don't have much of cognitive psychology experimental human subject experimental background realise
there a lot of things that i you know there wasn't explaining that you need
to do in order to interpret the grass so i was
i was trying to decide how to adjust for that going forward i thought about
just cutting out all of the human experiments but that wouldn't be any fun so
i'm going to still try to talk about some of them but because i want
to make sure have time to talk about some of the interesting structure models that
were doing i may not like me and i put up the graph which you
which i may not expect actually understand in detail it's more of a queue for
me just to summarise what the point of the experiment is but then reference you
can go followed up and i'm happy to point you to any papers you want
to learn about the details of the experiment okay hope that will that will be
a good compromise feel free to ask any questions about the experiments with the models
whatever you like but i may just say i don't want to go into detail
of experiment because otherwise
we take too long
the motivating example we have for talking about learning concepts from examples was this example
here you have a few examples of
one of the new wording too far and from that you are able to generalize
and we said well if you think this is just the problem of learning from
from three positive examples it seems very hard impossible it seems a little bit more
approachable if you think of it as a semi supervised learning problem with these all
these unlabelled examples and from that you might be able to extract something about the
the general structure of how categories organizing this domain which this
very simple picture captured if you're if you look at the state and say others
three clusters there then all have to do is label or and you assume that
the concepts are are mapping one-to-one onto these clusters that you can pick out then
one positive example should be enough
but what this
picture obscure will it offline and essentially what i'm going to be talking about today
is all the things that obscures and how to learn how to solve those harder
problems so one of the most basic problems that come up in any machine learning
and statistics in particular when you're dealing with things like images of natural objects that
are intrinsically high dimensional or maybe even infinite dimension i mean like about the image
is a high dimensional vector you could say well there's really object in the world
and there's all sorts of things you could measure about it
only if you come up with the right features are you going to see the
right clustering so the problem of feature selection if you like is is the familiar
and as many different ways to approach but one way we can get some traction
on this is to say well imagine that we have lots of useful features we
compute in the brain is is
highly optimized revolution with the senses another processing to pick two to compute lots of
useful features then the problem might come down to one of sort sorting through different
features and deciding which ones are relevant for particular problem that we're trying to solve
and here is where the idea of semi supervised learning meets up with another popular
theme in machine learning these days also sometimes called transfer learning or learning to learn
we want to think about how by learning some concepts maybe from a few labeled
examples you might not only learn how to generalize those concepts but also something more
abstract about what kinds of features matter for other concepts like those in the same
domain does get some kind of transfer essentially learning inductive bias that you need to
solve these kinds of problems from learning from just a few examples based on other
so higher level learning of other concepts for from a few examples
so let me get concrete by giving a phenomenon from developmental psychology which motivated some
of the work on the talk about here and just because there is one of
the most interesting human learning phenomena that i know that it's interesting because it's not
all that complicated shouldn't be all that counterintuitive but it has a couple of really
surprising features and it's it's really nicely into a hierarchical bayes sort of framework which
are which will be using to treat
so here the this is it the phenomenon about how children learn the meanings of
words like we're talking about and it's it's called the shape bias
so here's the demonstration of the shape bias you can do this with any two-year-old
these any two-year-old has grown up speaking english this verizon an interesting ways across languages
and that's actually related to to the evidence that this might be something that's that's
a learned a constraint on inductive inference
so here's something you can do with the two children speak english you can show
them these funny objects again they've never seen before you can say this this one
is the tax and ask which of these
is it that show me the next
and what one of the objects in this one matches the
the dax in shape another one
this one here matches in material is something this one doesn't pointers little regular this
this one here doesn't match any
future but the key challenge is to say
well should generalize this new work based on shape or based on material
and two-year-olds speaking english habit have preference to generalize based on shape so i mean
this is just a simple kind of feature selection problem here is really you can
think of it as two features shape material and maybe even both cheaper material are
really sets of a lot of features and this is that you thinking it is
this feature selection that's kind of a more abstract level but somehow children come in
by this page two
knowing that a certain set of features those about shape are are the ones that
are preferentially going to guide the the learning of new words
and this is the powerful green one thank you
so that enables the one-shot generalization in this very simple task now an interesting thing
about the shape bias is that it's some
it's not
president if in slightly younger kids so
twenty month olds
it's not that they are insensitive to object shape and it's indeed if you look
at younger children even infants say free
twelve month old infants they
in some sense expect categories to be organised more about shape and they preferentially attend
to the shape of an object in
nonlinguistic task these are kids who who haven't even learned any words yet but they're
just sort of
and watching objects move around and expect they think of shape as as the natural
way projects to group but
when it comes actually learning this particular kind of categories words project
objects here they don't have a preference to just completely chance here going with say
she matcher material match
now it's possible all sorts of could be all sorts of explanations for that maybe
you know your brains just have to make sure there's a lot of aspects of
of the brain that are not necessarily something we think of as learning just what
what kind of scientists will call maturation
certain parts of the brain just get more neurons and maybe as a result you
you can remember more for example or process more complex sentences or something as you
get older
but there's a really nice evidence this is the kind of learning that was obtained
by linda smith and colleagues linda smith along with marble and others for studied this
predictions conditioned on the data
so we know how many ice-creams were reconstructing the weather from that the original model
was inconsistent with the data
by feeding the results of the model back into get new model were getting something
which is more consistent still not perfectly consistent and you can imagine
you can sell thinking about what we're going to do about that
but first i want to show you how we got these how we got these
actually before we do that let's just look at the differences between those who are
no we probably don't enter to do
OK so
let's look at the computation here of how we figured out
how we got those new numbers so he said
OK on day three
we were we had one percent chance of it being called a ninety nine percent
chance of being hot now we know that the three i screamed
we know that
we believe
that we have
before i do this and give intuitions
so over when we did this re estimation
over here
day twenty seven is being carried is like fifty percent likely to be hot fifty
percent likely to be called
so i said before
we were counting you were interested in the fraction of two ice cream days of
hot days and cold is according to this graph that were to icelanders do you
think we can twenty seven as a
as a hot or cold
when we're computing
these numbers over here
it was added to ice cream hot there are two extreme called a
what would be the right thing to do
you throw it out the be throwing everything out because none of these are like
really hot or cold
right so we say that cannot happen beach
so if you're trying to do this like figuring out how many pizzas you're going
to get party so if you are i invite ten people to party
if some of them are spp rsvps in three hours you no
the new order pizzas for seven people
but if all the forest i have a seventy percent chance of coming or something
like that then you still are seven pieces
right so we're just guessing you know whether is likely to be hard likely to
be called so let's this is
well i started showing you the spreadsheet over let's go today twenty seven which were
just talking about here we have fifty one percent chance of it being called the
few one percent chance of being high
now we know
that's the two i day
look at the headers up here this is the chance of a cold one ice
cream called two ice recalled three ice-cream day it's definitely two ice cream day has
a fifty one percent chance of being cold to iceland
and looking at these hot columns here
it has a forty nine percent chance of being a heart two ice day and
we know it's definitely not a one or three hours from day because we saw
the diary
OK so now we go down to the bottom i total these up
and you can see that we had a total of about ten called one ice
cream days three called to ice cream days and one half called three i screamed
and we just so that allows us to figure out
right and so we have a total of about fourteen point seven called this period
OK so
this point nine six one happen to go into the
called point nine six one went into the two ice cream color so in general
all of this point all this fourteen point seven cold days they all got divided
up between the one two and three ice cream called
so now we know what fraction
of one two and three ice cream
days are called
just by doing that computation
this is easy to calculate we see about sixty percent of the
fourteen point seven called days or one i screamed is about twenty one percent or
two ice cream and ten percent three
so that's how we got these numbers
notice that we also re estimated these probabilities
let's go back to this graph
so what do you think from this graph
do you think that
i don't know what you get by by looking at this reconstruction graph do you
think the holiday is likely to follow another heart
looks like it probably is
because we have a lot of things which seem almost sort of the heart disease
which are in sequence
and they seem to be less likely to follow called
nevertheless are going to maintain that this graph is not enough
to re estimate is
transition probabilities like by graham probability
are asking whether two parts of speech two whether days are likely to succeed each
other how cold cold hot and cold cold
so the claim
that we can we can not from this picture
figure out
whether hot days were likely to be followed by heart is let me prove it
to you
so suppose we make the distribution of ice cream the same and hot and cold
so at this point what we have
it's kind of an interesting experiment
what's going on here
so this is saying called a
i usually three i strings hot day also usually three ice-creams
what happened to our weather predictions
what's the diary telling us
anything about the weather
nothing about whether the weather is totally uncorrelated with the number of creams according to
these assumptions
according to this model
when we if we reconstructed these days if we look at all the patterns
the high probability pads under this model
the the high probability has tend to have hot days followed by hot days are
hot days followed by cold
what do you think
so this is you know with those changes to the ice cream probabilities
what we come up with the a curve that is somewhat similar to that
so wrong if you put on the first
half kilogram
the always start to oscillate a little bit
and so we have to be a little patient
and in the beginning
you may be bored because
we're going to do
part of the curve
so it goes very slowly very gradually
we have
five centimetres
for the first half kilogram could you remove the half kilogram
it returns practically two zero
maybe it's a little higher but that
it's not very significant which make it one kilogram
the high
i are
o it's about nine centimetres
nine ten three using it in the linear part
nine to ten centimetres
you removed the
of kilogram wrong
one kilogram was one kilogram of
you have to just wait let them powder little oscillating
it's possible that you're ready to see
a small deformations
maybe one one and a half centimetres would question the question mark are possible
OK but what i have kilograms of
yeah i think it is
what we will question why
so now we are at
one and a half
so it is strictly linear you would expect something like fifteen
that's what of this fifty so it's still doing quite well can you take them
one of the half
but you see no longer
want to return
its original length is clearly long enough information has already occurred
so we now something like six centimeters
you make it two kilograms
two kilogrammes
it is linear
you would expect twenty
it's still amazing linear
it's as close as i can see it twenty but all these readings and lectures
no more accurate than half a centimeter or so
OK you removed two kilograms
all or look at that this community formation
no longer returns
zero and it is
o confidently ten centimetres long
OK you make it two and a half
now slowly approaching the part i hope you're going to see
that it is going to take off like a rocket
it was a little bit of extra weight
it will start
remove substantially we haven't reached that point
we're close to it
well now
twenty six twenty five twenty six
it looks quite linear
you take it off wrong
actually no need to take it off any more
because it's clear that we
that we have prominent information no sense in following that so what don't make three
so what was what i said it was
was the numbers
twenty one
twenty five or so
so we have three now
is why it was hanging in there i must tell you
thirty two
you make it four
watch very closely and on the wall
because the drama is about to start now
what did i say thirty
so thirty two
still moving
fifty two
that at fifty three
now don't get
the what now look at this spot now you have remember number right
fifty three
you eat one kilogram not
look at that
became almost twice as long it is still moving
still going
o people will settle right on my fifty three
five kilograms
with five right
ninety seven output on six ninety seven ninety nine
i know what's the point
now you clearly the plastic flow of course
and in one kilogram of what the point is still moving was five ninety seven
so we're not six kilograms
o actually that is still easy for me to estimate i would say
it's about
double the length of that
i think that we have on the wall the stick is meters long
moving at more than a little bit more than four metres
close enough for me to support the idea
four minnesota four hundred
we don't have
go through the ceiling now
we lose it
what i want to do now
i want to get to the breaking point
we can no longer measure place
but we are very close to the breaking point
so we're going to load up to the point that will break
that allows us to measure the
ultimate tensile strength
we at seven hours
you put it on
we're running out of
you could see it said it was put on that you actually look at the
OK so it eight kilogrammes
the rate
OK let's of forty seven
numbers in here
so we have a one and a half half a kilogram
distinct three vectors in that set
of restrictions of functions in f two
OK we can get your minus
we can get the first point plus and the next to the other two minus
by function that
does this
missing picture that does this
it just goes down from plus one to minus one just between x one and
x two is a function that goes down between x two and x three and
we get all ones we can do
you know and so on and minuses
minus is to the left of x three in the next resupply so there one
two three four five six of these
three vectors
because the full the full set of all possible labellings we could get is of
size two to three is a
so if the cardinality of the
the cardinality of restrictions of functions in class x
two two sequence x of length n is equal to the m
then f is as powerful as it can be for that sequence of elements of
x it computes all possible dichotomies of x one through x
OK so
when we're thinking about the growth function
you know in fact in this case this is the
you we you can come up with another sequence x one
x two x three that gives a better a bigger table and this the gives
more rows than this
right a there are either distinctly not interesting to get more taxonomies so the the
growth function
is exhibited by any three distinct points and it's it's equal to six at omega
three in this case
OK so just to remind you the growth function for a class f
for a particular value of m is the maximum cardinality restrictions of after that x
is the number of rows in the table in the previous slide when we when
we choose the sequence x that maximizes the number of rows in a table
OK so
a couple of obvious things
that if we're going to find a class
the functions f then the growth function is no bigger than the cardinality of the
right we can have
restrictions on the
a number of restrictions exceeding the number of functions and clearly as n goes to
right the growth function
must approach the cardinality of the class
OK this is really a distinct functions then we have to be able to see
that on on these
these sequences
if f is finite
and it's obviously always smaller into the in the disordered earlier
right to the the is the
total number of dichotomies of n points that we can achieve
so linear threshold functions on the growth function
n is equal to two n
OK why is that we arrange our suppose we have
in points if they're not distinct and then we're not
getting as many dichotomies because in addition to the distinct that gives the maximum
number of dichotomies
we can place after we can get the all class one c or minus ones
and then we can place the threshold points between all of them
all of these points so that's two plus and minus one plus and minus one
is two n
more generally for linear threshold functions on rd
OK which is it doesn't have this nice or property
so he was thinking about functions that map from x two
i guess from threshold here
so it's a little different from this case maps from x to the sign of
the inner product between x and
and the parameter vector w and d
the number of farms
these dichotomies looks like well you know it's a it's a binomial some here so
something like that and the tendency of the the biggest order term is like into
the power d right it's n choose k
OK range in my twenties KEK ranges from zero to d is something that grows
polynomially with m
in the exponent that polynomial polynomials d
the VC dimension of that nature of interest dimension
it is defined as follows
so it
if the cardinality of the restrictions of f two some sequence
of length m is equal to two the m
then we say that f shatters that that sequence of that set
as i've written here
OK so shatters means we get all
all possible dichotomies of the of the set the VC dimension is the size
one of the largest set that shattered by
kalman filtering and going to begin although i been made much of saying we're observing
curves and when you look at an observation post because it should be thought of
as the point it's just an observation of the tangent of the curve nonetheless the
discussion i'm going to revert for a little bit to tracking with
o point observations
and i mean this is not without its its applications so for example the
california department of transportation sponsors research into automatic detection of traffic density on highways and
so on and cars are happily
quite close to
polyhedral especially in the elderly
this beautiful ones and so we might well be able to pick out enough points
on them actually tracked points a point-to-point tracking is useful
it even more artificial situations people want in the computer graphics industry who want to
track facial movements in love to be able to use computer vision so you could
just walk in there
and make faces and and have all this picked up for posterity
but just to be sure the very conservative guys
they take the time to take the director and put a little
sort of
starts all over their faces make look like punks and then track the movie
and here's the department of california tracking the density of cars going down the highway
over the whole day and use this is an actually the speed of so the
average speed is up here at sixty miles an hour and then drops to catastrophic
five miles an hour
one would suspect these must be the morning and evening rush hours and some some
other things you can do with this
of course such systems got work by day and by night which is a bit
of a challenge and ask so you can have
switch to flick i suppose and r by day the corners on the vehicles are
quite visible by night
you know the headlamps the most visible things also the cars not prepared especially in
traffic jams are most interested to separate themselves from one another just for the convenience
of your metrology
system so you know you can't deal with overlapping features in computer vision sorry they're
going to drop tubes in the rotor magnetic strips or something and computer vision will
be trash but you know be great to have a computer vision system solution because
then you could put the camera on the pole you would have to dig up
the road and i mean you saw the density of traffic even getting on the
road to dig it up
is going to be seriously difficult
so be nice to be able to put your solution on a on a traffic
enough of that
here here is that this is a nice plot of the distance moved by
cars in traffic jam monitored by one of these
systems and you see
at some point this shock wave travelling through the system where you know jam built
up and propagate backwards down this line of cars
it's quite pretty picture
OK so now
what about the back to the business of filtering of fusing information
so actually
well i can do is considered
rather as i did with the curve fitting problem i can consider the business of
dealing with successive point observations sequentially so i can imagine some process that sort of
runs around the car picking up all of the corners of the visible their positions
together with some
variability in position and so and that it adds the new piece of information into
the current opinion of where
the car is and in fact
will be that will generalize nicely across time because although happens
when you have at time step is that you now start with a new piece
of data and you just traversed the curve the curve just reverse the outline of
the car again the same car and
again taking the positions of these points so serially into your fusion machine and update
your opinion on whether car is so
in order to make this work
consider a simple state space where the car is simply translating so in place of
capital will have little x which is just going to be translation in the plane
but we will now have a statistical distribution
gas distribution representing your state of knowledge about where the car is a particular instance
so let's say we believe that its position x bar is the mean of the
and the covariance matrix for this galaxy distribution is p not
and let's say that you just let's take one measurement you taking one measurement of
the corner which is also in two dimensions
let's say that the center that made this measurement
does it's best not to live an unbiased sense so its mean position is the
true position of the car but also there's covariance
associated with uncertainty in that
so in that sense
in this case the feature detector in the camera
and so it turns out that the rule for
absorbing this information assimilating it into your current state of knowledge about where the car
is is quite straightforward and intuitive we already had this idea
from the
recursive least squares fit for curves of
the inverse variance being a measure of information
and so what happens is that the
information for the
new distribution that were about to construct
which is the normal distribution with mean x invariant covariance p
it is constructed by adding information so we take the the inverse of this variance
and that's going to be the new information and the new information is the sum
of the information that we had originally that's the inverse appear nought plus the information
in the new
you know
this is sort of a rule of thumb you might ask
you know i began by saying we have distributions in what we're doing is fusing
information using gas distributions so it gives me the right to some
information like this and this apparently rule of thumb manner but it turns out that
OK so
i'm going to talk about bayesian nonparametrics obviously
and the title of my talk is why bayesian nonparametrics
which i think
so of closely related to the the vision of this workshop
just to figure out
you know why people were doing it are doing it and it doesn't really make
sense what a
advantages and shortcomings
so this is obviously a personal view in machine learning researchers you know i'm becoming
more and more statistician but i'm not card-carrying statistician and different people have different motivations
for doing this nonparametric
in preparing the slides i was born
try to think at some point i was very excited about doing business on her
and so there are some very positive feelings in here about it and then the
other points so was
was sort of trying to figure out all the downsides and so there's ups and
downs including this talk is you
so i bring the question up into two questions
why be bayesian
and why do nonparametrics
i think the answer is sort of family
we like to be bayesian because it's a very simple framework so simplicity goes
in our favor as compared to other frameworks for doing
learning and inference
on the other hand we want to nonparametrics
because of complexity because
the real world is actually complicated in the data
that we're trying to model
come from complicated phenomenon
so let me first focus on the first part
why bayesian and i apologize to people who
you know
he didn't sleep
this stuff
well it's so damn simple and the framework in machine learning can you write down
with two rules OK even i can remember these rules
you know everything falls through
from two simple rules of probability the sum rule in the product rule
and you know
if you
forget everything else you could try to derive what you're doing from the sum rule
in the product rule
you know there's no rule that says
you have to come back to buy something and optimise it and then you know
the regularizer and dance around the table three times and then try again with the
cross validation you just write down to model
you apply some rule in the product rule is best you can do this the
footnote there
talk about the fact that we are part of the talk
what i'm really
you know fundamentalist bayesian nonparametric chen and you know
this is a beautiful
all right so we can use some of product
i wrote the sum in concerning computer scientists like myself former computer scientist of
in the audience because decided to get integrals but just look at intervals and turn
them into songs
there some
the math behind that you know all that
so we can apply to reliable sorts of interesting things
for example
two doing
inference about the parameters theta
given some data the
there are some model and some rule product rule we get bayes rule coming out
we can give these things names like likelihood prior and posterior
and then we know somebody says always the user that posted our predictions
i mean engineer there were predictions
OK well
predictions come from some rule
prior product rule
there's no other way of doing it
OK no arbitrariness
so it's very sensible you will be queen you say yes
makes sense
each of parameters make some predictions predictions of probability distribution you don't know which is
the right parameter you can do anything crazy like pick one of them
you know average
because you don't know
you know that another fundamental thing it's not just two equations in mathematics
there's something fundamental about bayesians is
we don't know where uncertain all the time
the that's why a few of us were wandering around granada
for half an hour trying to figure restaurant because
we just didn't know you know what was the best thing to do
we don't have sampling from them but you know i don't do with this equation
tells you is you take your predictions you have with respect your parameters and you
have written them with the weights given by
you know you are familiar some product rule a from
the data we observed in the model and the assumptions you put in
OK so that's one fundamental thing
you always uncertain
the only language for dealing with uncertainty is probability theory as far as i'm concerned
it's a bit like you know
the language for
dealing with the rate of change is calculus
i don't think there are people now arguing i got a better framework and calculus
for rate of change is something like that you know that that issue has been
settled for
a couple hundred years
the probability is language for dealing with uncertainty
so we express all forms of uncertainty
in terms of probabilities and models are all about uncertainty
the only thing was certain values data
so everything else we have to treat is uncertain quantities of probability distributions over the
which represent our
state of uncertainty before
and after observing the data
OK and then we can do other the nice things like model comparisons you
and a is the set
and we just
we just integrate over the set a so here we are integrating the constant one
that gives us the number
and we simply regard this as a function that maps set to number
and that's it
and we can we can do that we can be a bit more sophisticated
and put in
something here some function here
and the only requirement that we make is that function never becomes negative
so we're not interested in cases where we can we can integrate over region and
get number and then we integrate over a larger region and the number decreases
not looking in that case
in table and if we make this region larger the integral always increases and on
strict sense
and the interpretation here is that
that year of a is is
kind of mass of a so in the geometric cases could be volume
or it could be the physical mass of the body and that is actually this
is actually the context where the word density comes from density functions if you have
if you have a physical object
and you know it's you know it's density is mass density
so massive volumes if you want to get
the mass you know the volume you multiply density but if the if the density
is evenly distributed throughout the object then you have to integrate the density over the
volume of the object to get the
and in the case of probabilities
the idea is that this is the probability mass of of a random event what
we call random event and this event is some random variable takes its value in
it's very
primitive picture
but it's still have to keep in mind
she so we have some
some overall set
of values that we
some overall space that i will always call omega
this is our sample space of random variable taking values in the sample space
and then we have some thirty years called a
and the question is how how large is the probability that if we make a
random graph on a random variable and in this in this sense
now if we if we think of this function here as in this way so
far it's only an arbitrary function that maps et cetera number
that's that's that's what we call a set function is a function that maps sets
the number
and but but if we know that if we want to to stick to this
intuition of this
this function representing an integral
then it must have some additional properties so we can look at the properties of
and the rise properties of that function from
and integral has certain decomposition properties so
first of all this one is not actually decomposition property but we always know
no matter what function we put underneath integral here if we integrate with the empty
set and we always get zero
so a measure of the empty set no matter how we what else we do
to define this measure the measure the entities that must always busy
the second thing is that if we if we integrate over disjoint sets so i
think we integrate over one interval and or another into
then the the integral over the union is just the sum of the two integrals
the integrals are additive or disjoint sets
then we can demand that our or we have to be mounted on men should
also have this property so if we have two disjoint sets and we take the
union then
measure of union is some of measures that only works if these are two are
disjoint because if
if they overlap recounting things double
OK but we can do this not only with two sets we can do that
with three sets forces and so on
and because in
in calculus we are able to compute
infinite sums
countably infinite sums this actually works was a countably infinite union
countably infinite sum is something that can be well well-defined converge to converge to a
OK and finally if we if we have a subset
set in the subset
and then
because we say that that we don't put in negative functions here we know that
the integral always increases when we when we go from the set to a larger
so if b is a subset of a then the integral of of the or
the the measure of b must be smaller than the measure of a
and the second thing about subsets is
if we
if we take the set minus yes so if we if we cut out to
be set b from set a then the integral will be will be the difference
of the two
it's all things that we know about integrals without
any further making any further assumptions
and the the historic approach of back
who originally introduced the introduced measures in integration theory
was that he that he try to extract from this way that the integral used
to be five defined
until then in the way that the integral used to be defined the nineteenth century
the riemann integral was that you that you have the technical definition of an algorithmic
definition that tells you how to compute the integral of given function
he completely
completely changed the idea in the way that he said OK i'm going to start
from those integrals that we have defined already
i know my name is and they and the phd students today i will present
my work that is about moment approach for structured output prediction
and i would like to thank the person that i've been involved with the project
they and we still have to be an edit distance
from university of bristol and we developed this project while i was at university of
bristol as visiting student
and so i will briefly
the following outline of this talk
i will briefly introduce what is learning in structured output spaces how we do it
quite quickly because of the car did whole this morning and i will introduce our
approach for learning inspectorate output space that are based on the new objective function the
how we present some experimental results and discuss some computational issues related to our approach
and i will conclude with some ideas for four works
OK so
is a lot of problems that involve structured data which can be represented by sequences
trees or in general by graphs
sequences trees and graphs substantially more than temporarily specialist structural dependencies between objects in the
and this phenomenon writing in several fields such as computer vision computational biology and natural
language processing or web data analysis
machine learning and data mining algorithms must be able to treat and to cope with
this problem
and to analyse efficiently and automatically disallowed amount of complex and structured data
and that's why i recently a lot of effort has been poured so developed structure
learning algorithm
that can predict complex structures such as sequences trees or graphs
and using traditional algorithms to cope with problems involving structured that is suboptimal choice because
sometimes we know often we lost the
information about the structure of the problem and this concept was explained by task this
morning i will explain again quickly but with the other case studies
first of all i will briefly review what is the the traditional framework initial framework
for supervised learning is that we have that and that are available in form of
examples and their associated correct concept so we have a simple talk page where the
input is about y
he is usually is
colour and we want to find similar ipods and sage taken from inoperative ipod in
we wanted to do if the hypothesis performs well on a new test sample
drawn from the same distribution of the training set
and to do that usually we propose that the hypothesis performs well on the training
i think about supervised learning task is classification
and in classification one should have assigned to object to one of the number of
oh sorry
it's a bit
i mean i will show you an example of classification in the case of named
entity recognition
named entity recognition is the task of looking at the name entity the text and
entity of interest can be personal names organisation names location names or indication of times
or dates with them so
this problem can be more than in the traditional framework by a multiclass classification problem
so all four of for example yet we have the spanish war
and for each one of the in the sentence this story is spanish sentence for
each word in the sentence we should assign a label
and we know how to do that we usually consider so we got the information
about the world the in the feature vector a x that represent the input we
want to assign level two
each one of them so
we do it apparently so for the first order we should assign
the class their label all that indicates that p is an organisation
the same for the second one the same for the third and as well for
all the words in the sentence but one can easily argue that this is suboptimal
task because we should be able to consider the correlation between adjacent words
after that we should do we go we realize a joint labeling for all the
words in the center
but we
exactly what
eighteen months
what you see here
we were all
we are working on this from
i assume that work
now here we are
one of the kind of
all right
are or
if you are going
the second or you are in
all right
many of
or if they it would be
one of the
the problem
on the whole
all of
i b
now we need to decide what i measure replacements
and when we measure it so we can measure it here and here and here and
and add up all these distances between
these two
so yes
and when it have way of measuring distances between the two differences some sort
and we need have a decision about what's the density
points that which we measure the difference
we could
so i only care about the city in this region
so might say what
efficient idea
what do you hear
so this
there's an issue of
how do we measure
and you come up with a whole advances are not saying it is impossible there
is the the number of ways of measuring how close to see
each other
an idea that has a problem because it now means there an infinite number of ways
that's the question is how do we fit lambda
the state what we think lenders
okay so you do things that yes
but we get rid a bit weird but it still leaves some interesting questions left over yes
really aren't okay so idea number six
how do we find the mean of the gas in distribution well we just take
all the data points then we summarize the right plan
and then gives us a number we call the data
and then we can use them to construct an estimator and for galcians
new hat
equals x by actually turned out to be a really sensible idea
so that's something we can do with no bins that all we can take all these data points
we can take some
because the windows got the left-hand side remember the left hand side window
is at eight
so you can't have any points left and i made it be sensible to subtract of eh
so q
not essential
that's interesting thing that's the mean
all the distances from the left hand side window
and that's clearly has
and expected dependence on land big about value lambda has more points all
search to the right hand side and eventually they don't have the right to go to the middle average
this window if you have a really large value lambda
then you get a uniform distribution
this is precisely related to lambda
but in the case get goes to infinity
if the window is infinitely wide on the right hand side
something you might remember about exponential distributions
i mean this guy
he effects given lambda
this is the minus on lambda now
we know in
my by z
i mean this distribution
is lambda
expected value
so i think that's a really good idea
maybe there's something in the idea of computing the mean
absolutely we can
so you're now saying let's have a measure of discrepancy between the data mining
the predicted me
let's imagine doing at it is not a very difficult calculation to do
so i will just sketch in which
and we keep asking questions as well
the expected value x
for the real distribution is integral from there to be
it might affect lambda
divided by z
and you can solve at and it's they function of avian so this is some sort of
basically new all
this is
this is be
this is lambda what new actually looks like this is roughly linear
if you want to look start
and then click for the latest nightly built
and that should watch
the other thing is that i want to do this
so the people who are starting to keep on going people who want to download
it go to swim downwards
like their systems and in this case
you probably want one of the nightly builds
this will be already mapped maccabi but
so go into the folder that's that's
when you when you've unzipped up to
and there's a couple of
brown's first
one of them is what it's like seems
if you're going to be going along the
very much all of them
so these on some capital
but it did not have to work
the model
so it so it's very convenient something
this is just a memory
and o
there's a lot of
most people mostly
very slow
so also
so far there
you can just
the are fine
on the web
and then to load
an ontology learning
all of this is
one of the
these these things so i have this too
an ontology and the web you can do to my these slides are public so
it might be that if you if you went there
to copy and paste your rules
we're going to be
one of the
and before
now that we are going to change your redirect or something useful
so i'm going to think what need to use color other ontologies
it's a
don't want to switch to everybody so diligently typing
you can also just google for claude that should come up
is god
living be
to replace the OK
and let me
so we can have the ability to
since all of the word
so you can
you can probably find an ontology and the work
you're all just pop it and you can look at the bookmarks my bookmarks would
be a little bit different than yours but it's easy enough to
click on move on
they also get a humiliated
you know
so we did
the system and see the UK
of the
so far
running the
nine of the one so you have to look at it to make it work
will be looking for
and what is not discrimination
it is
if you look at the patterns given the parameters you need template them
i do i
told the passes
in this
one to two million
what are only the issues feel free
and this is something that's a good thing to do
you should spend some time doing it just loading arbitrary
we are getting is the
comparison between two values in association
of one value
with the object so
trying to get through this quickly and
the sometimes it's nine OK
let's let's move on
because i want to get to one other thing
and yet this is in progress and we want to do more with
interpretations for comparisons and
OK so another example
it was a derivational morphology
it is
these nouns like assassination which are
which pretty
are the verbal so
suffixes produced nouns from verbs
they appear
is like fascination of senior
there are times
the idea is
like verbs they have associated roles
the victim and perpetrator and so the
question is how do you
link the noun phrase
to the appropriate role
and this is actually a big topic in linguistics ever since chance wrote remarks
on nominalisation
the state of the art in terms of
the description of the phenomenon as far as i know
given in this book by jane grimshaw who argued that there are some
some nouns that have argument structure like verbs and nouns that don't so in general
nouns do appear to be somewhat like verbs that they can take the same
the enemy destroyed the city and that corresponds to the enemy's destruction of the city
or the destruction of the city by the enemy
so the
the enemy is the agent just to
the agent and the
transitive sentence
and you can have CP complements for both nouns and verbs infinitival complements locative PP
complement but the difference between verbs and nouns but
whereas for us
obligatory arguments seems like
the of phrase is optional pronounce
so you can see the doctor's examination was successful but or
the doctor's examination of the patients was successful but
you can see the doctor examined you have to have the object
but argues that if you disambiguate between process readings
it turns out that some nouns really do have
are structure like verbs and
have obligatory arguments
on the result
the name means like the exam that was given to the students john's examination was
there is an asian person john
is the author of the examination
process really
john's examination of the patients took a long time john is the one
during the examination to
but the difference
is the agent and examining that
has the phrase disambiguates between result in the process
and maybe i shouldn't talk about this for too long but
yes of always good to push so
comm shows
conclusion is that like verbs certain nouns do have obligatory arguments that there's
structure in there
his her turn from process nominals
are the ones that have obligatory arguments
four process nominals the of phrase is obligatory
linked to this to whatever the object would be of the verb
and then the question becomes which nouns have process readings and therefore had this argument
structure associated with them
it's not the case that any noun that has a corresponding verb
has process reading so
you can say to another child
mother child doesn't mean
the mothering of a child an event
mother and child
so zero right now
process readings
and it seems to be pretty much the only morphologically complex nouns like examination assignment
have this process readings
although i was
the we
the plane here
elders in marjah the former taliban stronghold seized this month in a NATO offensive
he president he was a piece of their minds this week during his first visit
to the town
and sharing
the leaders complained of excessive use of force by u s troops here
we have
which is not what it lacks
along the of phrase and the by phrase
and according to show that should be used is the process normal so i get
maybe users
isolated examples of
morphologically simple process normal but
i think that by looking
such as the new york times we would
come to a better understanding of what's actually going
process nominals
but anyway that exceptional site
have this rule here
the semantic interpretation for
so here
so called because most of them also show
right thanks colin for the clutch great to be here by the way
the first team to economy b six years ago my first trip to sub-saharan africa
and i liked it so much i end up coming back to live in UK
and on the other side so i've been mcgarry for about three years now
and one thing i found is there are abundant opportunities for machine learning
and that's something i have to tell you a bit about
current standards
so by the way if you're
puzzled curious scared stick your hand up and
sort and
OK so the
the thing we want to deal with here is is
machines being able to deal with very high level task
where you
have something specified in very abstract terms or something very high level then we need
to be able to deal with uncertainty
so this uncertainty might come from different slightly different types of uncertainty
you might have a problem which is defined incompletely
so we have examples of some of the types of input output we might want
so this is this is the face of
was a
find me another collection from the set of photographs which have face and but we
only have a few examples the problem is not completely specified the input space is
very large and we've got to try to work out what to do for unseen
OK we may also have uncertainty when the problem is just too big so think
of the traveling salesman person if we have a hundred cities that we need to
run between and find the shortest the shortest tour covering all cities the number of
is it's not only larger than the number of atoms in the universe of just
notices the squared to the number of atoms in the universe square that number and
you get the a number of ways ordering hundred city so this
obviously no possible way that any machine can work that out
exactly so we
to employ some approximation uncertainty in in the situation
we may also be trying to tackle the problem which is unheard inherently uncertain so
if we look at whether it's a chaotic system
never going to have enough information to be able to find an exact predictions
so i guess the
the angle what if you're coming to this from is being used to writing software
where the some inputs some outputs it's pretty well specified
what do we get this inverts we follow some logic and there's is that there
is the
action we take
but here that's
not really going to be enough we have this uncertainty to deal with and the
solution is we have various techniques to show
our machine examples of what we want to achieve and have it learn what to
so we look at how to
how to get that working for a few a few problems
it's going to be a fairly practical session
i think lines for how to are kind of cookbook various recipes to to get
things working
it's going to be
broad rather than deep we
we're going to want to cover
you know if few concepts and in order to do that within the time we
have will not be able to go very far into the into each particular technique
but at least hopefully you will get a flavor of how they had they work
but let me show you some
examples of uncertainty in practical applications particularly ones which
you may be interested in tackling here
will think about how to deal with uncertainty in general terms
look at a few more examples of what what kind of machine learning applications we
might be interested in and then after we've seen some applications we've got an idea
of the
problems we might want to solve then we'll
fire into how to go about solving them
all right here's a a blood smear
and i'm sure all of you have had the experience where you start to feel
feverish you have to go down to get get malaria test guy pricks her finger
some on the glass
slide they stain put under a microscope
now when the lab technician is
peering through the microscope this is what he is looking at
and we have
very is broken down red blood cell material
and the dark stains spots are DNA
matters so we have nucleotides
we have this guy here which is present in so this is the this is
the parasite and he was caught in its engagement rings stage was the kind of
ring with full
you click on that
and when you speak to lab technicians about what they are looking for
explain the pattern in those kind of terms i'm looking for
engagement rings are looking for a common
or pair of headphones with these two nuclei in some connecting matter between them
now if you could take these images and
automatically from this image
be able to identify here's where the parasite is that would be an application of
enormous value we can start automate the
the testing process so even more experts are not available to
two look through the microscope we might be able to
make some headway on being able to do that automatically
so let's think about the uncertainty in here
when we have an image that i think about the space the input space of
possible images
high order cliques if if i get around
you call this pcx energy function
now the point about this which is the one of these pcx this is the
semantic function associated with the clique c
it takes as
input the random victim but the important thing is only depends
on the values of those XI which automatically
now in this particular case means your energy functions are the energy functions of two
or energy functions of one variable
because i have clique size two
and all that satisfy
it's fine expect right you have an energy function for those two
and g function for those
so in fact that's going to happen it's weight cop comes down to age weight
since for each other
now slides and not new as i have a slightly later on which says this
just say now
i find it
yes maximizing typically what you want to is maximize the probability of finding most probable
o thing so
that means
since the
if you take the logarithm of the formula
the logarithm of problem xie xie was constant which is log k
log one z rather
and the product becomes some
and the exponential go away because taking the logarithm of so you get the log
the probability that for
log px constant minus
some of these energy functions
and so if you take the maximum probability which is what we want to maximize
the probability of the minimum
of this energy function right so in other words
that's important result here is
any markov random field
you find the maximum probability essentially just an energy minimisation problem
having said that
we really just
for all intents and purposes last is the way we think about markov random fields
energy function
where the sum of energy functions which just one two
very depending on the size of the clique
of y energy
well you could cost like
i mean it's so by analogy with them
you think of things having springs between ages and you try to find out
you're trying to get down to the maximum state it's also it is energy when
you do these things with
in sort thermodynamic situations and things like that which also
represent by markov random field
basically thermodynamic systems will tend to go for negative energy states in fact these costs
represent energy
in that sense
potential certainly not connecticut moving
let's let's look now the case we just got two labels so each each random
variable has two labels
going to find
energy function
i will be
function from b and b is zero and one
the real right generally that for
the exiles the variables
literals these exile the exile barron all right so excited by our
excited by it
one minus six five point being
effect size one
zero zero this is why i
x one minus six i
generally were looking at we're looking at any energy function which is just where we've
only got two labels
is of this form so let's look at
there are various ways to represent things you
functions one is to list all the values for all possibilities all
two to the end
where n is the number of variables
think positive form
positive form which would probably need to do much
is like this constant posteriors linear terms
single very last
double ones plus so on where you i are either
x i
there are other nexi
born excited by
all your constant asia theropod
we'll see that or finally you can always put polynomial for
in in
in the variables so ultimately women i polynomial function
values of x i which is zero one
let's have a look
at that is the example tabla
so i listed x just got three variables here for instance of is the x
one x two three all eight possible values
and then i suppose in distress some value could three
two minus five these values function
here so f zero zero zero equals three zero zero one loss two
now the term that corresponds to
rather right
if x i x one zero x two zero next three is zero
corresponds to the termites one by x by extreme meaning
your variables x one x two and x three to take the values if and
only if
that term
thanks value one
right so
x one
let's take this to the second one x one by x two x three
when can that be one
when have value once either zero or one right because each one
well this is going to be
then x one
must equal zero x one by one
x two nasty one
extreme st one right
it's the
that section four
the point is one of only one of those terms can be one
in a given time for any assignment of values
so once you've got that right now
policy form
for the function
three times once each three times the first time and for any value function
any value of x one x two x three that represents
the fourth column
so that's the tableau and also the
this is not neither positive for more polynomial how to get this policy form
well get was transferred to polynomial
so first order polynomial we just replace each x i
by bar
by one minus six i
multiplied out function like that think it just replacing x one by one minus x
one and you get a point which represents the function
closed form representations are ambiguous
the x one x two but can also be seen to be
this policy for
whereas polynomial representation have been
going forth
okay binary symmetric channel with inputs zero and one and it flips the fraction effort
the bits so we'll talk a lot about the challenges course but we want to
understand coding theory for any noisy channel
andy whenever dealing with noisy channels we need to know how to do inference and
i used to introduce people to inference for the different puzzle instead of three cards
i would show people the three doors
where the game show host says
here's the rules of the game
i'm gonna hide a very desirable prize here eight national rail pass
behind one of these three doors
the game is always explains the rules first before the game happens in the rule
the i will hide the prize behind these doors
then i will ask u the player to choose the door you have a free
choice and new choose it by naming it and we don't open it
then i became co-host guarantee that i will open another the doors not one shows
and i guarantee when i do that's promise me i promise you trust me
that the prize will not be revealed at stage
so then the prize is clearly the behind
i don't want to model to in this
the example shown here the one being when you chosen door to be other door that he didn't open
and then be
player gets a chance to stick or switch
if you want
and then you'll get what's behind the final or you end up at after eva sticking or switching
andy options
for this puzzle then
like this there was the rules being explained now know you go ahead and play the game
the player chooses the one
the host said in accordance with the rules are now open in the door to
model three and will not reveal price and i promise you
opens the door is still three
it doesn't reveal price
and the question is
should you state
city districts
others it made no difference
and i used to use this as my
introductory example in probability theory because people would argue very hotly about and say well
it's even behind aaron don't wanna do
it's fifty fifty
is indeed automated differences fifty fifty
and other people would say oh no you should switch and some people would say should stick
and it used to be contentious but unfortunately most people have heard it is possible
and so it doesn't really work anymore with let's have a quick vote votes for eight
beaches raised
let's say it makes no difference so you see is a useless educational device
it's been ruined because everyone's gonna talk about it
and the really annoying thing is they talked about it in a way such that
no one has actually learnt anything
and due my proof about because a moment ago
you've voted four
a lot of you
not all the proof that this lot
you this
controversy had between me and see
education disaster has happened the three doors puzzle which is a fantastic puzzle is really
educational has been ruined because everyone knows the answer but they don't understand it
maybe see here these are exactly equivalent to each other three cards and three doors
they are the same problem as each other
yet i showed you the same problem and you didn't get a right even though you allegedly
merchant the answer so
learning is about memorizing things it's about understanding
so that's my little rant on the three doors
the message people should be getting from the three does problem is don't memorize the
answer to a stupid puzzle because then you be useless so in future inference problems
instead learn the message that you should use probability theory
and then you will be equipped solve any puzzle of this type in the future
rant over
so what we do now
let's talk about
noisy channels
what we're going to do with noisy channels is there are always can have an input and output
andy channel
defines a set of conditional distributions if you condition on input the channel defines what
the probability of the output is gonna be
the channel doesn't define a joint distribution
it just defines a set of conditional
and we can only ask do inference if you've got a