so from illegal to eleven
this is still the optimal
and now we can reduce uniform
and the course the nice thing about all this is that we're trying to reduce muta zero
because that's how we perturb things and we'd like to get rid of the perturbation
and so we've made some good progress here hand what do we have to do next
well now we see that four is the blocking
inequality because it gives us the force the blocking inequality which is the last one
that corresponds to this role here
the w forty equals minus four but
at mu equals four everything is good
and this
right hand side value is equal to zero and ghost a tiny bit less
this becomes a negative number where everything else is still good
and therefore is just doing eight dual-pivot were identified this as the leaving variable i
look across here for entering variables
and so
let's say i did look for things with a plus sign
here because i don't have the text box with a minus in front of it
so looking for things with a plus sign so i look at both of these
and i didn't do this little racial kinda thing
this is at fourteen going at a rate of three
and so i can go a little bit less than five
this one's at
one minus
forces minus two and if forget the minus sign because negative transpose it to
two minus mu is to in the dual
and new equals
four r
this was to going rate five
so this is going fast rate doesn't have referred go
so this is gonna be easy
entering variable so is exactly the same thing that i've already shoyu
they you identify
you are leaving or entering variable by these new inequalities you identify the other variable
the corresponding one
but these racial kind of calculations that we were doing befor you get a pair
entering and leaving variable and then you just rearranged equations together to a new dictionary
so if we do that here
here it is all this is the same dictionary isn't it
those are the same numbers right
so i have tool that illustrate this
in fact maybe i should do somebody's on the pivot tool
i think it's a little bit of fun
that's it was generate a random problem
so here we have it
and the this is the advanced version of the pivotal
which has that extra column and the extra regio
an extra column here next to the right
can sign extra role here under the objective wrote
this is exactly the same as we had in the two phase
simplex methods i'm just interpreting different now
differently now
i'm interpreting it as this times new
this times new this time et cetera i alright the news here because they use the same tool
for all these different algorithms
so when doing that
this version of the algorithm i think these numbers is multiplying new and i think
the second wrote all these numbers maltby multiplying new
and trying the
do this parametric methods and in fact the tool shows me here what range in new values are optimal
one thousand is my abbreviation for infinity
because just like i didn't know how to make an epsilon
in java i didn't know how to make an infinity symbol here so
i just put thousand anyway e
so there's the initial dictionary it goes down to o
the initial range music goes down to eleven
eleven is obviously generated by this variable here getting blocked
eleven minus mu is possibly less recall are which means mu is critical to eleven
so it's this is becomes my entering variable
i do the usual thing i look forward negative
so you look for positive numbers inside the text fields and the whole thing is negative
so that's a zero this is negative just going down the road to
starting at
ten plus one times eleven
so starting at twenty one going down the road to
starting at some
seventeen going down right three okay that's cannot zero quicker
this one is a negative sign sort of throughout this one
this one's uh twenty three going right five that's the fastest one that's going had
zero first s twenty three causes twelve plus eleven
so this is the one is zero first i do all those ratio calculations in
my head evaluating them at the current value of new
so it's the last
and it's the second column i do that
and it shows me automatically the new range new values that does all those ratios that
you have in there
that this kind of certain operations that is these inequalities to get the range new values
and so now it's determined that u equals three is the smallest one
whereas the u equals three
coming from
the new graphical three it's coming from i believe
this inequality here the number looks three times bigger than the number that's one doesn't look like it
and now it doesn't look like it by the way i only have to look at the purple ones
because all the ones are not purple
i have an inequality that satisfied with mu equals zero
so those are all happy and u equals zero
and so
the ones that are don't have a purple
the language
so we want learning algorithms trying to learn how to use that knowledge
we're not going to give it local rules we wanted to learn those
disambiguating rules
this is
we can in our problem we're going to be able to disambiguate these kind of
where the word in red is the one to be distinctly disambiguated so for example
no here there could be several cartons of milk in the world each with their
own symbol and the ones on the table ones in the fridge
and so on
so we think this problem is challenging
if you try learning from scratch now i could probably
make given my data so i could make a bunch of
a handcrafted rules like features life e to my classifier and you could probably do
well but we want to do here is try to discover this these things from
raw data such that if we had more realistic data set
then this in our algorithm is going to scale to that realistic dates and learn
realistic rules rather than just the fake handcrafted onsite are made for the toy problems
but first we just going to look at what's the simplest thing we could do
to do that and we need to do some kind of structured output prediction
because without putting a sequence of concept tags right for the whole sentence so the
classic way of doing that over the last years is to use this kind of
argmax function so this function g
it takes the input x and the concepts y dash and and the universe knowledge
and it's is good news
producer large score he thinks that well matched and then you're going to take the
maximum possible
concept labeling
we could try and train that
so in
indeed made a little simulations
i just showed you the some examples from before includes some actors and some rooms
in some pieces of furniture and fifteen verbs and simulation that makes these characters around
the world picking up objects and giving to each other
and we
made kind of grammar that generates natural language sentences that paired with those actions in
this way we could generate training data
that is
how sentences the concept labelled
and we tried just training
svm struct without without doing any feature engineering so we just use of words
and we don't do too well
if we add the
the concept relations
as well as by features then we do a little better so using the world
knowledge helped this is just the word per tag right
to say so
using world knowledge helps but can we learn hidden representations and do that
i'm going to try and do that with neural networks
what you
there are no actually it's
is the number of full sentences you got wrong i think number full sentences
so if you get any tag wrong in the sentence that's says that's in there
yeah exactly
you have to get the whole white correct here otherwise it's an error
was so we can begin to make a neural network
so this it's going to take the
the sentence and the world
representation u
and it's going to try and produce school
in in between it's going to try and learn some hidden representations both of the
words and concepts the symbols in the world
OK and then those things are going to be actually some
some low dimensional vectors just like in the previous two parts of this
she tutorial
and the final function is looks like this is going to be a sum of
over sliding windows
so g i is is sliding windows into the word i
and it's going to take all the predictions that you've made so far apart from
the ice one
and produced an dimensional vectors
for the for
for the input and then there's another neuron network on the other side function h
which is going to take the concept you're predicting
plus the world knowledge about it and produce another vector the same dimensional and then
we can take the
dot product that some over windows and that's the function g
just like in the previous slide and we're going to train that thing
and i've got a picture to show it
this is the
the GI function
it takes
the window
around the text
a window around the
concepts that we've so far predicted we're going to predict
the concept labels iteratively shave
in the next slide and it first represents those things is
as vectors and those things are going to be trained those representations
concatenate all those vectors into another linear map to get your final representation for the
whole window do on the other side the same thing
h function is going to be the concept that we're predicting
for this
so this for this center
all right so this is the function g i and then do the same thing
and then there's dot product
so that's
our model
and then to do inference we're going to use less so
kind of less so type model actually where
we do you want free inference so we can assume first all the positions are
unlabelled then we can compute
we're going to try
and compute the score for each possible concept in each possible position
take the largest ones are the most confident in and then repeat until with labeled
everything i'm going to train
our model
in other words the important thing is that this is paying attention to particular position
it's only the sort of the right
so this is one of the three sequences three four five and this four five
but these days don't know whether the position three in the centre position-by-position twenty two
so in the background model
the tribunal is what's called the stationary model which means that the probabilities are the
same and every time
as these numbers the probability of by x fifteen
x thirteen x fourteen is the same as x five x three x four
and what we have to show that
so let's see how we can get there using the kind of manipulation and so
and it's going to change the notation of
so what i don't know
it's exactly the same thing instead of three four five
i'm saying i minus two one minus one and also saying i equals five
this is exactly the same if i is
i minus two which is three are
annex i minus one x fours s
what's the probability that x i x five will be
so i haven't changed anything all these numbers are still the same
the result is still the same but what can i do now that i changed
i can back off
so i can said let's ignore the position
so now this probability model is asking for the probability of
four overall is that if x minus two is our next minus one is as
the next letter would be
and now see how much surprise how much better estimates we can get the probabilities
we now have twelve thousand examples of our best
and before i was a little less than ten percent now it's considerably more than
ten percent of those are being followed by
so this is just back off you know these probabilities could go up or down
some of them probably when some probably went there but the more reliable estimates there
when we say that now i can tell you what i mean when we say
that these estimates have high variance
what it means is that
these estimates are based on the brown corpus now suppose we also had to say
the green caucus
which is the same kind of text and the yellow corpus
all of these are based on just a small amount of data
so that the these ratios will probably very alive
from corpus corpus that's what we mean by high variance it means that were sort
of being enslaved by the particular training data that we got
and if you know another to we trust the training data we may get an
inaccurate estimate the variance decreases and you get more and more training and instead of
three or four hundred eighty five numbers get multiplied by ten to one hundred or
something then as we start to get more data will zero in on the correct
but the brown corpus is big enough for us to really trust these numbers
if on the other hand we back now these numbers are big enough that that
we don't have to be so
OK and notice that our estimate is not very different
it's going up by nearly three orders of magnitude
so now this is
instead of less than one billion into less than one
and that's only because our estimates are no more reliable i believe this answer more
than personal abilities as one
just because these numbers were too small
we can find out by trying some other corporate
for example we could use the web that's really big corpus but how
how likely is it is the story forces
but i would put my money on this one well
now there are better ways to build models you can play some tracks were you
interpolates between this model and
so we're with this model has updated you trust
and really doesn't then you start gradually moved towards this
i don't want to go into that this morning we don't have to be just
OK so i'm going to change the notation a little bit
people often right i mean this kind of the right way to write using variable
equals value other people often abbreviated this again this is a problem with making their
lives convenience
i know it's less clear
this is probability of each given or as in you're supposed to understand from context
that this means the probability that you will follow RS
in order to eliminate the notation at the time
let's use this beginning of sensible so i mentioned in the sentence before the beginning
of so asking whether
now these all look like try probabilities we imagine that we've started out with the
whole road beginning of certain symbols and then what's the probability that the next one
and once we got to the beginning of the sentence the next thing will be
we've now forgot
for the rest is the beginning of sentence so everybody has a little bit of
like context two characters
and the first public characters when they look at the two characters are context left
there are kind of the
in this version of beginning of sense and this is the no man's land before
this starts
trains the notation one more time
this is making the same assumptions about language as these try ground distance
and by putting this together
by multiplying these together we estimate or well
we estimate the true probability of course is we define
this function key
which is of particular as
in this particular function p
is probability
that we're using we hope it's close to the
of course is really trying to model
no it isn't
so this is just an essay
it's just that this is what people use it
there were will be technical reasons as well but i'm not sure precisely what they
are not impolite
OK so
do i not spend ages looking at
autocovariance is and precise procedures the reason is basically i don't trust them very much
of this problem that you could run a check that never seems to new distribution
you could do all of the analysis you want on the time series the places
he visited here
and that analysis can't know that in fact you've messed up the mister that half
the distribution
all over the world
what to do
so the question is why might be that some parameters look as though there was
that they reach their equilibrium distribution marginally according to variance in some parameters with
it can just be that if you measure some property
if your state space it's the same everywhere and other properties are different i mean
i don't i don't know about the precise details of this example but imagine that
we were doing something in this space
now in fact is made to completely equivalent because any pretty if we're in this
mode the predictions we would make exactly the same as everywhere in this model made
so if we were plotting properties to do prediction then it would say
it makes finding that would be true
if that was your application
if you approach plotting properties about
the value of me one it would identify the with the problem if you hold
if you did manage to actually help across the night and so you've got to
not only look at these plots but also question what you care about what you're
trying to do so it's hard
so what do i actually do
i think the the most important thing is just to
do some basic sanity consistency checks that
give you some
reason to think you're likely to get the right answer so i mean the first
thing to do when you can do anything with the probability model is just try
it on the tiniest smaller version of your problems well often you can compute things
exactly by brute force and see whether it actually returns the right answer say
that might not have necessarily so it's going to work when you scale things up
because it will be hard to make but it does
that is not just written about in your head
which none of these convergence analysis are going to tell you might say
hands up who has coded up gradients at some time to put into conjugate gradients
lbfgs or some gradient optimizer to optimize the cost function
OK now keep your hands up if
also check those gradients against when perturbing numerically to see that you've got right
now keep your hands up if when you've done that
they're always right
it's the same with MCMC like most the time you can take it up nontrivial
you're going to get it wrong i do all the time and
it would be insane not to test you just haven't got it wrong and i
think that is often overlooked in the literature because it's nice to get into technical
details of like whether this thing is converging looking taking functions things but
that's one of the most important thing
that's one for future what's another sanity cheque
we just written detailed probabilistic model if it was directed model and it will be
this is how we think how data is generated so just written down what we
think datasets again
so we can do is just draw
fantasy synthetic datasets onto real data and then we know the ground truth about data
we know exactly how they were generated we know what all the names when withdrew
from prior then we can run that inference algorithms
which will make predictions and we can see whether those predictions actually match ground truth
because the federal government and going to work on synthetic data that is not going
to work on real data that probably has
added extra complications and and the internet model
and this an example of this when i visited fermilab just because i have some
friends who to particle physics and
there are explained to me that
they're writing
tens of thousands of lines c plus plus to
trying to help prevent so if you're doing something like nick looking for new particle
you have to
still to all these tons of data and the idea then do statistics and identify
statistically significant evidence that this new particle exists here
when the graduate students go away and write that kate they're not let anywhere near
the real data this is my understanding of it because they're just going to tweak
the code until it seems to work so
they're not allowed
the real data until they can demonstrate that code would work on synthetic you want
to call generated simulations simulated data and that's i think exactly what we should be
doing as well because if you're going to go away and make recommendations based on
the data that you want to be really sure that you actually do anything
this is the more sophisticated version of this idea generation synthetic data infer in this
paper which i given your reference for i love the title of the paper getting
it right and it's one of the points that he has some tests were not
just going has convergence just going to test that you have messed up
and his exceedingly honestly say he says i've got these tests where i'm just going
to show consistency my sampling
and then i pulled out the old fortran code that i ran for these papers
in this that's journals
and he'd also claimed the random seeding the generator so he could rerun the code
and reproduce results in paperback with a new that he was doing the same thing
that claim to do in those papers and many many consistency checks and if and
of course the were right and he made six cadence you fix those we ran
came to different conclusions this is one of the most important thing to get right
does not
messing up and i think used a lot of people came and asked me about
convergence which is important but this is
equally if not more important
OK so a
that's the end of my
all of these robots are going to be done in parallel without any synchronization right
sharing and then inside that there's going to be threads
which run arbitrarily they can synchronize are truly they share data
and the programmer then writes one of those parallel threads
and thinks about having this thread being launched in the context where you know million
other brands that's that's how it works OK so enough talking about
esoteric GPU stuff on on to the actual machine learning problems that we're dealing with
we're looking at SVM training
CSD variant and were training the dual
so as people have have mentioned in the talk previously none of this would be
a surprise you we we have
alpha variables that were optimizing and the number of alpha variables we have is equal
to the number of training points trying to build up a classifier
by learning the alpha variables for each of these training points
we also have labelled data so that we can we can perform this and we
the standard kernel functions in our talk today we're actually going be focusing on the
gaussians kernel function since that's the one that we use them
the main algorithm that we're using for SVM training is the classic sequential minimal optimization
algorithm was invented by plant in nineteen ninety nine almost a decade ago
and that
despite the name
sequential minimal optimization is actually quite apparent
at each iteration what this algorithm does is just
exactly two of the variables and we have all variables were always the number of
training points and because we're addressing only two of the variables at the time the
entire space that we're looking at collapses into
the one dimensional problem we've got two variables in a box and then we've got
a one-dimensional we've got constraint linking that makes the space effectively one-dimensional so the actual
optimisation step is is quite trivial
the other good thing about this algorithm is that computing the full kernel matrix between
all these points is not required and we
basically generated on the fly as as necessary
the computation is dominated by KKT optimality condition update
and this can be done in parallel
i mean talk a little about the variable selection heuristics
so the job of the variable selection heuristic is actually quite important we have to
choose the two variables that we're going to be updating edits that
which is the wrong ones and we're converges very slowly
so the first order
selection heuristic that we use proposed by here b in two thousand one
is basically constructing this as a vector where the length of of the vector ten
is the length of the number of training points
and for for every training point we
we construct this vector iteratively
and at every iteration we're going to be searching among we're going to update this
vector based on the optimisation step that we just taken were then going to search
among this vector
according to these subsets in order to find the maximal violating pair from this factor
and the maximum violin pair is showing which which two points
i have the steepest gradient in in the functional which if we if we needed
to choosing two points is the same thing is choosing interactions with its finding steep
and doing this is required order of complexity for each step
however the first order heuristic can be confused by steep gradients which ultimately lead to
marginal improvements on the objective and
so to overcome this
on at all in in two thousand five for a second order heuristic which selects
the variables according to the actual change in the objective function or trying to avoid
situations like this where the grain is pointing in the direction it's very steep but
ultimately rather shallow we want to choose a direction
potentially that might have a gentler gradient but overall leads to a bigger improvement in
our objective function if we're going to do this in the most general way actually
requires a lot more work because we have to look at all the different pairs
to see which pairs cause most change in the objective function so instead of doing
that we we choose one of the variables in the same way that was done
in the first order heuristic and then the second one is chosen by
checking the change
in the in the
objective function or if we were to choose that as the other part of the
for all and
variables which actually lead to progression towards the constrained optimisation problem
to sketch the implementation
the first order
in every iteration that we use the first order heuristic
basically it has a single mapreduce that where we can we compute the the new
value of the vector for every point and then we reduce over that factor according
to the subset that were defined with the KKT conditions to find the maximal violating
the second order heuristics requires about twice as much work we have two mapreduce that's
where we are the first one is similar we update and then we compute
one is one of the variables by searching over it and then we have to
do another mapreduce that where we
compute the change in the gradient if we were to choose that variable as the
second half of the pair and then finally reduce over that fine
the variable we're going to be using
some other implementation details we use kernel caching as presented by keynes in nineteen ninety
nine we managed to cache on the CPU and keep the rows of the cash
in GPU memory so basically this soak up all the GPU memory news that the
and we also space pay special attention to ensure efficient memory access patterns keeping the
memory access coherence meaning that were accessing large pieces of memory once and making use
of GPU local stores which are basically the the on chip cache
the second order heuristic can be rather expensive like this so it can be about
twice as much work in the geometric mean are tests that about
twice as much work per iteration and so we actually made an adaptive heuristic which
periodically estimates the convergence rate measured by the gap in the optimality gap as a
function of wall clock time and then chooses the one heuristic that's progressing most productively
towards the optimal
and the important thing to note is that this adaptive heuristic performs
close to the best heuristics on our test so there there are certain cases like
for example
on this dataset where the second order heuristic does really well
in terms of runtime you know it's it's reduce runtime by a factor three and
there's other other places where the second order heuristic of increased are run time by
almost a factor of two
whereas the
the adaptive
i extend this spring
i extended over certain
i'm not certain distance in unimportant how much
i know
when i do that
there will be appalled
i put mass and one year
and i measure
that is full courses on these mass immediately after i believe i can measure that
so i measure acceleration a one
now i replaced this object
mass and two
but the extension is the same
so the pool must be the same bring doesn't know
what the masses at the other end right
the same
i put into their different mass
and i
national no acceleration a two
it is now an experimental facts
that one a one
he calls and two a two
and this product
a we call
the force that is our definition
of force
so the same pool
on the ten times larger mass
i would give it ten times
the second law
i'll read to you
the force action
on the body gives it the next generation
which is in the direction of the force that's also important
correlations in the direction of the force
and has a magnitude given by m a
it is the magnitude and the direction
is the direction
of the force
so now we will write this
in all glories
detailed this is the second law
i note and
perhaps the most important
all of physics
certainly in all of
it one
m a
units of this force
times meters
a second squared in honour of of the great man
we call that will not
like the first law the second law
only holds in inertial reference frames
and the first law the second law be proven
i do we believe in it
i do believe in it
because all experiments and all measurements within the uncertainty of the measurements
in agreement
the second floor
now you may object
you may say
this is strange what you've been doing
how can you ever the tournament bass
if there is no for somewhere
because if you want to minimize maybe put it on scale
and we put it on the scale to determine the mass you make use of
the gravitational force so it's not some kind of a circular argument that you use
the answer is no
i can be somewhere in in outer space where there is no gravity
i have to
pieces of cheese they are identical in size these genes without holes by the way
they are identical in size
some of the two
has double the mass of one
mass is determined by how many molecules how many atoms i have i don't need
gravity to have relative scale of mass is so i can determine the relative scale
of these masses without ever
using the force
this is a very legitimate way
checking up on the
second law
since all objects
in this lecture hall
and the earth
four is the
constant acceleration which is g
we can write down
that the gravitational force
would be an
time this acceleration g normally right in a free but i make an exceptional because
i call it
gravitational force and so you see that the gravitational force
to the earth on a particular mass
is linearly proportional risk the math
if the mass becomes ten times larger
then the force
was up by a factor of ten
what i have here
the softball in my hand
the reference frame
twenty six one hundred we will accept to be an inertial reference frame
it's not being accelerated in our reference frame
that means
the force on it must be zero
so here
is that ball
we know it has mass m
which in this case is about half a kilogram
there must be a force here
and g
which is about
five not
half kilogram
but the net force
it is very clear
i will follow it must
push up
with a force
my hand to the ball
which is about
the same which is exactly the same five
newton's is only now is there
no acceleration
so i can write down
walter lewin
the force of gravity
well zero
because it's the one dimensional problem you could say
that the force of doing
equals minus
vehicles have a
that there is no statement made
on velocity or speed
so long as you know f
and as long as you know and
eight is uniquely specified no information is needed on the speed
but that would mean
if we take gravity an object falling down
with five meters per second
that the law would hold
if it would fall down
with five thousand meters per second
it will also hold
will always hold
you speed
approaches the speed of light
newtonian mechanics no longer works
then you have to use einstein's theory of special relativity
so it is only valid as long as we have
speeds that are substantially smaller
say then the
speed of light
now we come
two newton's
if one object
exerts a force on another
the other exerts the same force in opposite directions on the one
i read again if one object exerts a force
on another
the other actors the same force in opposite directions
on the one
and i normally
summarize that
as follows
and the results
i have to admit what i see this still shocked that works well
the results are pretty impressive considering
are relatively small tool kit
to make all this work
so if you measure with the top five accuracy metric used for the imagenet challenge
to get about eighty five percent
but what are sort of qualitatively look at some of these results so here they're getting the right answers to predict
that this is a motor scooter leopard
but the one i think pretty interesting
things like this where are the correct answer was grille
turns out that top
match for neural network is actually convertible
and calling as dalmatians seems pretty understandable
this one i couldn't understand how people here know the word garrick means agaric
i i didn't know how to go look up on wikipedia
and a on wikipedia you see this picture
so i was pretty surprised by stuff like this that words i don't know
this neural network of figure out
using these fairly simple components
how to how to say that this might be a garrick
or mushroom
whatever the difference between those as
so this is pretty neat
system and the basic ideas we've been talking about so far actually enough to make something like this work
so when i say briefly something about other vision applications i wanted to do a little more on
this but
but for the time we've got just say a few words
if you want to do something like segmentation
if you can recast any problem
as a supervised learning problem you've got a bunch of labelled data
you can make progress using all the tools we just talked about
so for something like segmentation
if you think that each pixel is the label
and i need to say for example yes or know if this is
an membrane between two different regions in some tissue
you can think of that as a supervised learning problem to use all the algorithms
that we use so far
and danchi
has done some cool stuff with us
if you want to do segmentation scenes in different types
of surfaces and you have labels
you can think about is the problem i want to predict
the material that a certain pixel
another way of approaching this is to segment your image first using off the shelf computer vision software
and then for every super pixel each sort of a
block region
i'm trying to predict
what is the material that dominates in that super pixel
and using these sort of simple recast of each of these vision problems you can keep using
all the same tools
are of course if you sliding-window you can build detectors
out of supervised classification function
so pierre sermanet as work on worked on things like pedestrian detection some pretty cool results
and some sort of
a novel results from unlikely these group which students
this one from rss this year
so you do some pretty
cool vision related things where the task is not to classify an object or a segment or do some vision task
but fact to figure out where is it located grasp a coffee mug
so you're basically using neural network to rank how good are different grasp points
there's pretty cool videos on the web so as if you guys a chance at
some point to go through that link
afterward the results are pretty impressive
ross take a couple slides to say something about debugging tips because if you get this
far when you go home you go implementing tutorial somewhere
chances are you going to get to point to say you know this deep learning thing doesn't
and so it's true that sooner or later you get trouble and
it's a little bit like computer programming and that no one can tell you how to debug computer
program you just sort of got a
grid and there it goes through it but there are some tips that that make it a little less painful
one is
don't forget to check your gradient numerically
this is a simple thing to do
pick some random parameters
perturb them a little bit
and then just
guess compute gradient from those perturbed parameters numerically
and compare it to the one you computed with backprop
and if they're wildly far off you know something is wrong
so finally
you can verify on small training set the objective function decreases so
because we often have to implement our own optimizers for
the scale of problems the type of problem we're working on
we want to make sure that the optimizers by g
and so if you can just create a sort of small problem make sure the objective function is going
to make sure that your gradient as right
make sure that you didn't forget to use the negative gradient of the positive gradient
which comes up a lot
and sort of related to this
is if you can create a small dataset
where you think it should be possible to get a hundred percent accuracy
should check that you can actually train neural net that gets a hundred percent accuracy
if you can do that
doesn't necessarily mean that something's wrong but it's worth asking why you can't
maybe it's the case
that you have some functional form for neural network that just is able to represent a good
decision function you should think again about
maybe what sorts of non-linear jersey
and finally
again if you can afford it
using optimizer they use a second order information requires a new method
like l-bfgs
these optimizers are now available off the shelf in matlab
all over the place and they're really well to and
you can jettison all your own optimization code temporarily to make sure that your neural network is working
so that you don't have to deal with the optimizer
and finally just some advice from the machine learning world
let's say you've got optimizer working
gradient is right
or you get some minimum and you still get horrible results
then the standard pipeline for debugging these things is actually to look at
the training error in the testing error
so if you look at the training data and you're neural network is making bad predictions
even on the training data
more data can help you
if you're not fitting the data you've already got more data can picture problem
what we lack last access who's from cornell in the army command and pumpkins and
they were all released in the summer and what talk about is how the social
networks one right so they evolve by additions of nodes and deletions of nodes and
edges and for example as we saw in the previous talk right usually how is
how do we study this is a series of light snapshots of of graphs of
for example taken network and they use natural so the point is that very few
of study will usually all sorts of using snapshots nobody has actually seen how individual
nodes nodes and edges in the networks so basically the topic of this talk be
exactly so we will have large online social networks when we know exact node and
edge arrival sequences so these animations showed down here we know exactly when nodes which
edges they created so we know both basically atomic events of network
and there are two two important points all sorts of things that you can do
if you have
so the first one is you can
test series or models of individual and i can see how individual disappear one after
another in the network from the first edge to thirty million OK so for example
you can ask what is causing the AC power law degree distributions because there are
many different mechanisms that you have institutions and the other important point is that you
given the model you can calculate the likelihood of the model meaning you can calculate
what's the probability that under that model i would observe my network so instead of
comparing the quality of the model but we are like summary summary statistics for example
saying oh my model can produce power law degreedistribution actually comparing the probability that model
with generate so this is be sort of the points the points of the the
and to go
so i was setting is this and by network evolution if you think what we
need to specify
completely describe the how the graph was there are processes that first you need to
say how are you know the right so what what i was of new nodes
the second process is then
what we call the edge initiation process where the question is when two nodes wake
up and say oh i want to create an entry the setting would all creates
an edge goes to sleep and wakes up another point and says oh i want
to create another and then
this leads to the process that says
when i wake up and i say i want to create next edge where way
we're going to OK and the data we had with these four online social networks
so flickr delicious answers and the same for all of them we had data for
about three years to two year they are all quite large meaning for my seven
hundred thousand nodes through eight million nodes and the number of edges goes to millions
and for all of them basically we see that we have that they can complete
solution for the first that is fifty million four
OK so basically the plan for the rest of the talk is to describe this
process is show you
what our findings show experiments and sort of the model one iteration
so first is how and all the nodes are i hope you understand the sort
of to our surprise this is very different so for example what i'm showing you
here is time and the number of nodes in the networks in the network over
time and what you can see is that for example for africa after this initial
period you get exponential so flickr is growing exponentially on the other hand delicious which
is basically a social network of how people share bookmarks grows linearly with the number
of new users grows linearly with time for yahoo answers which is a question answering
a social networking website grow sublinearly over which is sort of a bit worrying and
they you look at least in it grows quadratically with the number of music videos
contract sort of the conclusion you can make it is not very satisfactory one but
not the arrival process seems to be network dependent depends on the main weapon network
comes from
then the next question you go and ask is what is life what is the
time span of an old rates when it created the first and the last that
if you go measure this for all four networks find the node lifetimes exponential so
if i ask you about the distribution of not node lifetimes which is the probability
i find i find that it follows an exponential distribution and here basically this
the beginning of distribution of people who get invited to the system created the first
so the conclusion here is a node lifetimes follow exponential distribution
so basically what we know so far so for another i was you know that
and in fact much of it was formulated before there was a good microscopic model
of matter before the atomic theory of matter and molecules and so forth was
well worked out
it's incredible how how powerful the whole formalism is
in some sense
although it may seem like like
neglecting what we now know to be an important part of nature
actually part of its powers of empiricism
the there are these very small number of fundamental laws from which everything else follows
and at this point of course there's just enormous confidence in that small number ones
because of their being verified in so many contexts
but at the same time we do now
about the atomic theory of matter we know there are atoms and molecules
so it ought to be possible
at least in principle
to start from a purely microscopic
approach to nature
just based on
figuring out the proper the microscopic properties
and then say well OK my macroscopic stuff is just a collection of those microscopic
i should also be able to figure out macroscopic around
i should be able to start from my microscopic picture
and get the macroscopic thermodynamic results
and in fact that is possible and the theoretical formulation for is what's called statistical
mechanics called that because of course it you will be surprised to learn that
it's going to require statistical treatment right to be dealing with walls of material but
now we're going to be trying to think about their microscopic properties and that and
so will be feeling
not with and number of moles but we can to the twenty fourth number of
molecules or atoms
and you know we won't be able to keep track of every one of their
individual states all the prime
right we may be able to do a terrific calculation of
the quantum mechanics of the count classical mechanics to describe the states that they could
but there's no way in practice but were either experimentally or theoretically keep track of
all of that
so we're going to at some point have to introduce statistics
to take what we know about the the microscopic properties and try to go from
there to the macroscopic results from around the seen so far
and that's the statistical mechanics is all about
so let's try to introduce a little bit
of statistical mechanics we're going to go from from what we know about the microscopic
properties all the way to macroscopic thermodynamics that's our objective
so let's start
by just trying to calculate
energies of individual molecules are individual particles
and what's the probability
some molecule one of the oxygen molecules somewhere in this room
it in a certain energy states
and what our strategy is going to be
is to determine
one of the probability is that molecules are in certain states
with certain energy
and if we can determine that for all the possible states
then we can average over those
so without keeping track of every individual molecule
we could then calculate on average energy which is what you would measure for and
when you look at the whole collection and measure what we call you
right of course we're really averaging over
disparate energies of lots of different atoms or molecules right they don't all have the
same molecular energy
and we don't try to measure the individual entries
so that's what we'd like to calculate and so we we
i like to be able to know what all these probabilities
of different energy states
and then from that
statistically averaging
what are the macroscopic average energy and other macroscopic one
let's start their probability
you no
specific as possible as in
he i and right now we're not even going to specify the nature of the
state we could be worrying about translational energy right what state is how fast this
was around the room
we can worry about its vibrational world rotational energy or electronic state
for now let's not even specified
let's just say it is the only thing we're really specify about the state
is it has some energy that we know that we only know
what we like
is the no functional form for the probability
we don't know one a or
let's just think about
two molecules
and there
the probability that one of them has energy by another one has energy e j
it also let me say would be sufficient to think about even one molecule and
say well let's think about independent parts of its energy let's translational energy in this
direction in orthogonal direction
what matters is we're thinking about two
energy could be separate molecules are in interacting
or independent degrees of freedom on the same molecule
but let's let's just consider it
so molecules in
they i
it in the
u j
right so what we're going to calculate is the
joint probability that they were in the two molecules are in those states so
we want the probability
this one will call
i vi ii
this would be
p j
and this probability together will be p on
i could just write the ikarma EJ but the energy that
and that's crucial
since the molecules are completely independent this should just be the product of the separate
two completely independent
the answer these things with probability one german together
that suggests the really simple functional form because
introduces a new prior so remember
there are different kinds of priors we can put in enough to not be talking
about these very broad priors like smoothness
like having multiple
factors in the representation
like having depth
in an an one extra priors this sparsity prior and the sparsity prior says that
i've already
factors that could explain important
only a small
subset that are relevant for any particular example for any particular input
that makes a lot of sense as a prior if you think about it
this notion of
explanatory factors i talked about this and think factors
one nice thing about sparse representation that enforces the representations to
to make some choices
representation parts
if u
i do i is redwood projection of the data to random mutation of it is not part so
when you have a sparse representation
different units are kind of forced to take on some particular meaning
so in quite a bit of work in representation learning with sparse representations but be
he came out as one of these e
ingredients that seem to help
in deep learning
around two thousand ten two thousand eleven
so what happens is shown in the lower left picture
where you see the neural nets
wear only a few units really
are used for any particular example
so the centre have that that
are activated
contribute to
to output into the air and alleles will be modified for a particular example
now as in this illustration that's
backprop can sometimes fail
this e
the problem that one my students work on was
presented at
i see conference i clear
last year
wear all of the machine learning methods that we tried and true including shallow networks these networks with training
is he ends
decision trees boosting
they all failed
got fifty percent error
on test set
four further those like neural nets which don't tend to overfit has as easily they
wouldn't you wouldn't be able to get even training error to to go down very
so it
so that was kind of intriguing
but it turns out that for this task
if you break down the problem
into two problems and train first network that's all the first task and then
we initialize the
you've got to initialize deep network you can sort out so it's kind of cheating
but if you can guide training by providing some kind of hints of what intermediate
level should be doing some problems which seemed
impossible suddenly become feasible
we know that as an optimization problem because if you initialize properly
you can solve this problem
so there are things that don't work well with backprop in
and maybe there are no solutions but hopefully there are solutions
one thing we discovered recently is kind of making us
i believe
be more hopeful than a few years ago
is done on this idea that neural nets are plagued by local minima maybe may be wrong
so is some
papers from
statistical physics and
the applied math and random matrices matrices
suggest that's when you consider high dimensional random function
is gonna be very unlikely that has
in a bad local minima meaning local minima
corresponding to a very bad calls
and you can think of it like
the critical point place where derivatives cancel
in order to be
i y local minimum
has to be
i have positive curvature in all directions
in if you have a lot of directions you know what's the chance of this
happening there's gonna be some direction aware it's going down and then you have a
set of points
you have cell so what happens is that there is exponentially more subtle points
then local minima except near the bottom where you have
both the global minimum and some local minima
so so if this is true and we have experiments suggesting that it seems to be true in deep nets
then that means that
the idea that we get stuck because local minimize wrong we're getting stuck
because the derivatives are flat yes that's be saddlepoint which means
if are smarter about optimization
you could find these directions going down
these these directions of negative curvature
maybe it's a needle in a haystack but it is rare it's not an impossible task
whereas if you if you think that you are stuck in a local minimum there's
nothing you can do short of using
something like
genetic algorithms or some something else that's global optimization as much harder
so that's kind of interesting and we've done some experiments to explore this hypothesis
where we
tried to
traditional newton methods so that they can go down when there is
when they are negative curvatures
basically what we do is we basically do newton except that we take the absolute
values of these i values the has been
and thanks to this we can
we can show that
in places where you are stochastic gradient descent or r
more traditional
quasi newton methods get stuck
you can actually escape
more even more recently
we're looking at
maybe even more drastic as change to
go around the limitations of background
so the reason why backdrop is problematic is not is relying on
are gradients derivatives and
derivatives make a lot of sense so long as the function you're trying to optimise
is very small as i explained earlier when you train very deep in there
very recurrent nett over many steps
you're trying to learn a function that's almost discrete
and if the function trying to learn is is very nonlinear discrete
this nonlinearity here
but this is that when there are too many people they start to compete for
the resources for the square
and this gives rise to an initial
exponential one this is negligible when the bush
and then the saturation
this is called negative feedback
too many rabbits eating grass that there are some groups of the population not enough
for a start either
the cross-strait levels
actually what is missing in this description
the possibility for positive feedback
possibly could prosecute
and the thing again the logistic equation it is called the frame it in the
case of lists population rules of price
same viable name
in population growth constant here
which cannot be of the past because of course when the population
goes to KK minus p goes to zero the rate of change becomes zero and
you this plateau
carrying case called the carrying capacity of the planet
so that's according to
but what
endogenous growth economies i've come to learn
that actually the carrying capacity of the planet has grown itself as a function of
due to innovations
research and development
growth of population list two exploration of new niches
invasion of new territories so
carrying capacity of the planet has grown itself was population to make a simple and
assuming that the carrying capacity also grows as the power of population to reflect simple
positive feedback of population on
on the extension of the carrying capacity open
your your then this equation we can neglect this if that thousand one
this is a nonlinear equation which is
in terms of the dynamics
because it leads to behavior
which most of scientists natural and social they don't like
give rise to finite time singularity
it means that there is no stationary solution
you cannot have existence proof for infinite time
if you can prove that in finite time solutions blows either go to infinity or
the rate of growth of course to infinity to infinity so this is for example
solutions really simple to calculate
this is
the blue
let's look at the data so
i'm looking at this problem with some
the hunt is on the population dynamics because it
i think it express very well the concept of positive feedback
but i want to push forward the underlying mechanism behind here i go back to
there a reconstructed over two thousand years
OK well writen somewhere here
and i took of course when one reconstructed world population
and the other one is the world's GDP
again i stress that automate is in log scale
log scale in our scale
an exponential growth is a straight line
this great like this occur
maybe here maybe here and the one sort one
OK so if you do an econometric work you need three of four exponential to
fit the data
it turns out that it's much more parsimonious and more efficient just fit this singular
behaviour which is the remarkable
description of the data
so actually
what we see here is that the population of the earth
of humans
group super exponentially over the
you see is
last five hundred years
and this is probably
the result of these
positive feedback of population carrying capacity and we can
summarise the situation i think
is was an optimist
the problem is not exponential growth problem is super exponential and this review is really
very clearly
the positive feedback phenomenon now
in market because we are dealing with financial market what can be the positive feedback
that give rise to this
girls of instability
community get crackdown many actually not going to spend time
telling any of them but just for the sake of completeness there are of the
technical and rational type and they are of the behaviour
a lot of of the modern instruments
they require for their risk contolled actually
two had to risk
two dimensional subspace of our
the fact that they work in
you're seeing that we we have some idea of dependence or independence is is in
our future
not to speak about
vector space
so again i'm getting a little ahead
because of this in section three point two but that
all right now i'm reading from the north
to keep the same metric
and this is going to be different totally different
so let me make the page down here comes a completely different
the north
what is it
it contains
not right inside the
it contains at
it contains all x's that's all there were no
and that's the key word here
maybe zero
so this campaign
this is all
and of course taxes are vectors x one x two and x three
the equations
well for quite
because we get
so you see what i'm doing
i'm now saying
OK problems were great
columns space we understood now i'm interested in
i'm not the only be uninterested in hours the BM all the right hand side
mount zero
and i'm interested in some of
whereas the novel's for this example
these are
i have three components
so the null space is the subspace we still have to show it is a
subspace of are
so this is an and we will show
so these factors that this is an
are three
the columns space was then
are for our
and in different n by n matrix
this is an
and this is an
the number of columns and tell me how many unknowns how many x multiply those
so it tells me that
big space
in this case are reason i mean
tell me why don't we figure out what the note
spaces for this example
just by
well i mean that's the
beauty of small examples
that's my official way to find no spaces
and column bases and
get all the facts right
it would be
elimination and will do that
but with a small example we can see that see what's going on without
going through the mechanics of elimination so
so there no
talking about the again
let me copy and the matrix
one two three four
one one one one two three four five
what's going on
so i'm i'm eighty eight times the
right again
and i want you to solve
o four price
in fact i want to find all solutions to those four ways
well actually the first of all what i'd like to ask you for all
tell me one what can only one solution that you don't even have to
after a look at the matrix no one solution to this
that way and it is
whatever that matrix
they contain
because a
find zero vectors are given
zero right hand side
so the knowledge base contains the
so it's going to change
the vector space and will turn out
tell me another
so this particular space
and of course i'm going to call it and a
it contains
well we already located zero vector
and now you tell me
another factor that in the bayes another another
you see what i'm asking for is a combination of those columns what i'm of
what combinations of
but now i'm looking at the
the the the way
the coefficients in the combination so tell me
i could set numbers the point in
one one one
one might say
one one minus
so there's fact that
but i got a space at this point certainly not right
i got a couple of vectors
there's no way they make a subspace
tell me
actually what i jumped the whole way now
only one more solutions
one more expert woodworkers
two two
get two
all these distances
and the reason is because if you look at the similarity matrix are shown before
this is the squared distance yeah
and the similarity these basis function the way we set up the diagonal is always worn
because it's zero distance between the two data points and it's e to the minus distance squared
so the diagonal these guys all matrices are ones
and if you are dissimilar
this can in the middle is user so the squared distance is basically to
and this where that's is square root of two
so i don't quite know what's going on my column at but all these distances
but dissimilar points are the square root two the only not square root two very
much along the diagonal
now what was
error function
classical multidimensional scaling
and it's important to use this error function to understand why things go wrong from a dimensionality reduction perspective
yeah function was mean absolute error of distances in latent space versus distances in data
space this is now a new set of distances in data space although it is
related space that we're computing things on
so when we try and do the visualization what we trying to do we trying
to minimize the mean absolute error between the distances we compute and these distances here
on which
only order
three hundred sixty
distances are not equal to the square root to all the distances are equal to
the square root of two so what's the embedding trying to do
it's trying to embed them
is to apart
can you do design a low dimensional space
we give on the from
can you embed if i want embed three hundred sixty data points
square root to apart what size space to i need to do there
so i'm gonna wanna by every data point has to be square root to apart
from each other which is more extreme than what i've got here
how how was space to any
that's put in three hundred sixty dimensional space
i can't do any other way
otherwise some other data points will be close together
so in the base case if all data points are similar they will all be
in a three hundred sixty dimensional space and in fact you can see that's gonna
be the case because the rank of this matrix here
is actually three hundred sixty minus one because in this century because the kernel matrix
is full rank
so actually when you do they
i can decomposition on this you'll find that it's dimensionality is not dimensionality expansion here
because we've got three six thousand three thousand six hundred
input dimensions going down for three hundred sixty dimensional data space but if you have
three data points it would still be
three there so if you had if u
so if you had five features in the data it would still be a three hundred sixty dimensional data space
so can appreciate is actually doing something different what it's doing is feature extraction
and it's mapping data to a high-dimensional data space certainly with this covariance function hand
because the way these functions are set up with pretty much any covariance function you
can think of which is the true covariance function we start making these things matrices
as we'll see later not covariance functions
things change
in this case you doing dimensionality expansion
and this is the result of embeddings this is the classic
i think this is what john platt once i need to ask john plant about
this but before i understood this effect well
john flowers saying i think he's dealing with salt taffy effect like sort of effect
i said he said well you know where where the arms and the embedding get
pulled out because of happy there any americans here
explain what sell taffy how you make it
you pull it so some sort of e
you pull it may still the seaside
so you pull salt happy to make the
o thing you're pulling it all strings out so this is all taffy effect
and why they doing now because okay these data points are actually similar because they're
that this as we go around this thing here we're going around the rotation and
the rotated sixes
so these guys are actually similar they're not embedded queries to apart
but this guy is trying to be square root apart from this guy
i'm going to pass from this guy and so on and so forth so the
way you tend do there is you go
in and out of dimensions your neighbors the ones who are genuinely close u
you stay close to them so when you look at this embedding in all its
dimensions it just keeps going out this is the angle between these is about ninety
degrees it goes and same here same here so goes out and back and back
and a ninety degree angle
and the fact that these things are sort the length one keeps everything swearing too far
but each of these things can actually be seen as an dimensionality
reduction this is a dimensionality risk expansion and you can visualize what these basic features are
and they're like features all the six
this one may be responding to the tail being at the top you that's all
so you've got all these features the six coming on a different time and so
is a feature extraction methods that you can do good classification and something people used
to do we can appreciate it you can appreciate and into linear classifiers and other
way of getting a nonlinear classifier but it's not a dimensionality reduction technique and just
show you give visualization about shape i've sort of
but a couple of random permutations on it
other any questions about back
well is
and he said
you could do you
and now makes you it doesn't make any difference on a computer with infinite precision
i don't think it doesn't matter if you're right you should
so it shouldn't
you should use your right that you should try and normalized data in order to
keep the computer operating in the regime where it's got most precision but i mean
for this example it doesn't
make that much difference
that's can appreciate
hi excellent just arrived she
don't tell them what i said
what i wanna do next is talk about spectral techniques
i got so ten minutes before i to the break so we'll see for how
far i get through these examples but be um
spectral approach dimensionality reduction the first example that in machine learning is canopy piece see
but the way these other techniques are quite well known isomap locally linear embeddings the
question i can maps maximum variance unfolding operator is
somewhat different to you and they do leads to a reduced dimensional representation rather than this expanded
feature set
so my favorite example
start with is classical multidimensional scaling so
again that's just a review of the sea and stuff
what i want to do is talk about isomap because i be really closely related to that's city distance example
so in the city distance example
we computed the distance between
all on
the cities in europe the forty eight that we had and we did classical multidimensional scaling on the
resulting distance matrix
and do lots and lots of things in between
so this is a list of the but all the characteristic length scale that here
things start to happen in function
so now we can see that we can all get if we use the modelling
scales then we have functions that are very much more rapidly
and if we choose one small in scale and one large lengthscale
you can see we have a function that varies
very rapidly as a function of this terrible and only slowly the variable
OK so this is a very useful effect sometimes called a rt
automatic relevance determination
so imagine a regression task
we have a bunch of input but you don't actually know exactly which of these
were inputs might be relevant to your prediction which might not
one way of addressing that problem would be to say well let's try to use
this kind of red function let's try to learn the length scale parameter by optimizing
marginal likelihood
and it happens that some of the links parameters go to very large very large
that corresponds to the function being insensitive to the exact same thing
both particularly those at the corner of the input
that correspond to that input being ignored
conversely if the but if the value of the
link for particular input it's very small this saying all
one of the function seems to to be extremely sensitive to the exact value of
the from
by doing that you can learn about
and then what you're trying to model then you look at the height of the
the length scale parameter they all you know
variable number sixteen increase a very very important and these five variables they happen you
know not have much
this is an example
of how you can
use the your understanding of the properties of the function
how that depends on the parameters
but you learn something about the property of the data
let's look at some other end so there lots of covariance function
so in the in the kernel machine literature usually use the gaussians in
kernel function of the polynomial kernel
actually lots and lots of of possibilities out there and some of them have
give rise to function interesting properties just list the few here
not any function can be chosen to be correct because remember
when you
when you write down the covariances
you have to get the matrix which is which
which is going to be used as the covariance of these scouts variables
and covariance pages have to be positive definite
or they can have negative eigenvalues
so these functions have the property
the call positive definite functions functions that have no matter what values of x i
chose the the covariance matrix must be
you must have known by
let's put some restrictions on the
on the ground
here's an article they the rational quadratic
covariance function
are here is is just the difference of x x prime
covariance functions that only depend on the difference between x and x prime of stationary
around because the covariances
don't depend on the absolute location o x will depend on the data on the
that means that
statistically the function looks the same all over the place
so the russian rather function looks like this would again be this square
divided by the length scale here we had one that raises some
power out there
one way of of
constructing a rational quadratic
covariance function is to start off with
the squared exponential
one function or gas in various functions
and then they look at large massacre in functions with a particular
values of the length scale
and then some together or integrate together
covariance functions with different length scales
OK and if you choose this
distribution over length scales are
the the inverse of the square scale
the ballot form here
then you get an interval cannot be solved you get this particular function
this kernel function of the brain functions embed somehow the idea that
the covariances act like a mixture of gaussians with different scales
so you don't have just one lengthscale signal is not expected just one link but
it expected to have
a different range of length scales that added together
and what the actual range is depends on the parameters of the distribution
OK so i show up
airport what the
what those what that covariance function looks like so just
the covariance the value of k here is just the function of the this part
of this
part of this and three different values alpha now this function has one extra problem
as alpha goes to infinity you get back the squared exponential growth
that's what i think we have
if alpha is about tool and you get this function
and the smaller value function here
you can sort of see that small
function our together different kinds of links
let's that will function so here again i drawn three random
that's all from account of this
function and the color the colour coding same
so the the green line here for four
the gulf
because see we
c square you know g you can look up
and so we find that the radius is about one centimeter
so if you could squeeze the first which is present radius of six thousand four
hundred kilometres if you could squeeze into one centimeter then you would have created a
black hole but of course
problematic to do that
if you take the sum
which by definition
there's one solar mass so you put in you the mass of the sun which
you can look up in your book
then you will find that the
radius of the event horizon is three kilometres
if you take a five solar mass black hole
there you will find that the radius of the event horizon
it is fifteen kilometres
notice it scales linearly with m
that's what you see here is linearly upstairs
so if you go from one solar mass
two five solar masses
the radius of the event horizon
scales linearly
in nineteen seventy one
astronomers stumbled
and merlin investor
king was the daring statement
that one of these systems
was the black hole binary
they looked at the spectrum of the donor
and they concluded that it probably wasn't twenty thirty mass solar star
and then they made the
but the shift measurements of the absorption lines in the spectrum of the donor
and so they went exactly sort of reasoning
that i showed you earlier which i think has been raised now
and they came up with the facts
that the creator
had to mass
of about
fifteen solar masses
so they came to the conclusion
that since it was an x-ray source u
that the creator was very small otherwise you couldn't get these high temperatures in the
so they made a daring statements that you created was probably a black hole
this had an enormous impact on the astronomical community
and a lot of people emotionally couldn't handle it
and there are lots of publications
four years to come arguing that it was all nonsense the black holes didn't exist
the data was misinterpreted the k was all kinds of other weird explanations
the black hole
still stands and
most same astronomers
that doesn't mean that all astronomers the saying but most saying astronomers
the believe that sickness x one
is a black hole and we now know of about two dozen of these systems
web idea creator
it's a black hole
and i decided to make sigma x one part of your problem set
so you have some
time to wrestle was it
i wanted to see a picture of sickness x one it is
not very
dramatic but i wanted to see it for emotional reasons you will just see star
you can see the black hole
just is star and that's all
but at least you can tell your parents that
we've seen it started is in orbit with the black hole
so if we can
get the first slide
the only slide i think i have
and we should be able
the show you a
it's the negative in astronomy we almost always work with negatives
so the cars the stars itself blackened the sky is white
and it is this star here
that is the
i don't know
it's quite bright you cannot see with naked eye for those of you are familiar
with magnitudes of stars it's nine magnitude star
and it is in orbit the black hole itself has a mass of about twenty
to thirty solar masses and the black hole
has about a mass of about fifteen so
and all of this
is the result of doppler shift measurements
profound far-reaching consequences
i think it is a wonderful moment to have a break
and i know that most of UK here not to listen to my lecture but
to take the the chris
and so
let's do that now then
so if you can help handing these out
for those of you
who come only forty many quiz i have some advice
you may have noticed
the question that i ask on the many queries on tuesday almost always goes back
to the previous lecture on thursday
think about that
so if you can help me handing these out
the biggest impact
is that it allows very simply to assess the what we call the goodness of
fit that is to say you can make some quantitative statement as to how well
the curve passes through the points
you can imagine a situation if i go back here
what's wrong way
it these are my data points
but this horizontal curves no matter what value y pick it simply doesn't describe the
data very well it doesn't have a very good goodness of fit whereas this line
with slope seems to describe the data better how can i quantify that
all the way that you can quantify is by simply using the
the value of the numerical value of the consequent function at its minimum
because if you look at this function what does it represents it represents the measured
value minus the fitted values
divided by the standard deviation the whole thing squared
so you can imagine that if the model is good
if the model this is the correct model you would expect the typical difference between
the measured values
and the predictive value to be on the order of
the standard deviation roughly the same size as there are and so you would expect
the contribution roughly one
per data point
whereas if you have a very large discrepancies between the measurements in the predicted value
we get some numbers bigger than one
now what you can show
is that if the hypothesis is correct
then this statistic the function of the data
under the assumption that the hypothesis is correct then it will fall archives squared distribution
that is to say this is the distribution that we saw i think on the
second day
so this is the case for distribution for a certain number of degrees of freedom
and the appropriate number of degrees of freedom in this case
is equal to the number of data points
minus the number of fitted parameters
so you can simply use
those features in order to compute a p value
quantify the level of agreement between measuring points
and the hypothesized functional form
of the current you're trying to fit
that is to say
you can compute the probability
to get a case where mean value
as large as you've got
or larger
because of course the larger the value of course would mean that means you have
worse agreement
between the data and the hypothesized functional form
so in the previous example with this first of all first order polynomial
that is to say that was the
straight line with with
it happened to give the mean of three point nine nine
there were five data points and two adjustable parameters the offset slope
so that means three degrees of freedom
so if i put three in there
integrate the cascade distribution from that value to infinity and i get p value of
o point two six three
moderately large values that means that if that hypothesis is correct
there's twenty six point three percent chance of getting a crisp value that high
or higher
now it it will typically be regarded as has an acceptable
level of goodness of fit
on the other hand if you consider the zeroth order polynomial that was that was
on the line that had high square value of its and its minimum of forty
five point five
that the number of degrees of freedom is in five points minus one free parameters
so i put four in there and integrate from forty five point five
to infinity and i get three times ten to the minus nine
so of course it's possible that
the hypothesis of horizontal line is correct but if you were correct you would expect
to get high scrap value
that high or higher
only with the probability three times ten to the minus nine
so that would that would be regarded as you probably say well that's unlikely to
therefore the horizontal line hypothesis is strongly disfavored
OK so fine running out of time so i want to get to a final
so that was all i wanted to say about parameter estimation that's certainly a very
important part of statistical analysis but there's one other aspect of
parameter estimation
in addition to getting actual numerical value for the parameter sometimes if it's important to
an interval
which will bracket a parameter with a certain probability
and that boils down to
in particle physics very often setting limits
such that
you can just imagine
one the this so
you created this gives you is one of the
this the slide official stated data mining problem usually computation is additional to
function and its competes smooth with nice of course you can so function any
so you should computations
but this is just an illustration of what's going on so what we see is
just the different colours is that this is
so the area that this
the more you get that a lot of money is the crosses
and this some here the parameters x one x are correlated
you can see that
like you know that's going like this
the landscape towards the development of these yellow here
these individuals not as we have genetic diagram here
that's patients
coming from a mutation crossover
this is place you want to use
is design
the global optimum which is this the best thing to do
comes close to me
since the accuracy of the we already talking about
generation one thousand four hundred one hundred individuals you
but there's not really much call
any more
so we are quite stuck this part of course asking for your results in some
cases of course such as the results i can also tell you about this kind
of you it's a very simple simplistic implementation but can do horrible things GA's choosing
the wrong operators which is the parameters to tune
this kind of classic GHT
we're not going to make it work very nicely in most cases
one the features of this problem is not very successful
it's c so one of the problems in genetic algorithms as well as well as
what musicians you have to do usually love of gravity before
that's what was on
of course because there are many problems you don't know the last but the optimisation
problem looks like what kind of characteristics we cannot afford to make a time prematurely
so that's definitely we use the difference in genetic changes
so my favourite algorithm
it's good for a moment p is also demonstrate D's
he hardly requires an inference we get all
and actually to my surprise i figured out that with one set
of parameters that find this you can take really
it used to define america problem by saying is what he does for you
and it looks like she is very sweet
exactly what you see
global optimum problem the funny usually hates make sort of online demonstrations of the program
surely the representation because you should never works the more you try to demonstrate that
d i can tell you this is no experimental random solutions generated a community sure
it will give me the result want to demonstrate absolutely fascinating so if we do
a little bit back in time here
just recalled this
i'm sure this again
you can see that after a few iterations
and why he chose parameters according to actually it turns out he is particularly useful
when they have problems we have correlated parameters this is all because this this difference
a famous a forward comes into the solution
so you don't have this fuzzy kind of trying to hold monthly meetings around the
genetic algorithms a lot of exploration always candidate solutions lots of them just to be
sure what is the dual
in this case you of course it's useless to have so much random exploration random
directions because
this problem is usually more difficult to find the exact location because the coalition parameters
and those of you that a little bit about the evolutionary computation as evolutionary strategies
have nice also to solve problems like this and they will find them in problem
like the two d problem but if you try dimension of a lot problems also
evolutionary strategies with he these seem to work beautifully also high dimensional problems
but before i go on the show you just one of example to illustrate that
because again
particularly nice again you know
again this is one of five
she is actually more like looks like in picture and if you run
the GA on this
can see
one more try
so it's very site was moved
all right
just the opposite action
and then again a lot of exploration anybody making any particular progress in the field
there was no way with minus thirteen
let me just show you one
the good old
particle swarm optimization would do with this pattern small
quite fine
when you use fact these parameters for these weights how much of the action
but it's is also quite sensitive especially if
the problem is very much more like this one
some problems
we find that acceptable like in this case
but the problem with this motivation because of the way
and the sometimes works and sometimes it doesn't
in this case was find people like to see
but this time because he said
local optimum
there is another this morning
so this is the classic implementation of particle swarm optimization of course you can find
extensions so i can get a lot of parameter tuning difficult to get anywhere but
let me show you what he does for you
because again this is
it's actually very impressive
run differential evolution on this slide seven of this
OK i don't think tank with best solutions to clients states the
this is
if the jump right into the middle as if the
is if the algorithm would have an idea where the ottomans waiting
so the only
trying to capture the science because of course because it is symmetric
all these problems are symmetric consolidating
but still you see the big difference in between the g p the
with he can tell
the middle
and again
so straightforward holes in for the right solution
just to give you a taste of what the
is capable of doing for you
OK now let's see what the boy in the case that we have the following
going to talk about
some new concepts
and that's the concept
of electrostatic
potential energy
for which we will use
this symbol u
and independently
electric potential
which is very different from which we will use the symbol v
that i have
a charge
q one here
and that's plus
plus charge and here I have the charge
plus q two and they have the distance and distance are apart
and that is point p
it's very clear
thatin order to bring these charges at this distance from each other i had
to do work to bring them there because they repel each other
it's like pushing in this spring
if you release the spring get the energy back if they were
they were connected with a little string
string would be stretched
takesscissorscut the string,they fly apart again
so i have put work
in there and that's what we call electrostatic
so let's work this out in some detail how much work i have to do
we first put q one year
ifspace is empty
this doesn't take any work to place q one here
but now i come from very far away we always thinkof that asinfinitely far away
cause that's the exaggeration and we bring this charge q two
from infinity
to that point p
and I Walter Lewin have to do work I have to push
and push and push and the closer i get the hard i have to push
and finally i reached that point
suppose i am here
and this separation
I reached that point
then the force on me
the electric force is outward
and so i have to overcome that force
so my force
fWalter Lewin
in in this direction
so you can seeIdo positive work
the force and the
direction in whichI'mmovingare in thesame directionI dopositive work
the work that i do can be calculated
the work
that Walter Lewinis doing
in going all the way from infinity
to that location p
is the integral
going from an infinity toradiusr
of the force
of Walter Lewin
the r
but of course
that work is exactly the same
you one is fine
to take
the electric force
in going from r to infinity
doty r
because the force the electric force in waterloo force i
the same in magnitude but opposite direction
so by flipping over going from infinity two are
two are to infinity
this is the same
this one and the same thing
let's calculate this integral because that's
louise easy
we know what the electric force this
school of law
it's repelling
so the force and we are now in the same direction so the angle theta
between them is zero to the cosine of data is one
so we can forget about all defectors
and so
we would get then that this equals
q one
q two
divided by four pi epsilon zero
now i have downstairs here and are square
so i have the integral now
the are
divided by squared
capitol are two infinity
and this integral
his minus one of or
which i have to evaluate between are
n infinity
and when i do that becomes plus
one of the capital are
right indigo
of the are of our squared i'm sure you can although do it is minus
one of our
i valuated between are infinity
and so you get plus
one of our
and so
which is the energy that the work that i have to do to bring this
charge at that position
that you is nokia one
and q two
divided by four pi epsilon zero
divided by the capitol are
and this
courses scale of his work
the number of jewels
if q one and q two
both positive
almost never negative i do positive work you can see that minus signs plus
because then they repel each other if one is positive and the other is negative
that i do eighty four
best players are released not
the right
so i got from the
well the
at the time that
one of
i want to
one the
o five
but if you have a
the world
the article was
what about the the
it's very
i have affair
around the world
i because
from that
the first
all right
most of the carbon through all
that the
the parts of the
first of all road salt
a lot of so
that's it
there are a lot of
one of the
so far
so what you are
well couple
well that's sort of
about four
the sign
one of the
going whether it's the business
or a product or your life
you have to put more in
and you can get called the learning in
and i think still often very exciting
in the end things go
i'm sorry
the business does go down
politics to pay
and your life
it i will take away
until you die
and of course
the answer
conceptually to that
it is very obvious
chris too quickly
i go back
you draw second life
and you are very careful to start the second line
before the first line peaks so that you have some of the resources
there is some money or time skills
on the first in order to start the second
the concept
it's not difficult
i can use it is in two minutes
and you don't need a great degree in order to understand
it is very important
the problem however is not understanding the concept
the problem is
how do you know
the dot is
on that curve how do you know
way to start to say
most people don't actually know where it is until way down the hill
on the other side
and they can look back ruefully as a of course
that's when we should have changed that's when we had the energy that's when we
have the resources
the point halfway down the hill
it's when they bring in the consultants you that's when they sacked the chief executive
and get rid of thirty percent of the company
and reorganize and struggle to get themselves up as far as they can to the
second thing you come in with your case writers
and write these wonderful cases
and were a
you meet someone says haha hopefully were not to have changed
two years ago
how do you know that parties
well you don't do it by logic
you do it by some kind of intuition
and that's something that you can't teach
you have to learn some
they practice
my wife and i have been married and have been business partners now for many
many long years ever since we met in singapore
like all great partnerships we argue a lot of the time
we are good very deeply
last night about something
now i
on the left brain man i studied logic and philosophy
i like the reason for everything highlighting the need boxes like an argument i'd like
to be able to say so therefore
we do this
my wife's is very much on the right hand side of the head and sometimes
i think
around here
so last night as so often
she eventually gave in to my larger alright he said
but i am right
and i have to tell you she nearly always is
and i have to learn
for instance she doesn't know anything about economics of business
but when you're at the sloan school MIT we are on very minor
minimal government grant so to supplement our income we had a little import business tiny
important business of
brass rubbing is now you may not know what brass rubbing is embedded in the
english churches
they have these brass on top of the tombs of some of
distinguished ancestors way back
fifty eight hundred forty eight hundred people rather the
on two onto parchment and they come out this sort of
my print really
so we got some friends in england to do this
and they wrote about the past sheets and the ship them off to america and
we put the made images from there are about six long
hang on walls
we thought the americans would love to buy and there's about going to act as
the marketing director for our little tiny business and go around selling them while i
was studying business
on the MBA course at the flow schools
and he said well
we've enterprise
and i said don't worry
i mean the marketing manager shelf
i know about that
what's the landed cost
and it worked out the cost actually not very much about two dollars
well i said we could be extravagant normally shall we on fifty percent i think
we've got an of fifty percent we could charge these three dollars
she said
i think you're wrong
i said that
i think this is
i was the marketing manager shell international she said
i just have an idea why don't we give is the project
to one of the groups in your business school and the marketing calls
she did that
and they came back and they said
you should so this is a luxury product we suggest you to forty two dollars
so we did i said that absolutely ridiculous outrageous it's immoral
so anyway we prices in the under twenty dollars
and he said more secret indeed the price fifty two
i tell you something in some situations
the brain is here
is much better
and the brain
the here